Speaker 1: It's Monday September 18th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We will discuss the history of sound in personal computing.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, we're back from if you can't guess another somewhat crazy weekend.
Speaker 1: Too crazy too crazy.
Speaker 0: That wasn't too crazy.
Speaker 1: We've had crazier Yeah, but it was too crazy considering I haven't had a. what was the last time we had a break weekend?
Speaker 0: God, where's the last time I got a good night's sleep?
Speaker 0: Yeah, not tonight, that's for sure.
Speaker 0: no no not tonight It's too late Yeah, but we went off into the city with her friends Kate and Adam and with Emily to do some.
Speaker 0: well Scott didn't participate because he is a pansy, but the rest of us did Japanese style karaoke.
Speaker 1: It's not cuz I'm a pansy is cuz?
Speaker 1: I don't waste my time doing stupid karaoke.
Speaker 0: You just don't get it.
Speaker 0: the sheer joy of singing Michael Jackson's beat it in a British accent was brought.
Speaker 1: I rest my case.
Speaker 0: Anyway, as usual.
Speaker 0: It's Monday, and we're exhausted.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm All right, so you want to just jump right into this news here?
Speaker 0: I think we should.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to talk about how tired I am.
Speaker 1: yeah, I got nothing else.
Speaker 1: so Apparently these guys in the quest to keep their computers cold without making lots of noise decided that they were going to use the technology of ionization to keep their computers cold.
Speaker 1: now If you don't know there are these air filters that you can buy air purifiers you mean the old lady killers?
Speaker 1: Exactly, okay, and what these things do is kill old ladies.
Speaker 1: exactly They're basically these air filters.
Speaker 1: You can buy that way.
Speaker 1: they do filter the air.
Speaker 1: They're they're not lying about that using Ions, I'm curious Scott.
Speaker 0: Do you know how they actually work?
Speaker 0: barely you.
Speaker 0: Okay, you create a charge right yeah?
Speaker 0: And most particle a little static bits are often also somewhat charged and attract them to a plate.
Speaker 0: It's the same reason that dust is attracted to your computer monitor No, and why TVs always get covered in dust computers always get covered in dust.
Speaker 0: everything electronic gets covered in dust.
Speaker 1: You basically just make an electronic thing to gather the dust kinda yeah, so somehow they use this to move air Get and keep their computers cold and of course.
Speaker 1: It's quiet because it's just electricity.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: there's no moving parts There's nothing vibrating.
Speaker 1: There's nothing to make noise and it worked.
Speaker 1: it cost a thousand dollars for the kit But it worked.
Speaker 0: did you actually read the article as to how this works?
Speaker 1: There's only like a paragraph here.
Speaker 0: So we're not gonna have some sort of cool in-depth discussion of well How this technology is cool, and how it works and why you should all care about it.
Speaker 1: We should care about it because it's a bad idea because you're going to fill your house with ozone and die.
Speaker 0: not necessarily Not necessarily, but probably I mean while I mean a lot of those early ionizers made a lot of ozone But I mean my Atari made a lot of ozone too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not as much as this thing though I don't know.
Speaker 0: my Atari made a lot of ozone.
Speaker 0: It smelled like a thunderstorm after I played that.
Speaker 1: but the other reason I chose this story is because it's on and gadget and in gadget Upgraded today to the new in gadget now.
Speaker 0: Here's the sad part.
Speaker 0: Scott said the upgraded in gadget.
Speaker 0: It's awesome Go look, so I went and I didn't notice any difference at all.
Speaker 0: It didn't look any different to me.
Speaker 0: He had to point out what they had changed.
Speaker 1: Well, the interesting things they done is number one you to post a comment on.
Speaker 1: in gadget You used to have to confirm every comment by email, which is a nightmare and it really well.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't hinder commenting on the gadget at all.
Speaker 1: people still posted a jillion comments.
Speaker 0: Why don't we change our forums to be that we have to personally approve each and every message people post?
Speaker 1: It's not a good idea.
Speaker 1: We already personally approve each and every person.
Speaker 1: I think that's enough.
Speaker 1: But they also.
Speaker 1: it did make the reading comments on engage it basically impossible and useless.
Speaker 1: now this comment moderation and everything.
Speaker 1: So and also comment threading so you can read the comments and they make sense and they're useful.
Speaker 1: The other thing they did is if you have a big monitor The picture is on and get.
Speaker 1: you are now high resolution and they will expand on your bigger screens and and also Contract on your smaller screens.
Speaker 0: No, they won't contract on the smaller screens at all.
Speaker 1: That's as long as it's not.
Speaker 1: but I think 1024 by 768 is the minimum resolution.
Speaker 0: I I'm at a higher resolution than that and I could not make the image be any smaller or larger than it was.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 1: I did it at work where the screens bigger.
Speaker 1: I Had two screens at work and I just stretched it across both screens.
Speaker 1: It went bloop.
Speaker 1: Ah So it's for people with widescreens.
Speaker 1: basically, you know, the widescreen monitors or giant projectors or HDTVs or what have you?
Speaker 1: But yeah in gadget is cooler.
Speaker 1: Now if you like gadgets, I don't know why you're not reading in gadget.
Speaker 0: Well, you could read gizmodo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which has some problems.
Speaker 1: It's basically like I used to.
Speaker 1: they were both basically equal back in the day But over time and gadget has been you know, beating gizmodo Puncher pun.
Speaker 0: I pretty much just read slash down in Kotaku and I ignore the whole gadget thing.
Speaker 1: and gadget also has a fun podcast Which is cool All right.
Speaker 1: I know you listen to podcast because you're listening to this.
Speaker 0: No, remember a lot of our listeners don't listen other podcasts Yeah, but you know, they listen to at least one podcast.
Speaker 1: They might listen to two If they might see if they're all you know.
Speaker 0: for all you know, they're listening on some pirate radio station somewhere.
Speaker 1: Hey, if you're playing us in a pirate radio station, we don't care.
Speaker 1: We want it because you're allowed to with the Creative Commons.
Speaker 1: Just tell us about it.
Speaker 1: Don't be all secret.
Speaker 0: thing is they don't even have to tell us the way we set it up Yeah, but they do have to give us credit.
Speaker 1: Yeah So they have to tell the people that are listening to us on the pirate radio station what they're listening to.
Speaker 0: But do they really because we give ourselves credit unless they cut off the closing bid Even though the closing bid is old and out of date and season two will rectify that.
Speaker 1: I think the license actually says like they have to credit, you know, it's like they have to do something.
Speaker 1: It can't just be us crediting ourselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really wouldn't care.
Speaker 1: either way It died and really care either.
Speaker 1: but I would like to know that's all.
Speaker 1: that's all I wanted.
Speaker 1: They should they should have a new Creative Commons license, you know.
Speaker 1: Attribution share alike no commercial.
Speaker 1: Let us know.
Speaker 1: You know Alright yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway This actually was somewhat surprising news because it goes against the trend of this entire Industry for the past two decades if not more.
Speaker 0: Now a while ago it came out that Universal was going to sue the ever-living hell out of YouTube for The such horrible crimes as someone lip-syncing to one of their songs in a crappy resolution video.
Speaker 0: Oh shits they want to shut YouTube down because it does nothing but facilitate this grievous Violation of copyright law and you know deprive their children of bread and all that sort of.
Speaker 1: have they heard of anime music videos?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm really surprised that the anime industry has gotten away completely unscathed so far in this AMV business.
Speaker 1: It's the anime industry isn't making the AMVs and they're not hosting the AMVs and they're promoting the AMVs Except that the conventions are straight up with tournaments.
Speaker 1: They sure are all these fan-run conventions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean even Otacon they.
Speaker 0: they escape any sort of ire about it.
Speaker 0: Hey, but the thing is Warner music has come out and said you know what?
Speaker 0: YouTube can use any of the music videos we've got and they can take any part of those music videos Which obviously includes the music in them and do whatever they want in a non-commercial way.
Speaker 0: All they have to do is put it back on YouTube for other people to say yeah I think that this might be the turn of the tide.
Speaker 0: this might be Gandalf standing here saying, huh?
Speaker 1: I think what it is is that someone at Warner music fine.
Speaker 1: There's someone there with a brain.
Speaker 1: finally there's someone at this place with a brain and what they're thinking is a Music video isn't really like a creative work that you're trying to sell.
Speaker 1: It's an advertisement that you want as many people to see and hear as possible.
Speaker 0: I mean if you don't believe that most music videos you just can't get they're not available It's not like you can buy a DVD that has all the music videos you want.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you can yeah sometimes but most They're not out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, music videos are advertisements for bands.
Speaker 1: That's what they are That's.
Speaker 1: MTV is just a TV network that shows ads all day long.
Speaker 1: I mean if it still showed videos But it doesn't.
Speaker 0: but unless you want to know how old we are when MTV came about and we watched it as kids the only non Music video content was like the night cartoon blog with Beavis and Butthead and MTV News and MTV News.
Speaker 1: Yep nowadays, it's pretty much all the music videos and like MTV too, but the point is is that Someone at Warner music was saying hey if we put this shit on YouTube It'll be like free advertising that a billions of people well not billions, but millions of people will look at it constantly every day.
Speaker 0: Isn't that what geeks and people who know better have been trying to tell the music industry for the last 20 fucking years?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and one person finally said, uh Now this is big news for one reason one reason alone Universal is with the status quo and Warner has just done something that at least for the music industry is Absolutely batshit crazy.
Speaker 1: I think it's only a matter of time before Someone discovers like some unknown band that long ago signed like a one-out signed a record contract with Univer with Warner, you know made one music video in one album then disappeared off the face of the earth Because it didn't sell and now it's gonna become crazy popular.
Speaker 1: now I wonder because someone's gonna make a funny video like Numa Numa to it or something.
Speaker 0: I'm waiting for the next Thing to happen the next company to react to this because if another company says we're doing what Warner did That is probably the beginning of a new era of copyright.
Speaker 1: And if that doesn't think it is the thing though, is that the Even though they're giving the music videos away, which are essentially advertisements.
Speaker 1: There's still advertisements for The CDs and stuff so they still need to have Either the overpriced CDs or the DRM stuff or at least they think they do in order to sell something to you.
Speaker 1: This is just saying alright, we were previously Pretending our advertisements were products.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna pretend that anymore.
Speaker 1: We're gonna you know, put our advertisements to get as much exposure for them as possible.
Speaker 1: Watch our commercials all you want, but our product is still copyright.
Speaker 1: blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah but the thing is now at least because you can't.
Speaker 0: the argument that oh I can just steal the music is separate from the Argument that I can use the music to create better things non commercially.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm if they're allowing the latter I'm so much more.
Speaker 0: Okay with them cracking down on people who pirate the music Is the man I mean way back when this whole music industry thing and you know mp3s really started getting bad and nabster suddenly got sued by a bunch of people.
Speaker 0: if The right the industry had been reasonable at all at any point along the way Then it wouldn't have been an issue at all because people probably would have generally said yeah, we can't steal their music But the record industry they were just such dicks about it to be perfectly blunt that Most people who knew better or knew about the technology just said, you know, what fine screw you we're done with you.
Speaker 0: We're going to destroy your industry.
Speaker 0: There's nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also another thing though, is that if they're letting anyone, you know remix any of their songs in any way they want You know, of course, it's within the confines of YouTube.
Speaker 1: But if they're doing that right a big one of the major arguments against all the things record companies are doing is you're hindering Creativity because now with copyright no one can use fair use to your remix and create new things with your music.
Speaker 1: But if they're gonna let people do that Then it really shoots a lot of arguments against them just gone.
Speaker 1: It's like no we're gonna let you do all that.
Speaker 1: We're just not gonna.
Speaker 0: you know what.
Speaker 0: it doesn't shoot down to be a cynic here.
Speaker 1: It doesn't shoot down the economics argument But yeah, but you know It does shoot down a whole lot of the argument.
Speaker 0: in the very least I expect to see a boom of Warner music related YouTube funny bits in the next several months.
Speaker 1: I predict Warner music will not do as well as music record companies did in their peak.
Speaker 1: However, they were going to beat the other record companies into the ground unless they follow suit or at least they'll beat Universal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because Universal now has basically infinite bad press among geeks.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw hockey Kicking your ass.
Speaker 1: Not I think in a day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you see we mentioned last week and for all of our new listeners This isn't what we normally do but we're doing something different because it's a very special time of the year.
Speaker 1: Yes If you are not aware Training camp for the NHL has just ended and the preseason is starting any minute now.
Speaker 0: now many of you are geeks and some of you are nerds as Since the show's geek nights is definitely not an insult to call you either one of those because we are also self-identified.
Speaker 0: But you might be wondering
Speaker 1: why
Speaker 0: are rim and Scott the hosts of geek nights about to talk about sports something that traditionally is anathema to nerds
Speaker 1: Because sports aren't all bad and
Speaker 0: in fact Well, we talk a lot about geekery and we you know, we cover the main geekeries, but you can be a geek in anything.
Speaker 0: I mean there are car geeks.
Speaker 0: There are sports geeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're also car nerds and sports nerds.
Speaker 1: They're scarier, you know, you want to avoid those people.
Speaker 0: I mean a job like you know when a lot of people talk about.
Speaker 0: we had a guy in the forums who went nuts about this about Damn those jocks with their stupid sports and our sports centric culture and that's you know.
Speaker 0: You call them a jock, but they're really just a sports nerd because they can only identify with other people through sports.
Speaker 0: But they're no better off or worse off than a chess nerd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just that old stereotype of you know.
Speaker 1: revenge of the nerds against the evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then try lambs.
Speaker 1: but It's really, you know, we don't see that as really existing.
Speaker 1: I mean we went to a tech school the nerdiest school in the world.
Speaker 0: It was also one of the most hockey in schools in the world.
Speaker 1: But the ice hockey team man if that arena wasn't full for every goddamn home game.
Speaker 0: Now also as another good thing when we're talking about hockey, right It seems that of all of these sports in the u.s.
Speaker 0: The major sports Hockey has probably the biggest nerd and geek following if any of them nice.
Speaker 1: It seems to be that way.
Speaker 0: I mean all a lot of the big tech schools though It might be simply because the tech schools happen to be a lot in the north
Speaker 1: and the east or it's that the non tech schools Concentrate so heavily on other sports that the only place the tech schools can get an edge in any sport is the less popular ice.
Speaker 1: Or it's because you know, we happen to be in the north very close to Canada above the Messier line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is an old joke, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I couldn't.
Speaker 1: I've looked it for the picture online.
Speaker 1: I can't find it again But this is funny map on the internet and someone drew and they basically drew a horizontal line across the middle of the United States you know, uh and It says this is the Messier line and above the Messier line Which is the top half of the United States and Canada it says hockey and below that line.
Speaker 1: It says no hockey.
Speaker 1: Now there are many.
Speaker 1: there are many NHL teams below the Messier line like the Florida Panthers Or the.
Speaker 1: that is not however hockey the Nashville Predators But anyone who lives above the messy line is like whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now we're geeks We're super geeks, but we are also really into hockey and not just ice hockey for the NES Which is the best sports game ever?
Speaker 0: Yes now someday we're going to tell the stories of the hockey games at RIT Because RIT hockey it was probably one of the greatest things that was ever happened to me in college Indeed.
Speaker 0: I mean it's in the top 10 at least.
Speaker 1: however to get to the point To celebrate the beginning of a new ice hockey season the second ice hockey season since the dang Unspeakable strike I just spoke of it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, which ruined much of hockey.
Speaker 1: We are going to attempt to slightly promote hockey by showing you the most entertaining part of hockey all this week.
Speaker 1: for things of the day We're going to.
Speaker 1: it is now.
Speaker 1: Yeah hockey fight week all hockey fights all the time.
Speaker 0: Now remember that we're gonna mean with each fight we're gonna try to highlight a different aspect of hockey.
Speaker 0: But there are non fighting aspects to hockey and we enjoy those too.
Speaker 0: We enjoy them very much.
Speaker 0: However, hockey fights are freaking hilarious.
Speaker 0: Even if you don't like hockey.
Speaker 1: That's the point the reason we've chosen hockey fights as our.
Speaker 1: you know, I'm not gonna show you amazing goals.
Speaker 1: You know cuz but you know, if you don't like hockey the goal isn't going to be amazing or exciting.
Speaker 0: Yeah Plus the goal doesn't mean anything really unless you know the team's behind it and you care and you're curious.
Speaker 0: and it's it's not.
Speaker 0: It's not that but anyone can appreciate two guys Punching each other in the face for like two minutes until one of them passes out.
Speaker 1: even a complete total chest nerd Chest boxing just boxing.
Speaker 0: now I'll start with my thing of the day because I chose it for a very specific reason in addition to showing a Fantastic hockey fight a hockey fight that I was in the arena live to watch in person.
Speaker 0: But it also illustrates that hockey fighting isn't just two guys beating each other up.
Speaker 0: There's a lot to it and hopefully you'll kind of get a perspective as to why hockey fights are so absolutely Freaking amazing and why there are fights in hockey and not in other sports and why that's okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean how rare is there?
Speaker 0: I mean you're watching a baseball game and suddenly there's a fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like a few times a year and it is about as many hockey fights in a week of hockey as there are in a Year of baseball there are about as many hockey fights as there are periods of ice hockey in a given season.
Speaker 0: Alright so this see I grew up in hockey town Detroit.
Speaker 0: Detroit is one of the most Hockey centric cities in the non Canadian northern United States.
Speaker 0: Hockey is big there.
Speaker 0: hockey is big there like Jesus is big in Spain.
Speaker 0: and there was this man named Claude Lemieux who he is pretty much widely regarded by even many of his own teammates back in the day as the cheapest wimpiest Turtling yet bite-causing Annoying pest to ever be a hockey player.
Speaker 0: This guy was responsible for so many fights.
Speaker 0: He injured players all the time But whenever he got into a fight his typical reaction was to turtle Meaning.
Speaker 0: he'd curl up in a ball and hope that the referee saved him.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Now he was responsible for a lot of horrific injuries but there was also.
Speaker 0: he played for the Colorado Avalanche back then and the Colorado Avalanche and the Detroit Red Wings had this Crazy crazy rivalry going on.
Speaker 1: a bunch of Russian guys pitch pissed off at a bunch of Canadian guys.
Speaker 0: Pretty much there were no Americans involved.
Speaker 0: Yeah And what happened was that at one point Claude Lemieux got this really cheap shot and hurt one of the Red Wings.
Speaker 0: Now they were gonna take it and they weren't gonna deal with this.
Speaker 0: They weren't gonna take it.
Speaker 0: This was the end.
Speaker 0: So they had one of the enforcers on the team.
Speaker 0: now Here's some terminology for you.
Speaker 0: If you're a fan of a hockey team the big guys who cause fights are called enforcers because they protect your good players From the other teams thugs.
Speaker 0: and Now any other hockey team that you are not a fan of.
Speaker 0: their big guys are thugs and all they do is start fights unjustly.
Speaker 1: that is correct.
Speaker 0: So that basically they hated Claude Lemieux and now there's about to be a face-off.
Speaker 0: They're about to drop the puck.
Speaker 0: the Red Wing Immediately jumps him and beats the ever-living hell out of him.
Speaker 1: That's what he does.
Speaker 0: That's all I got to say about that.
Speaker 0: Just watch the video.
Speaker 0: It'll probably explain a little bit about how hockey fights come about and why they're the way they are at least a little bit Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: now me who was born in Queens, New York and grew up in Connecticut is a me is yes me Is.
Speaker 1: I'm getting ready for pirate day.
Speaker 1: I Am by genetics I think a fan of the New York Rangers who Play in the world's most famous arena Madison Square Garden and are the most expensive team in hockey.
Speaker 0: Garden doesn't have it doesn't have a statue of Joe Louis's fist.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It has managed square Joe Louis's fist.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: It's huge anyway, and They are the most expensive.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure if they're still the most expensive team but in terms of what it costs to pay all their players They're the most expensive team in hockey And I think it's the only team that like every single relative I have is a fan of the Rangers and we care more about the hockey than the other sports even though, you know, we kind of care about the other sports, but Anyway, when I was really watching like every Ranger game on MSG every night when I was a kid, you know The enforcer of the Rangers the key one was a man named oof Samuelson.
Speaker 1: it's a obviously a north of northern European descent and he was a large dangerous and scary man.
Speaker 0: Yep, we had a man named Shanahan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but oof Samuelson I would see him about.
Speaker 1: you know, a few times a week beat the shit out of somebody.
Speaker 1: Well, I went and I searched for him on the YouTube and the Google video and I found only one video for you to see oof Samuelson in action.
Speaker 1: and This isn't a video of oof Samuelson beating anyone up.
Speaker 1: This is a video of another hockey player Ty Domi who is also an ass a thug You will from some other team that isn't even worth mentioning who Takes a cheap shot at oof Samuelson and knocks him out one hit.
Speaker 1: Basically what had happened was I'm linking to the 10-second video, but you'll see on in YouTube There's another video with a different camera angle.
Speaker 1: That's like two minutes long and that will let you see the whole situation.
Speaker 1: where Ty Domi tripped oof Samuelson.
Speaker 1: That got him a two-minute penalty Which means he's out of the game because it's only less than two minutes left in the game.
Speaker 1: So they're gonna have a power play no matter what and he's out of the game for the rest of this game no matter what?
Speaker 1: So why not punch oof Samuelson in the face and injure him and then he'll be out of the game, too And it'll be.
Speaker 1: you'll at least take someone with you.
Speaker 1: So that's exactly what he did.
Speaker 1: and they like they bring out the stretcher to carry oof away and it's it's pretty entertaining to show you.
Speaker 1: You know it goes both ways in the hockey fights like a bisexual exactly anyway.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna dwell on that anymore now.
Speaker 1: tomorrow We're just gonna go to with two hockey.
Speaker 0: I hope that wasn't too much needless exposition But we really wanted to set the stage because I can guarantee to you that the magnitude of the videos We will be linking to this week will only increase.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you think that these hockey fights are like oh shits wait You know wait do you see?
Speaker 1: the hockey fights are gonna link to tomorrow the next day the next day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't spoil it by going around Google video and YouTube just searching for hockey fights cuz that's you know.
Speaker 0: yeah We're basically doing kind of a. we'll give you the cream of the crop here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we filter it for you if you go searching around looking at everything yourself.
Speaker 1: What's the point?
Speaker 0: All right, and of course it'll culminate in Thursday where there's a good chance.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about hockey.
Speaker 1: yeah Straight up, that'll be crazy.
Speaker 0: Anyway, all right so on to the main bit Which is partly a cop-out because we're exhausted, and if you can't tell it was the only thing we came up with.
Speaker 0: We're trying to finish this show so I can go to bed.
Speaker 1: Yep, we're gonna talk to you today about the history of sound and sound cards and sound chips in personal computers.
Speaker 0: Yep Not so much from the technical perspective because I doubt many of you care and because if we get anything wrong James Lee gal at Us well someone will yell at us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if we get anything wrong about the electronics James Lee gal at us.
Speaker 0: if we get anything wrong about the music or the Chips they're can only yell at us someone else.
Speaker 1: We're so we're gonna.
Speaker 1: You know be a lot of our stuff.
Speaker 1: We're just reading off the internet, but we've done a bunch.
Speaker 1: It's it's a collected research to save you time yeah And also to teach you and hopefully entertain now you kids.
Speaker 0: I don't want to call you kids, but you kids have it easy today because any sound card works.
Speaker 0: I mean you buy a new computer.
Speaker 0: There's probably just a sound card that work.
Speaker 0: that'll work fine just built into the motherboard Every computer.
Speaker 0: you just don't even worry about it.
Speaker 0: sound cards are a commodity.
Speaker 0: They're pretty much all the same.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to even worry about them at all unless you're making music and even then your options are fairly limited.
Speaker 0: back in the day Wasn't quite like that before Soundblasters.
Speaker 0: there really wasn't sound in computers.
Speaker 0: the way you think about sound all right.
Speaker 1: well I think the one technical thing we have to talk about is the difference between PCM and Synthesizers.
Speaker 0: yeah, let also people will remember MIDI.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well MIDI is related to that, but yeah basically A synthesizer is a musical instrument.
Speaker 1: It's an electronic musical instrument But it is an instrument nonetheless.
Speaker 1: the what a synthesizer does is it takes some sort of Inputs.
Speaker 1: you know digital inputs usually dials switches sometimes even analog inputs like some waves or something and then there is some sort of logic in a chip.
Speaker 1: and What it does is it takes the based upon the inputs.
Speaker 1: it generates some sort of analog output.
Speaker 1: So you it's basically a machine that makes waves and sounds in a certain way Where if you keep giving it you know the same input.
Speaker 1: if you set the dials to the same place and push the same buttons It'll make the same sound and that's what a synthesizer is.
Speaker 1: and back in the day Most sound chips in computers because I mean this wasn't in the day of sound cards This is in the days were like you had an Apple 2 and there was a sound chip on the in the computer And that was it.
Speaker 1: or you had a Macintosh 512 K you know and in the Macintosh was a sound chip and that was it.
Speaker 0: or if any of you were too young for that a Nintendo or a Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: yeah, those things could make PCM They could play that.
Speaker 0: but for the most part the vast majority of what you heard was synthesized using square waves sawtooth waves triangle waves.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know it was.
Speaker 1: basically there was an instrument inside your computer a chip that was also a musical instrument and The computer programs your games or your software or your operating system or some other program on your computer Would send digital information or do some computation and then based upon that computation send Digital control signals you know zeros and ones to the musical instrument to play it.
Speaker 1: So it was as if there was a little man inside your computer Who was sending zeros and ones to a musical instrument and depending on which zeros and ones he sent.
Speaker 1: he was playing that instrument.
Speaker 1: you know it was pretty crazy because Each computer had a different instrument in it so each computer made different music.
Speaker 0: Yep, you really couldn't rely on a computer to sound the same especially when it came to even later on with things like MIDI.
Speaker 0: Now MIDI is a lot more complicated than I'm gonna make it out to be and it's not actually Like people think.
Speaker 0: MIDI is just a kind of music file, and it's not at all what it is.
Speaker 0: It's just us.
Speaker 0: It's basically sheet music for a computer.
Speaker 0: you put it in and it says oh I'll make this is from play this and this is from play this and a lot of games back in the day used MIDI to make the music and also a lot of people collected MIDI files and For the most part they sounded completely different on everyone's computer because everyone had different little instruments stored in their MIDI
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: you know and that was in the days You can even change what instruments are stored in there.
Speaker 1: You know a lot of people.
Speaker 1: just there was the default one and that was it.
Speaker 1: yep now You know back in the day what you had like in an Apple to GS had like this Ensonique chip which was like the same one that was in professional synthesizers.
Speaker 1: But then the Commodore was the most famous.
Speaker 1: it had these SID chip.
Speaker 0: now you may remember this is from some bands that we like Like one band like makani supremacy possibly.
Speaker 1: yeah, there's also an OC remix.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of Commodore 64 remixes, and you the SID chip is is a very famous chip because The the way something to do with the manufacturer.
Speaker 1: I don't remember exactly what but no two SID chips sound exactly the same as each other and It has a very distinctive sound that sounds like nothing else.
Speaker 1: So When you hear Commodore music you go oh And you know that that is a famous very important sound chip.
Speaker 0: But things didn't get interesting until the ad-lib came out yep ad-lib and then not too long after that sound blaster.
Speaker 1: Yeah before it wasn't until see before the PC the IBM PC.
Speaker 1: You know every computer was a special device.
Speaker 1: You know you had an Apple - and you got Apple - software.
Speaker 1: you had a Commodore.
Speaker 1: you got Commodore software.
Speaker 1: You had an Amiga.
Speaker 0: you got Amiga software, but pcs were standard.
Speaker 0: I mean you had a PC.
Speaker 0: you could everyone everyone's the same and everyone.
Speaker 0: everyone had DOS or Windows on their PC And then you could put any hardware in there you could buy standard peripherals like by a drive And you know that that drive could work on any one of these that they would all work the same yep.
Speaker 1: So the first real you know popular well-used sound card was the ad-lib and the ad-lib was basically a synthesizer on a board and they made this thing and they sold it and Everyone got one if they wanted sound in their PC.
Speaker 0: now It wasn't that great and it didn't really explode until not too long after the sound blasters Which were very similar to the ad-libs.
Speaker 1: well what happened was is the ad-lib was actually a very simple card to make.
Speaker 1: so once Everyone bought an ad-lib they looked at it And they said I can make that and they went to Radio Shack and they bought a bunch of chips and they made it.
Speaker 1: yeah and so everyone and their mother was selling ad-lib cards and You know some of them sounded different, but that didn't matter, but the sound blaster 1.0 Was basically an ad-lib card with a single PCM channel and a game port which is very important
Speaker 0: yes because remember back in the day there was no USB.
Speaker 0: if you wanted to Have a joystick Basically the only way that would happen was.
Speaker 0: you had a serial joystick which sucked sucked ass.
Speaker 0: there were some parallel peripherals Which also sucked for reasons.
Speaker 1: yeah, you could plug your joystick into the printer port which sucked Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or you can have a sound card that had a game controller and many sound cards.
Speaker 0: also had CD-ROM Controllers because CD-ROMs weren't IDE back then.
Speaker 1: no they were.
Speaker 0: CD-ROMs were this special thing and sound cards for Various reasons that we're not going to get into ended up also being CD-ROM controllers and joystick controllers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, part of it had to.
Speaker 1: well the reasons.
Speaker 1: They were joystick controllers because the game port the port that old-school PC game Game pads and joysticks plugged into on the sound card was also the same kind of hole that MIDI Controllers and MIDI devices go into.
Speaker 0: well it wasn't the same kind of hole for the most part But it was pin.
Speaker 0: it was pin identical in that you could plug a thing into it and just route the pins to different Shape connectors, and they would have two standard MIDI holes.
Speaker 1: yep So they had the same.
Speaker 1: they put a hole a little connector on the sound card that you would use for MIDI And then they could also use it for video game controllers.
Speaker 0: I remember I had a little device that would plug into my game port and then it split off into two midis and It extended the joystick part so I could keep my joystick plugged in.
Speaker 0: hmm of course I had to make sure not to futz with my joystick while I was recording music or anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we'll skip a whole bunch of history.
Speaker 0: up until pretty much the revolution in sound when the sound blaster 16 came out That was the first modern sound card.
Speaker 0: It was indeed is the first sound card that would basically be able to do almost all the things that your sound card today Can do.
Speaker 0: it could play music at normal bit rates at normal sampling rates.
Speaker 0: It could play more than one sound at the same time.
Speaker 0: it was pretty much that was when sound started mattering in games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh, I forgot to me.
Speaker 1: see we I believe been talking about synthesizing up until now.
Speaker 1: PCM which is all I'm gonna call it right now instead of confusing you is Pretty much all you're doing with your sound card today.
Speaker 1: PCM is a way of representing sound as a bunch of zeros and ones modern sound cards.
Speaker 1: all you're really doing is sending them PCM and then they turn the PCM into sound and you hear it.
Speaker 0: yep So now some games use synthesized music.
Speaker 0: But usually what will happen is the game will synthesize it itself in the software and then send the result to your sound card.
Speaker 0: that Way no matter what sound card you have it'll always sound the same.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I mean you have a CPU in your computer That is a processor which can process anything and you can send it any software you want and it'll do it.
Speaker 1: So you can write a piece of software that does the same thing as a very old synthesizer or a very new synthesizer And if the CPU is fast enough it can take you know Any inputs.
Speaker 1: process them in the same way.
Speaker 1: the synthesizer would get PCM's.
Speaker 1: send the PCM's to your sound card and you'll hear it.
Speaker 0: That's how it works now pretty much back then.
Speaker 0: in order to use the sound card you had to especially in games You had to know a lot about your sound card.
Speaker 0: You had to know how it was configured.
Speaker 0: you had to know all the bio stuff that was set up and It the gauge game had to specifically support each sound card.
Speaker 0: So you'd buy a game like tie fighter and then you'd run the setup program and it would say What sound card do you have?
Speaker 0: and it would have a list of like ten and if you didn't have one of those ten It was probably not going to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now the list was like seven sound blaster cards to ad lib cards and then an author that never works.
Speaker 1: Well, the famous one is Wolfenstein 3d.
Speaker 1: in the options menu had to add three choices Adlib sound blaster and none.
Speaker 1: those are your three choices.
Speaker 1: but eventually because what was happening was most people went with sound blasters and Other people wanted to also be able to sell sound cards.
Speaker 1: They ended up making their sound cards sound blaster compatible.
Speaker 1: so if you chose sound blaster, it would still work.
Speaker 1: and so the way they you know got around.
Speaker 1: this problem of Everyone had to you know, make their software specific to one sound card is by making all the sound cards the same.
Speaker 0: Yep, God my first computer came with.
Speaker 0: it was an HP that came with a fort 16 sound card and God was that thing as my Aptiva came with a sound blaster 16.
Speaker 0: See I went out.
Speaker 1: Perfect run-of-the-mill ISA car.
Speaker 0: I convinced my parents and I went out and I bought Physically for quite a bit of money a sound blaster awe which stands for advanced wave effects 32.
Speaker 1: Yeah It wasn't until I got my penny m3 450 that I bought a sound blaster live Value because I didn't need the non value and it was a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I bought the live way way later I got the Platinum for various reasons, but the author t2 was one of those few light not life-changing But one of those moments in computing were a whole bunch of computer knowledge.
Speaker 0: suddenly all clicked together.
Speaker 0: for me like I remember the exact moment because I had the game tie fighter and I had this fort 16 sound card and Tie fighter was great, but the music really sucked.
Speaker 0: It just sounded like crap and the sound effects like if more than a few sounds are playing at the same time.
Speaker 0: It just broke and it didn't work.
Speaker 0: So I install this all 32 and after a few hours I get it working and I get and then eventually I decide to play tie fighter.
Speaker 0: So I run the setup and I set it up separately because the all 32 acted like two different sound cards.
Speaker 0: So I told the game that used the Sound Blaster 16 in that sound card for the sound and used the all 32 which I wasn't sure what that stood for what it did or the music and The music in tie fighter was just MIDI.
Speaker 0: So then I started up the game and instead of hearing the tinny crappy You know Star Wars theme I heard the Star Wars theme and then I realized What MIDI really was and why it sounded different and suddenly this whole world of music clicked before me.
Speaker 1: You see I didn't realize.
Speaker 1: see when I had that sound blaster 16 I had a lot of MIDI's and pretty much in those days people made MIDI's out of sound blaster 16.
Speaker 1: So they sounded the same because everyone had the same card.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if anyone is old enough, you might remember Vikram's MIDI repository, which is pretty much the biggest MIDI site ever Yep.
Speaker 1: And then I took those MIDI's onto my new computer and I played them and they they it sounded like the computer Was trying to make them sound better, but they ended up not sounding the way I remember them.
Speaker 1: So I was kind of unhappy Yeah, and then I realized what was going on.
Speaker 0: much later I remember playing around with sound fonts and trying to make my own instruments.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sound fonts basically let you change what instruments are in your sound card.
Speaker 1: So when if a program tries to play the synthesizer in your sound card with MIDI you can choose, you know.
Speaker 1: Oh don't use that guitar use this guitar or don't use those drums.
Speaker 1: use this set of drums And then you can make it sound different.
Speaker 0: Yep, because this was days before mp3 So I collected a lot of MIDI files and I also had a really nice digital piano.
Speaker 0: So what we and I still have that piano to this day.
Speaker 0: my parents got it for me way way back but what I'd often do when I was in the computer room doing stuff is I'd Plug the MIDI into the piano and I'd play piano MIDI files Which basically meant that I had a player piano that would play anything I could find on the internet perfectly like a real piano Mm-hmm, and it was great.
Speaker 0: That was what I listened to because there were no mp3s back then.
Speaker 0: That was the kind of music you listen to on a computer.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Of course, I also had the problem of all these sound cards.
Speaker 0: We've talked about until the sound blaster live were ISA Which means it plugged into the big black slot that probably doesn't exist on any of your computers.
Speaker 1: No, it probably doesn't now.
Speaker 0: I also had an ISA network card for my cable modem way way back which meant that Whenever I was on the internet and I was downloading anything pretty much every packet that came in Would make the sound skip a little bit So I'd pause my music whenever I was downloading something.
Speaker 1: Wow That's crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah Then one day I because I didn't even realize I had an ISA network card because the the cable guy came and he put the network card in our computer.
Speaker 0: Because they actually gave everyone who signed up for this like trial cable modem a network card because no one had him back then.
Speaker 0: And then one day I knew where all my computers I look in.
Speaker 0: it was an ISA card like what the fuck.
Speaker 0: and I went Out and bought a PCI network card for like 60 bucks.
Speaker 1: Well, they probably bought around ISA cards because very few people had PCI in those days.
Speaker 0: I had two slots and one of them was empty and that bastard didn't put it in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember that It's six ISA.
Speaker 1: That was the time when my 46 couldn't keep up with games anymore.
Speaker 1: was I bought?
Speaker 1: I wanted to play Jedi Knight one And it said requirement, you know PCI video card and I didn't have one of those.
Speaker 1: I had an onboard one megabyte serious logic video card Which couldn't do much more than you know doom and doom 2 and all that but it did those hella well as for sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I said my like graphics blaster extreme from creative.
Speaker 1: Yeah So anyway the sound cards nowadays, uh We have two magic things that make sound cards work really nicely and all the same.
Speaker 1: One of those magic things is called direct X and if you're on Linux also, and if you're on OS X I don't know what the hell they call it, but it's there and It's probably it's one of the few things that Microsoft has done, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: what DirectX does if you don't understand it already and specifically in this case direct sound but all of DirectX is is the same basic thing is Remember how we said in the olden days if you're running a DOS game you to tell it which sound card you had and the Game had to include a different code for playing sound based on which sound card you had.
Speaker 1: and you know This got troublesome because like I said everyone just ended up making all the sound cards the same Which really hindered development of new sound card technologies?
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you can put a lot of awesome stuff in a sound card like just effects or noise cleanup stuff But if the software didn't use any of that you either had to put all of that logic in the hardware and does make it Difficult to change or break the standard.
Speaker 1: Yep So and no one was gonna write You know code for your specific sound card into their game.
Speaker 1: if you know You didn't pay them a lot of money.
Speaker 1: and if no one had your sound card, you know It's not if it's not gonna sell them more copies of the game.
Speaker 1: What do they care?
Speaker 1: So DirectX what it does is it means that only DirectX has to know about all the different sound cards in the world, you know DirectX, you know Microsoft and whoever makes drivers and support for every different sound card in the entire universe.
Speaker 1: and Then when you write a game and you want to put sound in that game You don't care what sound card they have.
Speaker 1: you just write code for direct sound.
Speaker 1: you say play these sounds direct sound and then Direct-sound figures out what kind of sound card you have and plays the sounds at the best of its ability.
Speaker 1: So if you're writing any sort of software now you just program the sound the way you want and you don't have to worry about which sound cart which sound card or What video card or what network card the computer that the game player happens to have.
Speaker 1: and that's what that's all about.
Speaker 0: Yeah now if you weren't that interested in this episode, I'll be perfectly honest that it was a cop-out.
Speaker 0: We came up with a bunch of good ideas for future Mondays But they all required a little bit of research a little bit of effort or a little bit of anything that we weren't willing to Put forth today.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh the last thing I'll talk about it very briefly is AC 97.
Speaker 1: You'll see a lot of people talking about AC 97.
Speaker 1: You'll see it on sound cards and stuff.
Speaker 1: That's just a way of talking to sound card.
Speaker 1: That is a standard that Intel came up with in 1997 and it basically allows You know the CPU to send a lot of PCM's to the sound card, which is all people do these days.
Speaker 0: I'll bet that no one cared about that last bit.
Speaker 0: You just add it in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just wanted it cuz I You don't you know why you put that in.
Speaker 0: you put that in because you looked it up a little while ago.
Speaker 1: Also, well, it's because I keep seeing AC 97 and like every sound card and I always wondered what the hell it was.
Speaker 1: So now anyone else who's wondering what the hell that was now, you know, you know what I'm asking my listeners out here.
Speaker 0: Do any of you not know what that wasn't care?
Speaker 0: I'm curious.
Speaker 1: I bet at least one person didn't know what AC 97 was.
Speaker 1: and now they're going.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's it's something that yeah, but I'm asking you to look deep in your heart and wonder if you really cared.
Speaker 1: Did you really care about anything in this episode?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this episode was a total cop-out.
Speaker 0: Don't worry the rest of the week will be awesome.
Speaker 0: We've actually got really good topics lined up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Come on people We're having a little bit of difficulty coming up with Monday.
Speaker 1: I know we're not.
Speaker 0: we have plenty of money ideas.
Speaker 0: The problem is every time Monday comes around we're exhausted from the week exactly.
Speaker 1: We need Monday ideas that don't require research effort or preparation.
Speaker 0: Oh great.
Speaker 1: So if you know have any Monday show ideas technology science sci-fi aside from the hundreds that have already been put in the forum They're actually I look through and there weren't that many Monday ones in there.
Speaker 1: There are mostly Thursday ones and a lot of them we did already.
Speaker 0: it was you know, and anyway, we didn't do security We didn't do networking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't do voting machines.
Speaker 1: Let's we got to work up to that, you know.
Speaker 0: No, we don't you just have to not be tired.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's never gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I might happen next weekend because all we got is that metal concert and that Jewish holiday.
Speaker 1: Well, no, you have the Jewish holiday and the rest of us day is like spirited beacon day.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we'll take Pete and Jess out to that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's some hijinks.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway look forward to the rest of hockey fight week and look forward to us not being quite so tired tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Alright tomorrow be tucked like a pirate day.
Speaker 0: Yeah And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.