Speaker 1: It's Monday January 23rd, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We have special guest and scientist Peter Olson here to talk with us about the dangers of pseudoscience.
Speaker 1: Let's do this so as many of you might have seen in the forums Uh I had a little trouble with right stuff over the past six days.
Speaker 2: Those are those people with the giant anime catalog.
Speaker 1: right yeah And I hadn't ordered from them in a long time like once.
Speaker 1: I called in an order like way way back and just Recently they had a crazy crazy deal that a good friend of mine told me about and you know Cosmo warrior Which is in that whole my tell universe, and it was super cheap like four bucks DVDs, so I thought what the hell?
Speaker 1: I'll make an account on right stuff and order it.
Speaker 1: I mean they're they're pretty much the biggest name in that.
Speaker 1: what could go wrong?
Speaker 1: well you see apparently some people have trouble and some people don't and It turns out that they do manual credit card verification and manual credit card charging Meaning instead of having the big machine that most companies have you just swipe, and it just takes care of the credit card.
Speaker 1: They have a dude who looks at your number and then he calls your credit card company Verifies your address over the phone with them and then asks to make a charge against it.
Speaker 1: and they failed to do this with my credit card.
Speaker 1: and After that they called me like five times and she kept asking me for various information.
Speaker 1: at one point They asked me for the customer service number of my own credit card.
Speaker 2: So I had people ask for that before like on various sites and things But not often.
Speaker 2: usually they ask for that little number on the back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the the PSC or whatever it's called whatever the hell They call it.
Speaker 2: And then they have a you know a credit card processing computer that just you type in your number And it automatically does everything and there isn't a person on the other end.
Speaker 2: That's the whole point of having an you know.
Speaker 2: What do they call it?
Speaker 2: E-commerce you know an internet store is that you don't need a Checkout clerk to handle your order?
Speaker 1: Well, basically it's worse than that because their online store is not an online store like other online stores.
Speaker 1: When you make an order in their online store, you might as well have called in an order or faxed them an order.
Speaker 1: It's no different.
Speaker 1: Wow, it's just.
Speaker 1: it's all manual and so it really just depends on your credit card company because whatever it was they couldn't seem to And they kept calling me.
Speaker 1: I got sick of it.
Speaker 1: fine.
Speaker 1: I just told him to cancel the order.
Speaker 1: That's easy, and they were kind of indignant, but I mean I'm a big I'm a proponent of anime companies doing good things But right stuff didn't do me a good thing really pisses me off when companies.
Speaker 2: Just don't Upgrade and use new technologies or don't use technology properly.
Speaker 2: It's like alright You have a company.
Speaker 2: sure you might be profitable But you could make your company like a thousand times more awesome if you just did these three simple things.
Speaker 2: But no everyone at your company is a Luddite or is old-fashioned Or doesn't know anything and you don't even know enough to hire someone like me to tell you what you don't know.
Speaker 1: see it's not Even just small companies like this.
Speaker 1: I mean I work for IBM pretty much one of the biggest like big iron old-school tech companies And even inside IBM.
Speaker 1: They just have no clue about Technology in the outside world and the fact that the way they do a lot of things is old crusty expensive and obsolete.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's even scarier is a lot of times.
Speaker 1: They don't believe me.
Speaker 1: I'll tell them uh You could.
Speaker 1: that could be done within a week And they'll laugh at me and they expect it to take like five months and cost a hundred thousand dollars When Scott over here could probably code what I want in a week for nothing not for nothing.
Speaker 2: well for time Yeah, I cost a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm not cheap.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 1: I have it.
Speaker 1: I mean I always tell people I have a consulting rate and It seems to vary and I've discovered that whenever I think of my consulting rate It basically just shows me how much my time is worth.
Speaker 1: at this moment.
Speaker 1: it ranges from twenty to a hundred and eighty dollars an hour Depending on how I feel Depends on what you want me to do.
Speaker 2: I mean Oh Scott We need you to educate us about.
Speaker 2: you know LDAP.
Speaker 2: my consulting fee is a thousand dollars an hour Scott.
Speaker 2: we need you to write.
Speaker 2: make this video game for us.
Speaker 2: my consulting fee is one dollar an hour Scott.
Speaker 2: we need you to go lay and have fun with those hot girls.
Speaker 2: my consulting fee is negative ten dollars an hour.
Speaker 1: I don't think you're gonna get that for ten dollars an hour.
Speaker 1: You're kind of gangly.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's still.
Speaker 2: you know you get the idea.
Speaker 1: So we only have one news today, but being science and tech day It's a science and tech news, and it's one that we probably have a lot to say about Now.
Speaker 1: for the longest time pretty much since Windows 2000 and it got even bigger in XP That Windows has had signed drivers Meaning that you know you have hardware like I don't know a PCI card a video card, and there's a driver that you need to make that card work and You need and the driver.
Speaker 1: normally you just get it from the manufacturer and install it.
Speaker 1: now Windows started saying that if you pay them a pile of money, it's like 500 bucks a year per license or something silly like that and They test your driver and decide that it's kosher in whatever weird criteria.
Speaker 1: They have.
Speaker 1: Then your driver will be signed and it'll install without a problem.
Speaker 1: But if your driver isn't signed and you try to install it Windows would give you a little error message and say hey hey this driver might break your computer and kill your firstborn son and make You impotent.
Speaker 1: now any of you use Windows 2000 or XP.
Speaker 1: you've probably seen that a bunch of times And if you're smart you just ignored it.
Speaker 1: well Windows Vista in all of Microsoft's infinite wisdom is making this mandatory Meaning if your driver isn't signed you cannot install it no matter what root administrator privileges you have.
Speaker 2: Well, that's gonna be pretty much mean Microsoft can say that hardware is allowed to work on Windows and that hardware can never work on Windows.
Speaker 2: yeah, I mean little companies aren't gonna want to pay for this and people who make hardware that needs to interact or connect to Windows computers or work inside of Windows computers Aren't gonna be able to make that hardware work without paying Microsoft lots of money.
Speaker 1: and Even aside from the money it takes control away from me.
Speaker 1: if I have Windows And I want to do something to my own copy of Windows I should be able to do whatever I want if I don't install a broken driver.
Speaker 1: That's my prerogative.
Speaker 2: Yeah, what if I make a piece of hardware cuz I'm all cool like that And I want to plug it into my computer and make it do something I can't with Windows cuz I can't write a driver unless I pay Microsoft a pile of money.
Speaker 1: Now apparently this only applies to 64-bit Applications or the 64-bit version of Windows, but a lot of people have speculated that there is going to be in fact No, 32-bit version.
Speaker 2: there probably won't be a 32-bit version.
Speaker 2: so cuz I don't think Vista is.
Speaker 2: I think Vista is too bloated And it was written for 64-bit, and I don't think Microsoft took the time to write it for 32 and 64-bit.
Speaker 2: so That but I'm pretty sure it's gonna be 64-bit only yeah And that's fine because most newer computers are 64-bit.
Speaker 2: You're gonna need a newer computer to run Vista anyway.
Speaker 1: now theoretically It also says that this only actually applies to kernel mode drivers.
Speaker 1: so anything that requires access to hardware or certain kernel hooks or Basically anything that's low-level which includes almost all drivers.
Speaker 2: That's pretty much everything important.
Speaker 2: I mean, I'm pretty sure that actually even includes USB devices and stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean we don't know all the details yet since Vista isn't even out and
Speaker 2: there's a lot of Windows technology is a secret anyway That we don't understand and no one understands, but
Speaker 1: for any of you who really don't see why this is a big deal consider this Nvidia I mean ATI is all well and good But Nvidia pretty much makes the best video cards and the best drivers in general.
Speaker 1: now for the longest time You could download the Nvidia reference driver the official Nvidia driver for any Nvidia card.
Speaker 1: You still do and you know what.
Speaker 1: back then it wasn't signed on Windows.
Speaker 1: Nope If that happened now, it just wouldn't run and you couldn't use your fancy new video card.
Speaker 2: also a lot of times now You'll see people releasing like they'll take the Nvidia driver And they'll like modify it to do something special Like when people modify the ATI driver to cheat in video games and stuff like that.
Speaker 2: you won't be able to do that.
Speaker 2: You'll have to pretty much ATI and Nvidia will probably pay Microsoft to make their drivers signed.
Speaker 2: But so you'll be able to use the official Nvidia and ATI drivers, but you won't be able to use anything else.
Speaker 2: every other.
Speaker 2: You know hackers special gamers modified modified drivers all of those will disappear.
Speaker 2: They won't exist for Vista.
Speaker 1: Now here are the three clauses that because basically what I'm about to read is going to reveal to you exactly why Microsoft is doing this.
Speaker 1: There are three.
Speaker 1: these are the three clauses that are from the Microsoft article.
Speaker 1: citing all this One drivers must be signed for devices that quote stream protected content this includes audio drivers and that they have this acronym a protected user mode audio or Puma and protected audio path or PEP and Video drivers that can handle the same.
Speaker 1: so basically anything involving DRM.
Speaker 1: You can't touch in your computer anymore.
Speaker 2: well It actually what it is is a way to enforce DRM in that you won't be able to use a device.
Speaker 2: you won't be able to take a device that say has an open analog hole or Something like that and plug it into your computer.
Speaker 2: So your hop edges and things like that just probably won't work because Microsoft won't approve those drivers Yeah which aren't nice to DRM any that.
Speaker 1: and you couldn't just write a piece of software that looks at the data screen stream and Takes the video out of it in an unencrypted form because the Windows kernel just won't let you do that without a sign driver.
Speaker 1: The second one unsigned kernel mode software will not load and will not run.
Speaker 1: So any software that uses kernel mode in any way can't run period unless that could be construed as a security thing.
Speaker 2: And it's good in some ways but in other ways.
Speaker 2: You know sometimes I want to write stuff down there.
Speaker 1: It'd be fine if I could sign thing like maybe say if Windows did this by default It won't run anything unsigned But say every copy of Windows had its own signing mechanism so that you could manually sign anything you wanted to run.
Speaker 1: That'd be fine.
Speaker 1: That actually be a really good security fix for Windows in general?
Speaker 2: Well, it would be as a dialog box or it'd be like do you want to sign it?
Speaker 2: Yes, it would be no different than what we have now.
Speaker 1: Well, unless you'd made it hidden and undocumented.
Speaker 1: It's only like freaking geeks could do it.
Speaker 2: I guess but making it's just obscurity It's not real security.
Speaker 2: You know I'm saying because then the hackers would just sign things and send them out or send something to you.
Speaker 2: Maybe if you time you get your computer to sign it and then it's.
Speaker 2: you know what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean if you at least hide the key to an individual computer there are ways to do it.
Speaker 1: It'd be good for corporate environments and all that BS.
Speaker 2: It'd be alright.
Speaker 1: and Three even users with administrator privileges cannot load unsigned kernel mode code.
Speaker 1: This applies for any software module that loads including device drivers filter drivers and kernel services.
Speaker 2: so basically it means If you're running Windows Vista, then you have a Windows computer, and you cannot do Windows.
Speaker 2: Microsoft can control your computer to make it so that you cannot force your computer to do everything that it can do.
Speaker 2: it's like if I had a car and in the car were a bunch of features like power windows and a sunroof and heated seats and anti-lock brakes right but and anti-lock brakes?
Speaker 2: whoa those violate copyright they don't.
Speaker 2: but let's just pretend that anti-lock brakes equals copying movies, right that's quite a metaphor.
Speaker 1: you got going for
Speaker 2: the sake of my analogy and Microsoft could from far away even though my car has any lock brakes in it say you know what we're gonna disable all analog brakes For you, and you're never gonna be able to use them even though you've got them.
Speaker 2: And it's your car and you own every part of that car.
Speaker 2: We are the owners of the operating system on that car and we decide we don't want anyone using analog brakes So you can't use them all right Scott?
Speaker 1: You know what that'd be like?
Speaker 1: that'd be like if I had a computer running Windows Vista and Microsoft had a way to Control my computer from afar and prevent me from doing things.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that's exactly what it's kind of like the way we have it on cell phones now where cell phones can do all sorts of great stuff, but The cell phone providers like Verizon and Sprint and whoever singular They don't let your cell phone do everything that it can do because then they won't be able to rip you off.
Speaker 2: I have hiccups.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's pissed me off for the longest time that my cell phone has GPS in it.
Speaker 1: It's not the most accurate GPS because it gets it from the cell towers But it's still GPS.
Speaker 1: my cell phone also has a data cable that can come off of it.
Speaker 1: there is no way in the world to get that GPS data to come down that data cable into my hands.
Speaker 2: it's In the cell phone and the network.
Speaker 2: this well that the hardware in the cell phone and the network the cell phone is attached To.
Speaker 2: but because the software running on the cell phone is completely controlled by the cell phone provider And so is the network they won't allow you to do that even though you own the cell.
Speaker 1: Why does all this happen?
Speaker 1: money.
Speaker 1: people are assholes and they want your money?
Speaker 2: I'm gonna recommend to everyone in the universe that no matter what crazy games come out be it half-life 12 or counter-strike awesome or God knows what you know amazing MMO number 10. when Windows XP has died out and is no longer useful and Vista is the only way to go if this sort of regime is still in place I think Linux is the only option.
Speaker 2: besides well, I guess Mac But yeah might have some of the same DRM is going on - who knows I mean seriously work.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying oh you have to dump windows now because if you want to play games you got to run Windows 2000 Windows XP.
Speaker 1: But look to the future and be aware that you might not be able to use Windows Vista the way you expect.
Speaker 2: Yeah, imagine if you know you have this giant collection of mp3s in your XP computer, and then one day XP is useless.
Speaker 2: There's a giant security hole in it.
Speaker 2: Microsoft says we're never gonna fix it.
Speaker 2: XP is dead.
Speaker 2: you have to use Vista and you haven't learned Linux yet and you're all your mp3s are stuck in this XP machine, which is being destroyed by viruses.
Speaker 2: and So you get a Vista machine and now your mp3 collection is dead.
Speaker 1: I mean this isn't the only problem with Vista.
Speaker 1: Vista has is not going to be easily pirated if at all.
Speaker 1: Due to.
Speaker 1: I mean you know XP as its online authentication.
Speaker 1: Vista is gonna be about a thousand times that.
Speaker 2: yeah pretty much No one's gonna pirate it, but no one's gonna want to pirate it.
Speaker 1: So well the other thing is that it's so bloated.
Speaker 1: you realize that they're claiming Vista won't run on pretty much any PC on the market today.
Speaker 2: Wow isn't this supposed to come out this year?
Speaker 1: I don't actually know when it's coming out.
Speaker 2: I think it's coming out this year So it might run on like high-end computers.
Speaker 1: You know yeah, cuz that statistic I just mentioned was from a month or two ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who knows actually a few months ago Actually, it was about four months ago now that I think about it.
Speaker 1: time's moving too quick So my thing of the day isn't a new thing But it's something that while I had been vaguely aware of I was not aware quite of the extent to which it goes until just recently and It's cute and scary at the same time.
Speaker 1: now I don't know how many of you are familiar with this concept, but uh OS tons or Our or s chan's is there sometimes called or basically cute chibi female?
Speaker 1: personifications of major operating systems.
Speaker 2: Wait wait wait wait wait wait wait.
Speaker 2: so Someone takes a computer operating system like I don't know Commodore 64 OS whatever it was called and They turn it into a cute little anime character.
Speaker 1: Alright, I mean it goes to the point that all the different OS characters are well-defined and people in this community get yelled at if They deviate.
Speaker 1: apparently they even correlate things like breast size and appetite to such things as Gooey flashiness and memory requirements.
Speaker 1: Wow apparently Windows XP is fairly well-endowed.
Speaker 1: Windows 2000 eats a lot Yeah, and they all have OS X that have the biggest tutors right.
Speaker 1: there don't seem to be so many of Macs.
Speaker 1: They're mostly the various Windows operating systems though the two DOS girls are kind of cute actually.
Speaker 2: What about some Linux action and maybe some BSDs?
Speaker 1: There's a Longhorn There's new Linux, and it's just funny like goat looking girl.
Speaker 1: Now there's a lot of Japanese puns that might not make sense to people in English But pretty much this is the most punny thing I've ever come close to understanding in Japanese.
Speaker 1: But it's all.
Speaker 1: it's nothing about puns like.
Speaker 1: here's a nice example.
Speaker 1: The Windows girls are often seen carrying scallions.
Speaker 1: This is a pun a popular Japanese firewall program.
Speaker 1: any GIES Sounds like their word for scallion negi.
Speaker 1: so the OS ton.
Speaker 1: carry scallions around as shields or weapons.
Speaker 1: Negi maki, I could really use some beef negi maki right now.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah, I could just eat those forever.
Speaker 2: All right, so I don't know if I've talked about this before but there's an I don't watch TV.
Speaker 2: We don't watch TV so much, but in Britain.
Speaker 2: There's this awesome awesome awesome car TV.
Speaker 2: Show call about cars Called top gear.
Speaker 1: I was real skeptical until I saw it and it was actually highly amusing.
Speaker 2: it's just this really good show with like these cool British guys, and they just do things about cars and There's the coolest part of the show is that they're not endorsed or Supportive of any particular auto brand or anything like that.
Speaker 2: They're just totally.
Speaker 2: they just love cars in general, and they'll just be straight honest with you about whatever.
Speaker 2: I remember.
Speaker 2: I saw one show.
Speaker 2: the first time I saw this show was when this guy drove a v8 Audi Like like I think it was.
Speaker 2: it was other 400 miles or 800 miles.
Speaker 2: It was an obscenely long distance from like the bottom of England to Scotland and back on one tank of gas.
Speaker 2: It was like the.
Speaker 2: it was like beyond the limit of the rated fuel efficiency of the car.
Speaker 2: It was crazy, and they just.
Speaker 2: the whole show was just a Camera in the car looking at this guy like.
Speaker 2: what is the car running on?
Speaker 2: oh my god?
Speaker 1: Love.
Speaker 1: I love the announcer and just the way they talk to each other and the way they talk in this show is actually really Hilarious yeah, so the one I linked to is the one I just found today which is the second time I've seen this show.
Speaker 2: the guy who he drives a Hunt an Acura NSX which is a car.
Speaker 2: They just stopped making.
Speaker 2: it's a really awesome car actually Around the Laguna Seca racetrack in California, but he does it in Gran Turismo.
Speaker 2: I think three the newest before the newest one.
Speaker 2: and He sees what time he gets and he learned.
Speaker 2: he tries to learn the track where all the turns are when to brake when to Turn all that stuff.
Speaker 2: Then he goes to Laguna Seca with an Acura NSX and he drives it around trying to get the same time And pretty much right away.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: Oh, holy crap.
Speaker 2: He just starts cursing and he's just pissed off that it's not the same as the game.
Speaker 2: And you know he drives in the dirt, and he fishtails a bit.
Speaker 2: It's hilarious.
Speaker 2: So if you care about the cars or anything like that at all this is like the ultimate Car show ever and you should definitely check it out.
Speaker 1: So we've noticed that a lot of people seem to have trouble with what we're about to talk about.
Speaker 1: So we decided we'd do a show with a guest to kind of define it and maybe shed some light on this issue for Maybe some people in our forums who might think otherwise.
Speaker 1: But tonight we're talking about pseudoscience.
Speaker 1: We have with us Peter Olson who is actually a scientist and a friend of ours and We're just gonna go in about pseudoscience and rant about it until we run out of time here.
Speaker 0: all right, so for those of you that don't know me out there the Veritable legion of listeners who are unfamiliar with me I'm a microbiologist for the state of New York, and I won't go into the boring details of my job But I keep your food safe and make sure you don't die.
Speaker 1: yeah He tells us when it like every now And then he'll be like hey, you know such-and-such restaurant, or you know such-and-such food.
Speaker 1: Don't eat it.
Speaker 1: You'll die.
Speaker 0: yeah a warning I can give this in general if you eat bean sprouts wash the shit out of them.
Speaker 0: Just like wash them or cook them.
Speaker 0: You'll be a lot better off that way.
Speaker 0: So Pseudoscience, so what is it?
Speaker 0: This is a. this is an important question, and it like a lot of terminology that relates to science it gets thrown around and abused and misused a lot and I think we've got a Wikipedia article that says what it is and defines it.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of different definitions of pseudoscience and basically the way we want to use this word is simply Something that isn't science, but pretends to be
Speaker 0: yeah
Speaker 1: as in the willful deceit of people and using scientific sounding terminology
Speaker 2: The real problem with this word is that the the roots of the word if you pick it apart.
Speaker 2: It's pseudo which means Sort of or kind of and science which is well science right.
Speaker 2: so when you hear the word you're like pseudoscience.
Speaker 2: Oh, so that's almost science, but not quite no.
Speaker 2: pseudoscience actually means not science at all right.
Speaker 0: That's what it means is kind of the way science works.
Speaker 0: It's such.
Speaker 0: It's such a simplified Yeah, you know bare-bones thought process that there's really.
Speaker 0: it's it's kind of like on/off.
Speaker 0: It's science, or it's not science.
Speaker 0: I mean you can't really kind of be middle-ground quasi science.
Speaker 1: I mean if you want a nice example I here's a list of commonly things that are commonly known to be pseudoscientific in their nature.
Speaker 1: Acupuncture not as in the the placebo effects of it, but the theory behind why it works.
Speaker 1: It's not really a theory.
Speaker 2: There is no key flow that is being unlocked by magic.
Speaker 1: me any effects of alchemy have nothing to do with the basis of alchemy.
Speaker 2: acupuncture alchemy astrology chakra theory chiropractic reflexology reflexology eugenics All of these things are just completely made out home.
Speaker 1: You would at the Some home.
Speaker 1: I mean homeopathy has some.
Speaker 1: actually there is real homeopathy Allergy shots.
Speaker 0: yeah, the thing is homeopathy means well your your body's natural immune system is homeopathy.
Speaker 2: Well, there's two things that they that.
Speaker 2: no that's not true that.
Speaker 2: well Two things homeopathy is a theory of medicine where you have number one very high Dilutions of active ingredients.
Speaker 2: and two you're assuming that like cures like.
Speaker 1: so for example you take a Poison that causes a headache, and it'll make your headache go away.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's what homeopathy really says.
Speaker 2: That's the as the theory of homeopathy is.
Speaker 2: let's say you were poisoned by cyanide that some cyanide will cure you But you just dilute it.
Speaker 2: you you would take the site like one part cyanide and ten thousand parts of water.
Speaker 0: It sounds like a bastardization of the way they do.
Speaker 0: and you know a vaccine or something like that Which is based on your body's immune principles?
Speaker 1: Yep, it works.
Speaker 1: It is while some homeopathic things have been found to work in the past.
Speaker 1: it has nothing to do with the idea of homeopathy Because the the ideas and suppositions behind homeopathy as to why it works are mostly just bullshit.
Speaker 2: Yeah, see sometimes like can cure like which that's not even really scientific terminology whatsoever.
Speaker 2: Because you know look allergy shots I'm allergic to mold so you take a very small amount of the mold so it won't really give me an allergic Reaction and we dilute it heavily and we put it in me and because of the theories of immunology I now don't get the allergy so much not because of homeopathy.
Speaker 0: It works best with with the viral shots things like that.
Speaker 0: you take the actual virus itself you destroy it and you inject yourself with this.
Speaker 0: basically, it's kind of like cooked a virus for lack of better terminology without explaining it and the way your body's immune system works is recognizes these broken down pieces of virus and it develops immunity to them, but it doesn't work for stuff like Cyanide or you know Anything else that you know?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't immunize yourself to gamma radiation.
Speaker 2: Yeah, if you have the flu taking some drinking some water and a sugar pill that is like one part You know duck liver and ten thousand parts water and other stuff that doesn't do anything is not going to cure the flu.
Speaker 2: There's just no chance.
Speaker 1: Statistically and if you look at chemistry and physics homeopathy as it is practiced today can't work because Statistically not even a single atom or molecule of the thing They say they're diluted will actually appear in a diluted homeopathic solution.
Speaker 2: So let's so.
Speaker 2: if it's cat liver, which I know one of the very popular ones is after they dilute it They dilute it so much.
Speaker 2: There is zero cat liver in the medicine that you actually.
Speaker 2: Then you're also assuming the cat liver cures the flu, which it does not.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it doesn't do anything.
Speaker 2: It's just made up Just like cruelty.
Speaker 2: you could eat a raw cat liver and you would still have the flu.
Speaker 2: and not only that you'd probably be vomiting more Nasty raw cat liver.
Speaker 0: No, not so good.
Speaker 0: So basically delicious.
Speaker 1: We got on a rant about some specific pseudosciences out there But basically the the whole gist of this is just gonna be simply that a lot of things out there pretend to be science.
Speaker 1: or they say oh, we're backed by scientific research.
Speaker 1: or oh the so-and-so professors say this is good and People like us are really good at just spotting like oh, that's pseudoscience.
Speaker 1: I know that guy.
Speaker 1: he promotes all sorts of bullshit and this is probably more of it.
Speaker 1: and oh look He has no data behind it.
Speaker 1: or yeah that guy he always makes claims like this, but he never actually publishes an article Mm-hmm.
Speaker 2: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 2: Let's talk about how other people who don't know how to detect pseudoscience so easily can detect it.
Speaker 1: Yep Well Wikipedia has a list of the so-called characteristics of most pseudoscience.
Speaker 1: Pseudoscience asserts claims or theories Unconnected to previous experimental results.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 2: So if you know that it's commonly believed by scientists that say gravity exists or you know a Sediment if in works in such a way and Someone comes along with some other science that says everything that science already knows is wrong, right?
Speaker 2: They're probably making shit up.
Speaker 0: Yep, if there's no data to back up what you're saying The fundamental principle of science you make a claim you get evidence.
Speaker 0: you know you bring evidence to bear to support your claim and if you don't have the evidence at fuck you By asserting claims which cannot be verified or falsified.
Speaker 1: This is a big problem with intelligent design.
Speaker 2: There's a lot of things.
Speaker 2: This is one that people have a real hard time understanding.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It doesn't necessarily mean that any claim that genuine legitimate science makes is false or is erroneous in some fashion.
Speaker 0: What it means is that the claims and assertions you make the conclusions you draw There has to be a way to prove it to to generate a test that could falsify it.
Speaker 0: There has to be some kind of testability to it.
Speaker 0: If you're making a blanket statement with no holes in it No gaps nothing like that if there's literally just no way to that you could prove it wrong.
Speaker 0: if you make an assertion that there's a God up there that you can't interact with and you can't you know Take a gram of it and try to prove what it really is.
Speaker 0: That's not science.
Speaker 0: You can't do that.
Speaker 2: So if I come along and I say what did I say in the forums that I'm the evil Hitler God?
Speaker 2: There's something like that.
Speaker 2: There's no way you can prove.
Speaker 2: I'm not the evil Hitler God.
Speaker 2: There is no way to do that.
Speaker 2: Therefore that claim and or any validation of it is not scientific in any way whatsoever Don't any?
Speaker 1: there's another right after that asserting claims which contradict experimentally established results.
Speaker 1: That's one step further.
Speaker 1: That's not even something that can't be falsified.
Speaker 1: That's something that has been falsified and you're just making something up.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, you'd see a lot of people do this, especially audio files.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I've ran it about them much But these are people.
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about people who like music or like audio.
Speaker 1: well You know what the word should mean.
Speaker 1: These are people who will spend thirty to forty thousand dollars on a special magic power cable that they claim makes their CDs sound better Cleans the electricity.
Speaker 1: Yeah Because the electricity is dirty because it's you know, just freaking a less visit they get messed up that Yeah, even the best are the monster cables that are digital and they cost like a hundred dollars more than up by the.
Speaker 1: you know The cheapo digital cable and a lot of you don't seem to realize that digital is digital.
Speaker 1: if the data gets there It's perfect.
Speaker 1: No matter what if it doesn't get there.
Speaker 1: It doesn't get there.
Speaker 2: So digital works.
Speaker 2: It's a zero and a one.
Speaker 2: The only way to be messed up is if some of the zeros and ones go missing.
Speaker 2: and if some of them go missing It just doesn't work at all.
Speaker 1: so the audio files will claim that oh this cable makes my power better.
Speaker 1: but then Scientists study the cable and see that it's identical to every other cable.
Speaker 1: and then the claim contradicts the established results.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm by failing to provide an experimental possibility of reproducible results.
Speaker 0: Reproducibility is the biggest key to scientific experiments.
Speaker 0: if you do it once and you can never reproduce it Your claim is mostly invalid aka the person who brought up the famous Semifamous leaf experiment in the forums.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: This was an experiment done and I think it was 1940 by I talked about at the forums I don't remember all the details anymore but it was this crazy Russian electrician dude and He claimed to have found the aura of a leaf and that if he cut off a piece of the leaf and then did this technique again, the aura was still there showing that the leaf had memory of itself and No one in the last, you know since 1940 has ever ever ever reproduced this.
Speaker 1: so Science says alright his claim was bullshit or there was some sort of error in his original experiment some kind of fluke instrumental error.
Speaker 0: You know that sort of thing tech error.
Speaker 1: Yes in this specific case I believe it was discovered that in fact He had simply not wiped off his photographic plate before cutting off a piece of the leaf.
Speaker 1: So the moisture from the leaf was still there when he ran the test a second time.
Speaker 1: and oh the aura is still whole Science.
Speaker 0: whoo, of course, there's also the possibility, you know, he may have done that accidentally Or he may have done that intentionally to reproduce these results with the specific knowledge that this is what he would find Yep, that that sort of falsification of data.
Speaker 0: That is that is about the biggest Taboo in all of science.
Speaker 0: It's like the worst crime you can commit as a scientist is to make stuff up And as you know in college trying to pass classes We won't talk about that Moving on.
Speaker 1: well, that was a big issue.
Speaker 1: I know you're all familiar with the Korean scientist who claimed to have cloned someone and Then no one could reproduce his results and then it turned out that he just made the whole thing up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I don't I don't know if it went that far yet but there were enough claims that he falsified data and such that he had his own paper retracted, which is Usually a bad thing to do.
Speaker 0: You don't want to do that.
Speaker 0: You don't want to.
Speaker 0: you don't want to say like oh, yeah I don't have confidence in my research.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna retract my paper.
Speaker 2: So what it comes down to is if someone says they can do something or that something does something They make a claim and then they can't do it again, or you know, they can't do it all the time They can only do it.
Speaker 2: Sometimes they're just lying.
Speaker 2: if something works if something is scientifically, you know It's not pseudoscience and is real science.
Speaker 2: You can do it all the time over and over again in any lab at any place Any time.
Speaker 0: yep, you should be able to argue that if you can't reproduce it under the same conditions Just made up something's wrong or a lot of pseudo scientists will get around this by conducting an experiment.
Speaker 1: You couldn't see me but I made a little quote marks around the word experiment here.
Speaker 1: that cannot be reproduced like oh I did this.
Speaker 1: I'm during the planetary alignment of blah and blah that won't happen for another thousand years.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, that is it's.
Speaker 0: it's certainly interesting but it is not scientific.
Speaker 2: No, nor is it true.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now here's the big one not so much for pseudoscience itself But for you being able to spot it if you're not good at doing so By failing to submit results to peer review prior to publicizing them.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes If a scientist comes up with something real or new or important They're going to submit it to scientific journals and then the media are going to pick up on it.
Speaker 1: If anyone claims to have invented something or discovered something and they go to the press before they go to other scientists Something's wrong.
Speaker 0: Your review is a very important process in science.
Speaker 0: It's when your research gets passed around to basically a committee made up of respected scientists and they take a look at your paper they take a look at your research and They basically make sure that that the research you've done and the conclusions you've reached and all this stuff that it's.
Speaker 0: it's kosher Basically that it falls in the realm of science.
Speaker 0: and I got to say scientists are assholes.
Speaker 0: We're just we're bastards.
Speaker 0: We will rip your paper apart if you've done something that's even like Slightly maybe not the best science.
Speaker 0: you will hear about it and you will hear about it a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's a reason for that and that's because there's a lot of this pseudoscience out there.
Speaker 0: a lot of people will will use shoddy methods or maybe flub some numbers fudge a little data and You know, maybe that you use that you get an unfair advantage you get a grant that someone else should have gotten.
Speaker 0: or maybe you're in the Pharmaceutical industry and you fudge some data and you accidentally kill, I don't know a hundred thousand people.
Speaker 0: Something like that, you know, it's a very very critical thing.
Speaker 0: And if someone doesn't want to submit to peer review, they'll have a million reasons for it.
Speaker 0: They'll say like the committee does committees against them or scientists are closed-minded.
Speaker 0: I hear that one a lot But really it's been around it's been this way for a while and you know, it's.
Speaker 0: there's a reason it's established like this.
Speaker 2: So there's only one scientist who says yeah, this is the real deal Check to make sure the person's even a scientist.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, because that's mad scientist syndrome there in the movies You always see like the crazy Maverick scientist who comes up with something in his basement and the you know Established scientific community ignores him and it turns out he was right and then he stops the aliens.
Speaker 2: It never is that way in the real world.
Speaker 1: The one mad scientist come in with something in his basement is basically the crazy dude walking out on the street going.
Speaker 1: everyone's crazy But me.
Speaker 1: yep, everyone's crazy, but me.
Speaker 0: The big thing is if you see a paper released by someone and there's like one author on the paper You might want to question that a little bit.
Speaker 0: most Scientific research of any significant nature is done in a team and it's done in a team that goes well beyond whose name gets on The paper.
Speaker 0: that doesn't even account for the people that did the bulk of the work or anything like that.
Speaker 1: So yeah research assistants getting paid crap.
Speaker 0: Shut up.
Speaker 0: We do all the work.
Speaker 0: the director takes all the credit.
Speaker 0: Watson and Crick steal their woman's research, you know?
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of science is full of assholishness like that, but that's how it happens.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I guess you know I've always I've always been confused by the pseudoscience thing.
Speaker 0: Like how does it?
Speaker 0: how is it so pervasive still?
Speaker 2: Well, the number one thing about pseudoscience that I've seen and notice is it all.
Speaker 2: it's always something too good to be true.
Speaker 2: It's something people want to believe and it's false.
Speaker 2: So People will want to believe it so bad.
Speaker 2: They'll believe it despite any amount of contradictory evidence and this is actually a really good way to detect pseudoscience.
Speaker 2: if something seems really great like, you know Hey, we have this pill that cures cancer perfectly every time or perpetual emotion machine.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you never had to use gasoline again.
Speaker 2: The world is saved anything like that.
Speaker 2: The truth is the universe is much terrible and much more of a bastard than any.
Speaker 2: so If someone ever socks, so someone ever says anything and it just seems too good to be true It's ninety nine point nine nine nine nine percent of the time.
Speaker 2: It's just completely made up.
Speaker 2: because if it was real Imagine like think about if a psychic could actually for real It wasn't just pretend.
Speaker 1: if psychics could actually talk to the dead like you realize they'd be in every courtroom ever and there'd never be An unsolved murder ever again.
Speaker 2: Yeah, they would just talk to every freaking corpse and they would go up.
Speaker 2: We know exactly what happened.
Speaker 1: no one would have wills anymore.
Speaker 1: You just have a psychic ask you after you were dead where you wanted all your crap to go.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it would be world changing.
Speaker 2: the entire world would just flip over in a second.
Speaker 2: We would freaking go talk to George Washington and find out stuff and we'd go talk to JFK and ask who shot him.
Speaker 1: And yeah if John Roberts and a Sylvia Brown and all those assholes who talks claim to talk to the dead could actually talk to the dead we Yeah, there just wouldn't be questions anymore.
Speaker 0: We just we just know shit from the past.
Speaker 0: We don't definitely Yeah, we wouldn't have to worry about the things.
Speaker 0: Hey Alexander.
Speaker 2: What happened to your library?
Speaker 1: Oh, I got burned out.
Speaker 2: Hey Caligula, why were you so nuts?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should do another whole other show on Abraham Lincoln and how.
Speaker 1: not only was he a pretty terrible president But he was kind of an asshole.
Speaker 2: Yeah a little bit a little bit did some good did some bad and Really people don't pay attention to the bad so much and some of the good you think he did.
Speaker 1: He didn't really do Yeah, I mean he suspended habeas corpus.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course who recently suspended habeas corpus?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, we won't rant about politics.
Speaker 1: well, even though politics are really play into the pseudoscience thing because not to rag on our fearless leader President Bush, but He's very much for the teaching of intelligent design American schools.
Speaker 1: He said as much.
Speaker 2: well too late.
Speaker 0: That pisses me off more than any other pseudoscience.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe not any other pseudoscience, but probably in the top three pseudosciences that piss me off the most.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the ones that really bother me are the ones that are actually dangerous and harmful directly.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are crazy crazy people out there and I'm not kidding.
Speaker 1: They really believe in perpetual motion machines.
Speaker 1: They called they're called free energy.
Speaker 1: And if you google for free energy, you'll find a million of these people who claim they're just you know Another year of research away from perpetual motion.
Speaker 1: and they really believe it Yeah, and they're just kind of nutty but they're not hurting anyone except the other idiot to give them money.
Speaker 0: The real problem is the people that that use pseudoscience and they're in any kind of position that can influence a large number of people.
Speaker 0: intelligent design is Notorious for that.
Speaker 2: That's even intelligent design really can't hurt so many people it might.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it can.
Speaker 0: it definitely can.
Speaker 2: it can't hurt people as bad as say chiropractic, which is just oh We're just gonna kill.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it's Intelligent design is just creationism in disguise.
Speaker 0: and if you get a bunch of people Institutionalized believing in this one specific creation myth then it's not far to go to Institutionalized religion and then you get a whole Load of crap from there.
Speaker 0: physical harm is dangerous upon people not like.
Speaker 0: physical harm is not the worst thing you can do.
Speaker 2: Well, yeah, but it's not like.
Speaker 2: it's not nearly as bad as the people who said yes cyanide cures cancer.
Speaker 0: No, no, okay.
Speaker 0: Okay, I grant you that.
Speaker 1: I don't see.
Speaker 1: you all know people.
Speaker 1: There are people who really did say cyanide causes can't or cures cancer and they're still saying it.
Speaker 0: I will contend that in fact cyanide does cure cancer.
Speaker 0: It also cures that nasty problem of living that everyone seems to have.
Speaker 2: And actually the the specific thing is they had this Pill or vitamin was called lorat adene.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Loretta No, lorat adene is an anti decongestant or an anti allergy pill that I take.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's called Lara trial or large Vitamin b12.
Speaker 1: I know Yeah, b16 Whatever.
Speaker 2: No, you'll see you'll know when you see it.
Speaker 0: It's not a beaver.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: No, it's not a vitamin at all But that's what they call it Happens is is you eat this thing and it's not really harmful to you except once it gets into your liver.
Speaker 2: your liver picks it apart with some enzymes and After the enzymes pick it apart.
Speaker 2: One of the leftover bits is cyanide which will kill you nearly immediately.
Speaker 1: Well, basically what it's all it is.
Speaker 1: is there these people?
Speaker 1: and we have a we are friending our friend Scott Johnson Who is also a scientist?
Speaker 1: He has a bunch of friends who?
Speaker 1: They have some issues with pseudoscience.
Speaker 1: I guess they're a good example of people who fall for this stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean no offense to them, but they went on this whole rant in this email discussion We had about how this Lara trial cures cancer.
Speaker 1: It's a giant conspiracy to keep it away from everyone and their argument had every hallmark of a pseudoscientific claim.
Speaker 1: In fact, I'm going to post it in the forums After the show so you all can peruse it.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 1: This is a step-by-step example of what to watch for in pseudoscience
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: and the funny thing was despite the fact that I presented them with actual evidence to the contrary They ignored it and claimed that either the evidence was made up or the scientists are just part of the conspiracy to keep it Down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hear that conspiracy thing a lot from this pseudoscience stuff And yeah, I think it comes from a misrepresentation of what science and the scientific community is per se.
Speaker 0: there's no Conspiracy.
Speaker 0: the government's not even.
Speaker 0: really I'm a government employee.
Speaker 0: Okay, I work for the state.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you we're not competent enough to initiate some kind of global conspiracy like that.
Speaker 0: It You wouldn't even believe it and most scientists are far too busy doing their own stuff to even consider that sort of thing Really?
Speaker 0: I mean that's probably how a lot of these problems got past us in the first place.
Speaker 0: Like I didn't even realize how widespread pseudoscience is.
Speaker 0: but the reason is we've debunked it so many times.
Speaker 0: We're like people just have to know by now, right?
Speaker 0: We've already debunked it.
Speaker 1: We're already past this but they don't they just forget keep coming back to it Like the guy in the forums who brought up the aura thing that the aura.
Speaker 1: they call it a Curiology, I forget exactly what they call it now where they claim to photograph auras and it became a really big fad in the 70s as in the 1970s and all over the world people were really getting into it and it was debunked thoroughly and Completely back then and it stopped being an issue and no one talked about it anymore.
Speaker 1: And now for some reason it's coming up again.
Speaker 1: Yep, and there aren't that many good debunking is online Just because no one who cares even considered the fact that people would ever believe in this stuff again.
Speaker 2: It's mostly because back in the day when you wanted to spread information about something.
Speaker 2: It wasn't so easy.
Speaker 2: Now the internet makes it real easy.
Speaker 2: Of course It makes it real easy to spread lies too and people are gullible as all fuck and they'll believe just about anything Means.
Speaker 0: today you have to be even more More critical of what you read, especially on the internet.
Speaker 0: any research you see be very critical.
Speaker 0: Check the sources.
Speaker 1: I see that a lot of scientific institutions either turn a blind eye or just ignore Pseudoscience saying that it's not even worth our ability our effort to debate and debunk because it's obvious to us
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: and I'm starting to think more and more that while it may be a waste of resources I think scientists need to vigorously defeat the pseudoscience at every turn.
Speaker 0: Well, there are a couple of issues with that.
Speaker 0: At some point in debunking some amount of pseudoscience.
Speaker 0: I've grew up in a very Christian area and I can.
Speaker 0: I can talk about the creationism thing, especially a lot.
Speaker 0: No at some point you run into a wall you.
Speaker 0: there is a point at which all the logic and reason in the world will Not debunk somebody strongly held belief.
Speaker 1: damn it You know that that is.
Speaker 0: that is the problem with this pseudoscience because a lot of it is You know preying on things that people desperately want to believe, you know You really want to know like, you know, you if you're you want to talk to your dead father.
Speaker 0: You're and you're in a really tough spot about it.
Speaker 0: You're gonna be really really really inclined to want to believe the guy that says yeah I can contact your dead relatives and it's dangerous stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah Penn and teller do a show called bullshit and it's on Showtime and it's a really good show.
Speaker 1: It's a lot like Mythbusters.
Speaker 1: So if you're fan of Mythbusters, you'll love bull.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah but they do an episode where they take on all those psychics who claim to talk to the dead and I guess you should you guys should all watch it because it's not even a joke It's not even funny what they do to these people.
Speaker 1: It's not not Penn and teller but psychologists and the the psychics.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah it's.
Speaker 0: it's definitely like it's well, and that's I guess the best thing you can do to defend yourself against pseudoscience is to Educate yourself about what science is exactly and this.
Speaker 0: this can be a little tricky because there's a lot of you know In a dynamic field.
Speaker 0: It's very Changing Can be a little tricky sometimes.
Speaker 0: The best thing to know is I can explain it a little bit science is just.
Speaker 0: it's a very broken down Very very very methodical process of thought.
Speaker 0: It's not even a body of knowledge so much as it is Just a way of doing things.
Speaker 0: It's a way of thinking.
Speaker 0: It's a branch of philosophy.
Speaker 0: That's specific and it has a practical bend to it.
Speaker 0: and Really what you got to look at is is things that are making no good science will ever make just a broad Extraordinary claim or anything that it it that can't be supported by evidence that sort of thing if you're seeing just broad Extraordinary out there claims like alien life forms and things like that Science.
Speaker 0: good good scientists won't dismiss the possibility that it might exist But they won't go ahead and make extraordinary claims that this thin flimsy evidence points to this extraordinary thing.
Speaker 0: most science has done in a very very most conclusions that are drawn are very conservative and It's very very methodical and slow and stepwise.
Speaker 2: That's why you don't see new science every day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it takes years and years for breakthroughs to come out.
Speaker 0: That's what when they're when someone says like this is a new scientific breakthrough.
Speaker 0: It's not a breakthrough.
Speaker 0: There are about like 10 years of research behind that and like people got PhDs about it There have been more papers than you can even imagine.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of stuff going on behind the scenes that you haven't seen.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so someone put together a gizmo in his garage in like five minutes, then it's probably not real.
Speaker 0: Nope I mean, what's that quote by Edison and trying to invent the light bulb?
Speaker 0: No failed a thousand times and he said I've just found a thousand ways that won't work.
Speaker 0: That's that's about.
Speaker 0: that's about how science goes.
Speaker 0: It's about 95 99 percent of what you do just doesn't work and you know it doesn't give you the result you expected and you just keep trying and you keep repeating and it takes a long time costs a lot of money.
Speaker 0: and Eventually at one point, you know You finally have done this research and you can draw these conclusions and then you can publish your your breakthrough amazing paper.
Speaker 0: But it's never done overnight and it's not gonna be some Some wonderful revolutionary thing just like from this one experiment you did.
Speaker 0: just doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: Well, I hope to see some good forum discussions about this topic and I'd like to give a big Thanks to Peter for being here on the show with us.
Speaker 2: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 2: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 2: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 2: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 2: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206 3 3 3 1 5 3 7.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.