Speaker 0: It's Wednesday March 8th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about how to not suck at not being a fanboy.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So today I had an interview with a possibly new job down in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: We'll see how that goes.
Speaker 2: Hooray a job of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I may or may not continue to be working at IBM in the coming few weeks.
Speaker 2: So no more fun stories about stupid people.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'll say this much once I leave IBM and I know I'm never gonna come back.
Speaker 0: I'm not like.
Speaker 0: I can't reveal any of these secrets.
Speaker 0: I know like I can't talk about a lot of the like specific secret confidential whatever But I can definitely do a tell all my experiences at IBM.
Speaker 0: So expect at least one or two podcasts on that.
Speaker 0: if this comes to.
Speaker 2: so that'll be like a Dilbert Thursday.
Speaker 0: He has something like that.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so today You might have noticed I changed some things on The WordPress our blog that runs the podcast and everything.
Speaker 0: now if a million episodes of geek night suddenly appeared in your pod feeder We're sorry, but I think you did something wrong.
Speaker 2: Well, you didn't necessarily do something wrong.
Speaker 2: You just did something poor as In this is all Scott.
Speaker 0: I don't even use pod catchers.
Speaker 2: Yeah If you're using a crummy pod catcher like I don't know some random RSS reader or if you're subscribed to the wrong feed the feed You should be subscribed to is the feed burner.
Speaker 2: one feeds that feed burner comm slash whatever nights geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if anyone out there is subscribed to just a raw WordPress feed stop doing that because it's not good for you.
Speaker 0: that feed can change a lot.
Speaker 0: The feed burner feed is the official one.
Speaker 0: That's the only one that we I guess support.
Speaker 2: Mm-hmm, and if you have your pod catcher set up to download every episode no matter what you probably don't want to do that.
Speaker 2: you probably want to set it to download the most recent episode or Download episodes when you click on them.
Speaker 2: that way you don't automatically download a billion episodes.
Speaker 2: You know you already listened.
Speaker 2: The other thing is we do have separate feeds now if you oh you can only let you if you want You can subscribe to just Monday just Tuesday or just Wednesday of geek nights.
Speaker 0: We've already had about 20 people do this so far even though we haven't really advertised that these are there.
Speaker 0: I imagine these people found them via iTunes.
Speaker 2: Yeah, if you go to iTunes or Yahoo podcast you can find the separate geek nights feeds for Monday Tuesday Wednesday.
Speaker 2: And of course you'll still be able to find the geek nights Total feed which has Monday Tuesday Wednesday and Thursday all in one yep.
Speaker 0: And once we finish with the theme and everything's all set up with the new look for geek nights Those feeds are all going to be prominently available.
Speaker 2: Yep, one more thing is that if you're a person who is only listening or you found us via the Monday only Tuesday only You know links.
Speaker 2: I guess it would be a Wednesday only link because it's Wednesday, right?
Speaker 2: Yeah, yes, if you're subscribed to just geek nights anime guess what we do three other days a week of podcasting.
Speaker 2: So if you like things besides anime you should subscribe to the geek nights normal feed.
Speaker 2: that has everything in it.
Speaker 0: now eventually we're gonna add all that stuff to the Closing bit so we won't have to say this at the beginning of every.
Speaker 2: yeah And also we will have a Thursday only feed.
Speaker 0: I know some people like Thursday But yeah, we had some people tell us lately that Thursdays are the favorite days.
Speaker 2: really because it's not my favorite day.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's not the easiest day for me.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It'll be easier once we finish all the research We've got lined up for the big Thursday episodes.
Speaker 2: yep, but yeah, so everyone knows that's how your subscription should go.
Speaker 2: Everything is feed burner.
Speaker 2: don't subscribe to anything.
Speaker 2: That's not feed burner.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so someone interviewed Michael Dell today.
Speaker 2: I don't know if you know, but Michael Dell is the guy who's in charge of Dell computers, and they said hey How come you're not being all Linux II?
Speaker 0: and he gave some pretty good answers as to why not yeah?
Speaker 2: So basically what he said was he tried ready.
Speaker 2: They tried back in the day to just use Red Hat and the problem was is no one bought it?
Speaker 2: because they said We don't want to use Red Hat Red Hat sucks.
Speaker 2: Why don't you have this other distribution or this other distribution?
Speaker 2: so he says you know what.
Speaker 2: fine if we put only one?
Speaker 2: Distribution.
Speaker 2: everyone would complain that they didn't pick the distribution that they wanted.
Speaker 2: if they picked a few distributions like let's say three or four People would complain because why not have this one?
Speaker 2: and this one also?
Speaker 0: yeah, but I use kibonto bla bla bla.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, I use Mandrake.
Speaker 2: Yeah, Mandriva now whatever yeah, so the point is that he makes is that it's not possible or Practical for Dell to support all those different distributions.
Speaker 2: They could reasonably support a few, but the problem is is no distribution has such a vast majority of Following that they can pick that one.
Speaker 2: You know it's like Ubuntu might be the most popular.
Speaker 2: the most popular means 10% which means if they pick Ubuntu 90% of people who want Linux on a Dell would still complain.
Speaker 0: now my take on this is that they don't need to market this To people who already know about Linux.
Speaker 0: if you already have a favorite distro You're not likely one of Dell's Linux box customers.
Speaker 0: see.
Speaker 2: that's what you would think, but it seems like Freaking.
Speaker 2: people actually want to buy Dell's with their Linux of choice pre-installed.
Speaker 2: I don't know what they see.
Speaker 0: I think those people are minority.
Speaker 0: I think what Dell could do is offer maybe just Ubuntu or maybe a handful of OS's depending and Offer these not not offer them to Linux geeks.
Speaker 0: We'll do it on their own anyway But market them as a solution like an alternative to Windows like heavily market Linux as like all the smart people use Linux The cool people use Linux doesn't crash.
Speaker 0: you can use Linux - it's more secure.
Speaker 0: if you can't afford OS X Yeah, you know that's it.
Speaker 2: I think Dell's strategy isn't to sell computers of that Windows.
Speaker 2: I think their strategy sell computers period is to sell computers period and The only reason that they want to have Linux computers at all is because that way they could sell Computers to people who are Linux users.
Speaker 2: right now Dell really can't sell to Linux users.
Speaker 2: Linux users will go out and build their own computer.
Speaker 2: So that's why Dell started this.
Speaker 2: he says they started this n-series which comes with the free DOS Which means you can erase free DOS and put whatever Linux you want on there, and you don't have to pay the windows tax.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now part of the reason.
Speaker 0: I mean you wonder why don't they just offer it without any OS?
Speaker 0: but apparently Microsoft got really angry Way back when they decided to do that sort of thing claiming that they're just promoting piracy.
Speaker 0: You know who would buy a computer without an operating system.
Speaker 0: They're obviously going to pirate pirate windows.
Speaker 0: No one uses Linux.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I think that if but Dell really pushed it though today and tried to sell computers that OS is that they would probably succeed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't see Dell doing that anytime soon.
Speaker 2: No they have no reason to just throw free dogs on there.
Speaker 2: Okay, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 2: You know it keeps Microsoft and complaining what it doesn't mean.
Speaker 0: shit though I definitely think at least someone could make some sort of Linux computer combo and sell them to the market.
Speaker 0: as long as they advertised and did this marketing campaign.
Speaker 0: for You know just promoting Linux as a solution that is secure and maybe make people feel smart about using Linux.
Speaker 2: Yes, that's the one thing is it?
Speaker 2: no because Linux is free.
Speaker 2: No one's gonna put money in to try to sell it.
Speaker 2: all they do is you know they throw it on some really cheap hardware And say hey, here's a whole computer for only like a hundred bucks.
Speaker 2: 200 bucks come get it You know and it.
Speaker 2: it gives Linux this kind of like because they don't advertise all the good stuff about Linux.
Speaker 2: It gives it this kind of like Hyundai kind of feel like Kia kind of feel we're like oh, it's cheap But it's not as you know good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's cheap.
Speaker 0: therefore it must suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's that's the opposite of true, and I think if someone like sold some computers The opposite of true exactly not not false not it's a lie, but that's the opposite of true.
Speaker 2: again I am more tired today than it was yesterday.
Speaker 2: So
Speaker 0: see surprisingly despite the fact that I spent the morning in Manhattan And I took an ass early train into the city like I got to the train station so early There was no one else there, and I took the peak like commuter train in almost entirely by myself.
Speaker 2: Yeah, well I Did work at work today, so I'm all tired.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I also did work at work today, and I walked all around, New York City No great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what was I pass out soon?
Speaker 2: Yeah, if they put Ubuntu on a computer, and they sold it as this computer won't get viruses It won't crash.
Speaker 2: It does this and this and this and this don't you know don't?
Speaker 2: you're not to pay for software.
Speaker 2: There's software that does almost whatever you want already on it And you can still.
Speaker 2: I am your friends, and you can still do all these great things you know.
Speaker 2: But you know don't try to buy software in the store and don't try to play a game.
Speaker 2: Yeah That's the problem is like no matter what you advertise.
Speaker 2: There's still Something that someone's gonna try to do that you can't do and that's the problem with Linux.
Speaker 2: someone will go and buy That digital camera.
Speaker 2: that doesn't work that scanner.
Speaker 2: that doesn't work.
Speaker 2: They'll try to plug in their video camera to download a video off of it, and it won't work.
Speaker 2: You know that's.
Speaker 2: that's what you got to get over that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem is it's not fun to make that sort of thing work.
Speaker 2: No it's.
Speaker 0: I mean I'll admit it I when I buy a new you know bit that's gonna go into my computer.
Speaker 0: I'll look online and I'll find if someone else has gotten into work in Linux, and if no one else has I don't buy that bit.
Speaker 2: yep And that's the good way to go because now companies are being forced to make things work with Linux before they sell them.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean Nvidia.
Speaker 2: yeah The problem is is an already existing things and in super new things because a lot of companies will say well We don't need Linux support right away.
Speaker 2: It won't make a difference.
Speaker 2: You know and they'll put it out, and then you got to wait or Something is so old and Linux support isn't gonna come around.
Speaker 2: But it's something useful that everyone has like a webcam of some sort or something like that.
Speaker 0: Well anyway to move on to more relevant Anime related news since it is anime day Otakon for any of you who are planning to go to it has all but sold out of the hotel rooms that are remaining for This year.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 2: There's a big surprise.
Speaker 2: Yeah, they have a heart attack and die from not surprised.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is actually two of the hotels sold out within a week of the dates being announced.
Speaker 0: You know last August Mm-hmm, but yeah if any of you out there planning go to Otakon get your hotel room right now like literally stop listening to geek Nights and go get a hotel room.
Speaker 2: otherwise you're probably gonna be screwed Doesn't matter at this point if you get a hotel room you're gonna be far far away from the convention center.
Speaker 0: Away, I think there are a few rooms left that are closed But those are the expensive rooms that most young fan children can't afford.
Speaker 0: yep We used to be that way in other news.
Speaker 2: anime, Boston their artists alley sold out in five minutes and a few seconds.
Speaker 2: So next year, they're making their artists alley much bigger, but if you're looking for a good artists alley I would recommend going to anime Boston this year where we might go.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we're thinking about it, and they'll be Packed artists alley of awesome.
Speaker 0: and of course if you want to be in the Otakon artists alley subscribe to their RSS feed and Watch because last year.
Speaker 0: I think it sold out within an hour.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but you can't beat anime Boston's five minutes now.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: we'll see.
Speaker 0: it'll be a race at the artists alleys.
Speaker 2: Yeah, oh one more thing.
Speaker 2: there's some con in Australia or something And I think they set a policy for their dealers room that allows selling bootlegs as long as they're not licensed for release in Australia.
Speaker 2: so it's like if it's not licensed you can sell it here even if it's bootleg.
Speaker 2: so we'll see what happens to that convention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there's a whole bunch of tricky stuff about copyright law, and I don't know much about Australian copyright law.
Speaker 0: I know in many ways.
Speaker 0: It's a lot more draconian, but there might be a big loophole here.
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: see it's always weird to me.
Speaker 2: the places that can get away with selling bootlegs in the places They can't.
Speaker 2: it's like you have an anime convention for three days right if any bootleg DVDs are sold there It's like oh my god, but you have a store down the street from us an anime store And they sell bootlegs are crazy, and then no one cares.
Speaker 0: I don't think they have anything that isn't a bootleg.
Speaker 2: Yeah, because they can't really don't really compete with the Best Buy Pro DVD market.
Speaker 0: They can yeah, not even the DVDs.
Speaker 0: They have all these bootleg wall scrolls and bootleg posters and VHS bootleg.
Speaker 2: well They have some non bootleg some of the toys and things.
Speaker 0: yeah some of the toys.
Speaker 0: But I don't think they have a non bootleg wall scroll in that entire building Maybe not?
Speaker 0: they also know as I say that I've got a bootleg or tenof poster.
Speaker 0: I bought from them hanging above my desk.
Speaker 2: Awesome.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but also Another example like the super Midtown comic book store in New York You know they sell bootlegs at crazy stuff like all these old TV shows.
Speaker 2: you can buy like all of XO squad and DVD from Them.
Speaker 2: they used to saw all of Thundercats on DVD But then Thundercats came out on DVD.
Speaker 2: so they get the pros in and they sell the other one.
Speaker 2: You know they get the other.
Speaker 2: they take the bootlegs away.
Speaker 2: It's kind of weird.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I don't know how to get away with that.
Speaker 2: It's like this.
Speaker 0: You know why there's.
Speaker 0: so there's so many people out there selling bootlegs that you can't get them all and it's really not.
Speaker 2: It's like our friend Pete, but I mean all you did was walk into the store.
Speaker 2: There's a giant giant rack That's so obvious full of bootleg TV.
Speaker 0: I find out we had a similar discussion with Pete who you know tests food.
Speaker 0: as we were walking down in Chinatown over the weekend and we saw the shady dude selling raw deer heads out of a cardboard box on the side of the street and That sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: you just you can't stop it.
Speaker 2: if you can't stop it Then it's effectively not illegal and everyone should just do it anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: it's real easy to catch people at a con because it's easy to just walk around and look what everyone's got.
Speaker 2: Well, you keep it hidden.
Speaker 2: You know, you know, we'll close by.
Speaker 2: You know a lot of the dealers had those boxes under their tables and you just assume those boxes.
Speaker 0: You know what more any excess merchandise company was doing.
Speaker 0: that it a note.
Speaker 0: a couple Otakon's back and they got kicked out.
Speaker 2: How did they find out?
Speaker 0: they have Pete.
Speaker 0: they have undercover people looking around and people will report stuff.
Speaker 0: So I assume some kids saw it reported to the staff.
Speaker 0: staff came over and hate bootlegs.
Speaker 0: Oh Asset, what do you mean ass head?
Speaker 0: I'm fairly against bootlegs.
Speaker 2: Well, yeah, but I mean at the same time It's like the code of the schoolyard.
Speaker 2: Nah, nah, you know, you don't tell on people you let him get caught on their own.
Speaker 0: I tell on people.
Speaker 0: I told on some punk kids on the train once.
Speaker 2: Where were they doing?
Speaker 0: They ripped down one of the emergency signs because it's glow-in-the-dark.
Speaker 0: And then the conductor came over and I just said hey those kids ripped down the emergency sign That's supposed to be there and I watched hilarity ensue.
Speaker 2: Where'd the community do?
Speaker 0: He yelled at him and then this parent came over.
Speaker 0: Why are you yelling at my kid?
Speaker 0: and then the conductor's like her kid just damaged train property?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could cause you call the police.
Speaker 0: It was just hilarious.
Speaker 0: Uh Yeah, I was proud of that.
Speaker 0: punk kids.
Speaker 0: I'm no longer a punk kid now.
Speaker 0: I'm the crotchety old man who gets the punk kid in trouble.
Speaker 2: Punk kids and crotchety old man eternal enemies.
Speaker 2: We need to make a video game about crotchety old men versus punk kids And you can be either side.
Speaker 2: In fact, it's you a multiplayer online game massively multiplayer massively multiplayer online game Crotchety old men versus punk kids.
Speaker 2: Of course, you can only own property if you're a old man.
Speaker 2: you get this giant lawn And the punk kids try to invade it, but they have weapons and you don't so.
Speaker 2: but you do have a lawn And a law, you know cops.
Speaker 2: Yep But the cops are all NPCs And they eventually can get mad at you if you call them too often.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just make a progress quest extension?
Speaker 0: that does this game?
Speaker 2: Perfect.
Speaker 2: Speaking of progress quest.
Speaker 2: I'm currently level 27 outstanding.
Speaker 1: Yeah, great.
Speaker 2: I don't know how many of our listeners are familiar with the concept of Super doll fee.
Speaker 0: it's uh, if any of you are into it, that's cool But I personally find it a little scary and a little creepy.
Speaker 2: It is very scary.
Speaker 0: Basically what super doll fee is is I'll warn you if you try to define what super doll fee is in any way Anyone who knows what they're talking about is gonna jump down your throat in the forums.
Speaker 2: They'll find you Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 2: They're scary because they like super doll fee so they can shove it.
Speaker 2: so it's basically these ball-jointed dolls and they make clothing and Stuff for them and they cut their hair and color their hair and it's like a super customizable doll.
Speaker 2: Usually they make them look like j-rockers and make them like j-rockers anime characters, whatever they want, you know And it's kind of freaky.
Speaker 2: You'll see him sometimes in your artist alley or something.
Speaker 2: And yeah, they're generally Something you don't want
Speaker 1: to get involved in
Speaker 0: Unless you're really into that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't begrudge anyone having a hobby.
Speaker 0: just Be warned that if you're really into super doll fee I might find you a little creepy.
Speaker 2: Yeah, not to mention the fact It's really the money that makes it the most creepy and the amount of time spent on it.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It is about as addictive and time-consuming as Warhammer is.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's about equal to that Warhammer at least.
Speaker 2: there's a good game in Warhammer, you know Unlike some CCGs like magic or whatever or the penny arcade collectible card game.
Speaker 2: Yeah, Warhammer is actually a somewhat decent game.
Speaker 2: So there's something to it, you know super doll fee is just nothing.
Speaker 0: It's like Warhammer wasn't a game.
Speaker 0: Um, I know I submit that there are people out there for whom it is not a game.
Speaker 2: That is true.
Speaker 2: And those people are equally scary.
Speaker 2: So yes.
Speaker 2: Anyway, put that aside You can customize.
Speaker 2: super doll fees are made for customization But some dolls are not such as Barbie.
Speaker 1: But some people have
Speaker 2: decided to customize Barbie anyway,
Speaker 0: and they made Barbie into an
Speaker 2: otaku,
Speaker 0: haha.
Speaker 2: so here you will see someone who has customized Barbie into otaku.
Speaker 2: Barbie she has a T-shirt with one of Hello Kitty's friends on it.
Speaker 0: The fact that she has the little sketchbook with the little somewhat poorly drawn anime style sketch on it is just classic.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I think she also has like a little like a Japanese snack and a j-pop CD and a little bag of a little artist thingy a little portfolio bag and You know, she's totally drawing all sorts of little anime arts on a very Barbie sized sketchbook.
Speaker 0: You know with a little bit of editing Scott I could make a podcast where basically it's just you talking about how awesome this Barbie doll is.
Speaker 2: Yeah, well, that's not good because the last thing the Barbie does is transform into magical Barbie Sailor Senshi Woot, which is ultra frightening.
Speaker 0: I submit that the cross-dressing Ken is slightly more frustrating.
Speaker 2: I was gonna keep that a secret.
Speaker 2: So if you would go to the site and see it Oh, well, you know what.
Speaker 0: go to the site and see the cross-dressing Ken.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so at the bottom of the site is worse than otaku Barbie.
Speaker 2: It's cross play Ken and it's Ken with the tiara dressed like Sailor Moon And he's got a freaking beer belly and it's frightening.
Speaker 0: Hey, it's no Sailor Bubba bobblehead.
Speaker 2: No, it's not a Sailor Bubba bobblehead, but why don't those exist?
Speaker 2: they would sell like hotcakes.
Speaker 0: they do exist.
Speaker 0: They were sold at anime central.
Speaker 2: Where do we get them?
Speaker 0: I didn't get one, but I saw them there.
Speaker 2: I've been anime essentially where the official bobbleheads made by the bobblehead company or they knock off I don't know cuz the real bobbleheads have like ceramic heads.
Speaker 0: See, all I know is the only place I really saw Sailor Bubba with any degree of regularity was anime central.
Speaker 1: I saw him at an Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yeah He's not at every Otakon.
Speaker 1: No, he's not.
Speaker 0: he was at every anime central for a while.
Speaker 1: He's you know, he's not really as big now.
Speaker 1: It's like Jewish wolf would took his spot.
Speaker 0: And all you mean Mike Pfeffer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wonder if he listens to us after he was on.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So Mike Pfeffer, do you still listen to geek nights?
Speaker 0: Yeah If you don't we're gonna keep calling you Jewish wolf would.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he really doesn't like being called Jewish wolf.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's more that Jewish wolf would was something that made him really like well-known and popular.
Speaker 0: But it's not the thing he wants to be remembered for.
Speaker 1: he wants to be remembered for being awesome And he is kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: So he's really digging up that off Communist Party of anime thing, which I find fairly hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yes, so, um, we'll definitely hook up with him at some con in the future.
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe bring him on the show again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe we'll get him here so we can use the real equipment.
Speaker 0: You can hear what his voice actually sounds like.
Speaker 0: All right, so my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I had some other thing of the day which is actually kind of cool And then I decided to look in my delicious for some news and I realized that a while ago I had put something in my delicious and then forgotten about it.
Speaker 1: Now that's the point of delicious.
Speaker 0: now all of you are familiar with bleach because you're all listening to the anime portion of geek nights and bleach is One of the new popular shows like Naruto or Yu Yu Hakusho.
Speaker 1: It's a shonen action fighting show.
Speaker 1: It follows the already know you already know my opinion of these shows.
Speaker 0: it follows the formula of here's some awesome characters.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's an awesome story.
Speaker 0: Oh five episodes have gone by.
Speaker 0: Well, fuck that story.
Speaker 0: Let's have them fight for the next 3,000 episodes.
Speaker 1: That's exactly the definition of shonen action.
Speaker 0: I mean the characters are really kind of cute and cool and if it weren't for the fact that it's just a fighting show I'd Be all about it, but I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: It's just a fighting show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like Yu Yu Hakusho.
Speaker 1: You know the first two episodes like this amazing plot these funny characters and then oh We're gonna have a giant tournament Naruto ninja school.
Speaker 0: forget that ninja school ninja school was hilarious.
Speaker 0: And then suddenly they're fighting and in tournaments.
Speaker 1: Don't do you realize that they just took the first few episodes and dragged it out to be a 26 episode show?
Speaker 1: It would be amazing.
Speaker 1: But when they just start a fighting show instead, it sucks.
Speaker 0: It sucks to us.
Speaker 0: I find out that a lot of people like it.
Speaker 1: I Don't know what's up with it.
Speaker 1: Well, I gotta admit when I watch Naruto the first time it's something about these shows.
Speaker 1: We're like like rave master was another one that you don't realize.
Speaker 0: it's a fighting show right away.
Speaker 1: You don't realize the fighting show you've.
Speaker 1: you've gotten to the 13th episode.
Speaker 1: when they finally finished the fight You realize this is the 13th episode and then you go back and you look and you say hey this fights been going on since episode 5. oh I'm not watching anymore.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like it tricks you and as soon as you realize it you're you're safe.
Speaker 1: But you know, I don't know they have some sort of magic formula so you don't figure it out Though part of the reason bleach is slightly more interesting to me is that she'll probably embarrassed.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna say who she is, but we have a friend who looks exactly Like Rukia from the show.
Speaker 1: I don't know which character that is, but I'll look it up later.
Speaker 0: Well, she looks exactly like the person I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: All right But like it's creepy.
Speaker 0: She does a cosplay and she might as well be the character.
Speaker 1: There are lots of people, you know who could pretty much be any cat, you know certain characters, yeah, but anyway Bleach is very popular and I discovered I'm not exactly sure what this is.
Speaker 0: I think it's just the promo for something that someone wants to do or maybe they're making a musical But it's basically a bleach rock opera live action.
Speaker 1: That reminds me of the utenna pull a musical.
Speaker 0: All right, the utenna is Utenna and captain Tyler are my favorite two anime ever.
Speaker 0: I think Howie bebop is one of the best anime ever but Tyler and utenna are like near and dear to me.
Speaker 0: I could to go down to the infinite Horrible fanboy detail on all the various intricacies of utenna and I love everything to tenor involved.
Speaker 1: That's almost as scary as a super dolphin.
Speaker 0: the utenna musical Made me want to claw my own eyes out and then kill myself with them.
Speaker 1: I think we had a tape somewhere that had like a few.
Speaker 0: I still have that tape.
Speaker 0: It has most of the musical on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty frightening.
Speaker 0: It's like a fifth generation fan sub that's barely watchable of the last episode of utenna.
Speaker 0: and then the musical Here.
Speaker 1: to give you an example of what watching the utenna musical is like Imagine some people doing in utenna cosplay.
Speaker 1: They're seriously trying to act out what happens in the show But they're singing poorly and they have a slightly higher production value.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so just take a typical cosplay sketch and knock it up a notch.
Speaker 1: Not good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially since it's not one of those funny clever cosplay sketches.
Speaker 1: It's trying to be realistic cosplay sketch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was definitely.
Speaker 0: no the Muppets do antenna, which is one of the funniest things I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, um The bleach Iraq opera here is it's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: I got to admit it that I kind of like the music.
Speaker 1: the production seems pretty good.
Speaker 1: The music is average to me.
Speaker 0: Well, it sounds like the music would be good if someone better we're singing it.
Speaker 1: it seems to represent the show pretty well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people are fighting.
Speaker 0: There's Shinigami.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: No, they're fighting again.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's pretty accurate.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: The thing is I mean, I like the music.
Speaker 0: the problem the problem with this thing just seems to be that either they pulled the classic musical mistake of Hiring people who look good instead of people who can sing or these are just stand-ins and they're like trying to promote this thing.
Speaker 0: I'm really not sure.
Speaker 0: I haven't done any research on this.
Speaker 0: I just watched the clip and you should do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't tell I'm not Japanese or anything but if you like bleach or if you know what bleach is you should probably watch this little video and You'll either laugh or cry or something.
Speaker 1: It'll be worth your time.
Speaker 0: Yeah So anyway, it's anime day and it's also how to not suck week.
Speaker 0: Now we realized that all of the topics we could really cover how to not suck that involve anime are very very specific topics that many of you probably don't care about like How to not suck at running a panel at a convention or how to not suck at running an anime club?
Speaker 0: Or how to not suck at collecting comics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you already did how to not suck at a convention.
Speaker 0: I think well, we did three episodes on how to be good at a convention.
Speaker 1: basically Well, how to not suck is just our way of saying how to be good.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I guess we could do how to not suck at being an anime artist But all we'd have to say is go to art school and practice because we don't freaking know shit about art.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't draw a straight line.
Speaker 1: I can draw a stick figure happy one - yeah, you can Mean stick figure.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: So we decided partly because we're still very tired from the weekend We're just gonna do a very quick how to not suck at being a fan In other words how to not be a horrible fanboy.
Speaker 1: Yep, because a lot of people out there, you know I mean there are some things there were There are some people who are fanboys and proud of it like the comic book guy in The Simpsons.
Speaker 0: No, that's fine.
Speaker 0: I mean if you're that dude go ahead and be that dude all the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically I don't want to come near you, but I'll respect the way you do things and I'll stay clear and it'll be all good.
Speaker 0: Yeah We're also not gonna talk about taste in anime because you're allowed to like whatever you want and whatever Our opinions may be whatever even though our opinions are correct.
Speaker 0: Okay But anyway, all we really want to talk about here because we don't want to sound like assholes more so than we already are are Just things that you can probably try to avoid Because these are the kind of things that a fanboy does and maybe doesn't realize they're doing or doesn't realize that it's annoying to others.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there are a lot of people I'll run into at conventions where they'll be normal cool guys for the most part But they'll have something about them or they'll have a certain way about them.
Speaker 1: That is totally like.
Speaker 1: alright You need to get away from me now You know, it's an odor.
Speaker 1: Odor is the first thing on the list.
Speaker 0: Alright, so, uh, if you like anime, that's fine.
Speaker 0: If you have bo I don't care if you like anime or not.
Speaker 0: That's not fine.
Speaker 0: Don't have it.
Speaker 1: Yes There are two places you have to worry about.
Speaker 1: bo.
Speaker 1: number one anyplace crowded.
Speaker 1: if it's crowded and you're not wearing deodorant Or any purse print which I don't recommend wearing any purse print ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll get into that later.
Speaker 0: We'll do a whole show in some other episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah hygiene.
Speaker 1: We already did this one hygiene show.
Speaker 1: we can do another.
Speaker 0: well It's very simple if you're at a con or an anime club or out in public right your favorite store one Take a shower at least every other day.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: That's all I'm asking - in the summer every day.
Speaker 0: Yeah deodorant deodorant deodorant deodorant.
Speaker 0: if you don't own deodorant or You don't know how to use it or you own it but you're not using it.
Speaker 0: you're not a good person.
Speaker 0: In fact, you're a very bad person.
Speaker 1: Also, make sure you're showering properly.
Speaker 1: Just getting yourself wet and getting out is no good.
Speaker 1: You need to wash your hair with shampoo and clean your body with soap.
Speaker 0: in the very least go by George Carlin's method of showering armpits asshole crotch and teeth in that order.
Speaker 0: Actually, I think you want to do it in the.
Speaker 1: you know what I think he said in the order George Carlin.
Speaker 0: George Carlin made a joke cuz.
Speaker 0: then he said in the same order or in that order with the same brush Mmm, yeah, cuz he's George Carlin.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but wash the crucial areas.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know how many times I've been to a con and I've been floored by someone like Floored as in.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine how that odor could come from a still-living human being.
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially if you're at you know, I guess convention.
Speaker 1: we could talk about conventions more great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well anime clubs anime clubs and make let you walk it around all day or you're in a crowded room of people and it's Hot and you're starting to sweat.
Speaker 0: Not even just anime.
Speaker 0: if you're a comic guy and you leave your den of misery once a week to buy your comics on Wednesday That should be the day you shower.
Speaker 0: If you're gonna shower once a week make that the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, you got to look good when you go that comic book store.
Speaker 1: The owner will be friendlier to you.
Speaker 1: Maybe give you a discount.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you gotta think about these sort of things course?
Speaker 0: I Think some of these comic people Use the BO as a defense because they walk into the store.
Speaker 0: people back off.
Speaker 1: now They can get the comics they want without having to shove through the crowd perhaps but a lot of the crazy calm people have like Pre-orders, they don't need to shove through.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: Okay, number two Don't keep talking to someone if they don't seem to be like responding to you.
Speaker 0: I mean Basically, I was the president of the biggest anime club in the country for a year.
Speaker 0: I was on the board for three years and one of my many duties was being very polite and civil to people in public Meaning I had to always be nice to everyone no matter what because they're a member of this club and they're a member.
Speaker 1: I have to take care of them and I was the guy who got to say wow, you're a fanboy go away now.
Speaker 0: Tacked is a very beautiful thing.
Speaker 0: And if a fanboy is really bothering me, I usually won't tell him exactly what I think of him.
Speaker 0: I won't.
Speaker 0: you know, I I just I'm very not.
Speaker 0: I don't like to destroy someone's ego.
Speaker 1: I will if necessary.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not really pleasant, but I guess too much effort.
Speaker 1: it's
Speaker 0: a warning out there to people that if something if you're talking to someone and they keep looking away from you or not making eye Contact or they keep turning to their other friends or all they ever do when you say anything to them is go like
Speaker 1: Or yep.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah I got real good at Pretending.
Speaker 0: I'm paying attention to someone in those three years of running that clean.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing is this if I'm talking to someone and all they say is uh-huh Yep, and they're not looking at me or something.
Speaker 1: I go.
Speaker 1: Hey.
Speaker 1: Hey, are you paying attention to me?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't even want to hear what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: now Scott's a little weird I mean when it comes to that because basically one time we're we used to share a room in college and Just because we had a tiny little ass apartment and I'm laying in my bed I'm trying to sleep and Scott's trying to tell me something and all I remember is he stopped talking and he said like alright And I said and then he kept talking.
Speaker 0: then he said alright again and I didn't say anything and he said I'll write again And again, and then he said hey, hey, Ram Ram You're listening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then eventually realized that I wasn't listening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well and then he woke me up, but that's a whole other issue.
Speaker 1: Well the point is if I'm talking it's because I'm trying to communicate information to someone else and if I in some cases You know, I only want to communicate it if they want to hear it.
Speaker 1: and if they don't want to hear it I want to make sure that they don't want to hear it or not.
Speaker 1: So I do so and if they don't want to then I won't tell them anymore.
Speaker 0: So basically if you're at a con or at an anime club or out in public and you're trying to tell someone about this is this Is huge when waiting in lines for nerdy?
Speaker 0: Yes, because you're stuck with the people you're waiting in line with.
Speaker 0: and I've been stuck in some lines with people.
Speaker 1: I've been sucking some lines with some people and the trend seems to be there'll be a group that you'll be next to and the Group often contains a bunch of normal guys and then a cool guy or a loner Don't want to be in line next to loners.
Speaker 1: always get in lines next to groups.
Speaker 1: It's much more.
Speaker 0: by all means be friendly.
Speaker 0: try to meet people hang out with people talk to people.
Speaker 0: Don't be afraid.
Speaker 0: just walk over to someone and talk to them like hey, I like Dragon Ball you like Dragon Ball, too.
Speaker 0: But if they obviously don't like Dragon Ball don't keep talking about it.
Speaker 1: Especially don't talk about hentai or yaoi or anything weird like that at all unless you're sure That they want to hear about it.
Speaker 1: I mean you start talking about hentai and to me I will I will put you down solo.
Speaker 1: You want to kill your fury.
Speaker 1: You'll want to kill yourself.
Speaker 1: I'll be like wow, you're a perverted scumbag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like we have.
Speaker 0: uh, are we have a friend who's really into yaoi like really into yaoi and you know what?
Speaker 0: We're fine with that.
Speaker 0: Okay, and usually when she tells us about yaoi, it always ends up being a funny story.
Speaker 0: So we want to hear it and it's obvious we want to hear it, but we had a friend.
Speaker 0: Well, not a friend.
Speaker 0: There was a person we knew at RIT when we were there who would follow us around and Interject himself into conversations to explain what kinds of hentai he liked.
Speaker 0: I'm not exaggerating.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean, you know what our conversation was like, hey rim you want to go to the anime club tonight?
Speaker 0: Hey Scott Yeah, that'd be fine.
Speaker 0: Hey rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: I just watched Disembowelment hentai.
Speaker 0: It's my favorite kind of hentai.
Speaker 0: What kind of hentai do you like?
Speaker 1: Uh, no kind go away, yeah.
Speaker 1: But I mean, it's like the person we know that likes yaoi.
Speaker 1: when she talks about yaoi.
Speaker 1: It's always like oh my god There's a relevant yaoi.
Speaker 1: That's hilarious or you know, haha funny joke.
Speaker 1: It's never like.
Speaker 1: hey Do you want to come you know, see my favorite yaoi and then explaining the yaoi one time it was bad?
Speaker 1: But the thing is she no, I guess I wasn't there that time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she doesn't bring up the yaoi like out of the blue with no reason constantly because that just means you're trying to get attention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but she brings up when it's relevant.
Speaker 0: if if we're like at dick and busters Whatever hentai dubbing panel at Otakon or something because I hear that's hilarious and you start talking to me about the funny hentai We're watching that's cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it's informative.
Speaker 0: But if I'm walking down the street and you start telling me about your tentacle yaoi, I'm gonna hit you with a tentacle.
Speaker 0: You don't have a tentacle or do I?
Speaker 0: ha ha we made a joke that was about a penis.
Speaker 0: That never happens on geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right now Anime clubs out there.
Speaker 0: basically, it's tough to have an anime club.
Speaker 0: That's just about watching the anime because you know, you just watch the anime in your room.
Speaker 0: That's the argument that fanboys make at least now.
Speaker 0: to me Some watching anime in a group can often be one of the greatest experiences of an anime because they can turn a mediocre anime Awesome.
Speaker 1: All right now think about this.
Speaker 1: right you watch a show.
Speaker 1: Let's say it's a ridiculously crazy funny show like Excel Saga Or something else like that Genji Ken show.
Speaker 1: that's sort of new.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or like an old Lupin movie.
Speaker 1: Now when you watch these shows by yourself, you know, it's kind of funny.
Speaker 1: There's just something when you watch it in a room full of people where people yell out funny things or Every or you'll you know, because everyone is there paying attention that like if everyone starts laughing Maybe you'll notice a joke that you would have missed in your house.
Speaker 0: Or just that feeling of like something awesome happens like in an old Lupin movie Gee, Ken does something funny and crazy and everyone in the room goes Watching at home.
Speaker 1: You don't even like get that.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is or how it works.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should do a scientific study on how that you know.
Speaker 1: The yeah the psychology of watching things in groups as opposed to watching the same exact thing alone.
Speaker 0: So first off I guess if there's an anime club in your area Go check it out and try to watch anime with people.
Speaker 0: You might enjoy it a lot more.
Speaker 0: don't discount an anime club Just because they don't show the newest fans of that you're watching right now.
Speaker 1: Even watching an old show that you've already seen with a bunch of people can be greatly enhanced if those people do not suck Yes.
Speaker 0: Now this brings us to the critical point on how not to how to not suck number one If it's a serious part of a show.
Speaker 0: Shut up Unless now.
Speaker 0: keep in mind this all depends on the group you're with and you have to gauge the group.
Speaker 0: if you're sitting with a Bunch of people who just rip on everything and like everyone's cool with everyone just talking and yelling then by all means go in with that.
Speaker 0: But if you're watching magical girl Y and her the boy She loves is about to stab her to death and it's this horrible dramatic scene and you crack a joke Loudly in the middle of a silent room where everyone's paying attention You suck.
Speaker 1: You definitely suck even though it's magical girl.
Speaker 1: Why I don't care?
Speaker 1: yeah, so the second thing you want to do is if you have something funny to say and it is appropriate to yell something out like Let's say You know how sometimes in normal life someone will say something that leaves them wide open to a witty insult or a witty retort.
Speaker 1: Yes, sometimes an anime will say something that leaves someone wide open.
Speaker 0: You know like like the horrible yaoi innuendo and a show that has nothing to do with yaoi.
Speaker 1: Exactly now, you know before you yell out whatever you're about to yell out You can't delay too much because then it won't be funny.
Speaker 1: So if you delay it if you hesitate at all more than like two seconds, don't say anything because people will go why you're too late.
Speaker 1: But do spend a half a second to make sure that you're laughing on the inside when you think about it or else Everyone will go Groan and throw things at you.
Speaker 0: Yeah And once again just pay attention to the crowd.
Speaker 0: if it's a bunch of people who like to watch their show silently don't yell funny Stuff out.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, because that's just not gonna work.
Speaker 0: People aren't gonna like you.
Speaker 1: the other thing is you know, let's say you know, you think about your thing for half a second.
Speaker 1: yell it out if Everyone groans don't try it again.
Speaker 1: You're not a funny person.
Speaker 0: Oh my god We had problems with that more than you could imagine.
Speaker 1: It's like that was always.
Speaker 1: my strategy is if there was something if it was appropriate for me to yell something out and I had Something funny to say I would go with it.
Speaker 1: And if people laughed I would wait until I got the next one and I would gauge that one in Myself against the previous one.
Speaker 1: and if it was more funny, I'd let it loose.
Speaker 1: or equally funny I'd let it loose if it was less funny.
Speaker 1: I'd keep it in now.
Speaker 0: also don't be tricked by success.
Speaker 0: Say you yell something out and it's hilarious and like the whole room explodes with laughter Don't take that as a license to yell something out every five seconds for the rest of the anime because they'll kill you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you only yell something out when it like.
Speaker 1: just comes to you, you know If you're trying to think of stuff to yell out you're in trouble.
Speaker 1: You have to just you know, sit there let it come let it cut the anime absorb into your body.
Speaker 1: And then whenever something hilarious just pops into your mind, you know gauge it really quickly and let it loose.
Speaker 1: That's the.
Speaker 1: that's the the method.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The rule here is when in doubt shut your pie hole Yep, or in the very least whisper to your friend next to you.
Speaker 1: and if your friend next to you starts laughing Maybe you can manage to do a little room spreading action.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's often happened where something fun someone says something funny to me Ha ha ha and then the person on the other side goes, what did he just say?
Speaker 0: and I whisper it.
Speaker 0: they go Ha ha ha and then it spreads to the whole room and there's like this rumbling laughter growing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's a good one Alright, so last and least well I guess not least most for many people just because we don't want to you know Talk about fanboys for an hour here.
Speaker 0: It's not the most pleasant topic.
Speaker 0: But if you know the end of cowboy bebop and you know That the dude sitting next to you has never seen it or he just bought it and he's starting to watch it Don't tell him how it ends.
Speaker 0: In fact, don't tell anyone how anything ends unless you're sure they either want to know how it ends and don't care if you spoil It or that, you know, they've already seen it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and don't say endings to things loudly or in public places.
Speaker 1: or you know If you're telling it to a whole group Make sure every single person in the group is cool.
Speaker 1: If one person's uncool either get them to leave the room or close their ears or something like that.
Speaker 0: I mean This is one of the biggest ways to spot a horrible fanboy because we'll have a group of people and someone will say oh Man, the end of eska flown a when wait a minute.
Speaker 0: You've all seen eska flown a right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And then if everyone says yeah, then they say whatever they're gonna say or other is they oh We'll talk about this later when so-and-so isn't here.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's just etiquette.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: and if you're in like a group of people and you're gonna watch something make sure that whatever you're gonna watch is appropriate for everyone who's in there in the room watching, you know, not in just in terms of you know Content but in terms of you know, we're gonna watch episode 13 of you know Crazy show that is very serial and well,
Speaker 0: you know, we're just fantastic at coming up with fake names for anime.
Speaker 0: We had magical girl why and crazy show Alright.
Speaker 0: Alright, um Sad super robot 59 sad puppy snow angel sad boobies.
Speaker 1: No So if you're gonna watch to the 16th episode of super robot 59
Speaker 0: You know the one where Mickey gets his head chopped off and then everyone cries
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know has the totally unexpected robot explosion, you know Don't watch that if people haven't seen one through whatever before that because then Now the whole show is kind of messed up for them.
Speaker 0: now It might be painful because we've had the full metal alchemist movie for a long time Just sitting here waiting to be listened to watched.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah watched I listened to.
Speaker 0: I'm so used to talking about podcast.
Speaker 0: I finally got out of saying watch what I mean.
Speaker 0: Listen.
Speaker 0: now I say listen what I mean watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just make your spotless and check and get on with it.
Speaker 0: Haha, but my exponent is four but my shade is whites.
Speaker 1: Oh my god white run away.
Speaker 0: Haha.
Speaker 0: Yeah burning wheels.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about that another show But anyway.
Speaker 0: So we had a bunch of friends over like three separate times where we could have watched the movie as a big group But every time there was at least one person who hadn't seen the end of the show yet.
Speaker 1: And we're not even sure if the movie spoils anything, but I'm reasonably sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not a hundred percent sure though.
Speaker 1: So it's like because we're not sure we don't do it.
Speaker 1: You don't take risks Yeah, because I mean unless someone doesn't if someone doesn't care like go for it, you know Things I don't care about.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I want to be spoiled.
Speaker 1: if anyone is gonna tell me the end of fancy Lala and what the hell happens with those dinosaurs I'll give you a dollar Yeah, or you asked me to spoil scrap princess for you a while ago because you didn't want to watch it.
Speaker 1: No, whatever I don't remember what you said, huh?
Speaker 0: Of course can't be careful because there's always the caveat of the person who you know.
Speaker 0: They'll say like they'll ask a question like they want to know the answer, but they don't really want to know.
Speaker 0: Generally don't answer that question or always at least preface it with a. Are you sure you want to know?
Speaker 1: yeah And that way if they didn't really want to know it's their own damn fault.
Speaker 0: cuz like Emily She's watching Last Exile right now, which we just watch all of and soon we're gonna do our final thoughts.
Speaker 0: episode on Yeah, I promised all of you out there have been asking.
Speaker 0: starting next week We're probably gonna start actually reviewing anime again because we've got a whole backlog of shows now Yeah, and even more episodes is sitting on the computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus we're watching the original slayers again.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I love it But she'll sometimes she'll ask like does he die?
Speaker 0: what happens to him?
Speaker 0: now?
Speaker 0: it's obvious that she doesn't actually want the answer to that question.
Speaker 0: a fanboy will immediately answer.
Speaker 0: a Non-fanboy will ask are you sure?
Speaker 1: the other thing is sometimes and this is a it doesn't take a lot of judgment skill But it takes some.
Speaker 1: there are sometimes it's okay to just tell all.
Speaker 1: there's nothing wrong with saying Luke Darth Vader is his father because everyone freaking knows and if they don't know hit him.
Speaker 0: Alright, I gotta tell the story about Greg and it does fake spoiler.
Speaker 0: He did.
Speaker 0: Alright, cuz this is awesome our friend Greg.
Speaker 0: He told us this story.
Speaker 0: We were with him, but apparently this happened And even if it didn't happen, it's a damn good story.
Speaker 0: So remember episode 2 of Star Wars when it came out.
Speaker 1: You mean it was a. so episode 2 not Empire Strikes Back, but yeah the clone war.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the attack of the clones okay, so apparently he went to see it and On his way out because they saw like the midnight first showing there's a line of people Waiting for the second showing of it.
Speaker 0: So he starts talking and in a very loud voice says man that was awesome, but I can't believe they killed Yoda and This guy in the line goes.
Speaker 0: Thanks a lot asshole You just ruined the movie.
Speaker 0: and then he realizes what he just said and That guy got pooned in a way that no man has ever been pooned before.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you don't realize why that's funny, I Don't know what to say to you.
Speaker 1: We have a Star Wars episode somewhere in the archives.
Speaker 1: You should go listen to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had a thing of the day that was Star Wars related But I'll use it tomorrow if I don't find anything better tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a quick one.
Speaker 1: We'll just let that loose whenever.
Speaker 0: yeah Geographically related to us Was oh, yeah, you know, I let it loose right now because we're devolving into the end of this episode.
Speaker 0: Okay, so a guy was caught selling crack near us in Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of crack guys up there.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah now now any guess what.
Speaker 0: his name was Lando Calrissian Butler.
Speaker 0: his first name is Lando Calrissian.
Speaker 1: We're not sure if that was a misspelling by the newspaper and it's actually Lando Calrissian.
Speaker 1: Or maybe his parents didn't know how to spell Calrissian and they made it Carlesan or whatever they wrote there.
Speaker 0: or maybe he gave a fake name and they don't have an ID for it.
Speaker 1: What's your name Lando Calrissian Butler?
Speaker 1: That's my name.
Speaker 1: What was the who's?
Speaker 1: the actor Billy Dee Williams Joey Jojo.
Speaker 1: Yeah Billy Dee Williams was Lando Calrissian.
Speaker 1: never hilarious.
Speaker 1: if like you went and they tried to arrest you for crack and you'd like they'd be Like what's your name?
Speaker 1: They know Calrissian Billy Dee Williams charge.
Speaker 0: All right, so we're done with that The our first theme week kind of.
Speaker 0: basically the reason we use this theme is simply that now, you know to go to some meta bits.
Speaker 0: We're tired this week and that seemed like an easy theme to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah next week.
Speaker 1: Let's do favorites week All right.
Speaker 0: So next week is going to be favorites week meaning we're going to talk about our favorite things our favorite technology our favorite video games our favorite anime manga and comics and our favorite other shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably music and movies.
Speaker 0: and we've got a lot of different weeks coming up.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do an old-school week at some point.
Speaker 1: We'll do a most hated week.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's gonna be an awesome week.
Speaker 1: most hated video games.
Speaker 1: Most hated anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah ultimate quest of the Avatar.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh god great digital target.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, man, don't give don't give him the previews.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right, and tomorrow we're gonna have a surprise How to not suck mainly because we're not sure what we're gonna do yet, and we don't want to lock ourselves in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because we could do anything.
Speaker 1: but it will surprise you I guarantee.
Speaker 0: And my last metabit here On the forums make you might have seen that I posted that we were like the number one search on Yahoo!
Speaker 0: Podcast for a whole bunch of things like anime manga comics geekery technology Science, we're like number six or seven now almost anything related to us you search for.
Speaker 0: we're the number one Like.
Speaker 1: I really don't know how that happened.
Speaker 0: But now I'm starting to figure out how it happened.
Speaker 0: But then right like a few hours later Someone posted in the forums that you guys don't show up for shit in there and I looked as sure enough we didn't.
Speaker 0: So I did some investigating and it seemed basically I've discovered that Right.
Speaker 0: when it screwed up is when Scott added all of the feed burner feeds that I had created for all the days of the week of geek nights And I they're added in iTunes and Yahoo got really confused for a while about geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not too many people use Yahoo!
Speaker 0: Podcast, but I'll note we have over 20 subscribers through Yahoo!
Speaker 0: Podcast alone.
Speaker 1: Yep, but who knows how many of those subscribers actually like I got?
Speaker 1: I'm subscribed by Yahoo!
Speaker 1: Podcast, you know, it doesn't really.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not someone actually utilizing.
Speaker 0: Well consider that the popular podcast on Yahoo have maybe maybe 40 subscribers there.
Speaker 1: So I'm telling you is that not too many people are actually using Yahoo!
Speaker 1: Podcast seriously.
Speaker 0: Oh, I really doubt it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's a thing but though enough people are tagging geek nights with the appropriate tags to make it come up very highly in The searches.
Speaker 1: that's good.
Speaker 0: And we've got three reviews written there.
Speaker 0: Whoo.
Speaker 1: Oh really?
Speaker 1: I only read like one.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, so.
Speaker 0: But anyway to answer the question someone posted in the forums.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the 20 means we have 20 Yahoo!
Speaker 0: subscribers.
Speaker 0: It does not mean we have 20 subscribers.
Speaker 0: geek nights has far more than 20 subscribers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or else I wouldn't be here.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: yeah, we're switching to Libsyn real soon for the mp3 hosting.
Speaker 1: good because we need to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz we're running out of space and bandwidth real quick.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if geek nights goes down or something Don't start calling us on the phone and stuff because that means we'll be back shortly.
Speaker 0: We're working on all those issues.
Speaker 1: Yeah, hopefully we can just stay up, you know by the skin of our teeth until we have.
Speaker 0: yeah Cuz Libsyn's has had its own issues.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I was actually gonna migrate two weeks ago, but they had some problems.
Speaker 1: Are they over their problems?
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: I'll have to check that this weekend.
Speaker 0: this weekend I'm gonna do a whole bunch of podcast stuff.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: All right, and we're out tomorrow.
Speaker 0: expect how to not suck at something Everything and that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 2: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.