Speaker 1: It's Thursday December 14th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about the barge.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Fuck this show.
Speaker 1: I quit what it's over.
Speaker 0: No, not really sure we could stop anytime.
Speaker 1: We could just stop right now.
Speaker 0: I just.
Speaker 0: I really don't feel like doing a show today.
Speaker 1: I think part of that is because we started a lot later than we planned on mostly because we didn't have an idea for the show and Despite the fact that our listeners and me Both all wanted another zombie episode.
Speaker 1: Scott wasn't up to the challenge.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not the challenge.
Speaker 0: It's not motivated.
Speaker 0: I don't really care.
Speaker 1: hence You're not up to the challenge.
Speaker 1: the challenge of doing another one of these important documentaries that'll someday save lives.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't really want to do that episode and I was all about it.
Speaker 1: I knew exactly what I was gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why don't you do the show on your own then?
Speaker 1: big shot see I've tried to do shows on my own and I could But it's usually not as entertaining.
Speaker 1: entertaining is having more than one person on the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, any one person talking at a podcast for more than about 15 minutes really starts to drag.
Speaker 1: Well, it works in video podcasts for some reason but not the not for me not the audio ones Other than ask a ninja which I don't find funny anymore Probably just due to the fact that they're all pretty much the same kind of like strong bad.
Speaker 1: Yep I can't stand any video podcast.
Speaker 0: Well, I just found a new video podcast today that I thought was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So yeah, yeah, I just want I don't have time to sit and watch something like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway between all the anime definitely got to keep it short.
Speaker 0: if they want me to watch if it's like actually a TV show Forget it.
Speaker 0: I don't have time to watch TV shows and I don't time to.
Speaker 1: I don't know if there were a pseudopod equivalent Videocast where it was basically just horror fiction acted out.
Speaker 1: I'd be all about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know when I'd watch it.
Speaker 0: I mean event if there were too many of those we could just get rid of Netflix and just watch those instead.
Speaker 1: That's kind of what I want.
Speaker 1: Netflix is a temporary patch in my life because it allows me to get all the movies I want to see at a rate.
Speaker 1: I can watch them legally and for almost no money.
Speaker 1: It would be alright, but whatever Yeah, but yeah, we were gonna do the zombie show.
Speaker 1: Scott wasn't up to the challenge.
Speaker 1: then we didn't have a show.
Speaker 0: And now we have a show.
Speaker 1: we've got a show.
Speaker 0: We don't have a show.
Speaker 1: You can't do ten shows whatever.
Speaker 1: you can't make ten swags.
Speaker 0: No, we're gonna this weekend.
Speaker 0: That's what we're gonna do.
Speaker 0: is we're gonna make swag?
Speaker 1: Well, we're gonna start the process of considering the possibility of beginning the production of the first piece of swag.
Speaker 0: No, I'm pretty sure we're gonna finish the first piece of swag.
Speaker 0: How what do you mean?
Speaker 1: How are we gonna finish the first piece of swag?
Speaker 0: We'll just make it.
Speaker 1: Well, what design are we gonna use?
Speaker 1: What art is going to go on this?
Speaker 0: It won't be too hard.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do, but you're gonna draw something If it take me a long time, but I could know you couldn't it would just take a long time.
Speaker 0: No, you couldn't do it at all.
Speaker 0: If given enough time I could do it.
Speaker 1: I don't think given any amount of time takes a good artist.
Speaker 0: five minutes takes me five days But I can.
Speaker 1: I don't think you could do in five days what Emily or Yuko or any of our artist friends can do.
Speaker 0: Well not in the same amount of time.
Speaker 1: No in five days.
Speaker 1: You couldn't do what they can do in five minutes.
Speaker 1: I'll say that right now and neither can I.
Speaker 0: I could if I didn't sleep and I spent all the time working.
Speaker 0: No is but I probably couldn't do that.
Speaker 1: I think all you do is eventually wear a hole through the piece of paper as you kept drawing a stick figure erasing it And on it slightly crook.
Speaker 0: Eventually, it'd be the best damn stick figure the world ever saw.
Speaker 0: I'd be the stick figure master.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the fact is we haven't really picked swag yet other than the generic swag.
Speaker 0: We're working on it.
Speaker 1: No, we're not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we haven't worked on it at all.
Speaker 1: We've been working on the DVD.
Speaker 0: this weekend We got nothing and next weekend.
Speaker 0: We got nothing.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna be working on next weekend's Christmas.
Speaker 1: I'll probably be going somewhere.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna go somewhere?
Speaker 0: probably I'll sit here and work on swag.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did put together one thing.
Speaker 1: The outtakes reel is almost done.
Speaker 1: I put together every outtake we have From the first season and sadly there's only one outtake so far from the second season and it's four seconds long.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, it's a good thing.
Speaker 0: We're trying to run this episode a little long because we don't got much to say today.
Speaker 1: No, no, just the DVD is gonna be pretty cool.
Speaker 1: You can hear the outtakes you'll hear like when we do interviews the prep talk and the post talk that you might not have otherwise heard.
Speaker 1: Most of the outtakes are honestly from the first month of geek nights Where we didn't know how to deal with what we do when we fuck up.
Speaker 1: So here I'll act out say we fuck up.
Speaker 1: now it's like and so in the news the consumer advocacy Consumer advocacy group and that's how we deal with things back in the day.
Speaker 1: It'd be like consumer advocacy.
Speaker 1: Fuck.
Speaker 1: I fucked up the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got to totally cut that out fuck Haha, and then we get going and we had a bunch of outtakes like that.
Speaker 1: But now it's sad to say but I guess we've become professionals.
Speaker 1: There's no more outtakes.
Speaker 0: Well, no more outtakes like that.
Speaker 1: The only outtakes we ever had.
Speaker 0: I think the real thing is that we do stuff that could be considered outtakes, but you don't take it out.
Speaker 0: So it's not really an outtake.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, we've almost cut nothing out of the show.
Speaker 1: anyway at this point I cut out, you know The the 20 seconds of silence from when I hit record until one of us says something and I cut out the.
Speaker 1: so are we?
Speaker 1: Done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're done at the end.
Speaker 1: I Guess I could save that for a year and then put them all in a row next year for the DVD - so we're done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're done.
Speaker 0: We're done.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to bed.
Speaker 0: Yep Scott.
Speaker 1: You're making the post fuck you click.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: Okay, so got a news action.
Speaker 1: I've got a news from the year.
Speaker 0: I was born But that's not news.
Speaker 0: then is it?
Speaker 1: it's not news.
Speaker 1: It's geek nights great.
Speaker 1: Actually, I bring it up because it's on dig.
Speaker 1: It's been all over dig.
Speaker 1: It's been all over Fark.
Speaker 1: It's on the internet again.
Speaker 1: and the thing is I have seen this come back on the internet every single year for the past five or six years at least and Despite that every time it comes around a lot of people haven't read it and don't realize the truth.
Speaker 1: You see I'll put it very very briefly Diamonds are not actually valuable.
Speaker 1: They're in fact quite common.
Speaker 1: Their worth is generated solely by restricted supply Coupled with intense marketing.
Speaker 1: the primary market of diamonds is the United States because the rest of the world long ago Realized that they're not really worth it.
Speaker 0: Well most of the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I mean they're Africa actually knows exactly how much they're worth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they know that they're worth a lot because they can sell them for a lot of money to idiots in this country, yeah But yet their diamonds are aplenty.
Speaker 0: you can go around the world and if you add up all the diamonds There's lots of them.
Speaker 0: There's a lot more diamonds than there is gold or platinum or silver or anything.
Speaker 0: There's shit tons of these things and they're not worth much.
Speaker 0: but De Beers is one company that gets a lot of diamonds and they put most of them in a vault thus artificially reducing the supply and then they heavily marketed them for many years.
Speaker 0: so that Get.
Speaker 0: not getting a diamond is unthinkable.
Speaker 0: If you're getting married or engaged or anything like that, you know, you must get one.
Speaker 0: Therefore they have artificially increased the demand a bajillion fold.
Speaker 0: and here you have it a bunch of idiots with too much money Spending them on useless common rocks.
Speaker 1: I mean quite seriously if you look at the history of Diamond-purchasing in the United States and compare it to when advertising efforts of De Beers began and the cartel and everything The there's pretty much a one-to-one Correlation between them marketing diamonds and diamonds selling and before that there was no tradition of diamonds being used for much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we think in 1800s people bought diamonds like when they got married.
Speaker 0: There was none of that shit.
Speaker 1: I mean they might have bought a really really cheap diamond like a poorly cut Really cheap thing that maybe cost him a week salary.
Speaker 1: if that and even then most people didn't.
Speaker 0: This whole wedding thing that you know, the whole diamond wedding ring Tradition is even a hundred years old.
Speaker 0: not even yeah face.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go through the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend if you don't know much about the diamond industry or you've ever considered purchasing a diamond That you read this article because I can safely say that I'll probably never in my life purchase a diamond on purpose.
Speaker 1: I mean if I really less it's in a computer motherboard.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I mean if I really needed a shiny useless rock I would buy one that was Manufactured and much cheaper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then you could choose the color.
Speaker 1: remember scientists can make diamonds straight up.
Speaker 1: You could just make them in a machine.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about like making something that looks like a diamond and feels like a diamond but isn't the time We're talking about making a diamond?
Speaker 0: it comes out.
Speaker 0: It is a dime.
Speaker 1: In fact, not only is it a diamond but it's perfect.
Speaker 1: It is absolutely flawless.
Speaker 1: It is better than any diamond you could ever find in the ground.
Speaker 1: You can make it whatever color you want can make whatever size you want cut it however you want It'll have no imperfections whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have a machine that they can just put some stuff in it.
Speaker 0: You know carbon.
Speaker 0: basically.
Speaker 0: wait and out will come a yellow diamond the size of your fist.
Speaker 1: Well, not quite your face.
Speaker 0: Well, they could if they wanted to but they don't.
Speaker 0: but I'm sure if they wanted to and they tried hard enough They can make one the size of your fist.
Speaker 1: Well, it really depends on the method.
Speaker 1: There are like four different machines that can make diamonds and they all work in different ways.
Speaker 1: They're all.
Speaker 1: they're all pretty cool.
Speaker 1: If you ever are bored.
Speaker 1: I highly reckon you read up about artificial diamonds artificial gem.
Speaker 0: There's a whole bunch of companies.
Speaker 0: I just don't remember any of their names right now.
Speaker 1: Genesis.
Speaker 1: I believe that's one of them.
Speaker 0: That's one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a whole bunch of them though.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's the best one.
Speaker 0: There's some better ones
Speaker 1: yeah, but I really if you don't know read this article and hopefully you'll realize that Purchasing a diamond is not an investment and it's not worth even a quarter of the money you paid for
Speaker 0: The other thing I did the only that last thing we didn't say about diamonds is that a lot of them when you buy them Down the chain.
Speaker 0: The money is actually going to very bad people.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean even aside from the fact that it's a poor investment and that they're not actually valuable a lot of diamonds are Pretty much mine solely based on human suffering.
Speaker 0: Well, they have a system where like diamonds are labeled and tracked and they have certificates and things.
Speaker 0: so you can buy one and be Sure that yours isn't an evil one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know where that came from.
Speaker 1: the diamond industry noticed that people were starting to argue against diamonds because they called them blood diamonds the diamonds that Basically poor Africans were forced to mind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know when people say conflict diamonds.
Speaker 0: That's what they're talking about.
Speaker 1: So the diamond industry decided to start making certified diamonds that they guarantee to us weren't mined in Under those conditions and for those reasons, yeah, and they sell them for more money.
Speaker 0: Yep, they do.
Speaker 0: But if they are certified you can be pretty sure that they're not blood diamonds, but if they're not certified.
Speaker 0: Probably some slave in Africa was treated poorly.
Speaker 0: It was forced to dig these diamonds out from the ground by an evil warlord who then used the money to buy a use The money to buy ak-47s for terrorists.
Speaker 0: and you just paid for those ak-47s.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah We just called a bunch of people in exchange.
Speaker 0: You got a useless rock now.
Speaker 1: It's not totally useless.
Speaker 1: I mean you can cut small amounts of glass with it.
Speaker 0: Yes, but you can get a glass cutter for like 10 bucks at Home Depot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably less than 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: This is a much more expensive glass cutter and a far less effective far less effective than the Home Depot version.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I got I got some geek news here kind of geek news kind of I'm curious.
Speaker 0: so the Detroit Tigers?
Speaker 0: they have a relief pitcher named Joel Zumaia and Last year, you know the Detroit Tigers are in the World Series and before you get to the World Series If you're in the American League, like the Tigers are you have to play in the American League Championship Series, which they won.
Speaker 0: but He missed out on Like three games of the American League Championship Series.
Speaker 1: No, why Scott did he miss out on three games of the American?
Speaker 0: It hurt his team and they ended up not winning the World Series.
Speaker 0: You know, who knows if it would have turned things around if he was playing in those games.
Speaker 1: Oh a Michigan non hockey team choking at the last minute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway He didn't play in the games because his wrist hurt huh from pitching too much.
Speaker 0: I imagined Yeah, that's what you would think.
Speaker 0: No one even questioned it at the time.
Speaker 0: Maybe he was in the World Series months ago.
Speaker 1: Maybe he was training and he hurt himself.
Speaker 1: He threw one too hard.
Speaker 1: He was stretched wrong.
Speaker 1: He was lifting weights and he dropped one.
Speaker 0: Well, the first thing that's pretty sad is that he's younger than we are.
Speaker 0: He's 22.
Speaker 1: Ah, that's like when I see f1 drivers realize that they're actually young - yeah We're older than Fernando Alonso the world champion of Formula One who's got a bajillion dollars the video game pianist when we were all Hanging out with him.
Speaker 1: We're like, how old are you?
Speaker 1: and the number he told us was real sad.
Speaker 0: It was very sad.
Speaker 1: What do we do?
Speaker 1: we're 25. we do a podcast.
Speaker 1: yeah, I'm only 24.
Speaker 0: Yeah for like I'm still 24.
Speaker 1: like four weeks I am possibly one third to maybe one quarter of my life pass.
Speaker 0: Well, think about it in four weeks your insurance is gonna go down.
Speaker 1: My insurance is already pretty much nothing.
Speaker 0: It'll become negative then.
Speaker 1: I pay like ten bucks a month for car insurance.
Speaker 0: Anyway His wrist injury went away though, and he was fine in the World Series.
Speaker 0: But just now he had discovered the cause of his wrist injury.
Speaker 0: He played too much guitar hero now Perhaps a month ago.
Speaker 1: I would have said what that's stupid But having finally gotten a chance to play guitar heroes I have to say that I would probably be in a similar situation if I was a star pitcher for the Detroit Tigers and had Access to both guitar heroes and the World Series
Speaker 0: plus.
Speaker 0: He's a relief pitcher.
Speaker 0: All right, and he's a baseball player.
Speaker 0: He's got mad money's.
Speaker 0: what's he doing?
Speaker 0: You know when he sits around for the first seven innings of the game before it's his turn to do anything.
Speaker 1: Well after snorting the cocaine off of the hookers behind you play some fucking guitar heroes, bitch Man, guitar heroes is all shades of awesome and it was the thing that pushed us over the line of buying a ps2.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I think the other thing was I can get one for free with my Sony points Yeah, and then I'll buy.
Speaker 0: check this out.
Speaker 0: I've only ever had one credit card in my life.
Speaker 0: I got it in Sophomore year of college, you know because I wanted to buy stuff online.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to like get a line of credit and you know buy things without paying for them.
Speaker 0: I didn't care about that.
Speaker 0: I had plenty of money.
Speaker 0: Well plenty of money for what you know, I could afford.
Speaker 0: But I couldn't buy anything online without a credit card.
Speaker 0: I didn't have one.
Speaker 0: So rim says, you know, you can just go get one.
Speaker 0: You just fill out a form online and they'll mail you one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I had a credit card since I was like 14.
Speaker 0: So, yep so I went online and I said oh which one will I get?
Speaker 0: and I pretty much went to the first credit card website that Came up and there it was the Sony card.
Speaker 0: for as much as we hate Sony I have had a Sony credit card for like six years.
Speaker 1: It's the only credit card I've ever had and so far we've gotten a cheap TV and now a free ps2 out of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's uh, it's working out.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah consider But it's so funny.
Speaker 0: It's like I go to the Nintendo World Store.
Speaker 0: I don't own a single Sony video game system and I buy a Wii with the Sony card.
Speaker 1: Why didn't you buy a ps3?
Speaker 1: you could have flipped it on eBay for zero profit.
Speaker 0: Well, I would also gotten like how let's see if I bought a ps3 600 times three 18 I would have gotten like a hundred and eighty dollars worth of Sony points, huh?
Speaker 1: That would effectively been a hundred and eighty dollars off of ps3 Something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, what's so much a better deal?
Speaker 0: if I buy a plasma like a Sony LCD TV That's like two thousand dollars with my Sony card.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Why don't we do that?
Speaker 0: Because we don't need a TV like that and I don't have $2,000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you do.
Speaker 1: I saw your accounts.
Speaker 1: I looked at your finances a couple days ago.
Speaker 1: You've got that much money.
Speaker 1: So do I?
Speaker 0: yeah But I don't have that much money for an LCD TV.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna spend that money on rent food and stuff?
Speaker 1: Things of the day?
Speaker 0: I Got an awesome thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, do you now I do?
Speaker 1: Well, what is it?
Speaker 0: Well in it of it itself, it is not so awesome.
Speaker 0: You see what it is.
Speaker 0: It is a trailer for an upcoming documentary called nerdcore for life.
Speaker 0: Someone is making a documentary about nerdcore hip-hop.
Speaker 0: And this is the trailer for said documentary.
Speaker 1: now that's either gonna be hilarious and awesome or Self aggrandizing and just totally lame.
Speaker 0: I don't really care about the actual documentary or the trailer.
Speaker 0: What I do care about is that when you watch this trailer you can see Examples of every geekery that you know, we're into like this DDR plane.
Speaker 0: There's they're playing a game of Arkham horror.
Speaker 0: There's some people role playing.
Speaker 0: there's some people LARP in this.
Speaker 0: people cosplay.
Speaker 0: these people reading manga is people playing video games.
Speaker 0: It's everything.
Speaker 0: so it's just.
Speaker 0: you don't even need the audio on when you watch this thing.
Speaker 0: you just watch it and it's this great montage of mosaic of geekeries that is quite Impressive to behold and awe-inspiring All right.
Speaker 1: so in Japan They like to pull pranks on people as parts of pretty much all their daytime TV.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell It seems like every show on TV in Japan at least shows that end up being put on YouTube over here in the US are either anime or talk shows with guys dressed up as women pulling pranks on people and yelling at famous rock stars
Speaker 0: and hard gay
Speaker 1: and Hard gay is the category all by himself.
Speaker 0: He is indeed anyway.
Speaker 1: Now the other thing I've noticed about Japan over the years is that you can pull Pranks that border on Sadistic and yet there's no problem with this.
Speaker 1: You don't get sued.
Speaker 0: I think almost everybody that taught the porta-potty the toilet seat.
Speaker 1: That's probably that's my favorite prank ever.
Speaker 1: Even I like that even more than the skeleton on the motorcycle.
Speaker 0: No, I think the skeleton on the motorcycles the best one Vile corneas.
Speaker 1: But I think the toilet one is probably the funniest to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah But this one here is not only I'm pretty sure this is real like they actually did this to some guy Because otherwise the guy acting like the guy who they got in this prank is a great actor because that is the perfect Representation of the oh shit.
Speaker 1: I'm going to die face basic.
Speaker 1: They tricked this guy I don't know how I don't understand Japanese and I heard like one or two words that I might have understood But I've gathered that they tricked him into getting into this cab.
Speaker 1: Like take this cab will take you where we need to go for whatever like the attractive.
Speaker 1: So he gets in this cab and he takes off.
Speaker 0: He's not wearing a seat buck.
Speaker 1: He's a dumbass taxi driver is uh Driving a little crazily.
Speaker 1: There's a camera hidden camera in the taxi so we can see Exactly what's going on in there?
Speaker 1: Furthermore?
Speaker 1: There are cameras along the route where you can see what the taxi is doing Right away.
Speaker 1: It peels out starts drifting around Spinning out the guy's starting to really freak out.
Speaker 0: Then I'd freak out would you.
Speaker 1: then he really starts going fast like really fast and there's these Construction guys in the middle of the road and the guy in the backslide pointing like there's construction guys.
Speaker 1: There's construction And he just like bowls right where he's about to hit him and he knocks the car up at an angle and drives on two wheels for a while Which it can be done in many cars.
Speaker 0: I saw this great video the other day.
Speaker 0: Oh, man If I'd make it a thing that maybe next week of some guys in Iraq stolen SUV And they pops it up onto two tires and they're driving it around.
Speaker 0: And I was.
Speaker 0: I saw that video and I said there's nothing wrong with Iraq.
Speaker 0: It's all good over there Everything's cool.
Speaker 1: See my general philosophy on people is that while a lot of people are really kind of dumb and a lot of people are Really kind of mean in general.
Speaker 1: There are cool people everywhere in the world even in the shittiest part of Darfur.
Speaker 1: There's some kid who plays punch-for-punch with this other kid and just whales on him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a kid who does some hotfoot somewhere.
Speaker 1: There's Always cool kids no matter how bad the situation is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just watch city of God if you don't believe it.
Speaker 1: Oh city of God, which is a semi almost kind of maybe based on a somewhat true story Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so he pops it back down and the guy's freaking out and they have this conversation Which I think amounts to you should probably put on your seat belts and the guy puts on his seat belts.
Speaker 1: So then the cab continues going and I can't really ruin it.
Speaker 1: Let's just say that all hell breaks loose and it ends with them actually crashing the cab.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well they they drive to sort of this pre set up area with all sorts of with Hazard explosions.
Speaker 1: the car catches on fire the doors fall.
Speaker 0: Oh they had some field and they set up a bunch of hazards in the field and the guy takes the car to the field and Drives through all the hazards and the cars on fire and shit For real like really on fire.
Speaker 0: The guy's totally freaking out as should be expected and the meanwhile the cab drivers driving totally legit just like The cab driver is clearly a professional driver and should drive some awesome race cars or something.
Speaker 0: Maybe he's a professional like movie stunt driver, which it just is good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know though knowing Japan's record in f1.
Speaker 1: Oh super agree Maybe that's it.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's what's-his-name from super Gary.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: I know what he looks like.
Speaker 1: What does he look like?
Speaker 0: Little tiny Japanese man.
Speaker 0: Okay, who's much younger than that guy?
Speaker 1: But see this is the cut.
Speaker 1: This is what I love about Japan that you can do this sort of thing and you can get away with it.
Speaker 1: You can film it and you can put it on TV.
Speaker 1: If that happened in America I think everyone involved would have been sued and at least a few people would be in jail right now Probably definitely lots of suing going on and there was no way it would get on TV or anything.
Speaker 0: It really kind of sucks was?
Speaker 1: it doesn't seem like in America.
Speaker 1: like in America You see a lot of ads for like prank videos and now you see him on YouTube a lot.
Speaker 1: All the best pranks seem to come out of Europe South America specifically from Mexico in Japan.
Speaker 0: However You know what else I saw today, you know a hobo fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah bum fights you mean bum fights That's right, which was actually pretty horrible It is.
Speaker 0: but you know, I don't get I don't deny the guy the right to make it so Apparently he was on dr.
Speaker 0: Phil, right?
Speaker 0: So really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I watched this clip where dr Phil has the guy on.
Speaker 1: he says this is terrible But the guy who made it or the guy who fought in it like the main hobo What do you mean the main hobo?
Speaker 1: There's one hobo that was kind of like the poster child of bum fights.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, this is the guy the guy like the president the founder of bum fights.
Speaker 1: Well that that's quite a life if your job title is.
Speaker 1: I was the president and founder of bum fights.
Speaker 0: He seemed like actually a pretty smart guy.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz it's the same idea we had.
Speaker 1: he just didn't take it far enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the barge on international waters with the helicopter escape and the gladiatorial arena.
Speaker 0: Yep He just paid bums 20 bucks to pull their teeth out in video and we should do a show on that.
Speaker 1: We'll outline our idea and maybe someone will do it.
Speaker 0: In fact, we could do that show right now.
Speaker 1: We could because that could be our first contest whoever does that?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so they dr Phil shows like you know this like he first he disparages the guy and then he shows like a video clip that Explains to everyone and shows them like what bum fights is and everything.
Speaker 1: and then wait What if you don't know from the name of bum fights what bum fights is?
Speaker 0: you've got issues Yeah, and then right the guy's sitting there and he's getting ready to talk and then dr.
Speaker 0: Phil is just like yeah I don't want to talk to you.
Speaker 0: go away What yeah, basically like.
Speaker 0: I was actually kind of pissed cuz while you know The bum fight guy is obviously taking advantage of bums, you know Which is not so good to make lots of money off of them and he gives them like 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: We should be giving them a lot more.
Speaker 0: Um Dr.
Speaker 0: Phil was just kind of like yeah, I don't even want what it seemed like.
Speaker 0: Dr Phil didn't have an argument against the guy because the guy did seem smart.
Speaker 0: He did seem like he was gonna successfully.
Speaker 0: You know hold his own against dr.
Speaker 0: Phil, but dr.
Speaker 0: Phil was just like yeah, I don't want to talk to you.
Speaker 0: go away Sort of like, you know, like.
Speaker 0: I don't want to promote whatever you're selling even though he just did two seconds ago.
Speaker 0: And then the guy the only words he gets in is you know What are you yelling at me for taking advantage of people?
Speaker 0: all you do is drag people up on your TV show and show their Problems to the world taking advantage of them.
Speaker 0: and I was like hell.
Speaker 1: Oh Maximum burnage.
Speaker 0: and then dr.
Speaker 0: Phil is just like no go away.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk to you because I don't think he had an argument.
Speaker 0: I think he really not.
Speaker 0: I think he saw himself in that guy.
Speaker 0: Well, they remind God got upset reminds me very much of the definitely plan to not talk to the guy in the first place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah people do that Remember captain?
Speaker 1: shut up.
Speaker 1: Shut up.
Speaker 0: They did I think they realized like they saw this bum fight thing and they wanted to put it down in their show.
Speaker 0: But then when they actually found out the guy in charge was like semi intelligent They realized they couldn't argue with them.
Speaker 0: So they said I got it.
Speaker 0: Well bring up on the show and then just tell him we don't want to talk and make security.
Speaker 0: make him leave.
Speaker 1: Hahaha Yeah, that sure showed him.
Speaker 1: Yeah So Today we weren't sure what to do the show on not because we don't have enough ideas because we were talking about our idea with The barge.
Speaker 1: you want to do that?
Speaker 0: No, I don't know we could.
Speaker 1: I think we could.
Speaker 1: well Well, we could do a show on the barge idea.
Speaker 0: Oh great.
Speaker 0: You want to it's up to you.
Speaker 1: It's up to you.
Speaker 0: I'm not it.
Speaker 1: It's all you not it.
Speaker 1: I'm out Alright, see we were gonna do the zombie show.
Speaker 1: We're all set to do this.
Speaker 1: the much requested.
Speaker 1: We were not all set.
Speaker 1: I was no you I was all set.
Speaker 1: I could do the zombie show.
Speaker 1: Now anytime you come up to me and you ask me to do the next part of the zombie series.
Speaker 1: I'm ready I can just do it.
Speaker 0: No, you're just all talk.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't be saying that if you actually had to do it.
Speaker 1: But I'm all set to do it.
Speaker 1: I know I was all set to do it.
Speaker 1: In fact, I suggested we do it.
Speaker 0: now Stop trying to like What's it called?
Speaker 0: Called white pander told listeners be like, you know trying to get them all for you and against me or whatever.
Speaker 1: But I'm really ready to do the zombie show.
Speaker 1: You think I can't talk for another 40 minutes about zombies.
Speaker 0: on short I don't think you remember the stuff that we see.
Speaker 0: the thing is the first show.
Speaker 1: we talked about intelligence gathering.
Speaker 0: There are things that we said in the first show like that.
Speaker 0: We're just specifically saying what we're gonna say in the second show and I forget what those things are.
Speaker 1: No, we outlined different shows we would do in the future like the different segments.
Speaker 1: We need to cover.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we definitely need to listen the first show again before doing the second one.
Speaker 0: Nah.
Speaker 1: Yeah We don't listen to geek nights.
Speaker 0: I do sometimes rarely.
Speaker 1: I listen to it when we interview someone.
Speaker 0: I didn't even listen to the most recent one I did on the way to work.
Speaker 1: Okay Anyway, yeah, if you didn't listen to yesterday's geek nights last night.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah good show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well listen that one All right.
Speaker 1: So I was gonna say well your options are and lay them out.
Speaker 1: But then I realized there isn't actually an audience here unless you count Kara Yamato Edward Alaric and Alan Shehzar Luigi and toad and Bato And Lupin and taiko sitting on my desk looking at me and foo foos down there.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, and a puppy and fujiko You got too much shit on your desk.
Speaker 1: I got a lot of stuff on my desk.
Speaker 0: Okay You want to talk about the barge?
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 1: Or do we just keep mentioning the barge and just keep talking?
Speaker 1: keep talking?
Speaker 1: Don't actually ever put it in the show.
Speaker 0: So let's do the barge because it'll be quick and I can go to bed sooner.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Now before we begin I would like to say that if you were curious as to whether or not we are serious about this idea You shouldn't need to ask that question and I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: Yeah now we come up with.
Speaker 0: we often come up with crazy and sometimes less crazy ideas for ways to Make money start businesses not have to go to work nine to five, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now be it.
Speaker 1: bear in mind that if we had enough capital to just do one of our not crazy ideas We'd probably be rich already, but that's how money works.
Speaker 1: If you have money, it's trivial to get more money.
Speaker 1: If you don't have money not so easy to get more money.
Speaker 0: No, not as easy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, not without some form of trickery.
Speaker 0: well, you can always go into debt to get a bunch of money and Hopefully if it works out you'll be able to pay it back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but calculating that there's no way I can maintain my lifestyle If I borrowed that much money, nope, definitely not and I'm not gonna give up my lifestyle because it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yep So one of the crazy ideas that come up with over the years is the barge.
Speaker 1: now The barge was spawned in great detail over the course of about four hours One night at RIT and then expounded upon over the next several weeks until the idea was solid.
Speaker 0: basically what it comes down to is People like to see people fight.
Speaker 1: I mean this goes back to even like ancient Rome What do people like to do?
Speaker 1: like to see chariot races in the hippodrome?
Speaker 1: They like to fight with each other in the stands of the hippodrome and they like to watch gladiators Kill people and or animals.
Speaker 0: people like hockey people like football When a fight breaks out at baseball or basketball or anything like that where it's you know, not common people are all standing up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah now bear in mind thing is popular.
Speaker 0: even pro wrestling where people pretend to fight It's very popular that we don't want to bring animals into this.
Speaker 1: This is just people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I wouldn't want to see a guy versus a puppy.
Speaker 0: Well, I'd like to see a lion eat a guy.
Speaker 1: I Only would like to see a fight with animals if the animal has an actual chance of winning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll say this very a guy versus squirrel is not good, but a guy versus a monkey.
Speaker 1: That's awesome if a bullfight had.
Speaker 1: if whenever a bull gets a bullfighter in a bullfight like actually gets him I Cheer because those bulls are put through a lot.
Speaker 1: That's really not worth it.
Speaker 1: And those guys totally deserve it.
Speaker 0: That's my only problem with bullfighting is that it's not actually fighting the bull.
Speaker 0: It's just like the ceremony of killing a bull.
Speaker 0: It should be fucking fight the bull.
Speaker 1: the bull can win and if the bull wins you give him however many lady bulls He wants.
Speaker 1: you put him out to pasture for the rest of his life.
Speaker 0: Well, no, he has to fight again to become the champion.
Speaker 1: Well once he's the champion you put him out to pasture.
Speaker 0: Just one fight doesn't make you the champion.
Speaker 0: All right, that's all I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can't make him fight - it doesn't matter if you're a person or a bull or a giant You know, you got to fight more than one fight to be the grand champ.
Speaker 0: So the idea of the barge step one acquire a barge.
Speaker 0: see that.
Speaker 1: remember that this idea is crazy Among the front row crew is fairly legendary And in fact people that we haven't talked to in a long time if we make contact with them again Well almost invariably bring up.
Speaker 1: So how's the barge coming?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: is it?
Speaker 0: I don't remember anyone ever bringing that up.
Speaker 1: I've been asked that in the last six months twice Wow Okay by people who are still in Rochester.
Speaker 1: All right or in the Rochester.
Speaker 0: So you get this barge.
Speaker 0: you put the barge in international waters where anything goes.
Speaker 1: now before you put the barge Out there, you have to prepare it.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 1: We need a large arena area that has pretty much on the main deck of the barge.
Speaker 1: It'll have.
Speaker 1: you know, we could put obstacles in it or not.
Speaker 1: It'll be.
Speaker 1: you know, we can customize it.
Speaker 1: but it's a big arena and there are low fences along the edges So it's not easy to fall out.
Speaker 1: But yet you can throw someone over the edge if you want to.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: Second to that we have a Very secure hold where we can barricade weapons and barricade people and ourselves in case things go awry.
Speaker 0: Yeah any combatants of any sort need to not be near each other before the actual time of fighting because they might try to poison each other or Something like that before the fight to guarantee victory.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't have any of that.
Speaker 0: Everything's got to be you know up and up.
Speaker 1: more importantly.
Speaker 1: They cannot be near us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do not want a 700 pound man with the power to crush my skull with his pinky finger To be in the room next to me when I am holding the millions of dollars that he wants.
Speaker 0: So we'll have a special.
Speaker 0: Oh, you didn't read that volume of death note yet style way to exchange money with these guys Without them being able to get us.
Speaker 1: Yeah Congratulations.
Speaker 1: You won go to the back to get your money kick sploosh Exactly So the next step.
Speaker 1: we also need a Raised area which is basically where the if this were Roman times the Emperor would sit.
Speaker 1: replace the Emperor with myself Scott and maybe 10 people who have paid us a lot of money for the privilege of watching these fights live as opposed to over the fee and all on the all four sides.
Speaker 1: HDTV cameras and last and certainly not least a helipad with enough room for a helicopter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, two helicopters just in case and speed boats ready for us to escape should The worst come to worst meaning pretty much anything that can happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right step two We got the barge.
Speaker 0: We got the helicopters.
Speaker 0: You got people on it.
Speaker 0: We got everything set up.
Speaker 0: Next we go and we find people who are sane and willing to fight to the death.
Speaker 0: Then we get them to sign contracts saying yes, I am sane.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I am willing to fight to the death.
Speaker 1: I mean, we'll go straight up.
Speaker 1: We don't want to take advantage of people.
Speaker 1: We will have psychologists on hand to evaluate people to make sure that they are of their right.
Speaker 0: It's no fun.
Speaker 0: If we get like some nutty bum who's like, yeah, I'll do it It's.
Speaker 0: it's only cool if it's you know, someone who's like a serious fighter, you know Who's gonna you know actually fight and not just be kind of stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah We don't know if they really want to do it and we don't want someone who's coerced into it like a mafia that forces a In to try to win money for him or like a single dad who's hard on his luck and really needs the money.
Speaker 1: We don't want that.
Speaker 1: we want people with no family no friends who are badass and Willing to put their lives on the line for fame and fortune and actually enjoy this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we want like a like a bounty hunter who thinks he's so badass.
Speaker 0: or we want like Like some kung fu master who thinks no one can take him like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: That's what we're looking for.
Speaker 1: Yeah The kind of people who if fight clubs were real would be in them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm We got to get those people we got to get them to agree we bring them out to the barge we set up a little tournament and They fight to the death.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or to you know when they go to surrender, I mean if you surrender then it's okay We'll protect you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it'll be real.
Speaker 0: fighting on video Which we will sell for lots of money on the internet.
Speaker 1: now, they'll all be different.
Speaker 1: some of them Let's be.
Speaker 1: they'll be you know, wearing loincloths and they'll fight in the old wrestling style.
Speaker 1: Some of them, you know knives one of them will fry be.
Speaker 1: bring whatever you can carry on to the barge.
Speaker 1: That isn't a gun.
Speaker 0: But we don't want any guns and no rockets because then they can get us see the rule.
Speaker 1: The first rule is no explosives.
Speaker 1: No guns.
Speaker 0: Yeah arrows are cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll have a little like Pope shields.
Speaker 0: It'll be okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because we.
Speaker 1: not only do we not want to die, but we don't want our rich benefactors to die.
Speaker 0: No Those rich benefactors who are paying a lot of money to sit on that barge and watch people fight to the death live.
Speaker 1: See the other key aspect of this is the satellite uplink the live pay-per-view Broadcasts.
Speaker 0: Oh great.
Speaker 1: That will be secure.
Speaker 1: I mean it'll basically the way we would do it.
Speaker 1: it would be broadcast all over the earth via satellites or Various may possibly illegal radio waves doesn't really matter how we do it and we'd encrypt it and you could pay us for a decryption key.
Speaker 1: Hmm or another way we could do it is simply sell DVDs.
Speaker 0: That's I was thinking we just sell DVDs.
Speaker 0: That's the easiest way.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think there's a certain appeal and people seeing it live.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course The biggest money would probably still come from very rich people who would pay to be Helicoptered out there to watch it live do whatever they want.
Speaker 0: Eventually.
Speaker 0: It might need like a second barge with like a jumbotron Because There'll just be too many people who want to and then we'll charge like a billion dollars to sit on the barge with us.
Speaker 1: I don't think we could charge a billion dollars charge a billion dollars for a billion dollars.
Speaker 0: You could start your own barge Yeah, but you wouldn't have our bums on the bar.
Speaker 1: See the key is we really have to get a lot of showmanship involved.
Speaker 1: I have to hire some experts in this field to you know, make sure that the drama is there The fights are good.
Speaker 1: Make sure it doesn't drag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we definitely have to build personalities around the guys who don't die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we need people like the people in running man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a good one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly like that Except unlike running man.
Speaker 1: We won't be faking it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and unlike running man It won't be people who are perfectly innocent that we arrested and forced to be in running man.
Speaker 0: It'll be people who want to be in running man versus people who want to be in running man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want the kind of people will come up and say oh, yeah fight to the death.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's what we're looking for.
Speaker 1: Now of course we.
Speaker 1: there are numerous logistical concerns first and foremost pirates.
Speaker 1: International waters are a scary place.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna have to hire Blackwater to guard our barge, which you know, what?
Speaker 1: Isn't that expensive?
Speaker 0: No, not real not considering the money that we'd probably make by selling all those DVDs.
Speaker 1: And even if not Blackwater, I'm sure we can hire some security firm with a couple of small gunboats Maybe a small cruiser or something just to go around us.
Speaker 1: Make sure no pirates come.
Speaker 0: Alright problem number two Navies.
Speaker 1: Well, I can't imagine I mean what Navy is going to spend its resources to go out to the middle of the Atlantic Ocean?
Speaker 1: well, probably the Pacific Ocean, yeah and Stop us from having a bunch of dumb guys fight to the death.
Speaker 0: But if someone is really pissed at us for what we were doing They might send a Navy or a Coast Guard out to bother us.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is a lot of the countries I could see coming to bother us would probably rather ignore us or possibly sell our Thing to their people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some countries would but like if we got too close to the u.s.
Speaker 0: Even if you're technically in international waters I don't think that they would have a problem like, you know plus the people a lot of people in the u.s And protest and try to get them to do this to send like a Coast Guard boat to shoot at us or something To make us move or you know, try to fuck us up.
Speaker 0: Yeah now there are ways around that I mean we could do it in Antarctica and it would be awesome because they would be freezing cold.
Speaker 1: No, it would just be two guys in like triple fat goose Coats with hell hats and mittens on kind of padding at each other for an hour.
Speaker 0: I'll be the best we got to do that.
Speaker 0: It's only in Antarctica the barge nice barge.
Speaker 1: That'd be a decent fight.
Speaker 1: We have one fight.
Speaker 0: We're padding each other.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like you could take the clothes off, but will you freeze before you kill the other guy?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and even if you take yours off how you get a punch through his padding Can't even snap his neck and no knives or anything.
Speaker 1: No knives.
Speaker 0: Maybe I think it might come down to teeth.
Speaker 0: I Don't know, you know if I was in that fight, I would grow my nails out and get him like doubly thick.
Speaker 1: How are you gonna get your nails doubly thick?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's got to be ways to make your nails thicker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's diseases that do it.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: I Think the best way to win that fight is to cheat.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: How would you cheat?
Speaker 0: sneak a knife in?
Speaker 1: Sneak a stiletto in with poison on the tip.
Speaker 1: Whoo or syringe?
Speaker 0: Hey, you know what though, you know a good way to cheat.
Speaker 0: It's like having a poison tooth like a tooth where like it's a fake tooth.
Speaker 0: It breaks poison comes out.
Speaker 0: Just bite the other guy.
Speaker 1: Uh, you'd probably poison yourself.
Speaker 0: No, cuz the tooth would pop out of your mouth after you bit the guy and stay in the other guy You have to bite through the padding.
Speaker 0: Well, you could bite him in like the nose or the face.
Speaker 1: the face will be covered.
Speaker 0: the house He can.
Speaker 1: they see the ski mask ski goggles.
Speaker 1: Oh you could get that off Yeah, but then he got yours off.
Speaker 1: then he pokes you in the eye.
Speaker 0: I'd poke him in here.
Speaker 1: He poked you in the eye first while you were trying to bite him.
Speaker 0: I don't know It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: This is why we're not the fighters.
Speaker 0: We are the fight through the Don Kings if you will.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, we're the.
Speaker 1: we're the corrupt emperors exactly.
Speaker 1: but in terms of Navy's and all that We really have to I mean any Navy that came after us international waters.
Speaker 1: Hopefully we could appeal to the UN.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the UN's really gonna protect some guys who are having fights to the death on their barge.
Speaker 0: Well, you see the thing is they should.
Speaker 1: cuz international waters you can do whatever you want out there Even fight to the death.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you everyone saw that episode of the Simpsons.
Speaker 0: Going to broadcast major league baseball games with only Oral consent is not express written consent.
Speaker 1: So aside from the political issue of Navy's which we have some solutions for But it would really depend on what we I mean, maybe we could make a deal with like North Korea.
Speaker 1: Just make it with Sealand Sealands not so powerful.
Speaker 1: They don't have so much of a navy.
Speaker 1: They've got like one boat.
Speaker 0: They have a helicopter.
Speaker 1: If anything we get some country to back us or at least to provide protection.
Speaker 1: Or Maybe we get letters of mark And then we become pirates and forget the barge all together the barges that see.
Speaker 1: this is the beauty the idea one.
Speaker 1: We have the illegal fights, which is the first time we do that.
Speaker 1: They're not illegal if they're international waters Well, they're illegal in all the countries of origin.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah But we do them in the first time.
Speaker 1: people probably wouldn't realize where we were what we were doing if that was too late.
Speaker 1: By the time the Navy gets there the fights are over.
Speaker 1: The barge is empty.
Speaker 1: We've left with our money.
Speaker 1: We need to buy new parts the next year, even if we didn't want to bother with the fights at all.
Speaker 1: It was a total scam.
Speaker 1: once the rich people show up.
Speaker 1: We just hold him hostage Take their money.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah It's actually all a trick.
Speaker 0: all those guys that they thought were gonna fight each other to the death are actually just really strong guys.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna hold these rich people hostage.
Speaker 1: or better the rich people have to fight their way out.
Speaker 1: They either have to buy or fight their way off the barge just like the second chapter of Shadowrun for the SNES.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like You can fight the arena or you can give me a bunch of money.
Speaker 0: No, no, no the the what?
Speaker 0: What the most dangerous game?
Speaker 1: I remember reading that in like.
Speaker 0: I think I read that in middle school in high school like three times.
Speaker 1: I read it was assigned in three different classes in high school.
Speaker 1: And then it was assigned again in college.
Speaker 0: It was assigned in college.
Speaker 1: Yeah in that bullshit writing in lit class that they make everyone at RIT take no matter what.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: Was it a sign?
Speaker 1: It wasn't.
Speaker 1: yeah, I didn't read it.
Speaker 0: cuz middle school high school college.
Speaker 0: what the fuck is up with that story?
Speaker 0: The teachers must just freakin love that thing.
Speaker 1: well, the the lesson that was used for in two of the three instances where I had to read it was kind of this real literature versus escapist literature or something to that effect and they were like is this escapist or not?
Speaker 1: and The answer always given was yes, it's escapist because the end isn't actually in any way profound.
Speaker 1: It's just a twist.
Speaker 1: The argument was much greater than that and I didn't really care because I don't care either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, is anyone out there read most dangerous game or been assigned most dangerous game in a class?
Speaker 1: Yeah with the repass for the hounds at the end and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was the most comfortable bed He'd ever slept in.
Speaker 0: that's where I learned about the that trap where the we got a tree and it swings down and then Smashes you together with the other tree.
Speaker 0: Ah What's that trap called where the two trees come down on the road?
Speaker 1: Called but I learned about it from that book as well.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Okay Yes, anyway, so see now we've got bulk.
Speaker 1: Not only can we I mean say we have the fights anyway.
Speaker 1: so now we make the money from the fights we make the money from the ransoms and maybe we just kill those people anywhere make them fight and then we sell the special edition of.
Speaker 1: Here's Bill Gates having to fight this this dude to the death.
Speaker 0: Yeah Here's Bill Gates getting eaten by a lion.
Speaker 0: or people really wanted to see what's-his-face get hit by killed by a stingray Even though it wasn't real.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it was real but even though it wasn't on purpose like, you know Well, there was that one video that was that wasn't it but it was fake and it was obviously fake after you watch it.
Speaker 1: But so many people clicked on it on YouTube because they thought it was the real thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah So imagine if we actually have like a video like here's a dude being eaten by a lion for real
Speaker 1: plus Imagine if Bill Gates wins
Speaker 0: Man,
Speaker 1: oh that not only would that was that DVD sell for so much money
Speaker 0: Why there was just a video the other day of like an alligator eating some dude's arm that I saw and that was all Over you too.
Speaker 1: I was more impressed with the video of the guy who set his pants on fire and then screamed about it and why he did It to himself.
Speaker 0: That's different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but people still want to see that stuff.
Speaker 0: They do they do.
Speaker 0: it gets a lot of visits.
Speaker 1: Now the other concern and this is an important one is how to protect ourselves from the very dangerous people that are all over this barge.
Speaker 0: The answer is that why I have four words Guns, lots of guns.
Speaker 0: you see one.
Speaker 1: We're in this raised platform with some sort of mesh screen or maybe a Pope shield to yield Mounted right there and probably mounted on the other side of the boat as well would be probably Vulcan cannon.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah That's that's way too much.
Speaker 1: But oh, yeah I learned from advanced wars the point of Vulcan cannon at a human being.
Speaker 1: that's the end.
Speaker 0: There's nothing.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't care how many infantry you have one Vulcan.
Speaker 0: This turns you all.
Speaker 0: it's like pudding.
Speaker 1: Well, unless they have mechs, but we don't need to worry about mechs.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think they're gonna bring mechs.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna bring if a guy shows up.
Speaker 0: No The fucking can probably work against navies too because they don't expect us to have that.
Speaker 0: and like they'll send up a little Navy boat.
Speaker 1: But no, they'll send up a Coast Guard speedboat.
Speaker 1: Like what are you guys up to?
Speaker 0: Turn it into dust.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what they'll probably?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'd shoot at the coast guy.
Speaker 1: You mean they'll probably listen to reason.
Speaker 0: A funny joke.
Speaker 0: No, they'll listen to money also in bribes.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 1: We can bribe people cuz we'll have all this money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, they'll also listen to reason.
Speaker 1: But yeah crowd control is key cuz we don't want any trouble no other than the trouble that we're expecting
Speaker 0: The on-purpose trouble not the accident trouble, of
Speaker 1: course There's also the issue of how do we go back home after it's over because there's probably gonna be Some sort of warrant for our arrest in America.
Speaker 0: live on the barge.
Speaker 1: Well either that or we don't actually reveal who we are.
Speaker 1: We wear those cool We dressed like in black shrouds and we wear those cool masks with the long hook noses.
Speaker 0: Well now that we've made this podcast where they think the idea is shot then, isn't it?
Speaker 1: It could conceivably be two other guys Will be like the blue man group.
Speaker 1: So one day it's me and Scott one day It's Alex and one of our listeners one day.
Speaker 1: It's my mom and Scott's mom.
Speaker 1: You don't know who's doing it.
Speaker 0: Somehow I think that if it happened and then someone found this podcast Describing exactly the thing that's happening.
Speaker 0: They would know it was us.
Speaker 0: hence And when they come to look for us and we're not there and they notice that we've left the country.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well one stunt doubles To in the light in the spirit of the second most recent Perry Bible Fellowship entitled Robin Hood.
Speaker 1: I hereby announced the first geek nights contest.
Speaker 1: if you Successfully form the barge and profit from it and give us 50% of the gross profit Well, the net profits will be nice.
Speaker 1: the net profits you win.
Speaker 0: What do they win?
Speaker 1: They win Awesome.
Speaker 0: Go be a winner.
Speaker 1: I'll give him this little statue of Edward Elric that I got in front of me.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, that's so worth it.
Speaker 0: They don't make those things anymore.
Speaker 0: Actually, I think they still do.
Speaker 0: they're like five bucks.
Speaker 0: But no, that's so rare and valuable.
Speaker 0: You totally want it.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm not giving him my bottle.
Speaker 0: No, no, you can't give can't give up Otto.
Speaker 0: No way.
Speaker 0: Do they have to like trade your whole barge for that?
Speaker 1: And I'll include this lovely Ubuntu CD Because those aren't free.
Speaker 1: No, they're not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what do you cause?
Speaker 1: a lot of money actually be surprised?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh and I get this torn up check.
Speaker 0: Oh Made out to made out to cash for one barge.
Speaker 1: Actually, this check is made out to void and it's ripped in half.
Speaker 0: You can't buy ten barges.
Speaker 1: You can't for ten checks.
Speaker 0: Show over.
Speaker 1: no This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.