Speaker 1: It's Monday September 25th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about all the licensing issues of free software.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, we've survived the concert on Friday.
Speaker 0: It wasn't very difficult to survive not at all.
Speaker 1: There was a lot less pain than I expected and a lot less head banging and a lot less moshing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was expecting like some awesome mosh action, you know.
Speaker 0: But the last time I've had that was at the enter WK concert, which is like three years ago.
Speaker 1: So, you know, the music wasn't really conducive.
Speaker 1: It was more just good kind of nightwish style.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll have to wait until this, you know, some maybe punk rock concerts to go to or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we saw Epica and Camelot.
Speaker 1: Camelot by the way was badass.
Speaker 1: They were indeed the ass of bad and we found this new band that we really like called meta docks.
Speaker 0: They're okay.
Speaker 1: Well, they were great except that three almost every song they sang was something something something into the fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not too hot on the lyrics yeah, but at least the lead singer had a really good voice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it kind of surprised me.
Speaker 0: He reminded me of the head guy from entertainment system.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah kind of looked like him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna see them but that's that's later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we also saw operettica and I guess their CDs are better than the live performances.
Speaker 0: Yeah that lady sounded like she knew how to sing at least better than us and The guys playing music seemed like they knew how to play but it just didn't sound so hot and no one was really into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: What do you get?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a leader band.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and lady was pregnant.
Speaker 0: Maybe when she's not pregnant she sings better.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the if that affects it at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they just didn't really have a stage presence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely lacking in the.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean compare that to Roman skills to Epica, which I'm not going to mention exactly.
Speaker 1: what made the stage presence awesome Was awesome Alright.
Speaker 0: so speaking of you know entertainment system There is a convention in Utica New York, which is pretty much in the middle of New York State called sita con.
Speaker 0: It's the SUNY Institute of Technology anime club convention.
Speaker 1: It's basically if any of you remember we went to toro con.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be like that only bigger and more like a real con and actually three days long Yeah, and it's at SUNY IT in Utica, New York, October 6 7th and 8th.
Speaker 0: That's two weeks from now and We are going to be guests there along with a whole shit ton other anime podcasters and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yes I mean the people who are going to be guests with us are cool dudes and we know many of them.
Speaker 0: Yep, and basically we're doing a whole bunch of stuff there.
Speaker 0: I mean what we got like four or five panel.
Speaker 0: God, we're gonna run a game show wonder a game show an artist alley table.
Speaker 0: They basically let us take this convention over.
Speaker 1: so If you want to go to a badass convention that I don't know how much it costs.
Speaker 1: It's probably not.
Speaker 1: that doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: No matter how much the convention themselves screw up We're.
Speaker 0: we're doing such a large portion of this convention and the parts that we do We won't screw up.
Speaker 0: not that I'm saying they're gonna screw up because I talked to the guy You know the the con guy just a few minutes ago and he seemed like he knew what he was doing.
Speaker 0: pretty smart guy.
Speaker 1: Well, they've got.
Speaker 1: I mean, they've already got their act together more than several other conventions.
Speaker 1: I'm currently talking to.
Speaker 1: I won't name them to be polite, but they really don't have their acts together, but said Akon does.
Speaker 0: yes I mean they got Martin long the video game pianist who's pretty famous and they got Entertainment system and they got a whole bunch of podcasters and they definitely there.
Speaker 0: this conventions gonna be good.
Speaker 0: I can tell you know, so In the parts that we're gonna do I can guarantee will be awesome.
Speaker 0: So you should definitely come.
Speaker 1: if you're anywhere close come Yeah, and unlike places like Otakon it'll probably a lot easier to track us down and hang out with us at a con like this.
Speaker 0: yeah, and so if you want to get more info go to sitakon.com S?
Speaker 0: I T A C O N dot-com and You'll find all the goods there.
Speaker 1: We'll be plugging it all week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're gonna plug it all this week and probably next week and that'll be that I know.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about this before we do the news.
Speaker 0: just quick.
Speaker 0: that computer you got there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I now have two computers on my desk.
Speaker 0: So Remember I was yelling last week about my parents crazy computer and the power supplies.
Speaker 0: Well, I took the remnants of my parents computer and the only piece that didn't work was the motherboard.
Speaker 0: so I chucked that in the trash and I got a $20 motherboard from Newegg.
Speaker 0: It was a recertified motherboard from some no-name company.
Speaker 0: $20, okay $30 if you count the shipping.
Speaker 0: and yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: but it was a recertified piece of crap Motherboard.
Speaker 0: and let me tell you it's motherboard is a piece of crap.
Speaker 0: Like wow It's compared.
Speaker 0: I had to change the bus speed by moving jumpers around.
Speaker 0: It's so bad.
Speaker 0: But you know what it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it only has one drawback other than the fact that it's really really cheap and all the problems that come with things that tend To be really really cheap, but the onboard sound card is great playing back and making noise When you try to record with it, it basically can't record.
Speaker 1: It's so noisy.
Speaker 0: Well, I can record.
Speaker 0: it's just noisy.
Speaker 1: You haven't heard.
Speaker 1: I'll record something for you and play it back.
Speaker 1: It sounds like like the days before sound cards.
Speaker 0: anyway, the point is is that if you want a motherboard that Works perfectly in Linux the sound card the video card every part of this motherboard the network card Works in Linux perfectly with no problems.
Speaker 0: But and it's $20 now I wouldn't recommend it for you know everyday use anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because it's not, you know, it does.
Speaker 0: it is a $20 motherboard.
Speaker 0: it lacks a lot of the nice tease of the hundred dollar motherboards were used to from a bit and aces and all those other companies, but For 20 bucks if you got you know a chip that fits in it lying around.
Speaker 0: Hey, not bad.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised that it worked.
Speaker 0: I wasn't even expecting it to work and it did.
Speaker 1: that's amazing Yep, and also I'd like to say I mean we were bitching a lot about the Mac Mini we've got.
Speaker 1: but now that I've got this thing sitting here and While it was a less money than the Mac and it is a lot faster than the Mac It's about ten times bigger and four times louder.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though it's a pretty quiet relatively speaking to other computers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's quite compared to the jet engine That's in my old computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's for sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah Jet engine that was.
Speaker 1: I mean I turned off all those fans.
Speaker 1: the thing got right quiet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe time for the water cooler in the next one.
Speaker 1: No, no water cooling is mostly silly.
Speaker 1: Yes, I agree all I got to say about that.
Speaker 1: I'm in the I'm in the one big fan school of cooling though I got some non silly news here and I think this is pretty cool now.
Speaker 1: I'm sure all of you who are hip to the internet have seen this.
Speaker 1: This has been bantered about in the news for a long time and it has finally come.
Speaker 1: they finally exist.
Speaker 1: You can finally get your hypoallergenic cats.
Speaker 0: Great just that I want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they have genetically engineered cats that produce very little of the protein that causes the vast majority of cat allergy.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm not allergic to cats.
Speaker 0: I don't want cats.
Speaker 0: So I don't care.
Speaker 1: See I like cats.
Speaker 1: I'd rather have a dog.
Speaker 1: I really like dogs cats.
Speaker 1: I like kittens.
Speaker 1: of most cats I don't like but I've met some really nice cats in my day, but I don't know if I'm allergic to cats.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling I could become allergic to cats if I ever wanted a cat.
Speaker 0: theoretically anyone could become allergic to.
Speaker 1: well No, I mean, I think that I have a predisposition toward becoming allergic to a cat.
Speaker 0: I think you might.
Speaker 0: you are allergic to many other things.
Speaker 1: The thing is I'm really not allergic to many animals.
Speaker 1: I'm allergic mostly to molds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but what if the cats get moldy?
Speaker 1: if the cat gets moldy your price forgot to feed it.
Speaker 0: Maybe you'd be allergic to like the cat littery type stuff because a mold could get in there or something Possibly.
Speaker 1: I'm allergic to damn weird things Like.
Speaker 1: I'm not allergic to dogs despite the fact that I grew up with dogs or rats or anything.
Speaker 1: There's two birds and horses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought you said you weren't allergic to many animals birds and horses.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: Okay Yeah, I'm out of all the animals in the world - ain't so bad?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm allergic does basically nothing except poison ivy, but I don't know if that's really an allergy or if it's you know It's fucking poison.
Speaker 0: So what you know, it's a tough call.
Speaker 1: That's the trade-off.
Speaker 1: I'm in max because I am immune to poison ivy insofar as a human can be immune to it.
Speaker 1: So it's got Johnson.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Being allergic to nothing in exchange for getting poison ivy like a normal person as opposed to being Resistant to poison ivy and having a million other allergies that affect you a lot more frequently in everyday life.
Speaker 0: I think I'll take what I got I've gotten by.
Speaker 0: if you could if you could trade your allergies for what I've got in terms of allergies, would you?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: All right, I don't think it's such a hard decision.
Speaker 1: but well considering that not a few weeks ago I ended up running through a patch of poison ivy without realizing it if I'm wearing pants, I'm all good.
Speaker 1: I was wearing shorts Plus if you're wearing pants, you realize it gets all over your pants and then you just don't touch him.
Speaker 1: But you probably don't notice.
Speaker 0: and then that's the thing is that if I'm you know, you notice I look around for when I'm in Woods, you don't go into woods.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: That's another thing.
Speaker 1: Anyway now here's something I found interesting.
Speaker 1: a lot of people were talking about how the anti genetic engineering groups You know, basically the nut jobs
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: are All okay with these cats for the most part because they didn't do it in the lab So much as they did it through selective breeding which is effectively the same thing as genetic engineering.
Speaker 1: It just takes longer and it's not as accurate.
Speaker 1: So why it?
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into this we're not doing the show about it.
Speaker 1: But how is it that people who are against genetically modifying corn to make it more nutritious are fine with eating corn?
Speaker 1: We have now despite the fact that that corn is basically Genetically engineered over hundreds and hundreds and hundreds and thousands of years by humans and the corn we have today did not exist back in.
Speaker 0: The point is is that these people are idiots.
Speaker 0: They're idiots.
Speaker 0: They don't understand science.
Speaker 0: They're anti science.
Speaker 0: So a scientific argument isn't gonna work.
Speaker 0: They're making decisions based on feelings rather than ration Reason and logic.
Speaker 0: so reason and logic will not work.
Speaker 0: You need to somehow change their feelings to change their minds.
Speaker 1: now You know, it's funny because you didn't listen to the my thing of the day yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you basically said exactly what James Randi said.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, we're like-minded people.
Speaker 1: What do you got in the news?
Speaker 0: Oh, so there's a website called turn it in calm God and what it is, it's a website where it You turn.
Speaker 0: if you have a let's say I'm in a college and I have to turn in a paper to my teacher He might say turn it in to turn it in calm.
Speaker 0: Here's the codes or whatever for my class.
Speaker 0: I turn it in to turn it in calm.
Speaker 0: turn it in calm checks to make sure I'm not a plagiarizing fool.
Speaker 0: It checks it to make sure I didn't take it out of a journal and it checks it against a bunch of different papers written by other students in other schools around the country and You know papers they found online and all sorts of stuff to make sure I didn't cheat.
Speaker 0: and Then if I didn't cheat or if I did it tells the teacher and it gives the teacher my paper.
Speaker 0: now a Bunch of students are mad because you know, first of all, you know, you're basically insulting everyone by saying you're all cheaters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not just that.
Speaker 0: it's the point is Turn it in calm takes your papers and stores them and then uses them for its commercial purposes.
Speaker 0: This is a for-profit company that takes your paper that you wrote and then uses it to make money by checking to make sure no One else copied it now.
Speaker 1: This would be pretty much fine except for the fact that this blatantly violates all sorts of copyright law.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it's just ironic out trying to enforce the copyright law of plagiarism.
Speaker 0: They Infringe upon copyright law of.
Speaker 0: I own my paper.
Speaker 0: You can't use it for your business.
Speaker 1: Not only that but I ran into a situation once where I actually turned in the same paper to two different professors Mm-hmm, and I realized that one of the professor's used turn it in and the other one didn't.
Speaker 1: I realized if the other professor to use Turn it in calm it would have just said that I cheated.
Speaker 1: it wouldn't have come up with.
Speaker 1: hey, it's the same guy.
Speaker 1: He wrote that paper.
Speaker 1: It just would have said that I cheated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would have been tough to.
Speaker 1: Actually, I turned one paper into three different professors over the course of two years.
Speaker 1: Awesome, I wrote very generic papers on purpose in college.
Speaker 0: See, I always tried to be real specific to every topic they were asking, you know I was but I always made sure that it was applicable to other topics.
Speaker 1: or They are for all you kids out there in college.
Speaker 1: Here is a brilliant brilliant scam.
Speaker 1: if you really want to get out of doing some work Have if you've written a bunch of papers like good papers, you know This paper is good and you could probably apply it to a class.
Speaker 1: You've got going now.
Speaker 1: Totally.
Speaker 1: don't do a big project or turn it in late and half-assed and Then go to the professor very apologetic like I screwed up blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Can I do anything to make up for that bad?
Speaker 1: Grade, I'll write a paper for you.
Speaker 1: I'll do extra credit.
Speaker 1: I'll do something.
Speaker 1: I'll do extra work to make up for the work I missed and Then they'll probably suggest something and work with them and try to get it to where they suggest that you write on the extra paper For them that you've already written.
Speaker 1: Yes, and then you just turn in the paper that you already have written for the other class.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean the reason that plagiarism is wrong is not is because you're taking someone else's work and saying it's your own.
Speaker 0: if it's your Own who says you can't use it?
Speaker 0: five times in five different classes?
Speaker 0: You know if I get to computer programming classes and one guy says write a bubble sort and the other guy says write a bubble Sort I'm gonna give them both the same bubble sort.
Speaker 0: Why should I do it twice?
Speaker 1: Now theoretically the issue there is oh, well you should write the paper to learn But if I wrote a good enough paper before I don't need to learn to write a paper.
Speaker 0: that good again exactly All right, so yeah that covers the news is now.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: Also, I saw a lot of people's solution to this was to put a copyright notice prohibiting all of these things in Their paper and then suing turnitin.com.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if anyone actually did that or not.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, this is just people like me saying hey do this stuff Yeah, so I urge all of our listeners if you ever run afoul of turnitin.com put all sorts of copyright notices in your paper Mmm and our license your paper with like a Creative Commons license.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll talk about that in a minute.
Speaker 1: No protect it with anti-circumvention Measures then DRM on your paper then sue them under the DMCA.
Speaker 1: things of the day Mmm.
Speaker 1: now I listen to a lot of podcasts now a lot relative to how many I listened to before but not through a zero.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no I listen to a lot of podcasts relative to how many I listen to.
Speaker 1: Oh four years ago You realize I listen to a lot compared to.
Speaker 1: I mean when I started geek nights for the first several months I didn't listen to any podcast.
Speaker 0: You hadn't listened to a podcast ever when you started listening when we started.
Speaker 1: I gotta say I still hate the vast majority of Podcasts.
Speaker 0: Well, I hate the vast majority of any particular medium Even if it's a me, you know.
Speaker 0: Like the vast majority of stuff on YouTube sucks the vast majority of movies suck the vet.
Speaker 0: any medium most of it sucks.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but I've had such bad luck finding good podcasts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact, most of the podcasts I like are because I know the people who do them personally.
Speaker 0: Mmm when I started listening to podcast I subscribed to a whole mess of them and that I basically like.
Speaker 0: most of them I don't listen to anymore.
Speaker 0: They're very few that I've continued to listen to for a long period of time and I'm deleting and adding new podcasts.
Speaker 0: You know like all the time.
Speaker 1: Well, there are two podcasts that deal with skepticism that our listeners had both recommended to me or they had recommended both to me Skepticality and a skeptics guide to the universe.
Speaker 0: I never actually listen to skeptics guide to the universe But I listened to skepticality back in the day and it was okay, but I didn't keep it around.
Speaker 1: I like one of the two a lot more than the other.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna bother talking about them.
Speaker 1: I could do a show on what podcast I like later, but Skepticality the one I like Recently their most recent episode my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: They had an interview by dr Michael Shermer with the amazing James Randi on the amazing meeting and the amazing voyage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they had James Randi on the show like three or four times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this particular interview is really really good.
Speaker 1: I if you want to hear James Randi being James Randi, this is probably the most succinct version of that ever.
Speaker 0: He tends to be a guy who will say the same things in many interviews.
Speaker 0: so if you want you got to listen to this like one really big interview to get him to say everything he has to say And then you just read his newsletter.
Speaker 1: He's a little more off-the-cuff on this one, too.
Speaker 1: He gets all.
Speaker 1: he talks a lot about how angry he gets he does.
Speaker 0: he does gaze an angry little man Yeah, but yeah, he's very amusing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I love James Randi.
Speaker 1: I have nothing but the utmost of respect for this man And this interview is just really good.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's cool All right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day here is this cool video on YouTube.
Speaker 0: what they did is they took a camera and they followed some Skaters around, you know skateboarding kids and they did all kinds of skateboarding tricks and then they took this video to the editing shop or wherever where they have their fancy softwares and their Powerful computers and all that other jazz and they erased all the skateboards.
Speaker 1: Very well, mind you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it looks like someone literally frame by frame Photoshopped out every skateboard.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they use some sort of technology of tracking.
Speaker 0: I think they might have painted the skateboards green or something like that, you know to just erase them, but who knows?
Speaker 0: I don't know how they did it.
Speaker 0: I'm not I don't know about that shit.
Speaker 0: And of course we didn't do any research Yeah, but this video is wicked cool because you have these kids basically floating like six inches off the ground I don't know.
Speaker 0: How high is a skateboard?
Speaker 1: Not six inches.
Speaker 1: God.
Speaker 1: Have you ever been on a skateboard?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: four inches off the ground There's some kids floating around because they got no skateboards, but they're skating.
Speaker 1: It's kind of until they start grinding and jumping off of things and then it looks really awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also cool when they have like a whole bunch of kids skating around, you know, because it's like whoa.
Speaker 0: Anyway, definitely worth watching if you haven't seen it.
Speaker 0: It's only a minute and then two minutes long.
Speaker 1: So whatever Yeah, not terribly exciting things today.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's Monday.
Speaker 0: It's Monday.
Speaker 1: We were at a power metal concert followed by a weekend of gaming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, leave me alone.
Speaker 0: That's the thing that I got for you tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I'll give you something better the ultimate something of ultimate something.
Speaker 1: No that one of our listeners sent us probably the worst thing I've ever seen on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, tomorrow I'll talk about some gaming thing because the Tokyo game show was I don't know
Speaker 1: About two o'clock in the afternoon maybe one o'clock what the topic of the show would be suddenly and out of the blue because we both Independently had run afoul of the topic at hand in a negative way.
Speaker 1: now I was at work and there's this program called PDF creator that you can install it in Windows.
Speaker 1: It will give you a printer device that you can print to which will then make PDF files out of anything anything that can print.
Speaker 0: So basically your computer thinks there's a printer.
Speaker 0: so any program can print out of a printer that you know is a print a program That's able to print.
Speaker 1: Yep, all the program does is take the post script that your printing program makes good thing.
Speaker 1: We have a pop filter here.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it turns that into a PDF instead of sending it You know to a piece of paper with ink.
Speaker 1: Alright now really great open source.
Speaker 1: and my company comes to me and they want me to install this and all these computers And I think great.
Speaker 1: Finally they're using some open source.
Speaker 1: I can use this as leverage for blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: So I get ready to know we install it and first off I assume that they don't know anything about open source software.
Speaker 1: So I look at the license and I see oh, it's GPL.
Speaker 1: whatever I can do this.
Speaker 1: then I see that there is a version that contains ghost scripts the GPL version and another version that contains ghost script the AFPL version which I had never heard of.
Speaker 0: I also Only barely heard of it.
Speaker 1: Now all of the internet recommended that you use the a FPL version.
Speaker 1: So being a de studious person I decided to look up what the a FPL was.
Speaker 1: It is actually the Aladdin free public license.
Speaker 1: to skip all the details until later in this talk.
Speaker 1: I discovered that this license effectively Prohibited me from in any way using the software in any way that could ever be valuable ever.
Speaker 1: It basically made it to where I could not legally install this software on any computer at this place at this hospital Though it would have been legal if they had downloaded it themselves without any input from me and then installed it.
Speaker 1: Wow, this license is just terrible and I hate these people All right.
Speaker 0: So to get to the topic of the show what we're going to talk about today are all the different free software and other Copyright licenses.
Speaker 0: you see when you install some software, you know how it says do you agree?
Speaker 0: That is the license of the soft.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know all those words.
Speaker 1: before it asks you to agree you're signing a legal document.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe it is.
Speaker 1: essentially it's never been fully tested in court.
Speaker 0: But that's that we're not gonna talk about that.
Speaker 1: That's a whole other chance.
Speaker 0: the point it.
Speaker 0: well GPL is just tested in court in Germany.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Anyway, Eulis haven't been.
Speaker 0: yes The point is is that there is a contract which you agree to when you use pretty much any piece of software as to how you can use that software legally and how you cannot use that software.
Speaker 0: and They're in open source software.
Speaker 0: There are this set of licenses.
Speaker 0: You probably are.
Speaker 0: Yeah that are considered open source.
Speaker 1: You've probably heard of the GPL the LG PL the the BSD the MIT Creative Commons.
Speaker 0: Creative Commons isn't really used for software, but we'll talk about it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's in the same family of things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then Those are approved open source licenses.
Speaker 0: the license on say Microsoft Word is not an open source license because it does not allow you to do certain things with the software That open source licenses do allow you to do with the software.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean from a high level.
Speaker 1: the way it works is that by default if you create something it is copyrighted no matter what in The United States.
Speaker 1: yeah in the United States.
Speaker 1: We can't talk about other nations copyright laws for obvious and
Speaker 0: we're gonna talk in very general terms
Speaker 1: though There are international copyright laws, but we're not going to get into that because you don't care believe me You don't care
Speaker 0: don't care You
Speaker 1: don't care at all
Speaker 0: and that's not the poor talking about open source licenses not about copyright
Speaker 1: But by default if I create something that is copyrightable, it is automatically copyrighted the moment.
Speaker 1: I put my pen to the paper.
Speaker 0: Yeah If I paint a painting it's copyrighted.
Speaker 1: if I write a program copyrighted and it me and automatically I reserve Every single right I am allowed to reserve under that copyright meaning No one else has any right to do anything regarding whatever you just made ever.
Speaker 0: So, how do you make open source software?
Speaker 0: you're going to have to specifically give up a bunch of rights that you get by default and Thus you need an open source license to do so.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because before the open source licenses were written your only options were really to either do it Half-assedly meaning that all the people using your software were technically using it illegally, but you wouldn't sue them which is a bad situation Mm-hmm, or you could put it in the public domain, which is Basically you not only give up any rights you had over what you created, but you give up the right to say that you made it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's talk about public domain first.
Speaker 0: public domain Essentially means that no one owns it and yet everyone owns it.
Speaker 1: The public owns it is in the public's domain to do with what they will with unlimited use forever and ever.
Speaker 0: Now if you want to release something into the public domain you are free to do so.
Speaker 0: You can go to creativecommons.org and this little helper thing that will allow you to Anywhere can do anything they want with that work at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean you can do it on your own too.
Speaker 1: if you write a Document saying this or if you hand something to someone and you say in front of certified witnesses that I release this to the public Domain you can't take it back ever.
Speaker 1: It's done.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's game over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, public domain is the sledgehammer of copyright.
Speaker 0: It's the exact opposite of copyright Yeah, and the way copyright law works generally is that after X years it becomes public domain.
Speaker 0: So if you don't do anything, you'll in the United States.
Speaker 0: you get something.
Speaker 0: you make a work.
Speaker 0: It's you copyrighted by you.
Speaker 0: the copyright lasts.
Speaker 0: for what?
Speaker 0: 90 years?
Speaker 0: 75 years.
Speaker 1: They keep up in it.
Speaker 1: It started at like 7 and 14 and it started like 14.
Speaker 0: It's 75 years and that plus your life in a very long time.
Speaker 0: and when that time is over It becomes public domain.
Speaker 0: And if you go to like archive org, you can see a lot of things that used to be copyrighted But are now public domain like some very old Bugs Bunny and Superman cartoons and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: They're all public domain now.
Speaker 0: So anyone could do what they want with them.
Speaker 1: Yep Now aside from public domain before these licenses your only other option was to try to write Some sort of license that would allow other people to use what you made freely while still reserving some of the rights for yourself.
Speaker 1: But without a lawyer it is almost impossible to write a legally binding contract that would hold up in court.
Speaker 1: So this was out of the reach of most people.
Speaker 0: now men like Stahlman decided that this was a bad situation Yep, so they came up with a bunch of open source licenses and all sorts of other things That you could just take from a website and put them in your software.
Speaker 0: follow some directions and you're good to go.
Speaker 1: Yes they're open source from two perspectives one in that they cover open source software and makes things open source.
Speaker 1: and two that the licenses themselves are Effectively open source and that you can take the license put your name on it Put the name of your thing on it and it works just as well.
Speaker 0: You can also some of these licenses you can change.
Speaker 0: So let's say I have a license here and it restrict it reserves the rights I want and doesn't reserve the rights I don't want except for one right.
Speaker 0: I can add that one right into the license because it's an open license.
Speaker 1: Yep in fact if you wanted you could take the GPL put it on something hire a lawyer and have them rewrite it to.
Speaker 0: Specifically do whatever you wanted it to do and you can call it like the Scott GPL or the rim GPL or the rim PL or whatever you want to call it.
Speaker 1: You know you were trying to come up with some sort of joke and you couldn't.
Speaker 0: I've got.
Speaker 0: I couldn't think of a single acronym.
Speaker 0: That would have been funny.
Speaker 1: I couldn't think of one either.
Speaker 1: I was trying to think of how to make some sort of copyright thing that spelled out penis and I was running short on time Here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so creative what creative I want to talk about creative comments for us because it's real simple.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's also remember geek nights is released under the Creative Commons.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is.
Speaker 0: now What Creative Commons is is it's this group that helps you cop release things and revote.
Speaker 0: You know get rid of your rights that you have by default in a very simple and easy way.
Speaker 0: now They usually don't do so much with software, but they they handle everything else.
Speaker 0: They handle music video papers, you know photographs Scientific papers all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: And all you do is you go to the website and you choose what kind of license you want.
Speaker 0: now You have a but the default choice is a Creative Commons license.
Speaker 0: But you can also choose some other licenses like they have the public domain.
Speaker 0: They help you get stuff in the public domain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the way they do this is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: we found out just now looking at it that the way they do the public domain is basically they hand you a loaded weapon and They say are you sure you want to shoot your copyright?
Speaker 1: Because it's gone forever and we will make sure that it's gone forever.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: They verify it through email and everything.
Speaker 0: Yep, the other thing they have it they have a developing nations license, which basically says if Let's say I wrote a book and I put a developing nations license That means in the United States, it's treated like almost any other book, you know, they buy in bookstores and on Amazon, but in say Zamibia if that's even still a place it's free because those people are poor.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's a lot of legalese to work that out.
Speaker 1: the way this works the Creative Commons is that they give you very simple explanations of what it actually does.
Speaker 0: And then the actual license is all this legalese that's been poured over by lawyers and it's it's hidden from you So you don't have to read it, but they tell you in simple terms of what you're what you're getting and you can trust it.
Speaker 1: I mean, we we trust it.
Speaker 0: almost everyone out there trusted Yeah, people have looked it over who and they know what they're talking about.
Speaker 0: So it's all good.
Speaker 0: another license They have the sampling license just good for music.
Speaker 0: It says, you know, you can't just steal my music But if you want to sample my music and make a hip-hop out of it, it's all good.
Speaker 0: The only other really cool one they have is the founders copyright which says I want to copyright this like it's 1790 something 14 years of copyright and then public domain.
Speaker 0: So anyway by default they give you the Creative Commons license, which has a bunch of different options.
Speaker 0: Basically, you have three options, but they can be in any combination.
Speaker 0: The first option isn't really an option because you have to choose it.
Speaker 0: It's attribution.
Speaker 0: You always get attribution.
Speaker 1: All that means is anyone who uses what you you what you made has to say that you did it.
Speaker 1: You were still the author and you can claim that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: The second option is Modifications.
Speaker 0: now there are actually two choices for modifications.
Speaker 0: There's Nobody can modify what I have made.
Speaker 0: yes, you can modify what I have made in any way you want.
Speaker 0: and Yes, you can modify what I've made as long as you also take your Modification and put it under the same Creative Commons license that you are using this in.
Speaker 1: This is also known as share and share alike and it's kind of a viral property.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's creative.
Speaker 0: So let's say I make a podcast podcast called geek nights and someone decides they want to remix the podcast.
Speaker 0: That's all good That's cool.
Speaker 0: But they do have to say that rim and Scott made the podcast attribution and They do have to give out that newly modified podcast for free with the same exact Creative Commons license.
Speaker 0: They have to share it as well.
Speaker 0: They can't modify it and then you know copyright that modification and not give up any of the rights to it.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: totally out of the blue and we're not gonna talk about this on the show, but I just realized Let me read the email that mock and I supremacy sent us giving us permission to use their music.
Speaker 1: all right, because geek nights is out under the Creative Commons and Theoretically we could virally implant some mock and I supremacy music with the Creative Commons by putting it in geek nights.
Speaker 0: But any of their music that we would give is most of their music is downloaded for free on the internet.
Speaker 0: I mean, these guys have bootlegs from their concert on their website.
Speaker 0: I know I don't.
Speaker 1: I know they don't care But that's just.
Speaker 1: that's the kind of thing that people like Microsoft are really afraid of especially with the GPL.
Speaker 1: In fact Microsoft called the GPL a form of cancer at one point.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't remember if a Bill Gates or bomber but one of them said we'll talk about the GPL.
Speaker 0: next and The.
Speaker 0: the final thing in Creative Commons license is commercial uses yes or no?
Speaker 0: if you say yes That means someone could take an episode of geek nights and sell it You know for money on like a website or they could you know Put it on their radio network that has advertisements, you know within.
Speaker 0: if you say no commercial uses that means that they can't use your work if it makes them money in any way shape or form and You pick those options and you get a Creative Commons license for your works.
Speaker 1: now in terms of like say geek nights Or anything really that you make you can always at any time make the license less restrictive on anything you've made.
Speaker 1: So if we released most of geek nights with the non commercial license and then today we decide all right We want to allow commercial we can add apply the new license the less restrictive one to all of the old geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because all it does is that the same license plus we gave up one more right?
Speaker 1: Yep, but you can't Put more restriction on something you've already put out.
Speaker 0: Well, you could and people could choose to use that newer more restrictive license, but they're not obligated to do so.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if I release geek nights episode blah under the most open Creative Commons Then I re-release it identical under a super restrictive one.
Speaker 1: Anyone who wants can just say they're using the old license because it was released under that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as long as they can prove that and all that jazz, but whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah So you can always with copyright you get all the rights by default and you can only give more of them away.
Speaker 0: You can never take them back.
Speaker 0: That's why public domain is such a big thing.
Speaker 0: It's like you give it up.
Speaker 0: It's gone.
Speaker 0: Can't get it back All right.
Speaker 1: Now the GPL is probably the most famous of these.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it is what I mean Linux and all of those things are covered under, you know, GPL's and BSD licenses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, GPL is the GNU public license made by Richard Stallman.
Speaker 0: Yeah GNU and general public license Yeah, and the the free software foundation and all that good stuff.
Speaker 0: These are acts.
Speaker 0: now we're gonna actually talk about the licenses that apply Specifically to open source software.
Speaker 0: Creative Commons isn't really open source software.
Speaker 0: It's just a license.
Speaker 0: in general.
Speaker 0: That's really easy to understand the concept of a license but the GPL is this is for open source software and The GPL in particular is basically the open source software license.
Speaker 1: Now you might have heard a term that's bandied around a lot copy left.
Speaker 1: That is what the GPL is.
Speaker 0: That is what it is.
Speaker 1: Copy left as opposed to copyright.
Speaker 0: Hahaha Alright now the way the GPL works is let's say I write a program and I put the GPL on it.
Speaker 0: That says a few things.
Speaker 0: The first thing it says is this is copyright.
Speaker 0: Scott Rubin You're not giving up the copyright.
Speaker 0: You're saying it's copyright by you.
Speaker 0: the second thing is you're saying You can run this program that I have written for any purpose.
Speaker 0: You can run it to do this.
Speaker 0: you can run it to do that.
Speaker 0: So let's say, you know you write a program that has many possible uses.
Speaker 0: I mean open office doesn't really have too many uses but grep has a lot of uses and can be used for many things.
Speaker 0: So someone one guy might want to use it to do a hacking tool and someone might want to use it for a military thing.
Speaker 0: That's all good.
Speaker 0: the second thing is you give up the right to study how the program works and modify it and You have to give up the source code.
Speaker 0: So whereas Microsoft Windows they don't give you the source code They just give you the program with the GPL.
Speaker 0: That means you're gonna give up the source code.
Speaker 0: You're going to allow people to study that source code and also change it.
Speaker 0: The third thing you allow people to do is to redistribute copies of your program.
Speaker 0: So, you know if I write a program and I give the source code to rim Or I give a copy of the program to rim he can give it to someone else if it's got a GPL on it.
Speaker 0: and The fourth thing you allow people to do is to improve the program and release improvements to the public.
Speaker 0: So rim can take the source code of the program.
Speaker 0: I wrote Modify it and then release that source code to someone else.
Speaker 1: Yep Now here's what I can't do and these are the important parts.
Speaker 1: say I take someone's GPL software and rewrite it.
Speaker 1: Okay, if I rewrite it I don't even have to just give the source code back out if I just keep it for myself.
Speaker 1: But the moment I try to redistribute the program that I've made with that other code I have to give up the source code from my auditions.
Speaker 1: in addition.
Speaker 1: If I don't I'm violating the GPL.
Speaker 0: Yes, this is where you get problems.
Speaker 0: Like there was a lawsuit against Linksys because Linksys modified Linux.
Speaker 0: They put Linux in their Linksys routers and then they didn't give up the source code to That.
Speaker 0: you know that was in the Linux router.
Speaker 1: Now the bastards.
Speaker 1: the lawsuit was actually complicated because they they argued such things as the value of the software is zero Because it was given away free.
Speaker 1: Therefore your GPL is crap.
Speaker 0: And yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're called the GPL one in the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the point is, you know TiVo as a similar thing.
Speaker 0: But I think you can get the TiVo software, you know is if you take a GPL program modify it and use it You have to let everyone see your modifications.
Speaker 0: You can't keep them hidden, you know that way.
Speaker 0: You know if someone solves a bug in my program Let's say some company wants to use my program and they fix a bug in it.
Speaker 0: They have to let everyone know the bug fix.
Speaker 0: They can't hide that from us.
Speaker 1: Unless they modify the program to fix the bug and only use it internally to their own company.
Speaker 0: Yeah If they distribute it at all Then they have to do it.
Speaker 0: if you don't distribute it The reason they don't say you have to do it.
Speaker 0: if you don't distribute it is because there's no way to know they did It.
Speaker 0: if they don't distribute it, so it's kind of pointless.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, plus they're really.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a lot of a philosophical argument here that the people who made the GPL Really want free software to take over and the GPL is designed partially to prevent people who make proprietary Software from using anything that was made under GPL.
Speaker 1: So if I make a cool thing Microsoft and it's free Microsoft can't just take it and put it in Windows because now they got to release the source code to Windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, another thing about the GPL that you might find surprising is that it specifically allows people to sell copies of GPL software, so let's say rim writes a program in the GPL.
Speaker 0: I can take it burn it to a CD and sell the CD.
Speaker 0: Yep, I can say hey if you want this program that rim wrote pay me five bucks and I'll let you downloaded it.
Speaker 1: There was a minor scandal over God.
Speaker 1: What was that?
Speaker 1: Ethereal right or Nessus?
Speaker 0: Nessus?
Speaker 1: Nessus is a nice security software out there.
Speaker 1: And what happened was he released it under I believe the GPL or something similar and Companies would take his code Repackage it but not modify it and then sell it as their own security solution for a lot of money But not contribute back.
Speaker 1: He got so pissed that his new versions of the program don't use the GPL anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because these companies were just making money off of his hard work Even though they could have downloaded the exact same program for free from him.
Speaker 1: They didn't know better and they paid money for.
Speaker 0: yeah The problem with this is that you would think if the program is given away for free if someone tries to sell it That's okay.
Speaker 0: Because if the person on the other end should go wait a minute I can get that for free.
Speaker 0: Why am I paying you, you know, but if people need to sell it, let's say you're selling a Linksys router You're also selling a copy of the software that's in you know, the copy of Linux.
Speaker 0: It's in the router.
Speaker 0: That's why you allow selling is because if you didn't allow selling Linksys couldn't sell a router with Linux in it because they have to also sell that copy of Linux.
Speaker 1: Now for anyone who knows a lot more about software We're not going to talk about this in any length at all.
Speaker 1: But there's also a license called the LGPL the limited new general public license.
Speaker 1: now real briefly I said before that if Scott makes a program and it's GPL and Microsoft wants to use it They can't without releasing the source code in Windows.
Speaker 1: if they try to put it in Windows.
Speaker 0: Now what if instead of a program Scott made a library which is sort of like a program But I'm not going to explain it.
Speaker 1: Imagine like a thing that you could stick into Windows that Windows could use to decode say an aug vorbis file?
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean an audio file the special kind of audio file Scott made a little thing that allows Windows or any Operating system to just decode that and play it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Now if you release that under the GPL Microsoft couldn't put that in any of their products Because it was Steve Ballmer who said that Linux is a cancer.
Speaker 1: I just see it here in Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Okay, but the LGPL allows very specifically Libraries to be linked without forcing the viral nature of the GPL onto something.
Speaker 1: So the LGPL allows you to make a library that can be used by commercial software without breaking their a proprietary license.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So if I want to write a piece of software that plays all kinds of music
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: you know, I don't want to actually write the decoders that have to decode all the different types of music What I can do is I can go and collect decoding libraries that are open source not modify them in any way and use them in a program that allows people to play all kinds of audio files and All I do is you know in my source code of my program I say if this kind of audio file comes up use that open source code over there to decode it and I can sell this program that contains all these separate libraries and I can license it with a non GPL license as long as all those libraries have an LGPL license.
Speaker 0: if they had a GPL license I couldn't do it.
Speaker 1: Now the reason behind this and this is really important to the philosophy because there are a lot of people who are Rapidly against the LGPL.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But there are also a lot of people who see the value of the LGPL Because if you make something like say you make something better than Adobe Acrobat and PDF something great.
Speaker 1: You want people to use it.
Speaker 1: if you use the GPL then all the big like Microsoft and Apple can't use it.
Speaker 1: so most people will not be able to use your library and won't be able to use your file format and It'll just be a pain in the ass and you'll basically prevent what you made from ever being adopted.
Speaker 1: By using the LGPL your thing could be used in Microsoft and Apple and thus gain much more acceptance from actual users.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'd become very easy for just about any.
Speaker 0: you know If you develop a new protocol or a new file format and you write a library to handle that protocol or format You know if it's only open source then only GPL Only people who are going to use it are people writing GPL software and no one will care about your format or your protocol or Whatever you've written a library for.
Speaker 0: but if you LGPL it then people might care and use it all over the place And it might become cool.
Speaker 0: Now the other non GPL Open-source licenses.
Speaker 0: there are many of them, but two of them that are very similar are the MIT and BSD licenses.
Speaker 0: They come from MIT and Berkeley.
Speaker 1: Now the BSD style licenses.
Speaker 1: They're generally all lumped under BSD style licenses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there are a lot of variations They're actually less restrictive than the GPL.
Speaker 1: They are basically almost public domain, but not quite They are the other side of the free debate.
Speaker 1: I mean the GNU people.
Speaker 1: I probably anger a lot of people but they're really kind of fanatical about free software.
Speaker 1: Mmm, like I mean there the BSD people are more.
Speaker 1: we make free software because we want to.
Speaker 1: we want you to use our free Software for a better world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the GNU people say the same thing But they also say you shouldn't be able to make non free software.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're kind of crazy now.
Speaker 1: I mean they have valid points But I'll it.
Speaker 1: a lot of times they end up being counterproductive in the sense that they end up Restricting your freedom in order to protect your freedom.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, a BSD license basically says, you know, this is super free.
Speaker 0: It's copyrighted by me.
Speaker 0: If you redistribute this software if you give it to someone else you could have kept rhyming.
Speaker 1: You were all set for some poetry was I?
Speaker 0: yeah?
Speaker 0: Anyway, if you redistribute the software you can't change the license, so it has to also be a BSD license.
Speaker 1: So it's also viral like the GPL, but it's like a vice a benign virus.
Speaker 1: It doesn't do anything to you.
Speaker 1: It just sits there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is allowed a lot of BSD licensed software to be very widely used in distributed.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and It also says that if you you can redistribute this software in binary form But you have to include this copyright notice and etc, etc.
Speaker 1: Yep, a little different from the GPL which really also requires you to include the source code.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now that's basically it.
Speaker 0: So if Microsoft wanted.
Speaker 0: if you wrote a program with the BSD license Microsoft could come take your code Put it in Windows and no one would ever know.
Speaker 1: But they'd have to credit you at some point for saying that this is your code and by including the license you provided Mm-hmm, so they couldn't just take it secretly and stick it in without telling anyone Doing anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's basically it.
Speaker 1: Yep, they couldn't use the GPL.
Speaker 1: They could use the DL GPL depending on how they used it Mm-hmm, and really it just comes down to you.
Speaker 1: probably don't care about the specifics of the licenses But now at least when you hear all these words like blah blah blah LG PL BSD blah blah blah You at least know what the issue is.
Speaker 1: It's just a matter of how many rights that you were given under copyright law.
Speaker 1: Do you want to give up?
Speaker 0: this is an anecdote to explain, you know how this affects you in Ubuntu or Debian or Debian?
Speaker 0: Linux is the way we were talking about earlier.
Speaker 0: You'll notice that Firefox the program does not have the Firefox icon.
Speaker 0: or you know with the fiery Fox around the globe It just has a globe and no fiery Fox.
Speaker 0: The reason for that is because Debian and Ubuntu Ubuntu Basically Debian mostly which Ubuntu is based on reporting to.
Speaker 0: they refuse To use non free stuff anything.
Speaker 0: That's not free a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: They won't use it.
Speaker 1: and while you can distribute the Firefox logo wherever you want It is not totally totally totally free.
Speaker 0: It is not is?
Speaker 0: that is a trademark of the Mozilla Corporation and it is not super free.
Speaker 0: and you know.
Speaker 0: basically What happens.
Speaker 0: is the the Firefox that you get with Ubuntu or Debian is why you gotta keep saying that?
Speaker 0: Yes, you're kind of throwing me off track.
Speaker 0: Don't say Ubuntu Is not exactly the same as the one that Mozilla distributes.
Speaker 0: it is modified, you know from the original source Which is okay in the Mozilla license.
Speaker 0: however Firefox says You know.
Speaker 0: Mozilla says you shouldn't call it Firefox if you've modified it because it's no longer Firefox.
Speaker 0: It's now something else, you know, you can't do that.
Speaker 0: So they said hey Debian Ubuntu people Yeah, you should.
Speaker 0: either.
Speaker 0: your choices are don't modify Firefox and use the icon or Don't use the icon and don't call it Firefox.
Speaker 1: now this illustrates one of the biggest longest running and Contended issues in the Linux world the fact that a lot of the people who work on Linux are so pro Free software that they basically shoot themselves in the foot by not allowing very important things that need to be in Linux for normal people to use Linux to be there and you have to go out of Your way to get these things things like Nvidia drivers.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing with Nvidia drivers.
Speaker 0: Right, is that the Nvidia driver itself existing is?
Speaker 0: Okay, but you're because it's not free.
Speaker 0: It's it's you know, closed source.
Speaker 0: You're not allowed and being freezing beer but not freezing speech, right?
Speaker 0: You are not allowed to distribute the Nvidia driver.
Speaker 0: if I you know made a Linux Distribution that included the Nvidia driver in it on the CD or whatever Nvidia would come after me you're not allowed to do that, but the other thing is that the Nvidia driver is a closed source driver and It's a closed source kernel module and by linking it into the GPL open source kernel You are in some way, you know tainting the kernel.
Speaker 0: It'll even say tainting the kernel when you do it and it.
Speaker 0: you know The super Debian open source fanatics don't like that.
Speaker 0: However, without doing that you have pretty much no other choice to have a working Nvidia card that uses your hardware properly And I really have no problem with it at all, you know using an Nvidia driver like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean it's.
Speaker 1: I mean there's a lot of Java has issues with this video and mp3 codec.
Speaker 1: things have issues with this and These people are to the point where not only will they not I mean some things they could include and they choose not to.
Speaker 1: They won't even make it easy to install these things and they make they just put little barriers in your way.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like I have no problem if you don't include Sun Java with the distribution because it's not legal.
Speaker 0: Sun won't let you.
Speaker 0: actually they're changing Their mind on that but they won't let you.
Speaker 0: it's not.
Speaker 0: it's against the law.
Speaker 0: That's fine But there's no law that says you can't have a button that says install Sun Java.
Speaker 0: Click this button and then it takes you to the Sun website and does it for you?
Speaker 0: No law.
Speaker 0: that says you can't have a thing to click on.
Speaker 0: that will go and install the Nvidia driver or Even have all the hooks ready.
Speaker 1: So the Nvidia driver is much more easily installed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's nothing.
Speaker 0: there's no law that says you can't do that.
Speaker 0: You know, you could include the mp3 Decoding stuff, you know lame and all that other goody stuff with the distribution.
Speaker 0: You could put it right in your distribution legally.
Speaker 0: You could put the Firefox icon and Firefox in your distribution legally.
Speaker 0: There's no reason you can't accept because these people have a stick up their ass and they just make it.
Speaker 0: They make Linux crappier than it has to be.
Speaker 0: I mean if you decided to make a Linux distribution that didn't have us and you didn't have a stick up your butt your Linux would be like a zillion times better because not only would it be as awesome as Ubuntu is but But now anyone who uses it won't have to spend a half hour learning shit just to install stuff.
Speaker 0: They need to do their work now.
Speaker 1: Imagine if someone who was outside of the realm of being sued over any sort of copyright Made Scott likes to call it the fuck you Linux.
Speaker 0: Yeah fuck you.
Speaker 0: version
Speaker 1: of Linux that includes all of these drivers
Speaker 0: the Nvidia driver the ATI driver the NDIS wrapper Java Flash all that stuff that mp3 stuff all the stuff that doesn't come with Linux by default Not only that essential for making it useful in everyday
Speaker 1: Like a fork kernel that integrated all this stuff properly and just straight
Speaker 0: up yep Just screw all the laws You know.
Speaker 0: include all the non free stuff and the free stuff together in a pre-built Linux distribution That was as good as Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: if you put that on the internet somewhere It would just blow every freaking other Linux distribution out of the water.
Speaker 0: It would do some serious damage to Windows and Mac because everyone would go holy shit.
Speaker 0: There's a usable Linux that doesn't require any learning or effort.
Speaker 0: But because these people have the stick up the butt that's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we need some freedom fighters out there to make fuck you Linux.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know granted like corporations couldn't use the fuck you Linux.
Speaker 1: Well anyone like that.
Speaker 1: But you and me all of you out there who are sick of Windows don't want to spend all the money it takes to get A Mac but are afraid of Linux.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how many times do you see someone installing Linux and then going oh I couldn't get my wireless driver to work?
Speaker 0: that's because the NDIS wrapper that makes your wireless card work isn't a hundred percent free.
Speaker 0: if there was a distribution someone could easily write a Program that would automatically make your wireless card work with NDIS wrapper, but they don't because it's not a hundred percent free.
Speaker 0: So you have this case of super freedom making things less free.
Speaker 1: granted We don't want to really get into the issue of Why some of these things like the Nvidia drivers aren't open when there's really no reason for them not to be.
Speaker 0: yes If I had my way, you know, I got to say this I would love for the Nvidia driver to be open source and free.
Speaker 0: that would be ideal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't help that the reasons Nvidia gives for making it closed source are mostly bollocks.
Speaker 0: They are mostly bullshit.
Speaker 1: I mean if they had valid reasons, I'd say oh, oh.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: in a world in which you have to feel world where you had to face the reality that the Nvidia driver and other things Like it are not going to be open source and free But are still absolutely necessary for useful desktop computing in a Linux environment You just have to kind of take it in the ass and say alright, I'll deal with it.
Speaker 0: I don't care I want a working computer.
Speaker 0: It's much more important than your useless ideals which are only harming your free software more than helping it.
Speaker 1: There is no God and your idiotic human ideals are laughable.
Speaker 0: Yes So I hope you all now understand the difference between all the different open source Kidding.
Speaker 1: I hope you understand that these words exist and that they have some kind of meaning and that copyright is out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but maybe someone out there you go on Wikipedia and look up the different licenses and learn Specifically what they mean, I would recommend against reading the Wikipedia's because while they're very thorough They are not very accessible.
Speaker 1: No, I would recommend just googling around looking for summaries of all of these licenses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are plenty of summaries of these licenses.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't go to the GNU website either because there is faster the crazy free guys live.
Speaker 1: There is more propaganda there than there is license.
Speaker 1: Yes, no offense to the GNU people.
Speaker 1: I mean you people do a lot of great work, but good God.
Speaker 0: Well, they've done a lot of great work lately.
Speaker 0: They've just been updating their old great work.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should start calling it GNU Linux again.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not gonna talk to have that argument on the show And that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.