Speaker 0: It's Monday February 13th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We were gonna talk about DRM But we kind of get sidetracked and just wander around about meta bits and basically cop out of the episode.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: so last Thursday at the end of the show I started to tell a story and then I stopped because we were kind of out of time about my computer and my Monitor and my video card and something terrible that had happened.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to finish the story because I promised I would now.
Speaker 0: the other day I came home from work, and I turned on my Six and a half it's almost seven year old monitor.
Speaker 0: to you know.
Speaker 0: do my computer stuff?
Speaker 0: look at the websites I can't look at at work and all that sort of thing and I Turn it on and I go to unlock my computer And I noticed that my ex screensaver login thing is a little not looking so good.
Speaker 0: it's a little black and blurry and all artifact II and Generally looks like my monitor is fucked itself.
Speaker 0: So I log in and sure enough my monitor is fucked itself.
Speaker 0: There's dark lines that follow various colors around the screen, and it looks like the CRT has just died.
Speaker 0: So I'm pissed off, and I'm fiddling with things.
Speaker 0: I open the little OSD menu on the monitor.
Speaker 0: I'm moving stuff around trying to change brightness contrast see if I can get it into a usable state And it's not working, and I resigned myself to buy in a new monitor.
Speaker 0: Then I open the OSD one more time to change one more setting back to the way It was and I realized something that made me feel like an idiot.
Speaker 0: The OSD menu was just fine.
Speaker 0: It was perfect and bright and clear.
Speaker 0: just as though the monitor were new Turned out that my video card the GPU had overheated enough to where it shat itself.
Speaker 1: Yep, you should replace that fan a little sooner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the fans kind of spinning But I burned my finger to the point that I got a tiny blister on it when I touched the GPU on my video Card.
Speaker 1: Wow you know what though?
Speaker 1: my video card one of the fans a little and I think it might be dying but there's not much I can do about it and the other one still works.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, but Wow It's not gonna die soon.
Speaker 0: I had a little blister.
Speaker 0: It's almost gone, but you can still see it if you look at my right pinky.
Speaker 0: But it's a geforce 2 GTS, it's old as shit.
Speaker 0: I paid almost four hundred dollars for it when it came out, so I think I got my money's worth over all those years.
Speaker 1: This is a problem actually cuz like you don't think about it.
Speaker 1: But like back in the day when I had a Pentium 3450 right sure it had a normal heatsink with a normal fan on it And you didn't need a fan on the chipsets on the motherboard.
Speaker 1: You didn't need the cooling on the RAM or your hard drive.
Speaker 0: You needed one fan in the front of the case.
Speaker 1: you need a perfectly normal fan and heatsink on your processor and a fan in the front of the case and a fan in the back of the case and a fan of the power Supply.
Speaker 0: a lot of cases didn't even have a fan in the back.
Speaker 0: Those are places.
Speaker 1: those are places where you've needed fans and heat sinks since the beginning of computers.
Speaker 1: You know every computer in a zillion years ago always had those fans.
Speaker 0: Then they've started coming out of these motherboards that came with a heatsink unlike the Northbridge Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: well the thing is is that nowadays you need that?
Speaker 1: The problem is is that in the rush to make everything faster and faster and faster and more and more features is They.
Speaker 1: they've put more emphasis on speeding things up faster than emphasis on Making them you know stable and run cool.
Speaker 1: It's like nowadays.
Speaker 1: you can get like a 500 600 megahertz processor that runs without a heatsink you know without anything.
Speaker 1: just Completely fine and cool.
Speaker 1: You know, but if you want something faster Then you can get it, but it's crazy hot yep.
Speaker 0: It also uses a lot more power.
Speaker 0: I mean you need three four five hundred watt power supplies now to run pcs.
Speaker 0: old pcs will run on a hundred watt power supply At work.
Speaker 0: I have a workstation that runs on a 65 watt power supply.
Speaker 1: See it's all comes down to lazy programming.
Speaker 1: what they used to do back in the day like we would have hundred megahertz computers and big companies would have giant servers and Instead of the giant servers just having a whole bunch of the same processor.
Speaker 1: We have at home They would actually have processors that were like insane and we're super hot And they wouldn't give anyone at home something that ran super hot.
Speaker 1: they'd be like You know that's way too hot and way too unstable and crazy for people at home to use.
Speaker 1: Now they give us the crazy stuff and we buy it because it's the only thing fast enough to run These poorly written programs that are so super slow and unoptimized.
Speaker 0: well the other problem is simply that People don't really think much about cooling their computer.
Speaker 0: I mean it's geeks do but even a lot of geeks they think about it.
Speaker 0: But they think about it as though It's still the 90s where you need a fan in the front and a fan in the back and whatever fan came with your CPU.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 1: no people go create They or they go too crazy with the cooling to see something their nerds and like geeks they go crazy.
Speaker 0: But a lot of geeks who aren't real big on computers don't know Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: they just they use whatever came with a computer or they did.
Speaker 0: they get you know those little fans.
Speaker 0: They make a lot of noise instead of the big ones that actually do a good job Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: No one thinks to look inside the computer and make sure all their fans are still running.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I would rather just have a computer that had a heat sink on the CPU a fan in the front fan in the back You know the same loadout in the olden days and have chips That just didn't need to be cooled that were stable and cool.
Speaker 1: But the problem is is that all the software is written so poorly that I really can't get by with such a slow computer anymore.
Speaker 1: But if they hadn't ever you know started releasing crazy hot CPUs out to the public You know and and trying to catch up to Moore's law Then maybe programs would be written better, and we wouldn't have to worry about overheating and all that other bullshit.
Speaker 0: I'll point out that it's not all sloppy programming.
Speaker 0: I mean we do do more things with computers now We do.
Speaker 0: if I went back then and told myself you'll be editing audio in real time I would have laughed at myself and said that's impossible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but still even today if you the the processor that you can get that will run just fine with just one fan On it.
Speaker 1: you know with an uncooled Northbridge and uncooled video card is still pretty freakin badass.
Speaker 0: Well consider this.
Speaker 1: it's just the ones that the ones that need super cooling You know like the.
Speaker 1: if you've seen the new standard AMD heatsink for the new crazy AMD chips.
Speaker 1: It's like wicked psycho But that chip is also wicked psycho.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't know how many of you remember Ram bus Whatever fuckers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they made crazy insane fast RAM, but then they pulled some sort of intellectual property shenanigans.
Speaker 1: I never really understood the whole story.
Speaker 1: all I knew is that Rd Ram that Intel wanted you to use with some Pentium 4s is crap and no one uses it.
Speaker 0: here's the deal.
Speaker 0: to sum it up real real briefly it was developed by this company and Submitted to a consortium of whatever and approved as a standard.
Speaker 0: then the company after people agreed to this released their submarine patent said oh by the way, we already have patents on this yellow fails royalties.
Speaker 0: and Intel said yeah sure your Rams the best.
Speaker 0: and everyone else in the world said whoa fuck you.
Speaker 0: So only Intel and only certain Intel used this RAM and it was wicked fast.
Speaker 0: it was 800 megahertz like back in the day when a 400 megahertz thing was like unbelievable and It was so hot and fast that one you had to use it in pairs of two.
Speaker 0: You had to have two identical sticks for every bit of RAM you wanted To.
Speaker 0: you needed heat sinks on every piece of RAM or would overheat and break itself.
Speaker 0: Mmm, that's why it was relevant.
Speaker 0: heat sinks on RAM.
Speaker 1: Yeah It says here from my cursory examination of a Wikipedia article and on Ram bus is that they basically tried to make it to prevent Anyone else from making Rd Ram and then they charge a shit ton of money for Rd Ram.
Speaker 1: Oh apparently The n64 and the PlayStation through had Rd Ram.
Speaker 0: really I didn't know that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the PlayStation 3 will use Ram buses XDR memory because Ram buses technology was pretty good in a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: It seems that their technology was really fast really powerful Ram and a whole lot of it.
Speaker 1: But it was also kind of hot and a little latent Compared to DDR.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's good for certain kinds of applications.
Speaker 0: Yeah I only know the story of it as it pertains to PCs because when it comes to PCs there were fuckers.
Speaker 1: everyone hated them and it seems like they have some sort of bus interface, you know as opposed to whatever bus our computers use and That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Also called flex IO, but we could do a whole show on RAM one day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess.
Speaker 1: but yet
Speaker 0: the moral of the story is that oh my god Despite the fact that my video card is hot enough to burn my flesh and leave a blister and despite the fact that it's been That way for at least six or seven months and despite the fact that it's failed Mostly
Speaker 1: oh, is that is still the geforce 2 GTS?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Okay good get a new video card.
Speaker 0: I can still see the screen and I'm recording the podcast right now with this busted ass video card And I'm gonna keep using the busted ass visio card until next month when I buy a whole new computer.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So it's a race against the clock.
Speaker 0: What's gonna die first?
Speaker 0: my will to not buy a computer until March or my GPU Mm-hmm Yeah, so, uh, yeah ubercon yeah, that was fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah We went to ubercon a gaming convention in North Jersey last weekend and it sucked Driving there and back but there was fun.
Speaker 1: driving back was the worst thing ever, but the con itself was great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tomorrow is going to be ubercon day.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk almost entirely about ubercon and a gaming system called burning wheel Which the only way I can describe this is OMG OMG Heart heart heart.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: you know, I've never really attached to any other gaming systems other than like D&D because either they were larps and I'm not a fan or They were just D&D with different sets of numbers or it was just D&D with like a few things changed Like you die real easily or something like that.
Speaker 1: This is actually a whole different kind of RPG.
Speaker 1: That's like totally amazing and different and I think it's a lot more fun Yeah, and a lot less miniatures based calm and part of it is that the guy who designed it demoed it for us And then later we played it with him.
Speaker 0: and let me tell you this is an awesome, dude We're gonna have him on the show sometime soon to talk about burning wheel.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but we're not gonna talk about that today.
Speaker 0: tomorrow We'll talk about ubercon and a bit about burning wheel and as soon as we line up this interview We're gonna do a whole show on burning wheel by itself.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You probably won't talk a lot about burning wheel itself.
Speaker 1: tomorrow.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about the games that we talk about the game.
Speaker 0: We played.
Speaker 0: Yeah of it.
Speaker 1: Oh my omg, it's like because that'll be more like the experience of ubercon type of thing.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah So we're talking about RDRAM and their evil patent, whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, it seems like the Red Cross of all people is getting a little crazy with some trademark Trade.
Speaker 0: but wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Their trademark is one of the simplest things in the world.
Speaker 0: freaking Red Cross.
Speaker 1: Yeah it's just a red plus and they're going after video game companies who use it on med kits and medics and trucks and Helicopters and play.
Speaker 0: wait.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: That's like going after God, I don't even have an allergy.
Speaker 0: That's just are they?
Speaker 1: how come they haven't gone after like movies that have you know war movies Or anything?
Speaker 0: or maybe those movies pay a royalty or something.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'm sure there's some TV shows involving war that have Red Cross.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: This might be this might be because you know how.
Speaker 0: in trademark and copyright and patent law There's all those rules about you have to enforce it or try to enforce it or else you lose it.
Speaker 0: So they might not want to sue them but they have to sue them just to show that they're enforcing it.
Speaker 0: So they don't lose the trademark.
Speaker 1: Why don't they just lose it?
Speaker 1: It's just a red plus.
Speaker 1: No one doesn't know.
Speaker 0: I was about to say the Red Cross is a very good organization.
Speaker 0: They do good in the world.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine that they need to have their logo be theirs and sue people who don't have no use it without their permission.
Speaker 1: Everyone recognized everyone in the entire world, you know, except for people completely detached from society.
Speaker 1: Like I guess rainforest People, you know something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah or BoS users.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, that was a nerd joke.
Speaker 1: there they see the red plus and they know that means hospital healing.
Speaker 1: help Red Cross.
Speaker 0: You know what it might be the red crescent because they use the red crescent in a lot of places.
Speaker 1: do do they?
Speaker 1: it says It's.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's.
Speaker 0: I think it's a different organization, but it's almost the same.
Speaker 0: No It works in more in Muslim countries and such.
Speaker 1: But anyway, everyone sees that and they go.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know what that is There's no and it's not like they're used.
Speaker 1: the video games are using the Red Cross to signify the symbol of a fictional terrorist Organization.
Speaker 0: not like.
Speaker 0: you're playing World War two only instead of Nazis.
Speaker 0: You're fighting Red Cross workers.
Speaker 1: Yeah No, but I mean I could see.
Speaker 1: let's say I started selling.
Speaker 1: I made a movie cross t-shirts.
Speaker 1: Oh, no No Like.
Speaker 1: you use the Red Cross as a symbol to signify something other than what the Red Cross is Like.
Speaker 1: I made it the symbol of my new.
Speaker 1: I made it the logo For my new car company or all the cars had a big Red Cross on them instead of like, you know Ford has the blue oval or what if I made a game?
Speaker 0: Where you're like, maybe the bad guy is the evil head of the Red Cross who's doing evil.
Speaker 1: and they're not even like the Red Cross.
Speaker 1: He's the head of some organization organization that provides medical services.
Speaker 1: They know not even one the prize medical services.
Speaker 1: Like he's the head of some evil organization like you specter from James Bond, right?
Speaker 0: I'm saying straight out he uses but he uses the Red Cross as the logo.
Speaker 1: you see that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: I'm saying either way but in the end it shouldn't matter if I put on a Red Cross shirt and walk around my hometown No one's gonna think I'm working for the Red Cross.
Speaker 1: Well, they might.
Speaker 1: they might think you're an EMT or something.
Speaker 0: Well, they might think I'm an EMT because I I have this.
Speaker 0: it's weird but act a little aside.
Speaker 0: but at uber con we were sitting around in the lobby outside the reg desk relaxing and talking about cons and the staff lady from work on came over and Basically said I couldn't help but over here and she handed me a piece of paper and said write down all your suggestions.
Speaker 0: We wanna we want your advice And welcome you're talking about cons in general.
Speaker 1: we're really talking about uber con.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: we seem to give all this aura of we're experts because things like that happen fairly often.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I think it is.
Speaker 0: It's a combination of loud and opinionated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's nothing to do with people thinking you're an EMT cuz.
Speaker 0: well What if I was wearing a Red Cross shirt and I was talking about, uh, how many MT then people think you're one?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I don't know what the Red Cross out to.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's only because they have to do this or they lose Trademark and I'll bet.
Speaker 0: a lawyer for them said you can't lose the trademark and I'll bet.
Speaker 0: no one even question Why they need the trademark.
Speaker 0: They just said oh we have to keep it.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: That's my best guess whatever.
Speaker 1: So there's a thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, so you want to do all the news today?
Speaker 0: I guess that's fine.
Speaker 0: You can talk about this one, too.
Speaker 0: I'll just I'll provide witty banter and commentary.
Speaker 0: and I sort of there's this thing called HD CP High bandwidth.
Speaker 0: there should be a be there but they're assholes.
Speaker 0: whatever digital content protection.
Speaker 0: Hi, yeah, I've been with In the in the same vein of anything that has an acronym nowadays is bad Especially if there's a lot of D's in it or C's Like, you know DMCA ending is a is also bad.
Speaker 0: Yep, CD CBD tPA.
Speaker 1: This is one of those though this ends in peanut a. but anyway what this does is Let's say you have a very High resolution movie Like the one in a blu-ray or an HD DVD.
Speaker 1: or let's see of a very high resolution video game on a DVD or whatever that you installed your hard drive and You want to play it on a high resolution monitor?
Speaker 1: Well, it seems that in present times we have this thing called the analog hole which pretty much means at some point The signal has to go the video signal has to go from your computer or DVD player or whatever To the monitor.
Speaker 0: So if I want to copy whatever copy protected shit They give me I go out of this hole into my handy-dandy recording device and have a perfect copy from there on out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the monitor can't really do the monitor itself can't do any sort of decryption or Yet any.
Speaker 1: yeah, it can't do anything.
Speaker 1: All it can do is take a raw video signal and display it.
Speaker 1: So because it gets a rod a video signal plugged into it via a wire of some sorts You can make a device which takes in that raw video signal and writes it down to some sort of storage like a hard drive or a magnetic tape or what have you and You can copy anything.
Speaker 1: Well, they know that this is a problem.
Speaker 1: it's not a problem.
Speaker 1: it's supposed to be that way.
Speaker 1: That's the way it should be the way it is now.
Speaker 1: But movie companies and such think this is a problem and they don't want you getting such high resolution copies Copied perfectly because you have a digital connection between your whatever player computer and your monitor.
Speaker 0: Now their solution to this is just a whole new level of ass hattery.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's called HD CPA HDCP high bandwidth digital content protection HDCP goddamn.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter what it stands for.
Speaker 0: It's just like the CBD tPA.
Speaker 0: I still remember what that stands for CCCA, I don't know what they called it CBD tPA CD BTPA whatever.
Speaker 0: it's all bad consumer Broadband and digital fuck it, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah something that sucks.
Speaker 1: So what they're gonna do is they're gonna make monitors that are HD CP Like this monitor has HD CP and then they'll say this video card has HD CP or this DVD player has HD CP and this cable box is HD CP and only things that have HD CP will plugged into things that have HD CP will allow you to use the ultra high resolutions.
Speaker 0: So they'll make sure that the analog hole is mostly closed or they won't give you the high bandwidth high resolution.
Speaker 1: The way it will work is your.
Speaker 1: let's say I have an HD CP DVD player and HD CP LCD HD TV.
Speaker 1: television was a lot of letters.
Speaker 1: Player will read the disc will encrypt it send it to the TV The TV will decrypt it and display it so that if I tried to record What came out of the DVD player to a device it would be all encrypted and I don't have to decrypt it somehow.
Speaker 0: now I'm not of course.
Speaker 0: either Do some magic electronics and hook something up to the cathode ray tube and get the data from there and reconstruct it or you know point a video camera That's synced up properly at the monitor, but you're still gonna lose a lot and they don't care about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you unless you break this encryption somehow It's going to be pretty difficult to get the exact data of the high-resolution video copied to something else.
Speaker 0: no, this doesn't seem so bad on its own because you know, all right, they're doing this to us fuckers and Both ATI and Nvidia have.
Speaker 0: they have support already and all their new GPUs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even like I think on the level of CPUs like AMD and Intel is this support I think well The main article like the main thing we're gonna talk about is that ATI and Nvidia all their cards now say they support this And you know what?
Speaker 0: That's a goddamn lie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Well, here's what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Apparently if you this this is not.
Speaker 1: I don't have a hundred.
Speaker 1: this isn't 100% sure information but it's pretty sure.
Speaker 1: if you buy like an Nvidia video card in the store that has HDCP and Build a computer with it and plug it into an HDCP monitor, by the way There's not really so many HDCP monitors.
Speaker 1: I don't think there are actually any.
Speaker 1: there might be very very few like.
Speaker 0: well I know is I will not be buying 100. fuck you all ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah They They won't work.
Speaker 1: if you buy an HDCP video card and make a computer with it It won't work even though it says it on the box.
Speaker 0: It says HDCP on the box.
Speaker 0: It says it in the manual.
Speaker 0: It says it on their website.
Speaker 0: It says it supports it because it does support it.
Speaker 0: But not really.
Speaker 1: it only supports it won't support it because if you're the kind of person who builds a computer Then that means you're the kind of person who can probably you know break it or copy it so they won't make it work.
Speaker 0: So basically you'll only be able to use HDCP protected content if you buy an HDCP monitor and you buy a dollar gateway or an HDCP TV or a Sony Sony computer.
Speaker 0: so basically there's be computer.
Speaker 0: They've realized that Hobbyists and people like us will always find a way around whatever shenanigans they try to pull.
Speaker 0: So they're just pulling the plug on us hobbyists and only providing this content to.
Speaker 0: you know, the mouth breathers now.
Speaker 1: Here's the worst thing In Vista.
Speaker 1: Here's another great story about Oh God fucking Windows Vista.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be all HDCP action.
Speaker 1: So you're not gonna even be able to do You know the full resolution that's possible to do Perhaps for your computer's power unless you have an HDCP video card and HDCP monitor.
Speaker 0: So they're enforcing this arbitrary standard to trick you into getting a thing that will prevent you from watching things You want to watch later or at least watching them at high resolution?
Speaker 1: So you have the highest resolution monitor in the world and the most powerful video card in the world and the most powerful computer in The world but it will only go up to a certain resolution.
Speaker 1: You'll only be able to play games and watch movies up to a certain resolution Unless they're HDCP enabled video card and monitor on a pre-built computer And thus you won't be able to copy anything now.
Speaker 0: here is why I don't care.
Speaker 0: This is rims.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit section.
Speaker 0: I'm even gonna make some music for this in the future because whenever something like this comes up I always give my rant at the end about you know what.
Speaker 0: here's why I don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna make that a bit.
Speaker 0: I just thought of that right now.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get my own freaking.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: music and everything alright, but basically music has to just sound like yeah Okay, I don't care what the fuck you're all bad to put you saying that.
Speaker 1: you put you saying stuff like that over it.
Speaker 0: Maybe I will.
Speaker 0: yeah, I'll make a little jingle.
Speaker 0: I'll play a little ditty on the piano, and I'll sing something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, give me a few weeks to put that together.
Speaker 1: sound terrible with you singing, but hey I can sing a little bit.
Speaker 0: I can sing anyone.
Speaker 0: any song where there are no more than three unique notes in that song I can sing it fucking great.
Speaker 0: Hey get outside of that, and I have some issues.
Speaker 0: But all right the reason I don't care is that one.
Speaker 0: this only affects HDCP protected content and I've noticed that almost everything I watch is Either old cold crap technology.
Speaker 0: You know like DVDs VHS whatever or it's something pirated that I just download from the internet anyway Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I can watch that or whatever resolution.
Speaker 0: I want HDCP or not.
Speaker 0: yep - I have no interest in any of this new content.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna buy videos from someone like Google or Microsoft.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna watch the funny things on Google video for free.
Speaker 0: yep I'm not gonna buy on HD CD.
Speaker 0: Whatever I'm gonna download a freaking mp3 or a fleck mm-hmm and This has never anything to do with audio.
Speaker 0: This is high-resolution video, but blu-ray HD DVD.
Speaker 0: I note that current DVD is already more than enough as far as I'm concerned mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so I really have no desire for blu-ray at all.
Speaker 0: and Why would upgrade normally?
Speaker 0: because blu-ray is better except for all this DRM bullshit, so that's the end of that.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty much gonna stop in terms of consumer entertainment technology as soon as this stuff comes into play.
Speaker 1: We just got a new TV, so you're not replacing that anytime soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, our TV is not even HD because HD just isn't even really a standard anymore.
Speaker 0: It's just this DRM encumbered pile of.
Speaker 1: it's not DRM encumbered yet yet.
Speaker 0: However as soon as the DRM stuff comes out all the old HD TV HD TV won't even work.
Speaker 1: with the new stuff we don't really even have anything that would output HD because what we don't have a Cable box yeah, we don't have blu-ray, and we never will.
Speaker 1: yeah The only thing we would ever have that would be HD is like if we got an Xbox 360 or ps3 for free.
Speaker 0: Oh, but it turns out that half the Xbox 360 games aren't really HD either.
Speaker 0: They're just up sampled.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh, and we really wanted we could get that crazy DVD player that up samples everything for you Whatever, but so seriously don't protest.
Speaker 0: revolution won't be HD Yeah, but don't write letters to people.
Speaker 0: this isn't a law or anything.
Speaker 0: Don't don't do the stuff that people always do when acronyms like this come out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not a law.
Speaker 1: It's a technology that they're trying to make.
Speaker 0: yeah Devices use you know what.
Speaker 0: let it come.
Speaker 0: This is only gonna hurt people and then once people start getting hurt by this stuff They're gonna start caring and that'll be the end of that, and if they don't start caring just live your life free of Consumer entertainment.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling what's gonna happen is that?
Speaker 1: People might buy like a DVD player with HDCP, and they might buy a TV with it.
Speaker 1: But they won't know if they have a mismatch and they won't care like they'll think it's HD or whatever they you know.
Speaker 0: What was that statistic?
Speaker 0: something like 50 or 60 percent of people who have HD TVs aren't actually watching HDTV because they didn't hook it.
Speaker 1: Yes, or they don't know or they don't notice yeah, and they think it's HD TV because the TVs do look better.
Speaker 1: just default Way the technology is supposed to function.
Speaker 1: Theoretically is that if you don't have the HDCP support that it would just go with the lower resolution.
Speaker 0: So you don't even know it's broken?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might.
Speaker 1: there might be some sort of message.
Speaker 1: who knows?
Speaker 0: plus I point out that there's so much more and more content is coming out on the internet that isn't protected by anything.
Speaker 0: I mean we're gonna put DRM on our podcast.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean I listen to more podcasts than I ever watch TV even when I was a crazy TV watcher.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I mean and it's just those are just mp3s.
Speaker 1: I don't have to worry about crap like this.
Speaker 0: yeah anime ski various torrent sites You can get all the entertainment you need from the internet.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's like you're gonna prevent me from copying the stuff that I don't watch anyway.
Speaker 0: Fantastic yeah, so things of the day.
Speaker 0: I I found this a long time ago, and I was really stretching for a thing of the day today And then I used this site because I use it often for reasons I'm not going to get into but they're much nerdier than you would expect And it's basically just a nice Gathering of all sorts of British slang and it explains what these phrases mean and how to use it.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's really cool and really useful if you happen to be playing a a cockney kind of British Thug person who's also a fairy dragon in a Dungeons & Dragons game because you're a nerd like me.
Speaker 1: Yes, exactly like you.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought it was cool and - cuz we actually it's funny But we have multiple listeners in the UK and in Australia and places which we didn't expect, but I think is awesome.
Speaker 1: You ever see the third Austin Powers movie?
Speaker 0: Gold member.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, I never.
Speaker 1: actually I think I saw the whole thing, but I didn't really pay attention to the whole thing.
Speaker 1: But there's one part where Austin and his dad are there and they say and it's like wait, we're both British Let's speak proper or something like that.
Speaker 1: And then they start talking in a way where you can't possibly comprehend anything they're saying and there are subtitles.
Speaker 1: You know, but it's like the crazy British blah.
Speaker 1: You know where they use other words in places of other words.
Speaker 1: You just don't know what the hell's going.
Speaker 0: Cockney rhyming slang.
Speaker 0: I actually learned it.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell it was But it was just nuts and there was subtitles and it was funny Because I read a bunch of cockney rhyming slang and then I figured out what was going on.
Speaker 0: And now I get it and it's actually kind of clever.
Speaker 0: The problem is because actually a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 0: I did it at work I made a little funny slang like that because it's really kind of a cool bait.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna explain it it's real simple.
Speaker 0: basically I did it and I said something and I don't think Americans can really get it.
Speaker 0: I Just don't.
Speaker 0: I can't
Speaker 1: even get it and I'm smart
Speaker 0: if I explained it to you Which I'll do off the air or maybe I'll do it on the air if we ever do a show on like language or slang Or anything like that, you know, it's it's not difficult and it's actually really clever I think
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: but I thought this was cool because basically I play this character and I use it to type in a very authentic way Cuz I yeah, I also play the game online.
Speaker 0: So doubly geeky.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Triply really, so Unlike most geeks, I think at least I'm pretty sure I'm a fan of you know, Godzilla He goes, you know kaiju big battle.
Speaker 1: Well kaiju big vowel doesn't.
Speaker 1: I guess it kind of whatever it involves kaiju.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's for sure.
Speaker 0: That's all that matters.
Speaker 1: So My favorite guy is Ghidorah which is the three-headed dragon guy.
Speaker 0: really I'm more of a Mothra man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Mothra mother is my second favorite.
Speaker 1: In fact, even though Ghidorah is my favorite monster I will say that the best movie is Godzilla vs.
Speaker 1: Mothra.
Speaker 1: that is that is guaranteed.
Speaker 1: anyway The thing is there's a book in the from a long time ago, I think from 1967 called The anatom an anatomical guide to monsters as a Japanese book and it contains all the monsters like cut open.
Speaker 1: So you can see they're innards.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's kind of like that thing A guy did a while ago where he made the internal skeletal structures of a whole bunch of cartoon characters.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I like that.
Speaker 0: That's pretty badass.
Speaker 1: So there's a picture here from an old Japanese book that shows like where Gamera's brain is.
Speaker 0: does Gamera have a lightning sack of some kind?
Speaker 1: I Don't know but he's got like these four.
Speaker 1: It seems like they're digestive portions, but they might not be one of the breath weapon generators.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one of them seems to have red stuff.
Speaker 1: one of them has.
Speaker 1: it seems like a red liquid.
Speaker 1: one has a white powder One is some black bits and one has some other sort of white rocky bits And I think that those combined with this other gland over here He like he must cough him
Speaker 0: up and then you're already putting more thought into this than you should be.
Speaker 1: That's why this is the thing of the day and it's so cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is so.
Speaker 0: if you're wondering what Gamera's guts look like and and you're not man enough to cut him open and look So, uh We totally copped out today.
Speaker 0: We don't have anything to talk about.
Speaker 0: That's why we kind of went long in the news bits.
Speaker 1: We suck.
Speaker 0: we were gonna talk about DRM, but we're still tired from freaking over Khan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we cuz DRM kind of tied into the other news.
Speaker 0: But all we could say about DRM is that it's bad and we hate it.
Speaker 0: But we don't care cuz it doesn't affect us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just sucks.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that was it.
Speaker 0: That's the show today.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm fire bad Dr.
Speaker 1: I mean after the drive home Saturday, we're still totally shot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So for those of you who don't live in the Northeast corridor We went to UberCon.
Speaker 0: we drove there Saturday morning and we left Sunday morning.
Speaker 1: well Saturday night basically midnight Yeah, 1230 to be exact and we knew there was gonna be a crazy snow, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we know it's gonna snow, but we hadn't really looked and it was actually a huge fucking blizzard.
Speaker 1: Well, I knew it was gonna be huge fucking blizzard.
Speaker 0: I guess we just didn't prepare our things.
Speaker 1: I didn't care.
Speaker 1: I just drive home and it'll be alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then we actually got on the road.
Speaker 1: We had to go like 20 30 miles an hour the whole way.
Speaker 0: There were no other cars other than there's one car that almost spun out and hit us.
Speaker 1: No, I was driving in a brand new car.
Speaker 1: The worst thing about anything was that it couldn't see the lines on the road.
Speaker 1: That was the absolute worst part of it.
Speaker 0: Oh and SUVs passing us at like 60.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: There's three inches of snow on the ground.
Speaker 0: They can't break.
Speaker 0: They're sliding all over the place.
Speaker 0: They almost hit us, but now they can go 60.
Speaker 0: There was nothing worse than not being able to see the lines Because I Submit that it was worse to be lost in Jersey unable to find the Garden State because Jersey does not have signs for its roads.
Speaker 1: Surgeons of signs.
Speaker 1: the signs all suck and you can't make a u-turn without going on some wacky road.
Speaker 0: So sure Here's our dilemma.
Speaker 0: We're on a road and we see a little green circle sign that says Garden State Parkway this way exit.
Speaker 0: So we get on this little exit and we follow the exit to its conclusion.
Speaker 0: We see no more signs along this exit.
Speaker 0: The exit took us back to the same road where we then saw the same exit again, so he tried it again Sure enough.
Speaker 1: There's a sign that says turn right for the Garden State.
Speaker 1: So he turned right.
Speaker 1: after we turn right we can have to go straight or right.
Speaker 1: we can.
Speaker 1: you know There's two ways to go and it doesn't say which one of those is the Garden State and both of us taken back to the same fucking road.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it sucked.
Speaker 0: we'd read went around it like three times.
Speaker 0: then we just gave up and parked in a parking lot for a minute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a recruit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was hellish to a gas station to recoup again.
Speaker 1: Then I just kept going down the road until I got onto 87 north.
Speaker 0: We figured we just keep heading north.
Speaker 0: the worst case.
Speaker 0: we hit i-84 because it goes across the whole frickin country.
Speaker 1: This is all country.
Speaker 0: It goes across the whole country as far as we're concerned.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we tried to go past a spot where our i-84 is doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: We're lost.
Speaker 0: We're in like, Tennessee.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, we might have just 84 it we could have gone on some road.
Speaker 1: We're like 84 just kind of went on a little bridge over us or we went over it on a bridge and then we didn't Even know.
Speaker 0: yeah, and you know what.
Speaker 0: then we did Canada.
Speaker 0: They have to stop us at the border.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then we'd be alright Not to mention the fact that we've been gaming all day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had just finished a four-hour game which was like about tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of the best for our games ever.
Speaker 1: So we're shot to this week, but we do have.
Speaker 1: we're good for like two or three more weeks now.
Speaker 1: We've got stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like tomorrow uber con straight up like a whole day of uber con Wednesday.
Speaker 0: We've seen some frickin anime too many anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there may or may not be a show Thursday because I'm going out of town again this time for katsu con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not a cop-out.
Speaker 1: That's not here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so been regardless.
Speaker 0: You'll probably get an extra long week next week and you'll probably get an extra long show tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus all these cons will bring really quality episodes.
Speaker 0: when we talk about what happened at the cons Yeah, I mean uber con lat this previous weekend katsu con this coming weekend New York comic-con the next weekend.
Speaker 0: the weekend after that.
Speaker 0: We might have all our friends in the world coming to our house and messing it up like we tend to have.
Speaker 1: I think the non Con is that weekend?
Speaker 1: I got a check.
Speaker 0: Oh great another con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if we're gonna go to that or not.
Speaker 1: We got to see.
Speaker 0: yeah, at least all the other cons are far off.
Speaker 0: I mean kinetic cons aways out yet.
Speaker 0: Oh two cons aways out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It's con season.
Speaker 1: So good episodes, even though we might miss a few like this.
Speaker 0: Though keep in mind that katsu con if I get a thing in time I'm gonna be interviewing some people there just for the show about cons, whatever but starting with Tora con We're gonna be doing full-on live shows at these conventions.
Speaker 1: Yeah So don't be surprised if an mp3 gets downloaded on a Saturday or a Sunday from your feed reader Catcher or whatever you got going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz once we start we're gonna start going to these cons in an official capacity soon.
Speaker 0: all the cars we've gone to now We were gonna go to anyway.
Speaker 0: We just happen to be doing a podcast so we might talk about it at the con, but we're not there as geek nights.
Speaker 0: We're going to these cons coming up as geek nights like rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Where are those two guys?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm That's all we got today's.
Speaker 0: today's a loss.
Speaker 0: Thursday may or may not be a loss.
Speaker 0: I guarantee tomorrow be worth listening to because while it's gonna be a gaming day We we did a lot of stuff that I think everyone wants to hear about.
Speaker 1: Everyone needs a week off.
Speaker 1: I mean the fact that we do four podcasts a week is insane compared to most people.
Speaker 0: This is our 58th podcast not counting the ten or so we did before we put the site up.
Speaker 1: There are podcasts that have been going for years and years and years.
Speaker 1: Well, not years but over a year at least that are still on episode like they just managed to get episode 50 People do.
Speaker 1: weekly podcasts who've been doing it for a year are on episode 52 We're on 58 and we've been going for like a few months.
Speaker 0: That's why we're adding those feeds for all the different days because our anime day is a whole anime podcast basically Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: We just it's.
Speaker 0: basically we're doing four separate podcasts.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the fact that we're not dead yet I think really speaks highly the fact that we can take abuse and stay up late every night.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I don't know how we do this.
Speaker 1: I do it laying down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I sit in my chair anyway, so yeah when I redo this site Everything should be easier.
Speaker 1: and if you have any questions, you're not sure how podcast subscribing works I guess you might not be listening then.
Speaker 0: but yeah, though we're starting to see more and more people are moving to the feed so you guys are either learning how to use feed things or We're getting new listeners and you guys are leaving or I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you don't know how to use podcast feeds just ask us or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if enough people ask let's do a show on how podcasts work like on a fundamental level.
Speaker 1: Oh and in the forum There's a thread.
Speaker 1: it's sticky It's at the top and it says like introduce yourself or something like that.
Speaker 0: Don't feel obligated to because I know a lot of people lurk I lurk.
Speaker 0: I mean I still lurk to this day.
Speaker 0: I've read a cut.
Speaker 0: there's a webcomic called college rumors from hell that I've read for the last like six years and I lurk in the forums to this day.
Speaker 0: I have never posted.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but You don't have to go and say who you are whatever if you don't want to.
Speaker 1: But I think it'd be really cool if everyone said who they were in there because all the people I mean even the ones who?
Speaker 0: Haven't done publicly.
Speaker 0: the people we've gotten to know in our forums are really cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of them I say 99% of them actually the only ones who might not be cool are ones that we already know.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, and now that everyone out there is trying to figure out is he talking about me?
Speaker 0: No, if you're thinking that we're not talking about you.
Speaker 1: Also, you might notice that on the right side of the home page right now under my links Scott's links There's a frapper map.
Speaker 1: It's been there for a long time But you can go in there and say where you're from and it'll put a little like a thumbtack on.
Speaker 0: I totally forgot.
Speaker 0: you set That up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I totally forgot also.
Speaker 1: I just thought of it.
Speaker 0: Just yeah, believe me once we set the site up more We're gonna have like our own flicker like just for geek nights and all this sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: That's gonna bring the little community around the show together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna remake this site to be super awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm working on it at home.
Speaker 1: And as soon as it's ready, I can upload it in the switch.
Speaker 0: You won't even notice because it'll be so seamless and we got a whole bunch of artists working in their part-time Kind of toward getting us some cool logos and we're gonna get rid of that geek nights neon thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna get a real logo that doesn't suck and you'll have little pictures on your iPods and everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if any of you out there are artistically inclined and you want to add to the pool I can't promise we'll use whatever logo you come up with with for us but one if you need reference photos we can provide them and To if we ever make t-shirts or anything anyone who's art we use or anyone who freaking sent us art I'll probably get a free one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyone who I'll tell you what.
Speaker 1: everyone who has some sort of logo making ability.
Speaker 1: if you try to make the geek night's logo, which should be Something that looks good in a square because we have to use square pictures for iPod picture
Speaker 0: For the site like our big graphics we actually have people who are working on those really so don't worry about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well not like.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah If you want to do something that's like the identifying trademark logo of geek nights if you can come up with it And it's good then you'll win something.
Speaker 1: We'll give you some awesome something that's worth it.
Speaker 0: Well, let me put it this way.
Speaker 0: You won't use a lot of bandwidth and a lot of time Between the two of us.
Speaker 0: We're actually fairly wealthy Like we're not wealthy in terms of.
Speaker 0: you know wealthy people don't have mansions and Ferraris.
Speaker 0: No, we'd like them, but we do not want for geekery at all.
Speaker 0: so we can come up with some fairly awesome prizes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean just think about like something that you've been dying to buy like I don't know video game or maybe a manga comic Some like.
Speaker 0: even better if you guys get the word out if we hit a thousand listeners We'll put together some sort of awesome prize, and then we'll give it to someone somehow.
Speaker 1: yeah so Try to make a geek night's logo of awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you can't tell we're just kind of filling in here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, heading out the podcast a little it better than no podcast like some people.
Speaker 0: yeah Cuz you know there are nights.
Speaker 0: I mean half most nights.
Speaker 0: We come home.
Speaker 0: We're like yeah I'm talking about this and this and this.
Speaker 0: the podcast can be freaking awesome But every now and then we come home when we sit here like god damn it Let's just not do one, but we do it anyway.
Speaker 1: I don't know how penny arcade does it.
Speaker 1: not only do they consistently do three nights a week, but it's always awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there seem to be two philosophy well three philosophies.
Speaker 0: There's the third philosophy of just put crap out and it sucks, but like penny arcade They consistently produce something awesome, and they force themselves to nothing better than that.
Speaker 0: But then there's like Perry Bible fellowship which updates whenever But it only updates when the guy has a great idea and does it.
Speaker 0: so every one is a perfect gem Always quality, but you never know when.
Speaker 1: yeah Then we have ours.
Speaker 1: we always do it no matter what and sometimes.
Speaker 1: It's good sometimes It's yeah like.
Speaker 0: honestly recently someone reviewed geek nights And they happen to listen to two episodes where we just bitched at each other and argued yep.
Speaker 0: So I guess the fact that he still had fairly positive feelings toward us was a good sign.
Speaker 0: I think so I mean we At least now that Scott drives to work instead of taking the train and he leaves late And then he leaves work early.
Speaker 0: We have a lot more time now.
Speaker 1: You know how long that last is.
Speaker 1: no one at the office.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: supposedly more people are gonna be there.
Speaker 1: So we'll see what happens when more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see what happens if I end up working in the city instead of where I work now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we'll see what happens if more people work at the office that I work at eventually because then I might not be able To just run away from it.
Speaker 0: But I can tell you we're gonna keep doing four days a week because everyone who everyone actually gives us feedback says it's great.
Speaker 0: We've never had anyone give us bad feedback, so if you don't like geek nights tell us Because we're just assuming we're awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you don't like it This will probably be the only episode you've ever listened to and ever do listen to.
Speaker 1: If that's the case listen to another one, please because this one's not so good.
Speaker 0: What was a really good episode we did?
Speaker 0: Most of the ones on anime are good.
Speaker 0: Most of the reviews of video games are good Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: actually the one pot just from Google You know poking around our most linked to podcast is the one we did on Pseudoscience when we had our guest scientist Peter Olson.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean we're gonna have Pete on the show more because Pete is a. he's a good friend of ours.
Speaker 0: independent of that he's a. he's a fairly respected scientist at a government agency and That's a great way of spinning it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well.
Speaker 0: He's respected by the people who know him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he does work for a government agency, and he is a scientist.
Speaker 0: I in no way lied.
Speaker 1: No, you in no way lied.
Speaker 1: however people misinterpret that and think like you know what I'm a friggin spin doctor.
Speaker 0: What do you want?
Speaker 1: Dr.. Spin Here let's see what the most downloaded episode is recently.
Speaker 0: yeah, but the February 2nd 2006.
Speaker 0: February 2nd 2006.
Speaker 1: what the hell was that it's been downloaded 104 times in the month of February, so it's the most downloaded episode for February as of today.
Speaker 0: Well the February 6th podcast was in fact the one on instant messaging.
Speaker 1: I Think I said February 2nd not 6th.
Speaker 0: Oh you said 6th.
Speaker 1: did I all right?
Speaker 0: February 2nd is toys of our youth.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was a good one.
Speaker 0: That was a good one.
Speaker 1: all those of our youth episodes like toys and then TV of our youth and those are good episodes.
Speaker 0: They're not particularly insightful, but everyone who gives us feedback Just says that we're bastards because we send them down some sort of horrible Nostalgia fest and then they try to find all their old toys and play with them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely nostalgia in the house.
Speaker 0: Alright, I think we've done enough filler.
Speaker 0: so tomorrow ubercon burning wheel Wednesday too terrible anime Most likely.
Speaker 1: no let's watch a good one.
Speaker 1: I think what's the one we just watched today?
Speaker 0: if I finish last exile?
Speaker 1: Yeah, finish it.
Speaker 0: I'll finish it tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I might not have time before katsu khan.
Speaker 0: alright You know we'll talk about that one.
Speaker 0: We just watched the good one the slow one.
Speaker 1: Yeah the slow one It wasn't that good.
Speaker 1: It was slow, but it was better than most.
Speaker 0: yeah See you're getting a peek now all you listeners out there into what we talk about when we're not on the air Because we're just kind of talking it when we're trying to figure out what to talk about.
Speaker 0: yeah someday I think we're gonna do an episode.
Speaker 0: We'll do two episodes, but on Monday.
Speaker 0: We'll do the episode and on Thursday We'll play back.
Speaker 0: the recording will make of us talking about what we're gonna do in the episode Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I think that would be a good set episodes cuz actually we just Monday we did.
Speaker 0: I don't know well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the thing is we're doing it now.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Yeah, but there have been two.
Speaker 0: the two biggest things that people have requested of me of geek nights that we do a show about Is one people keep asking me to do a show on how to do a podcast.
Speaker 0: like what equipment we use?
Speaker 0: yeah?
Speaker 1: There's so many podcasts.
Speaker 1: That's have that information.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing and there's so many websites that have been information.
Speaker 0: half those websites Honestly just give wrong or bad information or bad advice or the people don't know what they're talking about.
Speaker 0: and the other half Assume that you have infinite money, and they're just like yeah, buy this buy this buy this.
Speaker 0: So when we finally do that episode?
Speaker 0: We can tell you how to do an awesome podcast that sounds at least as good as geek nights for less than $200.
Speaker 1: yeah the thing is if your podcast You don't you mean doesn't even have to be as quality as ours.
Speaker 1: a lot of the podcasts I listen to which are more popular than this one are made with less money and less equipment and sound shittier.
Speaker 1: It's all about the content.
Speaker 1: You know the content is so good that I can suffer there.
Speaker 1: You know slightly less quality audio.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the only reason our sounds as good as it does is just that we actually do know more than a little bit.
Speaker 0: We have a look we have enough knowledge to be dangerous when it comes to audio crap And we're learning a lot.
Speaker 0: if you
Speaker 1: want to make a podcast all you really have to do is plug a microphone into your computer fiddle with the recording volume So you don't go too crazy loud or too crazy quiet that no one can hear or that it breaks all the time with too loud.
Speaker 1: You said it just right and then you push record and you talk.
Speaker 1: then you turn the wave into an mp3 and you upload it.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's it.
Speaker 0: and if you want to go one step above that by just buy like a $20 microphone from RadioShack Because that'll beat the crap out of the $5 microphone.
Speaker 0: You've got now.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean the logic headsets.
Speaker 1: microphones actually aren't so bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if you get that stick creative Microphone that comes out of the $2 thing.
Speaker 1: There's no good.
Speaker 0: That's probably the worst microphone money cannot buy.
Speaker 1: yeah All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah but the other thing that people in requesting the most is Now I forget because I'm stupid You are huh an episode of a how stupid you are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that'd be awesome.
Speaker 0: Awesome All right, and the other one that was requested a lot and for all of you since this episode is just blah at this point Anyway, I just cut out a whole section of me sitting there trying to remember what the other most requested one was.
Speaker 0: It was a show that people want to know where we came from.
Speaker 0: Like why.
Speaker 0: this is the whole story of us in the front row crew Yep, which we could do a show on that.
Speaker 0: We've talked about it bit by bit and if you've listened to the whole show Like from the beginning you could probably piece most of it together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you don't know what the front row crew is or who we are who our friends are and all that Someday, they'll be.
Speaker 1: it's probably Thursday episode.
Speaker 0: on that Yeah We were trying to save episodes from that like that for when we're in rare form because some days we're good to go some days We're not today.
Speaker 0: We weren't.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Alright, that's it.
Speaker 1: I'm going to bed.
Speaker 0: So am I but I gotta do friggin post-production.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna brush my teeth.
Speaker 0: Yeah my last bit.
Speaker 0: This is the last thing I'm gonna say.
Speaker 0: I'm ordering a dynamic range compressor a hardware one to put between the mixer and the computer and to sum it up very simply it is going to one make the podcast sound a lot better and Two is going to cut my post-production time in half, which means I'm gonna get more sleep Which means I'm gonna be able to say better more insightful things.
Speaker 0: Maybe yeah, we'll see or I'll just stay up later doing other crap like playing Phoenix, right?
Speaker 0: Like I'm gonna do right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm probably gonna brush my teeth and play that.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy 4 even though it's slightly annoying.
Speaker 0: Yeah It gets less annoying later on when the plot is more is so Engrossing that you start forgetting about the stuff that bothers you in the game.
Speaker 1: I think I'm gonna walk around and level up a little tiny bit even though I don't want to but I I think I have to Yeah, you might want to do that before you go up the other mountain.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: All right, we're done.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.