Speaker 1: It's Tuesday March 14th, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about our favorite video game.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, if you can hear this that means that libsyn is yet again working Adequately, I suppose it's
Speaker 1: quite surprising That you know there's so many people in the forums at libsyn having trouble that it would make you believe Going there that libsyn is super broken, but really all the users are just super stupid.
Speaker 0: I mean there were a lot of problems with libsyn recently that they've also apparently recently resolved.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but still the amount the sheer numbers of people who did not know what the hell they were doing is near staggering.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the main problem is that libsyn really doesn't offer any documentation whatsoever and The only support there is is hidden in their forums contributed by I guess their employees.
Speaker 0: I'm really not sure.
Speaker 1: Well, they have this there.
Speaker 0: you.
Speaker 1: libsyn is using this business model that I learned about recently.
Speaker 1: It's known as the.
Speaker 1: It's the gym membership model.
Speaker 1: what you do is you get a whole bunch of people to join and pay money But then only a small portion of those people actually take advantage of these services that you have sold them.
Speaker 1: It's like if everyone who had a membership to like Gold's gym Actually showed up to work out.
Speaker 1: They'd be out of business so fast you wouldn't even know what to do.
Speaker 0: You know the fact that only like they count on the fat guy who has a New Year's resolution Gets a year membership and then doesn't come back after March.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like as long as only 20% of the people go they're all set They don't have to make a bigger gym or anything.
Speaker 1: So libsyn is doing the same thing.
Speaker 1: They're hoping all these people will pay money.
Speaker 0: Well, at least that's what you're assuming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's the only way they could be making money off of this.
Speaker 1: giving you infinite bandwidth.
Speaker 0: Come on infinite bandwidth isn't really that expensive.
Speaker 1: It's pretty expensive.
Speaker 1: What they do is they have a whole bunch of people who either you know say they're gonna do X podcast But do much fewer or they have many very much fewer listeners.
Speaker 1: Or they have people who sign up and don't actually podcast at all or stop podcasting.
Speaker 0: And well, you stop podcasting you stop paying almost immediately.
Speaker 0: if you're smart enough to stop paying It's real hard to accidentally continue to pay because it's PayPal.
Speaker 1: Alright, but doesn't it just automatically subtract everything?
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one's gonna leave libsyn going if they don't have a podcast.
Speaker 1: people leave MMOs going and they don't know.
Speaker 0: No people leave MMOs going because they don't want to lose their character.
Speaker 0: if they ever want to play again.
Speaker 1: people leave libsyn going Cuz.
Speaker 1: they don't lose their podcast.
Speaker 0: I really doubt that.
Speaker 0: I don't think that that's a significant number at all of their membership.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: These people are so dumb.
Speaker 1: They don't even know how to use the thing.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know how to use it.
Speaker 0: I had to read this forum post to try to guess at how half the libsyn crap works.
Speaker 0: Well, okay, they don't document it at all.
Speaker 0: You click upload you upload it Yeah, and they have all this other stuff like.
Speaker 0: I had to go in and find the crap web page They made for us and get rid of it.
Speaker 0: So no one got confused All right.
Speaker 1: But anyway That's how they're making money is a whole day.
Speaker 1: a few people are using it a whole lot and using a ton of bandwidth and they're Being supported by the people who aren't using so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well at least that's your assumption.
Speaker 0: We don't really know.
Speaker 0: I mean, we don't know what their books look like.
Speaker 1: if they're not doing it that way I can't imagine a way they are doing it and unless there's some secret to it.
Speaker 1: They're gonna be out of business.
Speaker 0: I think very simply not that many people listen to podcasts.
Speaker 0: So it's really not that much bandwidth.
Speaker 1: all told no They were using what was it like terabytes a day.
Speaker 0: I think they said yeah Yeah, whatever penny arcade gets two million unique hits a day.
Speaker 1: Yeah for an image.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're talking about like Zillions of mp3 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I just don't think it's really that much.
Speaker 1: all things considered It's quite a lot.
Speaker 1: You don't seem to understand these.
Speaker 0: No, I just don't think that many people listen to podcasts yet.
Speaker 1: No, they really do Do you?
Speaker 1: I need to play for you the podcast they were.
Speaker 1: they interview the Libsyn guy and ask him how it's going.
Speaker 1: It's crazy Absolutely crazy.
Speaker 0: All right, whatever the point is we're on Libsyn now.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway in the news You know Sony had their dual shock patent dispute where this company called immersion For those of you who aren't familiar with this basically had a patent on.
Speaker 0: Now this is gonna sound stupid but rumble packs at least in terms of console game controllers work all the same way.
Speaker 0: They have an unbalanced weight and you spin it to make a rumbling effect.
Speaker 1: Well, how come they're not going after a Nintendo or anyone?
Speaker 0: I was about to get to that.
Speaker 0: this patent specifically covers having two of these devices in a controller hence dual shock.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't realize.
Speaker 1: the dual shock had two rumbles.
Speaker 1: I thought it was called the dual shock because it had the two analog sticks and it had a rumble.
Speaker 0: now It had two rumbles that were identical And X Microsoft used the same thing in the Xbox and they settled quietly out of court.
Speaker 0: Sony tried to fight it lost appealed and just recently lost the appeal.
Speaker 0: Oh They're gonna have to pay at least eighty two million dollars to the company.
Speaker 1: Yeah They make a lot of freaking money off of those controllers.
Speaker 0: now Nintendo only has one gyro in there because they knew about the patent and they didn't want to infringe on it.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: I gotta say for it.
Speaker 1: I don't see how to is that much better than one?
Speaker 1: I mean is better is two more than it for the small effect that the rumble actually gives in a game at all.
Speaker 1: You know the the one rumble in the GameCube controller is just fine.
Speaker 0: I think the point was that if you have two rumbles you could control them separately and have different effects.
Speaker 1: Maybe but I don't really feel like I'm missing out on anything then what we're really missing out on is force feedback.
Speaker 1: You know why there's no force feedback controllers anymore because there's a patent and that company isn't licensing it or anything.
Speaker 0: Well, also the fact that support for force feedback was varied and marginal at best.
Speaker 1: Well, they were going.
Speaker 1: they were on the verge.
Speaker 1: They were making a standard.
Speaker 1: they had a standard actually for how force feedback should work.
Speaker 1: It was in DirectX and everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then these patent holding bastards messed up the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So now there's no force feedback joysticks or anything.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: There's no joysticks.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's no PC games that need good joysticks.
Speaker 0: There's no good joysticks.
Speaker 0: Force feedback doesn't.
Speaker 1: but there is evidence to suggest that if they had to force feedback and went through they would have made because Microsoft Was making the joysticks with force feedback Would have made the games for.
Speaker 0: and somehow I don't think force feedback was gonna save the PC gaming industry.
Speaker 1: I wasn't gonna say the PC gaming industry, but it would have saved joysticks I don't think it would have because there still wouldn't have at a market.
Speaker 0: I mean how many people buy joysticks now?
Speaker 1: No one cuz they don't sell them.
Speaker 0: No, they sell them.
Speaker 0: They're out there.
Speaker 0: I bought one a while ago so I could play x-wing Alliance.
Speaker 1: awesome Yeah, but anyway it would as they would have helped Something.
Speaker 0: nah, I think it was too little too late.
Speaker 0: The problem was is that we I mean, you know, I could sit in the bottom of the Titanic with a bucket.
Speaker 1: See.
Speaker 1: the other problem is that all the force feedback you've ever experienced is the shitty kind because the good kind is super patented.
Speaker 0: Oh, I didn't say force feedback was bad I just said that's definitely not.
Speaker 0: that wasn't gonna help the PC gaming industry and no Force feedback would have been.
Speaker 0: it still would have gone away because there aren't any games.
Speaker 1: There would have been games if there was force feedback.
Speaker 1: that was so quality.
Speaker 1: people would have made games just to use that and sell It based on that gimmick alone.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like there was.
Speaker 1: no there aren't any touchscreen games and now this is touch screen.
Speaker 1: So now this touchscreen games.
Speaker 1: well there weren't any force feedback joystick games.
Speaker 1: This is no force feedback joystick.
Speaker 1: point out However, that there's a huge huge market for Nintendo DS game But the market did not appear until the DS is made just as the market for force feedback Joysticks would not appear until the joysticks existed.
Speaker 1: You have to make the product first.
Speaker 1: then the market appears.
Speaker 0: see the problem is people were moving away from the PC gaming market already And I don't think people were gonna know.
Speaker 1: This is a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 0: PC gaming was in decline a long time ago.
Speaker 1: No, it wasn't in decline.
Speaker 1: This was even before like You came out.
Speaker 0: you're entitled to your opinion.
Speaker 1: It's a fact.
Speaker 1: this was in the olden days and PC gaming was at its peak that the force feedback debacle occurred.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 0: I didn't care about it then and then PC gaming died and I stopped caring.
Speaker 1: you didn't care about him because it was the stupid Dispute.
Speaker 1: Oh my god alright.
Speaker 1: So the whole hubbub on the big the net today.
Speaker 1: Is that Dell may or may not be buying Alienware?
Speaker 0: I haven't heard anything about this and if it's true, I don't care.
Speaker 1: I saw it on my play.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit song if I had it finished yet.
Speaker 1: I saw it on like 10 websites like Dell buys Alienware.
Speaker 0: Question mark, why does anyone even care?
Speaker 0: Alienware doesn't make good hardware.
Speaker 0: Dell makes average hardware.
Speaker 0: Alienware isn't special in any way anymore.
Speaker 1: That's exactly the whole story.
Speaker 0: is that so it's not a story.
Speaker 1: Well, the story is is that you know people who buy pre-made computers and have too much money.
Speaker 1: They don't have to do with all by these Alienware things and all the normal people buy the Dell things and Dell also makes this Like line of gamer computers.
Speaker 1: So now there's people who are like If this really happens then all those Dell gamer computers are gonna be super cheap and we can go scoop them up.
Speaker 0: Yeah Computers are already super cheap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you can build a tricked-out computer for you know, $400.
Speaker 1: No, these are like the insane Oh computers.
Speaker 0: Oh so useless.
Speaker 1: Well, no not useless.
Speaker 1: The fact is what would normally be useless because it's so expensive would become cheap because Dell would just try to get rid of that Computers to put in the new Alienware line.
Speaker 1: But we have no idea about if this is true or not.
Speaker 1: However, the latest evidence is that you know on to the already existing pile is that Dell has canceled some?
Speaker 1: sneak preview press event at the game developers conference, so We'll say That's like the scandest evidence for anything else the game developers conference.
Speaker 1: and it's Dell.
Speaker 1: so Dell makes computers.
Speaker 1: They're gonna talk it again.
Speaker 0: developers conference Alienware then Yeah, makes gaming computers, you know, there are very few things in this world.
Speaker 0: I care less about than Alienware or Dell.
Speaker 0: I just care a little bit about Dell because I deal with them on a regular basis, but Alien, yeah I don't really care because it.
Speaker 1: I don't really care because it won't affect me at all because I don't care about Dell or Alienware as far as I'm concerned, but as far as tech in general is is concerned this could cause some Changes like what?
Speaker 0: Like you know, yeah, I'm listening Decrease Okay, so suddenly there's a flood of cheap powerful PCs and then that dries up because they're not making them anymore.
Speaker 1: well, no, not that but the fact that Dell buys Alienware and And now I can't think of any ramification that really matters at all.
Speaker 1: All those idiots buying like expensive computers, you know can't buy Alienwares.
Speaker 1: they have to buy Dells.
Speaker 1: They might not want to.
Speaker 1: they might all buy Dells in you because they're Alienwares, you know things to get weird.
Speaker 0: That doesn't sound so worrisome or weird.
Speaker 1: or maybe they'll be all.
Speaker 1: maybe there'll be some sort of Intel AMD thing.
Speaker 1: I mean AMD is currently winning now in terms of gamers and which which is faster I mean in the latest steam survey, there's more AMD's than Intel's going on.
Speaker 1: So maybe you know Dell doesn't really make so many AMD's as far as I know.
Speaker 1: So if they get the Alienware, maybe they'll be less AMD's and more Intel's Yeah, or maybe this will change something in some sort of Nvidia ATI way.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I don't think this is gonna have any effect anywhere.
Speaker 0: If it even happens, we'll see.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day I found this Transcript someone made of World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: had it been a text adventure.
Speaker 0: Wait, so is it actually a text adventure you play or no, no, no No, it's just a transcript of what World of Warcraft would be like if it was a text adventure.
Speaker 1: Okay, so it's like N and then there's a carriage return and then it says there's a monster something like that.
Speaker 0: All right, and basically in my opinion this distills Everything that I hate about World of Warcraft because it takes you know This abstract game and it compresses it down into.
Speaker 0: here's what you're actually doing.
Speaker 0: They're pretty.
Speaker 0: graphics aside.
Speaker 0: Here's what you were doing with your life hour after hour.
Speaker 1: Maybe people who played see the problem is there are a million things like this that just plainly show What's wrong with these sorts of games and people who play it read it and laugh and go?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what it is and they keep playing.
Speaker 1: If someone shows me something I'm doing is dumb.
Speaker 1: I stopped doing it.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm not gonna get into it here, but you don't make eggs.
Speaker 1: very well when you cook I make I like I weigh like.
Speaker 1: I like the way you make McDonald's eggs.
Speaker 1: It's not a McDonald's.
Speaker 0: Have a solid massive egg that you make hot and there's just this dense mass of a.
Speaker 1: that's what egg is.
Speaker 0: It's not a.
Speaker 1: you make it hot until it's not goopy anymore and you eat it.
Speaker 1: That's how you.
Speaker 1: it's what you do with an egg.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, that's right, so uh, what's your thing of the day mr.
Speaker 0: McDonald's egg?
Speaker 1: Well Mortal Kombat 3 is sort of the not so good fighting game.
Speaker 0: I'd submit that it's one of the worst fighting games ever made.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: I said one of no in the pit of worst is definitely in the mediocre Fighting game area.
Speaker 1: the worst fighting game area is reserved for many games.
Speaker 1: I can't even mention cuz battle raper.
Speaker 1: Um, no, they're even worse ones than that.
Speaker 1: Let me think can you name Shaq foo?
Speaker 0: Shaq foo was kind of awesome until I wasn't a fighting game.
Speaker 0: It was a what it was a platformer slash walk down the street hitting things game weapon lords.
Speaker 0: That game wasn't so bad.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was the worst.
Speaker 1: that all right.
Speaker 1: We'll play it later and we'll see.
Speaker 0: I'd rather play that than Mortal Kombat 3.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it was much worse than Mortal Kombat 2 and 1 for sure.
Speaker 1: So Of course like every other Mortal Kombat game they had fatalities which are introduced in Mortal Kombat 1.
Speaker 1: We're basically this little gimmick of thing.
Speaker 1: You know, you memorize some button pattern and you could see a cool animation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a horrible thing.
Speaker 0: Basically the way it worked.
Speaker 0: for any of you never played Mortal Kombat.
Speaker 0: I mean modern fighting games.
Speaker 0: the combos make sense like in Soul Calibur.
Speaker 0: a Combo is basically just doing moves in a certain order usually or getting into a stancer make.
Speaker 0: there's some sort of flow to it.
Speaker 0: in Mortal Kombat Moves were things like up up down left down up down a be down up down left.
Speaker 1: No, they're simpler than that.
Speaker 1: But there's something.
Speaker 0: everyone had a complex.
Speaker 1: some of the special moves are pretty complicated.
Speaker 1: But all the combos in Mortal Kombat 10, especially starting in Mortal Kombat 2 tended to be juggle combos.
Speaker 0: now until you get to fatalities Yeah, when you beat someone like beat him beat him like you've already won the fight.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter now You've won the end.
Speaker 0: then they'll stand there all woozy and you have about three seconds to do a crazy Combo like something that's almost impossible to do with human fingers.
Speaker 1: Well, some of them are simple like I remember.
Speaker 1: some of them were like down down down high kick.
Speaker 0: Yeah some of them were like up down left right circle two buttons at once and you had to be a certain distance away from the Guy and yet he's facing in the right direction and if you screw up at all, it didn't work.
Speaker 0: Yep, a lot of times instead of doing it You just punch the guy once and then he'd fall over and it'd be over.
Speaker 1: or a lot of times you just uppercut the guy Or your guy would like duck and stand up and then jump and then it would be over And the other guy see.
Speaker 1: if you didn't do it quick enough the other guy would just fall over and the fight was over.
Speaker 0: but it was only really two Bands of appeal in these one.
Speaker 0: middle school kids want to see violence and they were incredibly horridly violent.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's what it was about - if you're in an arcade It was just like the final stake of humiliation into the guy's throat after you beat him.
Speaker 1: Mortal Kombat 2 was really towards the end of the arcade days Like I remember.
Speaker 1: we have an arcade in our mall where I live and it's still there But it doesn't get so much action now, you know back in the Mortal Kombat 2 days and that machine was there There were people about like crazy playing Mortal Kombat 2.
Speaker 0: There's an arcade called tilt.
Speaker 0: actually in the mall where I grew up There used to be water slides in the mall.
Speaker 0: Whoa, and then they got rid of those water slides.
Speaker 0: I never got to use him because I know when I was really young I'd always see him and I never knew what they were.
Speaker 0: and Because they were like in this special glassed-off area and before I was old enough to do it They shut it down and they put an arcade in there instead.
Speaker 1: No, that's not so bad.
Speaker 0: And so I used to hang out of that arcade, you know back when arcades were awesome They're still awesome.
Speaker 1: Just people don't go to them Yeah, and most arcades end up not being awesome because they either go out of because no one goes to them Yeah, because they don't have good games, but they don't have good games cuz no one goes.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's really.
Speaker 0: it's almost impossible to have a good arcade unless you're in Wildwood.
Speaker 0: go to Japan.
Speaker 1: go to Japan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Mortal Kombat all I got to say about Japan's arcades Mario Kart arcade Yeah, that's all I got to say.
Speaker 0: So I remember when Mortal Kombat 2 like the machine came out and they got two of them in that arcade.
Speaker 0: There was a crowd of people so thick you could not even see the machine Does from the moment that mall opened until the moment it closed every day?
Speaker 1: Yeah I remember when a few months after that every movie theater had a machine and there were at least two guys playing it all the Time and everywhere it was.
Speaker 1: it was the greatest.
Speaker 1: Well, not the greatest but anyway Mortal Kombat 3 was not quite so popular because it was after these days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Mortal Kombat 1 2 & 3 are basically the same game just with more characters and moves and different characters and moves.
Speaker 0: Yeah But uh other games progressed in technology and Mortal Kombat did not.
Speaker 1: Mortal Kombat just add.
Speaker 1: like a Mortal Kombat 1 you had fatalities.
Speaker 1: Mortal Kombat 2 was like the perfection of Mortal Kombat 1. in 3 they added like Babalities and animalities and friendships and all these gimmick crap crazy Nonsense.
Speaker 1: and you'll see in my thing of the day which we finally are getting to now is a video of every single fatality Babality animality and friendship in Mortal Kombat 3.
Speaker 0: so if you think Jack Thompson, you know I mean he hates grand grand theft auto because of all the violence and gore and whatever.
Speaker 0: I Don't think the people who crusade against video games these days Remember the shitstorm that arose around Mortal Kombat when we were young.
Speaker 1: no, man That was the first thing they went after.
Speaker 1: it's just they gave up on it when other games, you know became easier target.
Speaker 0: I watched this again, and I forgot that Mortal Kombat is still one of the most violent games I've ever played.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just.
Speaker 1: you know At least in Gran Turismo the gore makes sense.
Speaker 1: It's like somewhat realistic like you shoot a guy he dies.
Speaker 0: This is like you punch a guy you knock his head off and you grab his spinal cord and rip it out and whip it.
Speaker 1: Or you know you chop a guy up into ten pieces then blood blows everywhere and then his skeleton comes out.
Speaker 1: There's a million Gibbs falling from the sky.
Speaker 0: Unless you had the SNES version of Mortal Kombat 1 then it was sweat and green slime because they weren't allowed to show blood Yep, but the Genesis.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it was working just fine.
Speaker 0: blood code.
Speaker 1: Of course, if you had either one of those systems, you're probably better off playing Street Fighter.
Speaker 1: - yeah Either turbo for the SNES or championship edition for the Genesis Which were pretty much equal games.
Speaker 0: Alright, so it's favorites week and it's Tuesday, which means we could talk about either video games or board games.
Speaker 1: We're you do video games this time and board games will be saved for favorites week - yep Which will come whenever we run out of things to talk about another week.
Speaker 1: Yep, and now for our disclaimer Which we're going to say at the beginning of every favorites week episode because you know Some people only listen to some days of the podcast.
Speaker 0: Yes, and if you don't know we have more than one day every week.
Speaker 1: Yep, is it?
Speaker 1: favorites is not the same thing as best.
Speaker 1: the best thing ever is Something that everyone can agree on or that you know experts can say oh that is definitely the best video game ever made.
Speaker 1: But it's also very okay to say something's the best and also hate it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also very up to interpretation and argument.
Speaker 0: I mean Babe Ruth is the best baseball player ever.
Speaker 0: No Hank Aaron's the best baseball player ever.
Speaker 0: You can go to hell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could argue that Babe Ruth is the best baseball player ever But at the same time not like Babe Ruth or be a fan of him at all.
Speaker 0: Yep, so we're very much talking about our favorite things ever which means one.
Speaker 0: you can debate us But you can't argue with us because it's our opinion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could be like.
Speaker 1: the thing you think is the favorite sucks and I'll say okay that means it's not the best.
Speaker 1: It doesn't mean it's not my favorite because when I say it's my favorite it is, you know, I'm lying.
Speaker 0: I Don't think we're gonna lie about this.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think.
Speaker 1: why would I lie?
Speaker 1: Big especially when I'm talking, you know If anyone who knows me will know I'm not lying when I say that the best video game Well, not the best video game.
Speaker 1: The best video game is probably Zelda 1 or something I don't even know.
Speaker 1: my favorite video game ever is Mega Man 2.
Speaker 0: this kid freaking loves Mega Man 2 in a way That is unhealthy.
Speaker 1: I played Mega Man 2 for the NES like a thousand times.
Speaker 0: I don't even know He is as much a machine at that game as I am at bionic commando.
Speaker 1: No bionic commando.
Speaker 1: I got Mega Man - I got my NES the day before my birthday like April 29th some year I don't even know.
Speaker 1: and I got Mario Duck Hunt when I got it the next morning.
Speaker 1: They were like, okay Here's your birthday present is Mega Man.
Speaker 1: -.
Speaker 1: Mega Man - oh my god, I Nowadays Mega Man like.
Speaker 1: I'm playing the Mega Man X collection right now, which I'll talk about soon enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have my opinions on most Mega Man games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but new.
Speaker 1: now it's all about figuring out It's.
Speaker 1: it's all about knowing what order to beat the guys in knowing where the secret power-ups are the horrible and arbitrary secrets.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're not arbitrary secrets.
Speaker 1: You just don't understand.
Speaker 1: but Arbitrary secrets are like Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles.
Speaker 1: That's an arbitrary secret.
Speaker 1: or ogre battle 64.
Speaker 1: That's an hour.
Speaker 0: Don't get me started on that game.
Speaker 1: All right, but Mega Man - I played that without anyone's help just all on my own.
Speaker 1: I beat it from start every single guy.
Speaker 1: like when I first started playing I had no skills whatsoever And I was just trying to beat all eight robot masters.
Speaker 1: Imagine trying to beat eight robot masters not knowing anything.
Speaker 1: It's like you try all the different levels.
Speaker 1: you die in quick commands level because the lasers so you just give up on him and wait Until you have more powers.
Speaker 0: Yep, even though honestly, I always tried to beat him first when I first got that game
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then like with flash man I would just flash man was the first guy I could beat so it always beat flash man And then tried to beat everyone else or I'd write down my flash man password and then tried to beat everyone else.
Speaker 1: But then I realized I wanted to be crash man before flash man So I could break all the blocks in his level to get the E and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep, and what I you know, I don't think you needed to break the blocks to get the E. I think you just get the E without them, but you still wanted to break the blocks to make the level go easier.
Speaker 1: But yeah, wow, that game is so terrific.
Speaker 1: I mean Megaman one, you know Megaman 2 doesn't really have much on Megaman 1 in terms of gameplay.
Speaker 1: It's just the level design and the bad guys and everything was just more polished You know.
Speaker 1: and Megaman 1 was also stupid hard and really rough around the edges you know and especially like in the later levels like guys would fly around and patterns that kind of didn't make sense.
Speaker 0: and You know, I never beat Megaman 1 ever.
Speaker 1: I beat Megaman 1 but Megaman 1 is just kind of like really bland In fact, I never beat guts man ever.
Speaker 1: Wow, I can be okay.
Speaker 1: I've gotten to the wily parts of Megaman 1.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely because that's for you.
Speaker 1: fight the yellow guy who you got the one eyeball.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah, I've seen I know him.
Speaker 0: I know what he looks like.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, that's that's Megaman 1.
Speaker 0: see the first Megaman game I played was Megaman 3 Megaman 3.
Speaker 1: a lot of people say the Megaman 3 is better than Megaman 2. and you know, that's where the slide first appeared and parts of That's our protoman appeared.
Speaker 1: You know, I can't deny some of these things like protoman and the slide or the famous hold left on controller - yeah.
Speaker 1: But parts of Megaman 3 also, you know just not.
Speaker 1: It was just different.
Speaker 1: It's a whole different feeling.
Speaker 1: I mean you had like Gemini man.
Speaker 1: It's really the bad guys the eight robot master.
Speaker 1: That's why when you go buy a Megaman shirt This is I defeated the eight robot masters.
Speaker 1: Whatever eight robot masters.
Speaker 1: you see on that shirt the Megaman 2 robot masters.
Speaker 1: There's a reason for that.
Speaker 1: It was all about the robot masters and their levels that were so perfect and the music that was so perfect That music would be like it's still better any video game music.
Speaker 1: You'll ever find the Megaman 2 music.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Especially the first wily level.
Speaker 1: they had the best music like ever.
Speaker 1: They're like a thousand remixes of it.
Speaker 1: It's so good.
Speaker 0: now see if we're talking that era of games You know the prime of the original NES.
Speaker 0: It's really a toss-up for me between Zelda 2 and bionic commando But I'm gonna have to go with bionic commando.
Speaker 0: that game is just fantastic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people yell at you if you say Zelda 2 is good.
Speaker 0: Hey, I think Zelda 2 is better than Zelda 1 and you can all go to hell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got a problem But anyway bionic commando for any of you haven't played it You know, there's platformers and platformer was basically the primary genre of the original NES Because Super Mario Brothers and then everyone tried to make a game that was kind of like that.
Speaker 0: now bionic commando was a platformer Except you couldn't jump.
Speaker 0: There was no jumping in this game.
Speaker 1: No jumping.
Speaker 0: instead You had a grappling hook and this was an entirely new mode of play that created.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Awesome Awesome, I cannot express to you how much I love that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah The variety of moves and different like platform situations that can occur in bionic commando is really crazy and like you always have to figure out exactly the right way to use it to avoid getting hit and make it over the whole.
Speaker 0: and Like if you've seen someone playing the game versus watching say me play the game or someone else who's good.
Speaker 0: Normally the game you like you're very careful.
Speaker 0: You're trying not to get hit.
Speaker 0: you die all the time.
Speaker 0: Watching someone who's good at that game play that game is like watching a ballerina.
Speaker 0: Did you're flipping yourself through the air catching things?
Speaker 0: You didn't even know you could catch flying around all over the place dodging bullets by the skin of your teeth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Mega Man 2 is really a game where you know, if you suck which I did back in those ancient times You know, you gradually improve your skills and it hones you into being the you know A master until what you cannot play Mega Man 2 better in any way.
Speaker 0: the learning curve on bionic commando is a brick wall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, bionic commando is like this brick wall.
Speaker 1: But once you mount the brick wall It's like this amazing amazingness of crazy like it took.
Speaker 1: limit is so high to what you can do.
Speaker 0: It took me I think three or four months from when I first got the game Until I could get past the first half of the game because the game culminates in level 6.
Speaker 0: Level 6 is like the.
Speaker 0: this is the trial by fire.
Speaker 0: If you can beat this will let you play the rest of the game.
Speaker 0: and let me tell you the first day I beat level 6 I ran around my house screaming I couldn't believe it and then I learned that the rest of the game was twice as hard as level 6.
Speaker 0: Wow Of course bionic commando is also the game where at the end you kill a naked Hitler.
Speaker 0: yep, Hitler appears and he's naked and he says the word damn which oh.
Speaker 0: And then you kill him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Mega Man 2 I beat it like downstairs in my living room my brother watching and we were like, oh I think it took me two tries once I finally got to the alien guy at the end.
Speaker 1: man.
Speaker 0: Remember those days when when you got close to beating a game?
Speaker 0: You'd call your friend or your brother and they come and watch to kind of verify your victory The first time I beat Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: I did it using I think only the silver arrow in front of like a bunch of friends My brother in my room.
Speaker 1: That was a crazy day.
Speaker 1: I remember it actually very clearly like it's crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember the first time I beat Final Fantasy 1.
Speaker 0: I screamed and my brother runs into the room and all the Texas flying by and We sat there just staring at the screen like wow, it's over.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: I would like.
Speaker 1: if you would have asked me ten years ago Zelda 1 would have been my favorite game.
Speaker 1: The problem was all.
Speaker 1: the one is that when you're a little kid and you have that like, you know Wonder and whatnot and you'll burn every bush.
Speaker 1: You've never played Zelda 1 before you know, and you don't know everything already.
Speaker 1: it's so fantastic the exploring and the figuring things out and the going from level to level and Levels in any order and collecting different items and using one different things.
Speaker 0: I don't have time for that shit anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was so great.
Speaker 1: But nowadays it's it's not so great anymore.
Speaker 1: I just I can beat Zelda 1 in like 40 minutes, you know, so it's kind of like.
Speaker 0: and now it's just yeah And there are games that are as good and are very similar, but I just don't have the time to sit there and burn every Bush.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the first time I beat Zelda 1 like when I finally got to level 9 I was like scared shitless with that music and I didn't know where to go and it was like, oh Yeah, but nowadays it's like doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: Let's go begin and there he is He's dead.
Speaker 1: I got the princess.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: I remember as a little kid.
Speaker 0: I would actually get scared Endangerous parts.
Speaker 1: Oh, I was super scared in Zelda 1.
Speaker 0: Holy shit Simon's quest.
Speaker 0: when I got to that because at the end of Simon's quest which Simon's quest is right up there in my Opinion that's my favorite Castlevania game ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like Castlevania 1 the most but I'm not really the hugest Castlevania fan.
Speaker 0: So yeah I just really like Simon's quest.
Speaker 0: that game scared the hell out of me when I was a kid mainly because the game is poorly Translated right and you'll find these cryptic things around like you'll find a bunch of people just hung to death in the background And then you'll find like a cryptic poorly translated text that as a little kid It just kind of scares you know at the end of the game you walk into Dracula's castle, right?
Speaker 0: But Dracula's already dead.
Speaker 0: So the music changes.
Speaker 0: It's the scary music and it's this long long Castle.
Speaker 0: you have to walk all the way through it and up and down ladders and stairs and whatever.
Speaker 0: There's no monsters.
Speaker 0: There's no nothing.
Speaker 0: There's nothing in the castle, but you have to walk through it and I was scared shitless that something was gonna jump out at me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna talk about the scariest games legacy.
Speaker 1: the wizard might be the scariest but that was just me.
Speaker 1: It was just so strange and sort of eerie and the way the game was and the music combined.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: It's like you're a little tiny guy and the game is all sort of cute and happy But you're going down and down and down to this dark scary crazy dungeon and it gets scarier and darker the more down you go.
Speaker 1: It's like you're going all over these weird places and only certain people go.
Speaker 1: Oh god Play the game sometime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't like it that much just because I don't have patience for games like that.
Speaker 0: But it's a game.
Speaker 0: I just respect it.
Speaker 1: I just wish that like some of these games are experienced different based on your state of mind and level of skill.
Speaker 1: and like Nowadays, you know with the person I am the game isn't as good as if I was the person I was.
Speaker 0: You know, yeah, well our brains are different.
Speaker 0: We've experienced more.
Speaker 0: I mean if Empire hunter D was a goddamn masterpiece when I was in fourth grade.
Speaker 0: now It's just a mediocre guy killing things bloodily.
Speaker 1: It's like when you're a 20th level fighter a kobold is nothing but when you're a first level fighter a kobold is great.
Speaker 1: I just sometimes I'm like a 20th level fire.
Speaker 1: We are wishing I was a first level fighter.
Speaker 0: So if you experience the joy of killing kobolds, we're Lena inverse and we already killed chevron igdo.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, we're watching slayers.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Let's see.
Speaker 0: All right Friday the 13th used to scare the hell out of me when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah the game No, not the movies.
Speaker 1: the game no, none of the nut.
Speaker 1: that really didn't get me anything.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's talk about some PC games.
Speaker 0: Alright, I'd have to say my favorite PC game ever ever ever ever would have to be Quake 2 not tie fighter.
Speaker 0: I don't see type.
Speaker 0: Alright best single-player game ever hands-down tie fighter.
Speaker 0: Best multiplayer game ever hands-down Quake 2 and all the associated mods.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So, uh, let's start with single-player first since we've been talking mostly about single-player old-school type games.
Speaker 1: Oh single-player is tough.
Speaker 1: It might be met warrior - It might be One or half-life - Oh half-life one might be civilization - ooh It's a tough call especially if you're gonna keep it to only PC.
Speaker 0: I have to go with tie fighter.
Speaker 0: that game Destroyed my life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't play tie fighter that much.
Speaker 0: That's why you know, I played it all the way through Beat it and then went all the way through again like destroying everything like I flew around destroying Entire like fleets with my one tie fighter.
Speaker 0: I got that good in that board.
Speaker 1: Huh if I had to think of which ones like, you know had the most effect on me, especially back in the day.
Speaker 1: It's go.
Speaker 1: you met courier - I mean damn.
Speaker 1: you had these missions and there was a story that you keep track of and you Customize the max and the missions are complex and it was a complex simulation of a giant robot and you're shooting guys.
Speaker 1: It's better than any other mech game that's ever been around.
Speaker 0: Well tie fighter is probably the best free space fighting game ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean basically descent - is also really good.
Speaker 0: But it is really good, but it didn't have the Star Wars theme and high fighter was just so clean.
Speaker 0: I mean that the basic history here is that x-wing came out and it was an amazing game.
Speaker 0: It was fairly revolutionary is very well done.
Speaker 0: It was hard as hell and it had a lot of rough edges.
Speaker 0: So fast forward a few years and they made tie fighter Which is basically the same game.
Speaker 0: only now you're on the bad guys side and they polished it a bit and by a bit I mean There was a time when PC gamer the ratings that they gave to games mattered Like they were fairly objective and if they said a game was good.
Speaker 0: It was good they gave tie fighter the highest rating they had ever given a game and Then a few years later a game beat tie fighter.
Speaker 0: You know what game beat tie fighter?
Speaker 0: Tie fighter on a CD.
Speaker 0: It was the same game just re-released.
Speaker 0: And yeah, I Remember that tie fighter which is so well done because on one hand you're a tie fighter pilot and you gotta you know Fight the rebels and the fighting was really good.
Speaker 0: The missions were really good at primary and secondary objectives and you only had to do the primary objectives to continue.
Speaker 0: The secondary ones were just for fun or to prove how badass you were to unlock the story.
Speaker 0: there were also these secret missions where you could basically become a spy for the Emperor and Do crazy stuff in the game.
Speaker 0: Oh, you'd get tattoos if you were good and the Emperor would give you powers.
Speaker 0: I Love that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah if I had to pick a single-player FPS to say that was like Ever, you know, it's really tough because half-life 1 was like such a great Freaking game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but half-life 2 single-player.
Speaker 1: I had I can't deny that it was better.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's just.
Speaker 1: uh, I hate naming recent games because I like to be old-school but half-life 2 has to be it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I haven't played it yet.
Speaker 0: So I can't say oh my god I can't.
Speaker 0: I can't pretend that quake 2 is a good FPS single-player wise because it's half-life 2 had.
Speaker 1: all the Feelings of half-life 1 are like, you know, you're in danger You're short on resources.
Speaker 1: You're running around.
Speaker 1: the story is is you know combined with the action?
Speaker 1: solidly and You know you feel you you're you in.
Speaker 1: most FPS is like in Wolfenstein.
Speaker 1: I don't feel like I'm the Nazi prisoner trying to escape.
Speaker 1: I feel like just a crazy guy trying to kill all Nazis in doom.
Speaker 1: I don't feel like I'm the doom guy stuck on Mars.
Speaker 1: I feel like I'm just gonna kill all his demons.
Speaker 1: when half-life you feel like you're Gordon Freeman, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I poo-pooed it because I didn't play the game until much later like well after it had come out.
Speaker 0: In fact, I only bought it because I wanted to play counter-strike.
Speaker 1: You'll talk about kind of strike in a minute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but as I played through half-life 1 as a cynical like yeah Whatever this game and after about the first hour of playing it and I've got you know I've progressed through the game for a while I was Gordon Freeman and I was scared shitless that the military is gonna come and kill me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, half-life 2 is just that and more like parts of the game aren't as good as other parts.
Speaker 1: But yeah, just wow.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: You haven't played half-life 2 the single-player.
Speaker 0: damn Now if we're talking multiplayer Honestly, I love natural selection and I love counter-strike.
Speaker 0: and We're not gonna talk about tribes - we'll do a whole show.
Speaker 0: I was gonna talk about tribes - tribes - is the best game ever.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: You just can't play just doesn't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: It's the problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whiners ruined it.
Speaker 1: It's like you can still play Megaman - you can still play half-life.
Speaker 0: - you can't play tribes - actually There are some servers out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not the same as it was.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: I'd like to do a whole show on tribes - I got tribes - the day came out.
Speaker 1: rim ordered it for me online.
Speaker 1: It was in college.
Speaker 1: We had two copies.
Speaker 1: I played it online and The first day that game came out and all those people were playing on a server with like 50 people.
Speaker 1: with my wicked Low-paying.
Speaker 1: that was like the greatest FPS team action ever.
Speaker 0: We walked around the campus for the next week going Pretending.
Speaker 0: we had jetpacks like tribes - all our friends thought we were idiots and then they all bought the game.
Speaker 1: God tribes - is just so freaking terrific multiplayer game.
Speaker 0: We would come home from class and just start playing like I'd come home and start playing.
Speaker 0: Scott would come home from class and start playing.
Speaker 0: I look up at the clock and turn the game off and go to class.
Speaker 0: then I'd come back and start playing again and he'd still be playing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The thing is you can't play tribes - anymore.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's free now if you want to if you want to try it But it's just not the same as it was.
Speaker 1: there aren't enough people.
Speaker 1: They don't play the same way they used to play.
Speaker 1: It's just not the same now.
Speaker 0: I've got a crazy idea.
Speaker 1: I would pay a lot of money to bring tribes to back or get another game going.
Speaker 1: That was like just basically tribes - all right.
Speaker 0: so all of you out there who listen to geek nights if you either one liked tribes - or - might think you might like tribes - check it out and If enough of you want us to we'll put up some sort of server somewhere.
Speaker 0: where?
Speaker 1: where are we gonna put up a server?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'll get another hosting.
Speaker 1: All right, it's all you.
Speaker 0: we'll do something because if enough of you want to play and We you know, we can play tribes - old school all the way with the original rule set.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm That'd be fun, but I don't think it would be easy to get going.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think it would either.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm asking.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what.
Speaker 1: go to the forum and we'll start it tribes to thread.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we're not gonna tribes - is not in the consideration because it was the best game ever, but they ruined it.
Speaker 1: It's no longer playable.
Speaker 1: the game that it that was the best game ever does not exist now.
Speaker 0: Like I said, I like that and counter-strike and natural selection.
Speaker 0: But honestly, I spent more time in my life Playing quick - and all of its mods than I've played any other FPS ever.
Speaker 1: Wow,
Speaker 0: I mean I played quake - pretty much from the day It came out online and then lithium deathmatch and then a weapons factory action quake weapons of destruction action quake version - weapons or a weapons factory version - in fact I contend that weapons factory was better than any incarnation of Team Fortress ever.
Speaker 1: Well, Team Fortress is sort of this on and off sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just I have so many good memories of playing that game.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, see when I first actually was able to play FPS is online for real was when I got to college because before then I had a little dial-up so I couldn't really play online so well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you kind of missed a whole era there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I played Team Fortress classic on the half-life engine and that was really not so great.
Speaker 1: I mean it was better than anything I had previously played but it wasn't so great except for the hunted.
Speaker 1: The hunting was terrific the hunted if you don't know is basically Counter-strike assault with the VIP trying to get to a checkpoint and then they win but if the VIP dies they lose.
Speaker 1: Then some guys are talking about counter-strike and they said oh if you die, you're out and I'm like, oh that sucks I don't want to play something like that.
Speaker 1: But then I realized oh you're out for the round and there's an objective and it's quick and I got it.
Speaker 1: Then I played counter-strike probably more than I played any other multiplayer FPS ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got really into counter-strike starting right around beta 5, I believe Yeah, the thing is counter-strike like any other multiplayer FPS or really any other multiplayer round based game.
Speaker 1: You can have good rounds and bad rounds, you know It could be painful to play or it could be like the best time you've had playing counter-strike ever.
Speaker 0: We've had some crazy times.
Speaker 1: crazy times, you know when crazy stuff happenings or when your team just clicks and yeah It feels really good.
Speaker 0: Like say you you're the defenders and you're trying to defend the bombsite and you get owned like 20 times in a row.
Speaker 0: They just they run in and they destroy you and then that one time Somehow your team just goes nuts and kills the entire enemy team without taking a loss and the whole server is going WTF WTF hacks or That's like.
Speaker 0: that's that's gold.
Speaker 1: That's always chat actually hurt counter-strike a little bit, you know, yeah, it helped and hurt.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think it made the game different and a lot of the end and a lot of the changes to the engine and Stuff change things.
Speaker 0: Well, the game was often broken.
Speaker 1: I mean was often broken, but sometimes when it was broken it was more fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except when they first introduced the p90.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was basically a death machine.
Speaker 1: I remember a time when there was no cheating like way early on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all you kids out there Yeah, people used to not cheat.
Speaker 1: when you play counter-strike beta 7 there was no cheating.
Speaker 1: They just didn't.
Speaker 1: you'd no one cheated.
Speaker 1: they were just people were good and everyone got about.
Speaker 1: you know, pretty good scores.
Speaker 1: That was the times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well see Scott I'll just point out you know that there's an entire era of FPS gaming way before that when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, cuz thing is I was really lucky.
Speaker 0: I can't pretend that this was because I was awesome.
Speaker 0: It was just luck of where I happen to live.
Speaker 0: But basically I had broadband since I was a freshman in high school Like we got some of the first broadband connections in the state of Michigan.
Speaker 0: So basically me and my friend we got cable modems because we begged our parents.
Speaker 0: It was like 50 bucks a month and I got pings of like 20.
Speaker 0: I mean people.
Speaker 0: no one knew what to make of it.
Speaker 0: I connect to a server and I have a ping of like, you know 20 25 and most people had dial-up and pings of like three or four hundred.
Speaker 0: and back then High ping meant death because ping was not dealt with at all.
Speaker 0: You just lagged that far behind in the game.
Speaker 0: But I played quake 2 weapons factory like religiously and Once again, no one cheated.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: the idea of cheating back then was just unheard of.
Speaker 0: The thing is it was difficult to play.
Speaker 0: FPS is back then like, you know You play I don't quake 3 or whatever doom 3 and you can just bind keys to whatever.
Speaker 0: back then you couldn't do anything.
Speaker 0: You had to write scripts to take care of your key bindings at all times like complex difficult to manage scripts to make the game work.
Speaker 1: Yeah scripts that you really weren't supposed to have to write ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying that was good I'm just saying that's the way it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is definitely I still have.
Speaker 0: I had a keyboard that I used all the way through our IT till it finally died that had all the all This marker writing over it as to what was bound to what key for different classes and I had scripts to go along with that keyboard.
Speaker 1: So now I'm also gonna mention natural selection.
Speaker 1: natural selection is a half-life 1 mod where it's kind of like an RTS Alien vs.
Speaker 1: Predator also FPS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, imagine RTS where one guy's the commander and he's doling out troops and whatever but all the troops are guys playing an FPS.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: the thing about natural selection is that if you gave me a choice between a really good game of natural selection and a really Good game of counter-strike the game of natural selection probably more fun and more awesome
Speaker 0: Mostly because of the community around it the
Speaker 1: problem with well and because the game itself I think is just inherently.
Speaker 0: I think the communities were really did it for me?
Speaker 1: but the thing about natural selection is it's so much harder to get a good game of natural selection than it is to get a Game of counter-strike.
Speaker 1: and I just because there are fewer players because it requires so much more effort and coordination and like one Asshole can ruin it one asshole can ruin it.
Speaker 1: in counter-strike one asshole just dies every round You know or he team kills and then he dies the next round.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's one thing counter-strike never had.
Speaker 0: was that Deeply rooted sense of community which may sound silly for a video game, but I swear to you it was there.
Speaker 0: I mean natural selection.
Speaker 0: It was a small group so you'd see the same people over and over and you'd start to learn who was who.
Speaker 0: and you'd see A guy and you know that guy always plays bender waves whenever he does.
Speaker 0: Well, everyone just called him bender or that guy sucks and you'd know like you'd know the guy and your friends with him, but you just know we sucked from his name and In the old old days.
Speaker 0: It was the same way.
Speaker 0: everyone kind of knew each other and Everyone was kind of cool with each other and they talked outside of the game and you know who was who?
Speaker 0: You don't really have that in counter-strike.
Speaker 0: You just play with random schmucks constantly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like sometimes I feel like I should go get.
Speaker 1: one of these newfangled FPS is like the battlefield.
Speaker 1: There's something like that and you know get some people together with like a clan of non Schmucks and really try to turn it into what it was in the old days, but it's so much effort.
Speaker 1: It's not the same and I'd had to buy a better computer and it's just you know.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's just so much trying just to get something that came easily before.
Speaker 1: I don't want to.
Speaker 1: I'd feel bad doing that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean natural selection.
Speaker 0: I remember one of the defining moments for us was a game ended and I forget who had won.
Speaker 0: but we're back in the team room, which is the the start room where basically everyone gets together and then you pick what team you want to be on whatever and everyone's standing there waiting for the next round to start and Everyone just started dancing and raving and playing music into the microphone and flashing their flashlights.
Speaker 0: And then in this room, don't ask me why there was a table and on table was a piece of cheese.
Speaker 1: I was gonna talk about the cheese.
Speaker 0: All right, fine.
Speaker 0: You can talk about the cheese.
Speaker 1: There's a piece of cheese on the table and some guy says let's pile on the cheese.
Speaker 1: He gets on top of the cheese a guy gets on top of him a guy gets on top of him and everyone's jumping up and down on top of the Cheese in a giant pyramid of people meanwhile and aliens.
Speaker 0: one guy goes into the game to try to start and he comes back out.
Speaker 0: He's like and he sees the pile.
Speaker 0: He's like what WTF are you guys doing?
Speaker 0: Don't you want to play the game?
Speaker 0: and we're like forget you cheese.
Speaker 0: What kind of game can you have where everyone is more interested in hanging out with each other and piling up on cheese than they Aren't actually playing the game?
Speaker 1: one time I joined an NS server and there's one alien and he was playing Techno music and dancing around the ready room and he was all alone.
Speaker 1: Everyone else is playing.
Speaker 1: so I went into the game for a minute and the game was kind of bleh.
Speaker 1: So I'm back to the ready room and started dance around and bit by bit more people started going to the ready room as people Leaving the game.
Speaker 1: where the game ended people came to the ready room and started the techno with us and then after we've done technically We started a real game.
Speaker 1: That was actually good now.
Speaker 0: We don't really have a category for this.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's in the bimani category, but dance dance revolution has affected us in profound ways.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I should get back into that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean basically we'd never heard a DDR.
Speaker 0: We had no idea about it.
Speaker 0: and we get to RIT and this guy has this dance man And he's dancing and there's arrows on the screen and that looked like the dumbest thing in the world to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we both said this is the dumbest thing ever.
Speaker 1: It's like some little kids game or some shit.
Speaker 1: I'm not doing this.
Speaker 0: So then Scott goes off to play Dungeons & Dragons with all these people, but I had nothing to do.
Speaker 0: I wasn't in that game.
Speaker 0: So I'd started trying to play this dancing game.
Speaker 0: I had nothing better to do.
Speaker 0: Four hours later they get out of their D&D game and I'm still dancing and Scott says something to the effect of what the hell that Game looked stupid and I just looked at him and said try it and see what you say
Speaker 1: and I try anything once To make sure
Speaker 0: and sure enough not too long after I got a ps1 modded.
Speaker 0: it got the import games We bought dance mats we duct-taped them permanently to the floor in our apartment and we play DDR every day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is DDR isn't what it used to be just like it seems like everything that's our favorite isn't what it used to Be?
Speaker 0: yes that you know what that means.
Speaker 0: It either means the world is changing or we're crotchety old men.
Speaker 1: now I think we're just crotchety.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we are because we used to be punk kids.
Speaker 1: The way we experienced these things when they were new and awesome or you know in our youth younger days Was the way they should be experienced and for the most awesome.
Speaker 1: and the way we experienced them now Isn't the same as the way we experienced them then.
Speaker 1: so we don't like him as much now as we did then.
Speaker 0: Well consider this DDR.
Speaker 0: we played it for years where we had dance mats in our apartment and that was and other than other people's apartments.
Speaker 0: That was the only time I could ever play it and no one really was good at it because no one had it.
Speaker 0: Then one day an Arcade machine appeared near us Like we'd always wanted an arcade machine we never even like.
Speaker 0: once I'd seen an arcade machine at Cedar Point when I went back home to go on vacation with my family and One day our friend Scott Johnson calls us.
Speaker 0: he says I heard there's a DDR machine at blah blah blah and we I just hung up because we were on our way to that place immediately and Our whole group of friends congregated at this arcade and like a shining altar in the middle of the room is a dance dance revolution.
Speaker 0: Fourth mix machine.
Speaker 1: fourth mix was where it was at.
Speaker 0: We about cried.
Speaker 0: I bought like $50 worth of tokens and I used them all.
Speaker 1: that was the summer of dancing.
Speaker 0: Yep, that was the summer of dancing in the summer of Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: Yep, we all we did that summer was dance dance revolution in Puerto Rico the board game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That was a good summer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I mean it does this community and happiness and fun around that one machine was just so fantastic.
Speaker 0: Yep, like yeah, everyone knew everyone who played on the machine.
Speaker 0: Everyone's real polite to each other.
Speaker 0: No one was a jerk.
Speaker 0: Everyone was about the same level of skill.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there weren't any like, you know Asians Get it out to be racist or anything.
Speaker 0: get an epic.
Speaker 0: Kaya nub exactly.
Speaker 1: There were none of those guys doing like the crazy hard stuff Like who look at me I'm so much better and no smelly people.
Speaker 0: and now there were smelly people.
Speaker 0: I think you're that's definitely a rose-tinted glass right there.
Speaker 0: It might be now I remember some smelly people.
Speaker 0: All right, and there were the people who were really good, but they weren't jerks about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because they're not like good at that one time.
Speaker 1: We tried to play in New York and they were jerks about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though the thing is there was a point at which we got really good But that was after you know a year of playing every day now.
Speaker 1: We're not so good anymore.
Speaker 0: No, I remember this one time we were playing in our apartment and we always play in our boxers or like shorts.
Speaker 0: Just cuz you know you get hot playing DDR and it was summer and these drunks are standing outside.
Speaker 1: I have been like four or five times.
Speaker 0: Yeah And they see us in there and they couldn't figure out what we were doing and they'd start gathering a crowd and they start yelling Or cheering.
Speaker 0: one guy mooned us.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one time these drunk sorority girls wandered in and wanted to play with us.
Speaker 1: I don't know why we didn't take advantage of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because we were more interested in playing DDR at the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah playing DDR.
Speaker 0: I Don't know there's something about a drunk sorority girl who comes into your apartment Randomly and starts hitting on you.
Speaker 0: that really kind of turns you off a little especially when they're not so hot More that they were so drunk.
Speaker 0: It was not good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they were really into DDR, I guess.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, yeah Now DDR, I mean DDR machines were so rare.
Speaker 0: and then suddenly there was an explosion and there were DDR machines everywhere.
Speaker 0: and then that next summer we went to Wildwood, New Jersey with Scott Johnson our good friend and all of our other friends and There were like 10 DDR machines on the boardwalk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there wasn't.
Speaker 0: you didn't have the community around those DDR machine No But what you did have were slack-jawed tourists who had never seen anything like that before and no one knew how to dance on it Except us.
Speaker 0: and they go ooh, and ah, yeah, that's a good feeling.
Speaker 0: It's a silly feeling but it's a good feeling Yeah, but now it doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 0: Now every machine there is an 8th mix machine and it's all these epic kaya nub kids playing DDR.
Speaker 1: Yep Uh Why does everything have to go away?
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: Why do we have to get old and crotchety?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean if we were young punk kids, we'd probably be talking up Whatever the new great thing is.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: The new great thing is in the groove - yep I consider it the spiritual successor to Dance Dance Revolution because DDR is basically dead as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well mostly because we can't find a fourth mix machine anywhere anymore.
Speaker 1: You mean a fourth mix plus machine?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, so it has the kpop songs.
Speaker 1: There was a fourth mix.
Speaker 1: well No The fourth mix has the kpop songs.
Speaker 1: fourth mix plus has the extra mix type songs and such.
Speaker 0: of course I have a special place in my heart for Dance Dance Revolution.
Speaker 0: third mix Korean.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because mainly there was a machine on the boardwalk.
Speaker 0: It was a quarter for five songs.
Speaker 0: Alright, once again, we could talk about this topic forever and we're gonna stop now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I could talk about you know favorite RPG type games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could talk about like specifically our favorite game in every genre for every console or era of PC gaming ever.
Speaker 1: I mean, I didn't even mention a single space shooting game at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott's real big into the shmups.
Speaker 1: Galaga.
Speaker 0: Ah There you go.
Speaker 0: I was never good at those games though.
Speaker 0: I liked our type the most.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Galaga.
Speaker 1: Okay, so now that we've said Galaga three times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'll summon Galaga and then we'll play it.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: A million bugs will invade the earth and a tiny tiny ship will fight them off.
Speaker 0: But stay tuned on some other week where we're gonna cover, you know our favorite board games our favorite other kinds of games In favorite week 2.0 sometime and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at two o six three three three one five three seven.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.