Speaker 0: It's Thursday July 13th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We talk about the horrors and ordeals of trying to move all of our stuff from Rochester, New York to Beacon, New York.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I'm sitting in my office all alone today and some people walk in.
Speaker 0: did they catch you doing anything bad?
Speaker 1: No, no, I go and I see and he's two young guys.
Speaker 1: one guy he said he was 24 the other guy was 30-something whatever and They were door-to-door salesmen.
Speaker 1: I didn't which I didn't realize at first.
Speaker 1: I was like did anyone from my company tell you to come here?
Speaker 1: did you know?
Speaker 1: because yeah?
Speaker 1: People from my company don't communicate with me so much, so if they were sending someone I wouldn't know man how many people would kill for jobs like what we have yeah, and they said that they were from a company that does Rico copier.
Speaker 1: you know service stuff and I had a Rico copier right there and They didn't even realize it like they were going door-to-door, and it took me like a whole minute to get that out of them.
Speaker 1: so anyway You know they.
Speaker 1: they looked at my copier a bit And I tried to get them to do some stuff for free, but they wouldn't.
Speaker 0: what'd you try to get him to do set up?
Speaker 1: Copier to do like the scanning properly.
Speaker 0: That's pretty easy to do.
Speaker 1: yeah I don't think I think they were too smart to do anything without actually getting a service contract.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but as time went on it proceeded to just kind of sit down and talk to these guys and hang out for like 20 Minutes and talk about stuff.
Speaker 0: Did you tell him about geek nights?
Speaker 1: No, but I talked to them about you know geeks and nerds and video games and All kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: one guy was like you know man.
Speaker 1: You should get on the Craigslist.
Speaker 1: I'm like yeah I know all about Craigslist.
Speaker 1: He's like yeah, you could use it like one guy was only.
Speaker 0: That's like a guy coming up to me and saying yeah, there's this internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, but it's like one guy.
Speaker 1: He thought it was all into video games that the older guy and the other guy was all about.
Speaker 1: ladies That's all he.
Speaker 1: he was like man.
Speaker 1: You could totally like get some ladies right in here.
Speaker 1: And I was like yes the thought had occurred to me before But the problem is is like you never know.
Speaker 1: the CEO can just show up randomly, and then what do I do?
Speaker 1: uh?
Speaker 0: You know what you do what George Costanza?
Speaker 0: Did you ever see that one episode of Seinfeld where he got caught having sex with another employee?
Speaker 0: Nope, he goes it like.
Speaker 0: they fire him like equally They call him in like the boss calls him into the office the next day And he's like.
Speaker 0: George has come to my attention that you engaged in blah blah blah blah at your desk and George sits there and says Was that wrong?
Speaker 0: Was I not supposed to do that?
Speaker 0: because if there wasn't a memo or anything so I wasn't entirely sure if that was against company Or not.
Speaker 0: you see and he just goes on and on and on.
Speaker 1: Have a feeling that if I'm doing some random girl from Craigslist well semi random girl from Craigslist in the office And the CEO shows up.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be fired.
Speaker 0: see now one you probably would love to get fired.
Speaker 0: So not only would I give you an awesome story, and it would give you an excuse to leave that job But it would lose me a whole reference for the next job.
Speaker 0: No, because the people call say yes.
Speaker 0: He was employed by us.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: He did great work.
Speaker 0: Why'd you fire him?
Speaker 0: because he made it with some woman in his cube Not in my cube in my entire empty office, and then they think oh he was the manager of an office somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus you.
Speaker 0: when you go to another job, and they ask why'd you leave your last job?
Speaker 0: You say I was fired And just tell him exactly what happened.
Speaker 1: no, but I might you know put a thing on Craigslist.
Speaker 1: like I am a geek Is there a geek girl out there?
Speaker 0: You know what you should because if nothing else we'll have some awesome stories to tell on the show about.
Speaker 1: at the Absolute worst I get no emails whatsoever.
Speaker 1: at the absolute best I get laid at the absolute minimal in between honestly.
Speaker 1: I dare some emails.
Speaker 1: That'll be humorous.
Speaker 0: You should check out otaku booty.
Speaker 1: You know that doesn't?
Speaker 1: it doesn't seem to happen in actually.
Speaker 0: yeah well the thing is from what I can gather it seemed really happening when it started.
Speaker 0: and then The horny kids who go to anime cons realize they didn't need a website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if only I was a horny teenager again, oh yeah I gotta say if anime culture those are the days and anime cons Existed in their current form when I was between the ages of 14 and 17 well see I already had that.
Speaker 1: It was just not at anime cons.
Speaker 1: It was at some other kinds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had that too, but it was in band camp, but Anime culture is just so far and away from that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though you ran into some stealth geeks.
Speaker 0: I also found Archaeological evidence of a geek somewhere in beacon Archaeological evidence, so I was riding my bike around today.
Speaker 0: You know I was poking it because I promised our friend yuko We explored a bunch of factories before but the one I really wanted to like go in and show her the inside of someone had locked it.
Speaker 0: So recently some kids had unlocked it and I've been going by it periodically to make sure it's still unlocked and I can still get into it.
Speaker 0: and As I was biking around I passed a park bench, and I sit on it to retie my shoe And then I see there's graffiti on the park bench in marker and one of the graffiti says very specifically Inu Yasha rocks exclamation point.
Speaker 1: heart Sounds to me like some girl from beacon high school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what a geeks?
Speaker 1: a geek Yeah, but it's not someone useful to us.
Speaker 0: Hey finding any geek would be an advantage at this point because as far as our lives is gone All I can say is that if girls from beacon high school start showing up.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: you know You're gonna be in trouble.
Speaker 0: No he put him on the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I would pretty much interview any geek and I met him a file you At this point.
Speaker 0: I mean if some hole is that one of those homeless crazy guys on the street was walking by and he was Like grumble grumble grumble master Keaton I'd whip out a microphone and interview him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that would be great All right, so do I do the new segment?
Speaker 0: oh the new segment that we don't have music for yet But we decided to do over aim about seven hours ago.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: We have a new segment.
Speaker 1: everybody Guess what.
Speaker 1: we have a new segment.
Speaker 0: It's called geek back.
Speaker 1: Yes every show from now on Before we do the news we're gonna do geek back because mainly a lot of other podcasts will.
Speaker 0: they get a lot of user art Listener feedback I almost said user feedback and they'll you know read the emails and play the voice feedback and then they'll talk about it every episode and we Get a lot of emails.
Speaker 0: like we get a lot of stuff from fans But we always respond to it in email and it never really sees the show.
Speaker 0: so it's like we're doing geek nights the show And we're doing geek nights the forum and we're doing geek nights the email personal conversation, and they're all separate.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: So the geek back segment what we are going to do is each show we will either play one voicemail read one email or barring a lack of Emails and voicemail well at least good ones.
Speaker 1: yeah good ones.
Speaker 1: we will read something from the forum and then talk about it for a little bit and This should hopefully a encourage more user fee listener feedback and I Don't know make people feel good when we read their stuff on the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because I can say okay, and hopefully it's entertaining for all the people who do email us and contact us.
Speaker 0: We do read every single one of them and even if we don't respond to you we talk to each other about it a lot and
Speaker 1: That will continue until the number of emails we get is too many and it is not yet too many
Speaker 0: at which point I think we'll start paying mr.. Period or something and we'll get him to be a secretary and filter the email for us or something.
Speaker 1: Yep, all right, so the email we're gonna read today is from our good friend Bayway Chang Who you might remember is our only PayPal donator as of yet?
Speaker 0: Yep?
Speaker 0: I can say up.
Speaker 1: What did you do?
Speaker 1: What'd you do?
Speaker 0: Now I can say that I think what?
Speaker 0: because we whenever we get money I think we're not gonna use it on ourselves.
Speaker 0: We're probably just gonna buy more equipment for the podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like more microphones.
Speaker 1: Maybe some booms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I need a boom guy.
Speaker 0: I think for this one for the the money you gave us work I'm gonna buy some sort of dynamic omnidirectional mic for our geek roundtables that we're gonna be doing at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So anyway, oh again about the PayPal donations.
Speaker 1: don't pay us money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, seriously you have the ability to give us money, but don't all right, so let's read Bayways email.
Speaker 1: Remon Scott I was on vacation when I listened to your podcast in which you outed me as a PayPal donator to the show.
Speaker 1: Thanks didn't expect that.
Speaker 1: You didn't have any place in the PayPal form to include a note So I didn't get a chance to give you some kudos along with the dollar sign.
Speaker 0: I like kudos.
Speaker 1: I found your show via Mark Johnson's mention on board games to go and I was hooked by your podcast style.
Speaker 1: Great professional job.
Speaker 1: You guys are doing.
Speaker 1: you really managed to keep a tight interesting show going every night.
Speaker 1: kudos I've been catching up on all your other non gaming shows except anime, which I don't have any interest in and They're fun and interesting.
Speaker 1: Hope you guys keep going for a long time.
Speaker 1: use the dollar sign for whatever just want to support stuff that I listen to regularly.
Speaker 1: Also, you may have been the first folks who have ever pronounced my name correctly without hints and on air - Cheers Bay.
Speaker 0: Yep, I gotta say when it comes to names if it's a nationality or language We're at all familiar with we usually don't have any trouble with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if I see a name that I have no idea how to pronounce I go with the phonetics You know hoping that someone romanized it correctly.
Speaker 0: The only thing that'll get me is if it's a like if it's written in Cyrillic, I can't read Cyrillic at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I'll just read it the way it looks which is completely wrong.
Speaker 1: I Tend to read, you know I go for the phonetics which means I pronounce things more often than most people because a lot of people don't can't even manage that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: and then if that fails if someone says it correctly to me once that I'm good unless it's a tongue twister and I Just can't do it, but that's so rare Yeah, so Thank You Bay way.
Speaker 0: Yeah Wow, we didn't have so much to say about that partly I think because we decided to do this bit before the show today and then we talked for a while about name pronunciation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that and then we tried to talk about it again.
Speaker 1: The only things I really have to say about it is yeah, Mark Johnson has a cool podcast called board games to go Where he just talks about board games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should probably play his promo at some point.
Speaker 1: I think we should play it Tuesday.
Speaker 0: That was my plan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good one.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, it's kind of weird people giving us props.
Speaker 1: We're still waiting for a hate mail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the first hate the first legitimate hate mail is gonna get into the geek back section.
Speaker 0: So, you know what?
Speaker 0: I think the first real legitimate hate mail we get we'll send them a prize like congratulations.
Speaker 0: You're our first hate mail.
Speaker 0: Thank you so much.
Speaker 1: Yes, and we'll know if it's a real hate mail or not.
Speaker 1: So all you listeners looking for prizes, we'll know.
Speaker 0: yeah, if I get an email smarter than you from like That's why you listen to us and not vice-versa if I get an email from Pete saying yeah you atheists are all gonna rot in hell and Yeah I'll know.
Speaker 0: Alright, so we got some news and it's Thursday so we can do whatever the hell news we want.
Speaker 0: Because we've kind of decided.
Speaker 0: originally we tried to make the news Bit whatever day of the week.
Speaker 0: it was whenever we could.
Speaker 0: so if it was Tuesday We try to have some sort of gaming news or related to gaming news.
Speaker 0: But lately if you've noticed there's been so much tech news That we've been just going longer and longer longer on the news and our show is basically geek nights.
Speaker 0: Plus the 20-minute twit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, so we're pushing ourselves back to that.
Speaker 0: of course now it's Thursday so I could shout to hell until next week.
Speaker 0: But I actually had a bunch of news.
Speaker 0: is that I'm holding off on now until the appropriate day?
Speaker 0: because really and actually Someone who sent us some feedback.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna read yet on the air Accused me of editorial izing why to which I say We don't cover the news.
Speaker 0: We do nothing but editorial eyes.
Speaker 0: What do you want?
Speaker 1: I mean if you're listening to this show The news segment of geek nights is not to tell you the news and inform you.
Speaker 0: if it was I'd be talking about Israel.
Speaker 1: right now If you need to be informed you need to go on the internet to Google News and read a lot or Fark or dig Or anything anything slash that even the point of us going over the news is.
Speaker 1: we say oh look This is a story that happened today.
Speaker 1: now Let us talk about it, you know And we hope that the reason you're listening is to hear our interesting perspective on the events of the recent times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess you know Penn Jillette on his show always says yeah, we take the nut position.
Speaker 0: I guess Scott and I tend to take the asshole position.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: We take the asshole Geek somewhat elitist position.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because we're not gonna pretend we're not just a little bit elitist Yep, at least on some things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're very proletarian.
Speaker 0: on other things Yes, namely things that would give us a bunch of money that we could then use to become elite.
Speaker 0: Ah Anyway, my news is actually video game related But it's also a bunch of other things related and it's something that I knew For a long time because of where I worked and I couldn't say anything about it and now it's been released Officially by other sources meaning I can talk all I want.
Speaker 0: Sony has admitted that the yields on the PlayStation 3 chips are Terrible.
Speaker 1: now wait, wait, wait, didn't you say that, you know Sony ordered X chips and IBM gave them X chips.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is IBM doesn't make all the chips because there are a lot of other companies involved.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the cell chips here.
Speaker 0: Yes, the cell chips I can't talk about this part in great detail.
Speaker 0: you asked about the one thing I still can't talk about but IBM does not make all of the cell chips.
Speaker 0: IBM's primary thing is that they came up with the cell chip and they know all about it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Manufacturing is licensed out to a lot of other fabs simply by the fact that Sony's 300 millimeter and 200 millimeter fabs while very advanced are not as big as the fabs that like AMD and Intel and Chartered and all these.
Speaker 1: of course AMD and Intel have the biggest fabs in the world.
Speaker 1: You can't really an Nvidia?
Speaker 0: I guess Yeah But the point is just that the yields were low.
Speaker 0: now when you make chips The yields are basically the percentage of chips that come out the end of your production line working.
Speaker 1: yeah, because when you may have anyone who doesn't know and you make chips you make them on this big wafer and the wafer has Like a zillion chips on it like hundreds of them even and it's a big wafer of silicon.
Speaker 1: They're really cool-looking.
Speaker 0: I had a shiny one that I that was busted that I used as a.
Speaker 1: yeah it's a big silicon disk and on it are a bunch of chips like just laid out in a grid and They cut the chips out because they're all little squares or rectangles.
Speaker 1: They cut them out and they test them individually and some of them work and some of them don't.
Speaker 0: actually there's.
Speaker 0: there's some chips Where they can test them on the wafer.
Speaker 0: There's yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know you get the idea but the point is that the yields on the cell processors are abysmal.
Speaker 0: and By abysmal and I'm not kidding they're taught.
Speaker 0: we're talking five to ten percent of the chips succeed.
Speaker 1: So that means you make a hundred chips on this wafer and only like five to ten of them actually work.
Speaker 0: the rest of them You just throw away, but you still paid for making a hundred of them.
Speaker 1: imagine if at the the Ford factory where they make Mustangs if they made a hundred Mustangs and then only five of them worked and They had a 95 broken Mustangs that they couldn't do anything with except recycle for materials.
Speaker 0: or imagine your your and you're in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: you want to buy some falafel and you give the guy money and there's a 95% chance that he says no falafel for you.
Speaker 0: Try again It sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean it could be why the PlayStation 3 is so expensive despite not being that much more powerful than other stuff.
Speaker 0: well I mean yield yields tend to be a very tricky business and the Information about yields in factories tends to be very well guarded.
Speaker 0: I happen to know a lot of this because I worked in the factory where all this was going down and it's fine.
Speaker 0: I mean it's finally been released that the yields are so low and A lot of people are saying that the cell chips just can't be made efficiently and that there's really no Solution that's going to come anytime in the near future.
Speaker 0: And all I have to say about this now is that either IBM is losing a lot of money on this or Sony is losing a lot of money on this.
Speaker 1: so betting that Sony is losing the money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because honestly There's other things I can't talk about but IBM is not stupid.
Speaker 0: I don't think IBM cared at all if the PlayStation 3 was successful or not.
Speaker 1: Michael my you know.
Speaker 1: The thing that I got is way back in the day when the when the word cell chip first came around.
Speaker 1: the idea was that Instead of having a CPU you would have like a GPU and a physics PU and an audio PU and that they would all kind of work together in sort of this, you know Communication way like a bunch of cells and that way without instead of having a central processing unit one big powerful Chip, you just have a whole mess of chips that were all kind of weak but combined all working together They would form some sort of living working.
Speaker 0: there was actually a lot of confusion in the outside world as to what cell meant because no one was very clear on it.
Speaker 1: it Became almost a buzzword Yeah, and now it seems like it doesn't really mean anything except a different architecture other than PPC and x86 and etc.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's just.
Speaker 0: there's all sorts of trouble with it.
Speaker 0: Someone's taking a bath and I don't think IBM cares because honestly I You said taking a bath.
Speaker 0: I get the impression Why is saying taking a bath bad?
Speaker 0: what you're busting my balls here?
Speaker 1: It's not bad.
Speaker 0: It's just you're busting my balls.
Speaker 1: Just humorous.
Speaker 0: why you gotta bust my balls?
Speaker 1: Okay, because you didn't take a bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're always silly on Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Anyway, uh my guess my uninformed Me just guessing out of the air.
Speaker 0: This is not factual.
Speaker 0: anyway opinion is that the PlayStation 3 and the Sony orders were largely just kind of a test of the cell chips and a way to recoup some of the cost of R&D and I think cells are going to find a lot of applications in other arenas and Sony is just getting fucked over this.
Speaker 0: Okay, I note this only because I know that a lot of people I talked to while I worked there Who were higher up than me or who knew more about the manufacturing process than me?
Speaker 0: I would always say things because I always knew all the news that I could know from the outside world.
Speaker 0: In fact, my department has talked to me a few times Complaining that they don't know what's going on anymore because I'm not there.
Speaker 0: I told him Reed Fark but I would say things like the PlayStation 3 is gonna fail for these reasons or I heard that the PlayStation 3 is aren't doing well because Of this and I'd say something like that's really gonna hurt IBM's bottom line, isn't it?
Speaker 0: And they would just laugh and that was it Awesome.
Speaker 0: I think Sony is really just not gonna come out.
Speaker 1: so well Yeah I mean if I make engines and some car is gonna use my engine and I sell those engines to those guys and then Their car doesn't sell sure.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna sell any more engines.
Speaker 1: But you know that it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: where they make a deal where I'm gonna constantly make engines It's a deal where they say make this many and I profit on each and every single order they make and if I'm not Doing that then I'm running my business improperly.
Speaker 1: So as long as you take it one order at a time, you can't fail to profit in the manufacturing business.
Speaker 0: Now because I'm not bound by the NDA is anymore.
Speaker 0: At least I'm not bound by NDA is when it comes to new information that I made discover I'm only bound by the NDA.
Speaker 0: is that cover information.
Speaker 0: I learned while I wasn't employee Mm-hmm, so I'll see if I can get some inside sources and find out more about this goal.
Speaker 0: Cuz if I convince someone else to tell me it's perfectly okay.
Speaker 1: It's for it's them breaking the NDA not you.
Speaker 1: Yes alright, so My news is that you know, the RA goes around suing everyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they sued a bunch of mommies and old ladies and kids.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now there was a lady in who lives close to us.
Speaker 1: She lives in like Poughkeepsie or someone and she was fighting and some other lady I think in Oregon was fighting.
Speaker 1: Yep, but there is one woman in Oklahoma named Debbie Foster.
Speaker 1: Oh Oklahoma where the wind comes rushing down the plane you mean where the RA fails in the core.
Speaker 0: That was lame.
Speaker 1: That was lame.
Speaker 0: That was bad.
Speaker 1: I couldn't think of anything that rhymed better, but look he mighty.
Speaker 1: Yes So she fought the RA.
Speaker 1: They said what they did is they came up to her of course and they said settle the case for $5,000.
Speaker 1: She said no, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go fight you in court.
Speaker 1: So she said RA you must provide, you know dates and the names of the files I downloaded and all this kind of evidence, you know evidence.
Speaker 1: and the RA said Yeah, we can't Provide that information.
Speaker 1: We don't have any evidence basically.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: They gave up.
Speaker 1: So Debbie Foster filed a motion for summary judgment, which basically says Hey judge, they don't have any evidence.
Speaker 1: end this shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah it's kind of like one of the mechanics and burning wheel dismiss.
Speaker 0: you just go up to the judge and basically say This case is stupid and it's obvious.
Speaker 0: Please throw it out and the judge can say yes or no.
Speaker 1: now before the judge had a chance to say yes or no the RA said you know what.
Speaker 1: since we got no evidence we out and The court said all right, you're out with prejudice.
Speaker 0: Now that is something that judges can do it.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of situations where they can do it.
Speaker 0: But if they if you dismiss a case, it's like alright the case is done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you dismiss it with prejudice It's the judge officially saying that not only is this done, but you're an idiot.
Speaker 1: Now, let me read this sentence here in his opinion judge Lee R West wrote Because this court finds the plaintiffs voluntary dismissal with prejudice services as a complete education of the issues set forth in Their complaint and acts as a bar to further action on their claims.
Speaker 1: The court concludes the matter has been finally educated in the defendants favor.
Speaker 0: I think you mean adjudicated.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're right adjudicated God Which represents a judicially sanctioned material alteration in the legal relationship between Deborah Foster and the plaintiffs.
Speaker 1: miss Foster is therefore the prevailing party for purposes of the Copyright Act and That also means the RA has to pay for the legal fees of Debbie Foster.
Speaker 0: See I wish they'd sue me.
Speaker 0: I have a lawyer ready.
Speaker 0: I'm just waiting for someone to sue me at this point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't have a lawyer so I don't really want to be sued so badly.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah, but I just note again because I've said this a bunch of times but for all the fire and fury of the RIAA and the MPAA suing people They haven't won as far as I know any case.
Speaker 0: every single case They have brought every single lawsuit has either Settled out of court.
Speaker 0: or if the person had the cajones the testicular fortitude to fight They always win because the RIAA's case is bullshit Yep, and they got no evidence.
Speaker 0: I mean honestly even if you upload and download files There is really no way to prove in a court of law that that was the case And the amount of effort and energy the RIAA would have to put forth to actually even come close to securing a judgment in their favor Would be more than the money they could ever get out of the purse
Speaker 1: and especially when you consider the number of cases They're doing.
Speaker 1: if everyone fought they basically wouldn't have enough legal power to actually do all those cases.
Speaker 1: They only have enough legal power to do all those settlements because settlements are easy.
Speaker 1: It's give us money or else.
Speaker 1: Okay, here you go.
Speaker 1: If they actually had to fight all those cases in court They'd have to just give up most of them and they probably lose all of them.
Speaker 0: the moral here is very simple if you were sued and you know, you're in the right or you know that you will win or You have testicular fortitude Fight you'll probably win.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't be a wuss All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't be a menace.
Speaker 1: Yeah Since the beginning of time humans have sought to express their innermost thoughts Their deepest desires.
Speaker 1: van Gogh Picasso Caveman number 17 all were overlooked in their time.
Speaker 1: yet their works went on to be praised as Masterpieces and from that great tradition.
Speaker 0: Whoa, hold it.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: if you're interested in current art trends or one advice on how to create art on the computer?
Speaker 0: Find out about helpful online tutorials to improve your skill hear insightful interviews with artists that are still alive and kicking Or find out how to get started in art trades or commissioning.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't really know.
Speaker 1: Maybe I can find you a website.
Speaker 1: I'm not really cut out for that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Some people need the classics for them.
Speaker 0: We have museums for everyone else.
Speaker 0: There's the artist alley podcast.
Speaker 0: come by and see us at www.candycornstudios.com.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 1: Any things today?
Speaker 0: I got a thing.
Speaker 0: This is something.
Speaker 0: this is actually a new thing.
Speaker 0: I'm not copping out with one of my retro things which means I couldn't find a thing.
Speaker 0: There's this video out and it's it happened.
Speaker 1: news flash rim can't find his thing.
Speaker 0: You know what when I buy a Wii that'll all be taken care of.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So there's a video floating around and this was on live news this morning.
Speaker 0: like it just happened some Fox reporter is in Lebanon.
Speaker 0: no, he wasn't always in the gobbits Gaza Strip.
Speaker 0: Yes Well, I mean I just remember that cuz the fighting right now is in Lebanon mostly.
Speaker 0: but anyway, there was a reason in the Gaza Strip and there's a Israeli tank division or brigade or something right over the hill?
Speaker 0: I just out of camera range and he's there covering the story and You know, he's just there in those open field No one around wearing this little flak jacket and he's talking about, you know there's Israeli troops right there and he's live on the air and then Someone who is most likely an Israeli troop start shooting at him.
Speaker 0: Yeah and and the funny thing is it like it he runs away and it cuts back to like the guys and The two guys and the girl who were at the Fox studio and the one woman's like run away hide run away.
Speaker 0: What are we like?
Speaker 0: yelling at the guy to like get out of the way and then it's all over and the one guy is Like yeah, you know warzone whatever.
Speaker 0: and then the stupid guy.
Speaker 1: Oh the stupid guy.
Speaker 0: There's a guy sitting on the right of the screen.
Speaker 0: I don't know any of these Fox News anchors are but this guy not the brightest he has a kind of a sloping forehead and He starts saying like why would they shoot at him?
Speaker 0: He has press written clearly on the front and back.
Speaker 0: you could see it.
Speaker 0: and the smart guy is like, um, it's a warzone.
Speaker 0: They were far away and they saw a guy with something that might have looked like a weapon.
Speaker 0: You just shoot at him and he's like.
Speaker 0: but it had press written all over it.
Speaker 0: But but but.
Speaker 0: and the guys like.
Speaker 0: those bad people shoot at anyone they see.
Speaker 0: and then the guys like but it was Israel.
Speaker 0: and then the guy the smart guy just didn't say anything.
Speaker 0: and then they cut away and the guys like if that guy is still Has his job Wow, and the fact that after the guy said bad guys shoot at people and then later the guys like really and it was just this.
Speaker 0: I really can't describe how dumb this guy looked.
Speaker 1: Wow This guy is real stupid.
Speaker 0: more to the point if you're ever a press person in a warzone and you're filming live Don't say where any troops are because they're going to shoot you.
Speaker 1: the thing is I don't think that they heard the guy sang.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, no, no, definitely not.
Speaker 0: but there's a good chance.
Speaker 0: that I mean Israel I know for a fact is probably watching any live news They see to make sure that there's no intelligence leaking out and I wouldn't be surprised if the guy kept reporting or something.
Speaker 0: They were just shelled the area.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean they have planes everywhere.
Speaker 1: They can just go boom anytime they want.
Speaker 0: Yeah where they want because I mean the situation going on now is a lot like the six-day war where?
Speaker 0: Israel has complete and total air superiority.
Speaker 0: So no one else really has a chance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: I'm just glad I'm on this side of the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's a bunch of crazies over there and I feel bad for the non crazies that are over there because there's a lot Of non crazies over there those non crazies.
Speaker 1: escape escape over here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're not crazy, then you won't mind doing that.
Speaker 0: I mean for every time on the news you see like a bunch of Palestinians dancing around a burning American flag.
Speaker 0: There's twice as many Palestinians sit in their houses going god damn it.
Speaker 0: They're at it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know every time you see like Israeli soldiers marching in somewhere, you know shooting at people There are a bunch of Israeli people sitting at home playing video games going god.
Speaker 0: Damn it Yeah, so you got a news.
Speaker 1: yeah, I do a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, it's things of the daytime.
Speaker 1: So at USC, which I guess is University of South Carolina, I'm not sure There's this the vice president of the Student Council went away to Washington to do some talking.
Speaker 1: I guess I don't know.
Speaker 1: What about some?
Speaker 1: something lame?
Speaker 1: Anyway, while he was away the rest of the Student Council filled his office with balloons.
Speaker 0: Now one.
Speaker 0: this is an awesome prank that I've pulled more than once in my life on people and to.
Speaker 0: The thing of the day that Scott is about to describe is Much like the video of the dude attacking those kids who were skateboarding an example of what is wrong with this country.
Speaker 1: Well wrong with people.
Speaker 0: I think wrong with people who are indignant and annoying and able to be annoyed right now.
Speaker 1: The first problem is when you pull a practical joke, right?
Speaker 1: What you want to do is you want to have a lot of people there and when the joke is pulled You need to have those people immediately Laughing hysterically non-stop or else it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: unless it's one of those subtle Andy Kaufman style jokes Yeah, but those don't really work so well, you know in general they work really well.
Speaker 0: The problem is not many people get to see the result Yeah, or they're a long-term thing like you screw with a guy over the course of several months.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Obviously if we had done this to someone everyone would gonna.
Speaker 1: And if like it happened to you you would just go.
Speaker 1: oh you got me.
Speaker 1: All right, let's pop all these balloons Yep.
Speaker 1: Now this guy obviously has a Pole longer than 10 feet long up his ass.
Speaker 1: There is no question.
Speaker 1: and he goes in and he you know, he's already mad about something Maybe he knows the balloons already.
Speaker 1: and he goes in and he opens his door and he starts yelling at everyone.
Speaker 1: He's like, oh, it's not funny.
Speaker 0: The best part is when he's like the one guy who's standing there's just laughing hysterically.
Speaker 0: He's like you.
Speaker 0: don't think I'm serious.
Speaker 0: Look at me being serious.
Speaker 1: And everyone's like this is a waste of the students money.
Speaker 1: blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And at this point everyone stops laughing because they're like they realize that wow, this guy's just a giant douche.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you can't stop laughing or else that's what helps these people out.
Speaker 1: You have to keep laughing Even if it's not funny anymore.
Speaker 1: keep laughing cuz it's so much better.
Speaker 1: If a guy is yelling and screaming seriously and you just keep laughing Then it makes it feel stupid.
Speaker 0: if you actually shut up then it puts him above you and it's like oh Though then that this guy starts arguing with these people like this was a waste of money of student money.
Speaker 0: And they're like, yeah who paid for these balloons?
Speaker 1: He's like we paid for them.
Speaker 1: They're like 80 bucks for balloons big deal.
Speaker 1: Then he's like, well, where'd the air come from?
Speaker 0: Air's not free.
Speaker 1: Yeah says that he does say is that this is a guy with no sense of humor and These are the people that I I say are the worst people on earth people who are just no sense of humor.
Speaker 1: You're a bad person.
Speaker 0: Well, there have been multiple Canadian.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know why I said Canadians.
Speaker 0: There have been multiple Canadian comedians out there who have made jokes to the effect of all the problems in the Middle East.
Speaker 0: Come down to the fact that the people involved in these problems just have no sense of humor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Yeah, that's really it.
Speaker 0: if you have a sense of humor It's very hard for you to do evil things
Speaker 1: And the better your sense of humor is the harder it is for you to do evil
Speaker 0: or in the very least even if you can Do evil things and laugh about it like a maniacal.
Speaker 1: I think what was Lewis Black's joke?
Speaker 1: Like, you know you go up to someone and you say Yeah, if you if you go and become a suicide bomber then when you get to heaven, there's a bunch of virgins You know, but someone actually doesn't have a sense of humor and believes that.
Speaker 0: well now you got a scary dude Yep, plus by the converse anyone who has a sense of humor is much more easily able to deal with problems.
Speaker 0: I mean Say you're walking into a movie and you drop your drink.
Speaker 0: Someone with a sense of humor would go and maybe make a self-deprecating joke.
Speaker 0: Someone without a sense of humor will.
Speaker 0: that's the end of the world.
Speaker 0: my drink Son of a bitch damn it.
Speaker 1: Damn it.
Speaker 1: or even worse Let's say a guy with the sense of humor You know is walking down the hallway and he bumps into someone and they spills and the soda spills on both of them.
Speaker 1: if The both guys have a sense of humor they go.
Speaker 1: Oh Shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're all wet.
Speaker 1: All right, let's go wash it off.
Speaker 0: All right, talk about a sticky situation.
Speaker 1: If they don't have a sense of humor, it's gonna be a fistfight.
Speaker 1: So, you know when someone what that's great?
Speaker 0: because then everyone else around with a sense of humor gets to watch a fistfight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is is sometimes if it's more than a fistfight like in the Middle East and such well Yeah, other people nearby get hurt.
Speaker 1: I mean, what if it was a bomb fight?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not so good in the movie.
Speaker 0: See, why can't Hezbollah just sneak into Israel and instead of blowing someone up just throw a water balloon at someone and run away?
Speaker 1: Go to the Knesset and fill it with balloons.
Speaker 0: You know what if that happened if if terrorists we started doing things like that like instead of blowing up a building Go and set off a bunch of balloons in the building or some sort of giant prank in the building that says one Go
Speaker 1: fill the White House of golf balls.
Speaker 0: cuz think about this.
Speaker 0: in one go.
Speaker 0: It says I could have blown you up, but I didn't.
Speaker 0: and two it's funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get your point.
Speaker 1: That's what we need to do.
Speaker 1: We need to start an organization of Comedic terrorism.
Speaker 1: Frank Eris we go and we'll fill the Empire State Building with whipped cream.
Speaker 1: Okay All right, anyway, so yeah watch this guy and despise him.
Speaker 1: and if you ever meet someone like this make sure you.
Speaker 1: I don't know laugh deprecate them.
Speaker 0: actually I remember a book I read when I was in middle school and I don't remember what it was called or anything But it basically involved.
Speaker 0: I think it was Poseidon or Zeus.
Speaker 1: Poseidon such a prick.
Speaker 0: I know Poseidon is the big but he's the awesomest.
Speaker 0: what besides?
Speaker 0: just an asshole.
Speaker 1: He's so awesome.
Speaker 0: I only get away with saying he's an asshole cuz I don't go on the ocean often.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't get me so easily.
Speaker 0: You can bet that I'll be singing a different tune if I'm on a ship with Odysseus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's right, but I forget if it was Poseidon or Zeus or exactly what it was.
Speaker 0: But there's this book about.
Speaker 0: you know modern world and as this Greek God wakes up, and he's like hey I'm back and you know what are the ramifications of that.
Speaker 0: and In the end it gets to the point where the reason he left in the first place way back was that he took over a village and the villagers realized eventually like the villagers drove away by laughing at him like they were like you're just as washed up old God and the village laughed at him.
Speaker 0: And then he just killed them all and went to sleep.
Speaker 0: and the end of the book involves everyone just laughing at this God again To try to make him go away, and he finally realizes.
Speaker 0: Oh, and then he just leaves.
Speaker 1: yep It sounds like a good.
Speaker 0: you got to do to people like that.
Speaker 0: what the people in that book in that village that was fake Did to Zeus or possibly Poseidon mm-hmm?
Speaker 0: I wish I knew what book it was or what it was actually about.
Speaker 1: if someone knows the book tell us Yeah, no, I read it.
Speaker 0: Nope the book wasn't that good Serious never mind.
Speaker 1: It wasn't.
Speaker 1: won't tell us cuz then we might read it by accident.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like.
Speaker 0: what are the socio-political ramifications of God's coming back.
Speaker 0: It was like.
Speaker 0: Here's a pulp story about a god coming back.
Speaker 0: It was alright.
Speaker 1: I guess you know lensman's actually turning it out to be kind of a pulp story, but it's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait till you see the fucking anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, we've got it.
Speaker 0: We could watch it right now.
Speaker 1: Well, we're not gonna.
Speaker 1: We're gonna wait till I finish reading all these goddamn books.
Speaker 0: I know the folks over at anime world order have seen lens man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen it like six times.
Speaker 1: Well, we're gonna cover it all.
Speaker 1: so you guys just wait for us to read those books.
Speaker 0: and yeah We should finish that Tezuka stuff first.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should all right all right, so today's Thursday.
Speaker 0: You know talk about anything day And we had a bunch of ideas.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about logical fallacies But we're gonna wait a little bit on that though.
Speaker 0: Mad props to all of you in the forums who have been arguing by means of fallacies as in pointing fallacies out in other people Because not to flame the guy whose name is blast flame.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was a terrible argument.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean seriously You just contradicted yourself.
Speaker 0: You can't come in.
Speaker 1: your hypocritical.
Speaker 0: your uh your your presidents were all begged the question and It was just downhill from there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really and the burden of proof was still on you.
Speaker 0: in fact It is still on you if you want to keep arguing.
Speaker 1: yeah, so I think he's pretty much given up at this point.
Speaker 1: It'd be interesting to see if he has anything.
Speaker 0: Was I think it was the goth father, but I can't say offhand who who just posted.
Speaker 0: He didn't say anything He just quoted this dude, and then he was like fallacy of accident And I felt I almost laughed out loud at work.
Speaker 0: that was like the most awesome thing it made my day Yep, so keep that up, but we decided we would tell another geek fable.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's a geek fable.
Speaker 1: How was the last time we did a geek fable?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's been a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's been a while since a how to not suck also Yeah for and this is kind of both But it's more of a fable because we're not gonna talk about how to do this though.
Speaker 0: That would be a good episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're going to talk about what happened when we did it.
Speaker 1: alright, so let's start.
Speaker 0: We're both living in Connie yep Colin manner in it in a really nice apartment as far as our IT apartments go in Rochester Yep, and rim moved out to go to Here.
Speaker 0: yeah, well all around here to work at IBM.
Speaker 1: I lived in like five different places Yep, and you just kind of put your stuff in storage somewhere right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I put some of my stuff in storage.
Speaker 0: I had a lot of my stuff at Emily's house.
Speaker 1: That's right Emily's house.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I had a lot of stuff in Rochester.
Speaker 0: I had a lot of stuff still in our apartment that Scott was living in with Kevin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: There was stuff in the apartment.
Speaker 0: there was stuff in Emily's basement There was stuff in storage and in addition you had stuff in your house and stuff in colony And I think you had stuff in storage.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I. what I did is I took all the stuff that I actually cared to keep and the stuff that I needed on a Day-to-day basis.
Speaker 1: I brought to Connecticut when I left our RIT like a year later The stuff that was important, but I didn't need day to day.
Speaker 1: I put in storage in Rochester in one of those store-to-door boxes and the stuff I didn't care about.
Speaker 1: I just left with Kevin.
Speaker 1: I said up it's not and I don't really care about it anymore.
Speaker 0: And also all my furniture.
Speaker 0: we left there.
Speaker 0: Well, most of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah the stuff we didn't care about.
Speaker 1: So what we did we?
Speaker 1: finally I was living in Connecticut and rim was living in around here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we told the story of how we found our giant house and got it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we found this place and we decided to rent it.
Speaker 1: We signed the papers and it was time to move in.
Speaker 0: So now we're when we're sitting in our house our empty house and we're like, alright now we have to get all of our shit.
Speaker 0: yep, and All I have to say is that it was quite an ordeal.
Speaker 1: Moving sucks.
Speaker 0: Now the worst part is it could have been so much easier.
Speaker 1: It could have been if you would have hired some guys and paid more money.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: there are a whole bunch of companies that will come to your house pack up everything you own take it to your new house and Unpack it all or at least put it all in the proper room and leave.
Speaker 1: they cost a fortune.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing they don't cost that much and because that much.
Speaker 1: but they cost more than what we got now But not that much more.
Speaker 0: actually I got some quotes hundreds of dollars hundreds dollars, whatever.
Speaker 0: that would have been so worth it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and plus we get big discounts from our IT and I got an IBM discount.
Speaker 0: but or every single one of them.
Speaker 0: because oh, that's right, I called like ten of these companies and Every one of them was like yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this will be great.
Speaker 0: I was they were like, how far are you moving?
Speaker 0: I was like about four three hundred and twenty miles.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh that'll be great quote and it wasn't a bad price at all.
Speaker 0: And then they were like, all right from where to where.
Speaker 0: and I was like Rochester, New York to Beacon, New York One end of New York to the other and then they'd be quiet and none of them would do it.
Speaker 0: Apparently none of these companies will ship your stuff within a state.
Speaker 0: They will only go over state lines.
Speaker 1: I don't know what people do if they have to move like across Texas or from the north of California to the south.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: the same thing we did suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't know why that is.
Speaker 0: If anyone does know why tell us yeah kind of like how come in New York City?
Speaker 0: They give everyone a straw no matter what you buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah Why do people do that?
Speaker 1: I don't know anyway.
Speaker 1: So what we did is he went to Rochester where most much of the goods were and we rented a truck.
Speaker 0: now I rented a twelve foot or a four.
Speaker 0: I rented a 14 foot budget moving truck.
Speaker 1: now That's a pretty good sized truck.
Speaker 1: It would be a tight fit for all our stuff, but it would have been okay Yeah, plus there were some things like the couches.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna throw away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were gonna throw away a lot of the big stuff.
Speaker 0: So it wasn't a big deal and also was cheap and it was pretty much the largest truck I would have felt comfortable driving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we get there and as I pull up I noticed that there's nothing but 24-foot trucks as in not a truck, but it's almost a semi.
Speaker 0: It is a giant tractor like just oh my god kind of.
Speaker 1: it wasn't a trailer, but it was a big truck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's one of those.
Speaker 1: any bigger would have been a tractor trailing Yeah, but it was massive like.
Speaker 0: I had a lot of trouble with this thing, but I'll talk about all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is is that they reserve the right to give you a bigger truck for the same price, you know They won't give you a smaller truck for the same price because that's ripping you off.
Speaker 1: But if you want let's say, you know a pickup truck They'll they can just give you like a moving van at the same price as a pickup truck.
Speaker 0: So now we've got this truck and we're in downtown Rochester and we're trying.
Speaker 0: I'm trying.
Speaker 0: no Scott wouldn't drive it and Pete wouldn't drive It.
Speaker 0: so I had he can't drive.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, no, he wouldn't drive it of course.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he couldn't drive and you were just afraid to drive it.
Speaker 1: I wasn't gonna drive I wasn't gonna be held responsible for something that was rented in your name.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, you could have rented it.
Speaker 1: No No, yeah, why I wasn't gonna was yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm driving this giant truck.
Speaker 0: I ran over how many curbs and like waste paper bins on the side of a corner and Bumping into things.
Speaker 0: this thing was massive and I did.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: it took me a long time to realize that When you're driving a truck that big you have to practically go past Any street you want to turn down and then do this really sharp kind of turn to get onto it and it was just crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, so we rented this thing and it all told it cost us over a thousand dollars for the truck and the diesel fuel.
Speaker 1: anyway We had to go around filling this truck with our shit.
Speaker 1: So we went to Colony and we emptied that out.
Speaker 0: We got everything in except we took the love seat.
Speaker 0: But we had a big couch that was nasty and we just told Kevin he'd keep it.
Speaker 0: I just threw it away.
Speaker 1: Yeah the thing was that it was kind of good that we got this giant truck because We were able to put so much more stuff in it and we didn't have a problem fitting it in because it was so much More space than we needed.
Speaker 1: We just kind of kept loading stuff in with no worries about running out of space.
Speaker 0: Yep, like with the smaller truck it would have all fit but we would have had to pack it all like specially and planned it.
Speaker 0: It would have taken a long time with the giant truck.
Speaker 1: We just kind of tossed shit in until we were done Yep.
Speaker 0: So then we got all of our stuff from colony.
Speaker 0: that took hours and it was tedious and painful and everything was heavy.
Speaker 1: Then we went to the place where my stuff was stored Yep, which meant I had to drive around downtown Rochester again, which sucked.
Speaker 1: that was right near the airport We should have known but anyway, we got there and it was actually pretty simple.
Speaker 1: we drove the truck up to the box as close as we could and I didn't have so much stuff in the box and we just kind of emptied the entire contents into the truck and it Didn't really take long at all.
Speaker 1: It was like oh, we're done.
Speaker 0: then I had to back that goddamn truck out of that place.
Speaker 0: I was so afraid I was just gonna like mow down a bunch of nuns.
Speaker 1: It would have been awesome.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I wouldn't want to get nun juices all over it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep All right, then we had to drive the truck all the way out to Leroy, which isn't so far.
Speaker 0: It was like a 40-minute drive.
Speaker 0: I couldn't speed at this point.
Speaker 1: I was no longer in the truck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott just drove back to our house at this point.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 1: I took the car and I was like say
Speaker 0: yeah So me and Pete are driving this truck to Leroy to Emily's house to get like things like my giant bed which I couldn't leave in the apartment because Kevin needed a place to put his bed and Brendan doesn't know me.
Speaker 0: My bed is a giant ass queen size like cherry oak bed with a giant like double thick pillow top and the bed is huge.
Speaker 1: It's just a queen size bed.
Speaker 1: It's not that big.
Speaker 0: Well, no tall wise it's huge.
Speaker 0: I mean the mattress is like almost two feet thick.
Speaker 0: That's about average for a mattress and then the box spring separately is another foot.
Speaker 1: That's how box springs are.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, well, my bed is almost is almost a foot taller than your bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's because the frame of my bed is is set lower on to the grass.
Speaker 0: It's this giant as wood bed and is a big headboard and a footer and all that stuff and it's old as hell.
Speaker 0: There's a cool story about it like it's from my family from way way way back and Stuff like that that I couldn't keep in in the apartment.
Speaker 0: additionally They had a giant couch that they didn't want anymore and the couch had a lot of attachment.
Speaker 0: I mean they'd had it for a long time and Emily had that very fond memories of laying on that couch when sick or just hanging around in the couch when she was young.
Speaker 0: And it was it's a pretty good couch and it folds out into a bed.
Speaker 0: So they asked me you want the couch?
Speaker 1: and I said, yeah, sure because we had just left Kevin the shit couch.
Speaker 0: So, alright now we have a good couch.
Speaker 0: You have to buy one.
Speaker 1: It's yeah We were gonna buy a couch.
Speaker 0: if we didn't you know This couch is a thousand times better than the couch we left behind and it was free.
Speaker 1: Yep So hey better than buying one.
Speaker 1: Let's take it.
Speaker 0: So Pete and I go to pick it up and carry it out of Emily's family's house at which point I forget which one of us said it.
Speaker 0: but we said that thing's a fucker.
Speaker 0: it weighed an infinite number of pounds.
Speaker 1: I mean it was like a couch and a bed with a metal frame in.
Speaker 0: it Is like steel.
Speaker 0: the whole thing is steel It's just it and a big heavy wood and God.
Speaker 1: and it's so cumbersome because of the way the sofa bed is inside of it.
Speaker 0: But you got to be careful or it'll fall out while you're carrying it.
Speaker 0: and it was.
Speaker 0: it was so heavy that We could barely lift it, but you finally got it into the truck.
Speaker 0: Yes after much doing and then you know We tooled around in Rochester for a while and then Pete and I had to drive this truck all the way back to beacon.
Speaker 0: Hahaha now the thing is Pete.
Speaker 0: originally I was gonna go buy Albany drop Pete off at his house and then Continue to beacon where Scott and I would then unload the truck.
Speaker 1: You're gonna stop and go driving around Albany in this giant truck.
Speaker 0: now I hadn't even considered at this point unpacking.
Speaker 0: I hadn't really thought that through and neither had Scott.
Speaker 0: We just didn't really think about that.
Speaker 0: So Here Pete and I are.
Speaker 0: we've got what we get on the throw.
Speaker 0: We were about to go and then Pete hems and haws and then he eventually says, you know what?
Speaker 0: Uh, he's gonna skip work on Monday.
Speaker 0: He'll just come back to beacon with us.
Speaker 1: Hooray, which means now We don't have to drive the truck all around some crazy roads.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah instead I got to take the fun route 17 way through the mountains Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So we're driving this massive truck as fast as it can go through the mountains of New York the Poconos Yep on what semi windy not quite a freeway yet roads make your jokes about poking people with noses.
Speaker 0: yeah, I just I had to get gas at one point because It's real heavy and that thing had a giant diesel tank, but damn did it use diesel real quick Especially how fast I was trying to make it go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it was carrying shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, lots of stuff like the fucker.
Speaker 0: So I had an adventure going to a truck stop because I was trying to find diesel fuel and no one had it.
Speaker 0: I eventually had to get off go to a truck stop where I found a diesel fuel thing and truck stops Don't work like gas stations.
Speaker 0: There was a thing that I thought I could put my credit card in and it didn't work and eventually it I realized that was A special trucker card and I had to go into the truck stop tell how many gallons of diesel I wanted.
Speaker 0: I didn't know.
Speaker 0: she looked at the truck and guessed how much I would need.
Speaker 0: It was like something sick like 30 gallons Twice as much as my car holds and I said there was like a timer thing where it filled up automatically.
Speaker 0: So while that was going on I went into the truck stop and you know Watch my face in the shower room and I saw a bunch of people watching TV and I got some food and Pete was hanging Out.
Speaker 0: we didn't talk to any truckers.
Speaker 0: We want to get back on the road But that was an interesting experience in a truck stop.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll talk about truck stops someday.
Speaker 1: So much experience in one truck stop.
Speaker 0: No, I've been in a total of four truck stops.
Speaker 0: I have showered in two truck stops.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Yeah, there's this one truck stop in Canada that I stopped at a bunch of times and one time I just showered there Uh-huh, but anyway, we get back on the road now.
Speaker 0: the thing didn't really have a CD player It just had a radio.
Speaker 0: So we're trying to listen to the radio and there were phantom rock because I we'd hit scan right where it would sit on a Station.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah for ten seconds and then we go to the next station, but if it scan again, it'll stop.
Speaker 1: meanwhile I'm sitting in beacon going.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah in a mostly empty house with nothing to sleep on or anything.
Speaker 0: At least the electricity was on by that point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was doing good.
Speaker 0: So now we'd be sitting there to be like crap music.
Speaker 0: guy yelling about Jesus crap music.
Speaker 0: another guy yelling about Jesus.
Speaker 0: Zeppelin guy yelling about Jesus and we had really slow reaction times because we were just kind of cruising.
Speaker 0: So we'd get back to the guy yelling about Jesus.
Speaker 0: We're like, hey Zeppelin.
Speaker 0: So I hit back.
Speaker 0: it would go back to the previous guy yelling about Jesus next and we'd go to the next guy yelling about Jesus and We couldn't find the rock station that was just there and I that wouldn't have been notable Except that that happened like a thousand times.
Speaker 0: There's probably just one or two really weak rock stations But they'd come in on the scan and then when we try to go back they wouldn't be there and even if I went manually I just couldn't find it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it was.
Speaker 0: I Was getting kind of desperate for some non crap music or non guy yelling about Jesus.
Speaker 0: We ended up.
Speaker 0: you listen to a guy yell about Jesus for a while And he didn't convert you.
Speaker 0: it was mostly just funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright, so we finally get home and we park it and we get out and Scott stand at the door Like you said something like what took you guys so long and I think I flipped you off Something like that.
Speaker 0: and then he's.
Speaker 0: and then Scott says Oh Pete and I was like, yeah Pete came and Pete's like yo Hey now for anyone doesn't know Pete we've talked about Pete before Pete's been on our show because Pete is a scientist and Pete is our resident geek night science expert.
Speaker 0: We consult him and occasionally our good friend Lisa who was also a scientist whenever there is some sort of sciency truthiness We need to know about.
Speaker 1: and Scott you any other Scott.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Scott Johnson Pharmaceuticals and also science.
Speaker 0: Yes, we know many scientists.
Speaker 1: I'm a computer scientist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever I'm a usability engineer.
Speaker 0: Oh All right, so then we open up the back of the truck and we're like, all right We gotta unpack this thing and the thing right there is the fucker.
Speaker 0: so This is the point at which Scott and I realized looking at this thing that if Pete were not there at that moment and Scott And I had to unload this truck by ourselves.
Speaker 0: There would be no geek nights because we would be dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the police would have found two Gangly thin geeks crushed to death under a massive steel couch behind a budget truck on Conklin Street and beacon.
Speaker 1: that is what they would have found.
Speaker 0: Yes Even with Pete it took us like a half hour to get this thing into the house.
Speaker 1: It was just ridiculous.
Speaker 1: And even then when he fuck cuz we have to go upstairs to get shit into our house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz our house is big and basically our front door and our back door.
Speaker 0: There's a deck on each of them and the deck is up about a half a story.
Speaker 0: So it's nice because we have these big decks and they're elevators, you know, the zombies can't get us.
Speaker 0: All we have to do is destroy the stairs and we have a zombie fortress.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so this day we did a half hour at least I'm not kidding and then on its way into the house We actually damaged one of the walls in the house.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean we had enough time just getting the thing off the truck.
Speaker 0: like we got it off the truck and now it's laying on Its side in the street and we're standing there like Fuck this thing.
Speaker 0: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: Let's just leave it here Let's just leave it.
Speaker 0: We don't know where it came from And we finally get it up and we get it and we roll it into the house because we can't really fit it through the Door so well, so it's like up on end and it comes into the house and then it leans over And then it goes BAM into the wall and just push this gash right there and the house We've just moved into.
Speaker 0: we've just put a giant security pot deposit down on Put a dent in the wall within an hour of me coming to the house.
Speaker 0: We've already damaged it fucking Luckily, we fixed the damage pretty easily, but we finally got the couch in and I was done.
Speaker 0: I really didn't want to unpack anything else.
Speaker 0: I would have been fine.
Speaker 1: It's just that couch Yeah, but I think we did eventually bring the rest of the shit in the house.
Speaker 0: Yeah We've decided to unpack the whole thing that night because we didn't want to.
Speaker 0: Nothing would have been worse than going to sleep Waking up and realizing we still had all of that shit to unpack and of course not sleeping on beds Yeah, even though I didn't actually put my bed together.
Speaker 0: I just slept on the floor.
Speaker 1: I slept on my bed Yeah, and keep it.
Speaker 0: I mean we didn't unpack it.
Speaker 0: We took us about two weeks Unpack everything we owned to the point that we could live in our house as opposed to just living in a sea of garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and now like even though I might want to move to somewhere else, you know Cuz I have to drive pretty far to work The the effort of moving all this shit out of this house and into some other house is so great That is a huge deterrent to moving anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I mean all told it took us multiple days of concerted effort weeks of planning lots of phone calls over a $1,000 plus the agony of driving a 24-foot fucking truck through the mountains and dropping a couch on us.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the moral of tonight's show.
Speaker 0: We love morality.
Speaker 0: turn turn turn.
Speaker 0: tell us the lesson that we should learn don't move Keep your ass wherever it is just park it and don't move.
Speaker 0: or if you're gonna move either pay a bunch of people to do it all for you or Sell everything you got.
Speaker 0: move somewhere buy new shit.
Speaker 1: exactly.
Speaker 1: Don't move with more than you can fit in say the trunk of your car.
Speaker 1: I mean good God, you know, or maybe if you can rent a u-haul, that's not so bad.
Speaker 1: But now if you have to move like a lot of big things Either pay a shit ton of money to have guys do it for you so that you don't have to do anything or Don't move now.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of little corollaries to this.
Speaker 0: I mean one thing is that I was a very much a pack rat like I would keep anything that I thought would ever be interesting or useful and After moving I threw away a good quarter of the things I owned because they just they weren't useful.
Speaker 0: They were in the way and if I ever move again I'm gonna have to lug that crap around somewhere and stick it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna take it out of one closet Put it in a box go to another house take it out of that box put it back in a closet Exactly.
Speaker 0: So I threw away like all my DS game.
Speaker 1: Yes, like I threw away a lot of shit.
Speaker 1: You know, there are certain things I keep but you know I keep it limited and there's a lot of shit that I would have kept when I was in say high school that now I Just go huh?
Speaker 1: This is trash.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep The collector mentality is pretty much dead and if you're a collector Either a become not a collector and sell your shit on eBay or be don't move.
Speaker 0: I mean God.
Speaker 0: like books are the big thing.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: I own so many books, but I've lost track or lost or destroyed probably more than half of the books I've ever owned.
Speaker 1: Well, you tend to just eat books while you read them.
Speaker 1: It's like I think you just well honestly I think your hands have like these book grinders on them.
Speaker 0: Most of my books I don't the books that you've seen me eat are the ones that are very very large.
Speaker 0: You know small books, I don't eat.
Speaker 0: my small books are all in good condition, but like the Count of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: so just gonna use as an example the count of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 0: one is the longest book I ever read and In like all the way through I've skimmed books that were longer, but those were textbooks.
Speaker 0: It's the longest thickest most number of pages book I've ever read and in addition It wasn't bound so wonderfully and I read it over a fairly long period of time.
Speaker 0: that book saw some action.
Speaker 0: But once I read a book I really completely lose track of it.
Speaker 0: like it doesn't exist anymore I almost immediately will lend it to someone or leave it somewhere.
Speaker 0: I'll probably never see it again Mm-hmm, which is fine because I love just lending my books away at this point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I lend all my books out and whatever.
Speaker 1: But yeah I like.
Speaker 1: I need a new book shelving solution because I'm starting to buy a lot of manga and trade out for bags.
Speaker 1: So right now I have like two or three stacks of them on the floor that I got no shelf to put on.
Speaker 0: Looky-mighty if I ever get all those books that I own before I went to college that are currently sitting in my mom's house Aren't those?
Speaker 1: aren't most of those just lame D&D books?
Speaker 0: No, a lot of them are but by no means not even close to the majority not even a third.
Speaker 1: All right, granted.
Speaker 0: I do own almost every one.
Speaker 1: How many of them are fantasy novels?
Speaker 0: Not that many.
Speaker 0: most of the fantasy I read when I was young were actually the Forgotten Realms novels Which I just said with a D&D book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I read mostly well and like Tolkien You know all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: I read a decent amount of God, I'm not gonna talk about this now But I'll tell we'll do a show on what we used to read and what we read now.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm because I could go on for great deep for many many moons.
Speaker 1: if you want to see what I read just go to Apre, ch e dot list.
Speaker 1: all l is ta l calm.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm currently reading a nancy boys.
Speaker 0: I just finished the difference engine.
Speaker 1: I'm currently reading galactic patrol the actual first book in the lens min series.
Speaker 0: I should find the novelization of MD Geist and check that out.
Speaker 1: Is there a novel ization?
Speaker 0: Probably not.
Speaker 1: Is there a manga?
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I really don't know.
Speaker 0: Remember my only experience with nb MD guys is that I saw the first like 20 minutes of it and then I heard that review Which was the funniest thing I've ever heard on a podcast other than monkey Tuesday.
Speaker 1: All right, I think this episode's over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though Honestly, I'm really in no in addition to the morale the moral, you know, don't move.
Speaker 0: I'm really in no Pressing need to move because the only places I could move from here are closer to New York City which means I'd spend a lot more money.
Speaker 0: and Even though I'd be spending more money I'd get smaller and smaller Houses and the closer I get to where any place is that I'll work the smaller my house will be and the more money I'll pay for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my thoughts on moving are if I get a lot more money I would like to purchase some larger house Perhaps one with three bedrooms or yeah Like maybe three bedrooms and then like a library or something like that.
Speaker 0: what I've a separate dining room And what I'd really like to have is a house like a three or four bedroom house basement But in addition to that, I'd like it to have an apartment attached So a friend could live or like the guest apartment or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah or a basement of finished miss.
Speaker 0: Yeah for awesome gaming and geeking but in terms of like the area I don't see myself leaving the area I'm living anytime soon just because it's so close to so many places I could commute to if I ever change jobs again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it all depends on my job situation.
Speaker 0: You're probably gonna get a job.
Speaker 1: You're gonna get a job in the city probably over the next six months and depending on that is what I will do.
Speaker 0: Yeah We're pretty much at the best Cost-benefit ratio analysis place we can be for working in the city because we can't really afford to move closer and especially since it costs to Move it's really hard to.
Speaker 1: you know, wherever we are is is oh, you know, it's hard to beat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus the fact that our house is really even if we find a place that's a little bit better It's not worth the effort of going to there but a place.
Speaker 1: if we weren't anywhere yet if we were still nowhere we could have chosen a better place maybe
Speaker 0: but a place that is that much better would be so much more and Honestly all the places that are incrementally closer to New York City that we could afford it takes longer to commute there from there than From here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because there are express trains that go from Poughkeepsie and Beacon right to the city.
Speaker 0: But if you move to the next few towns down there aren't.
Speaker 1: we'd have to move to Croton.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's real expensive to live in Croton.
Speaker 1: Is it really?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Are you ever seen the Croton Harmon train station?
Speaker 1: It's pretty fancy.
Speaker 0: That is a massive train station.
Speaker 0: It is well, that's because they also have the rail yards there Yeah, but in addition that is a massive commuter place.
Speaker 0: I mean that whole area is just nothing but commuters who make big bucks in the city and I think we're served better by living further away having a longer commute But in addition having a lot more disposable income.
Speaker 0: Nice smelling air as opposed to you know, the Bronx or Brooklyn, which I love the work proven where there's a train yard Yeah, and the fact that it's quiet.
Speaker 0: I mean I love the fact that I get the New York City and I can go there anytime I want But yet I can also get away from the city whenever I want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just you know.
Speaker 1: a physical house that was perhaps larger or perhaps where we had the basement is all I really asked for.
Speaker 1: All we really need is like one extra room and a basement.
Speaker 0: Honestly, what all I need.
Speaker 0: what I really like to do is just get land somewhere in Beacon or near about like somewhere in this area and Build a house.
Speaker 0: to my own specification that would always be good like that would be the most perfect fantastic thing But can't afford not yet.
Speaker 0: Honestly, I think I've got the credit to get a mortgage at this point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's really hard to get a mortgage for a land and building a house.
Speaker 0: Really not.
Speaker 1: it's easier to get a mortgage for knowing an existing house.
Speaker 0: It actually really isn't so bad.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of people who've done it.
Speaker 0: In fact, my grandpa built the house.
Speaker 0: He lived in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well if you build the house, that's different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we could pull it off.
Speaker 0: It's just a matter of.
Speaker 0: I think we have better things to spend money on right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, almost definitely like all these cons we keep going to.
Speaker 1: yes.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's it.
Speaker 0: It's Thursday.
Speaker 0: We're done for the week next week.
Speaker 0: We may or may not do a theme week.
Speaker 1: We're not sure yet if you have any ideas for a theme week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let us know for him.
Speaker 0: front row crew calm and of course Otakon is going to be our big podcast extravaganza.
Speaker 0: I suggest that anyone who's in the area or anyone who's planning to go to Otakon Be aware of that awesome thing.
Speaker 0: We're going to be doing and the parties that will be following.
Speaker 1: Yep, and Think that covers it.
Speaker 0: Yeah The only other thing is we got to figure out we there may or may not be Episodes of geek nights the week after Otakon.
Speaker 0: We're not sure what we're going to do yet.
Speaker 0: Just a heads up to everyone that there's a tiny chance.
Speaker 0: The worst case scenario is there will be no geek nights for one whole week.
Speaker 1: then I got.
Speaker 0: then there will be an infinite Sea of geek nights for the next month.
Speaker 1: Yeah Probably the best geek nights you ever heard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I I mean we're.
Speaker 0: I just can't imagine how much recorded footage We're gonna get from that con.
Speaker 1: Oh god.
Speaker 0: All right, we're out.
Speaker 0: We'll see you next week.
Speaker 0: Keep sending the feedback don't send us money and Don't suck.
Speaker 0: and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.