Speaker 1: It's Thursday January 5th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight we talk about TV from our childhood.
Speaker 1: Let's do this alright, so My company owns this other office.
Speaker 1: Well, they own a lot of offices all over the country, but they own this one office that's like on the border of Connecticut in New York in a weird place and they've been trying to make me go there or like asking me to go there recently and the other day I accidentally slept too much and my alarm didn't go off or I fucked up or who knows.
Speaker 1: and They you know sent me an email after I told them I wasn't gonna show up because it's not worth it to go with the Train and such to the city at such a late hour.
Speaker 1: and they're like, why don't you go to Vista?
Speaker 1: and I'm like Because I have a crap car and I'm not gonna drive like an hour and a crap car, you know, it's not worth it.
Speaker 1: So today the boss's boss calls me to his office and I'm like, oh, maybe I'll get fired because my job is pretty boring right right now because I don't have a project to do and I haven't been doing much there.
Speaker 1: some kind, you know, I'm kind of ambivalent to whether I keep the job or not?
Speaker 1: so They he tells me to my surprise They want me to work in the Vista office because they need someone there.
Speaker 1: There's no one there.
Speaker 0: So why do they need someone there?
Speaker 1: I don't know they don't.
Speaker 1: I gonna ask I'm gonna I'm gonna go in and be all-in Next time because that's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: But to get me to work there, they're good.
Speaker 1: Just gonna give me a car.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: He was like, yeah, we'll just lease you a car or give you a raise so you can buy one.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad deal.
Speaker 0: Then maybe you have to see how far a drive this actually is.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go there tomorrow and then on Monday I'm gonna sort it all out at work after thinking about it over the weekend.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, but if it really is like an hour drive, it might just be too painful.
Speaker 1: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I had a 45-minute drive down the mountain when I used to live up there to work and it really wasn't that bad.
Speaker 0: But I don't know if that extra 15 minutes each way would have added up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Plus I had a nice happy drive through the mountains.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have a crappy drive through non-throughway parts of New York State Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: The real question is whether maybe if I get like an iPod in car type of thing I could be maybe okay You know, did you have an I trip that you lost?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was only an I trip mini now so that I got a nano.
Speaker 1: it doesn't even matter if I lost it.
Speaker 1: nah I'm waiting for my trip nano that I pre-ordered to show up.
Speaker 0: Is it even shipping yet?
Speaker 1: No, I pre-ordered it and I'm still waiting and they said December.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: It's January.
Speaker 0: Well raise a stink.
Speaker 1: I might raise a stink or I might just say fuck it and get one of those like car integration kits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're not that expensive and they're actually a lot better than the I trip.
Speaker 0: Yep It's great and all but it uses the FM mini broadcast type thing and that's real antenna weather Moon phases sunspot dependent in terms of quality.
Speaker 1: Well, if I accept this offer and get the car They'll probably look into the integration kit and not if not, I'll probably just wait for the trip to show up.
Speaker 1: Yep All right.
Speaker 0: Yep, but in real news remember that horrible horrible windows exploit.
Speaker 0: We've been talking about the WMF thing.
Speaker 1: We had to talk about it again.
Speaker 0: Well windows released an emergency patch today And I just want to kind of warn all of you out there who might not keep abreast of this to go download it Immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's probably not gonna be a Windows update.
Speaker 1: It's probably gonna be a hotfix that you can get you know, so the hotfix is the quickest safest way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just there's a link on slash dot.
Speaker 0: I can't follow it because I run Firefox and Linux and it it notices that and doesn't let me see but you need this Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean We talked it up and I'm not gonna talk about it more other than that.
Speaker 0: This is a terrible problem that will screw you if you don't get it fixed Hmm.
Speaker 1: Well, when did we first notice this problem?
Speaker 1: About a week ago if that so they fixed it in a week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they fixed it much later than that other guy who just put out a patch that fixed it did.
Speaker 1: How fast does it usually take like I don't know Gen 2 Linux to fix a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah about a day at most fair.
Speaker 1: How about Firefox?
Speaker 1: When does how long does it take Firefox to fix problems?
Speaker 0: Ah, the only problem I was actually aware of But I mean most problems I became aware of them after they were already patched.
Speaker 0: I remember one and it came out and I was like crap.
Speaker 0: Now the Internet's dangerous.
Speaker 0: and then a patch came out like two days later.
Speaker 1: Hmm Microsoft is lose.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, though I did find out one interesting thing about this exploit and this is the last thing I really have to say about it.
Speaker 0: Do you realize that it's not a bug?
Speaker 1: Well, it's not a bug it's a.
Speaker 0: it's a flaw or no, it wasn't really even a flaw It's not.
Speaker 0: it wasn't like a buffer overflow or anything you'd expect.
Speaker 0: it was a feature that was built into the WF parsing stuff a long long long long time ago and Just no one remembered.
Speaker 0: It was there.
Speaker 1: So what?
Speaker 1: What was someone supposed to use this for this feature as best I can tell.
Speaker 0: I just kind of cursorily glanced over it.
Speaker 0: It was a function you could call within WMF To escape and then run a process.
Speaker 1: So it's an image file format But it's a meta file.
Speaker 0: I mean it.
Speaker 0: I think that it looks like you can store other data in.
Speaker 1: it Seems to be a very broad file format Mm-hmm, you know, I've never actually seen anyone use them heavily.
Speaker 0: So no, I mean I saw Heavily Visual Basic uses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was about to say when I used to write Visual Basic crap.
Speaker 0: back at RIT I used a lot of WMF files Hmm and a lot of really poorly written applications that I get from third-party developers at work have WMF files like embedded in them.
Speaker 0: But other than that, they're.
Speaker 0: they're only in the wild if someone's trying to get you with this exploit, basically Yeah, if you make your website with WMF files, you've got issues.
Speaker 1: Yeah use use pings Pings and JPEGs and gifs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we won't say Jeff even though it's technically correct technically correct Which there was a guide about.
Speaker 1: they got popular recently about the pronunciation anyway.
Speaker 1: So the consumer electronic show was currently happening in Las Vegas.
Speaker 1: Ah means lots and lots of Electronic goodies for us to look at anything interesting.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: Most of it was just new cell phone new camcorder new cell phone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever great Oh that kind of stuff, but there were two things that caught my eye because they were new and interesting.
Speaker 1: The first one was this Phillips LCD screen.
Speaker 1: that's flat.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: It's an LCD screen and it goes on a table and faces up.
Speaker 0: Isn't it also touchable?
Speaker 1: It's a touchscreen also and it can also detect other things Like little cubes that rest on it and their positions.
Speaker 0: Now I assume that Phillips has some stupid ideas about what they like to use it for but I have three words Dungeons and dragons.
Speaker 1: That's a good one.
Speaker 0: I have one more word battle tech.
Speaker 1: So that's another one.
Speaker 1: Actually the demonstration that I see here it looks like a normal You know roll the dice move around the board kind of game but It has a theme of like taxi cabs driving around a city and they have these nice Translucent cubes moving around that you can move around the board.
Speaker 1: you can touch the board to like select where you want to go or what you want to do and That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I mean you wouldn't have to bother like publishing and buying $40 board games anymore.
Speaker 1: We could just buy one of these things, you know when it becomes cheap enough because it sure not cheap enough right now.
Speaker 1: Nope, it's gonna be thousands of dollars right now.
Speaker 1: But in the future, you know These things are probably pretty cheap and then we'll be able to just download and program board games for it whether they want us To or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because pretty much one of the main things that slows down our board gaming
Speaker 1: cleaning up resetting it Yep,
Speaker 0: or even getting it out because Puerto Rico we used to play that like years ago and over the summers We had nothing to do 10 20 times a day
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm
Speaker 0: and Pretty much.
Speaker 0: we spent about as much time Resetting and cleaning up the game as we did playing.
Speaker 1: not only that but think about this rules enforcement.
Speaker 1: You won't mess up rules because the game will know.
Speaker 0: yeah No matter how tired you get you can't accidentally buy like seven heroes at the end of San Juan Yep, and you won't be any question like people looking at other people's stuff or anything kind of.
Speaker 1: it'll be perfect.
Speaker 1: Absolutely solve every board game problem that ever existed like the occasional game of Tigers and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: We'd have word.
Speaker 0: like three quarters of the way through the game someone looks and there's like a red tile on a river.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're like who the hell put that there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that won't happen.
Speaker 1: So I'm looking forward to this maybe a few years down the road possible.
Speaker 0: I have to be real big though.
Speaker 0: living room installment for sure Like I'd like a coffee table size one.
Speaker 1: This one looks pretty big.
Speaker 1: you could probably play Like monopoly on it and if you can play monopoly on it, you can play most German games on it.
Speaker 1: Yep, I don't know about battle tech unless you have some sort of zooming in and zooming out But they could make it bigger.
Speaker 1: I mean LCDs are getting bigger every day.
Speaker 1: The other thing is something that at first I glossed over But then came back to and realized why this is the big news of the day.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, Sony come out with this e-reader device.
Speaker 0: All right I'll say right now that I have pretty much zero interest in e-readers.
Speaker 1: I also had zero interest in e-readers and ebooks because they said what the hell I like reading a regular book.
Speaker 0: better I mean, I had a nice PDA a while ago till I sat on it and I used to use it like back at RIT.
Speaker 0: I'd put textbooks on it that I didn't want to pay for.
Speaker 0: that I found online and then I just kind of read them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and It really just hurt my eyes was a pain in the ass and socks.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and I agree with all those things.
Speaker 1: however, this e-reader Is amazing and let me explain why.
Speaker 0: is it magic nano paper where it feels like a real book and I can just flip the Forever.
Speaker 1: No, in fact, that's.
Speaker 1: it's one flaw is that it's actually still like an electronic device with buttons and everything But it's not too thick.
Speaker 1: It's actually a good thickness you know thinner than most laptops and it's about the right size you would want.
Speaker 1: where the screen is about the size of manga and the device itself is only a slightly wider than that maybe like a half inch on either side and like an inch and a Half on the bottom where the buttons are.
Speaker 1: The awesomeness of it is that it's still black and white which is kind of a but for reading books.
Speaker 1: Who cares is that?
Speaker 1: everyone who's seen it and every picture I see of it the completely normal black and white screen is as paper No eye hurting.
Speaker 1: No no LCD.
Speaker 1: No CRT.
Speaker 1: No nothing It's.
Speaker 1: it's this amazing new screen technology and it looks like paper and it hurt doesn't hurt your eyes.
Speaker 1: It's like as you're reading paper, is it luminescent at all?
Speaker 1: The problem with it is that there's no backlight so you can't read in the dark without a light.
Speaker 1: Aha, but other than that it Terms of your eyes and the pain.
Speaker 1: it's as paper.
Speaker 1: now that alone is not enough to make it amazing.
Speaker 1: The amazing part is that even though it's an evil Sony device It's going to be wide Freaking open.
Speaker 1: you're not going to be able to only read special Drmd ebooks on here.
Speaker 1: you're gonna be able to load PDFs on here.
Speaker 1: If you try to load a document file on there, it'll convert it to a PDF The software will support like if you put an RSS feed it'll automatically download like the articles from the RSS feed and Turn them into PDFs and put them on here so you could just plug it in.
Speaker 1: wake up in the morning Take it get on the train and go and the newspaper will be on there.
Speaker 1: Well, you're you know, you're constructed.
Speaker 1: internet newspaper will be on there Just to read as if it was paper in black and white, of course, but whatever.
Speaker 1: now you're ready for the killer.
Speaker 1: Is the killer?
Speaker 1: They were demonstrating something to read on here and you know what the demo image was.
Speaker 0: Call it Cthulhu.
Speaker 1: No the Trigon manga Really?
Speaker 1: Tokyo pop.
Speaker 0: All right, I see now the potential and the potential is cancellations.
Speaker 1: That's a good potential but Tokyo pop.
Speaker 1: I don't know the.
Speaker 1: I know the Trigon manga from Dark Horse But Tokyo pop is already publicly announced.
Speaker 1: They have fully signed on to this device.
Speaker 1: you will be able to soon get digital Tokyo pop manga and read them on this thing and I think that's awesome because the number one problem I have with manga is Storing it all and if I can store it on a hard drive and read it on one handy-dandy device That's worth at least a hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it just comes down to how much it costs.
Speaker 1: then right now The guesstimates are between three and four hundred but I say I'll wait for the second generation of the device and it'll be probably one 200.
Speaker 0: yeah, I pay about 150 for that.
Speaker 1: now that I think about it And I think that's what it's going to be when the second generation of the device comes out.
Speaker 1: So evil Sony Is one good thing they've got going as some potential.
Speaker 0: I can't believe that's Sony.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't like one of the few tiny non evil branches of Sony.
Speaker 1: That's the problem with such a big corporation is that you know different parts of it are good and different parts are bad.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, but if you don't believe me just look at some of the pictures of this thing.
Speaker 1: You can tell from the photographs that the screen is like awesome like paper.
Speaker 1: It's great and the controls look like you can actually you know Go forward and backward through the book sensibly which is important.
Speaker 0: So as all of you know, I read Fark and A little while ago since was the new year.
Speaker 0: They had a contest for the best Photoshop of 2005 and I got to say many of them are very hilarious and I have linked to the collection of the winners.
Speaker 1: it's a good thing this is a collection because Usually when you look at the Fark photoshops They don't.
Speaker 1: they're not filtered very well and it's like 90% crap and there's very few good ones.
Speaker 1: So when it's a good thing that they did this because now you can tell the good ones in one place Yep, it's not like something awful.
Speaker 1: where they have like the perfect moderation Yeah and only the really good ones get shown except for the ones that are in the Hall of Shame which Get sure usually also hilarious for other reasons because they're in the Hall of Shame.
Speaker 1: yep, it's a also worth 1000 I think has a big list of theirs.
Speaker 1: usually they go for the Skill in photoshopping and not so much the funniness.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they also have the funniness.
Speaker 0: I found it funny that the number one like by a significant margin Was one making fun of the intelligent design people great and a flying spaghetti monster was there And a whole bunch making fun of good old George W.
Speaker 1: It's just so easy to make those jokes, yeah alright, so We all like art exhibits and art museums and things right?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: No, maybe anyway This one I'm sure everyone will like because it consists of art Based on old-school video gaming.
Speaker 1: the name of it is called.
Speaker 1: I am 8-bit and it's gonna be on display I think in San Francisco or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know But if you go to their website There's a cool gallery showing some of the arts that will be at the show and some of them are quite awesome.
Speaker 1: My favorite is this one where Dig Dug is like standing there inflating the giant lizard with a little pump.
Speaker 0: I gotta say I wasn't too impressed with the Promo art for this because I saw it, but it looks like it might be cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if the show was nearby I would totally go like in a second
Speaker 0: though There was that one time when I went to a gallery with Emily in New York City Just a random gallery and we're looking at art and in the bottom left corner of one of them Was and this is kind of random because it's not what I expected to see at all The mascot to my the anime club I ran at RIT was Mezinger Z
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: and in the bottom right hand corner of this random piece of art was a very obvious picture of Mezinger Z And it was raping some other robot from behind.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what Mezinger Z does you see?
Speaker 0: aha.
Speaker 0: So I've never actually seen Mezinger Z.
Speaker 1: Ah, I haven't seen much Mezinger Z. It's not something you really Want to watch all of.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's one of those shows.
Speaker 1: it's a very old-school robot show and really there are very few old-school robot shows that you should watch all of and You could watch a few Mezinger Z episodes just to be all cool and old-school, but I totally don't recommend watching the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Though speaking of old-school we decided since we had nothing better to talk about today.
Speaker 0: We were going to reminisce about All those old TV shows we used to watch when we were little because we don't watch TV anymore Yeah, and we realized there's a lot of these shows.
Speaker 0: So we pretty much just picked the ones that are all from a common-ish era And we picked the ones from our early childhood.
Speaker 1: We left the middle school and late elementary like the late elementary school was the cutoff pretty much.
Speaker 0: So we're not talking about Ren and Stimpy or Simpsons or anything just yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we'll talk about those some other day.
Speaker 1: Oh, thanks.
Speaker 1: Since those are more recent and we have more memory of them.
Speaker 1: They could probably take up whole shows on their own Though we figured we'd start.
Speaker 0: we just kind of picked an order here.
Speaker 0: good old Sesame Street.
Speaker 1: Ah Sesame Street taught me everything.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I remember nursery school.
Speaker 0: I learned how to count to ten in Spanish and French.
Speaker 1: Mmm, me too.
Speaker 1: I also learned how to eat cookies.
Speaker 0: I gotta say there need to be more shows like that.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess I was lucky that my parents were smart and They made me watch Sesame Street, and I guess I was lucky that I was smart enough to enjoy it thoroughly.
Speaker 1: I agree with both those things.
Speaker 1: It's also kind of funny how even today like Some of the things from Sesame Street if I see them now It's not like it doesn't feel like a dumb like I see dumb kids shows on TV or if I watch Sesame Street today Or it all started like when that Barney came out, right?
Speaker 1: Then kids shows started getting dumb and painful to watch Teletubbies.
Speaker 1: Yeah stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But I can still watch the Sesame Street that I watched when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: if I watch it now It's not painful.
Speaker 1: And in fact, it's awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if that's because of nostalgia.
Speaker 1: It could be because of nostalgia for it and you know, like memories that it invokes.
Speaker 1: But I'm pretty sure it isn't because I'm nostalgic for some other TV shows from my childhood and watching them now is just painful.
Speaker 1: So the fact that Sesame Street isn't painful really says something.
Speaker 0: I just really wish it was more popular.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it used to be huge popular.
Speaker 1: Like it was the only show for little kids.
Speaker 1: now There's just so much competition that you know The people who do the heavy marketing instead of the nonprofit people trying to be intelligent, you know.
Speaker 0: Yes, I noticed that I mean the two other shows that were educational that we watched.
Speaker 0: we were kids.
Speaker 0: square one and three to one Contact.
Speaker 0: Yes square one.
Speaker 0: I don't think either.
Speaker 0: one is still around.
Speaker 1: square one didn't last very long at all But it was.
Speaker 1: it was so amazing.
Speaker 1: I can't believe.
Speaker 0: you know, in fact, I remember when I was a little kid I'd get into arguments my friends at school because none of them had heard of or watched square one and they all watch three to one contact.
Speaker 1: Yeah, didn't watch three to one contact.
Speaker 1: that much like.
Speaker 1: I remember it coming on and I remember about it But I never don't really remember anything from it.
Speaker 1: square one.
Speaker 1: I remember vividly certain parts.
Speaker 1: Yep Especially that episode where they talked about negative numbers because I didn't know anything about negative numbers less than zero less or hero Yeah, that one.
Speaker 0: I remember the song and everything because I remember he goes to throw the javelin and it goes backwards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're like, oh The thing was that I knew about.
Speaker 1: I knew that there was a such thing as negative numbers But I didn't quite get it until I watched that episode and I was just like enlightenment.
Speaker 0: I remember in particular the one about fractions where the guy had a key ring with eight keys and he was two of them and then he had Six out of eight keys left and I was like, oh that's what fractions are
Speaker 1: the one about Percentages where they go into like the store and he's like, yeah you take off some number percent get it.
Speaker 1: Oh I know what the percent sign means now.
Speaker 0: I mean that show really didn't pander to kids at all.
Speaker 0: It was just like alright, here's here's learning.
Speaker 0: Here's our alert.
Speaker 1: here We're gonna teach you all the math that you will learn throughout elementary school.
Speaker 0: in one TV show man I know we're watching watch his name running away from the tornado guy.
Speaker 1: Oh my god That was the absolute best part of the show and it was also the absolute worst part of the show.
Speaker 0: cuz he'd be go he's like He's going strong.
Speaker 0: He's going strong and then he'd be like, oh don't eat.
Speaker 1: It was so great because you love video games and you love pac-man.
Speaker 1: so watching that was the same kind of feeling you get now when you see cool internet videos and things and It was just my most.
Speaker 1: I waited it.
Speaker 1: I waited for that part of the show more than any other part But the guy was so dumb and he always got eaten by the tornado and I was always pissed off.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure there were a couple times where he got away.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I don't remember it that well but if anyone can get videos of maybe him succeeding at the puzzle or the tornado getting screwed, but Actually, I thought the tornado was cute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my other favorite part was actually the the math squad at the end.
Speaker 1: Well, it was uh, what was it called?
Speaker 0: Math net math net cuz I remembered you guys realized that there was a movie to that.
Speaker 1: Was there really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have to get it.
Speaker 0: I had it on tape.
Speaker 0: So when I fly out to Arizona to see my mom, I'll see if she still has it We have to get that is on Netflix.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I'll look.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna check eBay as soon as we're done here.
Speaker 0: because that movie it was actually kind of cool because I remember watching it and it was about a lottery scan and All I remember thinking I was a kid was wow I should pull that scan because there's no one that smart in the real world to stop me.
Speaker 1: Yep The thing about math net was like at first.
Speaker 1: when I would watch Square one math net would come on.
Speaker 1: it was always be the last thing in the show and it would be like five minutes long And it would start and I remember the opener seemed real boring.
Speaker 1: It's like at first.
Speaker 1: I just didn't watch it.
Speaker 1: I would just turn off the show right there because I only wanted to see the funny cartoon bits and you know the math pac-man guy.
Speaker 1: but then I finally watched it one day and I was like Yeah, this is the good The thing is as a little kid.
Speaker 0: I took it at face value.
Speaker 0: Like I didn't realize it was supposed to be a joke I just took it like wow, they're awesome mathematicians and they solve crimes.
Speaker 1: see the way I took it was that the first part of the show was to teach you new maths that you didn't already know and That the math net was the part where they showed you how the math was actually useful in the real world.
Speaker 1: somehow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, and that's that's what it was about.
Speaker 0: So though the region one contact had a similar thing.
Speaker 0: They had the bloodhound gang that always came on like right at the end or right after.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, which I watch.
Speaker 0: I didn't like it that much mostly because I thought the kids were dumb and they could have gotten out of the situations in easier Ways.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I always hated things like that were whenever you The problem with educational shows that if you've already learned the education, but you want to be educated instead of just you know Nostalgic or something that if they're doing something that you know is dumb or they're not figuring it out as fast as you did It's just painful to watch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like they'd be going.
Speaker 0: I mean it was kind of a gritty show for little kids learning about things because they go after like drug dealers Kidnappers they get kidnapped they get beat up.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I just remember I'd always think why don't they just call the cops?
Speaker 0: They know where the drug dealers are.
Speaker 0: They're still there and they have drugs weren't they the cops?
Speaker 1: they were real detectives, right?
Speaker 1: They were just math detectives.
Speaker 0: What no, no, no in through, you know, the bloodhound gang.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah They were like little punk inner-city kids.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they should have called the kids like sticks for weapons.
Speaker 1: if that Yeah, that was whatever.
Speaker 1: not much you can do about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was still a good show.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's it for the educational.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, we'll talk about mr.
Speaker 1: Rogers a little bit actually.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, mr Rogers, I never really liked it that much but I used to watch it mostly because my little brother wanted to watch it.
Speaker 1: See, uh Parts of mr.
Speaker 1: Rogers were kind of painful and parts of it were kind of great like When he was just hanging out in his living room.
Speaker 1: It was usually kind of boring because he was just talking about something dumb.
Speaker 1: But like whenever he went into the backyard where the sandbox was that meant he was going to do something kind of like a science Experiment and that was always cool.
Speaker 0: Yep, cuz I always loved science.
Speaker 0: He shows like mr.
Speaker 0: Wizard.
Speaker 1: No, mr.
Speaker 1: Wizard Yeah But the part where he said the little trolley into the land of make-believe.
Speaker 1: Like half the time it was cool and half the time it sucked.
Speaker 1: because depending on what puppets he pulled out Like I remember there was like an owl puppet that was way cool and like the king was way cool But like there was like a bird or some kind of animals and they weren't cool.
Speaker 1: They were just stupid.
Speaker 0: So like depending on what the story was dependent how much I enjoyed that part of the show I remember I was fascinated with the fact that he had a traffic light and I wanted a traffic light.
Speaker 0: Hmm yeah, yeah, that's my main memory of that show is wanting that traffic light All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember my parents eventually got me a toy traffic light.
Speaker 1: It was freaking awesome, dude I had a toy Fisher Price Main Street.
Speaker 1: That was the best freakin toy.
Speaker 1: Let me know you could drive a little mailman around town and put the mail in the mail slots.
Speaker 0: Oh, dude I didn't have that but my cousins did.
Speaker 1: I could put the mail in the mail slots all day long.
Speaker 1: The firemen got a lot of mail because they had the easiest mail slot.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you that was a good toy.
Speaker 1: All right now that will do the non-educational shows the dreck It's not real.
Speaker 1: some of its drag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of its drug transformers was only kind of drag.
Speaker 1: The thing about transformers is that has a lot of plot holes.
Speaker 1: It has a lot of animation glitches a lot of corniness But it's and it was made only to sell toys and not to be a good show.
Speaker 0: Yes, and like for all of you don't know specifically it was designed to sell toys.
Speaker 0: Yeah from the start.
Speaker 1: It wasn't even a joke But you know what.
Speaker 1: I can still watch it this day and still get enjoyment out of it.
Speaker 0: I can't a little.
Speaker 0: I mean, I remember always rooting for Starscream.
Speaker 1: Yes, Starscream.
Speaker 1: It was so awesome But he always made a dumb mistake that pissed you off.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Rodimus Prime never liked him so much.
Speaker 0: No Bumblebee can go to hell.
Speaker 1: see ya Bumblebee can go to hell.
Speaker 1: I like everyone likes Optimus Prime.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, Megatron like he was cool, but he was just too Stupid.
Speaker 1: evil like he wasn't stupid But his evil was stupid like he was just blatantly so evil that he would mess up Yep, but he was also so powerful that he never lost really though.
Speaker 0: I actually didn't watch so much Transformers.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch so much of it only I think because of the time slot and the channel it was on But I knew I always liked it and I always wanted to watch.
Speaker 0: well plus I had an odd different similar show.
Speaker 0: That was my favorite though.
Speaker 0: We'll get into it in a second.
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah transformers is still good.
Speaker 1: the toys were actually better than the show.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean those toys are actually still kind of fun today.
Speaker 1: if you get some of them You know you transform them and they shoot and whatever the one show that we all remembered as being awesome and We watched it again.
Speaker 0: He-man is probably the worst thing ever created by humankind.
Speaker 1: watching he-man is like stabbing yourself in the eye Especially when you say to yourself I used to watch that and love it.
Speaker 0: not only watch it and love it But wanted to see the live-action movie.
Speaker 1: There's a live-action.
Speaker 0: Yes, there is he-man.
Speaker 0: the movie he-man and man-at-arms and what's-her-name come to earth and In the end the end.
Speaker 0: all I remember is that the final guy like that they're fighting is Galator.
Speaker 0: Not it wasn't.
Speaker 0: it was kind of it's complicated.
Speaker 0: I have very little recollection of this movie.
Speaker 0: All I remember is that he was defeated with a Casio keyboard.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I'm not kidding right, so I had more he-man action figures than any other type of action figure.
Speaker 1: But I don't actually remember so much of like watching he-man.
Speaker 1: I just remember like the castle grayskull and fighting Skeletor and I remember module lock.
Speaker 1: module lock was perhaps one of the best toys I ever had.
Speaker 1: you know module lock which one's that He was in.
Speaker 1: like a couple episodes as like this character They created just to sell a toy and it was like this two-headed red guy and the toy came with like two different torsos two heads four arms and like eight legs Some abdomen pieces and some tail pieces and you could create like either one giant module lock creature Or you could create like two separate module lock creatures and you could arrange them in all sorts of different ways To make different things for he-man to fight and it was really cool because in the show they did the same thing.
Speaker 0: huh Yeah, but the show if you watch it now is just painful and you know what for anyone out there Shira wasn't any better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was pretty much the same crap.
Speaker 1: Yep only with a girl.
Speaker 0: I mean god We're not kidding.
Speaker 0: Don't ever watch he-man again.
Speaker 0: That way you can at least maintain those memories and not think that you were just a complete dumb shit when you were a kid I mean like the cat man.
Speaker 1: Oh god the cat.
Speaker 0: He's more annoying than c-3po, but he never gets his comeuppance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's the other guy Orca?
Speaker 1: Orca, yeah Yeah, okay, whoever was riding he-man Don't let me meet you in a back alley For you know take putting stupidity into my brain when I could have been watching something better.
Speaker 0: there's one show that I watched religiously and A lot of my friends a lot of people didn't watch.
Speaker 0: it was kind of obscure show though It had in my opinion the best toys of this era associated with it mask mask.
Speaker 0: I Watched that show every frickin day.
Speaker 0: I have every single toy in duplicate half of them in mint condition.
Speaker 0: Wow, yeah the show upon watching it again was not as stupid as he-man but was definitely not quite what I remembered.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that happens.
Speaker 1: I mean there were a lot of shows that also were equally obscure that I watched here and there like I don't know bionic six Or that one where there was like a rock Lord's.
Speaker 1: I have a rock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually the rock the rock Lord toys were kind of cool, but the show now not at all.
Speaker 1: centurions Centurions also, I was a centurion for Halloween one.
Speaker 0: So was I?
Speaker 0: I had the blue guys cost.
Speaker 0: I had the yellow guy Because it came with this red rocket that didn't fire.
Speaker 0: I'd it was on the gun and to fire it you took it off and threw it.
Speaker 1: No, mine didn't come with anything.
Speaker 0: I was lame and it came with like a rocket thing.
Speaker 1: I must add the cheaper costume.
Speaker 1: mine was just like a vinyl suit and a plastic mask.
Speaker 0: Mine came with a helmet like a big plastic one.
Speaker 1: Oh, you got it.
Speaker 1: You had the more expensive costume.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was awesome.
Speaker 0: I played with it until it broke.
Speaker 0: Yeah But mask for any of you out here who watched it.
Speaker 0: and if any of you out there watched it Let me know because I really want to find other people who love this show.
Speaker 0: Mmm, it was really cool.
Speaker 0: Imagine transformers only better animated slightly with a better plot at least for the first half of the show and Cool, cool cool transforming things that fight with each other.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Do you remember a show where there would be like ropes in a canyon and vehicles would slide back and forth along the ropes?
Speaker 0: I remember seeing commercials for the toys and then not thinking not knowing there was a show associated.
Speaker 1: I think I watched the show like on Saturday morning twice and I had one of the toys and it broke.
Speaker 0: I had a friend who had all the toys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had a friend who had a whole bunch of them like all around his ceiling and you'd slide him back and forth.
Speaker 1: They'd shoot missiles.
Speaker 0: See, I think I had the best setup because I had all the Ninja Turtles toys, but the Ninja Turtles themselves socks.
Speaker 0: But the the places they had like the technodrome were awesome.
Speaker 0: So I use my mass guys who fit in those place.
Speaker 0: that's a lot better.
Speaker 0: and I had like the ultimate setup.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was always upset that I got.
Speaker 1: I got plenty of action figures but I never got like you would always want like 20 of the normal henchmen or foot soldiers and you never got that.
Speaker 1: and I only ever got one place other than you know, fisher-price Main Street To play with my action figures in and I think I still have it at my house.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should go get it But I never got like.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what the place is when we talk about the show by the way Because I had Boulder Mountain from mask.
Speaker 0: I had the the turn Ninja Turtles underground sewer and the technodrome.
Speaker 1: No didn't have any of those.
Speaker 1: My brother had the Ninja Turtles van actually eventually, which folded out into a nice playset Micro-machines I had like every friggin micro-machines.
Speaker 1: Oh, we had a shit ton of micro-machines.
Speaker 1: The problem is when they switched the standard for micro-machine playsets from you know, those squares and they would fold in half Yep, they would attach to each other to make cities.
Speaker 1: but then they got rid of that and there was like This big van that folded out to make a giant city.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I remember when the van came out I got it.
Speaker 0: I was like what the hell and I stopped buying micro-machines.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had the van and oh Maybe my brother had the micro-machines van and not the Ninja Turtles man.
Speaker 1: I think that was it.
Speaker 1: Yeah And it folded out into this great city and then I had my little squares that lock together down low.
Speaker 0: Of course micro-machines were far inferior to the older Hot Wheels.
Speaker 1: I had plenty of Hot Wheels and matchbox car.
Speaker 0: I had all four sets like the big like with the ramp, you know, they're all kind of identical.
Speaker 1: Oh I only ever had just one loop-de-loop and I got rid of it pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: But I had lots of fun just playing with the cars on their own and on the floor.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I was a fan of the Hot Wheels or matchbox.
Speaker 1: I guess I couldn't know difference.
Speaker 0: Yeah I really had no idea.
Speaker 0: I had cars that were all kind of that size.
Speaker 1: Yep, and of course they had big Tonka trucks.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but enough about toys.
Speaker 0: I will do a show on toys.
Speaker 1: one of the shows I watched when I was a kid that I can still watch today and still enjoy greatly is Voltron.
Speaker 0: see I didn't like it so much, but it's definitely not that bad.
Speaker 1: Voltron is great It's.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's a you know, it's a standard Sentai show.
Speaker 1: You know a bunch of guys group up to form Voltron or talk about lion Voltron, by the way If you like car Voltron, you can shove it where the Sun don't shine You know.
Speaker 1: and it had all this this great space epic plot that never got you know, like developed enough You know, like they could really go somewhere with it.
Speaker 1: And in fact, there's a semi-recent comic book that does go somewhere with it but It was just way cool.
Speaker 1: There was like a castle and they had to defend the villagers and the one thing that made it really adult was there was a guy Sven and he started out on the team.
Speaker 1: He was Sven the guy who talked like he was, you know named as fan but then like After a few episodes through the show like either he was a traitor or he died or something like that.
Speaker 1: and it was really sort of The intelligent kind of plot thing that the other shows didn't have.
Speaker 1: And that's how the princess took his seat in Voltron.
Speaker 0: That explains that.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz I was remember looking around and always One more guy In a suit than there were places to sit in a suit.
Speaker 0: I was wondering what was up with that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the best thing about Voltron was when they got in Voltron they would go down these tubes and they would go.
Speaker 1: it was way cool and The music was cool, too.
Speaker 0: And of course the last show which we upon watching it again with adult eyes Realized was much more sexually charged than we had thought.
Speaker 1: it's not sexually charged It's a story about adolescence and puberty, which I guess makes it indirectly sexually.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, just freaking the sword growing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, you don't know what show we're talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, already.
Speaker 0: I remember cuz I never actually seen the first episode of Thundercats until recently.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm like all the rest of it and I knew what was going on But watching the first one all I remember thinking was Wow.
Speaker 0: Chitara is naked pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Love the Thundercats probably more than and I remember it more than any other show.
Speaker 1: and that's the place that I had.
Speaker 1: I had the giant Thunder Mountain with the big blue head on it that had lights in it and everything.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow I didn't have that.
Speaker 1: It's I got it in my attic.
Speaker 1: I should go get it.
Speaker 1: I don't know where I'm gonna put it in this house but it's a fun toy for sure.
Speaker 1: and I used to put the Thundercats all in it different places and I Mean the show is kind of episodic and nonsensical But wasn't really.
Speaker 1: see the thing is it wasn't 100% episodic.
Speaker 1: It was like this half episodic half serial type of show like There would be like the first few episodes were all Serial where it was like, oh, this is how the Thundercats got to fun to the new Thunder.
Speaker 1: This is how they set up the castle.
Speaker 1: these this is them discovering the different people on the planet.
Speaker 1: They don't like the burbles which sucked the mutants which are bad guys mum rah the big bad guy, you know.
Speaker 1: But then it just got into a bunch of episodes.
Speaker 1: like mum rah does evil We beat him.
Speaker 1: mum rah does evil we beat him.
Speaker 1: the mutants do evil we beat them.
Speaker 1: the mutants do evil we beat you know, so on and so forth.
Speaker 1: and That eventually they started like that.
Speaker 1: the plot would change like lino would do like a quest thing to you know Become the real Lord of the Thundercats.
Speaker 1: and then people from space would come.
Speaker 1: and then they started a plot where they went to the you know back into space and then they came back and then there were new characters and do Thundercats and Then it became more serial again, but I didn't watch those episodes so much.
Speaker 1: that was after my time.
Speaker 0: No, I put in our Netflix queue all of Thundercats.
Speaker 0: this out on DVD.
Speaker 0: Awesome, so we might actually start doing some reviews of Thundercats specifically.
Speaker 0: That'd be so great in months because there are many shows before Thundercats unlike he-man.
Speaker 1: It won't be so painful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's get all a he-man and watch it again.
Speaker 1: No, how about we just get like one episode of he-man and that'll be enough.
Speaker 0: We'll review that at the same time.
Speaker 0: We review that mahjong show.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: I can't wait to watch that.
Speaker 0: And That was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 1: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds.
Speaker 1: feed burner comm.
Speaker 1: slash geek nights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Speaker 1: also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.