Speaker 0: So, a lot of you seem to really like cheesy 80's style metal, and for some reason seem to really like that tiny, half-assed clip of Zelda music that I put in as Thing of the Day music one day to make fun of myself.
Speaker 0: Thus, I present to you as a gig night special, a few minutes of me playing just kind of unedited.
Speaker 0: I just was recording, playing around with the keyboard, and I decided, you know what?
Speaker 0: I'll just hit record, and whatever I play, I will put up.
Speaker 0: This is incredibly cheesy, and not very good, but you wanted it, so you're gonna get it.
Speaker 0: If this is your first episode of Geek Nights, I will point out, as I always do, that this is not a normal episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: This is not even an episode.
Speaker 0: This is what we call a special.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend that you go to the feed and look at any other episode besides this one.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.