Speaker 0: It's Wednesday March 15th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about our favorite anime.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, I spent yet another morning down in Manhattan and it looks like I'm gonna have a new job sometime in the next month or so.
Speaker 1: Job, that's better than the one you got.
Speaker 0: Oh significantly better in terms of paying at least $10,000 more a year and better benefits and Possibly regular travel to such places as Tokyo and London.
Speaker 1: Regular travel, I think.
Speaker 1: what did you say once a year?
Speaker 0: Yeah once or twice a year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see It's not like zipping around the world awesomeness.
Speaker 0: Hey go to Japan once for free is enough for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's better than zero anyways, of course.
Speaker 0: Honestly, if I go anywhere like that for business I'll totally take the print the next week after my business is done as vacation days and stay there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a good move.
Speaker 0: That's the plan.
Speaker 0: then all I have to pay for is a hotel room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe I'll sleep on the floor at katsu's family's house or something.
Speaker 1: Well I finally got my They the raise I was supposed to get like three month to a month and a half ago.
Speaker 1: Ah But I think they messed up and gave me too much money.
Speaker 1: Hopefully they're not listening, but that's okay As I got moneys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah money.
Speaker 0: So anyway in the news There's this dude and for some reason this decided to make it to the level of news where it was on Slashdot and all over the place.
Speaker 0: But some guy was playing World of Warcraft and he happened to be playing it on Linux in wine And he happened to be using a keyboard that allows you to make keyboard macros.
Speaker 1: And if he can get that to work in wine, all I want is steam.
Speaker 1: damn it Was he using the sedaga thing or is he using real wine?
Speaker 0: You know, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've never tried to make World of Warcraft run in wine.
Speaker 0: I don't know how hard it is.
Speaker 0: Some things just work really easily in wine.
Speaker 1: I really just want steam to work in wine without paying for stupid.
Speaker 0: Internet Explorer runs fine in wine, but not civilization - oh no Internet Explorer works better in wine than in Windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really does.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But anyway this guy now the fact that he was using wine is not terribly relevant.
Speaker 0: All it did was expedite his banning from World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: Basically, he programmed his keyboard to do repetitive tasks for him.
Speaker 0: So he hits the I don't know B, I think that fancy logitech gaming keyboard.
Speaker 1: the LCD display Yeah Where you can set up you can.
Speaker 1: it has like extra buttons on it and you can program it.
Speaker 1: to say when I hit this Button do like a then B then F G and then up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just macros.
Speaker 0: So we made macros that would kill mobs for him in the game and he just kind of sit there tapping the button while they watch TV.
Speaker 0: well, he was sitting there doing that and apparently a GM noticed and Private message him saying hey you a bot.
Speaker 0: and because he didn't notice the PM they banned him from World of Warcraft for botting.
Speaker 0: and His argument in his defense is that he wasn't botting he was using a macro keyboard and there's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 1: I don't think there is anything wrong with that.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing by the only reason I bring this up as news because one This guy sounds like a total douche the guy who's complaining because if you read the his complaints He basically says to the effect of I blah blah blah ISP I'm important blah blah blah blah and then he goes on and talks about his problem.
Speaker 0: Like he makes a big deal about himself.
Speaker 1: Well, see the real.
Speaker 1: I don't know why we keep having news about World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: the thing we hate because it's fodder for entertainment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is that get an epic talking about this news.
Speaker 1: That really bothers me is that This guy wrote somewhat intelligent emails compared to what most people write and the company like didn't even It's like companies don't communicate with people.
Speaker 1: It's like I hate it when you send a letter to a company and they don't actually read it and custom You know send you a response now.
Speaker 0: See I anticipated you would say that because I agreed with you at first.
Speaker 0: Until I actually read.
Speaker 0: he kept replying as far as I can tell to the do not reply to this or you will get an automated response email address.
Speaker 0: That's what I saw.
Speaker 1: No, it looked.
Speaker 1: it's like they were.
Speaker 1: they give you if you read the first email it says do not reply to this But you know like directly but they give you an address that you can email to.
Speaker 1: and then it looked like from then on He was talking to that email address that you're supposed to email.
Speaker 0: I'm going based on the comments from slashdot.
Speaker 1: Who knows what you can say about that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway the point is here that more importantly I don't care that the guy was banned and it's probably good for him.
Speaker 0: He'll probably get a life or so.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, definitely great for him that he was banned.
Speaker 1: I don't know why he's so.
Speaker 1: I mean you'd be upset because he spent all these hours to make some numbers go up and now the numbers are deleted in the database, but Good now he's gonna get a life.
Speaker 1: But the thing is he won't play another mo.
Speaker 0: apparently World of Warcraft Can be played by a keyboard without a person there.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so can every MMO.
Speaker 0: now now this is not some MMOs couldn't You.
Speaker 0: but anyway, the problem here to me is that if you're playing a game Against a computer that could be played just as well if not better by a computer as opposed to by you then Why even play?
Speaker 0: all you're doing is spending time to make a number go up.
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean think about if you're sitting there and there's a button and If you push the button a number goes up and all you have to do is push that button a whole bunch of times.
Speaker 1: What what are you doing?
Speaker 1: sitting there pushing that button repeatedly?
Speaker 1: What the hell's the point if anything?
Speaker 0: I say you should be encouraged to write macros to get through that tedious crap because I'll admit way back when I played the realm You know that old ass MMO by Sierra.
Speaker 0: It's still around.
Speaker 0: the fans bought it.
Speaker 0: It's kind of scary that it's still up, but Once I got past level 60 or 65, there was nothing else in the game to kill because the game wasn't done yet.
Speaker 0: And I wanted to be level 100, you know, because I was a middle school high school kid with infinite free time.
Speaker 0: Now instead of killing, you know Whatever's over and over again thousands and thousands of times a day hour after hour to get the one experience point I'd get to try to get myself up to a higher level.
Speaker 0: I Just wrote a little Windows macro that would attack any monster.
Speaker 0: it saw well it would.
Speaker 0: you easily stand on a screen and attack any monster that walked into the middle of the screen and kill it.
Speaker 0: because I Was so powerful nothing could hurt me and that way I didn't have to waste my time and I still got to level 100.
Speaker 0: I Don't see why people have a problem with other people using bots to level in a game.
Speaker 0: I don't need someone else.
Speaker 0: I mean if you have fun gaining levels in the game and exploring all the new content fine.
Speaker 0: If someone else doesn't enjoy that I say that there should be no problem with them using a bot.
Speaker 1: My question is why are any people playing it at all?
Speaker 1: It just uh.
Speaker 0: now I can see how the game would be fun.
Speaker 0: I mean I wouldn't mind playing the game if one I'd have to pay for it and Two if I could just pick whatever level I wanted to be play at that level.
Speaker 0: when I was done with that pick a different Level play at that part of the game and then when I played all the parts of the game just stop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean like I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: World of Warcraft was like a big world to explore some.
Speaker 1: you know Zelda's kind of fun when you're walking around exploring.
Speaker 1: So maybe if the whole game was I can go anywhere the hell I want and do anything I want and just see everything to see.
Speaker 1: then I might do that once.
Speaker 1: it would take me a few hours and I'd walk around Or ride around and see everything there was to see.
Speaker 0: I mean honestly The only thing that bothers me about MMOs at least current MMOs at all Is just the fact that most of the game is just a grind to try to get to a higher level or get a higher Whatever.
Speaker 0: and the only factor in determining how good you are compared to another character The only factor at all is how much time you spent playing the game.
Speaker 0: There's no skill involved.
Speaker 1: And if you say there's skill involved well, uh, you're wrong and I'll argue you till the end of time Yeah, Oh whoever spends the most time playing the game That means they're the best as opposed to whoever's the best is the best.
Speaker 1: I mean what if you know?
Speaker 1: It's like saying if one guy sucks at sword fighting But he practices for a hundred years and another guy happens to be a natural amazing sword fighter And he practices for ten minutes that the ten minute guy should never win Regardless of his natural talent.
Speaker 0: now some MMOs handle that.
Speaker 0: look at puzzle pirates.
Speaker 0: All right You've got puzzles that you do and say sword fighting is a versus Tetris II kind of puzzles.
Speaker 0: Now if you're if you play the game, you know for years and years and years and you get really really good at that.
Speaker 0: That's the equivalent of leveling.
Speaker 0: you've gotten good in the real world at doing that thing.
Speaker 1: Well, there are in sword fighting puzzles a bad example because there's actually swords that kind of change the pattern and make it difficult But not so much.
Speaker 0: All I was saying is that you can get better at it by practicing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you effectively level in the real world Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Now if you just happen to be naturally good or say you start a new character now, you're level one again or whatever You're still just as good in the real world.
Speaker 0: So now your low-level new character is gonna be awesome just because you're awesome in World of Warcraft or anything.
Speaker 0: if you start a new level one character your character sucks ass because there's really.
Speaker 0: The only thing involved are the stats and the stats only get bigger by playing the game longer.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, there is one thing is that if you played the game and you know your way around it It takes you less time to get the levels because you know, right?
Speaker 1: That's the only thing.
Speaker 1: is it's like if you already know this arbitrary knowledge about this imaginary world Then it will take you less time To do these things because you already know what you're doing and the time it takes to figure it out is now already spent.
Speaker 0: It's like when I beat Zelda 2 again.
Speaker 0: I knew where everything was.
Speaker 0: I just went and got it and it saved me about 20 hours worth of gameplay.
Speaker 1: It's like if you went to the store to buy a stick of gum, right and it costs five bucks for your first stick of Gum, but then every other stick of gum ever cost only one dollar because you've already paid the four dollar stick of gum entry fee Of learning how to chew gum and buy it.
Speaker 0: That was quite an example.
Speaker 1: I just had to make something up that was crazy because you got to be crazy to sit there and push a button over and Over again to make a number go anyway.
Speaker 0: I guess the only thing I want to say about this is to all of our listeners out there Even though this is anime day, so I'm gonna come off it in a minute.
Speaker 0: But it's my news so you can all go to hell for anyone who plays World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: Why on earth can I'd like you to give me in the forums any reason why people botting should be against the rules?
Speaker 0: All right, that's all I want.
Speaker 0: I Submit that to you all as a challenge.
Speaker 0: And if someone gives me a good enough argument, I'll concede defeat and you'll win something.
Speaker 1: If he says you're gonna win something that means you're not gonna win Argument.
Speaker 0: Well, I point out that no one won our previous mini contest.
Speaker 1: No one seems to even try any of our thousands of contests for prizes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one told me what the Duchy of Grand Fenwick was.
Speaker 1: yet I guess that means that everyone either doesn't know our trivia's and they can't stand up to our challenges because we're always right or they Don't realize that we actually do have a lot of money.
Speaker 0: and if someone actually came out with the awesome Yeah, hello.
Speaker 1: My company just paid me more money than they're supposed to.
Speaker 1: hello money.
Speaker 1: You can have it.
Speaker 1: It could be yours.
Speaker 0: I don't think we're gonna give him money.
Speaker 0: I think we'll give him swag.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so today's anime manga comics day And since we got all anime for the main part of our show I gotta talk about some manga news and some comics news.
Speaker 1: Well, the manga is my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So we'll stick the comics news here.
Speaker 1: You may or may not know but I bet that you know because I don't know movies and shit That's going on in the world and I know about this now.
Speaker 0: You may not know the guy's name Yeah, but if we tell you the things he's done you'll think oh that guy
Speaker 1: Yeah, so
Speaker 0: and if you don't listen, well,
Speaker 1: so there's this movie coming out V for Vendetta And actually I have cautious optimism, which is more than I've had for any movie since probably Lord of the Rings and it's gonna have the Rogers not Roger Smith agent Smith.
Speaker 1: slash Elrond is going to be V and Natalie Portman is gonna be the girl.
Speaker 0: Now it surprises me to this day and it makes me feel old.
Speaker 0: How many people don't know who Natalie Portman is?
Speaker 1: Remember the damn name.
Speaker 1: All I could remember was Star Wars chick and the professional chick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember from the professional but slash dot.
Speaker 0: for any of you who are younger that I mean Younger than us even because this joke was old before we knew about slash dot.
Speaker 0: Natalie Portman has been this long-standing inside joke on slash dot.
Speaker 0: I don't even understand the inside joke.
Speaker 0: It was before my time, but apparently all the nerds knew who she was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she was in an awesome movie called the professional and then she was princess whatnot in Star Wars episode Princess whatnot.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: What's her name?
Speaker 0: Alright Gauri.
Speaker 1: Okay, so The guy who wrote V for Vendetta.
Speaker 1: His name is Alan Moore.
Speaker 1: He's his British comic writer.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 0: He's a scary-looking dude, but he's brilliant.
Speaker 1: He looks like a Dane like you.
Speaker 1: read his stuff and you think he's just some like awesome British genius guy who writes awesome stuff.
Speaker 1: But really he's actually scary biker with a Rasputin beard.
Speaker 0: He's Rasputin.
Speaker 0: He must have survived and lived to this day in order to make comics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'll see a picture of him in the link.
Speaker 1: He's a scary biker.
Speaker 1: Awesome Crazy guy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, he wrote V for Vendetta.
Speaker 1: He also wrote Watchmen.
Speaker 0: Watchmen is what is I mean?
Speaker 0: I'm holding it in my hands right now.
Speaker 0: It is perhaps one of the greatest works of American comic-dom ever.
Speaker 0: Yep Well Western comic-dom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, this guy's amazing at the writing and He wrote League of Extraordinary Gentlemen, I think and all kinds of crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: now He was kind of the deep story is I'm not gonna go into all the details mostly because I don't know all of them But he did contract with DC Comics.
Speaker 1: He ended up being unhappy with the contract and He got out of it.
Speaker 1: but in the contract he pretty much gave DC the rights to his stuff and You know, he's like, oh they tricked me out of it, you know, but then another second he'd be like, yeah You know, I was I was stupid and I gave it to him but now He doesn't want them to have it.
Speaker 1: basically he wants them to like stop printing his books Even though they keep sending him a check, huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a little bit nutty in this department.
Speaker 1: I don't know what what he's thinking but like He's kind of mad that they're making these shitty movies out of his stuff and he doesn't want them to be able to make the movies.
Speaker 1: But if they're going to make the movies he wants them to take his name off of it.
Speaker 1: They're that he thinks they're using his name to like promote like He's.
Speaker 1: he commented on how they printed new copies of E for Vendetta that say now a motion picture on the top And he's real unhappy about that, especially since his name is in big letters on it You know.
Speaker 1: and how people are using his name like in association with the movie.
Speaker 1: When he's trying to say, you know, I think the quote was I've read this screenplay.
Speaker 1: It's rubbish Yeah, so this guy's real sort of angry at what people are doing with the things that he's written and You know the feeling I get is That he's just being cranky after he signed a contract and then later realized what he had done and too late you signed a contract.
Speaker 1: tough shit You know, that's my feeling just based on interviews with him and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't actually know much about him.
Speaker 0: I just know about his works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, his works are excellent.
Speaker 1: I suggest you indulge in all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you wonder why I was silent while Scott was on his monologue because I was holding watch in my hand I started flipping through it and then I started reading it and then I forgot that I was on the air.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's really good.
Speaker 0: It's one hell of a comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and so is V for Vendetta, which you should read.
Speaker 0: Yes, especially in light of the current socio political situation out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I from what I can tell is number one.
Speaker 1: I saw I watched the second trailer for the movie and It's a trailer anyone can watch.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's one of those spoiler trailers But there's at least one scene in this trailer that I know for sure does not happen in the comic anywhere.
Speaker 1: so either that's just a trailer scene or the movie is actually gonna change.
Speaker 1: what happened in a big way and I've also heard like whisperings around the net that like okay V for Vendetta if you don't know is about Literally anarchy versus fascism in a direct conflict.
Speaker 1: That's what it's about that to put it very very bluntly Yeah, that's without telling you any details of characters or plot or anything.
Speaker 1: But that's that's the general theme of it anarchy versus fascism ha extremes in conflict.
Speaker 1: from what I've heard the movie is like liberal versus fascism Like it's not the same thing.
Speaker 1: That says the whisperings I've heard and I'm not sure and I'll probably go see the movie just to be able to talk about it Or see if my cautious optimism pays off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whoever's making this movie.
Speaker 1: You're pretty much either going to like lose me on movies forever Or maybe you know like light a tiny little fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the stakes are high.
Speaker 0: Maybe Scott go to movies again.
Speaker 1: Maybe who knows it doesn't take much for me to go to movies used to make a movie that doesn't suck.
Speaker 0: Honestly, most of the movies we've gone to lately were anime movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't.
Speaker 1: Since Lord of the Rings when have I been to a non sucky movie?
Speaker 1: That wasn't anime.
Speaker 1: that wasn't in an art theater either like a Hollywood movie, huh?
Speaker 0: Oh, you know what snakes on a plane snakes on a motherfucking plane.
Speaker 0: There's not a goddamn thing you can do about it.
Speaker 0: So it being anime day now earlier today I was poking around looking for videos of old cosplays for various reasons and There are basically a lot of laws and problems with putting the cosplay videos from cons online.
Speaker 1: Like you're not allowed to portray copyrighted characters and all this stuff and it's all legal gray areas and blah.
Speaker 0: now Otakon has had a very strict Long-standing policy on this and they've gone after people who have put up the cosplay videos in the past.
Speaker 0: Well, I discovered looking through Google video that all of those cosplays are in fact available online.
Speaker 0: Awesome, not only those but cosplays from many other conventions.
Speaker 0: I linked to it in my post, but it's basically cosplay memories calm and They're basically flaunting all the warnings and cease-and-desist and whatever they've gotten and they just host a pile of cosplay videos.
Speaker 1: Now look, there's a big picture, Ohio con 2003.
Speaker 0: download the video now if you watch no other cosplay video in your life ever.
Speaker 0: I want you to go to Otakon 2004 Mmm, and watch.
Speaker 0: there are two skits and it lists because it breaks everyone up into four parts and it lists what sketches are in each part.
Speaker 0: Watch the one that involves Muppets and utenna.
Speaker 1: I think it's called like Something something.
Speaker 0: if you search for the word Muppet, you'll find it on the page.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and to shadow with an axe.
Speaker 1: shadow with an axe is the man.
Speaker 0: He is quite literally shadow with an axe.
Speaker 1: This guy's freaking awesome.
Speaker 1: I remember I saw him cuz I was in.
Speaker 1: I've got this new.
Speaker 1: was it starting in 2004?
Speaker 1: We started this thing where we would go to the overflow room for the cosplay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you don't have to worry about Coming and going.
Speaker 0: there's no line.
Speaker 0: You can yell and scream and make fun of people and no one cares.
Speaker 1: Yep, I think.
Speaker 1: and also in 2004 you there's a. you can see Mike Pfeffer our friend doing his Jewish wolf would yeah doing his comedy routine, which isn't so bad.
Speaker 1: That was actually quite a good year for cosplay the most recent one only.
Speaker 1: like one or two of them were entertaining the rest of Them were kind of bleh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I missed it this year.
Speaker 0: I forgot what I've ever last year.
Speaker 0: I forget what I was doing.
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: We only saw part of it.
Speaker 1: It was kind of yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: So I was gonna talk about this manga thing for my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: This is kind of weird and I just want to preface Scott's thing by saying if any of you know what the deal is with This let us know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go to our forums at front row crew calm Slash forum, whatever and tell us well, actually the forums have been pretty rocking this week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like more so than usual it seems like it gets real quiet But if I bother to start a thread it will explode which means there's a lot of people just sitting there checking for new stuff but not putting new stuff.
Speaker 1: so People if you put new stuff in the forum other people will start talking to you.
Speaker 1: They're there, you know.
Speaker 0: So I have noticed like now some people are starting to post the thread for the day's episode on their own Which is good because we didn't really want to have to do that forever.
Speaker 1: The only reason I did that was like sort of like as a a seed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's the word for the chemicals that make reactions catalyst?
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: It's trying to catalyze the conversations going on in there.
Speaker 0: I didn't want it to become a thing yeah, but our eventual goal was that you guys would all talk amongst yourselves and Just have fun without us always having to be there in the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but for now on my policy is gonna be if the forms are quiet for like more than I don't know like 12 hours I'll start something.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Let's just start horrible arguments.
Speaker 1: All right, cool All right, that'd be awesome to start giant flame war forum.
Speaker 1: Haha alright, so anyway when Osamu Tezuka first started drawing manga like Astro Boy and whatnot?
Speaker 1: or Tetsu on Adam or whatever you want to call him He everyone knows that he got a lot of inspiration from Mickey Mouse and Mickey Mouse has four four fingers.
Speaker 1: so he drew Astro Boy with four fingers just like Mickey Mouse And he stuck with that until one day He went and talked to some people at Disney and he said hey Disney people Why do you draw Mickey Mouse with only four fingers?
Speaker 0: Well, why did they draw him with only four fingers?
Speaker 1: well apparently if you try to animate Mickey Mouse like an animation of him as opposed to a Comic on paper and you draw him with four fingers Well, if you draw him with four fingers It looks fine.
Speaker 1: If you draw Mickey Mouse with five fingers and animate him with old-school animation technology It looks like he has six fingers when he's moving.
Speaker 0: now I've seen because I know the Simpsons did that for the same reason in fact even made jokes about it one day.
Speaker 0: They talked about like the fifth magic finger on someone.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm So I don't know what that's caused by but I assume it's true.
Speaker 1: But what happened was after they told that to mr.
Speaker 1: Tezuka?
Speaker 1: He stopped drawing Astro boy with only four fingers instead of drawing him with five because he's probably thought that was stupid Uh-huh, and it's probably just their shitty animation techniques, which whatever.
Speaker 0: I have no idea, but I have no idea.
Speaker 0: I have no idea either but I know that other animators have had the same problem.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: I do have no idea.
Speaker 1: But I also know that I've seen Astro Boy with four and five fingers in different situations.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So anyway, anyway, there's a new problem quote-unquote problem.
Speaker 1: in manga Someone or a few people are drawing people with six fingers now.
Speaker 1: There are a few examples on this page here.
Speaker 0: The one from Death Note is kind of scary-looking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the one from Death Note is kind of freaky, but the most of them involves someone pointing.
Speaker 1: So what it looks like you see it doesn't look too freaky when someone's pointing so I can understand what it's about is, you know Four fingers clenched with a thumb clenched looks like a fist.
Speaker 1: It looks perfectly normal If you add an index finger pointing, but you still have the four clenched fingers.
Speaker 1: It looks kind of.
Speaker 1: it doesn't look kind of scary.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't look out of the ordinary.
Speaker 1: You won't catch it because four fingers clenched in a fist makes sense It looks right and one pointing finger and a bunch of clenched fingers looks right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, even though there's six fingers there, it doesn't Get all weird on you.
Speaker 1: so maybe the artist messed up or maybe they did it on purpose because they thought it looked better.
Speaker 1: because In some ways, you know drawing only three fingers clenched can look kind of silly, you know with one sticking out.
Speaker 1: I can see that.
Speaker 1: but the one picture that's the scariest is the one from Prince of Tennis.
Speaker 1: This guy's throwing a ball in the air and his hand is looks kind of like a squid Cuz.
Speaker 1: he's got like the four fingers.
Speaker 1: It's you it's a. That one freaks me out.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they did there.
Speaker 1: That's the one that messes me up.
Speaker 0: So well, I know in photography, I mean there was a long time ago at the end of high school.
Speaker 0: I was at a photo shoot, you know, most people get their high school like photo whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah high school pictures We just we had a photo studio.
Speaker 1: We all went to.
Speaker 0: yes I went to the studio and one picture they wanted is they wanted me to be like standing there with my sport jacket off But holding it like up over my shoulder in my like in my finger with my fist.
Speaker 0: You've seen this pose and you know magazines whatever and I held it the way I always do two fingers in the coat to hold it up and then my other two fingers just in my fist Mm-hmm, and that's the way most people hold a coat.
Speaker 0: just because it's easy one finger is not enough.
Speaker 0: and The photographer said nope.
Speaker 0: You gotta only have one finger in there.
Speaker 0: otherwise, it looks weird when I take the picture even though it looks okay in the real world.
Speaker 0: and That stuck with me to this day.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, huh?
Speaker 0: Showed me cuz he took two pictures.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure enough.
Speaker 0: My fist just looked kind of off when both fingers were hidden.
Speaker 1: hmm Yeah, I gotta admit the four-fingered with the point one single finger pointing looks okay You know.
Speaker 0: now I gotta look at Phoenix Wright and make sure he only has five fingers.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, if Phoenix Wright has six fingers, I'm surprised.
Speaker 1: Hold on.
Speaker 1: I gotta go to the website.
Speaker 0: Well, the pause there was while we looked it up and sure enough Phoenix Wright has five fingers.
Speaker 1: Hooray Phoenix Wright is not a freak.
Speaker 0: So it being favorites week and it being Wednesday.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about our favorite anime and I guess we'll say a favorite manga in comics for some other day.
Speaker 0: Yeah Since we realized that talking about comics my any one of these categories would take an entire show at least so probably have favorites week Number two sometime in the future basically whenever we run out of better ideas for themes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I think I've said this at the beginning of every episode this week And I'm going to continue to because we have separate feeds and some people might be only listening to this episode this week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wouldn't imagine why.
Speaker 1: yeah, I don't know why either but The favorites week is not the same thing as best week.
Speaker 1: You see when something is your favorite that means you like it more than anything else.
Speaker 1: when something is the best That means you consider it to be superior in quality, even though you might completely hate it.
Speaker 0: Now it's not the same thing.
Speaker 0: So for some people it is the same thing.
Speaker 0: But I found that most people there's actually a very clear distinction.
Speaker 0: if you actually think about it now.
Speaker 0: I'll clear there right away.
Speaker 0: my favorite anime are irresponsible captain Tyler and shoujo kakumei Utena.
Speaker 1: But the best anime in my opinion are cowboy bebop Evangelion eska flown a yep I mean if you think about movies the best movie is citizen Kane But I really couldn't watch it too many times without going but it It's the best movie.
Speaker 1: But my favorite movie would either be like the original Star Wars trilogy or the first matrix movie or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe Lord of the Rings.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, all right, so anime.
Speaker 0: now we've both been watching anime for a long time.
Speaker 1: Let's see When I was in thundercats and such.
Speaker 0: Oh if you count that stuff my whole life.
Speaker 1: But if you only count real anime, we I think we both go back to the sci-fi channel in the early high school days.
Speaker 0: Yeah high school.
Speaker 0: I'm talking fourth grade.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think it was on sci-fi channel.
Speaker 0: Maybe it wasn't even though the first time I'm aware of the sci-fi channel showing anime I was in fourth grade and they showed vampire hunter D. Kashan robot hunter robot carnival.
Speaker 0: Oh god What else.
Speaker 0: project a co Odin which I'd forgotten about until those anime world order guys talked about it.
Speaker 0: It's the worst show ever.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, I think they actually said it was the worst show ever.
Speaker 0: I mean I used to say great digital target was the worst show ever, but I think it is.
Speaker 0: I'd forgotten about Odin.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe we'll have to reconsider by watching them both.
Speaker 1: The Worst week is gonna be a different week.
Speaker 0: So yeah Now when I first saw anime like when I first realized that wait a minute These are cartoons, but they're good and they're not just for kids.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I Freaked out and I loved any anime I could see.
Speaker 0: I watched anything.
Speaker 0: I rented every single tape.
Speaker 1: They had a blockbuster I remember like I wasn't like super into anime like I had seen it and I knew what it was and I kind of wanted to See more.
Speaker 1: but I wasn't like whoo crazy.
Speaker 1: and then there was like an anime week on the sci-fi channel at some point.
Speaker 1: We're like every night.
Speaker 1: They showed some anime and like the first day was like fatal fury.
Speaker 1: It was like king of fighters or something like that.
Speaker 1: You know, the the neo-geo fighting game And I was even watching that and like all excited.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I mean I read much to make me go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean any anime in the world.
Speaker 0: I loved it and it really honestly for all the years.
Speaker 0: I watched anime.
Speaker 0: It wasn't until I got to college that I saw what I would consider good anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah towards the end of high school.
Speaker 1: I actually wanted to watch a lot of anime And then when I saw there was a little anime club, I was like, oh, yeah There's where I'm gonna get it cuz right now I can't really get it so much.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: I remember very clearly that the first anime club meeting of the RIT anime club now all of us the whole crew was there But none of us knew each other yet.
Speaker 1: We're sitting.
Speaker 0: I was sitting like with some weird stranger people that yeah I was sitting with a friend of mine from high school.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And all I know is that they showed cowboy bebop episode 5 and showed that.
Speaker 1: yeah, they showed gunsmith.
Speaker 0: Yeah, gunsmith cats, which is awesome.
Speaker 1: They showed music videos, which I'd never seen before.
Speaker 0: Yeah anime music videos.
Speaker 0: I had found one once when I was in high school.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what the hell they said.
Speaker 1: they were showing music videos.
Speaker 1: I was like, what the hell?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I found an AMV and I didn't know what it was, but it's.
Speaker 0: I still have it to this day.
Speaker 0: It's just a crappy little AVI to Sailor Moon and Phil Collins some Phil Collins song.
Speaker 0: And I remember thinking it was this unique awesome thing and the person who did it must have been so cool.
Speaker 0: and Then I saw AMV is there's a million of them and oh it's real hard to be cool now on the internet where everything is mixed with everything But a cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: and To this day.
Speaker 0: I still really haven't found a show that as a whole in my opinion is better than cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: I mean, I gotta agree.
Speaker 1: The best anime is kind of bebop.
Speaker 0: But I mean there are shows that are real close.
Speaker 0: Evangelion I think is a masterpiece.
Speaker 1: No, I think Evangelion, you know, it's great, but it's not the best because it just you know, it's not accessible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I guess it's the best you need to have everything.
Speaker 0: I guess I can agree in any area.
Speaker 1: if you if you're min-maxing you can't possibly be the best.
Speaker 0: All right, then how about eska flown a which I think is very much up there even slightly higher than Ava?
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really because it's just a. it's just a really really good, you know fantasy anime.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have any amazingness that would make it, you know the best.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see part of it might be that I saw eska flown a a long time ago, but I've seen it again recently.
Speaker 0: I still love it, but cowboy bebop is looking for another watching sometime soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can watch it like it's one of the it happens to be the best but you can also watch it a thousand times.
Speaker 0: I remember one time our friend Pete was over.
Speaker 0: I think it was Pete me I forget who it was and We were gonna watch like the first five episodes of cowboy bebop because he'd never seen it and we ended up watching the whole show.
Speaker 0: Alex might have been Ali.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: that was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we ended up just watching the whole.
Speaker 1: we couldn't stop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we just watched the whole show over the course of a weekend.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, it's a show.
Speaker 1: you really once you see one episode.
Speaker 1: if you have the rest of them there is just dangerous weapon.
Speaker 0: well I guess one test that seems to really show in terms of cowboy bebop is that I gave cowboy bebop to my dad and he Loved it and I've lent it to people who hate anime never heard of anime don't care about it, whatever and Without exception they've all loved it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've all wanted to see more.
Speaker 1: That's what's so terrific about it All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, my favorite anime not the best anime.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna argue that they're the best anime are probably the original macross
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't want to say initial D, but I think I might
Speaker 0: See to me initial D at least the first season and the movie because the rest of the show I'm really losing interest real fast.
Speaker 0: But I love it, but I listed as one of those shows that I know it's dumb, but I love it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah initial D.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say it's good.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're gonna argue about the best anime, it wouldn't even get on to any of anyone's list.
Speaker 0: It's definitely on the B list.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe even the C list, but I just can't watch it without feeling really really good.
Speaker 0: I think that's a side effect of one the eurobeat music which we had never experienced before until we saw this show.
Speaker 1: But I mean I've why I've watched all of initial D Maybe five times at least the first season at least five times.
Speaker 1: He's not exaggerating and he was not Every time.
Speaker 1: and it's to.
Speaker 1: even if I watch an episode I've seen before it's still exciting.
Speaker 1: I get I still getting the manga and it's still exciting.
Speaker 0: You should see how many inside jokes we have that are based solely on initial D.
Speaker 1: It's just so much fun.
Speaker 0: I mean, here's an example.
Speaker 0: There's a scene later on in the show where he's talking me the main characters racing some guy, right?
Speaker 0: Which yeah, you never expect that in initial D a show about racing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and suddenly talking me passes this guy and the guy turns and sees talking me there and he has this look on his face.
Speaker 0: and Now we make this.
Speaker 0: we make the look to each other whenever we see someone failing or whenever we're about to fail at something.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's like up you make the face.
Speaker 0: I Guess part of the reason we really like it is that initial D. when we first saw it We thought it was the stupidest thing ever.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I went to a club Watch four episodes of it.
Speaker 1: the first four and at the first.
Speaker 1: the fourth episode is a cliffhanger because you don't know who's gonna win The race and I remember we all walked out like that was the dumbest thing.
Speaker 1: I walked out and I actually thought that was really dumb, you know, and I also thought I wonder who wins.
Speaker 1: But at the same because I haven't seen any initial D I don't know who that the same guy wins every time and we kept kind of talking about it like yeah that show sucks.
Speaker 1: But I didn't you know, I definitely had a bad opinion of it after watching four episodes.
Speaker 1: It's like I must have not heard the Eurobeat music or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know yeah, so then we then we went and there was a marathon of the whole first season.
Speaker 0: and We went because we figured we'll go and we'll leave after we found out if he wins.
Speaker 0: just because we wanted closure We ended up staying to the end.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean when I went in for that marathon of the whole first season It's like there was a lot quieter in the room so I can concentrate and I can really absorb all the stuff that was going.
Speaker 1: You had to get into it.
Speaker 1: if you just kind of casually watch initial D you'll think it's this boring What the hell's going on stupidity.
Speaker 0: or if you expect any sort of deep meaning from this show, you're gonna be disappointed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're gonna be real disappointed.
Speaker 1: But if you sit there and watch initial D and you get into it and you feel the energy It's so much fun.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the best way to do it like a thousand times I guess my advice is never watch initial D alone.
Speaker 0: The more people you have in the room the better.
Speaker 0: even people that hate the show because everyone will be yelling by the end of An episode.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's what it's about.
Speaker 0: Now for me, like I already said irresponsible captain Tyler which is one of the first anime I watched all the way through and For reasons, I really can't really describe.
Speaker 0: I just love that show.
Speaker 0: It's funny.
Speaker 0: It's cute.
Speaker 0: The end made me cry a little bit.
Speaker 0: the movie made me cry even more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't cry at the end of initial D and I guess part of the reason I really like Tyler is that for anyone Who knows me?
Speaker 0: Uh If a person like Tyler existed, they would be my role model hero and God.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that makes sense.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't really plan at all into the future.
Speaker 0: I'm generally very happy-go-lucky.
Speaker 0: I tend to just leave everything to chance and Tyler is I guess the epitome of that.
Speaker 0: Plus in the show.
Speaker 0: he this is kind of us in a side.
Speaker 0: He ends up with this alien princess girl who?
Speaker 0: Ironically enough.
Speaker 0: I guess not ironically.
Speaker 0: just coincidentally I Dated in college a girl who looked almost exactly like her.
Speaker 1: you dated an alien princess.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll note that the alien princess actually just looked like a normal redheaded girl Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So rim has a personal connection with the show and thus making it his favorite.
Speaker 0: I Have no personal connection at all with initial D Other than the fact that you tend to drive fast and or recklessly at times.
Speaker 1: No, not really But they don't really drive recklessly and initially there's many wrecks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not less right now, of course.
Speaker 0: I could also give an equally important nod to shoujo kakumei.
Speaker 0: utenna Yeah, which we a bunch of us watch together for a while Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean Utenna is a good show, but it's kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's got some aspects of it I like a whole lot and other aspects are just kind of like and I'd rather have just that part of the show.
Speaker 0: Watching utenna is like reading Hawthorne.
Speaker 0: Every single sentence is just a metaphor metaphor metaphor metaphor metaphor to the point that you're barely aware of the fact that there's a show Happening around it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that part of the problem with utenna is that a lot of the times imagine if You just someone's blatantly doing things that are supposed to be symbolic like they're just throwing symbols at you but a lot of them just represent nothing or they're just Symbols for the sake of making symbols
Speaker 0: see very few of them actually mean nothing in the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think because no matter what symbol if I made a show that was just a bunch of symbols Someone out there could come up with a meaning for every single one of them no matter what the plot was.
Speaker 0: I think most of this part that you're referring to is from the.
Speaker 0: there's a part in the black rose saga Which is in the middle of the show Where it the show seems to make fun of itself and they start throw it like absolutely ridiculous metaphors all over the place.
Speaker 1: Well, that's one particular the point that there's.
Speaker 0: even at one point There's like it shows something and then there's a hand that appears on the screen Pointing at it to draw your attention to it to remind you that it's symbolic of something.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, which was just silly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's just.
Speaker 1: that's one part in like one episode.
Speaker 1: but in general the show does all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: You know whether some of it means something some of it doesn't.
Speaker 1: some of it you can make mean something like Nikki in the stopwatch thing and oh, no, that's specifically not supposed to mean anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you see what I'm talking about Mickey's just an anal kind of little person Yeah, and like people always lie when they're meeting in places and they'll have the shows over dramatic.
Speaker 0: All right All right, here's how I like it.
Speaker 1: on very prurient level It's most of the symbols are just weird accessories in scenes that they draw attention to frequently.
Speaker 0: See, I think that there's a lot more.
Speaker 0: I think that there was a lot of thought put into what was shown where and when.
Speaker 1: oh Yeah, there might have been thought to it.
Speaker 1: It was crazy thought But it was.
Speaker 1: you know, it doesn't matter whether the thought was there or not.
Speaker 1: the point.
Speaker 0: on a very basic level I like the show because it's got the tall thin pretty angular people and rose petals flying everywhere.
Speaker 0: Everything's overdramatic and crazy.
Speaker 0: Everyone is just really really Anime, I guess is a one way to put it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and honestly what I really like about the show is just that Once you see the end and you figure out what's going on because the show is kind of weird You go watch the show all over again.
Speaker 1: It's totally different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, watching the show the second time through this is one of those shows where once you realize what's going on Every every single thing in the show is different.
Speaker 0: now because you watch it again and you realize wait a minute But in the very first episode that happens because of this.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: I get it.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: This is crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like when we first I didn't figure it out until like two minutes before the end Yeah, and I didn't open like I had it in my brain and I should have said something because then people would have been like Oh Scott got it.
Speaker 1: But no, I didn't say anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz not a shit talker.
Speaker 1: I Could be lying, but I'm not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I figured.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's.
Speaker 0: it's one of the few shows where we were all watching it together.
Speaker 0: And there's a point in the show at the end where quite literally we all screamed.
Speaker 0: It takes a lot to make me scream during a show.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I mean I've cried.
Speaker 0: I'll admit that I cry like a girl and a lot of anime.
Speaker 1: I used to cry at a lot of stuff but not anymore.
Speaker 0: Really I cry like a little girl.
Speaker 0: I just start bawling sometimes I try to hold it in just doesn't work.
Speaker 0: I just I cry but I don't scream.
Speaker 0: and utenna made me scream.
Speaker 0: Yep, well, we could list all the shows we've cried at the end of no because I can't really remember.
Speaker 1: try gun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kinda yeah you cried.
Speaker 1: we all cry more in like 23 than 26.
Speaker 0: yeah, 26.
Speaker 0: See try gun.
Speaker 0: I think is a really good shot.
Speaker 1: Definitely wouldn't call it the best or my favorite but it's very high on my list if try gonna continued more in the vein of the first few episodes instead of it kind of Changed a little towards the end.
Speaker 1: It would have been a much better more favorite show.
Speaker 0: See, I don't know because the first few episodes were just silly and then later it had, you know plot meaning character development.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should read the manga.
Speaker 0: the manga makes no sense.
Speaker 0: the manga is just crazy batshit.
Speaker 0: I can't follow the manga.
Speaker 0: if I had not already seen the show the manga would be entirely indecipherable to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the manga doesn't really create.
Speaker 1: the guy draws really action scenes.
Speaker 1: Well He's like a hammer trying to whack all the nails and also the screws and the bolts and the nuts.
Speaker 0: I just can't follow it.
Speaker 0: I'd like to because I want to know more about these characters in this world.
Speaker 1: Oh, I kind of know but maybe I'll explain it someday.
Speaker 0: I just can't read that manga and this is coming from a guy who's read Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you my other favorite anime I said already was Matt the original Macross.
Speaker 1: now I saw Robo tech not when it was shown in the 70s, but when it was shown on Cartoon Network.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I watched much of it then and I didn't know much of what was going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah See this is the thing is that was the first show where I was watching Toonami like religiously when Moltar was the guy I miss him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when they would show Space Ghost and Thunder.
Speaker 1: That's why I started watching because it's Space Ghost and Thundercats.
Speaker 1: One day they show the show Robo tech and I was like, alright I'll watch the first episode of this show and it was alright.
Speaker 1: and the next day There was another episode and it continued from episode one.
Speaker 1: So I promised myself I wasn't gonna miss any episodes and I managed to make it well into the second story of Robo tech.
Speaker 1: You know Which was actually?
Speaker 1: I think it's Southern Cross is the name of the real and because it Robo tech if you don't know It's like three or four animes combined.
Speaker 1: They basically put these animes end-to-end.
Speaker 1: So the first anime is Macross Southern Cross and Genesis Rider Mospita and they put these shows end-to-end Right as if they were one big show.
Speaker 1: But really it's three animes stuck together and redubbed and they said that they made a proto culture.
Speaker 1: yeah, they took proto culture and they pretended that certain characters are related to other characters to make them stick together.
Speaker 1: and Basically if you just watch these three anime separately on their own they're all much better than Robo tech.
Speaker 1: Yes, but when I watched Robo tech for the first time I realized that the show had changed and I learned that they were actually separate shows.
Speaker 1: and the first show is Macross and like Back this is so long ago.
Speaker 1: I was still crying at the end of anime, but I didn't really cry but it was just like at the end.
Speaker 1: I was like Yeah, yeah Macross is a good show cuz I watched the whole thing through.
Speaker 0: well He bought that crazy box set that came out way back in the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so then I watched started watching the second show and I watched the second show through to the end.
Speaker 1: But it didn't really quite give the odd because I think it was destroyed too much by its Robo tech a vacation.
Speaker 1: So Southern Cross, I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: You're not so good.
Speaker 1: I never actually saw the third one because Cartoon Network didn't air it and I don't know where to find it.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I could get it on DVD now, but whatever.
Speaker 1: But then when I got the the box set which is I think sophomore year college Yeah, we were gonna make that took all of the original of Macross the original on Robo tech a fine version.
Speaker 1: They read they up to the graphics so they were visible and they added subtitles instead of dubbing.
Speaker 1: and you watch that and it's like.
Speaker 1: And then I could really see what the hell was going on.
Speaker 1: And it's hella good.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: let's see what's so great about it.
Speaker 1: number one, it's got awesome robots But it's robots that make sense.
Speaker 1: It's not like crazy condoms with super attacks or anything.
Speaker 1: It's like Imagine if we had military technology, you know a hundred years from now It's definitely gassaraki robots as opposed to big O robots.
Speaker 1: Yeah Imagine if like we had some alien technology that we learned stuff from and we advanced far into the future from now.
Speaker 1: It's like fighter jets.
Speaker 1: Well, our fighter jets would transform into robots.
Speaker 1: It makes sense.
Speaker 1: and the fighter jets in the show?
Speaker 1: The story is that one of the guys working on the show actually said what if we had a plane that turned into a robot?
Speaker 1: That would be awesome.
Speaker 1: And everyone was like what you're crazy.
Speaker 1: So then he made the toy first and the toys so high quality.
Speaker 1: So then they just made the show look exactly like the toy and it makes perfect sense.
Speaker 0: Didn't the toy come first in big O as well.
Speaker 0: I I remember reading something like the guy made the toy to try to pimp his show idea.
Speaker 0: You know the big O robot and all I remember the very funny part was that the people he showed the toy to asked him Why the hell does he have interchangeable fists?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's good one No, but then macross also has the great music.
Speaker 1: even the dubbed Robotech has awesome music and the thing about it.
Speaker 1: It's not like The music isn't like music in other shows.
Speaker 1: It's classy sort of show tune pop tune type of things that min may sings and they're all really like no matter what Set decade you're in no matter what the music style of the times is.
Speaker 1: if you watch this show the song is kind of grow Like they play the same.
Speaker 1: you'll hear her sing the same song and like every single episode and she has about maybe ten songs at most probably less than that, but they all grow on you and you recognize them and it's like And you begin to associate them in your mind with different things going on.
Speaker 1: It's just really good and the space battles don't have too much stock footage.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: Now another show that's near and dear to me though people often make fun of me and I have good reasons for this show Being as good to me as it is or as I'm going to claim it is Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: So in one sec, I've seen all 200 episodes and all the movies and I'm gonna be proud of.
Speaker 0: well, the thing is way back.
Speaker 0: there wasn't so much anime I can get my hands on and I found this fan subber and I ended up.
Speaker 0: these are like this is back before they were digi subs.
Speaker 0: Like you couldn't get fan subs.
Speaker 0: So I got all these VHS fan subs of Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: It was like the first non American released anime I'd ever seen.
Speaker 0: so being the anime fan that I was I sat down and watched it And I gotta say of all the magical girl shows out there.
Speaker 0: I think Sailor Moon is still probably the definitive one and If you cut out about a hundred and seventy five of those episodes I really think there's a good plot there.
Speaker 1: if you cut out a hundred and seventy five episodes Maybe I mean if you want to just compare based on quality and enjoyment I don't think you can really say that Sailor Moon is better than fancy Lala.
Speaker 0: I Sailor Moon has a hurricane michiro, which I think who I think are awesome.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the hell that is actually, it has the Sailor Moon s because it's broken up into different story, you know, yeah and Sailor Moon s. if any of you have never seen any of Sailor Moon and you want to see kind of not really the origin But like the defining magical girl show watch Sailor Moon s from start to finish.
Speaker 0: That is in my eyes.
Speaker 0: What is magical girl show should be?
Speaker 1: is that the one they kept out of American?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was that.
Speaker 0: that was right at the point because they were showing Sailor Moon in America to little kids and they were dubbing it and changing it and then they got to Sailor Moon s and that's when they realized that this show probably isn't for American kids because Lesbians death.
Speaker 0: Oh my god plot.
Speaker 1: So the lesbian porn part with is what you think a magical girl show should be.
Speaker 1: See, there's actually the last time you watch this.
Speaker 0: Actually, the last time I watched it was when I was a senior in high school.
Speaker 1: So are you sure your memory isn't slightly blurred based on your senior in high school wanting to look at Lesbians?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I'm not saying the show is great I'm just saying that in terms of shows that have affected me or shows that I like there's a place in my heart for Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: All right, because I think the show is favorites Which means has to be the top of the list.
Speaker 1: because if we're just gonna go based on shows that I like and shows That affected me.
Speaker 1: Well, let's let's see.
Speaker 1: Let's get a little pen and paper out here.
Speaker 0: Well, see if we're talking about favorites, I mean Even if I list every show I've liked that's less than maybe 5% of all the anime out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: But if you're gonna talk about just liked at all, we got like Gundam.
Speaker 0: see I like Sailor Moon a lot I mean.
Speaker 0: granted a lot of that is clouded by the fact that I saw it a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm trying to you know, but since it's favorites, I'm trying to stick with stuff.
Speaker 1: That's like, all right Yeah, really say I like that more than I like that.
Speaker 0: Well, like you mentioned Gundam seed I wouldn't even bring it up because I liked it, but I didn't like it that much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know I could really think of stuff that I liked as much as initial D and Macross.
Speaker 1: I could think of stuff that is as good as and stuff that I liked a lot but not as much I remember in high school.
Speaker 0: I really liked Tenchi Muyo and to this day.
Speaker 0: I still love it though I hate every spin-off and every TV series after the original.
Speaker 0: Well We've been talking mostly about series for a lot of reasons because we tried to think of anime movies that really affected us or we really loved or our favorite movies.
Speaker 0: and It's a lot harder to pick a favorite movie.
Speaker 0: I think than a favorite show.
Speaker 1: I think it's just.
Speaker 1: there's not a lot of quantity of anime movies and a lot of them are like Summary movies and recap movies.
Speaker 0: So you really can't grow movies that are just long episodes like the cowboy bebop movie or all the Sailor Moon movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I think Ghibli is like, you know overall is the anime movie King?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think we even need that.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll consider non Ghibli movies because honestly Ghibli movies are just amazing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if I had to pick one Ghibli movie, I would just pick spirited away Overall.
Speaker 1: the rest I think.
Speaker 0: for me, I don't know I actually really really liked house moving castle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I liked it a lot too, but I think spirited away had a few things on it.
Speaker 1: Hmm like little.
Speaker 1: well Let's see house moving castle had the fire.
Speaker 1: That's really like a huge trump card right there But it's pretty.
Speaker 1: we had a little footballs and I think the story made a little bit more sense.
Speaker 1: You know stuff like that now.
Speaker 0: honestly if I had to pick my favorite anime movie ever I left a list too because one of them is fairly fairly recent.
Speaker 0: So I want to give a nod to the old movie that I like as well Because the old movie was kind of knocked out of the first place position recently.
Speaker 0: my favorite anime movie prior to the second one is Lupin the third castle of Cagliostro.
Speaker 0: Oh Lupin.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I love every Lupin movie.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah crappiest crap.
Speaker 0: Lupin movie Babylon gold is on my list of good anime and it's really close between the fuma conspiracy and Cagliostro.
Speaker 0: those are both like the prime of Lupin.
Speaker 0: But I think Cagliostro edges out just a little bit just because of the scene at the end.
Speaker 0: Not gonna spoil anything, but the last scene in that movie just brings a little man tear to your eye.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Cagliostro is real good and I really like Lupin, but I think fuma conspiracy I like more because Cagliostro is like just missing some of those like Lupin Elements that all the other Lupin movies have.
Speaker 0: well Cagliostro was a little more serious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was more serious And you know while more serious, I think makes it a better movie It doesn't make it a more favorite movie of mine, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can see where you're coming from and I got to admit this isn't a spoiler because it happens immediately.
Speaker 0: Fuma conspiracy the main thing going on in that movie.
Speaker 0: Is that going on gets married?
Speaker 0: If you don't know who going on is that doesn't mean anything to you.
Speaker 1: But if you do if you don't know who go mine is why haven't you seen a new upon?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll talk to us.
Speaker 0: We'll give you some movies.
Speaker 0: I mean Dan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you need to see every Lupin movie and Probably the TV show as much as you can and at least the movies.
Speaker 0: I think the movies are better than the TV show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the movies are where it's at and even if you hate Lupin Castle Cagliostro is an amazing movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, if you don't.
Speaker 1: even if you don't like Lupin Cagliostro, like I said doesn't have all the Lupin things in it.
Speaker 1: It's more serious and whatever.
Speaker 0: so plus it has one of the best lines in any show ever With your sword and my anti-tank rifle, yep dot dot dot Yep, but I got to say both movies were edged out recently by the place promised in our early days.
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't like police promise that much.
Speaker 0: I don't know why the show affected me so much this movie, but I just loved it.
Speaker 0: It was just.
Speaker 0: this movie has the saddest happy moment.
Speaker 0: I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: Imagine a scene where nothing bad happens.
Speaker 0: In fact only good things happen, but it's still sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it did have that and I just think it was generally a very good atmospheric Well-drawn well-done movie.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It was all those things.
Speaker 1: I won't deny.
Speaker 1: All right, so I just didn't.
Speaker 1: I Know I actually liked the other work by the same guy.
Speaker 1: What was it?
Speaker 0: Oh a Hoshi no Koi.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like that a lot more and it wasn't even a whole movie.
Speaker 0: See I like that one, but I liked it a lot less than this one.
Speaker 1: No, I liked Hoshi no Koi the most this one because I'd seen Hoshi no Koi.
Speaker 1: a lot of this was Hoshi no Koi ish You know, it just seemed a little more Slower and dragged out.
Speaker 0: and see what were you say slower and dragged out.
Speaker 1: I say atmospheric and yeah That's all point of view type of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean we have different tastes.
Speaker 0: Scott likes the giant robots a lot more than me and I like the show Joe crap as he Would call it.
Speaker 1: I don't like the giant robots because they're giant robots.
Speaker 0: Shows that have giant robots happen to have be the type that you don't like giant robo, which I think is awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't like it.
Speaker 0: I don't it's awesome.
Speaker 1: No, it's like.
Speaker 1: giant robo is a lot more like Astro Boy than it is like other than macross or anything.
Speaker 1: All right, it just happens to have giant robots.
Speaker 0: All right, so I've listed place promised.
Speaker 0: What's your favorite non-loupon?
Speaker 0: Animated movie.
Speaker 1: I'm the part anime movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's real hard.
Speaker 1: The Pat LeBourne movies are really really good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't like him that much but they're good.
Speaker 1: I think the second one is the best one and I mean well Akira is really good.
Speaker 1: But once you read the manga, it doesn't feel so good anymore.
Speaker 1: It's like when I saw Akira before and I'd only seen a few other anime movies.
Speaker 1: It was kind of like whoa my god, but then once you read the manga, it's like yeah that movies not so much.
Speaker 1: Yep, now the beginning of the movie beginning the first half of Akira is the best anime movie.
Speaker 1: The second half The second half of the Akira movie is not the best anime movie ever.
Speaker 0: I gotta give a big nod to the ghost in the shell movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because they I mean one goes to the first one a lot more than the second one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like the second one a lot for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: I mean, it was really pretty.
Speaker 0: it got me For any of you who have seen it that scene where you thought the movie was broken.
Speaker 0: that got me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I liked seeing a lot like just kind of a look into Bato's life.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I like that a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Bato, it's like the major is just totally.
Speaker 1: if you want to know about her you can read the manga.
Speaker 1: So the fact that they focus on the other characters and the TV show in the movies is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz you see Bato and he's got his dog and he's got his life and it's just.
Speaker 0: I really like that movie and I I guess The two of the ghost in the shell movies together would be very very high in my list as an entity.
Speaker 1: That's got to be a high on anyone's list.
Speaker 1: The Galaxy Express like.
Speaker 1: I would have said that was the best but then re-watching it I mean, it's still really good, but I don't it does.
Speaker 1: it's not the same as it was before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though.
Speaker 0: We're watching a lot of that stuff now.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like my memory of watching the ghost in the Galaxy Express movie the first time would be like the best.
Speaker 0: but oh Yeah, that completely chart.
Speaker 0: because I said place promised and Lupin movies.
Speaker 0: But there's one other anime movie that like it.
Speaker 0: it's tied with all of them.
Speaker 0: to me It's eraser at Sura to beautiful.
Speaker 1: Oh, you like that one.
Speaker 0: Well, I like you're a say at Sura.
Speaker 0: I just think it's cute and funny.
Speaker 0: But the thing is for anyone doesn't know the story and I'll be real brief.
Speaker 0: The second movie there are five or six movies and the second movie was done by different people.
Speaker 0: In fact, it got licensed by a different company.
Speaker 0: So you can buy a box set that has one three four five six and then you can buy two by itself and there's a hole To stick it in in the other box Mm-hmm, and I guess it is.
Speaker 0: it is just a very good Screen representation of how dreams work.
Speaker 0: That may sound weird But it's a good movie like a really good movie and I saw it on the sci-fi channel way way back and to this day I still consider it one of my favorite movies ever animated or otherwise.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you also like that whatever tenchi movie It was.
Speaker 0: I like the first tenchi movie tenchi muyo in love because it's just cute funny happy whatever You know.
Speaker 1: early watch and I watched it.
Speaker 1: It was lame.
Speaker 0: No, that was the second one I had you watch because it's only an hour long.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: The second one is kind of a. the third one is just a freaking doujinshi.
Speaker 0: as far as I'm concerned It's just terrible.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't really know anything or care.
Speaker 0: Yeah for any of you who like all those like, you know modern harem shows like I don't know love Hina Tenchi muyo is the original Yeah, the creator of the harem to show.
Speaker 1: Thank you very much.
Speaker 1: Thanks for bringing these terrible types of shows into the world.
Speaker 0: It's okay to have one of any kind of show.
Speaker 0: the problem is when people keep trying to make that show over and over again.
Speaker 1: No, the problem is when that type of show is a nasty harem show.
Speaker 0: I thought it was funny and generally heartwarming.
Speaker 1: I thought it was a harem.
Speaker 0: You haven't really seen much of it.
Speaker 1: I saw enough.
Speaker 0: No, you didn't I seen enough.
Speaker 1: I'm not about to go seek out anymore.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, oh, I just remembered an anime movie I like a whole lot.
Speaker 1: Oh like just as much as the Pat LeVoir movies and spirited away.
Speaker 0: All right, Tokyo Godfathers I forgot about that.
Speaker 1: I like it a lot a whole lot.
Speaker 1: like I could watch that thing a hundred times.
Speaker 0: Oh my it's not in my top ten list.
Speaker 0: Like I list every movie I mentioned so far above that one.
Speaker 0: But yeah, Tokyo Godfathers is really awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I knew about it and then I watched it and it's like but then it was like.
Speaker 0: And then with the thing at the end but yeah at the end when you just kind of like you get it's a movie You gotta just roll with.
Speaker 1: yeah, man.
Speaker 1: That's a terrific movie.
Speaker 0: It's another good movie to watch with a group of people.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of movie that'll get people yelling and screaming.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Well, we could probably talk a lot longer about this, but we'll save it for another day.
Speaker 0: someday in the future We'll do favorite manga favorite comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think rim will have too many favorite comics that are not in manga.
Speaker 0: No, no, probably not though, of course I've read enough Rockato to know that it's awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, we're gonna get the trade paper back soon.
Speaker 1: now I'm gonna start.
Speaker 1: I'm starting to buy comics monthly.
Speaker 1: now that way the way it works where I get them from it's $75.
Speaker 1: if I buy $75 worth I don't to pay shipping.
Speaker 1: So if I wait a whole month and then buy it Maybe I get free shipping and you know, I'll read them all and then I'll have time to read other stuff, too.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the favorite manga one will be real easy because I own almost every manga I like Yeah, plus any manga that might be your favorite.
Speaker 1: you either haven't read or you don't can't get yeah, then we don't know about even Yeah, how long did it take us to get sanctuary and Eagle God?
Speaker 1: How long did it take me just to get freaking a cure back?
Speaker 0: Crap, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: If you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.