Speaker 0: It's Tuesday March 28th, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we talk about Starfarers of Catan and Galactic Civilizations 2.
Speaker 1: Let's do this!
Speaker 1: Pund.
Speaker 0: I say it, Pund.
Speaker 0: I see you people in the forum seem to disagree on that.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that the word evolved separately in many different areas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that seems to be the logic.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, one guy sees- that's what happens to the internet!
Speaker 1: One guy does something, it spreads to internet-enabled people in different areas, and then it spreads from those internet-enabled people to their circle of friends.
Speaker 1: You know, like a web!
Speaker 1: A web.
Speaker 0: Because I actually remember when we were at RIT and we always said Pund, like everyone did, and then the freshmen.
Speaker 0: We call them the freshmen.
Speaker 0: They're actually almost graduated by now, but we still call them the freshmen.
Speaker 0: But when they got to RIT, they said Pund, which just sounded weird.
Speaker 1: Well, because on the internet, before now, when we have Skype, most people did things by text.
Speaker 1: So, one guy types P-W-N-3-D or something, and everyone in that game has a different pronunciation in their mind, and then who knows what it really is.
Speaker 1: So when nerds actually start getting together physically and talking, and one guy says Pund, another guy says Pund, another guy says Pund.
Speaker 0: Hoedown!
Speaker 1: Hootenanny.
Speaker 1: Hoedown Hootenanny!
Speaker 1: Hoedown Hootenanny Hootenanny Hootenanny Hootenanny Hootenanny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, it's video game day, and we've got two video game day newses.
Speaker 0: So, World of Warcraft, you all know that I'd rather dislike it, but-- Yeah, we can't stop talking about it.
Speaker 0: Because it always makes news, and once again, it's made news.
Speaker 0: Now, there's this guy, and he made some sort of unofficial strategy guide to World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: Strategy.
Speaker 1: Play a lot.
Speaker 0: Well, like, he gave advice on where to level and how to level and various things about the game.
Speaker 1: Places where other people aren't, and the monsters aren't going to kill you.
Speaker 0: Now, instead of publishing this as a book, he published it as a book on eBay.
Speaker 0: No big deal.
Speaker 0: And you think, "Alright, you sell him, I think, $15 a pop.
Speaker 0: I think that's a cool thing.
Speaker 0: I think he's a nice entrepreneurial-type
Speaker 0: person.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: Most people go to just-- they write a one in text, they put it on GameFAQs, you know, "This guy made a real book, so
Speaker 1: hey.".
Speaker 0: And I point out that he didn't steal anything, he didn't even use any intellectual property.
Speaker 0: I mean, he didn't reveal storylines, he only used a few screenshots that are clearly fair use.
Speaker 0: And he has a huge disclaimer in the front of the book and the back explaining that he has not affiliated in any way with World of Warcraft or any of the companies involved, and that the guide is entirely unofficial and unacknowledged.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Despite this, Blizzard, the Vendee et
Speaker 0: al.,
Speaker 0: have proceeded to send takedown notices to him and to eBay, to threaten to file suit under all sorts of things like the DMCA, and trademark infringement.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, well, okay.
Speaker 1: Trademark infringement, I can understand, see.
Speaker 1: 'Cause let's say I wanted to write a book about the history of some football team, right?
Speaker 0: You don't need permission.
Speaker 1: I don't, but however, if I use, like, the logos of the football team, or if I use any statistics, they can get you.
Speaker 0: Well, statistics, no, because statistics, as long as they are gathered, are a fact, and facts cannot be held by IP laws like that.
Speaker 1: Uh, they're actually, all the sports statistics are held by these companies, or these two companies, or something like that.
Speaker 1: It's weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if that ever really got challenged in court, I don't think it would last.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's not the point.
Speaker 1: The point is, the trademark of the, you can't put the World of Warcraft logo.
Speaker 1: You gotta say World of Warcraft TM and all that business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can do it, as long as you properly attribute it to the original trademark owner.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Like, you can write a book about how McDonald's sucks, you know?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, this guy did that.
Speaker 0: In my opinion, his guide is no different, and he even uses this example in his lawsuit.
Speaker 0: His book is no different than someone writing a book about how to use Microsoft Word.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically.
Speaker 0: And because this is a game, and because Blizzard is evil and stupid, they've decided to crush him under the weight of their legal system and their lawyers.
Speaker 0: And he fought back, and he's suing them, and we'll see what comes of it.
Speaker 1: He's probably gonna win, because if he doesn't, well, say goodbye to a lot of the computer books.
Speaker 0: Say goodbye to every computer book ever written.
Speaker 1: Say goodbye to a lot of books.
Speaker 1: Say goodbye to a lot of free speech.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And for all of you out there who play World of Warcraft, a nice little dig I've got for you is that, if you're still playing, you're supporting a company who does something like this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're giving money to someone who is squelching free speech, and in exchange, they're twiddling some bits in a database whenever you click.
Speaker 1: That's all it is.
Speaker 1: You click, and a number changes.
Speaker 1: And you're paying them money for the privilege of clicking and letting numbers change.
Speaker 1: Oh, wait, you get a chat room too, but those are free.
Speaker 1: You can get them from IRC for nothing.
Speaker 0: Well, if you play IRC in one window and have Progress Quest going in the other window, and you call yourself the same thing in both of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there you go.
Speaker 1: I'm level 50... I'm almost level 60 in Progress Quest.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 0: What class are you again?
Speaker 1: I am a... I forget.
Speaker 1: An Ur-Paladin.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: And I think my race is like something... Enchanted Motorcycle.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It sounds very Kingdom Alothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't... I don't care.
Speaker 1: I just let it... It runs in the system tray, and I hardly ever look at it.
Speaker 1: I look at it like in the morning.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Whether you know it or not, Final Fantasy XII is out in Japan.
Speaker 1: 12.
Speaker 1: As in, I consider VI to be the best one.
Speaker 1: There have been two times that many, if you don't count X2.
Speaker 1: So, in fact, it's kind of like XIII.
Speaker 1: And XI, I guess... Well, count it as XII, because XI's an MMO, and X2 was a real game, kinda.
Speaker 1: Anything higher than VI, you know, kinda higher than VII is definitely sucky.
Speaker 0: Well, no, no.
Speaker 0: Just different.
Speaker 0: They're not the same kind of game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So, XII.
Speaker 1: XII is this weird thing.
Speaker 1: I've been reading about it, and I sent you probably the best article on the internet about it.
Speaker 1: Of course, it's IGN, so what do you want?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've been seeing general sorts of brouhaha where people say that this betrayed the core of Final Fantasy, and other people said that it's not even a Final Fantasy game.
Speaker 0: But some of the really old school people said it goes back to the good roots of what it should be, and no one agrees.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you, from what I've read, this is my interpretation of what the words I have seen on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we haven't actually played the game.
Speaker 1: No, I have not.
Speaker 1: And it's in Japanese, so I don't see the point.
Speaker 1: Number one, it still has the crazy FMVs and the crazy plot.
Speaker 1: that's just as good as any other Final Fantasy game.
Speaker 1: Hooray.
Speaker 1: Nothing has changed in this department.
Speaker 1: So if you only play for the plot, go for you.
Speaker 1: Number two, it's got the item, magic, whatever system seems to have this weird new thing with, like, licenses.
Speaker 1: Like, if you want to use a sword, you need to get a sword license, and then get a sword, and then you give the sword license to the character, and then the character can have the sword.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but every Final Fantasy after seven or so has had something weird like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just, that's their weird thing.
Speaker 1: I'm just explaining what it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone has a weird thing.
Speaker 1: Now, the thing that seems to be getting the most attention is the combat system.
Speaker 1: Now, let me just say my opinion on, if you don't know it already, on current, average RPG combat systems.
Speaker 0: I think we can sum it up very succinctly.
Speaker 0: We don't have time for that shit anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, this is what I want to do.
Speaker 1: As I'm walking around exploring a dungeon, the fun part of the game, I want to, every, say, ten or so steps in the dungeon, meet an encounter where I have to push A repeatedly to make a number go up and continue doing the fun part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's great.
Speaker 1: That's just terrific.
Speaker 1: That hasn't changed in forever.
Speaker 0: Now, I didn't mind it so much when I was young, but the combat was fun back then, and by the time I got tedious, I'd already moved on, and I had just invented free time to spend playing these games.
Speaker 0: No, not so much, and I just get annoyed when I have to fight more often than I wanted to.
Speaker 1: So, the new Final Fantasy XII combat, from what I've read and from what I've seen, works kinda like this.
Speaker 1: You have a bunch of characters, and you set AI on them.
Speaker 1: Now, the AI isn't like other AIs, where you set, like, you know, "Okay, you attack a lot, and you defend a lot, and you heal a
Speaker 1: lot.".
Speaker 1: It's not simple like that.
Speaker 1: It's, you set things called "gambits" on the characters, where you can say, you lay out very specific strategies, like, "You rush in and attack, and when your HP is low, run back, and, you know, you, you know, cast this spell, but when the HP is low, cast your healing
Speaker 1: spell.".
Speaker 0: Like an extremely advanced version of the Secret of Mana AI.
Speaker 0: Extremely advanced and specific.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you tell everyone exactly, pretty much almost exactly what to do.
Speaker 1: Then, you kinda point your characters in a direction and go, and they just constantly fight.
Speaker 1: Like, you just point them north, and they'll start walking north, and as you encounter bad guys, they'll go over and fight them.
Speaker 1: It'll look like, it looks like a bunch of people running through terrain while fighting bad guys.
Speaker 1: You know, it's pretty cinematic and whatnot.
Speaker 0: It sounds really badass.
Speaker 1: The problem with this is, well, let's forget the problem.
Speaker 1: One more thing about it is that you get this, too, this passive mode and active mode, and it's basically the old active and wait business, where in the passive mode, if you pause to change something, the fighting will stop, and in active mode, the fighting will continue if you go to the menu.
Speaker 0: I played every Final Fantasy that had that option in passive mode.
Speaker 1: I always played with wait, as opposed to active, so yeah, it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the thing people are complaining about is, is that once you set up the AI, you don't really do anything.
Speaker 1: You just kinda point forward and go, and your guys do everything on their own.
Speaker 1: You don't have to touch anything.
Speaker 1: Now, on the one hand, that makes me really happy, because I hate having to push A a million times to continue, and it's, you know, it gets past the annoying parts of the game.
Speaker 1: On the other hand, so what's the game?
Speaker 1: You're not doing anything.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it depends on how often you have to change up the strategy or how long these sequences are.
Speaker 0: I mean, is it a game of walk around and talk to people?
Speaker 0: Is it a game of find the secrets in the dungeon?
Speaker 0: Is it a game of make the party that'll make it through the dangerous area and pick the right path to do it?
Speaker 1: We don't quite know yet, because I haven't played it, and I've only read a few sparse writings on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it's on, what, the PlayStation 2?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, we're probably gonna get a PlayStation 2 whenever the 3 comes out, so maybe we'll pick it up when it comes out over here.
Speaker 1: The other thing, there are two other things.
Speaker 1: Number one, you don't get gold from enemies anymore.
Speaker 1: All you do is find gold and treasure, and then you can sell treasure to get gold.
Speaker 1: When you're in towns, you can't just walk around talking to people, like in the olden days.
Speaker 1: Some people will talk to you, and some people won't talk to you, and if someone's gonna talk to you, they'll have a little bubble above their head that says, "I will talk to
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 1: So you don't just walk up to random people and say,
Speaker 1: "Hey.".
Speaker 1: They'll just be like, "Who the hell are you
Speaker 1: going?".
Speaker 0: Well, it seems to me that in original old Final Fantasies, you didn't walk up to people and say,
Speaker 0: "Hey.".
Speaker 0: You walk up to people, and they would just tell you a sentence.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And if you talk to them again, they would tell you the same sentence again.
Speaker 0: Sometimes that sentence would change.
Speaker 1: I think the reason they've done this is because they wanted to add people to the town who weren't, who didn't have text.
Speaker 1: That way they could make more highly populated areas.
Speaker 0: Which is a good idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it seems like on the one hand, they tried to appease people like me by making combat less tedious, which pissed off all the people.
Speaker 1: Literally, I think I saw a guy who said, "Man, I want to push buttons.
Speaker 1: I don't want my combat to just
Speaker 1: happen.".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Okay, so you want to push A a million
Speaker 1: times.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was always the kind of gamer, even when I liked these games, because I freaking love Final Fantasy IV.
Speaker 0: Whenever I could, I would just hold down A to B to combat.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I actually unequipped Rose's arrows most of the time so that I could just hold down A and not waste my arrows.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time, it's kind of appeasing people like me and pissing off the Final Fantasy crazies who like the combat bullshit.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really make me want to play it any more than the other ones because, you know, there's no game there.
Speaker 0: Well, there might be.
Speaker 0: I mean, we have to play it and actually see.
Speaker 1: There might be.
Speaker 1: I still have to play it, sure, but I'm really not interested in playing it.
Speaker 1: I'm just interested in looking at it, you know, because it's like normally if they came out with a Final Fantasy and it was just like all the others, I wouldn't even want to look at it.
Speaker 1: Now, because they changed something, I just want to see it.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll pick it up.
Speaker 1: All right, all you.
Speaker 0: All right, so things of the day.
Speaker 0: Now, I have a non-video game one, though it's cell phone, so it's all kind of related, but I think Scott's thing of the day more than makes up for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a double whammy.
Speaker 1: I could have split it up, but I didn't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we saved his for part two because I think it's the far greater thing of the day, but mine is very interesting nonetheless.
Speaker 0: Now, it has come to my attention over the last several months that the great majority of India, the nation of India, are basically Luddites or people who have absolutely no understanding of technology.
Speaker 0: They seem to be generally superstitious people.
Speaker 1: But wait, isn't this the country that sends all its people to America to learn about technology?
Speaker 0: There are a lot of smart people in India, in the cities.
Speaker 0: Now, basically what's been happening recently, and there have been countless stories similar to this on FARC, but this one caught my eye.
Speaker 0: Apparently, someone is calling cell phones in eastern India with 11 or 12 or 14 digit numbers instead of the 10 digit numbers they're used to.
Speaker 0: And these numbers are invalid, so you can't call them back.
Speaker 0: And they're calling them devil numbers.
Speaker 0: And they, a lot of people now believe that these phone numbers, if someone calls you and you answer it, you'll get sick or your family will die or something horrible will happen.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Like, this is widespread and the leaders of various cities and areas out there are trying to calm people down.
Speaker 1: So wait, how are these large phone numbers show up in the first place?
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't know, they're looking into that.
Speaker 1: Okay, so it's like a weird technology problem or something?
Speaker 0: Well, it could have been international calls, but, and it still might be.
Speaker 0: The thing is, the authorities believe that this is an effort by someone who plans to sell antivirus for cell phones in the future to scare people.
Speaker 0: Could be.
Speaker 0: Because if you answer, a lot of times, you'll get a person who says like, "Your family will die," or- Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or at least that's what they've been saying.
Speaker 0: There's been no actual evidence that anything has happened at all.
Speaker 1: So it could just be a wacky rumor?
Speaker 0: It's crazy rumors, but one guy who was interviewed, I think in the article I linked to, actually said that he answered one of these calls, and a guy told him that his cell phone could blow up if he receives calls from these numbers.
Speaker 0: So he turned his cell phone off because he was afraid his phone would blow up.
Speaker 1: Wow, what an idiot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The best quote was some guy who seems to be some sort of authority over there, basically keeps saying over and over again, "This is all rubbish.
Speaker 0: It's all
Speaker 0: rubbish.".
Speaker 1: Well, at least the authorities in India seem to be intelligent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they investigated it.
Speaker 0: They believed everyone.
Speaker 0: They said, "All right, well, we'll check it out,".
Speaker 0: and they went out there and they couldn't find anything.
Speaker 0: Nothing at all.
Speaker 1: And they come up with a somewhat reasonable explanation that's plausible, such as virus guy trying to make an antivirus.
Speaker 0: But no one believes it, and there's general mass hysteria in these areas.
Speaker 1: It's almost the opposite of our country.
Speaker 1: Well, not exactly the opposite, but where there are smart people and they're trying to tell the government to do smart things, the government's all stupid.
Speaker 1: In India, the government's all smart and the people hate it because they're all stupid.
Speaker 0: Why don't we trade governments with India?
Speaker 0: I think we'd get along a lot better.
Speaker 1: Dude, that'd be awesome.
Speaker 1: Totally awesome.
Speaker 1: All right, so this is probably an amazing thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Now, remember way, way back when my thing of the day was like 15 seconds of video from one of those Philips CDI Zelda games?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you don't remember, or if you didn't listen to this old episode or whatever, I'll explain this to you once again.
Speaker 1: There was a video game system known as the Philips CDI, made by Philips.
Speaker 1: They're still around.
Speaker 1: They make DVD players.
Speaker 0: It was a collaboration with Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Well, no.
Speaker 0: Well, it was going to be.
Speaker 0: Nintendo jumped out of that deal.
Speaker 1: No, you totally have it wrong.
Speaker 1: Philips was going to do some CD stuff for the SNES.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Until then, Sony was going to do some CD stuff for the SNES.
Speaker 1: However, both of them, it was like Philips was going to do it and they dropped out, and then Sony was going to do it and they dropped out.
Speaker 1: When Philips dropped out, they took the remnants and made the CDI.
Speaker 1: When Sony dropped out, they took the remnants and made the PlayStation.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing was they had the right to use Nintendo franchises.
Speaker 1: No, out of some weird contract that Philips had with Nintendo, they still retained the right to make like two Zelda games or three Zelda games.
Speaker 0: The Zelda franchise, they had the right to.
Speaker 1: I don't know, but they don't have it anymore, so it's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they made the three games they could make and then they were done and then the console disappeared.
Speaker 1: So there are three Zelda games for this system called the Philips CDI that exists that almost no one has played and no one wants to play.
Speaker 1: Thanks to the magic of the internet, the animated openings and endings to two of these games are now available for your viewing displeasure.
Speaker 0: Now, was it you who said that these games apparently look like Swedish animated porn?
Speaker 1: No, I think it was the internet that said they look like European animated porn, and yeah, they do.
Speaker 0: What scares me the most is that the ends of the two games are pretty much identical.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Ganon's exactly identical.
Speaker 1: Ganon's actually funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he almost says the exact same thing in both of the endings too.
Speaker 1: You bring light to my lair, you will die!
Speaker 1: No, it burns!
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's hilarious.
Speaker 1: If you know anything about Zelda and you watch this, you'll pee your pants.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, most people have, I mean, I played two of these games in a Sears where they had a Philips CDI on display and they were trying to sell it when I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: And way, way back, I totally forgot about that.
Speaker 0: And I had this memory in my skull of playing a weird game where you were Zelda, and I could never find any reference to it, I didn't know what it was, until the internet appeared.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The one thing I remembered about the Philips CDI is something that it was hard to find but was validated was the roller controller.
Speaker 1: It has this controller.
Speaker 1: you can get with a giant yellow ball that you kind of roll.
Speaker 1: It's weird, but it exists.
Speaker 0: I'd never actually seen that controller, it was a normal controller.
Speaker 1: That's all I remembered about.
Speaker 1: the Philips CDI was that controller.
Speaker 0: I wonder if any games even use that controller.
Speaker 1: Whenever someone said Philips CDI, I just thought of that controller.
Speaker 1: And then when I looked for Philips CDI, I didn't see that controller.
Speaker 1: And I was like, "What the hell is
Speaker 1: that?".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then I found the controller and I was no longer insane.
Speaker 0: So, let this be a lesson to Nintendo to never let anyone else ever get a hold of your intellectual property ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, um, yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know what the deal was, why.
Speaker 0: Nintendo must have signed a stupid contract.
Speaker 1: No, don't even ask about it, alright?
Speaker 0: Actually, I read a story a long time ago that explained the contract and why Philips had the right, but I don't remember now.
Speaker 0: If I can find it again, it'll be a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Remember, this was the stupid era of Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Towards the end of the SNES days, if they didn't mess- if they weren't stupid at that time, there wouldn't be any Xboxes or PlayStations or anything because all the Final Fantasies would have been on the next Nintendo that was powered by CDs and it would have all been amazing.
Speaker 0: Yep, because, I mean, there were some- and all that fiasco happened where, you know, Final Fantasy was on the PlayStation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, think about it.
Speaker 1: If that one point in history was different, we wouldn't have had Mario 64, we would have had Mario 32, and it would have had PlayStation 3D graphics and all kinds of craziness.
Speaker 1: The whole world would be different.
Speaker 0: I don't think Microsoft would have had a chance.
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 1: Nintendo would have just blown everyone away.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy VII would have been that other game that we've seen, like, two screenshots from and that's it.
Speaker 0: Hehehehe.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So anyway, it's, uh, gaming day, and we've got two games to review.
Speaker 1: Hooray!
Speaker 1: I've played, uh- well, I downloaded somewhat legitimately and played- Somewhat.
Speaker 1: Somewhat.
Speaker 1: Uh, Galactic Civilizations 2, which is sort of like- it's a sequel, obviously, to Galactic Civilizations 1, but it's basically Master of Orion 5.
Speaker 0: Yep, and not too long ago, Scott and I hung out with a couple of, uh, geeks/nerds in the basement, in a basement lab, like a creepy kind of place in Vassar College, and we played Starfarers of Catan for the first time.
Speaker 1: Which is, uh, settlers, but in space.
Speaker 0: So, both- And with- with rocket ships and such.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Alright, so let's do, uh, Starfarers first.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Now, if any of you have never played a Catan game, you know, Settlers of Catan, Starfarers of Catan, Seafarers of Catan, Kids of Catan, Settlers of Canaan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Cities and Knights of Catan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you get the idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're all- they're basically- these are like the introductory- everyone who's hooked on German board games probably played this game first.
Speaker 1: You can play Settlers on the internet in, like, ten different places, the best of which is actually Microsoft's version, but I don't think it's very free.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now, to go over it very, very briefly, Settlers games are basically along the lines of you have colonies or towns or something.
Speaker 0: You put them out there, they generate resources from the map.
Speaker 0: You need resources to build more things.
Speaker 0: You can trade resources with other players.
Speaker 0: First one to build X things wins.
Speaker 0: Now, Settlers games, well Catan games, are all usually very fun, but they're all fairly broken.
Speaker 0: At least, I'd say most of them are broken in the sense that once everyone knows how to play, and once everyone plays well, it's no longer a game of skill, it's just a game of luck because everyone makes the exact perfect decision every round.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically, there's dice rolling, and that's the first thing that happens in anyone's turn, is you roll dice to see who gets resources.
Speaker 1: Now, if your numbers keep coming up, then you're probably going to do a lot better than someone whose numbers don't keep coming up.
Speaker 1: And everyone knows the odds of all the different numbers coming up.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's 2d6, it's obvious.
Speaker 1: I mean, 6s and 8s come up the most.
Speaker 1: Well, 7s come up the most, but there are no 7s because that's the way the game works.
Speaker 1: So, you know, everyone tries to put their guys on the 6s and the 8s, unless someone's stupid, and if someone's stupid, well, then they lose.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it always turns out where, like, 5s and 10s come up all too much, and I'm never on 5 and 10, and because of that I lose, even though I have plenty of guys on 6 and 8.
Speaker 1: If everyone plays optimally, and everyone knows what they're doing, it's all the random dice, and it's kind of bleh.
Speaker 0: Now, the best thing about a Settler's Game, though, is that even experienced players can enjoy a Settler's Game that they haven't played often, or they haven't played before.
Speaker 1: We've never played Starfarers before, this is our first time ever.
Speaker 0: And I can describe Starfarers in just a very short, short sentence.
Speaker 0: "Pirates come and fuck you at every turn.
Speaker 0: The world consists of nothing but
Speaker 0: pirates.".
Speaker 1: Well, universe.
Speaker 1: Galaxy.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Basically, there are these cards, and you want these cards to get turned over.
Speaker 0: But it's always just pirates.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you turn over the card, and let's pretend that one of the cards is turned over, and I have to read the card to Rym.
Speaker 0: Alright, that means that the card is going to affect me, and he's just reading it, so I don't know how it works.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, every card is basically the sequence of logic.
Speaker 1: Like, you propose, you read what the card says, then the player makes a decision, and then you follow that path on the card based on the decision they made, and read the next thing, and eventually you arrive at a result of what happens in the game based on the player's decisions.
Speaker 0: Almost every one of them starts with, "You run afoul of space
Speaker 0: pirates.".
Speaker 1: Alright, you ready?
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: Alright, alright.
Speaker 1: Uh, okay Rym.
Speaker 1: I got the card here.
Speaker 1: You run afoul of space pirates.
Speaker 1: They demand tribute.
Speaker 1: Give them gold, give them three resource points to go away, or not?
Speaker 0: Uh, no.
Speaker 0: Fuck them.
Speaker 1: The space pirates attack you and take all your resource cards.
Speaker 0: Bastards.
Speaker 1: But gain one, uh, hero discy, fame disc.
Speaker 1: Because you stood up for, uh...
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, the cards are actually a really neat mechanic.
Speaker 0: It becomes broken when you've played the game enough to where you know all the cards, and you know how they all work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is, uh, it's sort of like this double-edged sword.
Speaker 1: On the one hand, the cards aren't very varied, because if, you know, if they were varied, they might be more interesting.
Speaker 1: Like, "Ooh, this is a different kind of card,
Speaker 1: hooray!".
Speaker 1: But at the same time, if they were all varied, then as soon as you heard the beginning of them, you'd know exactly what the card was if you had played before.
Speaker 1: So the fact that there are, like, ten cards that start with "Pirates,".
Speaker 1: you don't know which of the ten cards it is, so there's still your gambling when you make your decision.
Speaker 0: Now, the other interesting aspect of the game, aside from these cards, are the spaceships.
Speaker 1: The spaceships are awesome.
Speaker 0: These are probably the most enduring icon of this game.
Speaker 0: Every player gets a giant, well-designed plastic spaceship.
Speaker 0: The spaceship has places on it to stick various kinds of upgrades that you get throughout the game.
Speaker 0: In addition, the spaceship is filled with multi-colored balls, and when you shake the spaceship up and then put it down, two of those balls become visible, and that is how you roll.
Speaker 1: Yep, well, it's not how you roll the dice for resources, but it is how you roll to see how well your spaceship does every round.
Speaker 0: Yep, and just various tests in the game.
Speaker 0: It's also how cards appear.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's usually fighting against other players.
Speaker 0: Now, the basic game is just like any Settlers game.
Speaker 0: You start on some planets, you want to colonize more planets.
Speaker 0: Some planets have crap on them, you've got to get the crap off before you can put your guys there.
Speaker 1: I hate that, because it's like, you can get somewhere and colonize it, but it has this terrible, like, block on it, and you can't get the block off because you don't have enough other stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep, and of course, there's pirates about.
Speaker 1: Arrrrrrr.
Speaker 0: Now, honestly, even though the game is broken just like every other Catan game is, if you have a bunch of friends who like German board games and have never played Starfares of Catan before, it's well worth it to get them all together and play that game a few times.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of game where if you're at a convention or something and you see the game there, just pick, and you've never played it, pick it up and do it.
Speaker 1: But I wouldn't recommend you buy it, because it's kind of big and expensive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, convince someone else to buy it.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, that's a great idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Because they'll play it like one or two times, and then the bottom of the spaceship seems to break.
Speaker 1: Like, the little things that hold the boosters on seem to break, so you'd feel really bad if it was your spaceship's breaking, but if it's someone else's, who cares?
Speaker 0: Now, the one thing about the game is the way it's designed, it's very hard to run away with the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like in the original Settlers, plain old Settlers, you can frickin, if you build a couple cities and some settlements before other people do, or you go at just the right time and they keep rolling your number, you can just get 10 points and everyone else can't do anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this game basically has a lot of Mario Kart kind of elastics in there that'll hold a front player's back and back player's front, just a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I was doing pretty poorly, and then all of a sudden, who knows, I'm in second place, and then, uh, I didn't do so well, but...
Speaker 0: Yeah, and meanwhile, I was in last place for a while, but meanwhile, everyone's colonizing, I have craps, I just made a couple ships and I sent them off into the far reaches of space and forgot about them.
Speaker 0: Like, everyone was ignoring me because I was losing.
Speaker 0: And those ships eventually made it to the planets on the other side of the board, I colonized them, I got one victory point away from winning, then I sat there almost winning and failing over and over again until someone else won.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my problem was two of my ships during the game just, like, went to go colonize places, and then when they got there, couldn't actually colonize, or someone else, like, jumped right in front of me.
Speaker 1: So I ended up with these ships that were trying to do something, but for, like, I could have had, like, you know, four ships worth of stuff, but in the end I had two ships that didn't do anything because they couldn't get anywhere fast enough.
Speaker 0: The game also has a really cool alien science kind of thing where you can go off and talk to aliens, and you get victory points, and two, you get technology from them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like there are these, what, four or five alien spots on the board?
Speaker 0: Just things like, now your boosters are faster, or, etc.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you go to them and you trade goods with them, and I think there are five spots for each alien, and there are five cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and whoever has, you can control the aliens, whoever controls the aliens gets two extra victory points, kind of like longest road.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and each alien has a different kind of bonus, like, one of them has, like, bonuses to your ship, and one of them has bonuses to your resources, and one of them has, like, the cheating bonus.
Speaker 1: that kind of unbalances the game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So you just, you know, you try to trade with those aliens to get stuff, and whatever.
Speaker 0: But it was a fun game.
Speaker 0: If anything, it's in the old style of German board game, in that high production values, lots of little bits.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's more the family type of game than the hardcore type of game, I would say.
Speaker 0: Once again, like Scott said, it's a great game to get people into games like this at a con, or to get the creepy old guy with a lot of money to buy and then play it with him.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, this, if you got a family too, they'll love this, because they'll just love, anyone will love playing with the spaceships, no matter how hard the game itself actually is.
Speaker 0: And of course, it's a thousand times more intellectually stimulating than Monopoly or Life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Life.
Speaker 1: I heard the greatest quote about the game of Life on this board game podcast.
Speaker 1: He said, "The worst game in the world with the best spinner in the
Speaker 1: world.".
Speaker 0: Actually, my parents, when I was young, we used to play Life like once a month, like a thing.
Speaker 0: And all I remember is that I learned how to get exactly whatever number I wanted, no matter what with that spinner.
Speaker 1: Best spinner in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were none too pleased with that.
Speaker 1: We had to put graphite on our spinner to get it all lubricated and such.
Speaker 1: It was a nice trick.
Speaker 1: That thing was, they would literally fly, like, zzzzzzzzzzzzzz.
Speaker 1: It was great.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so, Galactic Civilizations 2.
Speaker 1: Well, I could talk a long time about this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't actually play it.
Speaker 1: All right, so, if you've ever played a Master of Orion space conquest game, this is another one of those.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 1: Um, it does a few things better than previous versions.
Speaker 1: Obviously, there's some updated graphics, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 1: New Alien Race is fancy looking spaceships, blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: All that good stuff.
Speaker 1: Is there a reason to play this instead of Master of Orion 2, besides the fact that it works more easily on modern computers?
Speaker 1: Yes and no.
Speaker 1: The first problem I had with this game was that I couldn't really figure out how it worked.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's because I don't have the manual.
Speaker 1: That, I think, had a lot to do with it.
Speaker 0: I wonder why you don't have the manual, Mr.
Speaker 0: Pirate McPirate?
Speaker 1: Uh, there was that story, they wanted everyone to pirate it.
Speaker 1: And I pirated it before- No, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: That was before I saw the story that said, "No, we actually
Speaker 1: don't.".
Speaker 0: Um, I think it was obvious because the people who wanted you to pirate were, in fact, Star Force.
Speaker 1: Oh, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: The hated evil of all the internet.
Speaker 1: Well, it doesn't matter because I deleted it now.
Speaker 1: I don't need to play this game anymore.
Speaker 0: So they still didn't get any money.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Which probably is fine if the game uses- So it didn't really matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if the game's as mediocre as you seem to say it was, then- Well, it's not that it's mediocre.
Speaker 1: It's a really good space conquest game, if you really like space conquest games.
Speaker 1: The problem, I think, is in me that I can't deal with the tedium of micromanagement anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I've had this problem, like I've mentioned, I've been playing Civ 2 a lot lately.
Speaker 0: Just because I love that old game.
Speaker 0: And I can't, like, it's actually painful to play on anything other than the smallest map.
Speaker 0: Because with the small map, you know, I expand.
Speaker 0: And then everyone expands.
Speaker 0: And then there's just a game of, you know, manage my little civilization.
Speaker 0: On the large maps, it's the game of, there's a giant island over there.
Speaker 0: And no one knows it's there but me.
Speaker 0: All I'd have to do is put settlers on it and send it over there and colonize the whole island and- But in order to do that, you have to push so many buttons.
Speaker 0: It's just like, fuck it, I'll let the Aztecs have that island, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it to me.
Speaker 1: I don't want to push all the buttons necessary in order to get that island.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep.
Speaker 1: Even though I could.
Speaker 1: It's like, I could win, I just don't want to push the button to make me win.
Speaker 1: Because I'd have to push it so many times.
Speaker 0: But yet you don't want the game to just have a win button because then it's not fun.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, like every other civilization type game, basically what you're doing when you play is you're controlling a bunch of sliders.
Speaker 1: And there's like sliders for each planet, sliders for the whole civilization, sliders for spaceships, and they all affect each other.
Speaker 1: But it's kind of hard to tell how.
Speaker 1: Like sometimes it's obvious, like, oh, if I do this, then that will happen.
Speaker 1: But sometimes it's like, alright, how does this affect the big picture from down here on this little old planet?
Speaker 0: Is there anything in it like the civilopedia that tells you exactly what everything does?
Speaker 1: Oh, there's text on every single thing in the game to tell you what it does.
Speaker 0: Did you read it?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But sometimes it's not, uh, like you can tell, okay, this will increase my manufacturing by two.
Speaker 1: How much is two, you know?
Speaker 1: It's like, um, will that build it this much faster?
Speaker 1: Will it, would it be faster to just build something before the factory?
Speaker 1: And you have to end up doing all this annoying math.
Speaker 1: And you get like all these different numbers all over the place.
Speaker 1: And it's like they made it lighter than something like Master of Orion 2 or 3, which is pretty heavy, but they didn't make it light enough as to where it's like.
Speaker 1: really just an abstract game.
Speaker 1: The other problem I have is there are three winning conditions.
Speaker 1: There's the research winning condition, the military, and the cultural one.
Speaker 1: The cultural one is the one I like to go for, because all you really have to do is build a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: You know, you just build like, uh, all these entertainment facilities, and then your borders just slowly expand without you having to do anything.
Speaker 1: All you do is have planets and build stuff on them and keep building stuff.
Speaker 1: And eventually you'll just conquer the galaxy without doing anything, except building.
Speaker 1: If you want to do the research one, well it's pretty similar.
Speaker 1: You just have to go around and micromanage all your planets to maximize research, and then just keep researching until you win.
Speaker 1: And you want to trade a lot of research if you do that also.
Speaker 1: The military one, see this is the one that's always a problem, is the.
Speaker 1: the fun way to play is military, because you fly spaceships at each other and they shoot.
Speaker 1: I actually didn't experience combat once.
Speaker 1: Not once.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: No matter how peaceful a game I ever try to play in Civ 2, it always ends up with like, the Zulus coming in with tanks.
Speaker 1: Well you see, I always researched the technologies that added to my diplomacy, and I gave myself a diplomacy bonus when I customized my race.
Speaker 1: So because I'm playing against the computer, they'll do whatever I say.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I can see this being a problem in multiplayer, because diplomacy points don't mean shit, and there's so many buildings- You know what happened?
Speaker 0: Rym's tanks would come in.
Speaker 1: There's so many buildings that just, and stuff in the game that gives you diplomacy points, that, you know, it's such a key part of the strategy, that the multiplayer I think would just break it, unless they like, maybe you could use diplomacy points to force other people's hands.
Speaker 0: Well I mean, I just use Civ 2 because I consider it one of the best games of this type ever.
Speaker 0: And because I haven't played Civ 4, which people have said is better, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: But in that game, even in the multiplayer, like say you have the Great Wall, or some sort of high diplomacy, the game would actually force other people to offer peace, or a ceasefire, or things like that.
Speaker 0: It would force their hand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Shoukei, a guy agrees to peace.
Speaker 1: He can still break the peace and shoot you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless the game decides to not let him do that for X turns, or has penalties for doing so.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Maybe your government gets overthrown, maybe some aliens appear and kill you, I don't know.
Speaker 1: That is one thing I really liked in this game, is once you get past the initial stages, you get to Republic and Democratic type of governments, and what'll happen is every turn is a week, right, in game time.
Speaker 1: Every so often, there'll be an election, and you'll actually see, you know, if you don't have enough influence, which is one of the sliders that you can't control directly, you just build things to increase influence, if you don't have enough influence over your people, then you'll get voted out of your government, and you can see they'll actually do an election with a picture of a parliament or whatever, and the voting, and what percent of the voting you got.
Speaker 0: What happens if you get voted out?
Speaker 0: Do you just overthrow the government and come back, or what?
Speaker 1: Actually, what I think happens is if you are voted favorably, you get a bonus.
Speaker 1: Like, I was always voted favorably.
Speaker 1: I had the majority party, like, all the time, so I got a plus 20 to my economic bonus.
Speaker 1: If I would have been voted down, I would have had, like, a minus 20.
Speaker 0: Wait, so all we'd have to do if we lived in that world is always vote for whoever's in office, and then the economy's just booming?
Speaker 1: Yes, but the problem is that, from a game perspective, it's if you want to be a democracy, you have the chance to get a bonus if you keep your influence up.
Speaker 1: If you don't pick democracy, you can forget influence, but other people might be getting a bonus.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand, if you choose democracy and don't keep the influence up, you're gonna get a minus.
Speaker 0: Huh.
Speaker 1: There are other cool things that happen, like, a lot of games have random events, like, this happened, you know, what do you do?
Speaker 1: Or it's like, this happened, your people die.
Speaker 1: In this game, it's this happened, and it gives you three choices.
Speaker 1: The three choices are usually, like, evil, good, and yin yang, you know, and they'll have different effects.
Speaker 1: Like, your people are protesting, what do you do?
Speaker 1: Shoot them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, freedom of speech, well, then you're gonna have, you know, this effect.
Speaker 1: Uh, yin yang, no effect.
Speaker 1: Or, uh, evil, you shoot them.
Speaker 1: And then there's another effect for that.
Speaker 0: Ha ha.
Speaker 1: But, like, if you do the evil thing, the evil thing, like, might increase research, but at the same time, the people won't like you, and you'll lose influence.
Speaker 1: That sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Huh.
Speaker 1: And the third thing is, every once in a while, every single race in the galaxy will meet and vote on some sort of galactic law.
Speaker 0: I always thought this was a really cool part of the game from what Scott was telling me earlier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, every so often, it'll say, "Next week, the galactic whatever
Speaker 1: meets."
Speaker 1: I forget what it's called.
Speaker 1: And you'll see every alien race, and everyone gets votes based on population, so if you have the biggest population in the galaxy, you're gonna have the most votes.
Speaker 1: And, like, we're talking tens of thousands of votes here.
Speaker 0: Now, can you choose to ignore, uh, intergalactic law?
Speaker 1: Uh, I don't know, 'cause I never really ran into any of these laws.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: But there will be something such as, you know, uh, transports are very vulnerable in this war-ridden galaxy.
Speaker 1: Currently, the law says you can't have any guns on transport ships.
Speaker 1: These are ships that carry goods and services, you know, on the trade routes.
Speaker 1: It'll be like, "Should we allow guns on transport ships, and if so, how
Speaker 1: many?".
Speaker 1: And you'll have like four choices, like zero, one, three, and five.
Speaker 1: And then you choose.
Speaker 1: And then whatever the races of the galaxy decide will become law.
Speaker 1: And this happens, and the law will last for like x years.
Speaker 1: Or, it'll say how long the law will last.
Speaker 1: Sometimes the laws are permanent, sometimes they're a year, sometimes they're two years, who knows.
Speaker 0: Huh.
Speaker 1: And it's kinda interesting, because it's like the rules of the game change game to game, you know, it's like, there are only so many trade routes you can make to other, uh, you know, it's like, trade routes are kinda like caravans in Civ 2, only you can't keep sending them.
Speaker 1: It's like, you create a trade route, physically, you can see the routes on the map, they're colored lines, going from planet to planet, and, you know, they just constantly create money for you, but you can only have so many of them.
Speaker 1: But, how many you can have depends on a lot of factors.
Speaker 1: So it's like, I tried to build as many as I can just to have lots of money, and then I used the money to just buy stuff, instead of building it.
Speaker 1: 'Cause I wanted to get the game over with.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It seemed to work.
Speaker 1: But, basically the game is, if you wanna play a space civilization game, this is the one right now.
Speaker 1: But, I still kinda like Master of Orion 2 better.
Speaker 1: Also, I haven't played the combat in this, but the feeling I'm getting is that, if you want to do the military, you have to micromanage to all hell, and customize little spaceships, and all kinds of crazy shit.
Speaker 0: Man, that would be awesome.
Speaker 0: You know, 15 years ago when I had free time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, um, basically if you like space civilization games, I don't think you can afford to miss this if you, but if you're just kinda casual, you probably shouldn't play space civilization games at all.
Speaker 1: Or if you do, play one that's a little more abstract and easier.
Speaker 0: I can't think of any.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: If any.
Speaker 1: Star Control, but Star Control is a slightly different kind of game.
Speaker 1: It's more like a space adventure game, even though you do build colonies and such.
Speaker 0: So, that's pretty much it for today, but I'd like to say that way back, well not way back, but when we went to UberCon where we talked up Burning Wheel, and we said we'd do an episode sometime in the future, and, you know, interviews with maybe Luke Crane and all that sort of thing, and we haven't done that yet, but I'll just tell you all who may be wondering that we're all making characters and reading the books, and playing around with Burning Wheel to make sure we know it, and we'll probably do an episode on it real soon, the next time we have all our friends over, we're gonna try to run a one-off of the game on our own.
Speaker 1: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: Without help from the Luke-ski.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see how much that works.
Speaker 0: We'll see if we can do it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It might take like a tag team effort.
Speaker 0: It might.
Speaker 0: And that was Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com, and if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows, it's actually recorded at night.