Speaker 0: It's Thursday April 20th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We're going to tell you how to get a job.
Speaker 1: Let's do this, so I'm still not doing work at work, and they continue to pay me.
Speaker 0: and yeah What are you gonna?
Speaker 0: Do if they start listening to geek nights?
Speaker 1: I don't think they'll ever find it and if they do I'll just quit.
Speaker 0: well I got to say my co-workers all found it and they listened to it once.
Speaker 0: they couldn't believe I do something like that And I think they all forgot about it.
Speaker 0: That's good Yeah, especially considering.
Speaker 1: I'm quitting and yesterday you insulted them.
Speaker 1: Yes I did quite uh profoundly and I insulted them, and I didn't even know them.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well you met one of them once.
Speaker 1: yeah great But yeah today since there was still no work.
Speaker 1: I Did some learning of Ruby on Rails.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm gonna make some Web-based board games cuz I'm not gonna work for them.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna work for me.
Speaker 1: damn it.
Speaker 1: So you know if I don't start getting work in the next few months you should start seeing a cool thing I'm gonna make and I'm simultaneously learning all this Ruby on Rails Ajax crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the most exciting thing.
Speaker 0: I did today was watch some Futurama Whoa That's pretty low.
Speaker 0: well and do a show and I guess pack for Tarkan.
Speaker 0: I got to put all the audio equipment away as soon as we're done recording tonight.
Speaker 1: Yeah already packed.
Speaker 1: Well at least I have a pile of clothes in the middle of my room But I just had to stick them in the bag.
Speaker 1: That's good enough.
Speaker 0: So we got some news right.
Speaker 1: yep, so there was a hubbub on dig today And I don't know if anyone noticed But it was pretty big.
Speaker 0: this hubbub even though it wasn't actually big on dig it was big on every other site on the internet.
Speaker 1: Well, that's part of what the hubbub is yep.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the dig editors were thinking.
Speaker 1: I mean everyone read it all right, so Apparently I'm just gonna get.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna give the specifics because those aren't really too interesting and you give the general idea.
Speaker 1: The way dig works is you anyone can submit as many stories as they want and then if you like a story you click Dig and and there's a number attached to the story that goes up by one and if the number gets high enough Then it'll be easier for people to find it and if the number gets high enough it gets out of the front page And then once it's on the front page It usually gets a hajillion digs, and then whatever
Speaker 0: think slashdot only with much more democracy and thus much less control or I don't know Insightfulness in many cases.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it has its good points, and it's bad points kind of like Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: and The way to get rid of a story is if a story is bad You can report it and you could report stories as inaccurate.
Speaker 1: you can report stories as lame.
Speaker 1: you can report stories as old.
Speaker 1: There's all kinds of things right.
Speaker 1: I said if a story gets reported too much Then they'll bury it and that basically no matter how many digs it has they'll just bury it to the bottom.
Speaker 1: now There have been some stories recently that say bad things about dig.
Speaker 1: so Apparently these stories aren't making it up dig.
Speaker 0: well they are making it up dig until they are noticed and then they're buried.
Speaker 1: yeah, and Also, it seems that certain stories like this guy noticed that there were two stories on the front page and They were both submitted by the same guy.
Speaker 1: now You know either this guy is really good at finding news or really good at writing headlines or something.
Speaker 1: But he noticed something strange about these two stories submitted by the same guy first off.
Speaker 1: They're submitted Very close to each other time wise.
Speaker 1: so he submitted them all you know.
Speaker 1: like he submitted one then we submit the other one and Then on the front page there in fact.
Speaker 1: There's only one story between these two stories.
Speaker 1: that what you know.
Speaker 1: and He looked at the first.
Speaker 1: you can see who digged it in what order who dug it in what order and all that.
Speaker 1: And he noticed that like the first 17 digs on both of these stories now 17 digs isn't enough to get into the front page.
Speaker 1: But if a story has it's sort of like this momentum stories have like their stories either stay at like single digit digs or Some stories like make it to like 10 or 11.
Speaker 0: The more dig something has the more likely it is to get done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically just it's like people vote for someone who's gonna win.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, it has all the same problems that the United States democracy has.
Speaker 1: But so when a story gets like 17 digs It's very likely to just keep getting digs and digs and digs and digs and then become on the front page The first 17 digs on both of these stories submitted by the same guy 16 of the people Were than the first 17 digs of both stories in the same order.
Speaker 1: One of those guys is the head dig dude who dug it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's enough to make everyone go.
Speaker 0: Now that itself isn't really the story.
Speaker 1: No It's not so the story.
Speaker 0: similar things happen on slash dot where it's obvious that the moderators do a little bit But I'll roll in big pain.
Speaker 1: All right, so here's the story.
Speaker 1: The guy wrote a blog post and his blog about the first 17 digs on both of these posts being the same.
Speaker 1: someone else Submitted that story to ding and then it you know got kicked off It got buried after it got a bunch of digs and then that guy's site his blog got banned from digs.
Speaker 1: So if anyone tried to submit a story from his site, it wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: now enter the bloggers fear.
Speaker 1: So a guy immediately writes a thing in his blog about it and tries to dig it and they try to dig this guy's story and then another guy Writes a blog entry links to the one that's banned and tries to dig that and then at the end of the day there was like a recap story on someone's blog and that got dug and it just Exploded.
Speaker 0: and then as it became apparent that the people in charge of dig were for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: well for very obvious reasons Blocking this it hit every other side in the world most notably slash Don's on.
Speaker 1: slash don't come going boring.
Speaker 0: slash dot is the main competitor today goes on everywhere Everywhere.
Speaker 0: It's obvious that the dig editors have some sort of evil way of manipulating things just like the slash dot editors Technically have unlimited mod points.
Speaker 1: Yeah It just shows that dig isn't really a hundred percent pure Democracy as it tries to pretend to be now wouldn't be a problem if they said that it wasn't.
Speaker 1: you know The problem is the way they put it off like on the dig website.
Speaker 1: It says dig is unlike other sites.
Speaker 1: the users choose the content not the editors.
Speaker 0: Well It seems that you know the editors really are sort of indirectly to not only that but I mean it's fine to do those shady Kinds of things but they were caught.
Speaker 0: they were very obviously caught by someone who can verify the fact they were caught and The fact that their immediate response is to do everything in their power to hide this information is laughable.
Speaker 0: Like I've lost significant respect for the people who run dig.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we'll hear I'm gonna hear them be interviewed about this on some podcast this week for sure.
Speaker 0: if they'll even talk Maybe they'll just get all freaky now because every time there was criticism about dig before the guy always talked What could they say other than yeah, we were stupid.
Speaker 1: I don't know but we're gonna find out.
Speaker 0: there's really nothing they can say.
Speaker 1: We'll see what they say.
Speaker 1: They probably say something like we didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: It was reported a whole bunch of times and if a site gets reported a bunch of times then we block it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever We'll see.
Speaker 1: But it yeah, it seems like.
Speaker 1: because what you can do on dig is you can see you can watch what one person is digging.
Speaker 1: So if you're really popular and a lot of people look at what you dig then if you dig something once Then that's like you can vote with a whole bunch of digs because all the people watching you and caring about what you dig will Dig it also.
Speaker 1: So that's sort of what happens is the editors are so popular on their own site that when they dig something it gets a hajillion Digs kind of like when John Carmack post something on slashdot.
Speaker 1: He gets plus five.
Speaker 0: You know, yep, of course his plus fives are always fully legitimate.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz he he doesn't seem to post on slash that unless he has something to say and it's usually about his own stuff.
Speaker 0: So yeah, of course, he's not quite the expert on the gaming industry that summer Gupta is.
Speaker 0: no We still haven't done our whole show on summer Gupta.
Speaker 1: we could make this show the show on summer Gupta.
Speaker 0: Let's not do that because I don't have all the research handy I want to go through like the Usenet post from the 80s from summer Gupta.
Speaker 0: All right, he's been around for a long time.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz he worked for you know, Nintendo and Sega and Sony and Microsoft and Nokia and God Jesus Buddha.
Speaker 0: I believe he worked for IBM in the United States military at one point Wow.
Speaker 0: He was a scientist at Oxford Yale Cambridge 300 years old.
Speaker 1: or did he work at each of those companies for one minute until they fired him?
Speaker 0: Obviously, he's some sort of immortal possibly a vampire.
Speaker 1: Oh I'll have to get my holy waters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, watch out.
Speaker 0: Eventually.
Speaker 0: He's gonna have to go back to Dracula's castle.
Speaker 0: I'll get some blood.
Speaker 1: maybe maybe not who knows anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway, so in other news I don't know if many of you are aware of palladium books, but they are the people who put out rifts and rift world and Basically, if you ever go into a gaming store, you know, there's the D&D section Maybe the board game section all the different sections and there's always that wall or that giant shelf full of a million rifts books.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, there's all kinds of different RPGs.
Speaker 1: there's like gurps and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But yeah rifts is like the the I don't know bastard stepchild or something.
Speaker 0: Well there I mean they're so big like there's always a giant section at any reasonable gaming store.
Speaker 0: And the thing is I'd never actually seen anyone so much as touch one of those books.
Speaker 1: I was slightly interested in playing them at some point because I there's always cool robots on the cover and they look sort and I Think there was even like a rifts robo tech at one point.
Speaker 0: I'll say this now because I've known people I've met people who actually have played rifts a little bit and I know a bit I've never actually played it.
Speaker 0: It is probably one of the worst most poorly conceived gaming systems I've ever imagined.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: The the way it was described actually fairly succinctly by someone else on slashdot When the story I'm about to talk about was posted where he basically said, you know When you were 14 and you rewrote the rules to Dungeons & Dragons and you thought you were some sort of visionary
Speaker 1: Gee, who do I know like that?
Speaker 0: Well That's what rifts is.
Speaker 0: rifts is horribly complex.
Speaker 0: The rules are not terribly self-consistent.
Speaker 0: There's a million books.
Speaker 0: I could go on and on about the system.
Speaker 1: So I didn't even think the company that made wrists is still around.
Speaker 1: I thought that they just kept selling old rifts books.
Speaker 1: because see I actually thought the same thing because I never seen a new rifts Book.
Speaker 1: the ones I always see in stores are like these really old ones and there's a whole bunch of them.
Speaker 0: well, apparently not only were they still in business, but they're shortly not going to be in business anymore and The reasons they're not going to be in business are either Farcical lies or hilarious or any combination of those three?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's hard to tell at this point.
Speaker 0: Now the one thing I do know is that they hadn't been doing so well for a while Despite what people say.
Speaker 0: the people who basically are two types people in the world people who love Palladium games and books and love rifts and thus will they have nothing but good to say about it and people who have never heard Of it and don't care.
Speaker 0: So whenever you read anything about palladium or rifts, it's always.
Speaker 0: oh, it's awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh only the awesome elite masters of gaming play rifts.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's such an intricate world.
Speaker 1: Isn't that what anyone thinks about whatever gaming system they play?
Speaker 1: I mean, oh only the elite masters play burning wheel.
Speaker 1: Well, the elite masters play curbs.
Speaker 0: So worst thing about rifts is that the system is kind of bad and the people who love it I'll always say things like yeah character creation takes eight hours and it's hellishly complex But that makes it good.
Speaker 0: It forces you to think about your character.
Speaker 0: You have to do research and shit Great and all sorts of God.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into the system because it's not a show about rifts It's a show about the news.
Speaker 0: So the news is they're basically going bankrupt to the point that the dude the rifts dude is basically begging all of his fans to buy $50 prints that probably aren't worth $50.
Speaker 0: so we can get enough money to pay off some debt and not go out of business.
Speaker 0: Now the main reason they're going out of business aside from the fact that I have never met anyone I like to played rifts for any reasonable span of time.
Speaker 1: I never met anyone I knew played rifts.
Speaker 0: few people at our wag had the books.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they did how our wag owned most of the books.
Speaker 1: They did they.
Speaker 0: I don't know if anyone used him anymore.
Speaker 1: I never seen anyone play it.
Speaker 1: I never knew anyone who was playing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you you all out there for Scott's ranch about the comic industry in America And the fact that they only exist in order to sell products to people who are already fans.
Speaker 0: Yep Rifts is a lot like that.
Speaker 1: It's exactly like that.
Speaker 0: Yes, and the people who play rifts keep playing rifts.
Speaker 0: well, the other reason that palladium wasn't doing so well and I swear this is not a joke the thing that they invested their money into and that they thought was going to save their company And revolutionize everything give them a pile of money Was a rifts game for the fucking engage.
Speaker 1: Yeah They apparently had a deal with Nokia and to make an engage game based on rifts and not not a computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they expected to get a bunch of royalties for it and stuff.
Speaker 0: now I submit that.
Speaker 0: now they say like oh, it's not Nokia's fault They did their best and it's not our fault.
Speaker 0: the the system just didn't succeed.
Speaker 0: and that sort of thing happens.
Speaker 1: No, you were stupid and you invested in the engage.
Speaker 1: No New is gonna suck.
Speaker 0: no one in the world except Nokia themselves thought that the engage was going to do.
Speaker 0: Well, no one.
Speaker 1: Well, apparently palladium did they.
Speaker 0: yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: There's two people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you don't know anything about video games.
Speaker 1: If you don't know anything about video games to the point where you think the engage is gonna succeed I knew the engage is gonna succeed as it was gonna fail as soon as someone said it existed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard about it and I thought that's probably going to fail Yep.
Speaker 0: and then I saw it and I thought that's Definitely going to fail.
Speaker 0: and then I saw the hype for it and I thought and then I knew that I was right when side Talking came out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That wasn't even the death knell for me.
Speaker 0: The death knell for me was when it actually came out and I didn't actually notice for months.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I didn't realize like it always I noticed because of side talking I'd heard.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's coming It's coming.
Speaker 0: and I thought oh, it's gonna fail.
Speaker 0: It's gonna fail.
Speaker 0: and then one day I saw it failed and I thought what it came out And sure enough it had come out.
Speaker 1: in fact, I remember the side talking I remember the side talking but that's how I remembered when it came out is because I didn't know it came out But I knew I saw people starting to make fun of it.
Speaker 0: But yeah The Palladium Games people invested their money in a game for the engage and when it failed they lost a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Well, you see here's the thing is that that makes a lot of sense and the guy even admits like yeah You know, we tried to make an engage game and it fell through.
Speaker 1: so that didn't go.
Speaker 0: well Here's where it gets interesting the guy himself.
Speaker 0: I forget his name It's hard to pronounce but I saw him once at a convention a long long time ago, and I don't know the dude.
Speaker 0: So what I'm about to say is definitely hearsay.
Speaker 0: But I've never met a single person on this earth who has a high opinion of that man.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm He is about as respected as Steve Bennett is in the anime industry.
Speaker 0: So he's respected by the people who love his stuff and hated by everyone else kind of like that Harlan guy Whoever he is the penny arcade kind of owned a while ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah the sci-fi I think.
Speaker 0: yeah I actually never heard that guy didn't know anything about him until penny arcade made fun of him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I knew his name and I knew he was a sci-fi writer.
Speaker 1: That's all I knew but I couldn't tell you one single story He wrote.
Speaker 1: and then when penny arcade made fun of him I went to check it out and I didn't recognize any of his stories at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a big deal is.
Speaker 0: it was funny like he thought he was famous.
Speaker 0: But now penny arcade has more hits per day than I think.
Speaker 0: if anyone has ever read of his fan.
Speaker 1: Penny arcade made a shit podcast and they just finally made a feed and they jumped to number 12 on iTunes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's 12 out of all the podcast.
Speaker 1: if Harlan Ellison made a podcast where he read his books I think I think geek nights would be more popular than that.
Speaker 0: I think so But suffice to say I made a comment on slash dot about this story.
Speaker 0: You can see my comment.
Speaker 0: It's modded minus one flame bait.
Speaker 1: awesome.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: All I said was I've never seen anyone buy a rifts book.
Speaker 0: How are they in business?
Speaker 0: Anyway, this was And the responses I got were from the same kinds of people who are apologists for American comic books.
Speaker 0: They basically said things like like what I just said.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, the system's complicated, but blah blah blah or You don't understand.
Speaker 0: I own all the books and I'm a fan.
Speaker 0: So, yeah Palladium books is going out of business and all I have to say about that is it's about fucking time.
Speaker 0: I thought you were out of business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and apparently the guy in charge says that the even does.
Speaker 1: you know that the engage and all that other stuff isn't you know?
Speaker 1: That stuff was bad.
Speaker 1: But the real reason he's bankrupt is because there was some sort of Embezzlement theft thing he can't talk about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he says it was like almost a million dollars.
Speaker 0: I couldn't believe that they ever had a million dollars.
Speaker 1: He had a million dollars.
Speaker 1: Why was he still making shitty rifts books?
Speaker 0: He had a million dollars.
Speaker 0: Why wasn't he making better rifts books?
Speaker 1: Yeah, hire some real good people who know how to make books.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just don't.
Speaker 0: If anyone out there is a fan of rifts send us some audio feedback.
Speaker 0: I'm really curious how anyone could like such a terrible system for any reason.
Speaker 1: the only reason I could see Someone liking that is the only reason I could possibly like it is the robots.
Speaker 0: other than that the robots are kind of terrible.
Speaker 1: They look cool on the cover of the books.
Speaker 1: if you want just going by the pictures on the covers of the book.
Speaker 0: if you want robots you're better off playing a mech warrior or Possibly Bezum.
Speaker 0: the Bezum has a decent giant robot system.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should play that sometime.
Speaker 1: We can play the d20 Bezum, we should play a Bezum super sentai whatever combining robot team.
Speaker 1: Ooh Yeah, that'd be fun.
Speaker 0: So things of the day now as since I work for IBM I work with a lot of Indians and many of them lived in India grew up in India not Native Americans.
Speaker 1: Indians Yes Indians from India Now like a poof.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 1: Come again.
Speaker 0: Now the one thing that they've all pretty much unanimously said, I mean they generally like India and they're very they like America.
Speaker 0: They like India too.
Speaker 0: No, it's not like they're apologetic or anything about anything of either of the countries but every one of them has unabashedly expressed that driving in India is crazy Like there are no lights or rules and everything just kind of goes.
Speaker 1: It seemed to be like a lot of countries other than like, you know real westernized countries like, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like like, you know, mister like, you know.
Speaker 1: It seems to me like all the non westernized countries of the non heavily westernized countries Also do not have strict traffic like well central South America mix pretty much Mexico down doesn't have strict traffic.
Speaker 1: and You know east of Germany, I guess I'm not really sure about that.
Speaker 0: But Russia actually has fairly evolved traffic.
Speaker 1: Russia has pretty evolved.
Speaker 0: The only difference is the fact that there's a lot of open land in Russia.
Speaker 1: Yeah, China I don't think has I think near the cities.
Speaker 1: The traffic is pretty good, but elsewhere I don't know.
Speaker 0: All I know is there's now a video on the internet of a typical intersection in India and All I have to say is that if you saw a similar scene in America hundreds would be dead.
Speaker 1: Well, it's just because people in America can't deal with it.
Speaker 0: but it's it's like Americans are so used to their perfectly regimented traffic system that if anything goes wrong if anything is out of the ordinary There's immediately an accident and a clusterfuck.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean just today there was like a tiny little fire on the side of the road like off the road in the grass Mm-hmm, both Scott and I were backed up for like 20 minutes half-hour cuz just gawkers little rubbernecking.
Speaker 0: Yeah But like if a traffic, I mean there's a big power outage in New York a few years ago like power.
Speaker 0: You all know this power went out and basically Northeast America for many days or these us?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Northeast America includes like Nova Scotia and shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but parts of Canada went down too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay fine and Actually was funny because I remember I called Scott on my cell phone from work because my cell phone still worked Yep, and I said the power is out I'm going home and he said the power is out here too and he was in Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And then I thought oh, I Also thought oh, I have all the whole bunch of stories about the power outage.
Speaker 0: I was actually out directing traffic during it.
Speaker 0: the thing is it took me over an hour to drive home because People couldn't deal with the fact that there were no traffic lights, even though there wasn't that much traffic.
Speaker 0: It's just that people don't seem to remember that if the traffic light doesn't work every intersection is a four-way stop.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's it.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: What's so hard about that?
Speaker 1: Of course in India?
Speaker 1: It's a four-way go.
Speaker 0: the thing is everyone's going constantly and people just kind of maneuver around each other and no one got hit despite the fact that Literally, I couldn't imagine anyone doing anything anything like that in America without just death.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what it is is in America is because the system is so regimented.
Speaker 1: You just kind of put it into reflex memory in your brain and you don't have to think about it.
Speaker 1: You don't have to consciously drive.
Speaker 1: you just sit behind the wheel and you become this machine of driving.
Speaker 0: Yep, which I think is very good things.
Speaker 1: It does have its advantages and disadvantages.
Speaker 0: It's a good thing that that's possible because on long trips or if you're driving long distances It's very good to be able to take some of your attention away from the road.
Speaker 1: That is also true.
Speaker 1: Is that in America you're gonna take a lot of long trips somewhere like Europe not so much.
Speaker 1: You're gonna take a train for a long trip and most of your driving is busy city driving, which should be conscious.
Speaker 0: Yeah to me the problem isn't that the our road system is set up to where it can be done semi-subconsciously.
Speaker 0: The problem is that many people don't know how to drive actively and consciously at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like when the system is, you know broken.
Speaker 1: somehow people can't return to conscious driving.
Speaker 1: They don't have the skills of conscious and reflex driving.
Speaker 0: They only have reflex driving like if there's a car parked block kind of blocking the lane of traffic.
Speaker 0: Most people don't seem to realize that you just can kind of edge over in your lane a little bit and get around it.
Speaker 0: Yep, instead.
Speaker 0: They'll give it like a 10-foot berth and cause a huge giant mess.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but it seems like in India and other countries where traffic isn't so strict and military precision That people seem to drive consciously and you know, they look out and they avoid each other.
Speaker 1: and you know There's some countries where people is bumping into each other all over the place and just go hey you bumped into me.
Speaker 1: You know, it's just a different thing and it works differently.
Speaker 1: That's not better or worse a wager.
Speaker 0: It's a lot less efficient.
Speaker 0: I mean, there are a lot more cars in America and long trips and cars are really our only major means of transportation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we're lucky.
Speaker 0: we live down by New York City where there's trains and buses and all sorts of fun things.
Speaker 0: But I mean when I grew up in Michigan, I'd never seen a train that wasn't at an amusement park.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw a freight train like once in Ohio and there were no trains.
Speaker 0: We had trains.
Speaker 1: Oh So, um, I got a thing of the day that's actually kind of old.
Speaker 1: It's like from a week or so ago, but I wasn't here and then other better things of the day came along.
Speaker 0: You're doing a Thundercats thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't believe you're doing that.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: Cuz it feels old to me.
Speaker 0: We've watched it already.
Speaker 1: I know isn't it?
Speaker 1: But there's some people who might not have seen it.
Speaker 1: So Thundercats possibly thunder Thundercats.
Speaker 1: Oh Possibly one of the best 80s kids shows.
Speaker 0: give him grant me sight beyond sight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a great way.
Speaker 1: There are so many things I could say about Thundercats like if I do a Thundercats show But we will do a Thundercats show great once we get the DVDs.
Speaker 1: Yes season two of DVDs just came out actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah season one is in my Netflix queue.
Speaker 1: Well at season two It just came out.
Speaker 0: I will awesome.
Speaker 1: So Some guys got together.
Speaker 1: Remember that live-action Zelda movie kind of thingy that was a few minutes long those guys put together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if we made it a thing of the day or not.
Speaker 0: Anyway, link is real doofy in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so some guys got up and they they got really good Thundercats costumes like really good.
Speaker 1: You know Lionel has these leather hot pants, but other than that, yeah, like Lionel's hair is cost like professional cosplayer done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these people look like super anime cosplayers doing Thundercats the mum ross a little weak, but whatever.
Speaker 1: and They do this cool Trailery thing that looks like it could be a trailer for a real live-action Thundercats movie and it's really well done and pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean the CG is a little weak.
Speaker 0: But what do you expect?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the CG is equal in quality to the one for that fan-made Star Wars movie.
Speaker 1: that actually was a whole movie You can go watch on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I've heard it's good.
Speaker 0: I haven't actually watched it.
Speaker 1: I watched part of it and the problem I had is it looked.
Speaker 1: it's probably acting was real nerdy acting Better than episode 1 Possibly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it all definitely but the acting was really nerdy Like I'm in a role-playing game kind of acting.
Speaker 1: Oh and that kind of bothers me.
Speaker 1: But other than that, it seemed great like fear of girls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: but Yeah, this Thundercats thing.
Speaker 1: The only thing I can say bad about it.
Speaker 1: Is that Some of the fight choreography is a little bit weak.
Speaker 0: They picked the worst song.
Speaker 1: They picked the worst song.
Speaker 1: they picked the Sephiroth song.
Speaker 1: You know the song where they scream Sephiroth Sephiroth in the background Yeah, which would be an okay song if there wasn't people constantly going.
Speaker 1: Sephiroth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz now Sephiroth isn't here.
Speaker 1: You should have picked the song with no words.
Speaker 0: In fact, he's dead though, or maybe you should have like remixed the Thundercats theme like Or just use the extended version of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there you go or something.
Speaker 0: Pick some generic Latin chanting song that doesn't say Sephiroth over and over.
Speaker 1: Yeah At least change it to like "lion, no".
Speaker 1: "Tetsuo, Tetsuo" "Mumraa" "The ever-living" Ancient spirits of evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we get the idea.
Speaker 0: We could do a whole show on Thundercats.
Speaker 1: "Sword of Omens".
Speaker 1: So anyway, let us get beyond this part of the podcast.
Speaker 0: So we'll move on to the bit the main Thursday bit.
Speaker 1: What are we gonna do today?
Speaker 0: Well, we weren't sure until a little while ago and it's not a cop-out.
Speaker 0: You mean a few minutes ago?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not a cop-out.
Speaker 0: I mean we cop out.
Speaker 0: It's basically a tech news roundup Or a we rant about politics.
Speaker 0: But no, we decided because we're both kind of Doing this currently.
Speaker 0: It's how to look for, find, and secure a job Not a job.
Speaker 1: Well, we can actually cover all kinds of jobs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll just do it.
Speaker 1: Oh, these jobs that we know how to acquire.
Speaker 1: Don't ask me how to get a job doing like crazy stuff Like working for Blackwater.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know how to get that job.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you need on your resume to work for Blackwater.
Speaker 1: I can tell you how to get a computer job.
Speaker 1: I can tell you how to get a minimum wage Manual labor job.
Speaker 1: I can tell you how to get a job at a college to do while you're at school.
Speaker 1: Yep, I can tell you how to get any kind of job I've gotten.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though We got to kind of mitigate our our advice because I know a lot of people have had trouble finding jobs But we really haven't.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's because we have a lot of skills.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean I've never Really been want for having a job.
Speaker 1: People are still sending me job offers, and I haven't been on the job market in months.
Speaker 0: I still get job offers to my RIT email account.
Speaker 1: A year later people are sending me job offers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so anyway.
Speaker 0: I'll say it now to get it out of the way.
Speaker 0: Get a job.
Speaker 1: Yes, get a job.
Speaker 0: Azuzu.
Speaker 1: Okay, you haven't been to Pirate Universe.
Speaker 0: All right, so I guess we could give a little bit of background on the jobs We've had.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right, my first job ever.
Speaker 0: I actually never had a legitimate paid taxes on it job until after I graduated high school Mm-hmm at that point.
Speaker 0: I got a job for the United States federal government working on the 2000 census.
Speaker 0: I actually have a whole bunch of cool Memorabilia that I didn't swipe because when the census goes it goes it finishes it shuts down and you can just everyone takes everything.
Speaker 0: So I have all these highlighters and pens and balloons.
Speaker 0: they census 2000.
Speaker 0: It was actually a really fun job and for being in high school.
Speaker 0: It paid 11 bucks an hour, which was like crazy.
Speaker 1: My grandma worked for the census a long time ago, and it goes every 10 years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she did it in like the in the World Trade Center and everything is a little.
Speaker 0: but while it was still there Yeah, it was actually a really fun job.
Speaker 0: I was an HR clerk, so I did like payroll stuff and I hired and fired and all sorts of fun things.
Speaker 0: I Worked with mostly older housewives who were bored.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, and I was probably the youngest person anywhere in that frickin facility.
Speaker 1: Maybe when there's another census we can go work for.
Speaker 0: actually I was.
Speaker 0: I got a letter of recommendation from the guy Elmer Maui who I. he was really old.
Speaker 0: I wonder if he's still alive.
Speaker 0: It's been a long time.
Speaker 0: He was a cool dude though, and he basically told me yeah If you want to do the census in 2010 you can be like a regional manager or whatnot guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, then you can hire me to be the Regional computer.
Speaker 1: whatnot guy thing is.
Speaker 0: I don't think the census would pay more than I make currently.
Speaker 1: Well, no, can't you do the census and your normal job at the same time?
Speaker 0: No, the census was a 40-hour a week job.
Speaker 0: Oh, well now you could.
Speaker 0: you can do like the door-to-door census Which is like 10 hours a week and weekends and fun stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but no I did the full-on job job part Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Well, so all those people must be normally unemployed people at the census.
Speaker 0: either that or they're people who?
Speaker 0: You know, they're a housewife or a house husband or something like that Or they're in school.
Speaker 0: It's summer vacation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that makes sense.
Speaker 0: I mean it was before I went to college.
Speaker 0: it was my first job ever and I never applied for a job before.
Speaker 0: like I had no idea what to do.
Speaker 0: and I'll say this government jobs and jobs for big corporations like big corporations are very different from.
Speaker 0: I don't want to say real jobs But I guess more intimate jobs or more skilled jobs in that they'll often have a very standardized way of hiring you.
Speaker 0: They'll make you take a test or something Mm-hmm, and I had to take a test.
Speaker 0: It was probably the most inane test I've ever taken.
Speaker 0: It was 40 questions.
Speaker 0: I got a perfect score.
Speaker 0: I finished in 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: I turned it in.
Speaker 0: They called me the next day because I got the highest score out of anyone who had taken the test pretty much in the last month and There were people who failed the test meaning they got less than half the questions, right?
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: What was the word the question?
Speaker 0: They were like basic math.
Speaker 0: like Susie has 10 apples and she eats six of them and then loses one more.
Speaker 0: How many does she have left?
Speaker 0: Three or they were like a train is going 60 miles an hour.
Speaker 0: How long does it take to go 70 miles?
Speaker 1: An hour and a bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was multiple choice and you had an hour.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the it was partly people who were bored and partly the dregs of society.
Speaker 0: Half the people who got hired went to the trainings.
Speaker 0: you got paid the 11 bucks an hour for the training and then they'd never Show up again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they'd collect their money.
Speaker 0: Just never come back Huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Figured you would actually do the job.
Speaker 1: The job is probably better than the training.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess they're stupid.
Speaker 0: The job was fun.
Speaker 1: All right, so Is that the only job you had?
Speaker 0: I had a whole bunch of jobs.
Speaker 0: I guess you can do one All right.
Speaker 1: So my first job.
Speaker 1: Well, the first real job was working at a dry cleaner doing boring manual labor after after school a few days a week.
Speaker 1: Wow, and I got enough money there to buy a computer and That was cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I pretty much made in a few weeks over the summer before I went to RIT the money I needed to buy my computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's see.
Speaker 1: How did I get the job?
Speaker 1: I went into the.
Speaker 1: I went around town to all the like any place that had a Wanted, you know sign and I went around the mall to different places and it's filled out application forms.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the one thing I remember that when I was looking for like temporary or non-skilled or I'm a punk kid jobs You could just like look in the newspapers or go to places When you're looking for a not a career but like a part-time job.
Speaker 1: All you do is go to somewhere and fill out an application and then if they're interested they call you Yeah, even a career.
Speaker 0: often if it's not a technical career You'll just find like an ad in a newspaper sign up and then you'll get a career.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: so I went around signing up and the dry cleaner called me back and I went there and I basically Made sure that shirts didn't get lost in the laundry for a year or so.
Speaker 1: Wow and kind of money.
Speaker 0: Did you make?
Speaker 1: Pretty good money minimum wage plus a bit which when you're in high school and you have no expenses at all Yeah, it comes out to plenty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the saddest thing in the world is I made like 11 bucks an hour doing the census in 2000.
Speaker 0: I Never made more money than that again until I got hired by IBM.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I made like seven bucks an hour at our IT and then I made like eight when I became an awesome employee.
Speaker 1: I also worked like two or three places as a three different camps at different times as a camp counselor in different situations.
Speaker 1: and The thing about a camp counselor job is it's real easy to get one.
Speaker 1: But if you don't do a good job They don't want you back.
Speaker 0: Ah, that's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just if you're the first time they'll always let you in pretty much.
Speaker 1: They'll stick you in like, you know Either with a good counselor or in a bunk that no one cares about or something like that.
Speaker 1: But Camp counseling is a lot of fun because basically you're paid to play sports with kids.
Speaker 0: Yep Now I had a whole bunch of non real jobs like while I was in high school like I used to tutor kids in the trumpet and I charged an obscene amount of money like 15 bucks a half hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I had a small number of clients that made me quite a bit of money for very little work.
Speaker 0: basically Turing young kids in an instrument boils down to telling them to practice and that's really all you can do and then listening to them And telling them either good job now practice this instead or you obviously didn't practice.
Speaker 0: No, that was it?
Speaker 1: No, and then can't counseling though.
Speaker 1: The trick with that is because if it's a sleep-wake camp Especially they let you live there and they feed you and you get all this stuff that you know.
Speaker 1: kids Usually have to pay thousands of dollars to go to the camp and you're getting it for Basically, you're getting paid to do what they pay for.
Speaker 1: that is you don't really get paid minimum wage.
Speaker 1: It's they usually give you like one giant paycheck at the end of your time there or a paycheck Halfway through and another one at the end and it doesn't come out to minimum wage.
Speaker 1: because yeah Well, if it's sleep-wake can't?
Speaker 1: that's 24 hours times minimum wage equals.
Speaker 1: I'm rich and the camp goes out of business and Since you're you're not really an hourly worker.
Speaker 1: They don't have to pay you minimum wage.
Speaker 1: There's laws.
Speaker 0: Yeah I remember like a waitress.
Speaker 1: they don't have to pay a waitress because they get tips and whatnot.
Speaker 0: the band camp from my high school.
Speaker 0: they always wanted me to come back and be a counselor and instructor there and I think they paid like $14 a day and I was like, all right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll make more work in construction somewhere You know it and if you want your summer whatever to be fun, it's a good job.
Speaker 1: But if you want to make a lot of money, it's not a good job.
Speaker 1: You know, you'll make more money working all day at some boring job, but it's fun.
Speaker 1: So it you know it evens out Yeah and at the end you just had this pile of money and you didn't.
Speaker 1: you don't have any living expenses because You're just out of a summer camp so you just have like a you.
Speaker 1: basically at the end you have a fistful of dollars.
Speaker 0: Now I remember we got to RIT and we had to get jobs eventually to pay for the fact that we needed things like food Mm-hmm, and I remember I worked at this bar cafe in the basement of RIT called the Ritz.
Speaker 1: Yeah I went over to the the crossroad just as a brand new food court Cafeteria and I said I wanted.
Speaker 1: they said they basically when they were opening There was like a day where they're like we need people to work here and The just guy was just like sitting at a table out in the front just having people fill out job applications.
Speaker 1: I went in to build one out and I was hired.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I worked there from the very first day it opened to.
Speaker 0: For like the rest of that year freshman year Yep Me and I stopped me and someone we used to know named Greg went to the Ritz to apply and they were like you're hired You can start today.
Speaker 0: We're like I will start tomorrow and we started the next day and it was a terrible job.
Speaker 0: But I made up for that by making terrible pizza And then Greg quit like he never showed up again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the crossroads is an okay job.
Speaker 1: Like when I was making subs, you know I would always make him like these huge giant subs and which you weren't supposed to do.
Speaker 1: You're supposed to weigh the meat and everything Yep.
Speaker 1: and then when I was in the grill I would just freaking make all kinds of burgers and stuff and then I was like cutting Up fruits and making salads and it was kind of fun because mostly it was food preparing and not much dealing with idiots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had to do a lot of the other end of that.
Speaker 0: instead of food preparing it was either well cooking pizzas which was okay or Cleaning up like the back room, which I never really had the cleaning job other people did like the dishes and stuff.
Speaker 0: It was actually really depressing when I had to work in the back because there were a lot of full-time people who were hired By RIT being paid almost nothing and that was their career.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was crossroads didn't have that crossroads is run almost entirely by kids.
Speaker 1: There were like three or four Like manager people that were sometimes there sometimes not and then there were like a couple of like cook People who were like one rung lower that were full-time.
Speaker 0: But other than that, it was all kids Yep, and then we all had other jobs like we worked on campus for various clerical or semi-technical things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a getting a clerical job on campus.
Speaker 0: It's like oh Even though you don't get paid that much I worked with the same department for like two years and all I basically had to do was review Contracts and put them in a database.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I work for the School of Art And I was the only one in the whole building who knew anything about computers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it worked out.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah relatively speaking.
Speaker 0: and then actually the summer after There was one summer where we all we lived in Rochester Like all alone with no classes really and no jobs or anything.
Speaker 1: I Had a job.
Speaker 1: I worked it.
Speaker 1: I was working in the art building during that time still.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I worked for a sub shop for a while and I worked for a temp agency where I did all sorts of fun things.
Speaker 0: I worked in a factory one day and I decided that I was I would die before I would ever work in a factory again Like it motivated me to get my degree.
Speaker 0: I'll say that Yep, and I worked for like a caterer once or twice like this Jewish caterer.
Speaker 0: That was fun.
Speaker 0: But all the jobs we've talked about Really don't matter.
Speaker 0: like the interview doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: All they're interviewing you for is to make sure you're not a complete reject and To narrow it down from the hundred or so people who applied.
Speaker 0: and other than that these jobs like they're trivial and you'll get one If you try.
Speaker 0: well, actually the job in the art building wasn't so easy to get Yeah, but to get a job of that level you would eventually gotten a job on campus.
Speaker 0: Yeah probably that would have paid about the same.
Speaker 1: the real reason that those jobs were harder to get is because Clerical jobs on campus are in high demand and low supply.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because they pay slightly more Yeah, and because they're a lot easier and a lot more pleasant than working in a cafeteria.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there are all sorts of job.
Speaker 0: I mean basically a job of that level.
Speaker 0: if you want one you'll get one.
Speaker 0: So we're not gonna really spend much as long as you try.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you're not a complete rejects Yeah, if you're a read that but yeah, that's basically what it comes down to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you don't if you don't know if you're a complete reject or not, you probably are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you want a part-time minimum wage job Yeah, go to places as many places as you can that you would tolerate working in fill out applications.
Speaker 1: Just go in.
Speaker 1: They'll talk to you to make sure you're not an idiot.
Speaker 1: They'll teach you how to do whatever the menial labor that you're gonna do is and you'll do it and then you'll get paid.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's all you got to do.
Speaker 0: So we're going to spend the rest of the time talking about real jobs.
Speaker 1: Oh Wow, I've had I guess two real jobs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would say that I've had two.
Speaker 0: I mean I worked for the ITS which is like the IT department at RIT and When I interviewed with them, I was so highly qualified that they were like, we don't have any work for you You're you're beyond this.
Speaker 0: and they ended up giving me a special job where I didn't really report to anyone and I was like a project implementer and I went around like implementing projects.
Speaker 0: I'm not I won't go to the details of it, but it was fun and it paid decently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the first real job I got was a co-op with the company that our friend James works for.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I forgot about getting that job wasn't really like getting other jobs because you know James There.
Speaker 1: so it was kind of like a secret in.
Speaker 1: so that's that's the first way to get a job.
Speaker 1: No, someone there get a secret in back door.
Speaker 0: I I would say that that is the primary way to get a good job in this world today.
Speaker 0: You have to have some sort of in or something or you're really kind of screwed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, think about it.
Speaker 1: If someone is slightly more qualified than you and you're just going up against them like directly You're not gonna win.
Speaker 1: You've got a you know, no someone at the company.
Speaker 1: You got to maybe have a relative You know, maybe you can even find a relatives relative or a friend's friend or that stuff actually works.
Speaker 1: You just talk to someone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they know you Someone they know better than you says good things about you and there you go.
Speaker 0: No, really The a lot of people say oh when you're in college, you've got a network.
Speaker 0: You've got a network and it may sound silly but that is really the primary benefit of college.
Speaker 0: college You'll learn stuff, but you could learn that stuff on your own College is primarily the enjoyment and the learning how to live in the real world and most importantly the meeting people.
Speaker 0: It's like if you have enough money to go to college you're paying for the privilege of meeting the people you'll need to know in Order to succeed later in life.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm They can't tell you like some of the people that I know Like from different places that later came and helped me out with something Like even like the guy who was in charge of that summer camp that I only worked at for one summer.
Speaker 1: Like because of him I got like two jobs.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's like.
Speaker 1: all I got to do is tell someone to call him and he says these great things about me and then I Get a job.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: we know some people who made friends with professors and met people then they got jobs through those people.
Speaker 0: We also know some people who graduated with actually better grades than most of us But they didn't really know anyone and they didn't really make Like networking type friends or they didn't really meet anyone.
Speaker 0: I don't want to sound cynical but useful and as a result despite the fact that they're talented they'd never found work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't get it.
Speaker 1: There are people with the same exact degree or an equivalent degree to the one that I've got and I have a high-paying Professional technical job.
Speaker 1: that were.
Speaker 1: you know, don't talk about how my job does nothing but the fact is that someone hired me and is willing to pay me a lot of money and other people with similar qualifications did not obtain the same level of Success in this department if you consider it success.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and even though they might have wanted to so another little bit of advice that Grades don't matter so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's some people who will.
Speaker 1: it really depends on where you're going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some people if they hire someone right out of college They want to look at that GPA number and compare it to other people's GPA numbers.
Speaker 0: Yep, like when I got heard by IBM, they had a policy of if you don't have a 3.4.
Speaker 1: We won't consider you Yep, but if you don't care about working for a big company, usually they won't care about your GPA.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and here's another secret Once you have work experience the more work your job your GP doesn't matter anymore.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean why worked at IBM as a co-op?
Speaker 0: So IBM appeared on my resume and I have not wanted for job offers since then Mm-hmm, even though I currently still work at IBM.
Speaker 1: But it's like if your only qualification is I got a degree from college and you're going for a job You got to put that GPA on there and it better be high.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you've got any sort of special things like I was the National Merit Scholar Finalist so I stuck that on there and any kind of.
Speaker 0: if you're on the Dean's list stick that on there Yep, but once you have a real job somewhere anywhere, none of that stuff matters.
Speaker 1: erase all that stuff right off the resume Cuz no one cares anymore.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: In fact at that point you want to flip your resume around.
Speaker 0: talk about resumes real quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah The basic format of a resume.
Speaker 0: and I will say one thing that I've had a lot of people tell me Especially counselors in school like oh your resume shouldn't be the way you've done it.
Speaker 0: You should do it this standard way that everyone does like the books say whatever.
Speaker 0: And I found that to be largely stupid because I actually have been complimented on my resume.
Speaker 0: So basically do whatever you think looks good and seems professional and unless an employer says something about your resume Don't listen to your counselors so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like the college wants to make everything real easy.
Speaker 1: So they come up with like this standard format and they're like everyone.
Speaker 1: do your thing in this format.
Speaker 1: it works really well or whatever.
Speaker 1: but Employers really don't care.
Speaker 1: All you have to do is make sure it's readable.
Speaker 1: make sure it's formatted nicely.
Speaker 0: No spelling errors.
Speaker 0: if there is any typo on your resume, you won't get hired.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's some things the counselors tell you.
Speaker 1: that's that's that aren't stupid and that's spelling errors.
Speaker 1: No one will hire you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't make it more than two pages.
Speaker 0: Probably don't make it more than one.
Speaker 0: You probably want like a normal one-page resume and an extended two-page resume.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you really have that much stuff to put on there.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is my resume is huge now Yeah, but yeah one pay a one-page thing is really good because then you just kind of hand them out like their business cards.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but if you go in for the job interview you bring the extended one that has like everything in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're like here.
Speaker 1: check this out and then people go through it like oh
Speaker 0: now the general format that I would suggest Really depends on whether or not you have had significant work experience yet if you're in college or fresh out of college I suggest Information about your degree and about you at the top.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then your qualifications and skills and then Your previous work experience.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's that's what I did on my and basically one skip the jobs that were stupid.
Speaker 1: well, what I did is I had a whole bunch of jobs and what I did is I list the jobs in chronological order and Then I list the the skills that I got from those jobs.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know like at that job I learned I dealt with because you want to know what you did at the job.
Speaker 1: You know if you just write I was this that doesn't know don't lie.
Speaker 0: But and it pad it out.
Speaker 0: now by pad it out I mean if you were an office clerk, don't just say office clerk say what you actually did like data entry HR Management blah blah blah is an example of what you want to do.
Speaker 1: I was at a dry cleaner basically Sorting clothing, but I also had to deal with customers.
Speaker 1: So I wrote gained valuable customer service.
Speaker 1: you know techniques or something like that, you know, I learned how to deal with people and I kind of did.
Speaker 1: but yeah, it looks a lot better than stood around folding shirts.
Speaker 0: Yes Like when I was a clerk for the IP office at our IT.
Speaker 0: all I really did was type things into a database and hit enter basically just data entry, but I was like alphanumeric and ten key data entry and I met all this sort of office clerical terms for all the various things I did like Filing and all that.
Speaker 0: Yep pad it out, but don't pad it out stupidly.
Speaker 0: If your job was like a server at McDonald's don't call it like interfaced with customers in a sales environment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that people can.
Speaker 0: in fact
Speaker 1: if you work at McDonald's don't put that on there unless you're applying to work at another McDonald's or Burger King or something
Speaker 0: or if you don't have any job experience at all or You work there for so long that you have to put it because employers are at this stage If you don't have a lot of work experience, there's.
Speaker 0: they really want to see something there that proves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he can hold a job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he wasn't just a bum.
Speaker 1: and if you have like a giant hole like let's say I did a job and then I did Another job that sucked that I did it and then I did a good job and now I'm applying for yet another job And I leave the crappy job out.
Speaker 1: Some guy's gonna go.
Speaker 1: What did you do for those years in that hole there, you know, cuz you have to write down when you worked at the jobs.
Speaker 0: Yep, now they really won't do this again if you're inexperienced, but once you're but once you have work experience It's obvious when you left something out.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and they really don't want to hear I was unemployed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'll be like, oh really yeah, I'm not hiring you you're gonna be unemployed for a while.
Speaker 0: Yes I'll say this make something up if you have to just like I was working on personal projects or I Needed a break or something.
Speaker 0: Don't just say I couldn't find work.
Speaker 1: at least come if you have to.
Speaker 1: you can come up with an elaborate lie Like I was on the tour the world vacation or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or a sabbatical Sabbatical is a real good word.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: or something like.
Speaker 1: You know something that sounds really interesting like I was practicing with some team Somewhere or I was developing open source Yeah, or I was researching something with some guy or I went to you know to a monastery to meditate or something.
Speaker 1: That'll start a conversation.
Speaker 0: Yeah because the main thing and I can't stress this enough you want to stand out from all the other people and I don't want to say that all attention is good attention because there are things you can do that make you stand out in a Bad way, but generally anything you do that makes you stand out at all is a good thing.
Speaker 0: If you don't do anything that makes you stand out get ready for a life of shit Yep, because everyone will ignore you and job interviews and you'll end up with the crap job where they want a drone.
Speaker 1: Yep So the stuff that makes you stand out is you know the stuff you do normally like.
Speaker 1: if I did a resume right now I'd put like geek nights podcast host and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I list all the websites We run and like yeah, I'd half sysadmin and half, you know, maintain the community blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I put all sorts of audio engineering studio recording type stuff because outside of geek nights I know about that.
Speaker 0: if you have a hobby that is in any way related to work or even if it's just something Interesting or technical put it on there.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: If you're a Professional mountain biker you could seriously put like professional mountain biker if you really are.
Speaker 1: Yep Don't lie on the resume.
Speaker 1: Yeah Don't you don't want to don't say like Professional lion tamer and mountain climber because someone will catch you and you'll be screwed or even worse You'll get the job and later they'll catch you and then you'll really be screwed.
Speaker 0: Yep, like if I got hired by someone now and say years from now the company says we want to do a podcast.
Speaker 0: You you know audio engineering you're on top.
Speaker 0: You're on top of that Brandon rim.
Speaker 0: You're hired.
Speaker 0: do that now That's your new department and you lied and you don't know audio engineering.
Speaker 0: You're done you're done.
Speaker 1: there are laws.
Speaker 1: I think about that.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 1: not only that but you'll be blackballed You'll be in big trouble.
Speaker 0: now I know I said The format of the resume.
Speaker 0: once you have at least one good job like a real job Like I worked for IBM or I worked for Microsoft or Google or a big company or that's what you want to put up the top there.
Speaker 0: at that point you switch.
Speaker 0: now your resume goes your name and Qualifications.
Speaker 0: by qualifications.
Speaker 0: I mean the degree you have and if you have any certifications, whatever those two and then your work experience in order and the skills you have from those jobs the duties you had in those jobs and then Skills that aren't listed there.
Speaker 1: You want to put.
Speaker 1: actually We know when I got out of college My resume was my oldest job first down to the newest one.
Speaker 1: now flip it.
Speaker 1: flip it Newest job at the top because the new it the most recent job is gonna be the most awesome job.
Speaker 0: Yep, also that way it's a nice reverse chronological order.
Speaker 0: Yep, you don't want him to see office clerk for crap.
Speaker 0: Oh company in high school first.
Speaker 0: In fact, you probably want to lop all that stuff off the resume at that point.
Speaker 1: Yeah only put as much as you can fit.
Speaker 1: put all the other stuff besides the jobs in the resume in the order it has to Be in and then keep inserting jobs into that middle part until you run out of space and I'll tell you that in general No employer cares about the job.
Speaker 0: you had more than three jobs ago unless it's terribly relevant to the job You're gonna do now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like if I was a painter and then I was a carpenter and then I was a computer guy and now I'm trying to Be a plumber they they kind of care about the old painting and carpeting jobs.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah now in terms of standing out When you interview with people, there are a lot of tricks and a lot of things.
Speaker 0: the main thing I want to stress now is that everyone tells everyone how to dress and the counselors were notorious for this.
Speaker 0: because I went to.
Speaker 0: I went to the interview with IBM right and Everyone was dressed identically.
Speaker 0: they were all wearing like the exact same blue suit white shirt red tie Yes, or some minor variation thereof.
Speaker 0: like everyone looked identical.
Speaker 1: I just always wore the only suit I had.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I until recently never wore suits to interviews.
Speaker 0: No Instead I wore a nice shirt good pants a thin tie and some.
Speaker 0: I would some sort of stylish thing.
Speaker 0: a lot of times I'd wear a sport jacket and a t-shirt and then nice pants Things like that because then you really stand out as you because everyone else looks like a cookie cookie cutter.
Speaker 0: Okay, the counselor told him to dress like that.
Speaker 0: This guy's like.
Speaker 1: well, that's if we're going to like some sort of multiple people interview Even
Speaker 0: if you're not even if you're going anywhere if you look like the standard Like guy going for an interview you don't stand out and they know that you just listen to whatever website or counselor told you how To dress.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: I've had a lot of good luck by just dressing the way I dress.
Speaker 0: Anyway, just snazzier.
Speaker 1: I Just wore the only suit I had when I had an interview and no one seemed to care and it worked whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing is if you can work into the conversation things that are fairly complementary to you.
Speaker 0: I Mean I really to this day think that the main reason I was originally hired by IBM way back was that I went to this like luncheon.
Speaker 0: IBM was putting on before and I knew that the people who were gonna be interviewing were in this room.
Speaker 0: So I was talking with some people just other students who were also vying for jobs and someone brought up high school and They mentioned like an AP class or something.
Speaker 0: so I went on a roll with that and talked about all the AP classes I took and we had this long conversation about AP classes and advanced stuff.
Speaker 0: and I Spoke in such a way that because I noticed at this point that one of the people who I thought was recruiter was obviously Obviously listening to our conversation but trying to act like he wasn't.
Speaker 0: So I really talked myself up and sure enough that guy told another Recruiter about me and I got a job as a result.
Speaker 0: I'm reasonably certain that that was the primary thing that had caused them to have an interest in me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just never want to interviewed for the job I have right now.
Speaker 1: You know cuz my boss is kind of cool even though he doesn't give me any work to do.
Speaker 1: But he asked me questions about like, you know, so what's your favorite editor?
Speaker 1: and you got.
Speaker 1: you got it You know, if you know your shit, you'll have an answer.
Speaker 0: But if you don't know your shit, you know, it's it's yeah No your shit because they will call you on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're unless if they don't call you on it, then it's not a job you want to work at.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now they'll a lot of time like a few jobs.
Speaker 0: I interviewed that they they like me.
Speaker 0: So then they called in the techie guy and they were like, all right grill him to make sure he's not bullshitting or something To that effect.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and the guy asked like just generic questions about Linux and networking.
Speaker 0: He was like What do you type if you want to know blood?
Speaker 0: I was like well blah or blah depending on the distribution.
Speaker 0: He's like, all right Apache where do the log files go?
Speaker 0: and I was like, well, they go here or here depending on blah and he's like All right, this guy knows what he's talking about.
Speaker 0: If you don't know they'll know.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: They sure will.
Speaker 1: I remember when I applied to work at What was?
Speaker 1: it was some online store or something?
Speaker 1: I never I didn't actually work there, but the guy asked me like all the hippies It was something kind of like hippies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember that.
Speaker 1: I don't know But that guy it was it was a Java web development job and they asked me some pretty like Is the kind of questions that ask you in a test in computer science class?
Speaker 1: Like what's the word for this?
Speaker 1: and I'm like, oh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: or like name the three properties and I was like, uh Wow, I've never had anyone do that to me.
Speaker 1: and I was just like are you reading from some textbook or something?
Speaker 1: Geez But then the job I had now they were like, you know What languages do you know?
Speaker 1: this and this and this and this and this because I know a shit ton of languages Computer languages anyway, I only know one speaking language.
Speaker 1: now just then they were like, you know pearl like.
Speaker 1: no I don't know pearl.
Speaker 1: I hate pearl.
Speaker 1: and then they're like, do you know who wrote pearl and I'm like Larry Wall?
Speaker 1: They're like, uh, cuz if I didn't get that if I didn't know that they would have been like you.
Speaker 1: just you know Some shit talking now.
Speaker 0: That's a big thing.
Speaker 0: that don't be a shit talker.
Speaker 0: just because you touched an HPU X system.
Speaker 0: let's say once or like you worked at a company that you know used web sphere Don't put web sphere on your resume unless you know it.
Speaker 0: god damn like.
Speaker 0: I know HP UX enough because I worked on a system helping some idiots fix it a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: so I can put it on my resume.
Speaker 0: I Know that my department uses AIX and I have touched an AIX box once or twice.
Speaker 0: We use X extensively.
Speaker 0: I don't put AIX on my resume because I am not terribly familiar with it.
Speaker 0: and while I could learn it I'm not gonna lie and say I know it because I don't.
Speaker 1: here's another thing.
Speaker 1: Let's say you know something.
Speaker 1: Let's say you know Z80 assembler.
Speaker 1: All right, right and you're applying for some job where they might want you to do Z80 assembler But you don't want to do it.
Speaker 1: or let's say you want to put your resume online, but you don't actually want to code Z80 assembler because it's it's Painful.
Speaker 1: don't put it on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't put it on there.
Speaker 1: No one will make you do it.
Speaker 1: You know if you know something that you don't want to do don't write it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and if you if you out there know web sphere There's a million jobs for you.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people who know web sphere don't like it and don't want to do it So they pretend they don't know anything about.
Speaker 1: yeah There are a lot of things like a lot of in computers because that's what I know most about.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of skill Sets where if you know like a combination of things there are like a hundred high-paying jobs for you at any moment in time.
Speaker 0: yep, the big ones right now that I've seen are good software engineer and All the things that go along with that.
Speaker 1: a good thing to know is if you know like Java j2e plus oracle plus You know that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah any sort of like enterprise style web application development using Java That'll make you a ton of money.
Speaker 0: J boss web sphere all those things.
Speaker 0: You only need to know one of them because if you know one you could probably deal with the rest of them even dotnet.
Speaker 1: There's a whole bunch of high-paying jobs now.
Speaker 1: Here's the other thing all those jobs suck.
Speaker 0: Yes, writing that code sucks ass.
Speaker 0: writing Java for a company usually sucks ass
Speaker 1: But those jobs are high paying and not too many people know all those things because the only way to learn those things is To either read a damn book about it or go work for a company that you know will let you do it and learn it before Hiring you to do it in the first place.
Speaker 0: Yep, the only people who actually know web sphere are people who already work for IBM Now.
Speaker 0: another big one right now is databases DBAs database administrators people who do databases or maintain databases or design databases.
Speaker 0: And I will tell you right now that when I went to RIT they told me yeah If you concentrate in databases, you'll make six figures immediately.
Speaker 0: and I thought ooh, and I took the introductory database class.
Speaker 0: I The class.
Speaker 0: I vowed to never take a database class again, and I don't care how much money they pay me.
Speaker 0: I would never be a DBA ever.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: I'd rather be a ditch digger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ditch digging ain't so bad actually, but um no it's like.
Speaker 1: I took a database.
Speaker 1: I knew databases are big so I thought I'd go learn about him, so I took like a PHP MySQL database class.
Speaker 0: It was actually sort of required kind of well I took like this high level like here are the fundamentals of databases and SQL and designing them and normalizing them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when they get into that stuff like normalizing and optimizing and all that other like high level database stuff I can't take it, but then now my current job It's like normal level stuff like you make a table you put some data in it Yeah,
Speaker 0: or my
Speaker 1: simple select and a join that stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't mind.
Speaker 0: Yeah like one job I was looking at they said like you know databases, and I thought crap.
Speaker 0: and I was like yeah I know database theory and I know SQL and blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: and they were like no we don't care about that.
Speaker 0: Could you back up like a MySQL database, and I'm like Yeah, and they're like.
Speaker 0: and then they they're like well, how do you do that?
Speaker 0: I was like my SQL dump.
Speaker 0: They're like oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, very few people actually want the the craziness.
Speaker 0: yeah And if they do they'll pay you six figures.
Speaker 0: databases if you have.
Speaker 1: it's like chartered accountancy used to be in like the 70s All right, so if you want a job Step one get skills.
Speaker 1: if you don't have skills no one will hire to you to use the skills.
Speaker 1: And you have to have something to prove you have the skills.
Speaker 1: you can't just say you have them.
Speaker 0: Yep, now the only way to prove it is to either have a bunch of work experience Which I know is against 22 already yep, or have a Bachelor of Science in the technical field.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about creative jobs because we know nothing about them.
Speaker 1: No not at all.
Speaker 0: We have a lot of friends who need like portfolios and shit for that.
Speaker 1: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: yeah To all of our artist friends out there if you give us audio feedback We'll do a second series on like other kinds of jobs that we don't know about and we'll gladly play what you have to say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how to make a freaking portfolio and shit.
Speaker 1: I don't know that.
Speaker 0: we're talking specifically about tech jobs and like science jobs not even so much science jobs.
Speaker 0: We don't know much about that either.
Speaker 1: Yeah engineer jobs or it falls in.
Speaker 0: yeah engineering jobs are similar to what we do pretty much Almost exactly.
Speaker 0: I mean we're basically engineers Just like I'm a network engineer and Scott is a software engineer, but yeah same kind of engineer computers instead of a.
Speaker 1: you know Chips yeah and gears, but basically it.
Speaker 0: the in the order of usefulness for getting jobs in a technical field are If it's a software job a master's.
Speaker 0: If it's not a software job a master's is almost useless.
Speaker 0: a master's in IT is completely useless.
Speaker 1: as far as I'm concerned Masters are usually good for if you want to work somewhere writing really complex fancy algorithms and things like Google Writing search if you want to be doing research or doing like pioneering new things you need your masters or a doctor.
Speaker 1: Yeah doctor.
Speaker 1: usually though you end up being a professor and not so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll end up going into academia, which I've considered yeah, but basically for normal jobs in the normal scale a Bachelor of Science or Good work experience.
Speaker 0: The two of those are equal and they are gold.
Speaker 1: Also gold is if you have a lot of skills But you don't have a job because let's say you got the skills and you were young and you have no way to prove You have the skills to get the first job all the projects you did for yourself.
Speaker 1: throw them all on there.
Speaker 0: That'll make people go and that's also a secondary.
Speaker 0: if you're between jobs And you're a techie in any way.
Speaker 0: do stuff like just pick a board game you like and try to write it out.
Speaker 1: Do something.
Speaker 1: yeah, you're like a Engineer make a car or design something.
Speaker 1: or if you're an architect like design a house in your spare time or whatever.
Speaker 0: Even if you're an artist just start working on that novel you've been putting off.
Speaker 1: Do something because if you don't do anything your skills will deteriorate And you won't have anything to say that you were doing.
Speaker 0: and yeah, yep now I said Bachelor of Science specifically for these jobs.
Speaker 0: There are schools out there who for various reasons will give a Bachelor of the Arts in things like computer science information technology.
Speaker 0: No good Seriously, if you're if you have one of those degrees you're on your way to get one.
Speaker 0: you got boned unless you're paying almost nothing Because that means they really couldn't get their program accredited as a science degree.
Speaker 1: In other words they're not gonna teach you shit,
Speaker 0: or they'll teach you great stuff But they give you a weak degree, and then everyone's gonna ask you forever How come you have a Bachelor of the Arts and they'll give you guff about it mm-hmm
Speaker 1: and now lie and write a BS?
Speaker 1: They'll catch you on it yep, and then you're in big trouble.
Speaker 0: IBM actually makes you show them your diploma.
Speaker 1: Oh really yeah.
Speaker 0: Wow Now a bachelor an associate's degree I Really don't want to sound condescending.
Speaker 0: It's almost useless.
Speaker 0: That's the equivalent of having like a Cisco certification.
Speaker 1: think about this.
Speaker 1: if you have an associate's degree.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be your boss.
Speaker 1: You're basically just gonna be some lackey that I wear.
Speaker 0: I'll put it in terms of IT if you have a master's you're working or a doctorate.
Speaker 0: You're either at a university or you're working at Google like coming up with the new fiber.
Speaker 0: cool thing.
Speaker 0: If you have a bachelors of science you are like the guy who surveys a site and says all right We need switches in these closets.
Speaker 0: network goes like this this kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna hire people to do this for you.
Speaker 0: If you have an associate's degree or like a Cisco cert you're the guy sitting in the closet making $10 an hour punching down All the cables.
Speaker 1: yeah Don't want to be that guy.
Speaker 0: Of course that is a stepping stone, but I'll warn you it's very hard to step from that into a real position.
Speaker 0: It's much easier to step from a real position down to that.
Speaker 1: so step one get skills.
Speaker 1: step two display skills.
Speaker 1: Yes step three To actually do the work of getting jobs.
Speaker 1: put that resume online in Craigslist and other places.
Speaker 0: Yeah, dice comm is good.
Speaker 0: this changes frequently, so we can't really commit to anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are a bunch of sites out there.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: just don't underestimate Craigslist.
Speaker 1: Craigslist is how I got my job And it was actually the most productive job finding place there was.
Speaker 0: places like monster.com are generally useless.
Speaker 1: They're just a sea of ads and crap.
Speaker 1: even dice is sort of like a sea of it.
Speaker 0: I mean basically real like the big.
Speaker 0: Oh find jobs through our sites.
Speaker 0: The only people who look at those sites are HR corporate drones who have no idea who they're trying to hire Mm-hmm people who are smart who want to hire techies.
Speaker 0: look on Craigslist for like the cool, dude.
Speaker 1: Another people that can help you are people whose job it is to hire people.
Speaker 1: They're a lot of headhunter types.
Speaker 1: Now you got to be a little careful with them because they're basically trying to hire Anyone just because they get money.
Speaker 0: if they find someone at the same time They don't want to put someone who sucks into a job because then they lose their reputation like oh That's the guy who gave us a shit, dude.
Speaker 1: So the the rule I take with them is as long as they don't want any money from you fine go along with whatever.
Speaker 1: They say you don't have to take any job.
Speaker 0: You don't want to yeah, and they might charge the employer a fee.
Speaker 0: But the employer is happy with that because actually an IT at least That's where most of the jobs are going.
Speaker 0: very few companies know how to hire an IT guy.
Speaker 0: So they hire a recruiter and say find us someone who can do this job.
Speaker 0: We trust you Mm-hmm, and that's how almost every job I've courted over the past few months has found out about me or forwarded me.
Speaker 0: some guy says I was hired to find someone to Fill this job.
Speaker 0: You look good.
Speaker 0: Let's talk Yep.
Speaker 1: And lastly a lot of companies is the bigger the more likely they are to have this.
Speaker 1: they have actual like Databases.
Speaker 1: they have of resumes and when they want to hire people they'll search their own personal resume database.
Speaker 1: So you want to you know?
Speaker 1: There's a chance that you might come up when someone at a company is searching for some skill set that you have.
Speaker 1: So submit your resumes directly to companies through their websites and many companies you'll.
Speaker 0: they'll say like, oh, we're not going to hire you But we'll keep your resume around.
Speaker 1: they really do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're not lying.
Speaker 0: That's part of how I got again that IBM job.
Speaker 0: because I was offered a job That I turned down because I admitted that the job he described to me was not the same as the job I read on the job description and I told him flat-out It's not something I could do because I thought it was a networking job and it was a network coding job.
Speaker 0: I'm not a great coder and I admitted straight up.
Speaker 0: I can't code that for you.
Speaker 0: I could but it'd be subpar.
Speaker 0: don't hire me.
Speaker 0: and He gave my resume to someone else who then did hire me for a different job that I wanted.
Speaker 0: Yep Now along the same lines if you work for a company Do good work.
Speaker 0: And if your managers or people in your company like you or notice you They'll tell if you're looking for a job in the future.
Speaker 0: They'll tell their friend who works in the other company.
Speaker 0: Hey, I got a guy who's leaving my company.
Speaker 0: He's good.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, the once again networking.
Speaker 0: I hate to sound like those counselors but Network Network Network talk to people make friends in the industry.
Speaker 0: That's the only way to remain employed.
Speaker 1: One other thing is if you go to a company with your resume Like let's say I go to Joe Corp and I say hey Joe Corp hire me.
Speaker 1: That stands out that Joe Corp a lot more than some guy on monster because that means I'm interested in them Like I you know, it's like oh this guy came to us.
Speaker 1: He wants us specifically.
Speaker 1: Yep, even though they probably know that you're going up to a whole bunch of companies.
Speaker 1: It's still better.
Speaker 0: now Don't try to be clever like the dude who spammed his resume out.
Speaker 0: Well, though sometimes it's good to be clever If you're not sure if you're being clever or not, you're not and don't do it.
Speaker 1: All right, here's an example.
Speaker 1: Let's give an example a good clever and bad clever.
Speaker 0: All right Bad clever the dude who literally hired a spamming company and spammed his resume to.
Speaker 0: like every recruiter in the world He is good clever.
Speaker 1: There's a girl I think she does from RIT because I read it in some RIT Publication who wanted to work at eBay and she found this like perfect job Description at eBay and she basically made it.
Speaker 1: she bought a toolbox from Home Depot and all little compartments of the toolbox.
Speaker 1: she put a little thing to like symbolize the skill she had and the Skill was good for the job and how it was exactly all the things on the job description.
Speaker 1: So she went into eBay like into the building and she like went up to the desk and was like Can you give this to the you know?
Speaker 1: She knew the guy who was hiring for the job and was like give this to that guy.
Speaker 1: And you know like.
Speaker 1: it was like this little toolbox resume thing that was you know She custom made a thing for the one specific job that matched her exactly.
Speaker 1: And of course this guy gets his toolbox on his desk and he opens it.
Speaker 1: He sees all little things and it says the girl's name and her phone number and the thing matches the job description And you get a job guaranteed pretty much.
Speaker 0: All right bad.
Speaker 0: Sneaking into a company finding the president barging into his office and saying I'm the man for the job I mean slapping your resume on his desk.
Speaker 1: Yes, not a good.
Speaker 1: He was also bad.
Speaker 1: calling like, you know when you call a place to to get a job You want to call him more than once, you know, you call him once to investigate.
Speaker 1: You call him once to do the actual deal.
Speaker 1: you do the actual deal.
Speaker 1: You can call one more time to say like thank you or whatever Calling more than that.
Speaker 1: You think you can get annoying.
Speaker 1: Yep, don't be the annoying guy But do call if like you have a legitimate question.
Speaker 1: Just call him and ask.
Speaker 0: Now good.
Speaker 0: Once again putting like interesting hobbies or things on your resume.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know I've talked a lot about how I used to run the RIT anime club.
Speaker 0: I put that on my resume.
Speaker 0: It's been on my resume for a long time.
Speaker 0: I listed right up there with IBM and RIT and you know what?
Speaker 0: I always get asked about it and people are always very impressed with it.
Speaker 0: If you ran like a big club or something in college Or you did something big through a fraternity put it on the resume.
Speaker 0: anything that involves public speaking.
Speaker 0: Actual leadership skills as in you are responsible for a large number of people.
Speaker 0: Anything like that is gold because very few people have those skills.
Speaker 1: Here's an idea.
Speaker 1: do things like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Don't be just that, you know, the normal schmuck who does nothing.
Speaker 1: go be that go be somebody.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: like if
Speaker 1: you nobody's fool
Speaker 0: like when we refreshment we got to RIT and we're sitting at the anime club And we all knew each other and we're all sitting there and we always had this idea like wow Those guys at the front of the room like they run everything how they get where they are.
Speaker 0: And then we thought one day.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just take over and be them?
Speaker 1: Oh, we did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we then we did.
Speaker 0: Don't be the guy who always thinks.
Speaker 0: Oh, I wish I could be that guy.
Speaker 0: Just go be that guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: So you got the skills.
Speaker 1: you showed off the skills.
Speaker 1: you let people know that you're showing off the skills You go to the interview.
Speaker 1: You just act like a normal person.
Speaker 1: Don't be all nervous because if you're all nervous They'll be like you're a gibbering fool.
Speaker 0: Yeah at the same time don't like be polite and don't be arrogant.
Speaker 1: And yes, you want to be confident, but just below arrogant because if you're arrogant they go.
Speaker 1: This is some know-it-all asshole.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you really you really need some Empathy skills at this point because I recently I went to an interview where I went through four different people And I had to sit with each one of them for a half hour like the HR guy like the head IT
Speaker 1: guy I hate those ones I love
Speaker 0: those the normal IT guy and then like someone else and that sort of thing and Every one of these people was very different and you kind of have to play off of them Like some guys will be very dour and like rah
Speaker 1: rah
Speaker 0: rah rah blah.
Speaker 0: You don't want to make a joke to that guy.
Speaker 0: But then there's the guy who looks at your resume and then he laughs and talks about like yeah I knew a guy who worked at that company.
Speaker 0: Haha.
Speaker 0: You can make a joke with him Mm-hmm read the person you're with and react accordingly.
Speaker 0: Don't crack inappropriate jokes.
Speaker 1: You don't have anything that would get you fired normally because you just won't be hired.
Speaker 1: Don't ask the hot chick interviewing you out on a date.
Speaker 0: Yeah Unless she is obviously flirting with you in which case that'll probably get you starts playing footsie with you.
Speaker 1: Then you're hired anyway, so just say whatever you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now the only other thing I'll really say is don't underestimate yourself Don't overestimate yourself, but definitely don't correctly estimate yourself.
Speaker 0: but because this I got hit with this when I was starting to leave our IT and getting out of the real workforce and I was looking at jobs and I was thinking like I Don't have those skills they want like five years of experience in blood.
Speaker 0: What if I'm not?
Speaker 0: I don't know what I'm am.
Speaker 0: I really qualified.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't feel like I know so much about this stuff.
Speaker 0: and Then I like.
Speaker 0: and then I got hired by IBM and I showed up and I sat down my off and I was like Am I in over my head?
Speaker 0: Can I really do all this crap?
Speaker 0: And then they gave me a sign was like, oh wow Yeah, I know all this stuff.
Speaker 0: This is exactly what I did in school.
Speaker 0: I'm badass.
Speaker 0: Yep, don't don't be afraid of a job.
Speaker 0: The job will always be easier than you think it will be unless you lied to get hired and then you're screwed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I noticed a lot of times when you look at jobs and you see the requirements and a lot of times online Employers are forced to write things like we need someone with five years in this and four years in that and one year in this.
Speaker 1: And if you had this it would be good to don't take that So literally, you know Like I used to take it real literally and not apply to things because I had four years and not five years Experiences.
Speaker 0: now I apply to jobs where I very specifically don't have one of the things they say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just apply anyway.
Speaker 1: What's the worst they can do just ignore you which is what they would do anyway, if you didn't apply at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and in fact, they'll usually think well he applied anyway, let's talk to him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you said you don't know PHP.
Speaker 0: You're like, yeah, but I started learning it just now because I'm interested in this job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll apply to any programming job I will apply to as long as I know the concepts behind the variety of programming they want because I can learn a programming language in a week.
Speaker 1: In fact, I did as James When I work for him, I learned to do language like boop because I had to.
Speaker 1: I could just learn him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like one job I was looking at they needed J boss.
Speaker 0: So I pulled up all the books and I read the basics of how to run J boss and if I'd actually gotten hired I probably would have sat down for a week and fully learn J boss.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't really I did Didn't go with that job.
Speaker 0: So I didn't bother because I don't like J boss.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you go buy a book you go online read documentation and bam you got yourself One more thing on your resume.
Speaker 1: now we could go on but I think we've gone on quite a bit.
Speaker 0: I think we'll split this into another show because I think there's another show we could definitely do on How the corporate world actually works.
Speaker 1: I'm not in the corporate world so much.
Speaker 1: I'm more Corporate world.
Speaker 0: I am in like the enterprise exactly like you read in comics and books and see on TV.
Speaker 0: corporate world Dilbert world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm in the Dilbert world.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know, I don't really go in the Dilbert world.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'm in the sub Dilbert world.
Speaker 0: We're both in the working world and all I have to say is that jobs The vast majority of people who have jobs in this country at least white-collar jobs Do so little work.
Speaker 0: It's amazing It's true.
Speaker 0: People really aren't efficient at all.
Speaker 0: And if everyone was efficient, we could all go home early.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like or we could do more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't want to talk about this now We've gone on forever, but we'll do another show where I guess we're going to reveal these secrets of the real world Outside of college and how.
Speaker 0: it's not nearly as difficult as you think.
Speaker 1: Oh one more thing.
Speaker 1: So in case you know, you're still deluded by school because you're rather young.
Speaker 1: Guess what your grades in elementary and middle school don't mean shit.
Speaker 0: In fact your grades in high school don't mean shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah The only thing your grades in high school mean is will you get into Harvard or not?
Speaker 1: Unless you're going for Harvard or an Ivy League school your grades in high school don't mean shit.
Speaker 1: No one can.
Speaker 0: and even then if you're smart your grades still won't matter because they'll see like oh you got all C's Oh, but he took all AP classes.
Speaker 0: Oh, look, he was the head of the band.
Speaker 1: Oh, alright, he's smart Yep, and then in college your grades really don't mean shit as long as you get the piece of paper.
Speaker 1: Oh and unless you want to work for the big corporation that actually cares and so it's unless you aim for the top the number Doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: and all I want to say the big corporation is not all it's cracked up to be.
Speaker 1: don't work for the big Corporation.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah work for the smart cool guy with a small business.
Speaker 0: You should hear.
Speaker 0: so I mean, I can't tell a lot of these stories of what I've gone through in the corporate world.
Speaker 1: See if you didn't live in the corporate world, you could tell all your stories.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I mean there are various non-disclosure agreements and such and some stories I can never tell.
Speaker 0: However, I can tell similar stories or I can tell stories that have the same moral.
Speaker 1: So this guy Joey Jojo Shabbadoo.
Speaker 0: So, I guess in closing I just realized that this little toad in my diorama is totally flipping me off.
Speaker 1: what Awesome double deuce.
Speaker 0: Get a job.
Speaker 0: and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: If you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com.
Speaker 1: And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.