Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, November 29th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight due to popular demand we go back to comics for a bit and review Mouse Guard.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So over the weekend since Emily can't really use it in her dorm She decided to give me her old Yamaha keyboard, which is actually quite a bit better than the keyboard I had when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty beefy box when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I had this tiny tiny keyboard.
Speaker 1: I had the same one.
Speaker 1: probably it was like the CT six.
Speaker 1: I forget you want it was this tiny little thing and out of tiny microphone in the top, right?
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: mine didn't have a tiny microphone really know?
Speaker 1: mine had a microphone.
Speaker 1: you could record One second of audio and then it would play it back through keys.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow No mine It was like a had very small keys for like little hands and it had two sets of eight buttons and the like.
Speaker 0: first eight Were different instruments you could play and the second eight buttons were different.
Speaker 0: like backbeats you could run
Speaker 1: Oh
Speaker 0: and you could change the tempo of the backbeats and you could change Like the pitch of the instruments a little bit see this thing and then you could record like a small demo loop and then play That back and then play over it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I had a little tiny one and then I had a pretty good one and then eventually my parents bought me that digital piano.
Speaker 1: But this keyboard sitting behind me now and I kind of integrated it into my desk is a full-on MIDI authoring keyboard.
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right That's not necessary.
Speaker 1: I'm really pleased with this and it is inspired me along with a couple of people in the forums who asked why I didn't just Arrange some music for geek nights.
Speaker 1: I responded in the forum that the answer was purely laziness and Hopefully over this Christmas break when I have some free time I'm gonna actually sit down and try to arrange something again, man If you think that's cool, you should check out like a modern keyboard.
Speaker 0: I'm well aware this thing is mad.
Speaker 1: I'm well aware of keyboard technology.
Speaker 1: in fact back in high school even my friend can had a Very very nice keyboard and he was doing stuff with MIDI before I even knew what MIDI was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean this thing can't even make the Eurobeat noise.
Speaker 1: So well, it can.
Speaker 1: I can make any noise if I plug it into a MIDI synthesizer as opposed to using the built-in synth?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but doesn't have a Eurobeat built in.
Speaker 0: So what good is it?
Speaker 0: It's not good at all Right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got in the news since I got nothing else to say about this.
Speaker 0: So a while ago I think I might have done a story about like the top 10 most important people in manga in America.
Speaker 0: The top guy is a guy named Kurt Hassler.
Speaker 0: Kurt Hassler his job until recently and that's the news is that it's no longer his job was to purchase Manga and graphic novels and you know comics for borders and Walden books because the same company that you know Cuz all the retailer really is is a middleman.
Speaker 0: they buy stuff from one person and they sell it to someone else.
Speaker 0: So when you're a book retailer, you buy stuff from publishers and sell it to people.
Speaker 0: So his job was to buy The Jillian's of copies of manga and graphic novels and then sell them to you and me and he Could he had to figure out how many to buy?
Speaker 0: Which ones to buy who to buy them from which stores to send them to all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: He was a real important guy Apparently on November 6 which is already like 20 days ago, but I totally missed the news 23 days ago.
Speaker 0: He Decided doesn't want to do that anymore.
Speaker 0: Now he's actually gonna go into the business of selling Some manga and some comics.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yep, apparently What's the name of this company?
Speaker 0: Some publisher that I've never heard.
Speaker 1: you totally deserve the thought bird right there.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna rip off anime world order a pair of hash it I don't know.
Speaker 0: Do you know the publisher named hatchet never heard of him?
Speaker 0: But honestly until I'm not even sure if I'm pronouncing your rights h a c h e t t e Hatchet hatchet, maybe it's hatchet.
Speaker 1: I've never really paid attention to who published the things I like.
Speaker 0: Yeah me either really anyway hatchet is a publisher and they're making a new imprint named yen press.
Speaker 1: Okay,
Speaker 0: and yen press is gonna be a new publisher of manga in America and it's going to be Kurt hassler is gonna be the man and he's gonna you know be deciding what manga they're gonna get and bring over here And he's gonna be trying to sell it to people who did his former job.
Speaker 0: So he's probably gonna do a good job of it because if it was your job to buy stuff And then suddenly you become the guy trying to sell stuff to your former position You know what to tell yourself to convince you to buy it.
Speaker 0: Tell the person who has your old job to convince them to buy it unless they're just a different person.
Speaker 0: It could be.
Speaker 1: but you know Considering that hopefully they make their decisions based on the same logic and such I mean suppose for a second that the guy who takes over happens to be say David Riley from fast karate for the.
Speaker 1: oh god, they'll order nothing but fist of the North Star and more fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: Well, I think Kurt hassler is a smart guy.
Speaker 0: So he if he knew Dave Riley and Dave Riley got his old job somehow, there would be much fist of the North Star license.
Speaker 0: No, but yeah expect to see a lot of yen press books in borders in.
Speaker 0: You know some months I guess I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, honestly, I've never been that impressed with borders section of a of manga.
Speaker 0: They do not carry Phoenix.
Speaker 0: Therefore they suck.
Speaker 0: Well, basically they carry everything.
Speaker 0: They carry all the Tokyo pops and all the mainstream stuff.
Speaker 0: They don't carry the Viz signature series, which is pretty much the only thing you need to carry because that's all the good stuff.
Speaker 1: well, I used to get all my manga from The book the bookstores in the mall like Walden books.
Speaker 1: Yep And before that I used to get him from media play off and on but now honestly I get them all from the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Amazon.
Speaker 1: In fact when I think about it, I Rarely buy anything other than food from any source other than the internet.
Speaker 0: I buy household goods from not the internet.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah household household goods and food.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I try to buy household goods on the internet, but you can never be sure.
Speaker 0: I mean I bought like some bedsheets and towels and stuff like.
Speaker 0: those towels are great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but man, I can't buy bowls or Spatulas on the internet just doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we buy them at the grocery store so we don't have to go shopping.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 1: I mean when was the last time we went to a mall?
Speaker 0: I don't buy clothing and shoes on the internet either.
Speaker 1: Oh, no But I try to buy them if I can down in New York City or sporting goods or outdoors actually cheaper.
Speaker 1: But other than that what outdoor goods would you need?
Speaker 1: What do you do outdoors?
Speaker 0: Hardware, I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't buy hardware.
Speaker 0: Like if I go to Home Depot instead.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what sporting goods do you need?
Speaker 1: What do you do other than other than walk between your car and the house in the cold balls?
Speaker 0: Yeah balls to play with.
Speaker 1: I'm well aware of that.
Speaker 1: So this isn't really an anime news.
Speaker 1: In fact, it's not at all an anime news.
Speaker 1: It's some video game news.
Speaker 1: But there's really no anime news I care about and I'm really not gonna talk about the anime news that anime world order talks about.
Speaker 1: Because if you really care about that stuff you can listen to them or you can read anime news network calm and get all The anime news.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah for anyone out there who doesn't you know who actually thinks that our show is about reporting news Our show is not the place to get the news.
Speaker 0: No, our show is the place where you comment on the news.
Speaker 1: We're also kind of a filter.
Speaker 1: if you don't want to read the news You'll figure out what's important to us from listening except for the fact that we don't talk about politics or military.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get like the like the top one or two stories and none of the you know.
Speaker 0: What you really need to know is the top five or ten stories.
Speaker 0: But if you read anime news network calm anime news service calm and anime on DVD?
Speaker 0: calm That's pretty much all the news.
Speaker 0: You don't need any other anime news.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Everything else is who know cares unless you can read Japanese then there are sites that you can look at get better news.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah back in the when the SNES started fading and the Nintendo 64 was coming into prominence That is when I abandoned console gaming to completely embrace PC gaming We also now that lasted me up until the DS came out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was still doing some GBA action.
Speaker 0: But and I got a GameCube and I did a lot of GameCube stuff.
Speaker 0: But even when I had the GameCube, you know, it only provided Intermittent gaming entertainment because it would be a game and I would go to the GameCube and play the game.
Speaker 0: Then I go back to the PC during the drought until the next game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the DS and the Wii have pretty much been my primary consoles now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we is really awesome.
Speaker 1: But we've talked about that enough now.
Speaker 1: There is one game.
Speaker 1: Well, really two games that I ever liked on the Nintendo 64 not counting, you know, Zelda's or anything like that But games that were kind of party hasn't played.
Speaker 0: Zelda 64.
Speaker 1: I have played it.
Speaker 1: I have not beaten it.
Speaker 1: Uh, you haven't played it and I haven't played Majora's Mask.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 1: I watched you play the first five minutes of it.
Speaker 0: I can't play that game.
Speaker 1: I understand the plot of the game.
Speaker 1: I don't I read a spoiler.
Speaker 0: I barely understand it.
Speaker 0: All I know is three days and then you shit yourself.
Speaker 1: Now a lot of people seem to like this this fancy new game called Halo and They talk about how it's this great FPS and I have a whole Scott's making farting noises.
Speaker 1: I have this whole rant I could do and Scott agrees with me.
Speaker 1: I don't know which one of us came up with the first where for the most part It seems to me that people who like Halo as on FPS and not just as a console FPS But they say it's a good FPS and they like it and they find it anything more than just an average FPS Are people who never played.
Speaker 1: all the FPS is that came out years and years and years and years and years before.
Speaker 0: hey Laura least, you know, maybe they played them, but they didn't play them like.
Speaker 0: yeah I was one of those guys who played counter-strike.
Speaker 1: see I don't know.
Speaker 1: most of the people who play Halo and really like it have never really played FPS is on the PC?
Speaker 0: Nope, not really.
Speaker 1: No, but they also Regardless of that argument just put that away.
Speaker 1: Anyone who thinks Halo is a great multiplayer FPS for the console has never played.
Speaker 1: probably the best console FPS ever made GoldenEye for the Nintendo 64.
Speaker 0: I mean if you really look at it, Halo is just updated golden eye Yeah, and it doesn't really update much.
Speaker 0: I mean golden eye was the graphics.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah golden eye was not the best game.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say it was some great game.
Speaker 0: But for what it was in its day, it was fantastic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I hated console gaming.
Speaker 1: I just I didn't never thought that Nintendo 64 was gonna be worth it.
Speaker 1: I didn't really like any of the games on it.
Speaker 1: But I remember at band camp Every night in this rickety-ass cabin in the middle of the woods with this power cable going down the mountain We were playing golden eye until the Sun came up.
Speaker 0: Nothing was better than a little midget running around on a boat and there's a frickin Baron Samity with a top hat and he's got two RCP 90s and someone fires the rocket launcher and he goes flying into.
Speaker 1: All about the moonraker laser.
Speaker 0: moonraker laser for the win.
Speaker 1: My general strategy in that game was to go to any open area strafe back and forth randomly while firing my moonraker.
Speaker 0: Yeah There are basically three weapons in the game that I cared about.
Speaker 0: that was the moonraker laser The rocket launcher, of course and the RCP 90 which got damn dual RCP 90.
Speaker 0: You know RCP 90 just so many bullets.
Speaker 0: you could lag the game if you knew what to do now.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we're not gonna review the game even though it's a fantastic game.
Speaker 1: No, what I put the news here.
Speaker 1: Is that Reggie from Nintendo Reggie?
Speaker 0: Can you pronounce his last name for me?
Speaker 1: I think it's fees on me, whatever The point is they didn't have it in front of me So I wasn't gonna go over all the details of the news.
Speaker 1: The Nintendo does not have the rights to use this old bond game.
Speaker 1: They can't just release it on a new system or any.
Speaker 0: yeah, because what happened was is rare.
Speaker 0: the company that developed games like Donkey Kong Country and GoldenEye was purchased by Microsoft done And now they make Microsoft games for the Xbox and The rights to make James Bond games went to EA and then it's currently held by Activision.
Speaker 1: now This game has is no threat to bond games that are going to be coming out.
Speaker 1: No one's going to buy this and then not buy the new bond game based on the freaking awesome bond movie I saw over the weekend, but Nintendo has realized that there has been for the last many years a Massive fan outcry for any way of Nintendo bringing this game back.
Speaker 0: Because really the only way to play Goldeneye is to have a Nintendo 64 or to have a Nintendo 64 emulator.
Speaker 1: Everyone wanted it on the GameCube and Nintendo said they couldn't.
Speaker 0: and now with a virtual console Everyone really wants it on the virtual console I mean rare made perfect dark for the n64 which was sort of the same engine without the James Bond license and it was good.
Speaker 0: But it it wasn't the same as Goldeneye.
Speaker 0: I mean it was technically superior, but it wasn't the same.
Speaker 0: fun multiplayer action.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know, there are games like TimeSplitters 2 for the GameCube that provides similar action.
Speaker 0: There's Halo which provides similar action, but then there was perfect dark zero, which just sucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but we'll skip all that because it's not video game day.
Speaker 1: the news is simply that Nintendo pays attention to what its fans want and Reggie said that Nintendo is exploring all the options and basically doing everything it can To get this game on the virtual console so we can play it on the Wii.
Speaker 1: Now that even if they fail even if Microsoft, you know, and all the people involved won't budge and they can't get it Nintendo cannot lose by saying this because if they succeed They will make a lot of money on people buying this game on the virtual console.
Speaker 0: Ten bucks ten bucks ten bucks for Goldeneye.
Speaker 1: if there were twelve bucks I'd consider it I wouldn't but I don't know the twelve but we could split it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then it's only six bucks.
Speaker 0: shit All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah but even if they fail and nothing comes of this they made a lot of people happy just by saying that they're trying and They'll even end up making the people who won't let them get the game look like the bad guys.
Speaker 1: It's win-win.
Speaker 0: Also, you know in addition to the awesome multiplayer, which is the primary reason to get Goldeneye It gives the game with a really good single player.
Speaker 1: There was a single player.
Speaker 1: I never even touched it.
Speaker 0: You gotta play it man.
Speaker 0: It's actually good stuff.
Speaker 1: I only the only games I ever played on a Nintendo 64 were Goldeneye multiplayer and Mario tennis.
Speaker 0: You got it.
Speaker 0: If you played the Goldeneye single-player, you'll see there's actually really interesting maps and missions going on.
Speaker 1: No, once I played Smash Brothers, I thought it was the stupidest thing ever.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry You suck Smash Brothers for the GameCube.
Speaker 1: However, it was probably the best game to come out with that console.
Speaker 0: No, I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: Well to come out with as in in the launch window.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I mean I counted as a launch game because Luigi's Mansion wasn't a game.
Speaker 0: I wasn't.
Speaker 1: it was just general beauregard.
Speaker 1: Beauregard Things of the day.
Speaker 1: now, you're all familiar with anime music videos.
Speaker 1: You might be familiar with our opinions on the current state of anime music videos.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Have we really gone into complete detail on them on the show?
Speaker 1: I think we've tangentially got to.
Speaker 1: we'll do a show on anime music videos.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea right there.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think when we do that show We'll list and link to all the AMVs out there from back in the day that we think are good and then what I'd like to do probably is we'll get all of our listeners to Try to prove us wrong and find videos that are recent that are just as good.
Speaker 1: The only reason I don't see him is that due to the way the anime music into you Anime music video scene is set up.
Speaker 1: It's really hard for good music videos to become widely disseminated.
Speaker 0: It really needs to be.
Speaker 0: maybe there is one and I just haven't found it But there really needs to be a blog of some guy who?
Speaker 0: Checks all the new music videos and then puts the good ones up on it in a blog somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we need like the OC remixes equivalent of AMVs because currently anime music videos org is Ninety-nine percent crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, if you think that anime music videos are lame And we know a lot of people who do even though I think that they can be really cool and they have their use
Speaker 0: They have potential the thing is most of them are lame as it with anything else, you know, most movies are lame But movies are the potential to be.
Speaker 1: yeah I defy anyone to tell me that the anime music video to antenna set to that rock cover of hit me baby one more time Is lame.
Speaker 0: it's totally not lame.
Speaker 1: It's double on lame.
Speaker 1: But haven't you ever wondered why anime has had this music video thing?
Speaker 1: That's gotten so huge to the point that it's kind of a fixture at almost every anime con.
Speaker 1: Yet most other fandoms until recently didn't have anything similar.
Speaker 1: I mean now with this machinima and all that a lot of video games are starting to have the same thing.
Speaker 1: But I had never really seen anyone do this to a mainstream movie before.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh Until now.
Speaker 1: Oh my thing of the day is a I want to say anime music video, but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's a movie music video to Lord of the Rings set to the theme from Newsies Oh God.
Speaker 1: and There's a worse one out there, but I don't want to link to it.
Speaker 1: Probably the worst music video.
Speaker 0: This one is painful enough.
Speaker 0: How could it possibly be more painful?
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is this is about as bad as the average bad anime music video.
Speaker 1: So it's really not more painful than that except for the fact that if you haven't seen something like this That isn't too anime.
Speaker 1: It might seem worse.
Speaker 1: Yeah I guess my advice to you is that if you watch this and you cringe and then you watch a terrible anime music video and Don't cringe you've just become sensitized.
Speaker 1: Oh, that doesn't make the enemy Desensitized.
Speaker 0: Yeah desensitized.
Speaker 1: That doesn't make it any better.
Speaker 1: I mean the worst one I ever saw which if you want to find it You're on your own was done to the Horatio horn-blower television series and it was sent to the song candle on the water and it totally makes gay illusions about Kennedy and Horatio.
Speaker 0: It's literally just this song playing and like Horatio had a particular attachment to that video He just kept watching it and watching it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well if you really want to find the video I'm sure you can find it on the Horatio horn-blower fanfiction archives.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah There are more fanfics there than they're fucking well should be.
Speaker 0: So there's one.
Speaker 1: I'm okay with her being one fanfic to anything.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with that, but the sheer number of fanfics to Horatio hornblower.
Speaker 0: Good God okay, so My thing of the day is really simple.
Speaker 0: There's Pocky.
Speaker 0: We all know about Pocky.
Speaker 0: Yeah Pocky's that flavored sugar on a bready stick snack that they overstayed sell it For five bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they sell it at anime conventions for ludicrously high prices.
Speaker 0: But anyone who's smart enough to go to the Asian market or as a good grocery store like Wegmans Can get it at normal prices of a dollar for a whole lot of it.
Speaker 0: and it's tasty.
Speaker 0: and you know, it's a good snack.
Speaker 0: It's fun and there's many different flavors and everyone knows a Gundam is you know robots?
Speaker 0: Robot models robot anime manga video games, etc.
Speaker 1: Now what if you were somehow able to combine these two forces of good and righteousness.
Speaker 0: you eat a sugary robot?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Are you pilot a sugary breadstick?
Speaker 1: or perhaps you just buy Gundam branded Pocky?
Speaker 0: Yes, there is Gundam Pocky and basically they're trying to get More people in our demographic to eat the Pocky.
Speaker 1: I eat Pocky all the time.
Speaker 0: I know but I'm talking about in Japan.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is not.
Speaker 0: you know, you know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: They're gonna be people selling that pot.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm getting to.
Speaker 0: I'm getting to that.
Speaker 0: all right but they're taking the men's Pocky the default Pocky and this other flavor of Pocky and they're Including in the box of Pocky a pretty simple Gundam model.
Speaker 0: Oh really.
Speaker 0: and the simple Gundam model They show in the picture here.
Speaker 0: The model is holding a Pocky stick as if it's a sword And there's three different models For the different flavors.
Speaker 1: I think you have to get them all to put on your shelf of Gundams.
Speaker 0: No, I don't know but it's quite obvious that if you live in Japan Why not buy this for fun?
Speaker 0: if you live in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Expect people who run anime stores and and are dealers of anime goods You know to get this from Japan for like a dollar and to sell it to you for ten dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't buy this at an anime con.
Speaker 0: I'm just warning you right now don't pay more than five bucks for one of these things.
Speaker 0: It's really not worth it because you're gonna eat all the Pocky.
Speaker 0: You're gonna make a really cheap one dollar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Pocky's not really that filling.
Speaker 0: It really is.
Speaker 1: I mean I really like Pocky and I just kind of snagged on it.
Speaker 0: I like some of the flavors of Pocky.
Speaker 0: the strawberry Pocky is by far The most superior because it is the same filling as the strawberry koala.
Speaker 1: Now see I like milk Pocky a lot.
Speaker 0: Of course that is really the best Japanese snack ever.
Speaker 0: is the default koala?
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't get any other koala.
Speaker 1: The default koala is pretty much the even though koalas that's the cheapest ass chocolate squirted into the inside.
Speaker 0: Oh, it sure is but the default koala is by far the greatest Japanese.
Speaker 0: We need to do a show on Japanese snacks.
Speaker 0: See the thing is talk about the gummies.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about the yen yen's because when I see people eating Pocky and it doesn't really bother me I just kind of makes me chuckle.
Speaker 1: but when I eat Pocky I'll take like one stick and kind of nibble on it for a while It's kind of a you know, you nibble on it a little bit of flavor a little bit of flavor and it lasts you a while.
Speaker 1: I watch people at cons spend like five bucks to get this tiny ass thing of Pocky.
Speaker 1: They'll open it up They'll grab all the sticks.
Speaker 1: They'll eat them in the span of like ten seconds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is the thing.
Speaker 0: my problem with Pocky is that the sugary coating does not cover the whole Pocky.
Speaker 1: It's not supposed to that way.
Speaker 1: your fingers don't get sticky when it melts.
Speaker 0: I know but here's my problem.
Speaker 1: What's your problem?
Speaker 0: Is in a?
Speaker 0: you know, I take a bite I don't.
Speaker 0: I try not to bite.
Speaker 0: I could eat the whole thing in one go, but I don't.
Speaker 0: I take like one bite, you know Like I get a third of the sugary stuff then another third of the sugary stuff and then the final third of the sugary stuff.
Speaker 0: Now I'm left with just this little bread bit and the bread bit doesn't really taste as good.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: I like the bread.
Speaker 0: I don't like the bread bit.
Speaker 0: I'm not a fan.
Speaker 1: like not be a fan of the bread.
Speaker 0: if I didn't feel bad about it I would throw the bread bit away.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: That's like those people who only eat the top of the muffin?
Speaker 0: I know I hate those people because.
Speaker 1: but or the people who cut only?
Speaker 0: yeah I hate people who cut the crust off the sand.
Speaker 1: I like how you knew what I was gonna say.
Speaker 0: the crust say it.
Speaker 0: yet The crust is where all the action is on the sandwich.
Speaker 0: That's the best part of the bread case.
Speaker 1: in point to Bella's They make the best subs ever other than you know, delis in New York City run by awesome people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but de Bella's the baked crust all around that sub bread is what makes 99% of that sandwich.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: but Pocky's the only thing where I I don't like the bready bit at the end.
Speaker 1: So you're one of those guys.
Speaker 0: yeah, but I do like Gundam models and I do like Pocky in general.
Speaker 1: So so there's no reason for you to not buy this Too much money.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we'll find available.
Speaker 1: We'll find it.
Speaker 1: We'll find it somewhere for a reasonable price.
Speaker 0: if anyone's out in Japan Go check the stores.
Speaker 0: either some Gundam Pocky.
Speaker 1: Yeah mail some back to Scott.
Speaker 0: I'll send you five bucks.
Speaker 0: I'll PayPal you five hours, right?
Speaker 1: So we were gonna do cuz.
Speaker 1: anime world order has been talking lately about you know, anime clubs.
Speaker 1: they've been asking people to Tell them about their anime club and they have this thing about how anime club seemed to be failing and I recently emailed them and provided The counter example the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: that's doing just fine and it's freaking gigantic and you know various things like that.
Speaker 1: We're having a little back and forth But I realized as a result that we should do a show on how to run an anime club.
Speaker 0: We should do that partly
Speaker 1: because we run that panel along with our friend Scott Johnson at I don't know almost every single major con in the northeastern United States,
Speaker 0: yeah, and
Speaker 1: I mean other than that We ran the biggest freaking club in the country for years and years and the club's still doing really well even though these other clubs are failing and I told them that we would do that show this week and then Now it's late and I want to go to bed.
Speaker 1: So instead we're gonna make peace with some of our listeners who have been bugging us for doing more comics on the show Which we haven't done in a while.
Speaker 0: Oh, I see some people just went Yeah, and some other people just went off fuck and they turned it off.
Speaker 1: Yeah But we're gonna talk about mouse guard which in my opinion is a really cool little comic but stay tuned for next week.
Speaker 1: Well, we're going to tell you exactly in explicit detail how to make an anime club successful in the United States in the modern times.
Speaker 0: Yes, and also we'll probably Skype in our friend Scott Johnson if he's available.
Speaker 1: Yeah We might have to make it a multi-part series considering that it tends to be a one or two hour panel at Conventions and we don't even cover half of it there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway Mouse Guard, so Months ago when Mouse Card first hit the street, you know, it was just a little tiny indie comic about Adventuring mice and you know who buys that and it's only sold in comic book stores.
Speaker 0: Not something you can find at borders.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't go to comic book stores.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't know this existed.
Speaker 0: So, you know who freakin knows about this thing, you know, not a lot of people go to comic book stores.
Speaker 0: They're buying the superheroes.
Speaker 0: They're not buying the little adventuring mice.
Speaker 0: So they did a very small print run and What do you know sold out?
Speaker 0: So what did they do?
Speaker 0: They said oh shit and fucking sold out.
Speaker 0: What do we do now?
Speaker 0: Oh print some more.
Speaker 0: All right print some more sold out.
Speaker 0: Mouse Guard number one I think is on like the fourth or fifth printing or something ridiculous like that.
Speaker 0: I mean in total numbers It's only sold I think tens of thousands of copies.
Speaker 0: But for an indie comic it's pretty much the hit indie comic of the year like far and away.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean take remember this I Generally do not enjoy the vast majority of American created comic books.
Speaker 1: I've said this openly and often.
Speaker 1: you might have heard when Scott talked about Captain Marvell and all that and my feelings as to that comic.
Speaker 1: So if I like a comic that's probably the most ringing endorsement you'll ever hear because it takes a lot for me to like a Comic.
Speaker 1: Mouse Guard is probably one of my favorite comics other than Scott Pilgrim to come out in recent memory.
Speaker 0: So if you try to buy like the first printing of Mouse Guard number one on eBay right now It'll cost you like a hundred bucks eighty bucks.
Speaker 0: It's it's out of control Really?
Speaker 0: You can easily get though like the new the current printings of these things at the the comic book store or the Internet Or any other place that sells comic books.
Speaker 0: now First thing you notice about Mouse Guard is it's a comic book sold issue by issue.
Speaker 0: I think it's what a six-part series.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that and there's gonna be a trade.
Speaker 0: So if you wait and I if you you know, don't have a comic store I suggest you wait.
Speaker 0: there will be I guarantee because I asked the guy who writes the damn thing David Peterson, David Peterson I saw him at Wizard World Philly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he signed some of your books.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not that I care, but he said there will be a trade.
Speaker 0: So eventually perhaps probably next year sometime I don't know that you'll be able to go to borders or Walden books or where Barnes & Noble or Amazon and buy Mouse Guard the whole thing in one book.
Speaker 0: So write it down and don't forget until then.
Speaker 1: So what's Mouse Guard about?
Speaker 1: I mean, why would we go and not just us but half the internet and half the comic community go nuts about this Tiny little comic.
Speaker 1: I mean the first one is 15 pages and it's kind of small and square and there are very few words in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't look like a comic book Like, you know, it's about as thick as a comic book and it's bound like a comic book But it looks like a record single cover.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: it looks like, you know, the tiny vinyl records, you know It's it's square and the cover is a little heavier stock than most comic books and the paper is heavier stock and the colors are Like I don't know what ink they use but it's really bright and a lot nicer than you know Most comic books these days with their newsprint or whatever they do it on
Speaker 1: Because it's so few pages and just the way it is they seem to have gone really all out on the production values.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what?
Speaker 0: what's the publisher?
Speaker 1: our chaos studio ass comics or our chaos studio press?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's her ass comics.
Speaker 1: calm That's right.
Speaker 0: Our chaos publishes a whole lot of fantasy stuff and they basically picked up David Peterson who was doing the mouse guard thing on his own As soon as they said, oh shit, that's awesome.
Speaker 1: So we can't really I mean we would review the comic in terms of talking about the plot in the story But it's so short and not a lot happens to where.
Speaker 1: really ruining even a single plot detail Wouldn't would really do you guys a disservice, right?
Speaker 0: so I think the best way to go about this is we can talk about like the universe and the setting of mouse guard and This like the first like the setup of the first three pages or so.
Speaker 1: so first off I mean forget about Mouse and Mouse guard.
Speaker 1: the setting here is simply kind of a Medieval low-technology era with little city-states here and there and there's this guard and the guard is kind of like an order of Knights and Rangers that protect the kingdom or the little city-state and protect travel routes and generally keep the peace.
Speaker 0: Yep, and You know, there isn't really a lot of magic going on.
Speaker 0: I mean there might be but it's not like this Wizards casting fireballs It's magic more like medieval.
Speaker 1: people believe a lot of funny things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean these.
Speaker 0: they have swords and daggers and shields and armors and cloaks and general medieval action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like that general medieval action.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The other thing they've got is political intrigue.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I mean the first plot starts out very simple.
Speaker 1: just a farmer is traveling carrying a shipment of grain and he disappears.
Speaker 1: So three guardsmen go out to find him and in the course of this they end up fighting a giant snake.
Speaker 0: Oh My god a giant snake.
Speaker 1: and also the actual plot or the leanings of the real plot are introduced to you And it is very much a kind of political intrigue between city-states warring factions kind of cool medieval style plot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's one.
Speaker 0: It's that standard plot hook that works really well every time where there's a very very small and Insignificant like task and you mean like a hobbit traveling through some cave and he happens to pick up a ring along the way.
Speaker 1: No, it's a little more subtle than that, you know, but like three mice going out to figure out what happened to a fourth mouse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, you know that you go out and it's like, okay We're going to go catch this robber and then you catch the robber.
Speaker 0: But then you realize there's more to this than just catching a rob.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you open his bag after you kill him and he didn't have money.
Speaker 1: He had a nuclear bomb.
Speaker 0: So, you know or wait a minute, there's a whole mafia behind that, you know, something like that.
Speaker 0: So that's what mouse guard is and I don't want to spoil anything because it's okay.
Speaker 1: now that alone would be an average You know medieval story.
Speaker 1: I mean it would be made or broken based more on how it was executed and the art and the dialogue than it would on the actual plot because the plot is very simple.
Speaker 1: but mouse guard in addition to all that is about mice and It's not like.
Speaker 1: they go out of their way to make it mousey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not like, you know, you read something like rats of NIMH, which I love and red wall Which I surprisingly don't like at all.
Speaker 0: I write course granted.
Speaker 0: I haven't read it since middle school.
Speaker 1: You ever see the rats of NIMH movie?
Speaker 1: No, but I got a rant about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the Rats of NIMH the book is great.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I think I read the sequel, but I don't remember it.
Speaker 0: and Red wall, you know those.
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: who's the guy who writes those things?
Speaker 1: Oh god, I don't remember but I like red wall.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I read one of them in middle school and didn't like it.
Speaker 0: So I can't say whether I'd like it now, but I didn't like it then.
Speaker 0: but this is supposed like.
Speaker 0: Supposedly the mouse guard guy didn't even know about red wall when he came up with it or so I hear there's an interview with him on What's that podcast?
Speaker 0: Indie spinner rack.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we met those guys at mocha remember for like two minutes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep But I mean in terms it's just it.
Speaker 1: that whole story We read is the plot except that they're mice and they don't go out like.
Speaker 1: they don't say like, haha I am a mouse.
Speaker 1: It's just they're mice and like say one of them has a weapon and the weapon happens to be a fish hook.
Speaker 1: They don't say it's a fish hook.
Speaker 1: They don't zoom out and show like the human drop in the facial didn't show humans.
Speaker 1: None of that it.
Speaker 1: just the guy has a fish hook and he uses it as a weapon.
Speaker 1: and that's that.
Speaker 1: it's just part of the.
Speaker 0: It's like all the mousiness of it really is in the illustration.
Speaker 0: You could take the writing of this comic and totally change the setting just by changing all the pictures to have them be humans or aliens or some other anthropomorphic Beast of some sort, you know, it's just the way it's drawn.
Speaker 0: They're mice and you know big thing.
Speaker 0: You know things that are small to us are big and dangerous to them and they use very tiny things.
Speaker 1: and that's how it So like a human night would fight a dragon and a mouse night fights a normal snake or a crab.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes the crabs crabs.
Speaker 1: But genius, I mean really it's such a standard straight-up cool medieval plot and the atmosphere of the mousiness Just for some reason adds so much charm to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing is a lot of you know stories that use like an anthropomorphic mice and other things Stories about adventuring cats or something like that.
Speaker 0: if they're I'm sure there are some puss in boots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they tend to not have like, you know, the super intelligent plots, you know, it's this the plot is so highbrow like with its political intrigues and Social commentaries, you know, I mean not much happens because it's.
Speaker 1: we only got about four little tiny comic issues Yeah, but yet there's such a world within the comic that they don't directly tell you about.
Speaker 1: it's just there.
Speaker 1: It's kind of this atmosphere around it.
Speaker 1: It's obvious that the author Put a lot more effort into the world that is shown in the comic like he built all the backstory in Order to write this story within it.
Speaker 1: I mean if I read the the opening bit from you know Before the comic starts kind of the preamble the mice struggle to live safely and prosper among all the world's harsh conditions and predators.
Speaker 1: Thus the mouse guard was formed after persevering against the weasel warlord in the Winter War of 1149. the territories are no longer is troubled true the day-to-day dangers exist, but no longer are the guard soldiers Yeah, but no longer are the guard soldiers.
Speaker 1: instead They are escorts pathfinders weather watchers scouts and bodyguards for the mice who live among the territories.
Speaker 1: Many skills are necessary for the guard to keep the border safe.
Speaker 1: They must find new Safeways and paths from village to village leads shipments of goods from one town to another and in case of attack Guard against all evil and harm to their territories.
Speaker 1: hail to those who are able.
Speaker 1: any mouse can any mouse will but the guard Prevail.
Speaker 1: yep, it was a little hard to read the fonts kind of funny, and I kept losing my place.
Speaker 1: So I apologize.
Speaker 0: it's a nice font though.
Speaker 1: It is it's just not a nice font for reading extemporaneously into a microphone.
Speaker 0: Yeah So there's three main characters the three guards mice and then every other character is basically yeah Not a guards.
Speaker 1: my Liam Kenzie and Saxon.
Speaker 0: yeah I don't know which ones are which.
Speaker 1: Liam is the like young brash really funny guy with the green cloak.
Speaker 1: Kenzie is kind of the old wise one traveling with them and Saxon is the gruff fighter.
Speaker 0: ah Yep, that's correct.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there you have it your adventuring party.
Speaker 1: now I really want to take a moment to talk about the art because the art adds so much to this.
Speaker 0: the arts pretty much the Whole damn thing.
Speaker 0: when you get right down to it.
Speaker 1: I mean the mice are really kind of stylized, but I hate to say this, but they're in many cases Absolutely adorable.
Speaker 0: it depends on the and the panel but in some panels.
Speaker 0: It's like you a mouse and other panels.
Speaker 1: It's like But their faces are so expressive and yet there don't seem to be a lot of liberties taken in terms of stylizing the faces.
Speaker 1: most of their Emotion is expressed merely through the way they hold their eyes and their whiskers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sometimes the mouth is open and the ears.
Speaker 0: actually he does a lot.
Speaker 0: Yes Yes You know sometimes the ears like folded one way or the other and that change and also the direction the head is facing is huge.
Speaker 0: It's like whenever their head is pointing up.
Speaker 0: It's always kind of cute.
Speaker 0: Whatever the head is pointing down.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like And it does.
Speaker 0: it doesn't do any use of the angle of the head instead of eyebrows.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's definitely not you know a manga or anything and it doesn't really have like super deformed or any of that stuff.
Speaker 1: But there are many cases when a mouse that's in the background or whenever they draw a mouse small They'll very pointedly use dot eyes and a kind of more stylized mouse and it's very cute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm looking at one right now and I almost want to just crack up.
Speaker 1: But at the same time on that same page is the mice doing something kind of horrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah They're.
Speaker 0: all the background are is Like.
Speaker 0: it's like the mouse.
Speaker 0: the mice really kind of stand out from the backgrounds at all times.
Speaker 0: Yes It's a good thing.
Speaker 0: the camera
Speaker 1: if there were a camera is very low like the camera is Underneath the mice that almost all times you're always looking up at them You almost immediately forget the fact that they're small mice and it feels like they're as big as us
Speaker 0: Except for when there's something bigger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even then I mean you see a crab and you don't feel like wow Look how small the mouse is.
Speaker 1: That's a crab.
Speaker 1: you feel like wow That crab is huge.
Speaker 0: Yep, but like everything else that's not a mouse.
Speaker 0: That's drawn is sort of like this like fantasy style that you know, what's the who's the guy who painted with the dots?
Speaker 1: I Can think of a lot of impressionist people who painted with dots, you know, they were instead of you didn't do the brushstrokes.
Speaker 0: He just did.
Speaker 0: you know a bunch of colored dots.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like that.
Speaker 0: There's lots of dots and just simple lines.
Speaker 0: There's a whole lot of them and that's what makes the backgrounds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the backgrounds are also.
Speaker 1: they're very atmospheric and they're in fact even the panels.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of panels that kind of do Really not plot.
Speaker 1: important setup.
Speaker 1: Just a lot of you know a mouse standing there or while they're talking It cuts to like a shot of the three of them from underneath and then while they're talking still it cuts to like one of them Holding the sword and then it cuts to like the Sun setting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the backgrounds they really aren't busy either.
Speaker 0: It's like he puts just enough there to be necessary.
Speaker 0: I mean like here's a frame with two mice fighting and you can tell there's a crowd of mice watching But it's basically just a brown splotch with some lines around it, you know.
Speaker 0: But you can totally tell what it is and it keeps your focus on what's important because the mice in the frame look really cool.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, it's not a bad thing.
Speaker 0: It's just that's the way it is.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of frames So there is no background.
Speaker 0: It's just like they're in a place with dirt.
Speaker 0: So it's it's kind of brown with shadows.
Speaker 1: I mean it.
Speaker 1: there's kind of the conundrum of.
Speaker 1: it's hard to really talk about something easily if you like it and I'm sure we were a little bit redundant.
Speaker 1: and it's also hard considering that we didn't want to talk about the plot at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: It's we got such a small amount of material to work with and if we say any amount of it We basically ruin the whole thing not
Speaker 1: to mention the fact that we did this episode because we didn't feel like doing the other episode We were supposed to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's good to pimp mouse guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just you know, I mean, it's basically.
Speaker 0: It's already a hit but it's like a hit in like this subculture.
Speaker 0: So people outside don't know that there's this awesome thing hiding away somewhere for them to go get.
Speaker 1: Mouse guard is so worth it to read.
Speaker 1: I can't recommend it enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean It's 350 an issue and I think there's five issues out now.
Speaker 0: So it's a 15 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it takes almost no commitment.
Speaker 1: It's actually really short.
Speaker 1: It's really good.
Speaker 1: Even if you hate it, you've invested so little into it that you might as well go for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you're really, you know, if you're really stuck up about it You know just go like read one at a store a comic book store or buy one issue online.
Speaker 0: It's easy to get a new printing.
Speaker 0: Don't waste $100 in the first printing.
Speaker 0: what the hell's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: In fact, if nothing else just buy the first one the first comic.
Speaker 1: it's 350.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm sure you can find it and if you're not hooked by the first comic don't bother.
Speaker 0: But if you like the first comic at all, if you're a fan of fantasy anything or comic anything I can pretty much guarantee you're gonna go Oh shits and buy the rest or wait for the trade and cry every day until the trade comes out.
Speaker 1: Yeah because seriously Even if these this weren't about mice I would probably still like it.
Speaker 1: the fact that it's about mice and it's about mice in such An amazing and well put together way.
Speaker 1: It's just bonus.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 0: it's like anyone can make a fantasy comic.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of anyone can make you know, an anthropomorphic mice comic.
Speaker 0: It's nothing to make a really damn good fantasy comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also have the really clever, you know and not the Kind of played out anthropomorphic mice setting.
Speaker 0: it's like all double bonus super combo Hundred hits you go down.
Speaker 0: I win.
Speaker 1: And also one last bit not about mouse guard, but about Wednesday shows.
Speaker 1: We've talked a bit about how we're going to do another final thought slash spoiler episode in the future and we've asked for your feedback.
Speaker 1: So we took all the nominations and in the forums on our website front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: right now There is a poll that if you are a registered member of the forums You can see and vote in once.
Speaker 1: all the votes are tabulated.
Speaker 1: We're giving you a few weeks to make sure you know everyone who wants to vote has voted.
Speaker 1: we are going to fully analyze whatever show you've picked as We did with big o2 many moons ago.
Speaker 0: So if you would like us to fully analyze, you know in great detail a particular anime that we have seen including You know the end and the spoilers and everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah Either go to the forum and vote or if you're not a member of the forum join the forum and vote.
Speaker 1: if you really really Don't want to join the forum email us and we'll tabulate your vote for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's kind of lame.
Speaker 0: that is kind of lame.
Speaker 0: If you listen to this show, you should really join the forum.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the forums are actually really really rocking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't keep up with them anymore.
Speaker 1: Also, if you don't want us to do a show like say you've never seen try gun for some reason Which is actually right now the front-runner You might want to vote against it because try guns awesome and you won't be able to listen until you watch try gun.
Speaker 1: It seems to be between try gun and Ava at this point Though ghost in the shell standalone complex and samurai chamblee have a surprising number of votes so far.
Speaker 0: That's good because both those shows are cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what are we gonna say about samurai chamblee?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: the thing is that there's a lot you could.
Speaker 0: we could probably talk about the show for a whole episode you know detailing the whole thing, but It's not a deep show as deep as some of the other ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah hidden meanings like in the very least philosophical Analyzing like standalone complex in the very least.
Speaker 1: we would talk about a certain thing that happens and spend a whole episode talking about that Thing pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah the thing that we can't talk about because it's probably the biggest spoiler in the whole show.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, though try gun.
Speaker 1: We could probably do multiple episodes on and Ava.
Speaker 1: God we have a week.
Speaker 1: Will they do ten a month?
Speaker 1: And we'll be tied if we ever watch fist of the North Star?
Speaker 0: Well, but I'd if we like if you would freakin read all six volumes of Akira.
Speaker 0: We need to cure a year.
Speaker 1: God we could do the Akira movie, but you know what he blows.
Speaker 1: it gets big and fat It turns into a blob crushes people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the end of Akira.
Speaker 1: And you know what everyone dies in the end of Ava.
Speaker 0: Yeah, is the thing with the Akira movie is that it's really good.
Speaker 0: But then if you read the Akira manga the movie doesn't seem so good anymore because the manga is just so damn good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not to say that Akira is a is not a good movie.
Speaker 1: It's fantastic.
Speaker 1: It's like with roller coasters.
Speaker 1: if you go to cedar point and you ride the magnum XL 200 which was at one point the tallest roller coaster in the world.
Speaker 1: It's an amazing roller coaster.
Speaker 1: if you ride the millennium force Which is a hundred and something feet taller than that and so much better.
Speaker 1: if you ride the millennium force first and you go back and try to ride the magnum XL 200 You'll just be thinking what the fuck is this shit Charles?
Speaker 0: That's exactly what it is.
Speaker 0: so Everyone should read the Akira manga because it's so good, but you should watch the Akira movie first.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have the maximum enjoyment in your life and then go watch the Akira movie again, and you'll go.
Speaker 1: Oh Plus the Akira movie leaves a lot to be explained.
Speaker 1: You'll probably wonder about a lot of what was going on.
Speaker 0: is we could do a whole episode of this?
Speaker 0: Let's not let's stop doing an entire other episode and save it.
Speaker 1: Suffice to say read mouse guard read Akira, and we'll see you tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website Which has everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.