Speaker 0: It's Thursday March 9th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about how not to suck at life Specifically how to deal with dangerous awkward and otherwise odd situations.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So today I get to work around 9 around usual time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually rolled in around 11 since I slept through my alarm.
Speaker 1: awesome, so Around 10, you know the phones start resetting which is what happens when they can't get an IP address because they're all vo IP phones.
Speaker 1: and since my computer is plugged into the phone, I lost my internet connection also and It didn't.
Speaker 1: usually it resets once and then it comes back online, you know Cuz sometimes a little hiccup and the phones are real sensitive.
Speaker 1: yeah, so it didn't come back on and the phones kept resetting and resetting and resetting.
Speaker 1: so I used my cell phone, which is the only Communication device I had at all that would work and called my boss and I said Hey, can you go to the optimum online website and tell me the system status?
Speaker 1: and he says There's a major outage.
Speaker 1: go home and I'm like, I drove an hour to get here and I've been here an hour.
Speaker 1: Why why would I drive an hour to get home now?
Speaker 1: That's just silly.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends what if there was nothing out there to do.
Speaker 0: I just drive home immediately.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but my parents house is like 30 minutes away.
Speaker 1: So I went there.
Speaker 1: I didn't figure you know, I called my mom and she was home.
Speaker 1: So hey, why not?
Speaker 0: Hey, you should have gone to Stu Leonard's Maybe yeah on the way home.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we still have croutons though.
Speaker 0: It's all good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I went to.
Speaker 1: I went to stop and shop and I got some good food there.
Speaker 1: we'll see if it you know tastes good some I try.
Speaker 1: got some new things there and You know, so that story didn't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: You know stuff The internet.
Speaker 1: well, here's the end of the story.
Speaker 1: I got an email that says yeah The Internet's not gonna be up there tomorrow either.
Speaker 1: don't go to work tomorrow.
Speaker 1: So I might finish that theme tomorrow everybody.
Speaker 0: Hey, at least they warned you.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah this weekend.
Speaker 0: We're doing a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do the theme Hopefully we're gonna do a Libsyn hopefully Awesome gonna gonna get all that crap done for all you people's and for us people's.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll rearrange the furniture in my room also.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure they all just care about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so in the news IBM now they've been doing a lot of arts outsourcing and a lot of companies been outsourcing mostly to India but also to Vietnam and Russia in various places.
Speaker 0: now IBM is doing something that hasn't been done often and they're doing it very Much.
Speaker 0: so they're outsourcing high-level jobs as opposed to low-level jobs.
Speaker 0: so normally when you hear about outsourcing you think you know, all right, they're outsourcing tech support or Phone calls like phone data centers or whatever or maybe chip manufacturing.
Speaker 0: now They're outsourcing actual solutions development to Bangalore, India.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well those Indian people are smart.
Speaker 1: They know what they're doing kind exactly.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: a lot of people in this country seem to be very unafraid of outsourcing because they say Oh, no one can do the job.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: Haha.
Speaker 0: I'm a smart American and Now that's really not the case.
Speaker 1: you're not special and those other people are smarter and they'll be willing to get paid less.
Speaker 0: They're also more determined.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Your choices are pretty much beat them in terms of how much you're willing to be paid and you know your quality of life and such or Be unemployed when they take your job.
Speaker 0: See, I'm very glad that I'm in IT because the part of the stuff I do is actually very difficult to outsource because I physically Do things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't seem to have problems getting a job either.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, honestly, I got three job offers in the past week and all of them are very enticing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when I had my resume up, I got a whole bunch, you know It's just a lot of them were kind of like I didn't want to do them as opposed to they didn't want me You know.
Speaker 1: and then I finally picked one and I got it and maybe a little while from now.
Speaker 1: I'll go find another one.
Speaker 0: Yeah but IBM already has almost 40,000 workers in India and they're going to be expanding that greatly.
Speaker 0: and I find it interesting that they claim They're not gonna fire anyone over this.
Speaker 0: They're gonna you know business speak realign their watch hits and inward-facing blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: But they're gonna repurpose all of the facilities that otherwise would be closed down that used to do what they're shipping off to India Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I wonder how long that'll last.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then there'll be this layoff that's completely unrelated to those Outsources, but that'll be at least years down the road.
Speaker 0: I do know that IBM despite all of its problems is very good about when when something's gonna be shut down.
Speaker 0: They give everyone who works for them time to at least find other jobs.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and if you can't find another job, then you probably deserve to be laid off anyway, because you're worthless.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I used to think that the IT industry was really in a lot in a rut, but not so much I mean, I'm really not kidding.
Speaker 0: I've gotten not just like oh, let's interview this person.
Speaker 0: But hey, do you want a job?
Speaker 0: many of them like people call me constantly now because I put my resume up online a few weeks ago and they just keep offering me more and For various jobs all over the place.
Speaker 1: because I think what happened is in the in the early 90s.
Speaker 1: there they when there was an explosion there was almost on this huge demand for I information in IT and CS workers and such and They fulfilled that demand by hiring, you know people who are like high school kids and stuff and everything.
Speaker 1: It was crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean when we were in high school You could get a job making web pages if you knew basic HTML and they'd pay you 10 20 bucks an hour.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are crazy times.
Speaker 0: yeah for any of you who missed the dot-com boom It was a an awesome time to be alive and I'm glad that I was not in the industry when it crashed.
Speaker 1: I am also glad anyway, but after that, you know it's like all of a sudden all these people who are CS and IT majors started graduating from school and people started taking CS and IT as as their major because there was big money in it.
Speaker 1: So now there's company and then yeah, and then all the companies met a business.
Speaker 1: So the demand decreased and the supply increased.
Speaker 1: But now We have this Increasing demand still for real IT and CS jobs and not companies that are gonna disappear tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah and there's a lot of companies that have people already who don't really have the skills the company needs.
Speaker 1: and all those IT and CS Graduates that you know took it for the money aren't really smart and they don't really know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: granted I took it just for the money, but this stuff isn't that complicated if you actually paid attention at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and You know, it was like in CS.
Speaker 1: You could always tell the people who knew it was going on.
Speaker 1: It was like two levels of programmers.
Speaker 1: There are people who did the CS work as work and they didn't care about computers or CS at all outside of their schoolwork.
Speaker 1: Those people didn't really make it.
Speaker 1: they got lame jobs.
Speaker 1: the people who code and you know coded before they got to school Coded things in their spare time and continued to code their own things after graduating.
Speaker 1: Those are the people that are worth something like me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, IT is much broader because the skill base is very varied and it really depends on where you're working and what you're doing.
Speaker 1: Well, this is a very varied skill base for CS.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, but yeah IT is very different from CS in that really people skills and just being generally smart matter a lot more than Knowing about specific tech because anytime you change jobs Every company uses a completely different tech.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have to learn it all over again.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but as long as you know the base like the like if you know TCP IP you can deal with whatever crap They throw at you.
Speaker 0: networking wise, you know.
Speaker 1: Yes, CS is sort of the same way.
Speaker 1: if you know object-oriented programming you can do whatever language they want.
Speaker 1: The thing is people always people don't know how to hire CS people, you know That's one thing that Joel on software always writes about is how to hire programmers.
Speaker 0: now actually, there seems to be a very large market growing in companies or people who know how to hire people and they offer their services to Companies to find them people so the HR people don't hire someone stupid.
Speaker 1: The thing is is that those people themselves are good workers that are now getting paid to Essentially not do work that they should be hired to do and that you know, that's fine.
Speaker 0: I Mean the thing is it's all well and good to care about your job but I work mostly because they pay me and I use the fact that I am paid to Fund all of my other fun things like podcasting or anime conventions or real life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I work for the money.
Speaker 0: But also I would not do a job if it was not if it was extremely painful to do Well, yeah, I mean being stung by bees in the eye that that's not the most fun job and it is rather painful.
Speaker 1: I meant like, you know a job I didn't like.
Speaker 0: I've liked almost no job I've ever had like.
Speaker 1: if they paid me my current salary Even if they paid me double my current salary if my job was like filing papers in a cubicle or something If someone paid wouldn't do it.
Speaker 0: if someone paid me double my current salary I'd do whatever they asked and then I just quit after a few years with a pile of money.
Speaker 1: No, I wouldn't do it It would have.
Speaker 1: it's not worth my time to do something.
Speaker 1: That's so unpleasant.
Speaker 1: No matter what I'm paid Well, not no matter what I'm paid They could pay me so much that I would only have to do it for like a week or two and then I could quit.
Speaker 0: no, no your example double your salary.
Speaker 0: if I was making six figures and All I had to do was file papers, that's great.
Speaker 0: I do it for two years.
Speaker 0: I have a giant pile of money.
Speaker 0: I'd quit and I'd go do something fun.
Speaker 1: No, cuz if I was getting paid six figures and I was filing papers after like a month I would just want to kill myself and it wouldn't be worth the money.
Speaker 1: Just that the immense pain of filing papers all day every day.
Speaker 0: See I don't find it painful to me.
Speaker 0: the eight hours I spend at work is lost no matter what.
Speaker 0: so I really don't care what I'm doing.
Speaker 0: if I work for a company They're buying my time and I will give them my time and I'll do whatever they ask Me of me in that time.
Speaker 0: and other than that I really don't care so that time's not lost to me.
Speaker 1: My entire goal in life is to get back as much of that time as possible while still getting enough money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the best way to get that back is to become rich and not have to work.
Speaker 1: Well, there's one way but the other way is to do work.
Speaker 1: That isn't a loss of time.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I don't think I could ever have a job in technology that I wouldn't consider a loss of time.
Speaker 1: I think I could.
Speaker 0: yeah, well coding is very different.
Speaker 0: coding.
Speaker 0: you create things.
Speaker 0: IT.
Speaker 0: you maintain things.
Speaker 1: I maintain things that are already created.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you also create new things.
Speaker 0: I don't create anything other than maybe a bash script here or there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we've gone off on a long tangent.
Speaker 0: The point is IBM is outsourcing.
Speaker 0: This is even technology.
Speaker 0: This is like solutions development stuff But high-level work that they're just outsourcing to India because there's no reason to keep it here in the u.s suck For some people.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Hooray for some other people.
Speaker 0: Globalism Actually.
Speaker 1: President Bush had a recent comment about outsourcing that was actually Uncharacteristically intelligent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, his speechwriter must have gotten a raise or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what he said?
Speaker 1: he was talking about outsourcing to India and he said yeah, it's a natural economic thing.
Speaker 1: It's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: All right, whatever you think about that.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: The next thing he said was you know Maybe you American people should think about making things to sell to all those middle-class people in India.
Speaker 0: And I was like, yeah, maybe we should Except no one wants to make anything here.
Speaker 0: No one wants a factory in their account in their town.
Speaker 1: Ah Just cuz you don't want one.
Speaker 1: at least Bush is at least willing to say it's not anything you need it.
Speaker 0: honestly I don't think he really paid attention to what he was saying.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure that was a speech writer and some AIDS could be but he did say it.
Speaker 1: Whether he meant it or knew it or not.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he said it so we'll go by it.
Speaker 1: All right, so in the other news Hillary Clinton our senator and Joe Lieberman my former senator not the greatest senators in the world, but not the worst but whatever I don't consider very many senators at all to be anywhere near great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Obama's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's.
Speaker 0: even though he's not great He's good, but he hasn't done anything amazing.
Speaker 1: Nope anyway, these two people have been notorious for anti video gaming actions and Just today they passed a bill.
Speaker 1: they didn't pass the bill into law.
Speaker 1: they passed it out of the committee into the Senate and it is the Children and Media Research Advancement Act the camera.
Speaker 0: Now isn't this the law?
Speaker 0: that's just supposed to put money.
Speaker 0: So the CDC will investigate the effects of games on kids.
Speaker 1: That is the major.
Speaker 1: the law does a lot of things but the number one thing it does is the Center for Disease Control And Prevention is going to do a major study.
Speaker 1: basically, they're paid.
Speaker 1: they agreed to Give them 90 million dollars to create evidence that shows that video games make violence and such and such as that.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is if they actually do science these studies could show that video games don't do anything.
Speaker 1: Yep And the problem is will they do science or will they just do basically?
Speaker 1: What you know happens when Microsoft pays someone to do a study?
Speaker 1: Microsoft the answer they want.
Speaker 0: Lieberman is very Devoted to this cause Hillary.
Speaker 0: However, I Really think that the only reason she even is ever anywhere near this issue is simply because it gives her a way to look Good in front of various soccer bomb types or other conservatives
Speaker 1: Maybe who knows we don't know them But
Speaker 0: because most of her other ideas and policies are generally very good and well
Speaker 1: Most of Joe Lieberman's other ideas are generally very good.
Speaker 1: I'd say he's about 80% good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know It's just I can't tell and there's no way to know.
Speaker 1: but maybe we should go ask the CDC what they're gonna do.
Speaker 1: And why is it the CDC that's doing this study?
Speaker 0: because that the Centers for Disease Control.
Speaker 0: One of the main things they do is they research possible threats to the health and well-being of Americans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't know if this really falls into a disease category, but if it has Physiological or psychological effects that it definitely does.
Speaker 1: Well, it says here that the advocacy group Citizens against the government waste.
Speaker 1: I'm for that.
Speaker 1: I am against government waste.
Speaker 0: careful The way the government works is that any time there's something named something and me it it's.
Speaker 0: it's actually rooting for the exact opposite.
Speaker 1: You mean how the Constitution Party wants to destroy the Constitution or how the Federalist Party was?
Speaker 0: Anti-federalist and the anti-federalists were actually federalists.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, they deemed Lieberman the porker of the month Criticizing him for spending taxpayer money on redundant studies already undertaken by groups like the Kaiser Family Foundation And the American Academy of Pediatrics, huh?
Speaker 1: so, you know knowing that that lends a little bit more credence to the point that This study is them trying to buy a study that gives them the result they want as opposed to a study that desperately needs To be done because it's already being done.
Speaker 0: It's probably a lot like the Porn stuff that the government's doing been doing lately against Google where they want to subpoena all their search results So they can see how much porn is out there perhaps.
Speaker 1: I Just don't like the whole thing.
Speaker 1: The government really shouldn't you know?
Speaker 1: Because the simple fact is they shouldn't be legislating it no matter what the result of the study is because of freedom of speech.
Speaker 1: Therefore they shouldn't be doing the study in the first place.
Speaker 0: well No I If they were actual science if they if the government was just paying scientists to study various things I'd be all for a study because it would add to the general knowledge base of the human race.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're not doing it, you know to be a study.
Speaker 1: They're trying to manufacture evidence.
Speaker 0: See that's the problem.
Speaker 0: The government should be paying for research.
Speaker 0: The government should be shouldn't be paying scientists to make up the research for them.
Speaker 1: And also if the government is gonna pay for research, they should not do so much redundant research.
Speaker 1: They should go for you know, something something better to be studying than this.
Speaker 1: That's not good.
Speaker 0: Well, that's just because it gets decided by committee instead of by scientists.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know that's the problem.
Speaker 0: So we've been wanting a griddle in our kitchen for a long time Mostly because we watch the hibachi guy use his giant Hot metal plate to make awesome hibachi food for us and we can't really do it in our kitchen.
Speaker 1: I know it's like all the easy and great foods that we could cook quickly that would taste great for dinner require a hot Very hot very flat piece of metal.
Speaker 1: and we have these coily electric things.
Speaker 1: and it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not so good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the heats not that even not only that but even breakfast.
Speaker 0: You know making pancakes on something like that is so much easier than using some sort of pan Yep, but anyway, there's a company out there that is just marketed and made a anti griddle.
Speaker 0: It's a griddle but instead of heating it freezes.
Speaker 0: it gets down to negative 30 degrees Fahrenheit.
Speaker 1: That's cold Fahrenheit.
Speaker 0: that's like negative woman.
Speaker 0: That's like negative 34 Celsius.
Speaker 1: Wow, you could like make ice cream on that or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the main uses they seem to talk about are say you make some sort of creamy You know pudding type thing.
Speaker 0: You can put it on this thing shape it into a shape and then take it off right away and it'll be frozen and crunchy On the outside, but cool and creamy on the inside.
Speaker 1: I see these being utilized heavily in the next pastry championship.
Speaker 0: I just hope we see more of these around because I got to say I like the Cold Stone Creamery a lot and there Aren't any around here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just ice cream to me, but you ever eaten at one It's ice cream.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's ice cream like subway where you pick what you want in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, I think this is cool.
Speaker 1: I think it's cool, but I don't know how much we would actually use.
Speaker 0: Oh, we wouldn't use one.
Speaker 0: It's like 800 bucks.
Speaker 1: I mean even it was.
Speaker 1: it was it as much as a George Foreman grill.
Speaker 1: How much would we use it?
Speaker 0: The only reason we wouldn't is because we don't have the skill to make the things that would go on it in the first place.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: It's like I have a blender.
Speaker 1: I barely use the blender.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should use it more Summer.
Speaker 1: I'll use it more in the summer.
Speaker 0: Let's make milkshakes every day.
Speaker 1: No, not every day.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: We'll get fat.
Speaker 0: No, you won't you anyway, I won't.
Speaker 1: so I found another thing on Craigslist.
Speaker 1: This is akin to the hey crackhead with the guy with the spark plugs getting stolen.
Speaker 1: This is in the same category and oh my god I. our podcast isn't marked explicit, but this is like beyond explicit and alright, so and I'm gonna read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the next few minutes are going to be explicit.
Speaker 1: So the introduction.
Speaker 1: Let me let me read this.
Speaker 1: It's from a social worker And the social worker is obviously having a hard time with terrible terrible people.
Speaker 1: And this is what he says.
Speaker 1: I don't even know it's a he or she.
Speaker 1: after years of idealism I finally decided I'm sick and fucking tired of helping the disenfranchised and oppressed.
Speaker 1: I have a master's degree in social work and I've worked in a number of different settings.
Speaker 1: I've been a social worker for Children's Protective Services a Therapist and a psych ward and I've worked as a case manager for a nonprofit.
Speaker 1: that shall remain nameless.
Speaker 1: I've had a number of clients over the years that I would now like to thank for helping me come to the realization that certain People are beyond help.
Speaker 1: He then goes on to describe six very specific Terrible terrible terrible people.
Speaker 0: now, we don't need to read these on the air here.
Speaker 1: Well, let me give you a taste of just one of these six.
Speaker 0: Yes, and if you're interested read the rest, these are.
Speaker 0: this isn't as fun like the.
Speaker 0: the medical thread We talked about a while ago was hilarious.
Speaker 0: This is less hilarious and more horrifying.
Speaker 1: Yeah So the crackhead mother with 27 cats.
Speaker 1: obviously she has Toxoplasmosis Exactly.
Speaker 1: I called you in advance to set up our appointment.
Speaker 1: You knew I was going to be at your house that day and that I would be evaluating your progress and making your home Habitable so that your kids would be returned to you.
Speaker 1: So why?
Speaker 1: oh, why did you answer the door with a crack pipe in your hand?
Speaker 1: Oh It's not yours you were just holding on to it for your neighbor.
Speaker 1: sure I'll buy that.
Speaker 1: Let me ask you something though.
Speaker 1: Are those your neighbors?
Speaker 1: cat turds overflowing in the kitchen sink?
Speaker 1: No, you're right.
Speaker 1: Those litter boxes are expensive.
Speaker 1: Perhaps you should consider getting rid of a few of the cats so there'll be room for your children.
Speaker 1: Just a thought by the way, is that your neighbor's blood coagulating over there on the couch?
Speaker 1: God Yeah, so there's five more of those and at the end that he said, I don't know if it's a he still he says Okay, I feel much better now.
Speaker 1: I think I might go back to school for an MBA or something.
Speaker 1: I'm tired of working to help these people for 60 hours a week at 35,000 a year.
Speaker 1: I don't blame this guy But I don't know what to do about these people and it's really tough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe we'll do a show on it someday because we had a debate about this just before the show a debate where neither of Us knew what to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we're very opinionated, but when it comes down to these types of people I mean, I guess these types of people sounds bad but the types of people that you'll read about if you read Scott's thing of the day, I don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: it's like I'm against killing and I'm against.
Speaker 1: you know hurting them and Jail or rehab won't really fix them because they're just so.
Speaker 1: that's terrible terrible people There's not.
Speaker 1: you can't help them but at the same time you don't want to let them go on hurting society But you don't want to kill them because that's wrong.
Speaker 1: So what do you do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't exile them because that just hurts them and someone else now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what is not?
Speaker 1: there's no right answer.
Speaker 1: I mean You know.
Speaker 1: if you you can decide that killing is okay.
Speaker 1: if you somehow decide that I don't know how you could yeah.
Speaker 0: And if you can watch try gun, it might change your mind a little.
Speaker 1: yeah But if you can't decide that you just kind of have to figure out what hurts society the least without being Evil.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we'll do a show on that someday so you can hear all of our varied opinions about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Wow, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah So anyway today the final day of our first theme week how to not suck week?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well we'll pick a better theme another time.
Speaker 1: I know I had not to suck.
Speaker 1: don't put anything in your mouth and apply suction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah Scott's been making that joke all week and he's been waiting for the opportunity to say it on the air.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's obvious.
Speaker 0: So today we came up with a lot of ideas and a lot of them we wanted to save or we already done and we'd forgotten.
Speaker 1: Yeah, can you imagine we haven't even done a hundred episodes and already we forgot some of the episodes We did.
Speaker 0: I had to go search in our own archives to see if we had talked about money though I note that unlike slash dot we don't have dupes because we actually do search through search through our archives to make sure we haven't Done something already.
Speaker 1: Yes Actually slash that hasn't had so many dupes lately.
Speaker 1: I think they've been improving because now dig is putting the pressure on.
Speaker 0: it is Though dig doesn't quite have the quality of comments yet No, but they have.
Speaker 1: this a comment system that a beginning to think is is challenging.
Speaker 1: slash that system pretty well.
Speaker 0: But anyway, anyway today we decided that we're going to do very simply how to not suck under pressure.
Speaker 1: What we're gonna do is we're gonna go through some situations that are pretty tough that most people would freak out in or mess up or do something stupid in and we're gonna tell you how not to do something Stupid.
Speaker 0: and then at the end we're gonna go through some generic advice on.
Speaker 0: you know, what did you learn from all these situations?
Speaker 0: What did you learn?
Speaker 0: because basically both of us have been in a lot of very difficult dangerous or otherwise frightening situations and We've noticed that most people when confronted with a dangerous or unexpected situation I don't want to say don't deal with it properly, but just don't deal with it at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's not just you know, physically dangerous things like you're in a store and a guy comes in with a gun.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know emotional personal situations where someone's freaking out or you know People are in a fight or someone's really really mad or something, you know, something like that.
Speaker 1: Those actually happen more often.
Speaker 1: It's much more useful advice to figure out how to deal with those than to deal with the rare occurrences Of crazy violence or a giant fire or something like that.
Speaker 0: Alright, so let's start off with something real real light.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're at someone's house.
Speaker 0: You stand over and you accidentally break something.
Speaker 1: Well number one don't try to hide it.
Speaker 1: admit you broke it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't be Peter from the family guy.
Speaker 1: If you broke it because it was if it was your fault that it broke like you bumped into something and it fell or whatever.
Speaker 1: Admit you did it Apologize and What's the word compensate?
Speaker 0: Yes Now we know specifically that many people don't do this because back when we lived in gotten colony and you know at RIT we had a bunch of eggs in our fridge and We had a bunch of friends over and then all the friends went home and we opened the fridge and all the eggs are broken.
Speaker 0: It looks like someone knocked it out of the fridge and there was egg matter on the ground outside the fridge and there's a big mess.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we don't know who did it.
Speaker 0: we to this day We don't know and no one ever did it.
Speaker 1: to consider this if we found out who did it We would have freaking been pissed off at them and maybe hurt them or something.
Speaker 1: But if someone would have just said I broke the eggs and cleaned it up and threw them out Whatever we wouldn't care.
Speaker 1: It's just two dollars worth of eggs.
Speaker 1: It's the hiding it and trying to be all sneaky that you know, we'll get the the heat put on you.
Speaker 1: so Don't try to be all sneaky.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's say you're driving your car and someone hits your car.
Speaker 1: number one Stop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone actually hit my car when we were driving back from Otacon lab this previous year.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I forgot about that.
Speaker 0: Didn't you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did.
Speaker 0: So we're in.
Speaker 0: I think we're still in Jersey.
Speaker 1: only his car was damaged.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I. but basically we're on the freeway and now I-95 or any of you've ever driven on it And at the end of any weekend, especially in the summer It basically becomes an unmoving block of traffic.
Speaker 0: So we're driving on it and I'm going along, you know Maybe 45 50 because he can't go so fast.
Speaker 0: and we come up over the crest of a hill and there's cars stopped ahead of us.
Speaker 0: So I slow down and come to a stop.
Speaker 0: guy come up behind me Doesn't even seem to notice that the cars ahead of him hurt a dead Stop doesn't even slow down until he's about 10 feet away from the back of my car.
Speaker 0: I see him slam on the brakes cars skidding back and forth.
Speaker 0: He barely misses my car.
Speaker 0: He hits my rear-view mirror with side mirror.
Speaker 0: Yeah with his side rear-view mirror his shatters in a shower of glass.
Speaker 0: Mine is undamaged.
Speaker 1: Those things are expensive the side mirrors.
Speaker 0: So I roll down my window.
Speaker 0: cuz now he's basically sitting next to us since traffic isn't moving and I say hey Let's pull over, you know insurance blah.
Speaker 0: and he flicks me off.
Speaker 0: Yells is your fault for stopping man and drives off like on the shoulder.
Speaker 0: Great yeah.
Speaker 1: so what you want to do is In a situation like that.
Speaker 1: There's not really much you can do because the guy's running away.
Speaker 1: But write down his license plate and yes, which I did.
Speaker 0: and to call the police which I also did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I never heard back what happened to him, but I filed a police report with the yeah It was New Jersey because that's where I filed the report.
Speaker 1: Yep Just you know, don't let it go if someone's that stupid now.
Speaker 0: Now this goes for crime in general because it seems that whenever like a crime is happening a lot of times Everyone thinks oh, it's not my responsibility.
Speaker 0: Uh, someone else will deal with it.
Speaker 0: Someone else already called 9-1-1.
Speaker 0: It's not my problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when I see you know something happening I call 9-1-1 even if I see people on the phone who are 99% probably calling 9-1-1.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like when we saw that horrible car fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah We were driving down the highway and on the other side of the highway is this car and it was on fire Like like wow, it was a giant fireball.
Speaker 0: Like if anyone was inside that car they were dead totally dead.
Speaker 1: There might have been dead people in it.
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz there was no one standing around it It was one person.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there's that one guy like.
Speaker 0: it was a kind of fat guy in a white shirt But I don't even remember who it was.
Speaker 1: It was just a person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like there was no one else around and this car was engulfed in flames.
Speaker 1: It was like this giant window fire was coming out of every window and go.
Speaker 1: it was a giant pillar of black smoke going straight Up, I'm surprised maybe the gas tank had already exploded or was about to but we saw this the smoke pillar coming around the corner For mile.
Speaker 0: really we're driver like.
Speaker 0: what's that smoke?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what the hell's that?
Speaker 0: And finally we get there.
Speaker 0: Oh cars on fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was crazy.
Speaker 0: No What was funny is that there was a cop like a half a mile back on the road pulling someone over for speeding.
Speaker 0: You had no idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm sure he found out pretty quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so of course we called 9-1-1 and the 9-1-1 operator says wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Is it on blah blah blah and blah blah blah?
Speaker 0: We're like, yeah, that sounds right and they said yeah We know about it.
Speaker 0: All right, but we called because a lot of times you'd be surprised How many times someone needs help and no one bothers to stop or call?
Speaker 0: They all assume someone else will do it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm There are even studies Farc had an article recently about it where they've shown that the more people are present at an accident or a dangerous situation The less likely it is that anyone will call for help.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because everyone thinks someone else did it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you know what.
Speaker 0: do it because you're that someone else to everyone else?
Speaker 1: Yeah, do it no matter what.
Speaker 1: if there's anything that requires 9-1-1 ever Always call it even if someone is saying they called it already and you know.
Speaker 0: If you're driving to work and you're the only other car on the road and you see an accident Don't just keep going.
Speaker 0: Stop.
Speaker 0: Make sure they're okay.
Speaker 0: Call the police.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if the police aren't there yet, you know, and you can do something about it.
Speaker 1: do something about it.
Speaker 1: In fact at the very minimum keep driving but call 9-1-1 and say hey, I just passed an accident.
Speaker 0: In fact, some states have laws.
Speaker 0: I don't know exactly which states.
Speaker 0: they're called Good Samaritan laws And some of these laws protect you if you try to help someone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if you try to help someone but you actually end up doing something bad.
Speaker 1: It's okay because you were trying to do good.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna get in trouble if you screw up.
Speaker 0: but some of these other laws State such things as if you were the first person to come across an accident and you don't stop and try to help or at Least stop and notify the authorities.
Speaker 0: you can go to jail or get a ticket or whatever the fines may be.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I guess by doing that you're just delaying.
Speaker 1: You know how long it takes until the accident is handled and you're actually hurting people, you know, it's by your.
Speaker 1: well You're not really hurting them But you know your inaction is causing greater harm when you could have prevented harm.
Speaker 1: One other thing I had I learned in Red Cross training is it let's say someone next to you as a heart attack, right?
Speaker 1: And you're gonna do CPR on them or you're gonna use a different fibrillator or something like that, right?
Speaker 1: You can't call 9-1-1 cuz you're doing that.
Speaker 1: What you do is you need to point at someone.
Speaker 1: you need to say you call 9-1-1.
Speaker 1: You can't just say someone call 9-1-1 because nobody will.
Speaker 1: you need to point at someone and say you do it and Then watch them and make sure they do it.
Speaker 0: Yep That applies to basically any dangerous situation.
Speaker 0: if you're going to take charge take charge if you kind of half-assed Lee You know like you start to do something, but you don't say or you're not very authoritative Nothing's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: you need to say you do this you do that you do this and I'm gonna do this.
Speaker 1: go go go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't wait for someone else to do that.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Cuz if you wait around for someone else to do that You're pretty much gonna wait for the police and I think it's been shown in many many studies that the number one factor in Saving lives and such is response time.
Speaker 1: So if you can do anything, you know - that is beneficial No matter how small it is.
Speaker 1: the fact that you're doing it sooner is very helpful Especially when it comes to CPR and other forms of resuscitation.
Speaker 0: When in doubt it I mean even poorly done CPR is better than no CPR in most cases if someone actually had a heart attack Or isn't breathing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I mean the Heimlich maneuver I mean even if you don't go for CPR training You should know how to save a person who's choking on something.
Speaker 0: In fact, I just say as a general corollary how to not suck under pressure.
Speaker 0: in general I think everyone who doesn't have a reason not to should learn basic CPR and you know basic Heimlich things like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Red Cross gives little thingies.
Speaker 1: You can go get training.
Speaker 0: You can read a website That'll give you the basic idea of it pretty handily.
Speaker 1: Yeah that too, but you know the Red Cross training it.
Speaker 1: you get the little card and stuff.
Speaker 1: It's cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have a little card.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't have the card.
Speaker 0: I did it in like middle school and with the Cub Scouts.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's go back to some less dangerous personal type situations.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's say you're hanging out and Two people start yelling at each other and fighting.
Speaker 0: We've had that happen often.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I think that's the number one most Occurrence that happens now.
Speaker 0: whenever this happens what I usually observe is that everyone is not involved Just sits there and like pretends it isn't happening.
Speaker 1: You know, that's not what I observe.
Speaker 1: I observe when It seems like there's different levels like when people are grr at each other, right?
Speaker 1: But they're not confronting directly.
Speaker 1: people just seem to not talk about it.
Speaker 1: Try to stay, you know, try to distract.
Speaker 1: You know obfuscate You know and keep the people apart from each other.
Speaker 1: if people are standing there yelling at each other, right?
Speaker 1: People will just kind of watch like ooh, what's gonna happen?
Speaker 1: Everyone will start paying attention to it instead of trying to obfuscate.
Speaker 1: As soon as it comes to blows people go in and grab them and pull them apart.
Speaker 1: It's like no no, no, you're not fine You know, that's at least that's what I've seen.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it depends on what tie I mean.
Speaker 0: if it is it two strangers is it?
Speaker 0: you know a group of friends and two people are angry at each other.
Speaker 0: Is it some drunks outside of a club man?
Speaker 1: If I walk no matter what if I see, you know, all two drunks outside of a club might be an exception.
Speaker 1: But if I see two people like fighting an angry fight like, you know Trying to hurt each other and they don't have deadly weapons.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna friggin try to break it up.
Speaker 0: Well, see I would say Larry just because you don't know what they're fighting about or whose side you should be on No, you'd be on.
Speaker 1: they're fighting.
Speaker 1: the fact people shouldn't be fighting no matter what.
Speaker 1: so you don't care whose side you're on.
Speaker 0: Alright, alright, but here's just here's my point my cynical point What if it's two stupid people fighting over something stupid?
Speaker 0: it if you letting them fight is probably the best societal outcome?
Speaker 1: No, it's not beating them.
Speaker 1: you beating them both up.
Speaker 0: separate Stupid people often tend to be fairly strong Sometimes.
Speaker 1: here's it is a slightly related example of fighting When I was walking down the street and there was a purse snatcher on the other side of the road.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I talked about this in a the podcast the day it happened.
Speaker 0: Yep It actually gave me a little bit of faith in humanity that maybe there's a lot of people out there who don't suck.
Speaker 1: quite so bad Is a purse snatcher.
Speaker 1: so people tried to catch him and of course a fight broke out and of course people ganged up on him And you know got him, you know You don't want to.
Speaker 1: there's sometimes when you got a you got a fight and sometimes when you break up fights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I guess in general at least far as I'm concerned I'll often take risks.
Speaker 0: if I think that the risks are appropriate to help people and If you're not if you won't take the risks, that's fine.
Speaker 0: But bear in mind that if no one takes the risk often someone's going to get hurt.
Speaker 1: Yep Another thing is if you see a fight about to happen You can sometimes do something to stop it before you have to pull people apart.
Speaker 1: Like if you see an angry guy running down the street, he's gonna hit someone, you know You can maybe stand in his way or knock him over.
Speaker 0: He won't see you coming because he's looking at the guy's going to hit or if two Drunk punk kids are about to fight outside of a club.
Speaker 0: Just walk over call me say Alright guys, neither one of you wants to get arrested because someone already called the cops.
Speaker 0: So we'd best all get out of here.
Speaker 0: Yep, you know if you have the gift of gab at all You can very easily defuse bad situations like that now.
Speaker 0: back when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: I was involved in a fairly Interesting situation along these lines and I'll just tell the story and how I reacted to it because I think it's a decent lesson in How to react to this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: All right, so I had a friend who was She's a good person, but she's a little unstable I guess and to make a long story short and to not mention any names She called me one day, you know early mid-evening needing a ride to her boyfriend's house and I wondered what was up and I heard yelling in the background, but I was bored and I figured this could only be interesting.
Speaker 0: So I drive over to her house I pick her up and I drive her over to his house and I park and she runs out of my car and runs Up to his front door.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: A large woman probably her boyfriend's mom since we're all in high school answers the door and Then the boyfriend comes out.
Speaker 0: There's a giant screaming shouting horrible mess of a rigmarole and rigmarole.
Speaker 0: yeah, I've said that word a lot lately and I probably would have walked out to see what was going on, but it ended before I could even really leave my car.
Speaker 0: and Basically when what I gathered later the guy had broken up with her and she was not too happy with this She immediately tried to throw herself in front of traffic.
Speaker 0: uh-huh, yeah, so I bolted from my car and I tackled her and At this point the people in the house had like closed the door and they wanted nothing to do with it ended at this point.
Speaker 0: So I grabbed her.
Speaker 0: I put her in my car and I had a. my car didn't have child locks But my lasers locks are actually broken.
Speaker 0: So I basically locked her in the passenger side of my car And then I pulled up my cell phone and I didn't call the police or anything right away but I called another friend.
Speaker 0: so I'd have another body to you know.
Speaker 0: help deal with all this and Basically to make a long long long story short we ended up calling a hospital and taking care of the situation.
Speaker 1: Hospitals good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and she from what I've heard.
Speaker 0: She's doing okay now, but Basically, here's a bad situation.
Speaker 0: a girl is trying to kill herself by throwing herself onto a freeway where their car coming.
Speaker 0: Now I tackled her and I can't think of any other way to resolve that situation.
Speaker 0: I Anything else I could have done.
Speaker 1: there really isn't much you could do now other than you know.
Speaker 0: Just sit there and not care.
Speaker 1: You could drive your car out in front of traffic in front of her But then you're kind of like that.
Speaker 0: I think that could have just made the situation worse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could have.
Speaker 1: you could have hit her with your car to like break her leg that way That way she'd learn her lesson and then you just drag her to the side of the road.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now the thing I know there's really there's not much else you can do though I guess I guess the examples I can make here that when you're in a situation like this You have to think and you have to keep a clear head.
Speaker 0: I mean if I just stood there going oh my god She probably would have been hit by a car Probably and to you have to think about a lot of things just in general and you won't be able to think unless you have A clear head.
Speaker 0: so I finally get her in my car and the whole time I'm watching because there was a way to unlock the door and I had to drive her somewhere so we could deal with her and I was very keenly aware of the fact that there's a decent chance She'll try to fling herself out of my car at some point.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I was prepared for that.
Speaker 1: She should have put her in the trunk.
Speaker 0: It was a frickin laser.
Speaker 1: It has a trunk.
Speaker 0: Not in there.
Speaker 0: You can put a person in the trunk the backseat at least There's all right.
Speaker 0: You've ever seen a laser.
Speaker 1: It has a tiny backseat.
Speaker 0: All right, I couldn't fit in the backseat.
Speaker 0: I could not sit back there.
Speaker 0: There's no way I was gonna shove her back there because she was resisting me.
Speaker 0: She was still trying to throw herself in front of traffic the whole time.
Speaker 1: great Yeah, that's pretty much.
Speaker 1: the number one piece of advice at all is don't go crazy and just start doing stuff reflexively.
Speaker 1: or you know Don't use your penis brain.
Speaker 1: Don't use any other brain except the one in your head and keep it in control.
Speaker 0: Just think logically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think about this.
Speaker 1: the purpose of seatbelts in a car Isn't so much to keep you from flying out the window Although it does have that effect is to keep the driver in the driver's seat in control.
Speaker 1: It's a safety mechanism which keeps the brain behind the vehicle Behind the wheel.
Speaker 0: I see the analogy you're making and it's a good one.
Speaker 1: Yes That is the number one thing no matter what the situation is no matter how crazy.
Speaker 1: Keep the brain behind the wheel.
Speaker 0: now case in point.
Speaker 0: Here's a nice quick example.
Speaker 0: Say you're in a nightclub and a fire breaks out Like a sudden flash fire and it's a crowd.
Speaker 0: now Half the crowd is probably gonna freak out and start screaming and running for the exit and creating a big mess.
Speaker 0: The first thing you need to do is one get away from the fire to get away from the crowd.
Speaker 0: Don't follow the crowd don't scream and run.
Speaker 0: just think and look for a way out.
Speaker 0: That doesn't involve the crowd and just walk slowly toward it.
Speaker 1: Also check for fire extinguishers fire alarms.
Speaker 1: You know know your exit paths But think these things.
Speaker 0: if you're not clear in the head There's no way you're gonna think of all that you'll be crushed by the masses trying to get out the door.
Speaker 1: if this smoke get Low if this fire stop drop and roll, you know, this is first-grade stuff.
Speaker 0: kiddies Stop drop and roll, but adults No one in the world seems to be able to actually deal with this sort of thing when there's ever an actual design.
Speaker 0: Like look at New Orleans It was just an unmitigated disaster.
Speaker 0: and of not counting all the federal mistakes and you know The various issues surrounding New Orleans the fact remains that everyone assumed that the government and other people were going to take care of them And they did not work.
Speaker 0: at least many people did not work to take care of themselves.
Speaker 0: Yep, don't rely on other people to save you because they often will not get there in time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and while the on the one hand these people do have some sort of a you know a complaint that hey The government said it would do this and it didn't do it true?
Speaker 1: on the other hand If they're not gonna do it, you can't complain so much if you don't do anything to help yourself at all.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean if you did everything you could and then it's still you were still stuck And then someone said they would help you and they didn't then you could have a real complaint.
Speaker 1: But if you're you know, just not doing anything and expecting someone else to save you I really don't have any pity.
Speaker 0: now even on a small scale just any small anything that happens to you Don't expect anyone else to just march in and save you.
Speaker 0: you'll often have to deal with the situation on your own And if you wait for the police to arrive or you wait for the fire department to arrive things may just get worse.
Speaker 1: on the interim Mm-hmm, and I notice a lot of people either just when things are gonna happen to them.
Speaker 1: they either just let the things happen and Then feel bad for themselves that their life sucks and then their life begins to suck because they let bad things happen to them.
Speaker 1: Or they you know, it's try to get other people to do things about it And then sure they avert a lot of trouble.
Speaker 1: But then they end up as people who can't really do anything and they're always relying on others.
Speaker 1: And then eventually they get into a trap and then they're like, oh my god.
Speaker 0: Now to back away from disaster talk a bit in addition to keeping a clear head.
Speaker 0: take action.
Speaker 0: if There's a situation and you can affect it and you think that affecting it or changing it will alter the outcome in a positive way act Now.
Speaker 0: this may seem stupid but most people just don't act, you know, they act by reflex.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know you might have the clear head and you might be thinking of the right thing to do.
Speaker 1: like, you know The best thing for me to do is to walk right out of that exit over there But your body is still running running like a crazy nut.
Speaker 1: don't do that Because then you're all your effort of clear headedness has gone to waste.
Speaker 0: now a nice non-threatening example.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're living with someone and they do something you don't like.
Speaker 0: Maybe they don't do the dishes or they're passive-aggressive weird and they bother you or they leave their toenail clippings out.
Speaker 1: Great examples from real life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not between the two of us, but mostly from other people we know.
Speaker 0: but anyway Now if you don't confront them about this situation you really have no complaint you can make.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean, let's say rim has a problem with Leaving his dirty clothes all around the house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like underwear just on the ceiling.
Speaker 1: yeah, now if I don't say anything like hey, can you stop leaving your underwear on the ceiling and One day there's like a crazy fight and I'm like, oh you leave your underwear in the ceiling.
Speaker 1: I really can't say that cuz I didn't tell him to stop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, is he supposed to know?
Speaker 0: we know a lot of people who are just very passive-aggressive out there and instead of Confronting a situation.
Speaker 0: They'll just get angrier and angrier and they expect everyone else to know that they're angry.
Speaker 1: It's much easier to just you know, sometimes tell a person.
Speaker 1: Hey, can you do this?
Speaker 1: Then to all at once go.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, you're terrible.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess to put it succinctly nip problems in the bud to quote the late and great Barney Fife.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and there's a. if a situation is bad Stop it before it gets worse.
Speaker 0: If there's like if you have a little fire on your desk put it out now.
Speaker 0: don't wait until your whole desk is on fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know stitching time saves nine.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: I could just keep saying things like that all night.
Speaker 1: Yeah Another thing the to keep in mind is you want to not be a wuss?
Speaker 0: Yeah, now that may sound very generic, but it's very true.
Speaker 1: I mean you might think of the right thing to do.
Speaker 1: you might you know?
Speaker 1: Exactly, you might get the action ready, but then you wuss out because you're afraid.
Speaker 0: Have you ever been in like a crowd situation?
Speaker 0: When you know you're right and when you know your course of action is a good one or you know, you know Like alright, that's what they should do to fix this and then you just stand there and wait for them to do it.
Speaker 1: Or you tell someone, you know, let's go back to the previous example.
Speaker 1: you tell someone Hey, stop leaving your underwear around the house and they don't stop Don't let it go.
Speaker 1: You know, you just let it go cuz you're too wussy to do something about it.
Speaker 0: in other words be that guy.
Speaker 0: You know how whenever this is normally you don't want to be that guy But in this case you want to be that guy.
Speaker 0: if no one's taking charge Be the guy who takes charge.
Speaker 0: actually at Katsu khan There's a little example.
Speaker 0: one of the announcers on stage was talking about.
Speaker 0: He was making an announcement about how two panels were switched the antenna panel and the club summit panel and he didn't remember the name Of the second panel.
Speaker 0: So he's up there.
Speaker 0: He says the antenna panel and the I don't have a and he just starts floundering and No one's like making a move to tell him what it is and he's not making a move to find out.
Speaker 0: So I just shout it out the club summit panel and he looks he's like, oh, thanks.
Speaker 0: And then the show kept going.
Speaker 0: you want to be that guy the guy who everyone thinks.
Speaker 0: Ah, he fixed it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, no matter what you think, you know bad will happen to you.
Speaker 1: The consequences of whatever You know the damage for your bravery might be or the risk because that's what bravery is It's a risk taking to achieve something good.
Speaker 1: You know, the more risk you take the braver you are and Whatever that risk is it's probably worse than just letting the bad thing happen.
Speaker 1: You know or equal.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess I have another relevant old saying Fortune favors the bold.
Speaker 0: if you're basically if you live your life actively and you take an active role in the Situations that can affect you you can alter their outcome.
Speaker 0: if you live your life passively and you passively accept what life gives you You're never gonna get anything beyond what life gives you.
Speaker 0: and I got to tell you life gives you shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, life pretty much gives you the sticks.
Speaker 0: I mean We're not - I only get one stick.
Speaker 1: Yeah sticks Like all these situations that happen that you remember are gonna be situations in which bad things are gonna happen.
Speaker 1: You know when good things happen, you don't have to do anything.
Speaker 1: You don't need to know stuff to deal with good.
Speaker 1: You know good hat.
Speaker 1: you need the same amount of good will happen that you can bring about.
Speaker 1: we have to do most importantly is take the bad stuff and Make it as less bad as you possibly can.
Speaker 0: What do you want to be?
Speaker 0: Neville Chamberlain or Winston Churchill?
Speaker 1: Funny I don't know how many people listening know about history.
Speaker 1: that would get the joke they better.
Speaker 0: that wasn't that long ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah We weren't alive though.
Speaker 0: No, we weren't alive.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, so that wraps up our first themed week how to not suck week.
Speaker 0: I'll note that the only reason we picked that theme was because it seemed easy and we're still recovering from last weekend.
Speaker 0: So we're kind of tired.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we're sorry if you know a week and how not to suck sucked but Next week is gonna be a much better week.
Speaker 0: We think we're gonna.
Speaker 1: week is gonna be such an awesome week.
Speaker 1: It'll make up for any suckage of the how not to suck week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly because we're gonna get a good night's sleep this weekend.
Speaker 1: Yeah here let me how not to suck at deciding what to do for the podcast all week.
Speaker 1: do what we're gonna do next week haha, I Don't know.
Speaker 1: Do you think we should tell people what we're gonna do next week?
Speaker 0: All right, let's warn him.
Speaker 0: Of course, that means that we're now locked in but we're gonna do favorites week on Monday.
Speaker 1: You'll probably get our favorite technology Yeah, something along those lines on Tuesday.
Speaker 1: We'll probably do our favorite board games and video games and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Wednesday is what our favorite anime manga and comics.
Speaker 0: Oh, and maybe Thursdays will be our favorite special topics and other miscellany.
Speaker 1: Ooh Who knows what we'll do Thursday.
Speaker 1: I don't even know yet.
Speaker 0: So there's still a mystery going on And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at Www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.