Speaker 0: It's Thursday April 6th, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we talk about procrastination, laziness, and we're generally lazy during the show.
Speaker 0: But it's awesome.
Speaker 0: Let's do this!
Speaker 1: So this is the 88th episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: And we're tired.
Speaker 1: Tired as fuck.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: If you could see us now, there'd be like these Z's floating out of our head.
Speaker 1: I was asleep until just recently when Scott forced me to wake up long enough to do the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if the show is not so great, or not so long...
Speaker 1: Well, uh, you can die in a fire.
Speaker 0: What's with you and the dying of fire?
Speaker 1: I don't know, I find it hilarious.
Speaker 1: It was on Penny Arcade.
Speaker 1: Then it was all over Fark, and I think it's becoming fast a new internet meme/cliché.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: Alright, so, in less happy news, there's this guy who's a listener and he's in our forums.
Speaker 0: We only know him as Rich, or Tech Support Rich.
Speaker 0: And he is one of the people who does a podcast called Movies You Should See.
Speaker 0: And you can go check it out at www.simplysyndicated.com/moviesyoushouldsee.html.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I listened to a few of them.
Speaker 0: These people really know as much about movies as the Anime World Order.
Speaker 0: people know about anime.
Speaker 0: Which is good, because I don't know shit about movies.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't pay attention to actors or directors or any of that.
Speaker 0: So when these guys say, "Oh yeah, that was directed by the same guy who directed this and
Speaker 0: that."
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Oh.".
Speaker 1: And of course, Mr.
Speaker 1: Period has no problems with how this guy posts.
Speaker 0: Nope, no problems whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So he gets more points.
Speaker 0: But, what happened was...
Speaker 1: His appendix exploded!
Speaker 0: I don't know if it exploded.
Speaker 0: He had appendicitis, which means it's all swollen.
Speaker 0: And if you don't know, appendicitis is really painful and...
Speaker 1: Possibly deadly.
Speaker 0: Basically, you have this organ attached to your intestine.
Speaker 0: that doesn't do much nowadays.
Speaker 0: I mean, it does something.
Speaker 1: You know what it does?
Speaker 1: It collects pus and tries to kill you.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like the Bender of the Middle Ages.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: It's like this little sack of poison that everyone has inside their bodies.
Speaker 0: And if something goes wrong, it gets swollen or it explodes.
Speaker 0: If it explodes, you're pretty much dead.
Speaker 0: But if it's swollen and painful, you can go to the hospital and they take it out.
Speaker 0: Well, they just took his out and we hope he gets better soon.
Speaker 0: And all that good stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whenever they put up their next episode, we'll definitely be linking to it because we're in it.
Speaker 0: Yep, we sure are.
Speaker 0: And I want to see a picture of this appendix in a jar.
Speaker 0: That's what I want to see.
Speaker 1: They usually don't give you the appendix in a jar.
Speaker 0: You gotta get it in a jar.
Speaker 0: What's the point?
Speaker 1: There's laws against that.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 1: Aww.
Speaker 1: Though I have.
Speaker 0: He's in the UK, though.
Speaker 0: The laws might be different.
Speaker 1: Ha ha!
Speaker 1: The UK, where people have slightly different rights.
Speaker 0: Less in some areas and more in others.
Speaker 1: Actually, I saw a story today on FARC about a guy who fought a parking fine with a law that was passed in England in 1600-something.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: He lost and the judge basically laughed at him, but the guy's taken it to a higher court and he thinks he has a valid point.
Speaker 1: Because the law was never overturned.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: It's a long, complicated story.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to get into it.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll talk about it someday when we talk about jurisprudence.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But I have a relevant appendix story.
Speaker 0: Well, Houdini?
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: Not Houdini.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Even though there's somewhat of an urban legend around how Houdini actually died.
Speaker 0: There is indeed, which is why I was going to start talking about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but no, no, no.
Speaker 1: This is very different.
Speaker 1: This was in high school.
Speaker 1: We had a friend, Aaron Nardi.
Speaker 1: And Nardi is an amazing drummer.
Speaker 1: Like, this kid could frickin' drum.
Speaker 1: We played in a jazz band together and he was an awesome guy.
Speaker 1: Now, he got his appendix out.
Speaker 1: And so suddenly, like, he had a problem and he went to the hospital.
Speaker 1: He, like, missed some school and his appendix was out.
Speaker 1: And he came back and there's this giant scar on his abdomen.
Speaker 1: Now, only a few people knew that he had had his appendix out in a semi-emergency surgery.
Speaker 1: So the story that everyone who knew and that Nardi himself propagated was that he was involved in an altercation down on 8 Mile, since we live near Detroit, during which he was stabbed.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: And for years and years, everyone believed this.
Speaker 1: Everyone thought he was stabbed on 8 Mile.
Speaker 1: And it was just his appendix.
Speaker 1: And they'd be like, "No
Speaker 1: way!".
Speaker 1: And he'd lift his shirt and there'd be the scar there.
Speaker 1: and they'd be like, "Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: Sorry I doubted you.
Speaker 1: Damn.
Speaker 1: You've been
Speaker 1: stabbed.".
Speaker 0: All right, so Rich, if you're listening out there, remember, to anyone who doesn't know, you were stabbed.
Speaker 1: On 8 Mile.
Speaker 0: By Jack the Ripper.
Speaker 0: You're in London, right?
Speaker 1: Jack the Ripper's dead.
Speaker 0: I know, but it's supposed to be funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I actually read the Wikipedia on Jack the Ripper today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Actually, there's this comic that Alan Moore wrote about Jack the Ripper.
Speaker 1: That's why I read the Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Called From Hell, which I've been trying to get, but you can't get it.
Speaker 0: It's like 60 bucks for a used crap one.
Speaker 1: I will say something that bothers me about Jack the Ripper.
Speaker 1: A lot of people have done a lot of relevant research trying to figure out who he was.
Speaker 1: But the fact remains that there's really no way to know.
Speaker 0: No one knows for sure.
Speaker 0: No one will know for sure.
Speaker 1: You should see the crazy crackpot conspiracy nutjob theories about Jack the Ripper that are out there.
Speaker 0: If this ever is something that we can't figure out, every nutjob in the world would make a crazy conspiracy.
Speaker 1: Even things we can figure out.
Speaker 1: I mean, oh, things are evolving?
Speaker 1: No, it was a guy in the sky.
Speaker 1: Or, oh, a building was hit by a plane?
Speaker 1: It must have been an explosion planted by the government.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you this, though.
Speaker 1: Abraham Lincoln shot first.
Speaker 0: How do we beat a giant stone Abraham Lincoln?
Speaker 1: Uh, giant stone John Wilkes Booth.
Speaker 0: I love that joke.
Speaker 0: That's the one, there's very few things I miss from television.
Speaker 0: But all those cartoon cartoons like Dexter's Lab and Powerpuff Girls were definitely where it's at.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though that was from South Park.
Speaker 0: Oh, was it?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 0: An episode that's coming soon.
Speaker 0: But it was Dexter's Lab where they brought Mount Rushmore to life and they...
Speaker 1: Are you sure?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm 100% sure.
Speaker 1: And then they had a giant stone John Wilkes Booth come?
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was a giant stone John Wilkes Booth.
Speaker 1: 'Cause that was from South Park.
Speaker 0: But there was a giant Abraham Lincoln made of stone and Mandark had another pres... Did Mandark have Lincoln and then Dexter had the other guy?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'd take Tefft.
Speaker 1: I could form a black hole.
Speaker 0: A black hole of teapot domes.
Speaker 1: Alright, yeah, we're tired and we're silly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so everyone go check out Movies You Should See.
Speaker 0: And there should be an episode coming soon where we do a mini review of a movie that everyone should see and you probably don't know about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you haven't seen it, we'll make sure you get it somehow.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So, fair.
Speaker 1: Alright, in actual relevant news, scientists recently discovered something that... This is actually a fairly significant find.
Speaker 1: Now, a lot of people are calling it the missing link.
Speaker 1: And it's not... I hate that term.
Speaker 1: I hate when people say the missing link when it comes to evolution.
Speaker 1: Because there's no such thing as the missing link.
Speaker 1: Someone will always say... Every time you find something, they'll say, "Oh, but there's nothing between that one and the one before
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: And then you find one in the middle and they'll say, "Oh, but there's a
Speaker 1: d-d-d-d-d-d-d-d.".
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: So don't use the term "missing
Speaker 1: link.".
Speaker 1: However, what scientists just found is a missing link.
Speaker 0: That's... There aren't any other English words for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically...
Speaker 0: It's a link.
Speaker 0: Let's just say it's a link.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's a link that until previously was undiscovered.
Speaker 1: The link between seagoing animals and land-dwelling animals.
Speaker 0: Like, we always kinda knew that some fish got some legs and crawled up out and were amphibious and then were land-based.
Speaker 1: They found this crocodile-like, shallow-water fish kind of thing that can also walk on land.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's what it was.
Speaker 1: They've named it the Tiktaalik Rosae.
Speaker 0: That's a great name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they took it from the Inuit language and I don't remember what it means and I'm not gonna go over and look it up.
Speaker 0: What happens to the fun names like trilobite?
Speaker 1: What's with you and trilobite?
Speaker 1: Wheee!
Speaker 1: Trilobites!
Speaker 1: You know, my mom's got like nine fairly well-preserved trilobite fossils.
Speaker 0: I'll buy one someday.
Speaker 1: You want one?
Speaker 1: I could probably get one for you.
Speaker 0: No, I'll get my own.
Speaker 1: My mom has a fairly extensive collection of fossils.
Speaker 1: She has a small fragment of a dinosaur egg.
Speaker 1: All sorts of cool things.
Speaker 0: I think I'll just go on eBay and search for trilobite.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll get a plushie trilobite.
Speaker 1: Ah, I've seen 'em.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen 'em too.
Speaker 0: I got a plushie stingray guy.
Speaker 0: Ooh.
Speaker 0: From an aquarium.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that thing.
Speaker 1: We used to throw it around the apartment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's cool, isn't it?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You always keep it next to your Charmander.
Speaker 0: It's worth seven bucks, which is what I paid for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: For whatever kind of, you know, adult, professional, geek guy whatevers, we have a surprising number of stuffed animals.
Speaker 0: It's weird because I had 'em as a kid and then I didn't want 'em anymore and I didn't really play with 'em when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I just kind of hid amongst them, like E.T.
Speaker 0: style.
Speaker 1: So did I.
Speaker 0: And then they put 'em all, eventually they got handed down from kid to kid and then my sister put 'em all in the attic except for like a couple.
Speaker 1: We had a friggin' my brother's room.
Speaker 1: We put a net, like, hanging from the corner of the room.
Speaker 0: And you filled it?
Speaker 1: We filled it and every now and then we'd get 'em.
Speaker 1: But we had to keep 'em up there because we had dogs.
Speaker 0: And they would just eat 'em.
Speaker 1: The dogs, we'd give them their own stuffed animals to play with and they loved 'em.
Speaker 1: But they always had this sense that the ones we didn't give 'em were far superior somehow.
Speaker 1: And they would stop at nothing to get their hands on 'em.
Speaker 0: You know why?
Speaker 0: 'Cause they tasted like you and they couldn't eat you.
Speaker 0: so they could eat those and it'd be close enough.
Speaker 1: I think it was more like they'd see us playing with 'em and they knew that they were important to us.
Speaker 1: so they must be awesome toys because we protected 'em.
Speaker 1: 'Cause they protected their toys.
Speaker 1: Though my dad has this four or five foot tall quality Wile E. Coyote stuffed animal.
Speaker 1: Like, it's quality.
Speaker 1: And one day, one of our dogs, he finds it 'cause the door was left open.
Speaker 1: So we're sitting in the living room and he walks in carrying this Wile E. Coyote that's bigger than him.
Speaker 1: And he has this look on his face like, "I'm the king of the world!
Speaker 1: Woo!
Speaker 1: Woo!".
Speaker 1: And we look at him and he looks at us and he realizes we're gonna take it away.
Speaker 1: And he just drops it and just kinda slinks away with his tail between his legs like,
Speaker 1: "Oh.".
Speaker 1: He didn't even fight.
Speaker 0: That's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but nowadays it's like we have all new stuffed animals.
Speaker 0: All things that are geeky.
Speaker 0: What do we got?
Speaker 0: We got a Cthulhu and a Cactuar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have the Cactuar, the Cthulhu, the Corolla.
Speaker 1: 1985 Corolla.
Speaker 0: 1985 Toyota Corolla from Japan.
Speaker 1: Yes, I have a stuffed 1985 Toyota Corolla.
Speaker 1: It's pretty big.
Speaker 1: I paid a lot of money for it.
Speaker 0: It's actually more of a pillow and less of a... I have a Calcifer from... Ah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: That's a really quality Calcifer.
Speaker 0: It's so cute when he opens his little mouth and he's got little hands and little logs.
Speaker 0: The logs are what's key.
Speaker 0: They had a non-log version.
Speaker 0: I don't know who would buy the non-log version.
Speaker 0: They got something wrong with them.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Though, anyway, the evolution thing.
Speaker 0: Alright, we're doing news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this thing is basically... I mean, evolution is pretty much proven.
Speaker 1: I mean, the fact... the idea that animals change and evolve into different species over time is fact.
Speaker 1: Fact, fact, fact.
Speaker 1: We've observed it.
Speaker 1: It happens.
Speaker 1: Despite this, on FARC, you should see how many people either said that this fossil is bullshit or it's fake or it doesn't matter 'cause there's still a missing link or you're gonna burn in hell.
Speaker 1: so it doesn't matter or just denying the fact that this happens and it boggles my mind.
Speaker 1: Mostly because there were two other related evolution things that happened like today and...
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was like some bird... another bird dinosaur.
Speaker 1: Yep, and they found that Gawi's skull, which is basically the link between Homo erectus and Homo sapiens.
Speaker 1: They're reasonably certain that it is.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: But also recently, a Canadian researcher was trying to get money for a grant to study the deleterious effects of the rise of intelligent design and creationism in the US on Canadian science education.
Speaker 1: The people in charge of giving him the money said that because he cannot prove that evolution is a fact, they cannot give him the money.
Speaker 0: Well, not only is evolution a fact, but there's one deleterious effect for his study right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: People not giving money to important science research.
Speaker 1: And just recently, Bill Nye was doing... 'cause Bill Nye, you know, Bill Nye the Science Guy, he's a fairly awesome dude.
Speaker 0: He's really awesome.
Speaker 0: Like, don't underestimate him.
Speaker 0: 'cause he did a show that may seem corny on the surface, but is actually awesome also.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, he's very well-spoken and cool.
Speaker 1: And he knows his stuff.
Speaker 1: And he was doing some lectures at various places.
Speaker 1: He's at this college and he's doing a lecture.
Speaker 1: And at one point, he starts talking about the origin of the universe and the moon and the sun and all sorts of things.
Speaker 1: And this woman stands up and is like, "This is horrible.
Speaker 1: We believe in God.
Speaker 1: I won't subject my kids to
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: And she storms out.
Speaker 0: Uh, nutcase.
Speaker 0: Why did you go to see Bill Nye the Science Guy if you don't believe in science?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Science.
Speaker 0: Everyone else there was cool, though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: They just kinda laughed it off and Bill Nye cracked a joke and they kept going.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Bill Nye's actually trained in not only science, like real science.
Speaker 0: He's not like some guy who pretends to know science.
Speaker 0: Or some guy who just knows some cool experiments like Mr.
Speaker 0: Wizard.
Speaker 0: Like, he's a real scientist and he's a real stand-up comedian and he's real famous and real cool.
Speaker 0: So, if you ever get a chance to go see Bill Nye somewhere, go see him.
Speaker 1: 'Cause he's currently, apparently, on tour.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you don't know who Bill Nye is, go find an episode of Bill Nye the Science Guy somewhere and watch it.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not- it's meant for, like, younger audience than- but, uh, even if you're, like, in high school, you'll still get something out of it no matter which one you watch.
Speaker 1: If anything, you watch an explosion and go, "Ha
Speaker 1: ha!".
Speaker 0: Yeah, or watch, you know, some crazy cool science experiment and go,
Speaker 0: "Ooh!"
Speaker 0: You'll learn something!
Speaker 0: I'll learn something if I watch one of those.
Speaker 0: It's been so long.
Speaker 1: But I guess my main thing here is just that I don't care what you believe.
Speaker 1: The contrary to the posts I made in the flame war art thing we had on creationism and, uh, God in the forum, but I don't care what you believe, whatever.
Speaker 1: But if you don't recognize that evolution happened and that there's evidence for it and that there's no real evidence against it, I don't know what to say to you other than that I really can't ever respect you as a person.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, um, there's, you know, one of the key- God's real, but you know what?
Speaker 1: Evolution happened, and we can't deny that.
Speaker 0: One of the key things they look for when checking to see if someone is insane is whether they can tell reality from fantasy.
Speaker 0: Well, if reality is staring you in the face, reality such as evolution, and you deny it, I submit that you are insane, and therefore you should be put in the loony bin.
Speaker 1: I mean, by the same token, if, uh, Buddha came down and walked over to me and said, "Hey, uh, I'm Buddha.
Speaker 1: I'm real,".
Speaker 1: and then he did some magic, I'd be a Buddhist.
Speaker 0: Yup, but first I had to make my wisdom check in case I disbelieved and he disappeared.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might just be a, uh, major illusion.
Speaker 0: It might just be a major illusion, but you know what?
Speaker 0: When it comes down to it, there's always that philosophy.
Speaker 0: it could just be like the Matrix, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But forget about that.
Speaker 0: There's not much you can do about it if it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but believe whatever you want.
Speaker 1: Just don't disbelieve things that are real and proven.
Speaker 1: That's all I ask.
Speaker 0: Heh.
Speaker 1: That's not- that's like so simple.
Speaker 1: That's all I want.
Speaker 0: If I hold up one finger and say, "How many fingers am I holding
Speaker 0: up?"
Speaker 0: Don't say two.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll cry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then I'll hit you.
Speaker 0: And then I'll hit you for every number you're off by.
Speaker 1: Schlagensee.
Speaker 0: Schlagensee.
Speaker 1: So, uh, obviously we're just kinda running the recorder here.
Speaker 1: We're not editing or stopping or anything, so Scott can do his news now.
Speaker 0: There is, um, not really a way to segue to this news, but, uh, a long-lost Nintendo game.
Speaker 0: Well, not so long lost.
Speaker 0: It was a game that came out for the Super Nintendo and was never a sequel, but was very popular.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's a lost franchise, basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's a Nintendo franchise that hasn't had more than one game.
Speaker 1: It's one that shouldn't have been forgotten because it kind of started a whole new genre of gaming.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's very, very awesome.
Speaker 0: And they're finally, for sure, working on possibly another one, probably for the revolution.
Speaker 0: They're gonna make Pilotwings 2?
Speaker 0: Pilotwings Revolution?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Pilotwings, baby, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Pilotwings is one of the launch games for the SNES.
Speaker 0: I remember it was a launch game for the SNES.
Speaker 0: It's one of the few SNES games they don't have a ROM for, but I might now because they downloaded a package of, like, a zillion SNES ROMs.
Speaker 0: Ooh, don't tell anyone.
Speaker 1: Villainy!
Speaker 0: I don't know what, another word for villainy.
Speaker 0: Haha!
Speaker 0: Scoundrelisms!
Speaker 1: You Montabank!
Speaker 0: Piracy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Arrr.
Speaker 1: But Pilotwings was a fun game.
Speaker 1: Basically, it was a game of learn how to pilot a plane, learn how to parachute, learn how to fly a rocket pack, learn how to hang glide.
Speaker 1: Do things to get points.
Speaker 1: Learn to do it perfectly and you'll get more points.
Speaker 1: Unlock things by doing things well.
Speaker 1: Do stunts.
Speaker 0: n64 which i never knew about until just now.
Speaker 1: it wasn't very widely played.
Speaker 0: there wasn't a pilot wings gamecube which apparently some people wanted.
Speaker 0: but there's probably going to be a pilot wings revolution.
Speaker 0: all right so it's the revolution.
Speaker 1: makes sense because it's got the awesome controller.
Speaker 0: yeah it's the third.
Speaker 0: so it's the third pilot wings not the second one.
Speaker 0: all right whatever.
Speaker 0: also something that was fairly obvious to me and a bunch of other people.
Speaker 0: um and i thought it.
Speaker 0: you can ask people who were with me at the time when i you know i've said it a bunch of times in the past few months they're actually going to make mario paint ds for real.
Speaker 1: probably i just assumed they would.
Speaker 0: i just assumed they would also but hopefully now all the people who go what's mario paint we can show them what for man i had mario paint the day it came out.
Speaker 1: i remember i came home from school and i was i i forget i think i was in middle school or other still elementary school i don't remember.
Speaker 1: but i came home from school and my parents were like there's something in your brother's room you can't go in there until he gets home.
Speaker 1: and i remember thinking what could it be?
Speaker 1: super nintendo's in his room it's mario paints.
Speaker 1: and i snuck into the room and played.
Speaker 1: mario paint awesome.
Speaker 1: and then my brother came home and my parents my parents yelling for me like brennan because you know back then i didn't call myself i would have what kind of parents my parents would have gone up to look at that room every few minutes.
Speaker 1: i they i guess they assumed i was doing something else.
Speaker 1: geniuses they were because i was in there with the door shut and they called for me and i'm like oh shit.
Speaker 1: and i tried like open the door to sneak out my brother sitting there and it's like oh owned.
Speaker 1: though to this day there's a debate not really debate more of an angry argument between my brother and i because i made on the game before he touched it an awesome stamp icon and he claimed i don't even remember it was so long ago that he made it or something.
Speaker 1: that story doesn't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: well okay it's like the.
Speaker 1: it's like the clamp it's and the what's it's.
Speaker 1: we're still fighting but we don't remember why.
Speaker 0: you mean the hatfields and the mccoys yeah yeah those ones like.
Speaker 0: i said at the beginning of the episode i'm tired we are tired and the episode is about tired to crap lazy pucks what.
Speaker 0: that's exactly my point.
Speaker 1: i'm not editing that out in fact we're going straight to things of the day.
Speaker 1: so anyway my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: um actually i didn't really have anything for today.
Speaker 1: so i was trolling around on google video and i found this little gem.
Speaker 1: now i'm not sure of the scenario here other than that these young boys are playing quake 3 and watch the video and watch the guy in the back right corner of this land party.
Speaker 1: he gets quite perturbed at what is going on in the game.
Speaker 0: he might remind you of a recent thing of the day involving a german kid.
Speaker 1: german kid where is des escaping?
Speaker 1: only this kid's korean?
Speaker 1: yeah and this kid looks i don't i'm pretty sure it's real because the guy holding the camera is kind of like staying back and you hear him going like yeah that's the best.
Speaker 0: is that in the german one and just kind of weird this one you have a guy who takes the place of you who's laughing with you.
Speaker 1: so yeah the german one was like wow this is funny.
Speaker 1: okay is this is fake?
Speaker 1: wow this kid have mental problems.
Speaker 1: this isn't funny this is disturbing.
Speaker 1: yeah this one's just funny.
Speaker 1: and then the guy notices that someone's laughing at him and he whips a can of something at him.
Speaker 0: i think he throws a pen or a pencil or something.
Speaker 1: yeah it was funny it made me laugh and it was the best thing i've seen on the internet today.
Speaker 0: awesome.
Speaker 0: so i was looking for something.
Speaker 0: i didn't come up very big but i found another funny video game commercial.
Speaker 1: so you're not gonna do the f1 crashes.
Speaker 0: no the f1 crashes can wait for another time in another place.
Speaker 0: perhaps an episode where we talk about f1.
Speaker 1: didn't we already talk about f1?
Speaker 0: we didn't do a whole episode in f1.
Speaker 0: i think we did an episode about sports.
Speaker 0: oh yeah yeah yeah we could do like a when the season's over.
Speaker 1: we could at the end of the year we can do like an f1 review or we could do a thursday episode on all those bad things on the internet like car crashes and people exploding.
Speaker 0: you mean a fox special and style project.
Speaker 0: so a fox special of geek nights?
Speaker 0: yeah okay.
Speaker 0: so anyway world's blankiest blank.
Speaker 0: this is a um a japanese early 90s commercial for the game boy version of dr mario.
Speaker 0: it's basically a bunch of people dressed up as germs synchronized swimming doing a crazy dance and it's pretty scary.
Speaker 1: the music is creepy.
Speaker 0: rim is making a funny with a toy a toy that i can.
Speaker 0: i have a similar toy but it's at work.
Speaker 0: yes the people who know me know that i'm really good at dr mario.
Speaker 0: he is really good like it was weird because i never had dr mario but i knew how to play it and i played it a few times on an emulator.
Speaker 0: but when it came down to playing dr mario against people i kicked everyone.
Speaker 0: i knows ass.
Speaker 0: so if anyone wants to challenge me to some dr mario if they ever make it for the ds or anything let's get it on.
Speaker 1: i'm actually quite surprised that some dr mario wasn't included in tetris ds.
Speaker 0: yeah i mean they had a level that's tetrisy.
Speaker 0: that looks like yoshi's cookie but they don't have a level that's like dr mario.
Speaker 1: i guess my only guess is that they're going to release dr mario ds.
Speaker 0: well no they released.
Speaker 0: um that like puzzle combination game for the gba that had.
Speaker 0: i think it had you.
Speaker 0: i'm sure about yoshi's cookie or not but it had dr mario and panel de pon.
Speaker 0: and if you don't know panel de pon is the what was originally pokemon puzzle league.
Speaker 0: pokemon puzzle league is just panel de pon with pokemon added in and that's the game where you flip to to the right and to the left sort of like horizontal medios kind.
Speaker 1: yeah even though i don't i don't like medios.
Speaker 0: medios is okay.
Speaker 0: i wouldn't think i would pay more than 10 bucks for it.
Speaker 1: well i remembered something we played because i did really well when we played with those guys at uh gaming for hope.
Speaker 1: and the reason i did well is because i remembered something taiko had said on penny arcade about medios.
Speaker 1: you can do very well for yourself by simply simply randomly dragging the stylus up and down on rows as fast as you can and all i did was scribble back and forth and i kept making things and making combos and shooting things up and i was doing real well.
Speaker 1: oh really yeah because i was trying and i did okay yeah but i just i just freaking scribbled around and without do not even thinking i kept knocking things up and hitting that planet.
Speaker 1: wow yeah it was kind of annoying.
Speaker 0: yeah the thing is i just wish they would have kept those.
Speaker 0: you know they were gonna make that puzzle combination game for the gba and they did and i was looking forward to it but they delayed it so long.
Speaker 0: i kind of wish they would have just moved it to the ds and added wi-fi and wireless to it.
Speaker 0: yeah i mean dr mario alone would be worth it.
Speaker 1: so anyway like we said our uh main bit today is about procrastination and laziness and how they uh work respective to geeks and how you can fight them if you want to or if you need to.
Speaker 1: i mean first i'll say that we're pretty lazy.
Speaker 0: god i am so lazy.
Speaker 0: but that is one of the three important uh attributes of a great programmer.
Speaker 0: yeah laziness.
Speaker 1: well the other thing is i mean we think of ourselves as lazy because a lot of times we'll sit around and we'll realize hey i could be doing something relevant and important and productive right now but i'm not.
Speaker 1: but then we realize how much we do compared to most people.
Speaker 1: i mean i guess if you compare us and most geeks to the average person we're the opposite of lazy.
Speaker 1: we're the most ambitious like driven people in the world.
Speaker 0: yet right now i'm so lazy i can't even podcast while sitting up.
Speaker 0: i'm laying down.
Speaker 0: yeah i'm sitting here i am reclined.
Speaker 0: that's how lazy we are.
Speaker 1: but i mean we're lazy.
Speaker 1: like we're really lazy.
Speaker 1: we really generally mostly enjoy to do nothing like when we go to the shore in wildwood with our friend scott johnson and stayed his beach house.
Speaker 1: i mean there's crazy things to do all over the place.
Speaker 1: but our favorite thing is to either lay in the beach house going ah or to lay on the beach going.
Speaker 0: it's so weird with our laziness is that we will put in lots and lots of effort in order to continue doing nothing.
Speaker 0: i mean if we're sitting in a restaurant someone has to do the tiny bit of paying the bill and we will viciously fight and put in more effort than it takes to pay the bill into not paying the bill.
Speaker 0: yeah it's the same thing.
Speaker 0: we're like if everyone's laying down and comfortable in a room talking and someone has to get up to say get a drink or get a the phone or get a video game from across.
Speaker 1: the worst is ordering pizza or order a pizza.
Speaker 0: that's a lot of effort.
Speaker 1: we all have a cell phone we're all adults but for some reason whenever we're going to order a pizza no one will do it.
Speaker 0: yep so we we will fight viciously with more effort than it takes to order a pizza in order so that someone else will order the pizza and not us.
Speaker 1: i mean i guess really it's a fault of the english language that we need to split lazy into two separate concepts because lazy the way i would think of lazy now are people who just don't do anything like the guy who comes home from work and then sits there watching tv and doesn't do anything and then goes to bed.
Speaker 1: compared to that guy we're the opposite of lazy.
Speaker 1: we're lazy in like this different sense.
Speaker 1: there's no word for it.
Speaker 0: um yeah i don't know.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like when you talk about laziness for a programmer you're not talking about doesn't want to do anything you're talking about a guy who doesn't or a girl.
Speaker 0: no no a lazy programmer.
Speaker 0: what they will do is because they're so lazy and they want things to be so simple and efficient and requiring the least effort.
Speaker 0: they will put in a whole shit ton of effort to write a complicated script to make life easier later and that's what it's like for us.
Speaker 0: we'll do a whole bunch of work up front that doesn't even seem like work in order to prevent other work that is possibly unpleasant.
Speaker 1: well like the little example of paying the bill at the restaurant.
Speaker 1: for us paying the bill is a mundane task and we generally seem to dislike anything mundane or routine.
Speaker 1: now arguing and fighting to not have to pay the bill while it takes more effort is much more enjoyable.
Speaker 0: yeah usually just comes down to saying not it but or not it.
Speaker 0: race is a fun game not it.
Speaker 1: i mean i would rather spend 10 times as much effort doing something i enjoy then spend any effort whatsoever doing something i don't enjoy.
Speaker 0: yep and i mean come on this is simple stuff like paying a bill in a restaurant.
Speaker 0: what the hell's wrong with us?
Speaker 1: yeah yet we say we're lazy.
Speaker 1: we've done 87 45 to an hour and 20 minute long fairly professionally done audio radio shows.
Speaker 0: this isn't anything.
Speaker 0: i'm laying down in a recliner talking as they normally would.
Speaker 0: we're just holding a microphone in front of my face.
Speaker 0: it's not effort because we have to do this anyway.
Speaker 1: yeah we'd probably.
Speaker 1: honestly i mean today tonight's geek nights for those of you who haven't realized it by now is completely unedited.
Speaker 0: well we took out a few uh empty pauses of nothing.
Speaker 1: yeah but that's short some silences.
Speaker 1: but other than that this is exactly.
Speaker 1: we didn't start we didn't cut anything out appear.
Speaker 1: and uh i guess all it'll show is that we really almost never cut anything out.
Speaker 1: we really are like this all the time on the air off the air we basically have the same kinds of conversations.
Speaker 1: the only difference is we're usually a little bit less informative when we're not talking into a microphone.
Speaker 0: yeah plus we usually are talking to people who already know stuff.
Speaker 0: so the only time we're informative is do you know this?
Speaker 0: just to make sure that someone knows something that might not be common knowledge you know.
Speaker 0: so if we talk the way we do to each other on the podcast you'd be like what are they talking about?
Speaker 0: i don't know unless you were really really smart like us and then you would know.
Speaker 0: but then why would the hell are you listening if you're so smart?
Speaker 1: i guess i mean the when i noticed this is that well one.
Speaker 1: a lot of our friends especially in college would always say that we're hilarious or like like.
Speaker 1: they'd like we scott and i would start arguing we'd have a bunch of people over and they would just start like people would all sit around and just kind of watch us argue and one day we noticed and it's like wow why are you guys here?
Speaker 0: it's just us arguing with each other and they were like it's funny i'm like okay and then we'd bring a new person over who didn't know anything about us.
Speaker 1: yeah they just be like hysterical on the floor rolling around not just us but like our group and the way we interact seem to be very entertaining to people who didn't know us.
Speaker 0: yeah i don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: it's not so entertaining to me.
Speaker 0: it's like i say things and they're not really funny.
Speaker 0: they're just normal things that i say and other people are just like ah oh my god oh my god.
Speaker 1: yeah so i guess while we do a lot i mean we put out all this content on the internet.
Speaker 1: it doesn't take effort for us it only takes time.
Speaker 0: yeah it would take effort if i had to like get up and walk around or something
Speaker 1: or if we had to think of things to say
Speaker 0: well we do have to think about what to talk about but once we get going we're good
Speaker 1: yeah and thinking about what we talk about is usually just all right.
Speaker 1: there's three things in the news.
Speaker 1: we can't talk forever.
Speaker 1: which one are we not going to talk about?
Speaker 0: the boring one?
Speaker 1: yeah someday we'll probably record the process.
Speaker 1: we you know what.
Speaker 1: let's do a show next week where we we don't actually do our news.
Speaker 1: we just record us deciding which news we're going to do and then we'll record the news for the next day one.
Speaker 1: it kills two episodes.
Speaker 0: news wise we'll wait for there to be not enough news.
Speaker 0: yeah no i got it on a day where there's like shit shit news.
Speaker 0: we'll just record us figuring out that this shit shit news.
Speaker 1: yeah coming to the conclusion that there's nothing and then picking two crap news isn't doing them all right.
Speaker 0: so what can you do?
Speaker 0: if you want to be productive and you have some ideas for things to do like projects and such but you're too lazy and you won't do them?
Speaker 1: well the easiest answer is do them.
Speaker 1: if you can't overcome your laziness to do it you didn't really want to do it anyway.
Speaker 0: that's pretty much what it comes down to.
Speaker 0: i mean if you set projects for yourself that you don't want to do enough that you you know you might want the result but if you don't actually want to do what it takes to get that result then you don't want to do it.
Speaker 0: you're not going to do it.
Speaker 0: if you have to do it you're eventually going to be forced to.
Speaker 0: so that's that's what we'll talk about.
Speaker 0: procrastination next.
Speaker 1: but yeah like case in point i was i decided i wanted to learn how to run jboss servers.
Speaker 1: so i got all this documentation.
Speaker 1: i'm reading through it.
Speaker 1: i decided i'm going to teach myself jboss because it's useful to put on my resume blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: but the thing is i don't like jboss and i didn't like learning about it.
Speaker 1: and every time like i'd have to force myself to read the documentation and like install the server and play with it and eventually i realized all right i'm never going to actually do this because i hate it and i stopped.
Speaker 1: meanwhile i decided i wanted to learn.
Speaker 1: uh a while a long time ago i decided to learn hongdol which is the way you're right in korean and i really wanted to even though it's useless to me because i wasn't.
Speaker 1: i didn't think i was going to actually learn korean and i learned it in like a week just because i actually wanted to do it.
Speaker 1: if you don't want to do something don't force yourself to do it because it's never going to get done ever and if it is it won't be satisfying you're.
Speaker 0: you're mainly just going to unpleasantness for yourself.
Speaker 0: if you want a result and you don't want to do the work required to get the result.
Speaker 0: here's an example.
Speaker 0: let's say you want a new uh piece of furniture and you think i'll build it but you don't actually like building furniture and you just never get around to it.
Speaker 1: not only will it suck to build it and cost you more but it'll look like ass when you're done.
Speaker 0: just hire someone to do it to get the result for money and spend your time doing something you like to do and maybe get money for that you can use to pay for the other thing.
Speaker 0: that's why we have an economy.
Speaker 1: yep i mean i see so many people that are so unmotivated and i can't imagine that.
Speaker 1: but then i realize that these people are all trying to do things that they don't really want to do.
Speaker 1: it's that simple?
Speaker 0: yeah i mean if there's like a book and you'd be like man i really got to read this book but you never read it.
Speaker 0: obviously you don't like the book.
Speaker 0: get rid of it and read different books.
Speaker 0: yeah
Speaker 1: i mean if you're reading i actually that happened to me recently there's a book i'm reading and i really wanted to read it but it wasn't the kind of book that you read straight through and i was having trouble just like picking it up and continuing it and i realized suddenly all right this is dumb.
Speaker 1: i'm just gonna read this book that i want to read and i'll put that one in the bathroom.
Speaker 0: yeah excellent well which book was that?
Speaker 1: it was the biography.
Speaker 1: it was a biography of peter the great.
Speaker 0: yeah no one can read that because i really want to.
Speaker 1: i'm really interested in peter the great.
Speaker 1: i know quite a bit about him but this is an extremely detailed biography.
Speaker 0: i looked at it in the bathroom once and i was just like what the hell.
Speaker 1: so now i read like a chapter every now and then but i don't force myself to read it when i don't want to.
Speaker 1: yeah now procrastination is an entirely different beast.
Speaker 0: it mainly affects students.
Speaker 1: yeah i will say with in no uncertain terms that i for the entirety of my time at the rochester institute of technology put off every single project i ever had until the absolute last second and then put myself through hell trying to finish it.
Speaker 0: i procrastinated 90 of the time throughout my entire student career.
Speaker 0: i
Speaker 1: mean i would literally i remember the moment my sophomore year where because for my whole life before no matter how much i procrastinated i would always like just pull it all night or the night before finish the paper fall asleep wake up like two hours later and go to class and turn it in.
Speaker 1: there was one time when i was writing a paper overnight and it was due the next day and the sun came up and class was in an hour and i still wasn't done.
Speaker 1: wow i finished it barely and you know what.
Speaker 1: that didn't change me i i procrastinated just as much in the next paper.
Speaker 0: so you know what eventually got me on the papers was.
Speaker 0: i realized it doesn't really take that long for me to write papers and that like i would write a paper and then i would spend a long time editing and rewriting and rewriting your drink.
Speaker 0: then one time i just wrote one and just submitted it because i was like oh whatever i got a good grade so i just stopped putting in a whole lot of work into them and i just did have been handed them in.
Speaker 0: i didn't care.
Speaker 1: yep well it depends partly at least if you're a procrastinator in college on the school you go to because rit had no pluses or minuses to grades.
Speaker 1: it was a b c fail and super fail and that was also d. well yeah d was basically a failure because it counted as a pass but it didn't count for the prerequisites of other classes.
Speaker 1: so you basically had to take the class again unless it wasn't a class in your major.
Speaker 1: so a d was effectively a failure.
Speaker 0: i did not know that.
Speaker 1: yeah d's did not count as prerequisites unless you got special permission which no one ever got.
Speaker 1: wow so at rit you either said i am going to put the effort forth to get an a or you shot for the low b because the low b was the minimum effort and you still got a b even though you almost got a c. but now you got a b.
Speaker 0: see throughout my entire schooling i always just never did put an extra effort.
Speaker 0: i did every graded assignment and i attended class and that was it.
Speaker 0: that's all i did.
Speaker 0: i never did reading assignments unless it was literature.
Speaker 1: i never bought my books.
Speaker 1: i never did my reading i never did reading.
Speaker 0: i only did literature reading like i just said.
Speaker 1: actually i didn't do that.
Speaker 1: oh i i never read the tree stars whatever that terrible book tree red stars.
Speaker 0: yeah i read that in like a day.
Speaker 1: i didn't even buy it or read it and but i did.
Speaker 0: um i'm losing it because i'm tired.
Speaker 0: yeah i mean basically oh i never studied at anything ever ever ever ever and somehow i always got like b's and a's and the very rare c except uh calculus.
Speaker 0: until one day i took calculus three and i did the same exact thing and i failed.
Speaker 0: and then i said oh shits i better take that again.
Speaker 0: and i failed.
Speaker 0: and then i said oh shits and it's a three in the summer and i gotta see yep three times in calculus three and then i said thank god i never have to take calculus again.
Speaker 0: god damn
Speaker 1: i guess all i want to say about procrastination is that a lot of people say it's a bad thing and all i have to say is that procrastination is probably responsible for much of the happiness in my life today because if i hadn't procrastinated if i had been diligent and done all my schoolwork like worked on my projects ahead of time throughout the quarter i wouldn't have had half the fun that i had in college.
Speaker 1: no i wouldn't be doing work i'd have a 4.0 but i wouldn't have enjoyed myself.
Speaker 1: i mean how many times did i like a lot?
Speaker 1: there were projects in it that were always like all right.
Speaker 1: you have all quarter 10 weeks to do this and basically if you go to the lab every weekend for like two or three hours all quarter you'll be done by like the ninth week and then you just turn in your work.
Speaker 0: but that pretty much rules out any all weekend activities.
Speaker 1: so instead i would just jack screw around all week all weekend all quarter and then around week eight i'd realize oh shit and then i'd kill one whole weekend like barely finishing the project and then i'd go back just like enough.
Speaker 0: it also depends a lot on your friends.
Speaker 0: i mean if all your friends are procrastinators then they won't want to hang out with you in the end of the semester anyway because they'll all be doing the same thing.
Speaker 0: you're doing yep bit by bit.
Speaker 1: all our friends that actually did their schoolwork drifted apart from us just because they they were around because we all skip classes to go do stuff.
Speaker 0: yeah and if you hang out with people who you know do their schoolwork then those then you have to do it too because otherwise you won't be available.
Speaker 0: at the same time you'll be you know freewheeling it alone most of the quarter and then at the end they'll have a little bit more free time and you'll be locked up.
Speaker 1: yeah i mean skipping a class alone for whatever reason is usually stupid.
Speaker 1: but the best time to skip a class is say you go for lunch at the cafeteria somewhere or like a campus thing and you're eating and then you run into three of your friends and you all have class at one and you eat lunch together.
Speaker 1: that's the point especially if they're not slackers when you have to convince them to skip class with you if they don't skip you might as well not skip either.
Speaker 1: but if you can get more the more people you get to skip something with you or procrastinate with you the more fun you'll have net.
Speaker 0: now you got to keep in mind when you procrastinate.
Speaker 0: you're saying all right i don't want to do this now because it doesn't have to be done now.
Speaker 0: it can be done later.
Speaker 0: and if you're going to neglect not doing it right now you better do something good.
Speaker 0: otherwise you should have done the thing instead.
Speaker 0: yep but it is the other thing a lot of people um make like little planners and things right.
Speaker 0: yeah now all i gotta say about this is number one.
Speaker 0: if you have a really terrible memory like you can't remember what i was saying to you a minute ago you don't remember the name of this podcast then you probably need some sort of little planning book or something.
Speaker 0: but if your memory is good and you know like i generally remember what i have to do like oh i have to go to work today.
Speaker 0: oh this is what i have to do at work.
Speaker 0: you know i might have like a really sort of sketchy to-do list somewhere but i don't really look at it so much.
Speaker 0: but you got to be careful.
Speaker 0: if you're the person who needs a list of things to do or a schedule or whatnot don't spend more time fiddling with that than doing the actual stuff.
Speaker 1: yeah these freaking life hackers who spend more time like trying to organize their life than they do living their life.
Speaker 0: yeah it's like they got these moleskines and things and it's like i have a fancy notebook and i write my things down in a special way and it's like you spend a whole you spend.
Speaker 0: how many hours writing down what you're gonna do you could spend doing stuff.
Speaker 0: it's like what the hell?
Speaker 0: yep uh just i don't get those people.
Speaker 0: don't be that guy.
Speaker 1: yeah the moral here is just if you're gonna procrastinate do it for a reason.
Speaker 1: if you don't have a reason to put something off you might as well do it now.
Speaker 1: the reason could be trivial.
Speaker 1: the reason could be like i want donuts so instead of doing your paper you drive out to get donuts.
Speaker 0: yeah but don't sit around going or i should be doing my paper.
Speaker 1: that's the worst thing.
Speaker 1: the people who procrastinate but then worry about what they're procrastinating about and as a result they don't get their work done and at the same time they don't enjoy the extra free time they got by not doing their work.
Speaker 0: that's like the worst thing you can do yeah because you basically just wasted time you didn't get fun and you didn't get anything done either.
Speaker 1: yep you're still fucked and now it's later.
Speaker 0: good job you're the winner or actually no you're the loser if you do that.
Speaker 1: yeah we just always make fun of our friend pete.
Speaker 1: you know pete the one who's now a scientist of somewhat he's somewhat respected ill repute.
Speaker 0: oh no wait that's the wrong words.
Speaker 1: and you know we had him on the episode on the show a while ago as uh when we talked about pseudoscience.
Speaker 1: we're gonna have him on again sometime hopefully soon and he'd always around midnight or one he'd go home.
Speaker 0: yeah i we're like why are you going home?
Speaker 0: everyone else is staying.
Speaker 0: he'd be like i got an 8 a.m class.
Speaker 0: i'm like you don't have to go to the 8 a.m class.
Speaker 0: he'd be like yeah i gotta go to the 8 a.m class.
Speaker 0: there's like a test.
Speaker 0: yeah we're like all right we don't want you to go but we can't prevent you from leaving.
Speaker 0: he would never go to the 8 a.m class.
Speaker 1: yeah ever he just go home and sleep through it anyway.
Speaker 0: yeah it's like he could have stayed and it would have been better off but no it didn't listen to us.
Speaker 0: good job.
Speaker 1: yeah there was a nice pause there because that's all we got.
Speaker 0: i think i think that's all we got.
Speaker 0: this is a pretty um ill planned episode of ill repute.
Speaker 0: i said repute twice you and ill repute.
Speaker 0: i don't know.
Speaker 0: i just i came to mind when you said candy man candy man candy man.
Speaker 0: yeah right betelgeuse.
Speaker 0: no because you said uh like scientist of and the first thing comes to mind is overpute you say anything that comes to mind.
Speaker 0: yeah if you say occupation of i i seem to think ill repute for some reason.
Speaker 1: really.
Speaker 0: yeah i don't know why like plumber of ill repute carpenter i'm a plumber all right that's enough of that.
Speaker 1: yeah did we ever tell the?
Speaker 1: it's a me mario story on geek nights from ohio con?
Speaker 0: yeah yeah okay we did great.
Speaker 1: in other news i doodled a fairly poorly stylized picture of a deer with three legs while i did this episode.
Speaker 0: is it anything like a formula one car with three wheels?
Speaker 1: that was amazing.
Speaker 1: i don't know what to say about that other than it should be your thing of the day on monday.
Speaker 0: i think it's gonna be if nothing else comes up.
Speaker 1: all right i'm going to bed.
Speaker 0: next thursday we'll have a better episode.
Speaker 1: yes actually next thursday we decided we didn't want to do it today because one we want to warn people and two we want to be awake.
Speaker 1: for this one we're i mean geek nights hasn't really done anything particularly i don't know risque or controversial.
Speaker 0: yeah i mean if i had to rate geek nights i'd give it a pg-13 except sometimes you say fuck.
Speaker 0: so you have to give it a rated r like yeah you can have up to one fuck in a pg-13 movie.
Speaker 1: oh really in many cases it depends on how it's used.
Speaker 0: so we're we're somewhere between low pg-13.
Speaker 0: well low r high pg-13.
Speaker 1: yeah something like that.
Speaker 1: next thursday we're going to delve into yet untested geek nights.
Speaker 0: so if you are of i don't know a different mind or maybe possibly under the age of 18 i don't know.
Speaker 0: yeah what are the?
Speaker 1: we might have to put the explicit tag on that one if you would violate a law by listening to two guys talk about masturbation.
Speaker 1: don't listen to next thursday's geek nights.
Speaker 0: we are going to talk about masturbation specifically male masturbation because we do not have vaginas.
Speaker 0: if we had vaginas we would talk about female masturbation.
Speaker 0: now that we have actually lots mostly because we are grand masters grand masturbators and i guarantee this is gonna be the funniest episode of geek nights ever you wouldn't believe how many stars we have.
Speaker 0: um for any of you because we know we have we might have to do a part one and a part two.
Speaker 1: we have.
Speaker 1: we know we have a lot of listeners who haven't been to college yet who still in high school and i don't think you guys realize the complicated nature of college masturbatory habits because you have a roommate and neither one of you wants to talk about masturbation but somehow you both have to make it known when you both will be there and will not be there so everyone can satisfy themselves.
Speaker 0: we should do part one uh stroking it and part two finishing it.
Speaker 0: i'm just i don't know.
Speaker 0: this is like a gold mine.
Speaker 0: so just be warned if you are the uh faint of heart yeah or if if you would in any way violate a law by listening to next thursday's geek nights or if you're easily offended.
Speaker 1: if you're easily offended why are you still listening to the show?
Speaker 0: i mean because they like being offended.
Speaker 0: and you know.
Speaker 0: if you're easily offended and you're listening to the show still and you're getting offended keep listening because i love offending you.
Speaker 0: it's great and tell me about it too.
Speaker 0: i want to get.
Speaker 0: i haven't got a single hate mail because of geek nights.
Speaker 1: yeah you're right we haven't gotten any.
Speaker 0: i want i've got.
Speaker 1: i got.
Speaker 1: hey i wrote a freaking article about being happy in the college newspaper at rit like this dinky little newspaper called gracie's dinnertime theater and i got fucking hate mail.
Speaker 1: why doesn't geek nights which has far more listeners than that had readers get hate mail?
Speaker 1: i want hate mail.
Speaker 1: i don't want fake mail though.
Speaker 0: yeah as soon as i when we get a real hate mail i tell you what any real legitimate hate mail and i can tell.
Speaker 0: don't think i can't tell.
Speaker 0: yeah we know we know you know mr period will check it too so he knows.
Speaker 1: yeah and someone already asked.
Speaker 1: we're not gonna tell you who mr period is because it's a long story but this person has a lot more free time than they should and for whatever reason they want to do this for us.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: so yeah watch your grammar and spelling in the forms and mr beard will come after you although he is going to be a little bit lenient.
Speaker 0: so if you write te he'll be.
Speaker 0: he'll be like all right that happens.
Speaker 1: i think that's mostly because the first person he went after was you.
Speaker 0: yeah what do you want?
Speaker 0: but see that was actually when he went after me.
Speaker 0: that was a typo and not uh i had the words there.
Speaker 0: i just accidentally deleted them i'm sure anyway.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: so next thursday and hate mail and that's it.
Speaker 0: yeah any hate mail will get on the show.
Speaker 0: yep legitimate hate mail.
Speaker 1: and that was geek nights with rim and scott special thanks to dj pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: you can send your email feedback to geekknights@gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: geek nights airs every weeknight monday through thursday.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience but unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.