Speaker 0: It's Tuesday May 30th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We have the first tiny bit of an amazement coverage and Scott talks about how much he hates planet side.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So we've always known about Google Calendar.
Speaker 0: I mean we knew it was there.
Speaker 0: We had it.
Speaker 0: We just didn't really.
Speaker 1: actually it's relatively new and I remember the day it came out because everyone was like oh my god.
Speaker 1: Google Calendar and I was like Whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't use any calendar software every calendar software ever.
Speaker 1: I've.
Speaker 1: just whenever I have a paper calendar or a digital calendar or anything like that I start to use it for two seconds or so and then I stopped using it and I never look at it again.
Speaker 0: Yep I've only ever used them at work where I had to schedule appointments and I don't remember Appointments because I don't really care about them.
Speaker 0: I care about conventions.
Speaker 0: So I never need to remind myself when I'm going somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's I don't forget where I have to be ever.
Speaker 0: but Well, the problem is we tend to forget if I already have something scheduled.
Speaker 0: when I'm trying to figure out if I can go to another thing Like someone says hey you want to go to something something on something something and I'm like, ah, maybe Anyway, so today I finally decided to click because we have the Google Gmail for domains thing.
Speaker 1: So I went in.
Speaker 1: there's a little calendar link in the top left.
Speaker 1: So I decided alright, I'll click on it and look see Apparently it's actually really good.
Speaker 1: It's probably the best calendar ever used and I added all the.
Speaker 1: I created one calendar for me and a calendar for the front row Crew and I added all sorts of front row crew events to it and it's all public and sharing and all that good stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep, someday.
Speaker 0: We'll probably expand it and offer email addresses to I don't know cool listeners.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll give them away as we don't have that many.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll get more someday.
Speaker 0: I imagine I was just paying for the full-on one maybe but for now No only the elitist of the elite get them meaning the people who already know us.
Speaker 1: But I think anyone in the world I can make it so anyone in the world can see the calendars.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I'll set that up soon and you'll be able to see the front row crew schedule, which is So far her.
Speaker 1: in June there are two conventions a board game meeting and a concert.
Speaker 1: great and I'm going to a baseball game.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: We should probably set one up for that Moz group, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I could set up a separate Moz calendar because right now I'm just using the.
Speaker 1: I just put Moz event in our calendar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I should probably make a Moz calendar or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's all I mean.
Speaker 0: no one listening cares about that.
Speaker 0: The most people don't listen to our show.
Speaker 0: No, no, even though we run all of their IT.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, but we like Google Calendar now and we're playing with it.
Speaker 1: So it's if you have a Google Calendar Maybe we'll start a Google Calendar thread in the forums and share everyone's Google calendars with each other or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd say tell your funny calendar stories, but there aren't any funny.
Speaker 1: If you have a funny counter story hot name, yeah, so one day this calendar and your mom.
Speaker 1: What about your mom?
Speaker 0: What were you doing with your mom in the back seat rolling around?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but I've got it scheduled for next week on my calendar.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, so video game day in the news.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you all have heard this but we were remember we're not the news.
Speaker 0: we talk about the news.
Speaker 0: So if we give the news and you've already heard it, that's the point.
Speaker 1: The we haven't already heard it.
Speaker 1: You're detached from society and you're not a good geek.
Speaker 1: Go read some websites.
Speaker 0: The Wii is going to be two hundred and fifty dollars.
Speaker 1: This isn't really news because I guess the story before was the Wii will not be more than two hundred fifty dollars.
Speaker 1: They guaranteed us.
Speaker 1: It would be 250 or less now.
Speaker 1: It's 250 for sure.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember that the Super Nintendo was two hundred and fifty dollars when it came out And it shortly dropped to two hundred.
Speaker 0: The NES.
Speaker 0: I don't know exactly how much it started as but we have two hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: I notice a pattern.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now this is going to destroy the PlayStation 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently before e3 they asked the Japanese gamers.
Speaker 1: Hey, what do you want?
Speaker 1: And yeah ps3s RPGs.
Speaker 0: I mean, we're talking like Famitsu readers like the hardest of car like Japan We are.
Speaker 1: the thing is to us.
Speaker 1: Famitsu is the elite gaming magazine in Japan.
Speaker 1: Famitsu is game pro.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's Japanese.
Speaker 1: It's elite by default.
Speaker 1: But You know, it's like we think shonen jump Japan is so awesome to them.
Speaker 1: It's just shonen jump.
Speaker 1: He might as well be spider-man, you know.
Speaker 1: They look at shonen jump the way we look at spider-man.
Speaker 1: So The Yeah, they're well.
Speaker 1: after e3 all the Japanese gamers are like And like 83% of them said the ps3 was too expensive.
Speaker 0: and of course once again for the price of a ps3 you can buy a fully loaded Xbox 360 and a Wii and Still have money left over in a somewhat legitimate poll.
Speaker 1: I think I said this yesterday.
Speaker 1: They asked people what system are you gonna buy?
Speaker 1: and half of People said a 360 and a Wii.
Speaker 1: 25% of people said we only.
Speaker 1: that means 75% penetration on the Wii Plan.
Speaker 1: that yeah, I'm sure you didn't Just had to work harder to get a hundred percent penetrate.
Speaker 0: Well, I gotta buy my own controller so we'll have some double penetrate All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's what I want to know.
Speaker 1: how much is the controller gonna cost?
Speaker 1: because if it's 50 bucks for one of those Fancy doodad things.
Speaker 1: There's no way in hell.
Speaker 0: I'm buying three extra ones When I get the system, well, I'll point out that the tradition in our household is that Scott buys a GameCube I buy a controller for me.
Speaker 0: Scott buys a revolution.
Speaker 0: I'm going to buy a controller for me.
Speaker 1: I still have to buy the two other controllers.
Speaker 0: or you know what.
Speaker 0: you can force all of our friends to buy their own.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well some people who will buy wheeze will have their own controllers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can be damn straight I'll have my own controller that I'll bring everywhere with me.
Speaker 0: I won't touch another man's we.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm getting green so I'm getting green.
Speaker 1: Say about that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: All right, we can both have green but we'll just mark yours with a. with a big black We'll mark yours.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm like by dipping it in red paint.
Speaker 0: All right, let's touch on that non video game news that we want to rant about.
Speaker 1: touch on the.
Speaker 0: we Are being silly today.
Speaker 0: This is just like a way started with an accidental non intentional.
Speaker 0: we joke, you see what kind of people we are.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let's talk about sunscreen.
Speaker 1: that Okay that you put on your way.
Speaker 0: It's a nice lubricant You know what?
Speaker 0: Thank you Ted.
Speaker 0: that was the joke exactly, okay now Oftentimes when you see news about a consumer product.
Speaker 1: Well, let's start with what happened.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go very broadly and then we'll go into what happened.
Speaker 0: I just want to say that a lot of times we'll see a product and we'll know Exactly where the buzz about this product came from and it's usually obvious to us if or if not Something is legitimately popular or if it is popular due to some sort of shilling.
Speaker 1: Shilling not Curt.
Speaker 1: shilling the major league baseball pitcher slash EverQuest player?
Speaker 1: No, not him.
Speaker 0: and not shilling as in the British currency.
Speaker 1: Nope, not those either.
Speaker 0: shilling as in Hocking words as in the people who keeps trying to get us to talk about their stupid books on geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yes Which we're not going to do.
Speaker 1: not going to interview about your book that we've never read.
Speaker 1: that no one cares about.
Speaker 0: If we did, we'd probably pan it just because you showed.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So there was an.
Speaker 1: here's the story of what happened today.
Speaker 1: There was an article on the ABC News website about this Miracle chemical.
Speaker 1: on they didn't think they said the word miracle, but it's a chemical called I can't in Mexico something It doesn't matter what the name of the chemicals, okay, Mexico real m e X o r y l. Anyway, the story behind Mexico and this is all true.
Speaker 1: I checked out.
Speaker 0: science wise is that what in your lab?
Speaker 1: Yeah I was wearing a lab coat at the time At that stolen from Lewis black.
Speaker 1: Okay, so The story behind this chemical is this the sunscreen that we buy in America has the SPF's and the SPF's Depending on the number block UVB rays.
Speaker 1: UVB rays cause Cancer and tanning and sunburn and tanning.
Speaker 0: so they're good and bad and you need some but not too many.
Speaker 0: if you have darker skin You need you.
Speaker 0: more is good and it can't hurt you as much.
Speaker 0: you have lighter skin more hurts you more.
Speaker 0: You know that it's all commonly known.
Speaker 1: SPF's that we get in our current Sunscreen do not protect against UVA rays, but that's okay.
Speaker 1: UVA rays don't cause cancer and sunburn, but they do cause wrinkles.
Speaker 1: So if you were able to block the UVA rays You would not be as wrinkly when you're an old fogey if you hang out on the beach all the time.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So I guess if you really, you know care about vanity and whatnot, that's a good thing.
Speaker 1: but This chemical Mexeril, I guess if that I pronounce it right who cares.
Speaker 0: I don't know Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, who cares of the name of the chemical?
Speaker 1: is it can block all UVA rays and some UVB rays and they've been using it in sunscreen in Europe and Canada and other places since 1993 and Most scientific studies say it's it's just fine.
Speaker 1: It's safe.
Speaker 1: It won't kill you.
Speaker 1: It doesn't hurt you.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: It's fantastic.
Speaker 1: Everyone should use it.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to not just put it in all the sunscreen and help people out and The FDA hasn't approved it yet.
Speaker 1: So it's not in sunscreen.
Speaker 1: But apparently some pharmacists are selling it under the counter for big monies and you could buy it online for big monies.
Speaker 1: And yeah now yeah, I saw right through this.
Speaker 1: You see most people on the internet read this article and they take it at face value.
Speaker 1: You know, it was on dig and it was on some other websites and everyone's like, oh my god The government is.
Speaker 1: you know, the FDA sucks.
Speaker 1: They're preventing us from using this amazing chemical bureaucracy.
Speaker 1: blah, you know.
Speaker 1: And yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Those things are true.
Speaker 1: The government's pretty incompetent and stupid and the FDA isn't perfect and they prevent us from getting things we should have.
Speaker 1: and You know, there are things we shouldn't have that they let us have because companies bribe the FDA and all this business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, homeopathy shouldn't be around.
Speaker 1: All that stuff is true, but that's not what's really going on here.
Speaker 1: What's really going on here is look You're looking at an article on ABC News.
Speaker 0: now know how it suddenly appeared on a major news as opposed to appearing slowly on many sites or and some Blog or on multiple news sites simultaneously.
Speaker 1: Yep which means Some PR guy.
Speaker 1: this is what happened.
Speaker 1: for anyone who doesn't see the obvious some public relations guy went to ABC News and said Hey, you know, there's this miracle chemical that blocks UVA rays called mexor ill.
Speaker 1: How come no one uses it?
Speaker 1: and the guy went huh?
Speaker 1: and he wrote an article about it.
Speaker 1: You know who they were.
Speaker 1: that PR guy was from L'Oreal the company which owns the patent on mexor ill, huh?
Speaker 1: Now we don't have any.
Speaker 1: you know, if you're looking for evidence that this like who was the PR guy When did he make you?
Speaker 1: we don't have that?
Speaker 1: It's just so blatantly obvious that the company that produces and wants to sell mexor ill in the United States is Going to round two newspapers telling them to write articles about mexor ill to get the American public all enraged about it.
Speaker 1: So the FDA will approve it and they'll be able to make a shit ton of money.
Speaker 0: How do I do that?
Speaker 1: It's so obvious that you know.
Speaker 1: But it it's the things like this that people don't see when you're not trained to look for them.
Speaker 1: So I'm not telling you not to buy mexor ill.
Speaker 1: In fact, you should buy some mexor ill if you can because it's awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really does work.
Speaker 1: yeah, but don't buy it overpriced under the counter from the pharmacist or anything like that.
Speaker 1: and If it comes on the market in the US as a result of all this PR Pushing by these companies that produce it so be it.
Speaker 1: But when it comes out buy it from you know, the no-name brand That way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's awesome.
Speaker 0: I mean just in general.
Speaker 0: remember that whenever you see a news article like that look for the warning signs of hey This is a shell because it often is he this doesn't.
Speaker 1: even this article is not.
Speaker 1: you know You have to be trained to see this kind of thing because it doesn't mention any companies.
Speaker 1: It doesn't mention anything.
Speaker 1: It says there is this great chemical.
Speaker 1: It does these great things.
Speaker 1: The FDA has blocked it all its try.
Speaker 1: But you know, you're like, huh?
Speaker 1: Alright, that seems like a legitimate news story.
Speaker 0: now warning sign number one The chemicals been around for a long time and this suddenly makes the news.
Speaker 0: Yep warning sign number two It appeared on one news site.
Speaker 0: that news site was not the AP wire or Reuters.
Speaker 0: Nope Because these people generally won't pay every news site.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it looks obvious Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Of course It looks more obvious when they only pay one because how come no one else is running this story?
Speaker 0: Very few journalists actually do their own investigative journalism.
Speaker 0: these days almost any story you see on the news is either paid for by a company paid for by a third party for some other reason or taken from the AP wire or Reuters
Speaker 1: or someone or some third party made the story and The company the news you're watching just bought that story and played it
Speaker 0: Yep, or a lot of companies just make news stories and give away for free.
Speaker 0: Yep, because they're actually shells.
Speaker 0: Or, you know President Bush makes news stories and gives them away for free and Fox News plays all of them or President Bush hires A gay porn actor to pretend to be a reporter and hang out in the White House asking softball questions.
Speaker 0: I Wish that story would get more press too bad.
Speaker 0: All those stories are true All right, so back to video game news because it's video game day.
Speaker 1: well, it's it's total game day But yeah, it's really only video games today.
Speaker 0: It's video games because we're not really gonna talk about non video games.
Speaker 1: Oh Okay, so some guys were testing out the Vista beta 2. now in the history of Windows Beta 2 has always been sort of important because It's the first version that you can actually use all the time, you know, the beta ones and the pre betas Were always too unstable and they would crash whenever you tried to use them for too long.
Speaker 1: But beta 2 has always been the first version.
Speaker 1: where it was good enough to use as your operating system You'd have to deal with problems, but it wouldn't crash and be useless.
Speaker 1: So they tried to play some games on beta 2 and they took some benchmarks and all that.
Speaker 1: Now the story here is that any game with the evil Star Force DRM didn't work Because Vista doesn't allow the installing of unsigned drivers, which we mentioned quite a while ago on geek nights.
Speaker 0: So one evil turn has prevented another evil turn.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure how this is gonna play out hilarity for geeks like us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, either games won't work Star Force will have to change its ways or Microsoft will take a lot of money out of Star Force.
Speaker 0: cuz Microsoft doesn't care.
Speaker 0: Microsoft doesn't use Star Force in their games.
Speaker 0: No, they don't care if this company survives.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna go easy on them.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna make a bad care about some Russian evil DRM spyware bad driver guys.
Speaker 0: If anything I would guess that Microsoft at least the people from the gaming side of Microsoft or even the operating system Don't like Star Force because it gives PC gaming a bad name.
Speaker 1: They want PC gaming to be strong and on Vista and even so if If Star Force wants their driver Which isn't really a driver to be signed by Microsoft Mary let's not go to approve it.
Speaker 1: if it makes people's computers crash like it currently does So they're gonna.
Speaker 1: Star Force might have to fix it or Star Force might have to die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Microsoft may be evil But they would.
Speaker 0: they would never let some let something make their operating system worse.
Speaker 1: if they can prevent it Especially when it's someone else They don't mind if they fuck it up because they can cover it up.
Speaker 1: if someone else fucks it up You know at least and they don't not gonna attach their name to someone else fucking it up Yeah Which me you know and signing the driver and allowing it to install and Vista would be putting their name on something shitty.
Speaker 1: If someone else wants to fuck up Windows Microsoft, let's.
Speaker 1: it's all you.
Speaker 1: It's nothing to do with us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't get me party software novel.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: I just thought it's funny.
Speaker 1: It's a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: rewind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're talking retro.
Speaker 1: We're talking before geek nights existed.
Speaker 1: We're gonna go with I guess things of the day from years and years ago because guess what there really wasn't anything on the internet today Not a humorous anyway, except for that monkey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll do the monkey tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we will.
Speaker 0: So anyone who's listening now if you look in rims delicious, you will see a link to tomorrow's thing of the day At least rims thing.
Speaker 1: No Anyway rim being me.
Speaker 1: so I'm gonna rewind it to one of my old favorite thing old.
Speaker 1: Oh incredibly old school thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Okay Lobster magnet.
Speaker 0: now This is probably the exact opposite of my thing of the day, which is from the same era.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It's one of the original memes.
Speaker 1: Basically, how did I find this?
Speaker 1: I think 8-bit theater has had a link.
Speaker 0: Yes it was 8-bit theater.
Speaker 1: a bit theater had a page of funny links and one of the funny links was Lobster magnet and it's this guy singing a pretty bad but amusing metal song.
Speaker 1: I guess if you want to call it that so you've got a lobster and you've got a magnet.
Speaker 1: take a ticket ticket ticket.
Speaker 0: Lobster has antenna, but don't you grab it?
Speaker 0: And We're not doing all.
Speaker 1: magnet made of iron.
Speaker 0: Lobster has a B.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's made of meat meat meat of meat and then later it's like rabbit made of steel.
Speaker 1: Lobster has a beak Dan in an in an in an in a. Lobster sticks to Meg.
Speaker 1: You can just.
Speaker 1: You can just watch the flash.
Speaker 0: Yes, this is old and I don't know why we found it So hilarious.
Speaker 0: maybe mostly because these sort of things were new back then.
Speaker 1: It's still good today.
Speaker 0: It's better than a lot of things.
Speaker 1: I've seen recently it is it's humorous.
Speaker 1: It's kind of wacky.
Speaker 1: It sounds cool.
Speaker 0: We used to sing upstairs funny-looking.
Speaker 0: We used to sing it somewhat incessantly much to the annoyance of the front row crew.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: You better watch out if you know the antennas and the magnets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the claws Bite your claw your eye Claw your ear and then it'll bite your eye All right, and then it'll sink your cruise ship.
Speaker 0: Now that is an example of one of the good memes back then.
Speaker 0: that was it spread far and wide.
Speaker 0: It was very popular.
Speaker 0: Mine is an example of perhaps the first dark age of memes.
Speaker 0: We are currently entering the second dark age of memes and I'll explain that in a minute.
Speaker 1: So this So wait, so there were.
Speaker 1: there were Crusades And Bad memes arose that were long forgotten.
Speaker 0: so I built a fourth me that one burnt down fell over then sank into the style project.
Speaker 0: So not too long after Lobster magnet came out.
Speaker 0: There was a news story about a bird a coin bird.
Speaker 0: a guy had I believe it was a car wash and Someone kept stealing quarters from his change machine.
Speaker 0: So one day one day he sets up a camera to catch the punk kids and Sure enough.
Speaker 0: He sees this bird Fly up to it fly in just wiggle its way into the machine come out a minute later with one quarter and fly away.
Speaker 0: Then about ten minutes later.
Speaker 0: It comes back and steals another quarter and does this constantly.
Speaker 0: He why he goes out.
Speaker 0: He waits for the bird.
Speaker 0: He watches it.
Speaker 0: It goes up onto the roof of his place.
Speaker 0: He goes up there and there are thousands of dollars worth of quarters all over the roof.
Speaker 0: The bird was just stealing the quarters and putting them on the roof.
Speaker 1: Was he making a coin nest?
Speaker 0: I don't know coin nesting.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember the story to nest.
Speaker 0: That is my recollection of the story that I read, you know I'll try to find the original story and if I can find it in with no effort will link to it.
Speaker 0: All right Now someone made a flash video about the coin bird.
Speaker 1: Well, some kid drew him MS paint comic, oh, yeah, you want the whole story.
Speaker 0: MS paint comics.
Speaker 0: Let's make a flash.
Speaker 0: flash was made.
Speaker 0: Someone made a song for it.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: This was an example of a me angry for Someone summoned the coin bird Coiny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I promise to help children and help coins.
Speaker 1: I like children.
Speaker 0: and Now this was very obviously an attempt by the people who made it to be the next thing.
Speaker 0: Like they saw lobster magnet was popular.
Speaker 0: They saw all your base was popular.
Speaker 0: They wanted to be popular.
Speaker 0: So they made this specifically in hopes that would be picked up by the internet and become popular.
Speaker 1: They tried to make a meme on Purpose instead of just trying to make something funny for the sake of being funny.
Speaker 1: They tried to make something.
Speaker 1: You know, they didn't try to make it funny.
Speaker 1: They tried to make it popular.
Speaker 0: I believe we have to come back with the Rama Sharma.
Speaker 0: You tried to do too much with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now it did not spread far and wide and it is not that funny.
Speaker 1: no, it's really not funny.
Speaker 0: now I say the first Dark Age because we are currently entering the second Dark Age.
Speaker 0: I mean there was Numa Numa and Numa Numa is awesome.
Speaker 0: Like Numa Numa is one of my favorite things on the internet.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it makes me very happy to watch it.
Speaker 0: It's a very Maya.
Speaker 0: ha Yep now look around YouTube or Google video.
Speaker 0: there are thousands of fat kids lip-syncing to something Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: They're all trying to be the next Numa Numa or the next Star Wars kid.
Speaker 1: But yeah, apparently those like two Chinese kids doing the Backstreet Boys were real popular.
Speaker 1: They're still real popular I don't.
Speaker 1: what makes them any better than the thousands of other high school punk kids doing some other song?
Speaker 0: Yep, they're coin bird as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: Yep Now I'll warn you lobster magnet is funny.
Speaker 0: Be prepared to not be amazed by coin bird.
Speaker 0: In fact prepared to be underwhelmed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much it's all MS paint.
Speaker 1: so what do you want?
Speaker 0: it's real bad.
Speaker 1: it's real bad.
Speaker 1: Wow, if it's bad, should it really be a thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it teaches a valuable lesson.
Speaker 0: Don't Underwhelming this.
Speaker 0: it is underwhelming.
Speaker 1: No, you know, you see what it is.
Speaker 1: We prime them.
Speaker 1: See if you would have said lobster magnet was terrible They would have watched it and said yeah, that was terrible.
Speaker 1: Just like you said if you would have said coin bird was awesome They would have watched it and said it was awesome.
Speaker 1: Just like we said, you know what we could have done.
Speaker 0: I mean, we could have set up two identical episodes of geek nights Except we say the opposite thing for the things of the day.
Speaker 0: I could have done that.
Speaker 0: Then if we ran the DNS server instead of contracting it out We could have set up a round-robin thing where every other person who downloaded the show got a different one and then we could see What the effects were?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's too late to do that But how do we know which people watch which episode?
Speaker 0: because then we say hey guess what we did.
Speaker 0: now the after everyone gives their opinions And then we ask people to self-identify.
Speaker 0: very not scientific, but I trust our listeners.
Speaker 1: See we do control the DNS server to do a round-robin.
Speaker 1: Do you just type something in the DNS record?
Speaker 0: Sort of there you can.
Speaker 0: there are softwares you can use to make like specifically round-robin.
Speaker 1: like every x1s go to y But you can freely modify the DNS record.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could do a basic round-robin.
Speaker 0: It's not very predictable or Well, it's not very predictable, but it works pretty well.
Speaker 0: The problem is we don't really need it.
Speaker 0: All it does is load balance.
Speaker 0: Yep, I would want to do a strict 50/50 or something with this.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm In the spirit of slacking off all week, we don't have a particular main topic.
Speaker 1: Well, we could talk about new Mario Brothers, but I just unlocked level 7 today.
Speaker 1: I've already beaten the game and so is red.
Speaker 1: But I just unlocked level 7 today and I'm trying to collect all the big coins and I want to see just how much Replay value the game has before I give a final verdict with the geek nights episode.
Speaker 0: because for some reason I wonder if any Mario game can ever have the sheer replay value of Mario 3 Mario 3, which you suck at.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm not that good at if you know what.
Speaker 0: I still fucking love the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Mario world It comes real close to.
Speaker 0: yeah, it does for some reason.
Speaker 0: I think Mario 3 is a tiny bit more replay value.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just something about Mario 3 where the levels are hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah in Mario world You can learn how to unlock every level and just beat the hell out of everything with the capes and the Yoshi's.
Speaker 1: just kick its ass Mario 3 this stuff that's hard to get like stuff.
Speaker 1: You only get one shot at like Hammersuits and stuff and white mushroom houses.
Speaker 0: Yeah plus There are a limited number of resources in the game a limited number of one-ups and no way to save your game No way to turn around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not like Mario world.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: I need a mushroom.
Speaker 1: Let me go back back to top secret zone back to an easy level where they just mushrooms all over the place.
Speaker 0: You mean top secret zone the level you didn't know about?
Speaker 0: Yeah level that is nothing more than I didn't have a super Nintendo.
Speaker 1: That's why you suck at Mario 3.
Speaker 1: You're busy playing easy Mario world.
Speaker 0: I was too busy playing.
Speaker 0: fucking pilot wings.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bionic commando Yeah, Scott and I are good at different games, but the games were good at were frickin good at I mean Scott.
Speaker 0: You should see him.
Speaker 1: He could probably speedrun Megaman - probably I haven't played in a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can still do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway as you all know I was at an amazement over the weekend.
Speaker 0: amazing it was an amazing.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say that every day all week.
Speaker 1: That is so corny.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: it is Though I have a funny joke a funny thing about the name of the con From the musical that was put on at the con that I will say tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway I just want to do a little quick talk about the video gaming that was on and about and actually a little bit of Board-gaming.
Speaker 0: at an amazement because as I did with katsu khan it worked very well to split the video gaming off into a separate day.
Speaker 1: Hmm was there any DDR actions?
Speaker 0: actually there was.
Speaker 0: now it.
Speaker 0: what an amazement is pretty much the biggest I small con can be.
Speaker 0: so the video game room was not large, but it was well run and well stocked.
Speaker 0: They had the guitar heroes Which we actually had constant play for the entire thing.
Speaker 1: every convention this year is just all about guitar heroes because it's really fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you get that feeling you're playing it and you feel like you're playing the guitar even though you're really not.
Speaker 0: You're just playing just hitting colored buttons, but it's it's great.
Speaker 1: I mean everything from uber con to Otakon is gonna is rocking the guitar hero big-time.
Speaker 0: They had the DDR in the corner, which had a continuous line of play once again for the whole weekend though Surprising the machine or a pad a pad.
Speaker 0: actually very few cons have the machines anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Otakon has really never had the machines.
Speaker 0: Nope Anime central always did so you know.
Speaker 1: what the thing is is that when they do the pads they tend to use a projector and stuff and The machines the real machines actually seem to take up less physical space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 1: then the pads and all the ps2s and the wires and shit.
Speaker 1: So you know it's usually better to have the machines that also because they play better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they do, but then you don't have all the custom things.
Speaker 1: no or like the step mania craziness No, but you can set that.
Speaker 1: or there are some people who have to have real arcade cabinets with computers and step mania inside.
Speaker 0: true Those guys are awesome, but the nice thing about the video game room is one.
Speaker 0: there was really no Oda-funk no Otafunk It didn't really there was all.
Speaker 0: there was very little Bo and an amazement despite the fact that it was like a thousand degrees and humid outside.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: You know being in South Carolina your air-conditioned inside weren't you?
Speaker 0: the air conditioning could barely keep up.
Speaker 0: The dealer's room was the most air-conditioned as was one of the panel rooms But the rest of the con was actually kind of warm.
Speaker 1: It says the thing.
Speaker 1: Otacon has those super mega industrial air conditioners of doom which have their own drawbacks.
Speaker 0: They suck the moisture out of you, and then you die and they have water everywhere.
Speaker 1: But it's so hard to find water when you need it.
Speaker 0: There was so much water.
Speaker 0: in an amazement.
Speaker 0: They were on that the video.
Speaker 0: there were like 10 water kiosks within a two-minute walk of any point in the con.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: the video game room was fully stocked with all that and they really planned.
Speaker 0: Well, the video game room was right next to the con suite which had drinks and snacks.
Speaker 0: awesome.
Speaker 0: So the people who weren't into the anime thing or were bored we're just kind of hover back and forth between the two until like 3 in the morning mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: and They had like they had a lot of game cubes.
Speaker 0: a lot of you know PlayStation Xbox just the typical game room run out.
Speaker 0: they had a good crew running the game room and Everyone was really I guess polite as in more polite than I've ever seen in an anime con.
Speaker 1: And the game is really the game room is the area of.
Speaker 1: in politeness yeah, and elite gamer tudes.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's really weird, but people always talk about southern hospitality.
Speaker 0: It's kind of true.
Speaker 0: I mean there were some people who were you know fanboys, but they were real polite about it.
Speaker 1: How did you?
Speaker 1: what do you?
Speaker 0: Your show sucks, but don't worry I'll come up with an example tomorrow of a terrible fanboy.
Speaker 0: I ran into who despite all that was very polite about being a terrible fanboy.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry that they smell so poorly and have terrible taste, and I'm a pervert, but that's just the way it is.
Speaker 0: Um how come when you're trying to do a polite person you have this pseudo British kind of thing.
Speaker 1: I don't know I'm trying to be froofy.
Speaker 0: Why is that froofy?
Speaker 1: I don't know what are you thinking?
Speaker 1: cuz I'm not polite.
Speaker 1: so I got it.
Speaker 0: look at that Homer Simpson with his Lottie.
Speaker 1: cuz I don't care about politeness, so if I'm gonna pretend to be polite I gotta be someone else.
Speaker 0: so why British?
Speaker 1: Is it sound British?
Speaker 0: I was just trying to be froofy boy.
Speaker 0: Okay right yeah, it's silliness now.
Speaker 0: the gaming room was really great and everyone's really polite.
Speaker 0: I ran into this guy.
Speaker 0: I didn't catch his name.
Speaker 0: He was apparently the Mac master of Marvel vs.
Speaker 0: Capcom and like no one could be Morris kept come one or two.
Speaker 0: I don't know Whatever.
Speaker 0: I didn't get to go in.
Speaker 0: I was actually guarding the door at the late at night Covering for someone who had to go do something for a while.
Speaker 0: You know security yep, and He retalked for a while.
Speaker 0: He was a really cool guy And he wanted to take me because I didn't believe him.
Speaker 0: like I'm not.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually not believe him But I was kind of a. you're really that good.
Speaker 0: He's like come on I'll show you I couldn't move, but was he like the world champion or something?
Speaker 0: I don't know, but apparently cuz I ran into some other people who pointed him out as being really really good.
Speaker 1: It could have been just the local awesome guy or the most awesome guy in the state or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could have been but he was good, and he was cool.
Speaker 0: Basically everyone I met in that room was cool, and I interviewed a lot of people over there.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm almost no funk.
Speaker 0: Though the one odd thing was there weren't many DS's or PSP's at the con.
Speaker 0: I mean most of the cons we go to.
Speaker 0: you'll see like crowds of DS players everywhere.
Speaker 0: yep at this con I ran into two people who had PSP's and They were talking to each other.
Speaker 0: actually I think they were either friends or brother and sister or something I really couldn't tell.
Speaker 0: I didn't have a chance to interview him, but they weren't really playing it out.
Speaker 0: They just kind of had it with them, and it was also their mp3 player.
Speaker 0: I ran into a bunch of people playing DS games, so I tried to play with them a little bit But they were all kind of busy and distracted And I was kind of tired that didn't really pan out And I was worried that there wasn't.
Speaker 0: there wasn't so much DS action at this con that maybe if you move away from the Northeast The DS kind of falls out of favor.
Speaker 0: then standing in line Watching over the cosplay crowd waiting for everyone to get in I start hearing people yelling things things like oh my god the bomb.
Speaker 0: oh my god dangerous bomb bomb kick and I realized that there were about seven people scattered all over the line playing Bomberman and yelling and screaming Oh, yeah And they wouldn't give the game up.
Speaker 0: the line started moving in and they're all like holding their DS's up trying to keep the signal Going and they kept playing as the line walked into the building.
Speaker 0: awesome Eventually the last guy like at the end of the line stopped and bent down like he was gonna tie his shoe And then all of a sudden I heard all the rest of the guys from inside yell It was over.
Speaker 1: It's actually funny cuz today.
Speaker 1: I was you know the one random day.
Speaker 1: I look at the game facts poll It.
Speaker 1: the poll is which system Do you plan to buy your next video game for which I thought is a pretty interesting question to ask.
Speaker 1: Number one was the ps2 with 28 29%.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna round off to the nearest 1%.
Speaker 1: Okay The DS was in second place with 20%.
Speaker 1: the Xbox 360 was in third place with 15%.
Speaker 1: in fourth place the GameCube 9%.
Speaker 1: you thought we were gonna say the PSP, but now the PC comes in next with 11% Then comes in other with 8% Then the PSP with 5% Wow.
Speaker 1: and then the Xbox one with 4%.
Speaker 1: so the DS 20% of gamers plan to buy their next game for the DS.
Speaker 1: 5% plan to buy their next game for the PSP.
Speaker 1: 4 to 1 people.
Speaker 1: and that's I rounded the PSP up and I rounded the DS down.
Speaker 1: the actual numbers are DS PSP 4.63%.
Speaker 1: so for every Four DS is out there or for every four people who are planning to buy a game for the DS real soon There is less than one person Planning to buy their next game for the PSP.
Speaker 0: now some people have pointed out that we seem to be very down on the PSP Pretty much any time it comes up.
Speaker 1: numbers people now.
Speaker 1: We're skeptics here.
Speaker 1: We go by the evidence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but just we're not saying it's a bad system.
Speaker 0: It's an awesome system.
Speaker 0: the same way the Game Gear was an awesome system and once again I still own my Game Gear and I wish it had been successful, but I knew it wouldn't be and it wasn't.
Speaker 0: But it still had some good games.
Speaker 0: I'm still glad I owned it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems the PSP is gonna even have less good games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those Megaman games.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to play.
Speaker 1: I know this is in the store a couple times But that's about it.
Speaker 0: Though actually I note how the ps2 is doing so well I wouldn't be surprised if the ps2 continued to outsell the ps3 for a time after the ps3 comes out.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the ps1 outsold the ps2 for a time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know because the backwards compatibility people don't mind continuing on with the system They've got knowing that eventually they'll buy the new system and they'll be alright.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I have actually no more real gaming coverage of an amazement other than that I ran into a small group of people playing a German board game that they had bought at the dealers room at anime.
Speaker 0: What game was it some game?
Speaker 0: I never heard of and I actually didn't catch the name of it.
Speaker 1: Oh, hopefully you.
Speaker 1: so there was a guy selling German board games at an amazement.
Speaker 0: Yes, there was.
Speaker 0: well He was a gamer story was selling all sorts of game repair of an alien dice.
Speaker 0: He was.
Speaker 0: the thing is he wasn't selling.
Speaker 0: he wasn't a I don't know high quality German dealer.
Speaker 0: He's.
Speaker 0: he had mostly like the munchkin things the Steve Jackson things.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's the most of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the super popular American or euro games.
Speaker 1: the only way you can make money in that kind of business is to really sell the popular stuff big Time and the other stuff, you know You buy exactly as many as you're gonna sell
Speaker 0: or be millennium games in Rochester and have everything because you know, it'll all sell Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh I when I was at the Dragon's Den this weekend playing games Yeah the guy was like Apparently dragons that had gotten in a few copies of Kayla's and they sold out and they want it You know, the guy was like when are you gonna get more?
Speaker 1: and the owner guy was like, yeah I just can't get him.
Speaker 1: You know the distributor is sold out and I'm like You should call this guy Ed and millennium games and ask him where he gets his board games from.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz he's got like 10 copies of the damn thing.
Speaker 1: So he went to the.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh and I spell the name weird It's like two ends.
Speaker 1: So the guy goes over to the computer and he finds the website and he's like 54 gaming tables.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and I'm like, yeah
Speaker 0: Yeah wrong
Speaker 1: with you mr Paintball cuz
Speaker 0: we we've we've always talked about it in front of this guy and with this guy and with all these Ma's guys that Our gaming store back in Rochester is probably one of the best gaming stores in the country
Speaker 1: As far as I'm concerned the best gaming store in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've ever seen not counting Germany.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as far as I can tell I haven't been to that complete strategist in the city.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should maybe when we go to that pillows concert or something.
Speaker 1: That'd be cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, but yeah the get.
Speaker 0: the reason I don't remember the name of the game is that it didn't look very good.
Speaker 0: it just looked very big and complicated and weird and I tried to talk to the guys a little bit, but they were really kind.
Speaker 0: I mean if you guys are listening I'm sorry But you were really kind of unfriendly and you didn't seem to want anyone to ask What you were doing or pay any attention to the game you were trying.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, then they're not German board gamers your German real German board gamers.
Speaker 1: They're like, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, check this shit out And they're talking all in funny accents and stuff, yep, but the thing the other thing was they had never heard of any game.
Speaker 0: I tried to ask him about, you know Tigers, New Freighties, Puerto Rico settlers never heard of any of those, huh?
Speaker 0: So, I don't know what they're German gamers.
Speaker 1: They were just some guys who bought some thing that they thought looked cool and we're trying to play it.
Speaker 1: That's probably why it's a game.
Speaker 1: You never heard of because they probably just bought it based on its looks or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, I wish they'd been friendly.
Speaker 0: I wanted to interview him, but they really didn't seem to want to talk to anyone at the con Assets.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So since rim talked about something I got one more tiny bit One more time a little bit.
Speaker 0: This is a our friend Nury who does artist Ally a podcast.
Speaker 0: She's appeared on the show.
Speaker 0: I believe once she will be appearing on it at some point in the future for another interesting episode.
Speaker 0: But she had an idea a long time ago.
Speaker 0: And when she told me this idea I said that's gold.
Speaker 0: That is solid gold.
Speaker 0: She started making die earring dice an earring that is a like a d8 or a d20 and They look really good like just you know, drill a hole in dice and do all the stuff to it.
Speaker 1: You put a hook into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you put a hook with the chain and another hook.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that but she does it really well.
Speaker 0: She knows what she's doing.
Speaker 0: They look for.
Speaker 0: they came out really well at the con.
Speaker 0: She'd made a few and was selling them.
Speaker 0: the demand was insane Not the you should see.
Speaker 1: how many do you make a website?
Speaker 0: I think that might be in the on the docket.
Speaker 1: now make a website with a little credit card thing and it made me very Happy.
Speaker 0: the amount of geekery.
Speaker 0: just that how many people would walk up to the table see these dyes and go.
Speaker 0: Oh my god That's awesome.
Speaker 0: I have to buy them for my significant other.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Do you have a d8?
Speaker 0: Do you have a d12?
Speaker 0: I want I need a d12.
Speaker 0: It has to be blue.
Speaker 1: I need a blue d12 for my blue.
Speaker 0: barbarian people were like if I give you some of my dice Will you turn them into earrings for me?
Speaker 0: Yeah So I thought that was very cool that there was that much geekery going on at the con.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's that's the level of geekery I come to expect and of course my full coverage of an amazement will be tomorrow on anime day.
Speaker 0: I only say this because we seem to have picked up quite a few new listeners from an amazement.
Speaker 0: All right, and if you're waiting for it, it hasn't happened yet.
Speaker 1: so Since rim talked the first half of the main bit I'm gonna get the second half all to me.
Speaker 1: Well rim will right chime in a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: Baba we baba we baba we okay, so we have a friend who plays this game called planets.
Speaker 0: I yeah our friend Adam aka art boy, you know him in the forums.
Speaker 0: He's really cool guy.
Speaker 1: Yep, so If you don't know planet side is it's.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's officially the first and only but it's pretty much the main MMO.
Speaker 1: that's also an FPS.
Speaker 1: so it's you know, you run around shooting, but there's a whole bunch of people everywhere.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of thing I dreamt about When I was a kid like I dreamed of the day when something like this in theory You know looking at it from that standpoint an MMO FPS could be awesome.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I was always skeptical.
Speaker 1: I never liked it.
Speaker 1: I really really there's no MMOs that are good It's far.
Speaker 0: if you ask me, yeah, I mean puzzle pyre which is probably the best.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Kingdom of Loathing was barely M barely.
Speaker 1: So He probably tells us the last time he was hanging out that you know planet side is free and I'm like, oh really well Me not being a shit talker.
Speaker 1: I guess isn't really shit talking.
Speaker 1: But you know, I don't knock it.
Speaker 1: before I tried it Let me tell you I could say that.
Speaker 1: so I went and tried it.
Speaker 1: now I'm gonna say some pretty negative things.
Speaker 1: So Adam before you Come and tell me how I'm wrong and stupid.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you I gave this game more chances than it deserved.
Speaker 1: I played it on two separate days for hours and hours each day.
Speaker 0: I can verify this because I heard him in his room.
Speaker 0: This is what I'd hear I'd hear click click click click click.
Speaker 0: What the fuck.
Speaker 0: click click click click click.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is just bullshit.
Speaker 0: Rim you got to see this crap.
Speaker 0: click click click click click click click click.
Speaker 1: God, it won't even work All right.
Speaker 1: So I made a list of every time I went like that now normally under normal circumstances The first time the game pissed me off.
Speaker 1: I would have uninstalled it and that would have been the end.
Speaker 1: Because you know, I wanted to give it a fair chance before I'm burping all over the place.
Speaker 0: I'm not editing that out.
Speaker 1: Okay Before I wanted to give it a fair chance before I talked about it, so I sat through all this pain and suffering before compiling my final list of grievances and why I think planetside is Terrible and shouldn't be played by anyone and no one should pay money for it ever.
Speaker 0: Now I will qualify his stuff by saying that I think the reason that art boys Experienced with this game are so much better at least in his eyes are mainly that he plays with a bunch of people He knows and almost anything is fun.
Speaker 1: If you play it with a bunch of people, you know, yeah, you know It's a mob mentality, you know, you do something.
Speaker 1: I mean, let's say I'm jumping up and down It's not cool.
Speaker 1: But if all of a sudden 50 people are jumping up and down with me and we all tell each other jumping up and down Is awesome jumping up and down is awesome.
Speaker 1: That's the whole point of guilds in World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: It's not any different than playing World of Warcraft on your own.
Speaker 1: All you do is click on the monster until it dies.
Speaker 1: click on the monster until it died.
Speaker 0: Now you've got someone else also clicking on the monster or clicking on.
Speaker 1: you both look at each other and say this is awesome Isn't it?
Speaker 1: and you both you tell each other that it's great and it becomes great.
Speaker 1: It's a psychology thing.
Speaker 0: Nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 1: Nope, as long as you recognize You know, we do it all the time to look at us right here.
Speaker 1: Just telling each other everything we do is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, we're so awesome.
Speaker 1: We just can't podcast isn't making a geek podcast.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: It's freaking fantastic Alright, so here's the I'm gonna this.
Speaker 1: I just kind of scrawled every time something pissed me off enough to pick up the pen And stop looking at the game.
Speaker 1: So let's see.
Speaker 1: First of all the load times.
Speaker 1: now I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be apologetic for every one of these just to be you know, I guess less than super.
Speaker 0: this sucks But it seems to suck.
Speaker 1: it does so.
Speaker 1: The load times.
Speaker 1: it might just be my shitty computer But my computer isn't that shitty my computer it plays half-life 2 like a dream.
Speaker 0: your computer remember Planet-side is kind of old.
Speaker 1: It is kind of old.
Speaker 0: your computer is more powerful than anything that existed when planet-side appeared.
Speaker 1: Yep Now I don't care about graphics and games.
Speaker 1: as far as I'm concerned as long as the graphics don't interfere with the gameplay They're all good.
Speaker 1: but Planet-side has shittier graphics than half-life 2 shittier physics than half-life 2. hell.
Speaker 1: it has shittier physics and graphics than tribes 2 Or maybe equal and the load times were preposterous Absolutely insane, I mean half-life 2 has a bit of a load time on my computer this.
Speaker 1: the load times are double if not more.
Speaker 1: Now the worst part of the load times.
Speaker 1: cuz I you know, I sat through it.
Speaker 1: There was no cancel button.
Speaker 1: So as soon as I started loading I was stuck until it finished loading.
Speaker 0: Granted the quake 2 and the first half-life had a little bit of problem with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where if you started to do something you were basically stuck until it finished before you go again.
Speaker 1: But you think this is an MMO that's constantly patched and updated.
Speaker 1: someone would have complained about the incredible load times and why there's no cancel button and they would have put a cancel button in by.
Speaker 1: Now after years and years of this game being out and there's no cancel button if you if you start loading something.
Speaker 1: So that's the first time is any time I did anything.
Speaker 1: the load was insane and it wasn't worth waiting.
Speaker 1: through number two When you join the game, it gives you a choice of teams and there's three teams.
Speaker 1: You can join at least three teams that I saw.
Speaker 1: the team that needs players.
Speaker 1: you get an XP bonus if you join that team.
Speaker 1: I guess that's a good incentive for getting people to join the team with the least players.
Speaker 1: But doesn't that kind of give sort of an unfair advantage to one of the teams?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Well, that team's probably already down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Don't know.
Speaker 1: You know it did.
Speaker 1: it seemed like an okay thing.
Speaker 1: It's not really a plus or a minus.
Speaker 1: it is kind of there and I don't you know.
Speaker 1: I'm just kind of skeptical of it a little bit, you know, I need to see more.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's see.
Speaker 1: Okay the training portion of the game.
Speaker 1: So you join the game and it does this awesome training thing.
Speaker 1: The training is an awesome thing on the left side on the right side of the screen I think it says do this do that.
Speaker 1: and it even tells you what buttons to push and everything.
Speaker 1: and As you do those things it puts a green checkbox and then tells you to do the next thing.
Speaker 1: it was perfect.
Speaker 1: It taught me a whole bunch of stuff about the game.
Speaker 1: The problem is after about Oh five different things that I did it Said okay do instant action.
Speaker 1: now instant action is this thing where you say instant action.
Speaker 1: and because it's a giant giant world With not so many players covering the entire world.
Speaker 1: There isn't fighting going on everywhere.
Speaker 1: In fact, if you go to certain places you can just walk around in this monotonous wilderness forever and ever and ever and never meet anyone Unless you try to mess something up like a base.
Speaker 1: then they'll come after you.
Speaker 1: but you know most of the time you'll just.
Speaker 1: you Know you just walk around the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 1: So the fighting is going on only in a few places around the world and certain continents and things.
Speaker 1: So instant action immediately teleports you well Not immediately.
Speaker 1: you push instant action then you can't touch anything for like five seconds And if you manage to successfully do that, it'll teleport you somewhere with a long loading time Of course where there is fighting going on.
Speaker 1: The tutorial told me to click instant action.
Speaker 1: So I did.
Speaker 1: it sent me somewhere.
Speaker 1: I came out of a spawn point.
Speaker 1: It was immediately killed.
Speaker 1: The tutorial was thus over and I didn't learn anything else about the game.
Speaker 1: I don't think it was going to teach me anything else about the game anyway And I barely learned shit.
Speaker 1: Like I knew how to walk and shoot.
Speaker 1: if I didn't know how to play an FPS already I would have been dead in the water.
Speaker 1: you know It was like the greatest tutorial software and system in the universe that stopped teaching you after.
Speaker 1: it taught you less than the basics.
Speaker 1: Okay, let's see what else we got here.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Their ads in this game.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's because I don't pay for it and there weren't ads all over the game But in the bases were ads for castrol motor oil.
Speaker 1: Wow Yeah, I don't think that needs anything else to be said about.
Speaker 0: Wow is?
Speaker 1: it seems that I?
Speaker 1: there are a lot of Systems in the game that just aren't explained to you and I wasn't about to read all the giant Documentation to play an FPS.
Speaker 1: I figured out everything there is possibly is in half-life 2 and tribes 2 without reading any documentation whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So why should this FPS be any more complicated?
Speaker 1: Apparently when you jump there's this little meter that goes down and then slowly rebuilds I guess to limit your jumping.
Speaker 1: and when you jump your guy grunts like he's in pain yeah, and you can hurt yourself by jumping it seems.
Speaker 1: and nowhere in the Guides or any, you know tutorial stuff that I read.
Speaker 1: Did it really explain what this was?
Speaker 1: I would have had to look up exactly how this little I guess energy meter worked and Exactly what used it and all that shit.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't mind it being there and you know I don't know the game mechanics of it because it didn't tell me it's just there.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of stuff on the screen.
Speaker 1: It's just there and it's never explained.
Speaker 1: and you have to read complicated documentation in a complicated format to figure it out.
Speaker 1: and for an FPS Hell no, I'm not reading that shit.
Speaker 1: Maybe for a civilization, you know type game or an RTS.
Speaker 1: I'll read stuff not for an FPS and an FPS I walk and shoot.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even for a game like civilization I mean The only things I read were as I played the game I'd read the text around things and figure out what was going on.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I would never read something before I played this game provided some help text For certain things.
Speaker 1: like you'd walk up to something for the first time and it would say this is this you use it this way, you know and that was kind of helpful, but It's like if I never came across something I would never know what it was or how to use it.
Speaker 1: And there's this VR room where you can go and try out all the weapons and vehicles in the game.
Speaker 1: Oh the vehicles.
Speaker 1: I Don't know if there maybe isn't a button to do it.
Speaker 1: But when you're driving a vehicle, you can't look around.
Speaker 1: So all you can see is straightforward where you're driving Which I thought was very very annoying Because I like to look behind me and to the left is the right to make sure no one's sneaking up on me To you know blow my vehicle up.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a button that does that but I don't know.
Speaker 1: it didn't tell me.
Speaker 1: now Let's see.
Speaker 1: What else is terrible?
Speaker 1: Okay here.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna cut it short and just stick with the major complaints.
Speaker 1: Running really sucks.
Speaker 1: How do you run an FPS rim?
Speaker 0: I hold down my fire button and I'm automatically running.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now how do you walk slowly?
Speaker 1: I hold down shift and then you also go forward right?
Speaker 1: Yeah in this game It doesn't work like that.
Speaker 1: Okay, if you hold down forward you walk.
Speaker 1: All right, if you let go forward you don't walk.
Speaker 1: All right There's a button that you push that enables running.
Speaker 1: you push it and your gut just once it's sort of like caps lock.
Speaker 1: you push it and your guy starts running and You push it again and he stops running.
Speaker 1: All right, it's not too bad Yeah, but it was really annoying.
Speaker 0: I guess it's more like is the game set up so that running is a means of transport?
Speaker 0: But it's not.
Speaker 0: you don't use that when you're fighting.
Speaker 1: I Really don't know because whenever I got into a fight and there were a lot of guys in the screen the game was incredibly laggy and bleh and I couldn't really aim it.
Speaker 1: guys.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, and I don't know, you know people have said about this game, you know, oh, it doesn't matter what level you are You just have the right equipment to counter your enemy.
Speaker 1: Well, I Was a brand new guy and I got a bunch of levels by doing the VR and I had a whole bunch of equipment at my disposal and I tried all sorts of different loadouts and No matter what I chose Everyone seemed to do a billion damage to me and I couldn't really damage anyone worth a shit.
Speaker 1: So I'm beginning to think that level and all that stuff has a lot more to do with it than you would think.
Speaker 1: Maybe you haven't been a noob in a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or maybe you know, you can deal with the lag that happens whenever you're near anyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean seriously half-life was the end of lag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the time in which they realized they could have netcode that fixed lives to worked perfectly on a 56k modem.
Speaker 1: I shit you not.
Speaker 1: Therefore this game on my cable modem should have been slick as hell.
Speaker 1: I had pings to the server of less than 30.
Speaker 1: Fuck you if there's lag there should never be lag.
Speaker 1: if there's lag something's wrong.
Speaker 1: Now and it's not me either.
Speaker 1: my ping was 30.
Speaker 1: It was sudden with the server and my remember my computer plays half-life 2. just fine.
Speaker 1: My computer isn't slow.
Speaker 1: Hmm all right the full scan You install.
Speaker 1: I installed the game and the way the game installs.
Speaker 1: This is incredibly long download of gigs and gigs and gigs of data.
Speaker 1: That's understandable because it's a big game and I'm downloading the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Okay The second time I played the game.
Speaker 1: It did a full scan that I could not cancel or skip where it went and rescanned Every single file in the entire game.
Speaker 1: It took like 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: I guess it was making sure I wasn't cheating or making sure the files weren't broken.
Speaker 1: I Don't know what it was doing, but it basically made me wait forever before I even started the game.
Speaker 1: So I didn't even encounter the first incredibly long load time and I was already waiting Like 10 minutes just to start the damn game.
Speaker 0: Well, you're a very patient man.
Speaker 0: That would have been enough for me to quit.
Speaker 1: Yep, I would have told you I gave this game a chance.
Speaker 1: I gave it a serious chance.
Speaker 1: a friend says try this game.
Speaker 1: It's free and I like it a lot.
Speaker 1: I fucking tried it and it sucks ass.
Speaker 1: No one should pay for planet side.
Speaker 1: It's terrible terrible terrible bad bad old game.
Speaker 0: I don't know why it's still alive Now if you make We're talking specifically to you Adam or anyone else out there who listens as a fan of planet side and audio rebuttal will play it.
Speaker 0: Yep, we want to hear an argument.
Speaker 0: We want you to defend your game.
Speaker 1: Yeah Kotaku had that great thing after III at e3 where they went around to the game developers and said justify your game.
Speaker 1: So yeah justify this game.
Speaker 1: as far as I'm concerned as an FPS It's mediocre as an MMO.
Speaker 1: It's nothing as a game Technologically speaking.
Speaker 1: It's terrible.
Speaker 0: It sounds like I would rather play World of Warcraft than that.
Speaker 1: I probably would rather play World of Warcraft cuz at least World of Warcraft works Works really well on many platforms.
Speaker 0: Well to plan max.
Speaker 1: Yeah The other thing the combat in this game was even were I prefer the halo combat to this I mean you really didn't.
Speaker 1: you couldn't jump or duck duck.
Speaker 1: It didn't really help strategically like in a counter-strike way, but you couldn't move fast and do awesome moves in a quake sort of way.
Speaker 1: it was just walk around and Find the bad guys and click at them in a slow and boring sort of way like less than what Wolfenstein 3d only slower Wow, you just.
Speaker 1: what all you could really do was pick the right weapon choose the right ammunition for the weapon Walk around find the bad guys point and shoot at them.
Speaker 1: The only strategy seemed to be on a more than one person level as in Get a bunch of people to all do it together And that's the strategy.
Speaker 1: is you know get a bunch of people to choose the right weapon and then hold the button down Aiming in the same general which I mean, I guess it's cool because that's the point, you know squad combat and all that.
Speaker 0: But it makes it so that The game is just units like large units of people moving around and the only people who really have a fun game now are the Commanders who tell people where to go.
Speaker 0: they're the ones playing the strategy game.
Speaker 0: if you're not doing that you're just no FPS skill Involved.
Speaker 1: imagine if it was FPS skill.
Speaker 1: then three awesome dudes with you know pistols.
Speaker 1: could you know?
Speaker 1: Take out some crazy awesome guys like in tribes.
Speaker 0: This completely eliminates that possibility.
Speaker 0: Scott and I could freaking like the two of us alone capture a flag if the other team wasn't so great or Depending on the server where you know, he'd.
Speaker 0: he'd bombed the generators with his satchel charge.
Speaker 0: I'd fly over and like grab the flag and then I was a heavy.
Speaker 0: then I toss it to him he'd get on a speeder Bike and speed away and I'd sit there mortaring everyone.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There really is no as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 1: There is no FPS skill.
Speaker 1: There's no room for any FPS skill whatsoever in planetside.
Speaker 1: The only things that make a difference in this game are number of people on your side in proximity to you.
Speaker 1: There's selection of weapons and the selection and what weapons you've selected and how many you have available to you and what vehicles you brought With you and what bases are nearby?
Speaker 1: You know and all that sort of shit, which is really good if you suck at FPS is like FPS.
Speaker 1: This is awesome for you.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is really good game for Luke.
Speaker 0: He really liked being the commander in a natural selection Yeah, but it doesn't seem like there's a commanding interface.
Speaker 1: the only type of commanding you can do is call your friends and say hey get on service just talk to people.
Speaker 1: and The other thing is this game.
Speaker 1: the one thing that bothered me the most actually is in the game.
Speaker 1: Every game has lingo, you know, like if I come up to you and say they nerf something, you know You don't know what that is.
Speaker 1: Unless you're a gamer, you know in the world of Warcraft is all kinds of you know Go that means resurrecting.
Speaker 0: got a hearth gank 45 l whatever bullshit.
Speaker 1: This game had a lingo But it seemed that the documentation for the game used the lingo and the game itself used the lingo as well as all the players And nowhere did it.
Speaker 1: the lingo didn't make sense and no one taught it to you and the game.
Speaker 1: The documentation talked to you in lingo of the game before teaching it to you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now compare that to natural selection where the lingo was one it did like incredibly obvious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone would say alright guys heavy train and you.
Speaker 0: and if anyone thought what does that mean?
Speaker 0: Suddenly a bunch of heavy armor starts appearing and everyone forms a massive line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there would basically be messages constantly popping up saying go to the weird name bla bla bla bla bla.
Speaker 1: and And I tried to do some stuff that people told me to do.
Speaker 1: like occasionally people try to help me and they say go to Res.
Speaker 1: how would?
Speaker 1: and I'd be like where people look on your map and I'd look on my map and I'd say, okay I see it on my map.
Speaker 1: Where am I on the map?
Speaker 1: Cuz I couldn't find the thing that said you are here.
Speaker 1: They're like, you're the arrow.
Speaker 1: I'm like, there are three arrows on this map And then they'd be like go to where the number three is.
Speaker 1: I'm like this two or three number threes Which one the big one?
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm gonna try, you know, yeah And then it just I'll compare that to natural selection where you say go to reactor core.
Speaker 0: You look on your map and you see reactor core.
Speaker 1: you see Hovering holographic reactor core in the direction of the reactor and you see a picture of you with a little thing that looks just like Your radar, you know, the interface of this game was pretty much bad overall.
Speaker 1: the way, you know You close a window and then it's almost impossible to figure out how to open that exact window again.
Speaker 1: and the way the because the heads of display is a bunch of little tiny windows and they all work in a non intuitive way and And the controls can't be customized the way I want.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm glad my video card died.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I would have been playing this game with you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Recently the new PC game I'm giving a chance is the bang howdy Which is the new game from the puzzle pirates guys.
Speaker 0: It looks kind of cool.
Speaker 1: It looks kind of cool, but I played it today and the beta and I was a little bit disappointed.
Speaker 1: So I'll get back to that in some other day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, give us a couple weeks Yep, and on that note we went long today Which is fine because you all keep demanding longer and longer episodes.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: So do you want to go watch that movie or in good bed?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Let me do the post-production and then see.
Speaker 0: just before this we almost made our thing of the day this kill bill thing But it reminded us how awesome kill bill is and we kind of want to watch the movie again.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep Yep, so without further ado once again tomorrow will be our coverage of an amazement.
Speaker 0: Thursday will be our coverage of how the airline industry is poop and that should make up for the all Scott day last week.
Speaker 1: It'll be a whole lot of rim days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, my day is tomorrow.
Speaker 0: tomorrow is going to be the day of Scott not having much to say.
Speaker 0: hooray other than it easy He I get reaction shots from him like oh Why did someone dress up like that?
Speaker 0: You know, yep though I will say one final little tidbit for anyone still listening the best cosplay at An amazement.
Speaker 0: by far was this group of guys who dressed up as FARC calm and I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 1: Oh really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, really And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 1537.
Speaker 0: geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.