Speaker 0: It's Thursday June 15th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We discuss ultraviolet movies, and why we love them.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: Hooray, I don't work.
Speaker 1: tomorrow's gonna be bland.
Speaker 1: then it's a weekend.
Speaker 0: yep I'll probably skip out of work early and get home and relax a little bit.
Speaker 1: I'll probably go to work late.
Speaker 1: Maybe not even go.
Speaker 1: I'll probably go come home early.
Speaker 1: then.
Speaker 1: Saturday is anime next.
Speaker 0: yep Anime next and our friend Katsu is coming out Friday night for anime next.
Speaker 1: hooray.
Speaker 0: It looks like Sunday.
Speaker 0: Nothing's going on probably for the first time ever.
Speaker 1: So what are we gonna do on a day where nothing's going on?
Speaker 0: I am gonna dick around in the house catch up on a month's worth of stuff I've been neglecting do a bunch of paperwork and take a nap.
Speaker 1: Probably gonna be do some sleeping.
Speaker 1: I'll probably do some Reading a lot of reading all those books I got over there not getting read.
Speaker 1: Maybe some video game that didn't get beat.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Not time to rearrange the furniture in my room yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you haven't even ordered your bookcase.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm gonna order.
Speaker 1: I think I'm gonna go down there and whatever.
Speaker 1: next time I go that way and get one you never go that way We'll come back from that way on Saturday at like midnight.
Speaker 0: No no no like on the 4th of July when we come back We're not gonna leave the shore over the 4th of July weekend at any reasonable hour.
Speaker 0: You know that I think we will plus Scott would be leaving on the 4th.
Speaker 0: There's no way the IKEA is open on the 4th of July.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 0: You didn't really think this through.
Speaker 1: I could just go down there when we have a free weekend or something.
Speaker 0: Haha free weekend.
Speaker 1: I could go down there Sunday.
Speaker 1: It takes an hour to get there.
Speaker 1: I'll just go get it come back go nuts I might even though I would have driven to anime next the day before and won't be in the mood for driving.
Speaker 1: Let's wait till another weekend with a free day.
Speaker 0: Oh Well, anyway, we got some news now everyone.
Speaker 0: This was huge news apparently and it was on far cuz a news flash and everyone's talking about it But it's not really a big deal.
Speaker 0: now Bill Gates has announced that he is Mostly done with Microsoft in that he's going to step down for many of his duties by next year or two years from now.
Speaker 1: He stepped down for most of his duties a few years ago when he stopped being CEO and he's now only chairman of the board You know, so now he's just getting rid of even more duties.
Speaker 0: now the thing is Bill Gates has not had a lot of Really much of anything to do with what Microsoft does day to day for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Steve Ballmer.
Speaker 1: and who's that other guy?
Speaker 1: Ray Ozzie Ray Ozzie and the other guy?
Speaker 1: everyone forgets his name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I forget his name and Ray Paul Allen.
Speaker 1: He hasn't had anything.
Speaker 1: that he left Microsoft a long time ago with his mad moneys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's the secret guy with all the moneys who ran away.
Speaker 0: So I just the news is making such a big deal out of this and it really isn't.
Speaker 0: it's not like suddenly Microsoft is gonna become a good company or a more evil company or Vista's not gonna suck or anything's gonna change.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Bill Gates really hasn't done anything in a long time at least nothing significant or really hands-on and He's not going to.
Speaker 1: he's gonna do even less.
Speaker 0: even back in the day He didn't really do so much technologically.
Speaker 0: It was more that he was very savvy on the business side.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even in the earliest days and Microsoft was in a quote garage All he did was steal stuff from other people.
Speaker 1: He didn't actually do much.
Speaker 0: He could do things.
Speaker 0: He was very smart Yeah, but he realized that that was That wasn't.
Speaker 0: he realized that wasn't what he needed to do to get ahead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other thing about Bill Gates is that from what he said a bunch of times is that?
Speaker 1: He has more money.
Speaker 1: He knows what to do with obviously and he you know, he wants to give it all away.
Speaker 1: but his problem is that It's not easy to give it away.
Speaker 1: Cuz what if you give it away to someone who does something bad with it?
Speaker 0: So there's an easy answer to that Give it to me exactly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Bill Gates if you listen to geek nights, uh, we could use some cash.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we sure could Just made my student loan go away.
Speaker 1: Just like 50 G's.
Speaker 1: with 50 G's my car loan of my student loan would be gone.
Speaker 0: I would be set hell if someone gave me 10 grand.
Speaker 0: I could be I could make myself filthy rich with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I need 50 because 40 makes the debt go away.
Speaker 0: I would make the debt go away.
Speaker 0: I'd use that 10 grand to make more money.
Speaker 1: Now I would just do the 40 to make the debt go away and then the last 10 to make more money.
Speaker 0: You're actually having 10 grand in cash is much more valuable than having 10 grand less of debt.
Speaker 0: No, I'm saying if I had 50 grand if I had zero debt and 10 grand actually That's a stupid investment because the the student loans you have and all the debt you have the interest on them is there.
Speaker 0: But it's not so bad.
Speaker 0: But having that much capital together is worth so much more money as an opportunity cost.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it depends what I'm gonna do with it.
Speaker 1: Probably what I'm gonna do is make some softwares and use the money to live while I make the software.
Speaker 1: Wow, I would just invest in real estate and such No stocks if I was gonna invest in real estate.
Speaker 1: I don't want like a million dollars so I could buy a whole bunch of houses.
Speaker 0: Well now use the 50 grand as cash or down payment or you use that to help finance a loan.
Speaker 1: But then I need to keep my job.
Speaker 0: No, not really.
Speaker 0: You can also live off of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah You just have to work on the other stuff full-time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't wanna.
Speaker 1: the idea is to just be able to work on my own thing and live whatever.
Speaker 1: so Netscape You know the browser that no one uses anymore.
Speaker 1: At least no one should be using anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah Netscape was good back when ie was version 2 and 3 and 3 as soon as ie 4 came out.
Speaker 1: That was the end of Netscape not just business wise there's a whole big story on the business end We won't get into.
Speaker 1: but software wise Netscape was dead as well.
Speaker 1: Since then Netscape has pretty much been Mozilla Reskinned to be Netscape.
Speaker 1: So nowadays, of course Netscape isn't Mozilla with a bunch of skins.
Speaker 1: It's Firefox with a bunch of skins.
Speaker 1: If you download the Netscape browser It's the same thing as Firefox only with a bunch of extensions and skins and all kinds of stuff to make it all Netscape.
Speaker 1: Aole.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, AOL owns Netscape now and Back in the day They tried to take Netscape calm since it used to be just a website for the browser and turn it into a quote Portal to compete with the likes of Yahoo.
Speaker 1: and who else is a portal back in the day?
Speaker 0: You know, I don't remember I didn't really go to.
Speaker 1: like goes like goes Like goes is dead, isn't it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I assume it is all those old-school sites that punk kids don't remember because they didn't use the internet in the 90s and even Back then the people who use the portals were usually not the most savvy people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the savvy people use the Alta vistas in the web crawler Yeah, or they just knew URL that's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah web crawler wasn't that good, but had a cute spider anyway.
Speaker 1: So a well just redid Netscape calm recently possibly even today and the redo of Netscape Calm is basically just a dig clone.
Speaker 1: That's what they did.
Speaker 1: is they took Netscape calm and they put a clone of dig on it Except of course without the democracy and the freedom and the awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, there's.
Speaker 1: there's obviously some stuff going on behind the scenes, you know changing votes or maybe it's just shitty software running the site.
Speaker 1: But all it does shitty software from AOL Do you think?
Speaker 1: That's a surprise.
Speaker 1: No, so The story is that the way their thing works.
Speaker 1: and dig you just submit stories And then if stories get enough digs they go on to the front page.
Speaker 1: At this Netscape the new Netscape calm seems to work where instead of users submitting stories.
Speaker 1: It sort of scrapes the stories off of.
Speaker 1: You know the news wires.
Speaker 1: So it's as if Google News was also looked like dig instead of looking like Google News And of course a bunch of AOL shit all over it.
Speaker 1: What happened today was that on dig there was a story about Netscape calm copying dig and it got dug a lot.
Speaker 1: People clicked on it and it took him to Netscape calm.
Speaker 1: and Netscape calm.
Speaker 1: one of the sources for stories is dig calm and People dug the story that Netscape calm took from dig.
Speaker 1: that was about Netscape calm Copying dig and a dug it right to the top.
Speaker 0: Dig dug.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what it's just hilarious.
Speaker 0: I tried to me.
Speaker 0: I tried to come up my head with some sort of funny Joke or thing where I'd say dig dug.
Speaker 0: at the end and we both laugh, but I had nothing.
Speaker 0: so I just said dig dug.
Speaker 1: It's like if I wrote a news story about how like Google is the worst company ever and Google News is evil And then it got to the top of Google News.
Speaker 1: That's what it's like.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's just awesome Things of the day.
Speaker 1: So we did the things of the day.
Speaker 1: we started doing the main bit and then rim Has keyboard on the lap and he hit the button and he deleted it.
Speaker 1: So now we're doing it again.
Speaker 0: Yep, mostly because I got my Mac and it's nice and shiny but for a lot of reasons I still need my Linux box every day.
Speaker 0: So I've got both of them on my desk now and I don't have a KVM or anything.
Speaker 0: So it's a real pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: You could just put that keyboard on.
Speaker 0: you know The wood there where this now the key the cord doesn't reach.
Speaker 0: that keyboards real crappy.
Speaker 0: It's that crappy one that you had.
Speaker 1: We throw out that wireless one didn't we?
Speaker 0: that wireless one barely worked.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it did barely work.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, cuz I still need my Linux box for a lot.
Speaker 0: The Mac is great, but it's not perfect.
Speaker 1: Let's redo them things of the day All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I've got this thing that I found and it's a little bit.
Speaker 0: you plug it into the headphone jack on an airliner.
Speaker 0: Now I know there's different kinds of headphone jacks.
Speaker 0: I don't know exactly which one it fits because a lot of airlines have those proprietary ones Where they try to sell you the $4 headphones.
Speaker 1: Bastards.
Speaker 0: now that matters.
Speaker 0: anyone who actually tries to listen to that music is really not deserving keeping their money in the first place.
Speaker 0: Nope but this device.
Speaker 0: you plug it in and you crank the volume all the way up and it will charge a little trickle charger from the Electricity coming through as audio and then it'll.
Speaker 0: you can use that trickle charger to recharge any electronic device.
Speaker 0: You have that charges via USB.
Speaker 1: That means to iPods.
Speaker 0: it charges at about a third the rate of the normal charger plugged in as it normally would be.
Speaker 1: hmm, it can help.
Speaker 1: I can see.
Speaker 1: maybe if you have like an iPod that you used a little bit and you just want to fill it Up all the way and you have a long flight
Speaker 0: or just if you have a long flight to make it last a third longer
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can make it last a third longer But
Speaker 0: actually probably more than a third longer because it charges much faster than it dissipates.
Speaker 1: Could be it takes.
Speaker 1: not it doesn't take very long to charge Yeah, but certain devices can use a lot of electricity depending on how you use them.
Speaker 1: Like if you have one of those portable DVD players you can forget it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but keep in mind that regardless they things charge a lot faster than these charge.
Speaker 1: nowadays Depends on the battery depends on the device.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most devices with lithium ion batteries charge very quickly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but here's a good example.
Speaker 1: if you have a Game Boy Color, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say you had a USB cable to charge that.
Speaker 1: somehow.
Speaker 0: if you that takes double-a batteries and uses a ton of power.
Speaker 1: I know no way to recharge is giving an example your examples silly and broken and giving example of a device that can use more electricity in one mode than in another mode.
Speaker 1: because if you if you use a Game Boy Color with Game Boy Color games Then it's fine.
Speaker 1: But if you put Game Boy games that use a little bit more electricity The GBA is even worse.
Speaker 1: if you put Game Boy or Game Boy Color games in a GBA It drains the batteries faster than if you play GBA games on it.
Speaker 0: but I mean I don't see how that's relevant because it's still extent no matter what mode you're using even if it Uses the battery really quickly.
Speaker 0: It still delays that by giving you some more power.
Speaker 1: It does it does help but you know in some modes of certain devices, they will discharge faster than they recharge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it still extends the usable amount of time it does indeed.
Speaker 0: So whether or not it discharges faster than it recharges is meaningless.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz if it you can recharge it faster than you can discharge it you will extend the life pretty much as long as the flight goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as opposed to it will run out anyway, but it still extends it.
Speaker 1: it does.
Speaker 0: That's really the whole point of the device.
Speaker 0: It's like those little bits you can buy where you Put a double-a battery in this thing and stick it on the bottom of your cell phone and it recharges it.
Speaker 1: Yep, personally though.
Speaker 1: I'd rather have a hand cranky type of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but those aren't really so efficient.
Speaker 1: They have more efficient ones than others.
Speaker 1: You know, it really depends on How comfortable.
Speaker 1: some of them are more comfortable to hold in the hand, you know.
Speaker 1: And depending on what you're trying to recharge like I wouldn't want to recharge a whole iPod with a hand crank Yeah, but I can recharge a GBA battery pack with a hand crank.
Speaker 0: now Of course regardless of the usefulness of this thing The point I want to make is that I am fairly certain within a reasonable amount of time This device is going to be banned from Airlines.
Speaker 1: Oh, they banned freaking everything from airplane.
Speaker 0: I just see it being people being afraid of it draining power from the airplane or being dangerous.
Speaker 1: That's first of all, it's not likely, you know, but If I was in charge, it really depends how the device works.
Speaker 1: I mean, does it just take the analog audio signal and convert it into electricity?
Speaker 0: It's probably just a voltage differential and draws as much power as it can.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that that might not be so good But if it just takes the sound, you know what though?
Speaker 0: honestly when I flew to Raleigh for an amazement There were just power outlets.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: They were just power outlets.
Speaker 0: I could have plugged anything into them if I wanted.
Speaker 1: trains have those also.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe this is for some planes that don't have power outlets.
Speaker 0: I think it's more just a gimmick to sell to people.
Speaker 1: People seem to like funky USB devices and shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know All right.
Speaker 0: Now we did Scott's thing of the day first.
Speaker 0: most only did my thing of the day first because Scott's is actually heady and kind Depressing a little scary.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: This is a YTM ND.
Speaker 1: You're the man now dog.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not a funny YTM ND.
Speaker 0: In fact, it seems to bill itself as the unfunny.
Speaker 1: It's called the unfunny truth about Scientology And the URL is the unfunny truth that YTM ND calm now.
Speaker 0: I'd like to preface this by saying that we really really don't like.
Speaker 0: I don't like stupid people.
Speaker 0: We don't like ugly people.
Speaker 0: We don't like smelly people at people.
Speaker 0: Scientologists are pretty much almost at the top of my list of people.
Speaker 0: I don't like because they I mean They have funny silly beliefs and we make fun of them for that.
Speaker 0: I mean they believe in aliens e-news and whatnot for real.
Speaker 1: but volcanoes and nukes and aliens.
Speaker 0: in addition to that They I don't know kill people ruin lives steal money generally make the world a worse place and they're a crazy evil cult a Real crazy evil cult not like a joke.
Speaker 1: Haha cultists, you know, like really those guys who all kill Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, really, you know like David Koresh style crazy cults man scary shit.
Speaker 1: So this little YTM ND will show you all of the major Incidents of Scientology evil.
Speaker 1: there are plenty more In fact, there are shit tons more but these are the big ones.
Speaker 0: These are the ones that are either really kind of disturbing or Really verifiable or just really graphic.
Speaker 1: Yep, or really famous the ones that made the evening news.
Speaker 0: I mean the really famous one.
Speaker 0: the Elisa McPherson case is here which it was a clear-cut case where Scientologists effectively kidnapped a woman and Starved her to death and then brought her back to a hospital after she died.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I don't know why that was their mistake.
Speaker 0: Well, they got off Because they have a lot of money and a lot of lawyers and the time didn't get off in the civil suit.
Speaker 0: Well, they we don't exactly know what happened in the civil suit.
Speaker 1: I think my guess is that the family wouldn't really care what there is if people knew what the result of the civil suit was.
Speaker 1: only Scientology would care.
Speaker 1: so I'm guessing the family got quite a bit because That that's in Scientology made them can Force the concession that whatever they got would be secret.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it was just a settlement.
Speaker 0: So they probably gave him a bunch of money to shut him up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was probably plenty of monies.
Speaker 0: But Scientologists are evil and they have done evil things.
Speaker 0: Some of them who aren't evil are just stupid but stupid and evil are interchangeable in terms of effect.
Speaker 1: Yep there are plenty of people who aren't in the.
Speaker 1: the people at the top of Scientology are evil and There are some people down and low in Scientology mostly these people who got killed.
Speaker 1: Who are people that just believe this shit and They don't realize they think they're doing good because they believe in something that's false?
Speaker 0: yeah, in fact, I could see how people could get drawn in because Scientology when they first explained it to you sounds a lot like the fourth way or all those other many myriad Philosophical interesting books and makes a lot of sense at first because it's real generic stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and once they hook you in with that the moon eats your soul, of course and Xenu appears.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean a lot of the stuff that Scientology will tell you when you first join them.
Speaker 1: you know seems to make a lot of sense and a lot of it is generic good life advice that I would give you if You came to me and asked me stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah the thing is they have this phony bullshit reasons for that advice meaning aliens and whatnot and Psychiatrists are evil.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like don't take drugs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that sounds good.
Speaker 0: Don't take drugs.
Speaker 1: doctors prescribe Don't take any drugs any.
Speaker 1: any disease can be cured with vitamins and minerals.
Speaker 0: Alright, well that cures one thing.
Speaker 0: I mean Darwinism is in full effect in that case indeed indeed.
Speaker 1: But of course the problem is is you know some person who is just stupid, you know is taking drugs.
Speaker 1: happily Scientologists take them take their drugs away from them and then they die.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean, I think there was one case there where they forced a guy to stop taking his.
Speaker 0: uh I think it was.
Speaker 0: it was see anti-seizure medication and he then shortly died of a seizure.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: Hmm, huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah Scientology has nothing to do with science.
Speaker 1: Not at all In fact is the opposite of science and it is evil.
Speaker 1: if there were some sort of You know superheroing going on some underwear pervert ISM.
Speaker 1: I am sure that Scientology would come under their wrath.
Speaker 1: Now if there is an evil organization on earth that needs to be destroyed this is it now?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not.
Speaker 0: the people who lead Scientology are obviously evil and obviously don't buy into it, but then some of them Yeah, well, yeah, they pretend to buy into it.
Speaker 1: You talk about my mother that way sometimes you They could just be insane.
Speaker 1: It might it's hard to tell the people at the top of Scientology It's hard to tell which ones are evil and they they're neither smart or the ones that are You know insane evil like mad scientist and the ones that are just stupid.
Speaker 0: Well mad scientist is a lot more like our friend Lisa than anything.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I'm talking about real mad scientist Like, you know that they really think they're gonna make a Frankenstein and take over the world for real.
Speaker 0: Yeah one Lisa real.
Speaker 1: Not only do they think they're gonna do it they think they're doing it right now and they're trying real hard.
Speaker 0: Well, she does have bird flu.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well as a serious, yeah But I'm really torn as to how to deal with the people who just were tricked by this.
Speaker 0: I mean on one hand they their lives are being ruined by this cult and I you really want to help them.
Speaker 0: but at the same time Yeah, well at the same time leave it this way Some people Christians.
Speaker 0: There's a famous quote.
Speaker 0: I love the sinner hate the sin Meaning hate Scientology, but love and help the people who are trapped in it.
Speaker 0: But then there's Morpheus in the matrix Yeah, and his solution to all these people who are part of the system.
Speaker 1: They're going to turn into agents and kill you so don't be afraid to just blow them away.
Speaker 0: if it saves your own ass though if any of you ever really want to have some fun come down to New York City with us some weekend and We will have our day of it going around the subways pestering the Scientologists.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you see people in the streets anywhere giving Personality tests stress tests etc.
Speaker 1: etc.
Speaker 1: with these weird little meters that have these metal handle thingies those are Scientologists, and you should harass them and pester them about Xenu cultists and Murders and all sorts of things.
Speaker 0: yeah, Lisa McPherson that name any Scientologist knows that name and is afraid of it.
Speaker 0: yeah, actually though a lot of new Scientologists don't because a lot of Scientologists aren't allowed to surf the internet without Someone from the church helping them out.
Speaker 1: yep keeping an eye on me.
Speaker 1: This is this is a news story that people who aren't in Scientology or specifically against Scientology know about because I mean seriously do you remember like that?
Speaker 1: Every year there's big news stories, and then there's kind of small news stories.
Speaker 1: This is a news story.
Speaker 1: That was like a local Florida type of thing.
Speaker 0: this is like what was going on while OJ was on trial in Tampa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I don't know you don't know.
Speaker 1: It's it was some small back news story.
Speaker 1: so very few people Remember it specifically and even people who do remember it is because they care about Scientology positively or negatively.
Speaker 0: well I like how you mentioned Florida.
Speaker 0: so when I needed the name of a random city.
Speaker 0: I just automatically said Tampa awesome.
Speaker 1: So this is not something a lot of people know about.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: so they don't realize Scientology is super evil.
Speaker 1: unless you show them the unfunny truth that YTM ND calm yep Which I highly recommend watching.
Speaker 0: I'll warn you it is a little graphic a little disturbing.
Speaker 1: it warns itself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: It's it should be disturbing.
Speaker 1: you need to be disturbed by Scientology.
Speaker 1: so watch this.
Speaker 0: yes unless you were already disturbed Now anyway, it's Thursday, which means we can talk about whatever the hell we want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and yesterday while we were talking about the mocha art festival.
Speaker 0: We mentioned Ichi the killer.
Speaker 1: Oh Each of the killer.
Speaker 0: now we didn't want to do a showist motion picture of our time.
Speaker 0: We didn't want to do a show just on each of the killer.
Speaker 0: so we brawn it a little bit.
Speaker 0: We would like to talk about our interest in now not just violent movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah violent movies.
Speaker 1: everyone seen.
Speaker 1: Rambo Predator.
Speaker 0: yeah now all the action flicks we have a special place in our hearts.
Speaker 0: in fact I would say that cockles are warmed by these movies.
Speaker 1: Ultra violent movies stupid violent movies Riccio Riccio Ebola syndrome people and the one that I watched at the most recent Otacon that no one else watched.
Speaker 1: that I forget the name of But you don't want to watch that one.
Speaker 0: that movie was just painful.
Speaker 0: I walked out.
Speaker 0: I was smart.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I can find it at the Otacon website.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll look while You talk here now.
Speaker 0: the difference between a violent movie and an ultraviolet movie at least the way We would like to describe it is that one.
Speaker 0: a violent movie has violence in it.
Speaker 0: it may be comprised mostly of violence But there is some sort of plot there are some sort of there are some non-violent scenes And the violence is definitely movie violence.
Speaker 0: hmm.
Speaker 0: and an ultra violent movie One you know in a movie when there's some sort of like a horrible thing is happening and the camera always like shows you a Bit and then cuts away and leaves it to your imagination.
Speaker 0: Ultra violent movies.
Speaker 0: the camera is fixed pointing at the horrible thing from start to finish and then a little while after Yep in some movies.
Speaker 1: You know violence is just a thing that happens like the Godfather.
Speaker 1: You know it's a story about mafia guys, and when there's a story about mafia There's gonna be a violence going on.
Speaker 1: and they show some of that violence when it's appropriate But they do it in a cinematographer.
Speaker 1: Lee Cinematographically.
Speaker 0: I like that word a lot.
Speaker 0: Scott cinema all right cinema that didn't get in kiss gonna bring you do.
Speaker 1: cinematographically Fashion like.
Speaker 0: a good example of this is in suicide Kings when Dennis Leary you know captain fish boots goes and beats the hell out of a drunken abusive guy and The way he does it is.
Speaker 0: he walks over and he picks up a toaster and he wraps the cord around his hands.
Speaker 0: He's got this basically fist toaster toaster fist toaster fist.
Speaker 0: I like that should be a superhero Cinematographer.
Speaker 0: cool, and he beats He cocks over and he starts beating this guy pretty much to death but it just shows him and his hand and him swinging the thing and hitting something off camera and Making the noise.
Speaker 0: that sounds like someone hitting a watermelon with a toaster cinematographer But they don't show the blood splattering or anything.
Speaker 1: yes You know what the point of that movie is not the violence.
Speaker 1: the point of that movie is other things.
Speaker 0: Ultraviolet movies are movies where the plot is violent.
Speaker 1: the point of the movie is violence like when you watch a porn.
Speaker 1: there might be A plot, but the point of the movie is to watch people doing it or to watch naked people Or to watch some other fetish.
Speaker 1: you have.
Speaker 1: The point of a violent movie an ultra crazy violent stupid violent movie is to watch Fake violence or perhaps a real violence.
Speaker 1: if you're that freaky Yeah, and it's full.
Speaker 1: and who cares about the plot?
Speaker 1: you might as well You know it's like watching those little clips on YouTube of a million people hurting themselves, but at least you know It's fake, so it's not like wow that's horrible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this stuff on YouTube is usually like a guy hitting his head or a guy falling off a skateboard.
Speaker 1: This is Disemboweling but fake.
Speaker 1: you know completely.
Speaker 1: mutilation fling, but flake.
Speaker 0: But also there are really dark sense of humor around everything.
Speaker 0: yep if I needed words to describe these movies I mean black humor doesn't quite cut it.
Speaker 0: black humor is like eight heads in a duffel bag.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is not.
Speaker 1: This is beyond.
Speaker 0: this is like eight baby heads in a thousand duffel bag.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's quite like a dead baby joke.
Speaker 1: in a way watching these movies you know you just if you don't have a If you have a weak stomach at all you can't watch them.
Speaker 0: I mean I consider myself a fairly jaded cynical person.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but when I saw each of the killer for the first time the full unedited.
Speaker 1: real deal If it's cut if the version of each the killer you watch is cut in any way do not watch it.
Speaker 0: now there were scenes.
Speaker 0: expect in fact almost every scene in that movie.
Speaker 0: I Physically cringed.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: I mean there was I. I don't.
Speaker 0: I can't ruin some of this.
Speaker 1: I don't want to be even when there wasn't violence because it was just.
Speaker 1: you know the way the movie was.
Speaker 1: it's opaque.
Speaker 0: I just knew the violence was coming.
Speaker 0: yeah And some of its quick and some of its slow and some of it is silly like the face.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the face on the wall yep, but if I needed our English words to describe these movies.
Speaker 0: I'm gratuitous I Unnecessary.
Speaker 1: Make sure you multiply all these words by 10.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean once again the key word here is ultra Ultraviolet mega super hyper like Ultraman.
Speaker 0: you have a man right a man's just a dude But Ultraman is awesome and ultra and powerful.
Speaker 1: we should.
Speaker 1: we should put the word fucking before it fucking Ultraviolet.
Speaker 0: yeah, you know what tasteless.
Speaker 1: there you go now.
Speaker 0: you might wonder How would Rimmins got to upstanding young gentleman?
Speaker 1: Well I'm not even upstanding.
Speaker 0: I'm lay downing and you're sit downing yeah kind of crouching over my little microphone here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, but I mean we tear.
Speaker 0: we cried Watching try gun when one dude got waxed.
Speaker 0: Yeah cried our eyes out now.
Speaker 1: We say wax.
Speaker 0: So You might wonder you know how could two men who cry watching anime Fall into this kind of genre and enjoy it to the point that they're going to talk about it on a podcast.
Speaker 1: Well it all started Flashback.
Speaker 0: actually we were.
Speaker 0: I'm in the process of writing a bunch of music to use for stingers and bumpers and all that sort Of stuff to kind of jazz up geek nights a little bit.
Speaker 1: Oh, we'll see if people like it or if they complain.
Speaker 0: Oh, it'll be weeks before I actually do this, but yeah right then is where I would have played one of those songs.
Speaker 1: alright, so Three realize the Otakon this year is gonna be our fifth Otakon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've been to four Otakons already at our second Otakon.
Speaker 1: I was looking in the program guide Friday and There's a section.
Speaker 1: well, there's a room at Otakon that only shows live-action cinema Mostly Asian live-action cinema yep for various countries Korea, China, Hong Kong Thailand Philippines Japan Anywhere.
Speaker 1: as long as they.
Speaker 0: that year it was video 7 the smallest of the video rooms.
Speaker 1: yes now We looking through this guide saw a movie called the ichi the killer.
Speaker 1: There was a description of the movie that claimed it was the most violent thing ever blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: And I was like oh really that sounds interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, really next to every movie in the whole program guide was a genre.
Speaker 1: now the genres you know obvious action horror comedy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, hentai whatever the genre for each of the killer was a genre that was applied to no other movie.
Speaker 1: the genre was tasteless.
Speaker 0: Now this was intriguing to us and in fact we and as a result almost the entire front row crew Who was there that year decided?
Speaker 0: We are going to go see this movie at midnight.
Speaker 1: Yep on Saturday Saturday It's always late Saturday night every Otakon at least for the past three years.
Speaker 1: Late at late on Saturday night is some horribly violent movie.
Speaker 0: now when we go to cons.
Speaker 0: We meet a lot of cool people.
Speaker 0: and That year because we were gonna go see this ultraviolet movie whenever we met someone cool, and we parted ways We always said hey meet us in Saturday and video 7 at midnight.
Speaker 0: We're gonna watch this horribly violent movie.
Speaker 0: Yep Now we said this all day Friday and all day Saturday up until the movie that took like hundreds of people Everyone we met we were like hey come see this movie with us.
Speaker 1: So as a result we get to video 7 and there is a line Like.
Speaker 0: we showed up almost an hour before and there was already a line bigger than that room.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Was it because of our word spreading.
Speaker 1: I like to think so.
Speaker 0: yes in fact I will assume so because we're that awesome.
Speaker 0: But who knows?
Speaker 0: now not only was I mean the line was long.
Speaker 0: there were like a hundred people in this line because the room It was gonna be showing but the room could not hold the line.
Speaker 0: now We stood around for a while and about it was about five minutes before midnight and the line had grown into and I'm actually not Exaggerating here over a thousand people.
Speaker 1: well because if there's a hundred people line everyone walking by thinks all this must be something good.
Speaker 1: Let me get in line for it.
Speaker 0: There were I don't know how many people were actually in the line, but there were definitely over a thousand.
Speaker 1: It was a lot.
Speaker 0: It was a mob.
Speaker 0: It was not a line.
Speaker 0: It was a giant unruly mob.
Speaker 1: now when the staff finally got the mob under control They sent us to the biggest video room.
Speaker 0: They had this room seats multiple thousand people.
Speaker 1: Yes, so we filled up at least over a third of this room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Then we watched E.T the killer and the movie has the most tasteless it right up front.
Speaker 0: During the opening credits something horrible happened.
Speaker 1: It's it's the.
Speaker 1: we watched the version that is completely and 100% Uncut with all the directors added whatnot.
Speaker 1: there was nothing missing from this movie And I recommend you do not watch it in any other form because that will inoculate you against the ultra violence That is each of the killer.
Speaker 1: Yes, if you watch the cut version and then you watch the uncut version it will not work.
Speaker 1: it's sort of like You know putting your foot in the water and then slowly gliding into the pool versus jumping into the freezing cold water.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is polar bear.
Speaker 0: This is beyond polar bear.
Speaker 1: This is But Let's just go through a few of the scenes in each of the killer to give people an idea.
Speaker 0: Alright, well, let's start with like the opening bit because there are two scenes in the opening the credits which the credits.
Speaker 1: Alright, there's a scene before the credits.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but then there's the credits bit and basically during the first scene the whole audience because no one really knew what to expect except for I think a few old veterans who had heard of this movie and The crowd, you know cheered when the movie started and then when the scene the first scene actually began Everyone kind of shut up.
Speaker 1: The first scene is what is a horrible rape.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got this mafia guy as a hooker and he's beating the ever-living shit out of her while raping her.
Speaker 1: yep, yeah and raping this woman now and Graphically mind you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you see him beating her and raping her.
Speaker 1: They don't hide anything.
Speaker 0: and that this penis the crowd went from to.
Speaker 0: And then after about five minutes of this the crowd went back to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean some people got up and left because they didn't realize they couldn't take it.
Speaker 1: and you know, that's granted That's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the movie build itself is the most violent horrible movie ever.
Speaker 0: What did they expect?
Speaker 1: and you know, it's fake.
Speaker 1: So you go in you seeing this because you want to see violence and when you see the violence if you're not cheering You probably shouldn't watch it now.
Speaker 0: Now you might just think alright, so it's this short violent scene.
Speaker 0: This scene is several minutes long.
Speaker 1: This movie was hours long.
Speaker 1: Goddamn.
Speaker 1: Was it too long?
Speaker 0: there was.
Speaker 0: I mean the scene was just an uninterrupted horrible scene and then the credits play and The were the first of the words.
Speaker 1: the guy gets killed first.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Well in a horrible bloody mess.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't even get to see that.
Speaker 0: Barely you get to see it a little bit you get to see the aftermath of that when the guy slips in the intestines.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now bear in mind the guy slips and falls because he stepped on some intestines on a floor That is a hundred percent covered in blood and slippery.
Speaker 0: now you might be thinking in your head You know B movie gore because there's a lot of B movies with gore.
Speaker 1: but they had a budget for this film a high one.
Speaker 0: This is like that hentai that anime world order was talking about my lady innocent.
Speaker 0: Yeah Where the production values are so high and the movie is so realistic and takes itself so seriously That it just it ends up being this Unfathomable thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: it's not like a fake blood and guts.
Speaker 1: It's like whoa, that is Expensive fake blood and guts.
Speaker 1: that looks all fancy in the CG and whoa.
Speaker 0: Now during all of this and then the eventual murder there is a guy outside Watching and getting off on it.
Speaker 0: He Kinda, yeah, he auto erotically arouses himself to a finish.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the point is is that he his.
Speaker 1: While he kills he is finishing.
Speaker 0: It's well I guess I'll cut to the chase.
Speaker 0: the title the title splash for the credits Nishi the killer Forms out of the puddle of semen that the main character leaves behind.
Speaker 0: Yep This movie it's the most it.
Speaker 0: Well, it was the most tasteless movie we had ever seen.
Speaker 1: No Okay, so Let's just do a couple more scenes in each of the killing.
Speaker 1: All right, let's see There's three that really stand out in my mind.
Speaker 0: Let me guess the hot grease the hot grease.
Speaker 0: Yeah nipples and nipples.
Speaker 0: Third one's up in the air tongue.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh Let's talk about the tongue.
Speaker 0: All right, that's it.
Speaker 0: That's a perfect example of why this movie is so violent.
Speaker 1: So there's this is the main character of each of the killer.
Speaker 1: actually isn't each of the killer?
Speaker 1: This is Yakuza guy and he's sort of like a punk Badass dude with all sorts of piercings and shit.
Speaker 0: And he has his mouth at the sides of his edges of his lips cut back into his cheeks And then he has two piercings holding it together.
Speaker 1: Yeah So if he takes these piercings out basically his cheek is completely split and he can open his jaw real wide.
Speaker 0: He doesn't do that though, but he smokes a lot and he puffs smoke out those holes.
Speaker 1: He puffs smoke out through the sides of his cheek.
Speaker 1: It's kind of scary I think.
Speaker 1: it's all CG obviously.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes So he's a scary mafia dude.
Speaker 1: Yakuza and he's like the main is the focus of most of the movie.
Speaker 1: Now he does something he screws up and he's not the head of the Yakuza He's.
Speaker 1: he has bosses above him.
Speaker 0: In fact, his screw-up was the grease incident.
Speaker 1: Yes, and He screwed up.
Speaker 1: So he needed to apologize.
Speaker 1: now, you know in the in the Yakuza, you know, you cut off a finger.
Speaker 0: Let that finger fly.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's the saying.
Speaker 0: I don't know how they say it in Japanese, but it was in sanctuary was yeah it was yeah, so He goes to the boss and he says I apologize.
Speaker 1: He says people say I have a sweet tooth.
Speaker 1: I will you know, I will apologize by cutting off the source of my pleasure.
Speaker 1: now You'd think he's gonna cut off his penis.
Speaker 1: because he said he's gonna cut off the source of his pleasure.
Speaker 0: the whole crowd went.
Speaker 1: But right before that he said I have a. people say I have a sweet tooth.
Speaker 0: now He reaches down like he's gonna undo his belt.
Speaker 1: He's getting a knife and then he pulls out a knife and then he pulls out his tongue his tongue with a piercing in it.
Speaker 0: Obviously now at this point a real movie would have cut away and showed you the reactions of the people as something horrible happened off-screen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you would see the mafia bosses cringing and you did see the mafia bosses cringing.
Speaker 1: Yes, but what you actually see is the camera stays on the guy's face.
Speaker 1: He holds his tongue in one hand out of his out of his mouth and the knife in the other hand and you see him cut off The front of his tongue like they don't cut away until the tongue is completely cut off and it's so realistic.
Speaker 0: I mean He's like he's actually kind of sawing at it because it won't go and pull it on it and tugging on and he pulls the Last bit like out and there's still the piercing in the bit that was cut off and he puts it in Little jar.
Speaker 1: He's like handing it to the mom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is the mafia guy and the boss is like, uh Just leave it there.
Speaker 0: and then in the Okay, his cell phone rings and he picks it up and he's like yo and he starts talking to the guy in the other hand Of the boat bloods just pouring out of his mouth.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of movie each of the killer is now.
Speaker 1: that's the kind of movie all these movies are now.
Speaker 0: We thought when we'd seen each of the killer that nothing could ever top that that that was the most horrible movie ever made.
Speaker 0: Well, well violence wise yes, whoa did Otakon prove us wrong.
Speaker 1: Oh the next year at Otakon We went back for Saturday night.
Speaker 1: We assumed they'd have more and boy.
Speaker 1: Do they have more?
Speaker 0: they had Ebola syndrome, which is probably the most tasteless horrid wretched movie ever Released unto man and beast.
Speaker 1: now I'm not gonna talk about the plot of each of the killer because it's just crazy stupid.
Speaker 0: someone Took drugs and made this shit up, you know, at least each of the killer has a lot of humor in it.
Speaker 0: It does and the end is is very ava tacular and that you won't understand what syndrome had.
Speaker 1: humor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's a different sort.
Speaker 0: That was a different kind of humor.
Speaker 1: Yes so Let me tell you the plot of Ebola syndrome because because Ebola syndrome did have one thing right is that it had such a simple Plot that it was able to execute that simple plot fully While also fitting in lots of violence and nastiness and easy.
Speaker 1: the killer had a complex plot that was just stupid Complex or end of Ava type of shit the whole time.
Speaker 1: So it didn't really, you know, the violence sort of made the plot.
Speaker 0: remember that scene in each of the killer with the muscle, man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was fantastic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Ebola syndrome, here's the plot.
Speaker 1: There's a guy.
Speaker 1: he's a bad guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he murdered the lover of his girlfriend and then his girlfriend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a bad guy.
Speaker 1: He went to jail or you know, he ran away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was.
Speaker 0: he got away after murdering them and he ran away to another country South Africa.
Speaker 1: It was yeah, it was South Africa.
Speaker 0: Yeah, South Africa during the worst days.
Speaker 0: Yes I wanted to say the bad days, but it's still pretty bad.
Speaker 1: He gets a job in a restaurant and This is a bad guy real bad, but he's working for a bad guy Slightly less bad guy but a bad guy nonetheless.
Speaker 1: and they go to buy some animals To use to cook in the restaurant from an African village Whatever.
Speaker 0: now the African village they go to apparently has some horrible play like there's Ebola in the region.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's actually a plot about how they couldn't get animals from the normal guys.
Speaker 1: So they had to go and get you know animals They knew were probably no good for cheap from the tribe.
Speaker 0: and like there are people dying of Ebola laying around and he's like Yeah, this meets fine.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So they think they bought some pigs, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, now while the the boss guy is negotiating this he said I don't remember exactly what happens But the the horrible guy gets sent off with the car to do something He comes across a woman who has just died of Ebola.
Speaker 1: like he sees her in the field doing something I think near a stream and she has she's obviously ill and then she just passes out and dies next to the stream of Ebola.
Speaker 0: And what he thinks and we know he thinks it because he says it out loud is effectively Hot-damn, I haven't been laid in a long time.
Speaker 1: Here we go and Sure enough Ebola syndrome comes through in spades.
Speaker 0: Now you might think okay, that's it.
Speaker 0: he catches Ebola and Well, actually he ends up being immune to Ebola, but he's still a carrier and he spreads it around.
Speaker 1: Yes The plot of Ebola syndrome is that this evil fuck guy Who is treated poorly by his boss and pretty much hates the world is in South Africa.
Speaker 1: He can give people Ebola But he only suffered the illness for a few days and then it went away and he is now immune to Ebola.
Speaker 1: But he can give it to people all he wants and he's gonna run around giving it to people.
Speaker 0: now He ends up for reasons.
Speaker 0: I really don't want to bother explaining.
Speaker 0: killing people Who have Ebola or killing people?
Speaker 0: Grinding them up turning them into meat and his boss and his boss's wife and serving them at his restaurant as hamburgers.
Speaker 1: He gives them Ebola he grinds them up and he makes people burgers and serves them to the people in the restaurant.
Speaker 0: now it just gets worse from there and Surprisingly the only scene in the movie that was like really made the whole audience cringe like more so than everything else Was a useless rat the useless unrelated rat.
Speaker 0: There was a at one point.
Speaker 0: There's a dead rat laying in the street.
Speaker 1: No, there's a living rat scampering about the street.
Speaker 0: I thought it was already dead.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: all I know is that they show a car running over.
Speaker 0: It's obviously a model But obvious they show a car just run over it.
Speaker 0: for some reason the whole crowd was like, oh It was like the movie was just horribly violent.
Speaker 1: and whatnot with this crazy bad dude?
Speaker 1: people dying of Ebola Which isn't pretty, you know.
Speaker 1: people getting chopped up people getting raped people getting killed all kinds of nastiness You know, I think he.
Speaker 1: animals getting killed whatever but completely unrelated to the rest of the movie.
Speaker 1: There's just a scene of a rat getting run over by a car.
Speaker 1: That has nothing to do with anything There's no context.
Speaker 0: It's just random and that scene elicited more empathy from the crowd than the rest of the movie combined.
Speaker 1: That's cuz.
Speaker 1: it was random and it wasn't related.
Speaker 1: So, you know It's like if I show you a video of an animal scampering about the highway and then getting hit by a car.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, but if you did five minutes ago, you saw that animal, you know biting someone to give them rabies.
Speaker 1: You'd be like, ah, it's completely different.
Speaker 0: Now luckily the movie has a nice comeuppance at the end But it leaves a space for a sequel.
Speaker 0: it does it does but I'll ruin the movie right now.
Speaker 0: they get the dude There's the detective after him and basically he gets set on fire Hit by a car shot and then the detective who's chasing him now.
Speaker 0: He's on fire and already hit by the car runs over and Unloads his pistol into the dude like running around in a circle and then starts cheering.
Speaker 0: cuz he got him.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then you see this team running around town and cleaning up all the Ebola that this guy cuz.
Speaker 1: basically at the end of This movie the guy was running and spitting at people cuz they give them Ebola and they were chasing him in bio suits and stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah literally.
Speaker 1: So, you know, they they spray this poison shit everywhere.
Speaker 1: He spit and cleaned up all the Ebola.
Speaker 0: I don't know why this movie had such an epilogue.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really didn't need it.
Speaker 1: But they they put it in there.
Speaker 0: the movie is just in bad taste.
Speaker 1: It is in the worst taste you can possibly have.
Speaker 1: I mean if movies were food Then this would be me krob Ebola syndrome would be me kra and each of the killer would be natto.
Speaker 0: Hey katsu likes natto and he's coming over this week.
Speaker 1: I'd see likes each of the killer - yeah He's I think he does.
Speaker 0: of course katsu likes each of the killer.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: I should like each of the killer.
Speaker 0: Now we didn't really have anywhere to go with this.
Speaker 0: We just really wanted to talk about violent movies and these movies that we'd seen.
Speaker 1: it's a note of contradiction.
Speaker 1: last year I was the only one who held out.
Speaker 1: It was a really bad movie.
Speaker 1: I. it was horrible and violent, but it wasn't really that horrible and violent.
Speaker 1: Most of it was just dark and Slow and boring and it was real late and we were real tired.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the tiredness was.
Speaker 1: it had some horrible violence in it, but it wasn't extreme and it wasn't in the high ratio That the previous movies were.
Speaker 1: but I held out and watched.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the name of it because it was so unmemorable.
Speaker 0: It was a sequel to something - yeah, it was number two.
Speaker 1: I couldn't tell you what happened.
Speaker 1: All I can tell you is there's some fat ugly lady who couldn't get laid but she was also a serial killer.
Speaker 1: And she was.
Speaker 1: she was a serial killer and she was a projectionist in a movie theater.
Speaker 1: and then crazy batshit happens in this horrible violence.
Speaker 1: the end Granted.
Speaker 0: I think the other movie we saw SARS Wars more than made up for the lacking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that was a comedy.
Speaker 1: That wasn't a crazy violent movie.
Speaker 0: So that doesn't really fit in but it filled my niche for that year enough.
Speaker 1: It did fill the niche for necessity to watch new amazing live-action films from around the world.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't call SARS Wars amazing.
Speaker 1: I would call it amazing.
Speaker 0: I Guess amazing in some senses.
Speaker 1: It's at least awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was fantastic.
Speaker 1: Yes Hey SARS Wars Yeah, so why is it?
Speaker 1: there's two movies that are about diseases Ebola SARS.
Speaker 1: I'd like this year We got to go see you know bird flu or I just wonder because they didn't top Ebola syndrome this year.
Speaker 0: Well this past year I don't think any movie out there exists that can top Ebola syndrome.
Speaker 0: in terms of the sheer horror There has to be a movie out there.
Speaker 0: Where where can we go other than actual snuff films?
Speaker 0: uh We can go see reenactments of actual snuff films But that's not so bad cuz that's just each you the killer without the plot.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: It's also got to be horrible and tasteless I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you any bird flu fever or What's the other disease?
Speaker 1: Everyone's worrying about West Nile?
Speaker 0: Outbreak.
Speaker 0: I'm telling you.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be that more gallons disease.
Speaker 1: Oh more gallons disease.
Speaker 1: That'll be a good one.
Speaker 1: the disease from outer the disease of tasteless violence from outer space The what you need.
Speaker 1: I think the way to beat Ebola syndrome is not with quality but with quantity.
Speaker 1: You need not a scene of a guy, you know raping Dead recently deceased woman who has Ebola.
Speaker 1: you need a squad of guys raping a village of mixed genders and ages all recently dead of.
Speaker 1: you know, the Bird flu.
Speaker 0: I think we also need to just throw in some racism some sexism.
Speaker 0: Every ism there is.
Speaker 1: that is one thing these movies seem to be lacking.
Speaker 1: other than you know The you know generic sort of toned down not serious racism, you know like me and rim will be like yeah those whatever's you happen to be we made up of fake cuz we What was it?
Speaker 0: Chuke?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we made up a fake racial slur.
Speaker 0: that doesn't particularly mean anyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah Eric racial slur everyone's a juke.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also no one's a Jew.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we gotta add real racism real sexism.
Speaker 0: I guess it's just that real.
Speaker 0: You know what makes these movies.
Speaker 0: I don't want to say interesting but interesting is that they cross Boundaries that filmmakers really don't cross.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even people who you know don't Tend to stick to the normal trends in their filmmaking don't do certain things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean not many filmmakers think it would be a wise decision to have your protagonist Necrophilia rape a woman who died of Ebola.
Speaker 1: Yeah that pretty much never happened in any movie.
Speaker 1: I mean even in movies you see like children don't get killed usually on screen.
Speaker 1: It's especially on TV.
Speaker 1: I don't think you were allowed to do that in America.
Speaker 0: It's not that you're not allowed It's sort of an unwritten rule.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know there are rules about it for television.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 1: have you made?
Speaker 1: a movie where some guy on screen like just?
Speaker 1: Stabs a bunch of kids in his classroom.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: It was like watch them all bleed to death.
Speaker 0: It was like when they made the movie based on Lolita, and there was all sorts of controversy about it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I don't know that.
Speaker 0: yeah, there was a lot even though.
Speaker 1: There's a movie.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah It's actually a fairly decent movie But there is a shit ton of controversy about that movie for a number of obvious reasons.
Speaker 1: obvious reasons Yes, now.
Speaker 0: I guess what it is is these movies are the aristocrats joke?
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: only they are Graphics not just talking.
Speaker 1: yes, yes We need to make each of the killer the video game or Ebola syndrome the video game.
Speaker 1: That's what we need.
Speaker 0: How about the live-action RPG system?
Speaker 1: or how about Custer's revenge the movie?
Speaker 0: haha I'm telling you Custer should be in Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: It could be the secret secret secret character.
Speaker 1: Yeah the only people who get to who can unlock Custer's revenge the people who get a Custer's revenge cartridge and Somehow wire it into the revolution.
Speaker 1: He only has one attack You get a ROM of Custer's revenge And you put it on a flash cart and you put the flash cart in the slot on the revolution And then you can unlock Custer in Smash Brother.
Speaker 1: That's how it is and you have to insert in each of the killer DVD eject it and then put in the Smash Brothers disc.
Speaker 1: That's how it works.
Speaker 0: You know what even if that were the case that would be on game facts within about seven seconds.
Speaker 1: So that is true, and we would do it and we'd use Custer every time And you throw each of the killer in smash or the the mafia guy at least.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the guy's name I don't remember.
Speaker 0: all I remember is that that movie ended in the most Unsatisfying way.
Speaker 0: I mean at least Ebola syndrome ended in a satisfying way.
Speaker 1: That's satisfying than the end of Ava is to some people who aren't satisfied with it Even though I was perfectly satisfied with the end of Ava.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there are a lot of people there who you know, that's the classic one that people you know Tend to agree is like a what the fuck ending.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess you the killer is more of a what the fuck ending than that because I guess my point is my idea Here is that with Ava the end of Ava was alright.
Speaker 0: people didn't like it.
Speaker 0: But look it makes sense.
Speaker 0: and look here's what it was saying.
Speaker 0: you can understand Why it was done that way kind of.
Speaker 0: there is something there.
Speaker 1: you can understand most of it.
Speaker 0: There is something that I'm not talking about the movie.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm talking about the original end.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah about that it there was something there.
Speaker 0: there was something to it.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about the ending and the movie.
Speaker 0: well the movie the whole end as a unit the movie was just the response to the Fanboys or weren't satisfied with the real end?
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah, but the point is I'm just saying yeah There's nothing to the end of each of the killer.
Speaker 0: There's no deep meaning.
Speaker 0: there Might be but it's just what the file remember that the Raven and then the kid and then the guy who hung himself.
Speaker 0: But not really.
Speaker 1: or did he really?
Speaker 0: or was that?
Speaker 0: I don't even know who that guy was?
Speaker 1: I mean go I think you go online and there's some explanations of it, and they did.
Speaker 1: those didn't even make sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, God someone's gonna call up and tell us we're idiots.
Speaker 0: No, because if anyone claims to understand the deeper intricacies of each of the killer or even just what happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the names of the characters, I know a little bit.
Speaker 1: I actually I don't want to spoil the movie for anyone, but I The way you spoil easy the killer is by describing all the violet the good violent scenes in great detail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait.
Speaker 0: There's the plot thing the hypnotism.
Speaker 1: I can't be spoiled the hypnotism bit.
Speaker 1: That's not a spoiler.
Speaker 1: Okay, no one cares about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you do you're watching this movie for all the wrong reasons.
Speaker 0: Go watch a better movie seriously All right, so I guess I want to open it up to the forums out there And it will probably talk about this again sometime.
Speaker 0: What horrible movies have you seen that are ultraviolet?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: We're looking for the most depraved Films that you have ever seen.
Speaker 1: TV shows I guess count to yeah.
Speaker 0: now We're not talking about realistic real not realistic But not real things.
Speaker 0: don't go film some mugger killing a guy in an alley.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, don't Come tell us that you watched a holocaust documentary, and that's you know.
Speaker 1: of course that's worse than each of the killer.
Speaker 1: It's real, but that's not what we're talking about.
Speaker 0: We're talking about fake.
Speaker 1: Yep fake and horrendously Violent.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone out there can top each of the killer in Ebola syndrome?
Speaker 1: I don't think either.
Speaker 1: and you know the only movies I can think of to come close are all the gory horror films like the Jason's and the Freddy's.
Speaker 1: and What are the other ones?
Speaker 1: Halloween Halloween yeah Get chucky kinda To a crypt keeper kinda all those sorts of things.
Speaker 1: and the bad 80s horror movies Oh, yeah, you know those kinda, but that's a different That's.
Speaker 1: you know that's super gory.
Speaker 1: make you want to barf scary.
Speaker 1: That's not super ultraviolet for the sake of ultraviolet.
Speaker 0: yep Cuz how hell?
Speaker 1: what's his face?
Speaker 1: so the pins on the face hellraiser?
Speaker 0: People seem to either love ultraviolet movies or hate them.
Speaker 0: There's very little middle ground.
Speaker 1: It's all a matter of iron gut or fleshy gut.
Speaker 1: if your gut is fleshy you'll bargo.
Speaker 1: I mean if your gut is iron you you will laugh mightily.
Speaker 0: as eg the killer went on.
Speaker 0: I remember periodically like there'd be a violent scene and Everyone like they got worse and worse as the movie went on and after every violent scene at least a couple people would get up And walk away in disgust.
Speaker 0: yeah But like even sometimes I'd be like oh Yeah, the crowd was really schizophrenic because they'd yell and scream and cheer.
Speaker 0: well each You know caught a person up into a million pieces, but then they'd stop and go.
Speaker 1: ah When they do it looks disgusting and it's making me all queasy, but oh it was awesome Not one.
Speaker 0: Finally these are not movies to watch alone.
Speaker 1: No Enjoy I mean do not watch these alone under any circumstance.
Speaker 0: if you watch each of the killer alone You're a sad man.
Speaker 1: You're a sad very sad, man.
Speaker 0: I mean these are movies designed to be watched with as many people as possible.
Speaker 1: I mean we watch each of the killer with thousand people yelling and screaming and cheering and cringing all in unison and I would have to say that that's pretty close to the minimum required to Watch each of the killer.
Speaker 1: a hundred just doesn't cut it.
Speaker 0: You Also, really can't be easily offended.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you are possible to be offended unlike us you should never watch these movies ever.
Speaker 0: Each of the killer is not so offensive.
Speaker 0: It's just violent and horrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Ebola syndrome is directly offensive to many sensibilities.
Speaker 1: Oh I mean it offended me.
Speaker 1: It's got some if I could be offended.
Speaker 0: It's got some racism.
Speaker 0: It's got a lot of sexism.
Speaker 0: It's got a rape.
Speaker 0: it's got murder.
Speaker 1: It's got cannibalism like necrophilia usually when someone does something offensive and people are offended by it.
Speaker 1: And I'm not.
Speaker 1: I say you shouldn't be offended by that Ebola syndrome.
Speaker 1: I say I'm not offended by that But you probably should be.
Speaker 0: I understand why Ebola syndrome is a movie where if you're not offended by it You'll think to yourself.
Speaker 0: Wow, my being offended gland is broken God damn.
Speaker 1: or you are should join the Club of Scott and we should go have an awesome party.
Speaker 0: Yeah Either that or you're a robot or you could be a robot.
Speaker 1: Yes robot You might be a robot if you watch Ebola syndrome without being offended.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I got real close.
Speaker 0: I mean there were scenes like wow, that was terrible.
Speaker 1: Or I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: well, you know the raping of the recently deceased Ebola victim.
Speaker 0: That wasn't even the worst thing in that movie not even close that.
Speaker 1: that was just the start of the plot The Seed For the rest of the film to grow.
Speaker 0: Okay, we're done.
Speaker 0: Tell us about your horrible movies.
Speaker 0: We'll probably read what you say next Thursday or sometime in the future and at Otacon this year, of course Saturday night There's a 90% chance.
Speaker 1: There will be a horrible movie that we will watch.
Speaker 0: in fact, we'll probably be there interviewing people Oh my god, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: you can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.