Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, December 20th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and I'm Rin, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we discuss dubs.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So weekly anime review kind of punked us in that despite the fact that we have you know 200 and a lot episodes under our belt like 250 or something like that.
Speaker 1: We don't have our t-shirts out.
Speaker 0: yet We don't even have anything to put on the t-shirts.
Speaker 1: Well, we have lots of things to put on the t-shirts But they're very conceptual and not very actually drawn on a piece of paper.
Speaker 1: Yeah but yet they took it upon themselves to Take advantage of the popular swag for swag program whereby any Podcast who sends us swag will get swag in return, but we don't have anything yet.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of just rubbing salt in the wounds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I don't think we've mentioned that program before but if you send geek nights your swag We will send you equivalent geek night swag provided you are a legitimate cosplayer.
Speaker 1: a cosplayer No, not cosplayer Legitimate podcaster.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't have to be a podcaster.
Speaker 0: You might be a webcomic.
Speaker 0: er Yeah, or you know something else.
Speaker 1: But but if our friend Peter sends us a white t-shirt where he has written the name Peter on it in black marker We were not going to send him a geek night shirt No and said we'll sell him.
Speaker 0: you send him a turd in an envelope.
Speaker 0: that is a fair exchange.
Speaker 1: It has to be a polished one.
Speaker 0: Yes Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's speaking of other podcasters.
Speaker 1: For those of you who listen to anime world order, which is a decent number of you I've noticed that there seems to be a lot of crossover between our Wednesday listeners and anime world order.
Speaker 1: They recently had their one year anniversary special which consisted of episode 42 and At the end of that episode there was a short audio drama.
Speaker 1: If you want to call it that I will say that in terms of the actual source material, I think it was very faithful To the spirit.
Speaker 1: I mean that that stuff is pretty much unintelligible anyway.
Speaker 0: So we're we act in it.
Speaker 0: We have two bit parts.
Speaker 0: So if you want to hear us do something funny You can go listen to the end of the newest anime world order as of right now.
Speaker 1: yep, and we will congratulate them on successfully completing 42 episodes in 52 weeks.
Speaker 0: and It just reminded me if that's their one year anniversary We're even podcasting longer than they have.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have.
Speaker 1: so I guess that makes us uh, I don't know veterans.
Speaker 0: We're definitely their seniors.
Speaker 0: They have to call a senpai.
Speaker 1: They'd better call a senpai Because we're probably gonna see him at katsu-kan.
Speaker 1: That's right bitches Right, so in the news we'll get right to it because the use there is.
Speaker 1: it isn't often that there's anime news We really feel like talking about or we care about in any stretch.
Speaker 1: I mean, we're not gonna tell you that some company licensed some show.
Speaker 1: That's just not what we do.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna tell you Oh OMG some you know movie got this many tickets sold.
Speaker 1: Ooh Yeah, and I don't even anime world order often has trouble finding interesting anime news.
Speaker 0: Lucas anime news just tends to be bland.
Speaker 1: Except oh this DVD came out Except when fans are involved.
Speaker 1: because you see you might all remember that before last year's.
Speaker 1: well this previous Otacon They made some changes to the artist alley rules and as a result the internet as a collective body Decided to go apeshit.
Speaker 0: At least the internet the part of the internet that cares about Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, the thing is anyone who wants to cause a ruckus on the internet can do it easily.
Speaker 1: I don't care if there's only two of you.
Speaker 1: if you're loud enough on the internet It can seem like thousands of people it can Go to enough websites.
Speaker 1: Yep, or just make them up enough noise or have enough shill accounts on dig.
Speaker 0: No shill accounts.
Speaker 1: But anyway The Otacon thing.
Speaker 1: long story short we covered this in great detail.
Speaker 1: We did a bunch of interviews everything about it.
Speaker 1: Otacon changes policy to Generally restrict, you know bootlegs or fan art that is blatantly violating copyrights in mass quantities things like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the rule used to be that if you manufactured plush Pikachu's you couldn't sell those because well, that's illegal.
Speaker 0: But if you drew a picture of Pikachu, that was cool.
Speaker 0: So they changed the rule to sort of not totally disallow you from selling a picture of Pikachu that you drew but To sort of discourage it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you can listen to our previous episodes about that to get the details, right?
Speaker 1: but suffice to say there were people who were disappointed with this change or who didn't understand it and as a result were very Indignant.
Speaker 1: and while they were it was a relatively small number of people.
Speaker 1: They did make a very large internet ruckus and That may have been justified except for the fact that the actual result of Otacon's rule change was that artist Ally carried on pretty much as usual and in fact, if anything the quality was improved.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd say the artist Ally definitely I mean the number one thing that was always wrong with that artist Ally anyway was a bad Arrangement of tables for inefficient space usage and they seem to have fixed that.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think it's pretty much as good as it can be in that regard.
Speaker 1: But the whole sky is falling.
Speaker 1: thing of the people who were complaining about Otacon's artist Ally.
Speaker 1: rules Really didn't come to pass and the artist Ally Almost everyone who went could do just about what they would have done anyway, and everything worked out really well.
Speaker 0: So some hot art.
Speaker 1: so I have some of that hot art sitting right over there waiting to be framed still.
Speaker 1: Oh god So it ended and the save artist Ally people went back into the woodwork.
Speaker 1: until now Katsu khan is coming up and they have made some changes to their artist Ally and the generally same group of people is Making almost the exact same ruckus with in fact the same live journal community.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's basically the same issue except that the rules changes are a little bit odd.
Speaker 1: So I guess we'll cover them a bit.
Speaker 1: but in terms of that the main argument here is the same as with Otacon that the people are mad about.
Speaker 1: you know Katsu khan changing the way they handle the artist Ally and making rules that Exclude what some of them like to do in the artist Ally.
Speaker 1: and the argument that they made When Otacon was coming was that the artist Ally is going to suck and no one is going to on a table.
Speaker 1: Yet the artist Ally at Otacon sold out.
Speaker 1: I don't know within a half a second.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the rules that they were originally angry about weren't the rules that ended up actually being the real rules at Otacon.
Speaker 0: so it's not really a An equivalent situation true.
Speaker 1: there was in fact a large Miscommunication on Otacon's part as to what the rules.
Speaker 0: it was sort of like someone coming up and saying hey if you cross this Street you go to jail for ten years what that's crazy.
Speaker 0: No, just kidding If you cross the street, then we just hit you on the head a little bit a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: so and that you know, it's like people yelled and screamed about the first thing but the second one they were like, all right
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I was reading through the various protests against Katsu khan on this and a lot of them look like the same people and if they're not the same people they write with the exact same style.
Speaker 1: almost every complaint I've seen is someone who starts off by either quoting or making up a quote about International copyright law or possibly the First Amendment Claiming that Katsu khan or as they did with Otacon is is being unfair or violating some human right that they have or Ruining their livelihood or going to ruin the artist alley.
Speaker 1: and then they go.
Speaker 1: then they go on to make some statement like Well, good luck with an empty artist alley.
Speaker 1: and I'll just note before we continue that despite these rules changes Katsu khan's artist alley is sold out as expected.
Speaker 0: Oh Well, look at that.
Speaker 1: So, huh?
Speaker 0: Well, was it sold out before the rule changes or after?
Speaker 0: how many of those people who bought a table knew the rules changes and Actually comprehended them?
Speaker 1: in their mind it the rules changes are pretty straightforward and from all the argument looks like most of the people arguing Didn't actually get a table anyway.
Speaker 0: Or maybe they just didn't buy one because they saw the rules and then decided not to.
Speaker 1: yeah But even if that's the case, it doesn't matter because there were enough people who despite the rules changes wanted a table.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but how many of those people actually read the rule changes and how many of them I can guarantee that all of them Because of the way Katsu khan handles artist alley now.
Speaker 0: really how did they handle it now?
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is we'll go over the rules changes first because part of that is how they handle the artist alley itself Because it isn't quite as clear-cut as caught as Otakon with their and be careful with fan art.
Speaker 1: Don't bootleg.
Speaker 1: The first rule they've added is that now this is really the big one.
Speaker 1: quote artist alley is intended for amateur artists working in a print paper medium.
Speaker 0: So what about the webcomic artists?
Speaker 0: They can't go to artist alley.
Speaker 1: I guess not.
Speaker 1: technically It is also intended for artists who make 3d renditions of their own art or 3d renditions of licensed anime characters.
Speaker 1: in that spirit Artists are required to use 75% or more of their table space for such art.
Speaker 1: So I guess geek nights could not have a table in the artist alley there.
Speaker 0: What about like a guy who sells cool t-shirts or something?
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: Can't do that.
Speaker 0: What if you like?
Speaker 0: you sew cool hats You do crafts.
Speaker 0: Crafts are no good.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: Anything like that has been.
Speaker 1: in fact, I remember last year at Katsucon there was an issue with someone who had a table in artist alley Who was selling chain mail and they either asked him to leave or disapproved of what he was doing.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the details.
Speaker 1: see since I was very drunk.
Speaker 0: that doesn't even anything to do with copyright or anything at all.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, it's not.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm saying that the Katsucon issue is a little bit different.
Speaker 1: They're not just changing the rules for copyright but they are definitely trying to shape the kinds of things that are in their artist alley and they're trying to at least in my Eyes make it distinct from other conventions.
Speaker 0: artist alleys Yeah, make it distinct.
Speaker 0: But also what people like about anime convention artist alleys is that they have these other things.
Speaker 0: those things make a lot of money A lot of.
Speaker 0: why would they get rid of those things?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they even if your artist alley still sells out, you know as a con you don't care.
Speaker 0: You know about not bringing in artist alley revenue that way but you might care about.
Speaker 0: you know People who come to cons who really enjoy artist alley might not enjoy your artist alley anymore though And then Katsucon will get a reputation for having a bad artist alley.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have cool stuff like chain mail and crafts and and all that other goodies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they definitely seem to want to encourage original art by original artist on paper and very little if anything else.
Speaker 0: Well, that's that's a go to a comic-con.
Speaker 0: if you want that this is an anime.
Speaker 1: Well, at least I mean in terms of a lot of the cool t-shirts.
Speaker 1: You see it a lot of cons in the artist alley tend to be ripoffs of licensed things and illegal and banned.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, but most of the cool t-shirts are that guy's a webcomic artist and those are his t-shirts.
Speaker 0: You know that that's where I see the cool ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I'm not sure but it does look like they really wouldn't allow Webcomic artists unless they were drawing stuff or just selling their own art and they weren't really promoting.
Speaker 0: What if I'm a webcomic artist like order the stick but now I have a book.
Speaker 0: is that okay?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: but it does say let's see that the artist alley reserves the right to refuse and turn away any artist selling solely Fabrics trinkets or other merchandise not appropriate for artist alley.
Speaker 1: Selling of commercial merchandise is prohibited.
Speaker 0: Well that that's a Given.
Speaker 1: but no, but they don't.
Speaker 1: if that's true then selling your own published book is commercial merchandise.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow You didn't think of that part.
Speaker 0: So what if you are An independent comic artist who self-publishes your own books?
Speaker 1: you can't sell your books there Technically according to what they've got written on the website.
Speaker 0: No, so isn't that sort of going against themselves?
Speaker 0: It's like we want this artist alley to be only for artists or you know amateurs working in the print medium But you can't actually sell their stuff.
Speaker 1: They also.
Speaker 1: artists may not solely display and sell fan art.
Speaker 1: It is strongly suggested that fan art should not make up more than 25% of your tablespace.
Speaker 1: Fan art and print should be kept to 20 copies or less.
Speaker 0: Well, at least they're not just saying no fan art.
Speaker 0: They're saying well they have.
Speaker 1: I mean if they actually said no fan art Which the thing is with the original Otacon thing?
Speaker 1: I would have been in a little bit up in arms too with the original rules where they actually Said they were going to ban fan art straight up and then when they clarified that that was not the case Everyone settled down except for the very very dedicated opponents.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it here I mean if there's an artist alley without fan art I I don't know if I'd care to even wander into it.
Speaker 1: I mean I see enough original art online as it is and I usually don't go to an anime con looking for original art.
Speaker 1: if anything I go to an anime con looking for new web comics to read and Cool art that probably is based on some sort of licensed property.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if you go to a comic-con, right?
Speaker 0: You know you you're not going around looking for new stuff.
Speaker 0: the people with new stuff are trying to hawk it on you.
Speaker 0: But you tend to avoid those people, you know all those guys are like.
Speaker 0: I like spider-man and I want to get spider-man art and Anyone that you walk up to at a comic-con no matter what the artist is.
Speaker 0: They'll draw you a spider-man Whatever, you know.
Speaker 0: So if you go to an anime con and you like them full metal alchemists and you can't get a full metal alchemist What that what kind of defeats the part?
Speaker 1: You know I can't get my picture of Roy and Al and link and Epona all kissing each other then this is not an anime con.
Speaker 0: I know it's.
Speaker 0: it's what.
Speaker 0: is it an independent art con?
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: It's an anime con.
Speaker 0: There should be anime and manga everywhere.
Speaker 0: That's what it's about.
Speaker 1: well that see that's what it traditionally is about, but it looks like they're definitely trying to Push the way the katsu kans artist alley is to make it different from other cons.
Speaker 1: I can't say if it'll be successful or not.
Speaker 1: We'll be there and we'll see it firsthand.
Speaker 1: now the other interesting part of this and this is what I was alluding to in the beginning in terms of enforcement a part of the process of getting an artist alley table is that you have to give them a list of All the items you plan to sell in the artist alley and then they personally approve or disapprove of you And if they approve you get a table.
Speaker 1: if they disapprove you don't.
Speaker 0: so they've already approved the whole artist so that's well.
Speaker 1: So everyone who is currently got a table in the artist alley is fully aware of the rules and unless they're lying on that Form in which case they're gonna be in for a load of trouble when they get to the con.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, huh?
Speaker 0: I think that's actually a pretty good idea.
Speaker 0: is that if they tell the con what they're selling before they get there or Actually like said a sampling of work to the con before they get there that way the con can arrange the artist alley in a Much more efficient fashion, you know with like goes with like.
Speaker 0: or possibly, you know Put don't put all the really popular things right next to each other to clog up the aisles, etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 0: That's a good thing.
Speaker 1: I think another interesting thing they're doing with the artist alley Now is that if you have a table you have to claim it by 9 p.m.
Speaker 1: On Friday or you lose it.
Speaker 0: No, that's that's cool cuz.
Speaker 0: a lot of people try to get those tables and they you know They buy it up for the whole weekend and they only sit there for like a few hours on Saturday And then someone else who couldn't get a table who would have sat there all weekend and really wanted to sell their stuff.
Speaker 0: You know, it's yeah, normally
Speaker 1: I would be against any sort of restriction like that But just due to the fact that Cons like Hobsicon and Otacon have such limited space as it is if you're not gonna use the table all weekend Then it will probably be better served in someone else's hands.
Speaker 0: Yeah If your demand for artists alley is bigger than your supply for of tables Then you have to have a rule like that just to make it fair.
Speaker 0: If your demand is not that high then having a rule like that is kind of annoying.
Speaker 1: I guess in the end these rules seem a little bit draconian But we'll have to actually go to katsucon to see how it turns out.
Speaker 1: Unless we get an interview with someone from katsucon or something.
Speaker 1: I think we'll just leave it at that for now and we'll report on it again after we go.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't sound good because at least Otacon, you know when the first rules came out Everyone was like that's not what the rules are gonna be and then it wasn't what the rules ended up being.
Speaker 0: this time It's like well, wow, there's the rules and they're crazy.
Speaker 0: So I don't know does not bode well Of course in the end.
Speaker 1: I'm not really worried because Katsucon is a not a con.
Speaker 1: I have gone to for the artist alley ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah I wasn't I had.
Speaker 0: no I've never been to katsucon yet But I did not imagine that it's artist alley would be among the greatest.
Speaker 1: I'll be perfectly honest in that Otacon really has the only artist alley I've ever been impressed by All right.
Speaker 1: I mean most most cons.
Speaker 1: we go to have a tiny artist alley like maybe 15 tables and often there's not much there or even worse.
Speaker 1: We went to a whole bunch of cons this summer and I saw the same group of people at all these cons Filling the artist alley like I'd already seen all this person's art and they're at every con I go to and that's that
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: and Otacon just is such an amazing artist alley.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't even bother really to go through them.
Speaker 0: I think it's.
Speaker 0: I think what it is Is that there are artists alley people who go to every artist alley.
Speaker 0: they can get into.
Speaker 0: that's close enough to their location.
Speaker 0: And then when you have a big con you see the artist alley people from places far away from where you are Because it's a bigger artist alley It's a bigger draw and you also get people who they're too good to show up at a tiny little artist alley.
Speaker 0: They only show up for the big ones.
Speaker 0: You know It's like if you had an artist alley big enough like that comic cat thing in Japan You could freaking get everyone in the whole country to show up.
Speaker 0: It's crazy Things of the day.
Speaker 1: Oh shit now I've been using a lot of videos lately and I got to say that this is one of my.
Speaker 0: you didn't use a video yesterday.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't but in general I've been using a lot of videos a lot of things on dig Or things that end up on dig in the time between when I find them and when I decide to use them.
Speaker 1: Today, however, I'm doing something very special.
Speaker 1: I found a video of Iron Man Acting stuff out in the real world.
Speaker 1: Iron Man is the man.
Speaker 0: Wait, you mean Iron Man the Marvel superhero.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh the underwear pervert.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Okay good cuz I hate that Iron Man.
Speaker 1: Not if why do you hate Iron Man?
Speaker 0: I just don't like Iron Man.
Speaker 1: What his power is just he's made of iron.
Speaker 0: No, he's not.
Speaker 0: He's a guy in an iron suit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so effectively the power is made of iron.
Speaker 0: No, I just don't like Iron Man.
Speaker 0: I never liked.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just never did.
Speaker 1: All right, I don't like spider-man.
Speaker 1: I'll be perfectly honest.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: But now I call it Iron Man only because that is the name of the video.
Speaker 1: It is in fact a man in a suit of armor that is probably made out of steel and not iron Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: now steel is part iron.
Speaker 1: It's not cold wrought iron that he is wearing.
Speaker 1: Yes Anyway I've been using a lot of practical jokes lately too.
Speaker 1: And I got to say that this is not as good as the Guy But it's up there.
Speaker 0: You mean the skeleton on the motorcycle?
Speaker 1: Yeah because they put this guy this little guy in his little suit of armor and you can't tell.
Speaker 1: there's a person in it and he Stands there in a museum like he's just some piece of armor on display.
Speaker 1: so people walk up and they're looking at him one guy's filming him and he moves a little bit and the guy like he's sitting there looking through the camera and he backs up and has this puzzle look and he takes the camera away and he's like looking At the thing and looking in the camera and it's not moving now and he's trying to figure out.
Speaker 1: he thinks he's going insane And then it moves again and he about loses it runs out of the room.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good and of course, there's always the one person who goes ha ha ha ha ha ha.
Speaker 0: You fooled me instead of running away like I was.
Speaker 1: But what makes it funny for me is the way the guy in the armor moves because he must not know how to wear armor Very well, and also the armor is probably not very comfortable because he moves very oddly.
Speaker 1: And I think a video of a guy that guy walking around in that armor would be almost as funny as the practical joke itself.
Speaker 0: I think you might be correct.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: Okay, I actually do a lot of research About this thing today because I couldn't comprehend it when I read the original story.
Speaker 0: So, you know Second Life, right?
Speaker 1: I'm aware of it.
Speaker 0: Okay, Second Life is sort of like an MMO except there's no actual game.
Speaker 0: It's just this big world that you walk around in and do almost whatever you want.
Speaker 1: If you ever read The Escapist, you might be under the impression that everyone in the world But you play Second Life and it's the best game ever made.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, yes Second Life you make an avatar you walk around you talk to people.
Speaker 0: you do things.
Speaker 0: now in Second Life Some things you want to do usually getting land or getting objects from other people requires money called Linden dollars.
Speaker 0: To get Linden dollars you give the company that runs Second Life your real dollars.
Speaker 0: They convert it and I think this is an exchange rate.
Speaker 0: But I know the exchange rate is to Linden dollars and then you can use those Linden dollars in the game to do stuff.
Speaker 0: You can also convert Linden dollars back into real money.
Speaker 0: So if you do things in Second Life and people give you their Linden dollars You can turn those into real dollars and you could run a business as in Second Life.
Speaker 0: And that's basically how Second Life the company You know the that runs it makes.
Speaker 0: Linden Labs makes their money is because they don't have to create game Content because they basically hire you to do it.
Speaker 0: and the more game content you create The more other players will give you Linden dollars and then the more regular dollars you get.
Speaker 1: I really like the concept of Second Life.
Speaker 1: It's just the game itself doesn't look like I would find it interesting.
Speaker 0: I've never actually gone into it.
Speaker 0: I've seen I've seen screenshots and I read about it on the internet.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there is a person in the game.
Speaker 0: They are known as Anshay Chung and apparently they're famous and they run.
Speaker 0: their avatar was on the cover of Newsweek and stuff.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: I didn't know about this.
Speaker 0: The real name of this person is Aylin Grafe.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I said that right.
Speaker 0: I don't even know if I said the name of their avatar, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll preachy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this person started with ten bucks in Linden dollars.
Speaker 0: Well, originally they had a business, you know farming in games like Asheron's Call.
Speaker 0: Then they went into Second Life and they bought ten dollars worth of Linden dollars and they started selling shit in Second Life.
Speaker 0: And now this person has a million dollars real dollars Wow from doing Second Life business.
Speaker 0: Basically, they were just really opportunistic and like when there was a new game feature I think the game feature they mentioned was like your characters able to do like different poses and like, you know movements.
Speaker 0: They started selling people like all these custom movements as soon as that became a new feature And thus they were able to make a lot of money anyway.
Speaker 0: in Second Life This famous Second Life millionaire was going to do an interview with CNET.
Speaker 0: in Second Life The CNET reporter was was Greeter Dan Godell, whatever.
Speaker 0: now Here's where the thing of the day comes in.
Speaker 0: they go to this, you know in Second Life There's some building the CNET building and the CNET guy shows up, you know.
Speaker 0: and then people show up to listen to this interview and then the famous person shows up and then lo and behold I Can't count them.
Speaker 0: hundreds maybe thousands of rubber phalluses Are.
Speaker 0: just just look at these.
Speaker 0: look at these.
Speaker 0: good God It's just they just start raining from the sky at this interview.
Speaker 1: What is this?
Speaker 1: It's like Dominion tank police when they release the ultimate weapon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so The famous person runs away.
Speaker 0: the CNET guy can't keep it under control.
Speaker 0: And before you know it there are these two monsters like literally monsters sitting in the interview chairs And it's basically some group called room 101 that goes around.
Speaker 0: This is the equivalent of griefing in Second Life because you can't grief really in a game where you can't.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: There's no fighting or anything, you know, but this is griefing.
Speaker 0: Someone was trying to do an interview in Second Life and you ruined it by filling the room with penises.
Speaker 1: now I think my opinion of this is that it is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean in other MMOs.
Speaker 0: while I think playing a lot of those standard MMOs is dumb in the first place Griefing is even more dumb and a game designed in such a way that allows griefing to even happen is bad design.
Speaker 0: However, this isn't really a game.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of this virtual world.
Speaker 0: So anything that increases entropy in a humorous way, especially humorous for people who aren't playing is awesome.
Speaker 0: The best thing to ever come out of World of Warcraft was Leroy Jenkins And as far as I'm concerned the best thing to ever come out of Second Life was a rain of penises.
Speaker 1: Well The evidence just keeps stacking up Scott.
Speaker 0: It sure does.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I think the issue there is simply that a lot of other MMOs You can do things in game or you can do things by coordinating out of game That the game designers decide they don't want you doing even though the game allows you to do it.
Speaker 1: So they'll punish you in game or out of game for the things you've done.
Speaker 1: Second Life doesn't really do that so much.
Speaker 1: the system works internal to itself.
Speaker 1: If you cause trouble people do things to you and your reputation gets hurt in a real way.
Speaker 1: and the actual people running the game Don't seem to take external punitive action on any regular basis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't seem like these guys got in trouble or anything About over what they've done.
Speaker 1: I mean if anything seen that just needs better security.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got it.
Speaker 0: If you have a building in Second Life and you're doing stuff in it and you don't want Penises to come flying at you.
Speaker 0: You better build big walls on it Which might cost you some extra linen dollars.
Speaker 0: for you know, the penis eliminator Some sort of penis screen, you know if they were really cool What they could have done is you can just make stuff in Second Life, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know enough about it But I imagine you know from what I've been told you just make stuff.
Speaker 0: so I would have had you know If someone attacked me with penises, I would just sit down and code and model an anti penis automatic turret and And then I would just start popping them out.
Speaker 1: This is an arms race with dangerous dangerous Possibilities I know but think about it.
Speaker 1: you were thinking that you will design a device your sole purpose to seek out and destroy penises Mm-hmm, except my own, okay Okay Don't ever try to do that in the real world.
Speaker 1: Oh bad idea, even if someone makes some sort of penis replicator and starts filling houses with them All right, all right, so this week we haven't really talked about specific.
Speaker 0: we didn't talk about a specific game yesterday.
Speaker 0: We didn't really talk about specific technology on Monday.
Speaker 0: We'd sort of had topics that were more general.
Speaker 0: So today we're not gonna talk about an anime a manga or a comic.
Speaker 0: we're gonna talk about dubs in general.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not gonna talk about specific studios.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna talk much about specific examples.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna talk about specific voice actors or anything.
Speaker 1: We're just the idea of dubs and how they affect us and how we feel about them.
Speaker 0: Well for anyone who might be completely stupid a dub is when you take a show that is in.
Speaker 0: well Technically a dub is when you have some video and you put audio on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when you're talking about anime you're talking about Hey, the original audio for this TV show was Japanese people talking.
Speaker 0: We're gonna erase the Japanese talking and put in English talking and we need to get some English-speaking people to do that talking.
Speaker 0: And that is a dove.
Speaker 1: now all factors aside Probably the most annoying thing when it comes to dubs is simply the fact that among the anime community There's this whole dubs versus subs like made-up war.
Speaker 0: I mean, I didn't even realize that this war was going on.
Speaker 0: I mean when I was in my first discovered anime, you know And I knew it was anime and like high school or whatever.
Speaker 0: I was watching on sci-fi channel Everything was dubbed, you know.
Speaker 0: And I knew intellectually on some level that this was a Japanese thing.
Speaker 0: And if I would have thought about it for a minute, I would have said hey, wait a minute That's not the original voices.
Speaker 0: There must have been Japanese voices something something.
Speaker 0: but that never actually occurred to me.
Speaker 0: I just kind of accepted the dub track and didn't think about it until I went to college Where it was apparently a big issue that was forced upon me.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean when we ran the RIT anime club Like we showed subs as a matter of course partly because attached to RIT is the National Technical Institute for the Deaf.
Speaker 1: So as kind of a way to be nice, we just always showed subtitled anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could have showed the anime with an English dub and also the subtitles or closed captioning.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but it was easier to just show a sub.
Speaker 1: So yeah by doing that we accommodated the deaf community and we actually had a good number of deaf members of the club and everyone Was happy.
Speaker 0: it was basically before DVDs.
Speaker 0: It was extremely more convenient because you couldn't really get the closed captioning to work So well.
Speaker 0: with the VHS God and the subtitled VHS you had a Japanese audio track.
Speaker 0: when the DVDs came around We had more options, but it didn't care.
Speaker 1: Well, see here's the problem.
Speaker 1: So once DVDs came around we want to show a DVD.
Speaker 1: Several times we decided hey, this is a good dub Why don't we just show it dubbed?
Speaker 1: and the club would immediately split into equal and angry portions.
Speaker 1: One half would demand that we show the dub because they hated reading subtitles and couldn't keep up with them and the other half Refused to come if we showed a dub because they think that all dubs are terrible and they have some sort of Ideological aversion to dubbed anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, we stayed with the status quo because of the sub because that's what we had.
Speaker 0: not always.
Speaker 0: we showed it did a couple of Times.
Speaker 0: yeah Not often though and
Speaker 1: I will note that the reason this whole thing is stupid these people who care so much about this Was simply that one time we were gonna show Hellsing and we decided that we were gonna show it dubbed and People bitched and bitched and bitched when we announced it the day of like.
Speaker 1: we're about to show Hellsing like by the way It's gonna be dubbed.
Speaker 1: then the lights turn off and there's not for art.
Speaker 1: Everyone's yelling back and forth and people like well, I'm just gonna leave.
Speaker 1: This is crap.
Speaker 1: I don't want to watch some stupid dub and they all stayed anyway And they all watch the show and at the end a lot of people noted that the dub was pretty good And they enjoyed it and after about 30 seconds worth of watching the show after the opener ended.
Speaker 1: They stopped complaining entirely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean before I got there to college.
Speaker 0: Like I said, it was a non-issue that as soon as I got there It was the biggest issue in the universe, you know People made all those usual arguments in favor of subtitles like ah, it's not the original you're losing so much.
Speaker 0: It's not You've destroyed the work of art.
Speaker 0: It's now something else Not what the original was.
Speaker 0: and you know, the voice acting is always terrible blabbity blabbity blah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't look at the characters and what's going on if you're always looking at subtitles.
Speaker 0: But all those arguments don't seem to matter now.
Speaker 0: So I it kind of weird to think back that they mattered then and now.
Speaker 1: who cares well see to me I hate to say it but well early on I mean dubs and subs.
Speaker 1: my Relationship with them has changed a lot over the years.
Speaker 1: when it started when I first watched anime I only saw dubs and then I started getting anime and I got a lot of subs for various reasons.
Speaker 1: and I had trouble watching the subs early on because the Japanese language and the way it's spoken is not like English.
Speaker 1: So you couldn't really glean a lot of the emotional content.
Speaker 1: I didn't know what sarcasm sounded like in Japanese or the difference between someone who's happy or someone who's faking being happy or anything like that and The language.
Speaker 1: you sounded strange and alien and foreign to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is true.
Speaker 0: I remember like the first one or two times I watched a sub.
Speaker 0: it was kind of just weird and novel in itself to hear So much Japanese being spoken more than I'd ever heard at one time before.
Speaker 0: but eventually it was just oh All right, I could just do it and now I still can just watch him.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is then as I watch more and more subs I started to get it.
Speaker 1: I mean, obviously I didn't learn the language.
Speaker 1: I still don't know the language but you start to.
Speaker 1: if you watch enough Subtitled media now not just anime but anything subtitled in a specific language Even if you never learn the language other than random words, you'll start to pick up on general emotional cues or just all the things that all the subtext and all the things that let you understand the Subtle nature of the language without knowing the actual details of what's being said.
Speaker 1: so you can watch an anime in Japanese with subtitles But yet you get all of that Sarcasm.
Speaker 1: I just keep using sarcasm as an example.
Speaker 1: Yeah because you've listened to enough of it to be able to pick those things out.
Speaker 1: you get a sense of the language and I think A lot of people who are opposed to watching subtitled things just haven't watched enough subtitled things.
Speaker 0: That is something else that before I had ever watched a subtitled show Well, at least the subtitle anime had watched plenty of subtitled things, you know I didn't really you know prefer either way.
Speaker 0: then after I watched a bunch of subtitled things and I was able to you know Get the full subtitled effect.
Speaker 0: then when I watched a dub I freakin noticed how it was different.
Speaker 0: it was like oh, oh Yeah, it's like a problem that doesn't expose itself until you've seen the solution elsewhere.
Speaker 1: Plus there was the issue back in the day that isn't a matter now where dubs cost less than subs on VHS simply because they knew
Speaker 0: that
Speaker 1: people who wanted a sub would pay the extra money no matter what because they didn't want to listen To the dub and people who didn't care we're gonna buy the dub anyway.
Speaker 1: So they basically just extorted extra money out of the fans who wanted a subtitled version.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they also printed a lot fewer subtitled VHS tapes.
Speaker 1: so lower supply higher price even though at the local Suncoast where I bought much of my anime back in the day Way back in the day.
Speaker 1: They had almost all subtitled anime and the only dub they had was Ranma.
Speaker 0: Well, that was a Suncoast.
Speaker 0: if you went to I don't know somewhere else there wasn't anywhere else.
Speaker 1: there was blockbuster where I could watch Armageddon and Do Megalopolis over and over again if I wanted.
Speaker 0: yeah, we didn't even have a Suncoast.
Speaker 1: really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was where I bought all my anime even though I remember paying like a hundred and eighty bucks for a VHS subtitled box set.
Speaker 0: And I didn't even realize anime could be bought legally in a store until like freshman year Because I never bought any of it.
Speaker 0: and then someone had like a Trigun DVD and I was like, that's a DVD It's not a like a tape from Japan or anything.
Speaker 0: Hold I could just buy that at the media play.
Speaker 1: Holy shit It was amazing that I remember buying Tenchi Muyo the original OAV.
Speaker 1: Half of them were subs and half of them were dubs just because.
Speaker 1: and I bought him over the course of months because I couldn't Afford to buy it all at once because it was like 30 bucks of tape.
Speaker 1: Well, but yeah I mean when I first saw anime and dubs seemed like vampire hunter.
Speaker 1: D was awesome and I didn't even think about it and I watched subs and I realized that the subs seemed to be a lot better and the More I started to get the nuances the Japanese language the more I like the subs mostly because the the sad fact Is that most dubs are actually really piss-poor?
Speaker 0: Well, you know a lot of people say this and it's absolutely true is that you can be in another room and you can just be listening to whatever is on the television and it within.
Speaker 0: you don't even have to hear a single word and you can tell if That's an anime dub on in the other room.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We've tried this.
Speaker 1: we've tested this in numerous.
Speaker 0: okay, like you could just have someone like with a bunch of like five second mp3s and one of them contains like Godzilla.
Speaker 0: one of them contains who knows and you just play one of them and Someone will say anime dub not anime dub.
Speaker 0: anime dub not anime dub.
Speaker 0: They have this distinct sound to them.
Speaker 0: That's I Don't know.
Speaker 0: It's generally unpleasant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but seems to carry across to a lot of cartoons, too.
Speaker 1: I mean in general you can always tell between Cartoon live-action without seeing the screen.
Speaker 1: Mmm with the possible exception of cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah But that's the thing is that dubbing doesn't have to be bad.
Speaker 0: I mean it usually is worse than subtitles in most cases But it doesn't have to be.
Speaker 0: it's very possible for dubs to be as good as or better than the original Japanese audio track because a lot of times Japanese has shitty voice actors too in the original so you can beat them out with Yeah, better English voice act.
Speaker 1: I mean it might be do partly or possibly wholly to nostalgia But I have watched eros a otzara to beautiful dreamer Probably 20 times in my life if not more.
Speaker 1: it's my favorite movie hands down and despite that I I've seen it subbed and dubbed but I prefer the dub to this day Despite known Inaccuracies in it.
Speaker 1: there are absolute inaccuracies that I've noticed that I have researched and that I just I don't worry about Because I think the dub is hilarious and I find the some of the voice acting on the sub to be annoying.
Speaker 1: and this is Even now after I've gotten enough of an ear to kind of know what good Japanese voice acting sounds like.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that has it.
Speaker 0: that is a lot due to nostalgia.
Speaker 0: I mean on the weekly anime review he played a short clip from the old Akira dub, right?
Speaker 0: Oh Right.
Speaker 0: So the really old Akira dub not the newer one because there are two Akira dubs And I listened to it and it was like this sledgehammer.
Speaker 0: That was half Nostalgia and half good God.
Speaker 0: is that terrible?
Speaker 1: It's like watching Robotech again.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, it's like well Robotech's night.
Speaker 0: It's like watching he-man.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, there's he-man.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's bad You know and it's like I had this strong feeling for it combined with a strong feeling against it.
Speaker 0: But it's a part of me god damn it and it's pretty terrible.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't want to give any disrespect to American anime voice actors But I just don't understand how dubs can be the way they are.
Speaker 1: It seems like they go through Errors were like if you listen to anime back in the day like Slayer like the era when slayers was really popular in the u.s.
Speaker 1: All the dubs kind of sound the same.
Speaker 1: and now listen to anime today all the dubs kind of sound the same But they don't sound the same as the dubs from before.
Speaker 1: in fact I'd say that a lot of them are in some ways worse.
Speaker 0: Well, I think actually I give the voice actors credit because and I'm not gonna go into great detail on how the dubs are Made and all that jazz, but yeah, I got a rant about how dubs are made.
Speaker 0: I get the impression that a lot some of the dubs they do put a lot of time and effort into and they spend a Lot of money to make sure they're awesome, but most of them they try to hack them out.
Speaker 0: You know just do a serviceable job and back in the day when they would do that for martial arts movies You would get what you would expect something.
Speaker 0: What are you doing?
Speaker 0: Oh?
Speaker 0: You would get you know go out your Bruce Lee movies original dub.
Speaker 0: It's just ass.
Speaker 0: It's it's completely useless.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I think what's actually going on is that most and you know not the big-time anime But most of the anime they're putting as much time and effort and money into the dubs as they did into those bad Bruce Lee Dubs.
Speaker 0: yet the product while still not satisfactory to us fans To us crazy fans You know it's a lot better than what you would normally get putting in that amount of time and effort and work.
Speaker 0: So I do think that they are.
Speaker 0: you know they're doing the best job that they can under the circumstances.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I don't think it's the voice actors fault.
Speaker 1: I think that it's the direction that they get and to an extent sometimes the writing done by the translators.
Speaker 0: Well, and it's also the anime companies for not trying to make their dubs awesome.
Speaker 0: They're just trying to get the dub done like it's their job instead of trying to do good art On the dub you know trying to make a good one And I think a lot of it would have to do though things are.
Speaker 1: I hope things are changing But a lot of older dubs.
Speaker 1: I know in America The philosophy was totally different and in Japan a lot of times They were dubbing a show.
Speaker 1: they'd have a whole bunch of people like all the actors from a scene in One room or in saw just doing all the acting playing off of each other in real time and record the whole thing in one Shot.
Speaker 1: where in America a lot of times they would tend to record each individual voice actors lines by themselves.
Speaker 1: they'd basically be playing off of nothing or off of the recording that the other person already made.
Speaker 1: and Because it seems like a lot of dubs in America either Lack energy entirely like there's no energy or flow to them or they have this super like tacked on fake energy.
Speaker 1: That gets to the point.
Speaker 1: We're just so annoying.
Speaker 1: I can't listen to it.
Speaker 0: The emotions definitely aren't natural and they don't seem to match up between Characters and scenes.
Speaker 1: very well also, and I say this to this day, and I'm not sure I mean I'd have to I couldn't come up with a lot of examples.
Speaker 1: But it seems like there are things or concepts that you can put forth or get across or say in Japanese.
Speaker 1: That don't sound cheesy in Japanese because it's the kind of thing people would say.
Speaker 1: but yet if you say those things Translated literally into English or not even literally But even just the meaning behind them to our American Western ears They sound really lame or cheesy because people just don't say things like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is actually more of an issue in manga adaptations, but it's still an issue in Anime, is that?
Speaker 0: well big complaint of dubs?
Speaker 0: I remember from freshman year when they you know all those crazy sub Nazis.
Speaker 0: they would say Oh the dub isn't the original meaning they change it.
Speaker 0: It's not what was?
Speaker 0: you know, you're losing something Not a direct translation and then you know it.
Speaker 0: later I realized wait a minute you can't directly translate.
Speaker 0: It's not possible.
Speaker 0: Sometimes, you know if they tell some Japanese, you know.
Speaker 0: And like.
Speaker 0: if someone says in America like, you know, a bird in the hand is worth two in the bush How do you translate the jet?
Speaker 0: That's a Japanese?
Speaker 1: Well, you say a bird in the hand is worth two in the bush.
Speaker 1: you translated literally no one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they might not understand what the hell does that mean?
Speaker 0: You have to come up with the equivalent Japanese, you know thing It's sort of like or you leave it in and let people learn about it.
Speaker 0: It depends on the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does like irresponsible captain Tyler.
Speaker 1: You could not do that because those puns were just out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like as among a dial.
Speaker 0: It's kind of way out there and actually I was among it as a good example for this whole thing.
Speaker 0: because in that show You could go on either road.
Speaker 0: You could either choose to leave everything in there literally and then use the show to teach the American audience about all this weird Japanese puns and jokes and you know all this like monzai comedy stuff going on or you could take it out and You know just translate it into something that makes sense in English and either way it works.
Speaker 0: It's just a decision you have to make in the beginning.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean, I guess if if a dub is done well, like if a show is dubbed really well It's done.
Speaker 1: Well, then I consider the sub and dub to be equal because there are two very different things.
Speaker 1: now the sub is the original Japanese voice acting with a very literal translation of what they're saying underneath because the subtitle now if you're subtitling something doesn't need to be Eloquent spoken it just needs to convey all the information that the person is saying.
Speaker 1: so you can have a very novelized style very literal very direct translation of what they're saying.
Speaker 1: and Even if the phrasing is a little awkward It doesn't matter because you're reading it while you listen to them talk.
Speaker 1: But in a dub, they definitely have to change it a lot more to make it come across naturally But they also.
Speaker 0: another thing dubs all seem to do is they they seem more concerned with matching the characters lips.
Speaker 0: Then I think they should be.
Speaker 1: yeah I remember I saw a thing a long time ago.
Speaker 1: someone demonstrated at some con and it was actually.
Speaker 1: no I wasn't Ohio con it was might have been a concert kind of wasn't that?
Speaker 1: I don't know when it was But I remember seeing a little short clip where it showed a dub and a sub and how the dub matched the voice Perfect like the lips perfectly.
Speaker 1: the person talking everything they said.
Speaker 1: every syllable matched what the mouth was doing in the anime but yet in the Japanese original it didn't match at all and the person kept talking for a full second after the Person's mouth stopped moving.
Speaker 1: and you know what.
Speaker 1: they were both fine.
Speaker 1: So why bother trying to match it up if it doesn't even matter?
Speaker 0: that is one thing I think that could be fixed with a lot of American dubs of anime right now.
Speaker 0: is they do seem even when it's not Like a big-time production dub like I don't know cowboy bebop or ghost in the shell or anything like that when it's a smaller show and they're obviously not Spending a whole lot of time and money on this dub.
Speaker 0: They still try really hard to match those lips and they seem to make you know Sacrifices in other areas in order to achieve that and that's really not the thing you have to concentrate on the most.
Speaker 0: you should concentrate On having the dialogue be better to make the show as good as you possibly can and making the characters sound.
Speaker 1: Hmm, right Oh going back of it I just thought of a perfect example for my thing I was saying about awkward phrases or things that don't sound right to our Western ears.
Speaker 1: You know what a lot of times in anime someone will say something that translates to do your best.
Speaker 1: No one says that here.
Speaker 1: no one would ever yell that to anyone.
Speaker 1: they'd yell something like good luck Or don't go go.
Speaker 1: Whoo Exactly, but what do you do now?
Speaker 1: If you translate it literally then it sounds lame.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not lame the meanings there But it sounds lame if you translate it in a creative way.
Speaker 1: the fans get mad because it wasn't a literal translation Mm-hmm, and they claim that you lose something when really Depending on the situation you don't lose anything.
Speaker 0: You don't lose anything as long as the writing is good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the voice acting is good yep, but anyway part of the reason we did this show was that we didn't feel like reviewing anything and We're tired and the holidays are coming up.
Speaker 1: So I don't know what you can expect us to talk about tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I Don't freaking know at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm going to bed.
Speaker 1: I will say one last thing and we're gonna.
Speaker 1: we're plugging this all week.
Speaker 1: If you were not a member of dig
Speaker 0: I recommend that
Speaker 1: you become a member of dig dig.com
Speaker 0: two G's
Speaker 1: you'll be pleasantly surprised because dig is quite awesome and to dig podcast has been unveiled very recently and It is leaps and bounds better than any other podcast directory known to man with a possible exception of iTunes.
Speaker 1: But iTunes has its own issues.
Speaker 0: You're using some podcast directory like Yahoo podcasts or plug D or Podcast pickle podcast alley any any weird podcast directory.
Speaker 0: stop using that shit and use dig podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean dig podcast is awesome podcast alley and all that.
Speaker 1: Do you really want us to tell you every couple of weeks to go there and vote for us when if you go to dig You vote for a podcast you like once once ever your vote lasts forever.
Speaker 1: So you don't have to be annoying and ask people to vote for you constantly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's not like we ask people to vote for us.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah.
Speaker 1: However, if you are a dig user and you like geek nights if you go and dig us It is only going to make us more popular.
Speaker 1: We're already number one on dig if you search for anime or video game or not video games.
Speaker 0: But anime or manga or comic don't feel obligated to do this because you're not.
Speaker 0: but whatever I'm just letting you know, it's there.
Speaker 0: We also have a botnet.
Speaker 0: if If you want to you know, make a hundred accounts and spam dig and and dig You can totally join our botnet or you know, it's open.
Speaker 1: what Scott means by botnet Is that all the people in our forums which are actually very rocking and I highly recommend you check them out Have decided to all make each other friends.
Speaker 1: indeed and as a result Geek nights and the front row crew and all of the cool people associated there in by all being friends Officially like as per the code within dig Tend to dig each other's things up and it's getting to be where anything that anyone in our forums likes Gets a gigantic boost on dig.
Speaker 1: So if you like geek nights and you join our forums and you join this collective dig body You will have more of an influence on to internet unless you're lame and then no one will dig the things For the green flags with the star.
Speaker 0: Yes, and then let your mouse hover over them for a second So you can see who dug it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I will also note that some of our overzealous listeners seem to be going through the motions of digging every single episode of our show.
Speaker 1: Okay I'll just ask you if you're gonna dig individual episodes of geek nights.
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say you shouldn't but only dig the ones that you think are above average are particularly good.
Speaker 1: Because if something someone digs every episode of geek nights, then that really defeats the purpose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever I don't care what the hell people do.
Speaker 0: I just use dig podcast so that we can get all these other podcast directories out of business because they're useless and they're terrible and They suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then phase two is putting all these other podcasts out of business And then we're the only podcast in the world No one will care about podcasts anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah after the nuclear holocaust when the dinosaurs come back Fucking dinosaurs, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.