Speaker 0: *sings along to the song*.
Speaker 0: Alright, that's enough of that.
Speaker 0: It's Thursday, May 25th, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, the Scott Only Show featuring user feedback and a bunch of meta bits.
Speaker 0: Alright, so if you didn't notice... Oh wait.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do this.
Speaker 0: Alright, if you didn't notice, I'm alone.
Speaker 0: "Rim went to an amazement, and I'm sure he will absolve himself of all responsibility for this
Speaker 0: show.".
Speaker 0: So, I'm just gonna say that so he doesn't have to.
Speaker 0: Also, um, it's really hard to do a show all alone.
Speaker 0: You don't have anyone else filling in the gaps when you don't have anything to say.
Speaker 0: You don't have anyone to, you know, respond to the things you say and thus start a dialogue.
Speaker 0: So bear with me and bear with the horrible audio quality.
Speaker 0: I'm recording this with my Logitech headset that I usually use for gaming, plugged into a laptop, sitting on my desk with audacity.
Speaker 0: And I'm not gonna edit it very much.
Speaker 0: So, I'm gonna try to keep this short and as pleasant as possible.
Speaker 0: And hopefully it will be somewhat entertaining and not a complete waste of your time to listen to.
Speaker 0: If you're already feeling pain, just stop listening now, pretend this episode doesn't exist, and listen again next Monday when we'll come back with real shows.
Speaker 0: This is a crap filler, but guess what, it's better than nothing.
Speaker 0: Better to have a, you know, if you're doing a webcomic, better to have some crap sketchup when you fail to make a comic than to have nothing.
Speaker 0: So, this is that crap sketch.
Speaker 0: I'm sure someone out there will enjoy it, even though most people will ignore it, but that's just fine.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's see, what's in the news today?
Speaker 0: Oh, so Microsoft came out with this new image format called, to compete with JPEG, called WMP for Windows Media Photo.
Speaker 0: And pretty much what they're trying to do is replace JPEG.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's gonna do so well.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's like, they tried to replace the MP3 with all kinds of formats, like AAC and WMA, and none of those managed to kick that out.
Speaker 0: No, I really don't think anyone in the world, even people who aren't open source zealots, no one is going to opt to use some closed, difficult to use format that only works on some devices, when, by default, every freaking digital camera in the universe, you know, pops JPEGs off of itself, and every freaking image software in the universe, you know, uses JPEGs and supports them fully, when Windows Media Photo will, I guess, not be fully supported by everything.
Speaker 0: I guess, you know, there are, it's true what they do say, that, you know, photographers don't like JPEG because it has all sorts of artifacts, and Windows Media Photo will supposedly have better pictures in smaller image files with less artifacting.
Speaker 0: But, you know what, if people want serious photos and such, they don't have to use JPEG.
Speaker 0: There are other formats like PNG and TIFF and, you know, even Bitmap that allow you to do lossless or near lossless image storage without screwing around with some new bullshit Microsoft thing that no one in the world uses.
Speaker 0: Plus, the reason JPEG is so popular is that it works just fine on web pages.
Speaker 0: I mean, Firefox doesn't support Windows Media Photo, and what if Microsoft, you know, is Microsoft just going to let Firefox make, or, and Opera and Conquerer and Safari just support Windows Media Photo, here's the code, to render these images, or are they going to require that Firefox pays a license fee to Microsoft if they want, you know, to make these images display in web pages.
Speaker 0: And if that's the case, no one's going to freakin' pay the license fee, and Windows Media Photo will bomb, even if it's technically superior in compression and image quality.
Speaker 0: This is just another attempt by, you know, Microsoft, which has consistently made profits with proprietary file formats, Adobe also, to go back to that old business model, now that their operating system web browser monopoly isn't really holding up as well as it used to, an Office monopoly also.
Speaker 0: So, we'll see what comes of that.
Speaker 0: My prediction is Windows Media Photo will do no better than Windows Media Audio is currently doing, and people who are super Windows users will use it for their personal photos, but if web browsers and sites like Flickr never support it, it'll never take off, and it'll just be one of those, you know, proprietary file formats no one cares about, except for the people who use it personally.
Speaker 0: Do, do, do, do, do, do, do, do.
Speaker 0: Alright, things of the day.
Speaker 0: I have a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Apparently, in Britain, there are stores that have lots of teens loitering outside the store.
Speaker 0: I guess if you're a store owner, that can be a problem, especially if these are, you know, dangerous-looking or scruffy-looking teens, 'cause normal people will be afraid to walk into your store, you know, or kids will block your window display, which attracts customers.
Speaker 0: And, you know, loitering's generally unpleasant if it's outside your store.
Speaker 0: If it's outside someone else's store, who cares?
Speaker 0: So what they've done is they've made this, they bought this device, some company is selling it, that produces sound that is at such a high frequency that people can't hear it, except people under 20.
Speaker 0: Most people over the age of 20 cannot hear the noise, but most people under 20 can hear the noise.
Speaker 0: So if you're a 40-year-old store owner, you put this thing outside your store, and all the teens standing outside your store have, like, this really annoying ringing in their ear, like, "Ow, ow,
Speaker 0: ow!".
Speaker 0: And you don't care, you're a 40-year-old guy who can't hear it.
Speaker 0: So you're all good.
Speaker 0: What's happened is that the teens have taken this noise and recorded it.
Speaker 0: And with that recording, they have created cell phone rings.
Speaker 0: Now, if you have a cell phone in your high school or your college or whatever, or your middle school even, and, you know, you have it on vibrate or ring, the teacher is going to hear when you vibrate or ring it.
Speaker 0: But if you use this mosquito noise, only the punk kids can hear it.
Speaker 0: So now, kids in Britain all have cell phones that ring, and only the kids in the class can hear it, and the teacher can't.
Speaker 0: So kids are texting each other back and forth in class now, and there's no way for the teacher to know.
Speaker 0: I say, "Way to go, awesome hacker
Speaker 0: kids!".
Speaker 0: And the teachers say, "Goddamn
Speaker 0: "Oh, well, you try to use technology to keep the kids down, and the kids use the same technology to fight back, you get what you
Speaker 0: deserve.".
Speaker 0: So this is just super awesome.
Speaker 0: I hope more things like this happen in the future.
Speaker 0: It's always pleasant.
Speaker 0: Okay, today's show is going to be about me reading emails we've received and some things from the forum also that I think might be interesting, if I find any that I want to talk about.
Speaker 0: And then I'm going to go over some meta bits.
Speaker 0: So let's read the first email.
Speaker 0: I'm going to go from the most recently received email to the less recently received emails, and stop when they start to get out of date or boring.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to read the entire emails unless they're short, but I'll give you the basic gist of what they say, and I'll reply.
Speaker 0: Other shows, other podcasts I've listened to have done this sort of thing in the past, and we haven't, so I think we're due.
Speaker 0: We do get, you know, we don't get a pile of emails like I'd like to, you know, more than I can handle, like other people seem to get.
Speaker 0: But we do get plenty of emails, and we don't seem to respond to a lot of them on the air.
Speaker 0: So here we go.
Speaker 0: Most recent email is from Daryl at Anime World Order.
Speaker 0: I listen to his show.
Speaker 0: Those are the guys who know a shit ton about anime.
Speaker 0: And it seems like every time we do an anime show, he comes and emails us and tells us how we're wrong and all that.
Speaker 0: He's talking about our show where we did the worst anime ever a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 0: He says he wants to keep the emails short.
Speaker 0: I guess he kinda succeeded.
Speaker 0: It's shorter than his previous emails.
Speaker 0: You know, he talks about how some shows are MST3K bad, and some are actual bad bad.
Speaker 0: The interesting part here is he talks about three shows that he calls the "Manga Video Holy Trinity of
Speaker 0: Suck."
Speaker 0: And these are shows that we never heard of, and he says they blow stuff like Lemniar out of the water.
Speaker 0: And these are shows "Violence Jack," "Angel Cop," and "Mad
Speaker 0: Bull.".
Speaker 0: And knowing the stuff that "Manga Video" put out back in the day, where the best of it was stuff like... I guess they kinda had Akira out, so they're not counting that.
Speaker 0: They put out like "Ninja Scroll" was one of their best things.
Speaker 0: So these must be really, really bad anime that were put out way back in the sci-fi channel anime days.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it's very hard to say the worst anime ever if you haven't seen all the anime.
Speaker 0: And these are definitely three terrible anime I never even heard of, let alone seen.
Speaker 0: He also disagrees with me about "Robot Carnival Sucking," which, yeah, alright, that's fine.
Speaker 0: But I just think it's really... it's just boring and drawn out and, you know, it's a bunch of little bits about robots.
Speaker 0: And they all try to be, you know, meaningful or clever or metaphorical in some way.
Speaker 0: But it's really just compared to other shows that combine shorts into one big show.
Speaker 0: This one's pretty much the worst.
Speaker 0: You got, you know, "Memories" kicks the shit out of it, you know, by far.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: And then the last thing he talks about is how I said that, you know, if a show has at least good art, or if it has at least good music, it's not the worst show ever.
Speaker 0: And he's like, "Oh, but there are shows like 'Odin' which looks amazing, yet is
Speaker 0: terrible.".
Speaker 0: And that's true,
Speaker 0: "Odin.".
Speaker 0: "Odin!"
Speaker 0: is a terrible show.
Speaker 0: But, you know, it can't be the worst ever if you have something good to say about it.
Speaker 0: Because there are shows out there that have nothing good to say about them.
Speaker 0: Bad art, bad music, bad plot, bad everything.
Speaker 0: And those shows are objectively, you know, not on a favorite scale, 'cause there might be someone who loves it, but on a best and worst scale, they're objectively worse.
Speaker 0: Because if one show has good art and nothing else good, and one show has nothing good, the show with good art is better and therefore not the worst ever.
Speaker 0: But there is a point at which the other parts of the show are so bad.
Speaker 0: So a show with good art and nothing else redeeming, and a show with nothing redeeming... Uh, no, hang on.
Speaker 0: A show with good art, nothing else redeeming, but a horrendous, horrendous, horrendous plot, and a show with nothing redeeming, but none of it is really horrendous?
Speaker 0: Those could be even, because the bad plot could detract from the good art, which is pretty.
Speaker 0: what Odin, that's what Odin does, for sure.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: And the last thing he says is funny.
Speaker 0: He says, "I guess in the end we may never be able to all agree on what the worst anime ever made is, but at the very least we can agree on something.
Speaker 0: M.D.
Speaker 0: Geist is the second
Speaker 0: worst.".
Speaker 0: I don't know anyone who would disagree.
Speaker 0: I've never seen M.D.
Speaker 0: Geist.
Speaker 0: I know what it is.
Speaker 0: I've seen it, tapes of it around.
Speaker 0: I know it's bad.
Speaker 0: I think that's good enough.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's see what the next anime we've got, uh, next anime, the next email.
Speaker 0: It's from, uh, oh, from Sahand Dilemapur.
Speaker 0: I'm usually better at pronouncing things than other people.
Speaker 0: Better at pronouncing people's names anyway.
Speaker 0: I don't think that was absolutely correct, but I think it's better than what most Amer- I like, I'd like to say, that's better than how most Americans pronounce it.
Speaker 0: So, Sahand, I'm sorry if I mispronounced your name, but that's- I'm gonna go with Sahand.
Speaker 0: So, that's what your name looks like phonetically.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: "It's the first time I'm writing you guys.
Speaker 0: I admit that I'm a hardcore socialist.
Speaker 0: I love your shows and I think you guys kick
Speaker 0: ass.".
Speaker 0: Well, it's nice that you think we kick ass because we're definitely not socialists.
Speaker 0: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm pretty capitalist, especially, you know, now that I have a copy of Adam Smith's, uh, Wealth of Nations.
Speaker 0: When you read it and you compare it to what teachers said about Adam Smith in high school, where they said, "Oh, he's laissez faire.
Speaker 0: He doesn't want any, you know, regulation of economy whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Everyone does whatever they
Speaker 0: want.".
Speaker 0: Well, that's not true.
Speaker 0: Once you actually read the Wealth of Nations, capitalism makes a whole lot of sense.
Speaker 0: when you consider, you know, if you look at the Communist Manifesto, I make this joke to rim all the time, it's really small, really, really tiny.
Speaker 0: If you look at the Wealth of Nations, it's really, really big.
Speaker 0: This thing is, like, tremendous.
Speaker 0: Like, war and peace big, we're talking here.
Speaker 0: And it's pretty cheap, go get it on Amazon.
Speaker 0: Um, Adam Smith thought of fucking everything when he wrote the Wealth of Nations and came up with, you know, he didn't come up with capitalism per se, but when he wrote the book on capitalism, you know, he thought of everything.
Speaker 0: Marx?
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: He didn't think of everything.
Speaker 0: That's why his book is really tiny.
Speaker 0: You know, and there's an old quote that a lot of people attribute to Winston Churchill, I think.
Speaker 0: But I'm not, I've seen things around the internet saying he didn't say it, he did say it, someone else said it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter who said it, the quote is still a good quote.
Speaker 0: The quote is, if you're under, it goes something like this, "If you're under 20 and you're not a socialist, you have no heart.
Speaker 0: And if you're over 20 and you're still a socialist, you have no
Speaker 0: brain.".
Speaker 0: And while, obviously, it's not some holy truth, you can see, you know, what the, uh, where the quote comes from.
Speaker 0: It's that people with a lot of compassion, you know, for others, they want socialism.
Speaker 0: You know, because it feels like, alright, if everyone gets the same amount of money, you know, it feels like a really utopia type of thing.
Speaker 0: Everyone, no one's poor, no one's homeless, everyone's got what they need, it's all good.
Speaker 0: The sad truth is that it doesn't really work that way, and the people who believe in capitalism, you know, like myself, we say things like, you know, it's justice, everyone gets what they deserve, which also seems really fair and utopia in a certain way.
Speaker 0: The difference is, it can kind of work.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I just went on a crazy rant.
Speaker 0: Uh, then he starts to talk about Che Guevara, who I think we mentioned on the show a couple times.
Speaker 0: Uh, he says Che was a doctor, he met Fidel, you know, and all the, he talks about what Che did, and he tries to clear up some conspiracies about Che.
Speaker 0: Uh, I'm not gonna read it all because I don't know how much of it is true.
Speaker 0: He didn't cite any sources, I didn't have time to go do research to see what was true and what wasn't, but just from reading it gives me the feeling that he's not 100% on target.
Speaker 0: So I just like to tell everyone out there, if you're really interested in Che Guevara and anything about him, you know, there's Wikipedia you can read, which I guess is slightly reliable, and there's probably a whole bunch of books on him, and I recommend you read at least two, because then read one book where he's a hero and read one book where he's a villain, and you'll probably arrive somewhere really close to the truth.
Speaker 0: I just don't really care that much to go into it.
Speaker 0: Uh, then he talks, the last part of his email, random story, last, I'm gonna read his email.
Speaker 0: Random story, last night I was in Walmart comparing prices on a couple DS games, and this mom and her son come up to me.
Speaker 0: The dude was about 20-something based on his looks, or he just had a lot of facial hair, in parentheses.
Speaker 0: The mom was like, ask him what's good, he seems like he knows his make-flipping gesture with her hands, video stuff.
Speaker 0: So I went on rambling and started pointing out games I thought would kick ass, and we started talking about that game Brain Age, the one that makes you smarter.
Speaker 0: Carrot, carrot.
Speaker 0: Then, suggested some games for the PS2.
Speaker 0: Personally, I'm a Nintendo fan, but the kid had a PS2, and I just recently bought one because of Final Fantasy XII, waiting for it, so yeah.
Speaker 0: The dude who works at Walmart is just standing there, and I went on talking about 10-15 minutes to these random people I've never seen before.
Speaker 0: Then I realized, walking away from that conversation, holy shit, I really ought to work at a video game store.
Speaker 0: I was kind of entertained by that event.
Speaker 0: Well, I think I'm not going to read any more emails word-for-word like that, because that was not pleasant, and I'm sure it wasn't entertaining for you out there.
Speaker 0: But yeah, when me and Rym go to stores, we talk to people all the time.
Speaker 0: We'll go to Best Buy, and if we see someone looking at the $200 power strip, we'll tell them how stupid it is, and how it's no different than the $2 power strips.
Speaker 0: And me going to video game stores, we'll chat it up with the video game guys, you know, the employees, the customers, everyone.
Speaker 0: You know, that's really the advantage of going to - one of the only reasons I still go to a brick-and-mortar store, as opposed to buying everything online, is that there are people there, and you can interact with the people in fun ways, as long as it's not a painful place like Walmart, where I would never, ever go.
Speaker 0: If Walmart was the last store on Earth, I wouldn't shop there.
Speaker 0: I would start a subsistence farm instead.
Speaker 0: Um, yeah.
Speaker 0: Moving on to the next email.
Speaker 0: Let's see what we got here.
Speaker 0: Okay, here's one from Brian Littecky.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter what his last name is.
Speaker 0: His email's pretty short.
Speaker 0: "What program do you guys use to keep track of web pages?
Speaker 0: Thanks, Brian.
Speaker 0: You guys
Speaker 0: rock.".
Speaker 0: Oh, we do indeed rock.
Speaker 0: I wish I rocked harder.
Speaker 0: I mean, if I hadn't given up the guitar after 5th grade, I would rock more.
Speaker 0: But, alright.
Speaker 0: "What program do I use to keep track of web
Speaker 0: pages?".
Speaker 0: Well, not exactly - that's not a very specific question, so I'm not 100% sure what he means, but just so everyone out there knows, me and Rim use a website called Delicious.
Speaker 0: H-T-T-P slash slash D-E-L dot I-C-I-O dot U-S.
Speaker 0: This is a website that is very cool and everyone should know about.
Speaker 0: I don't know, I think we might have talked about it in a show past.
Speaker 0: I don't know if we did a whole show on it.
Speaker 0: We probably will in the future.
Speaker 0: It must have been an early show where we talked about it, though, very early.
Speaker 0: Maybe one of the first few weeks of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Where, um, Delicious is a site that you do bookmarks.
Speaker 0: Now, when you do bookmarks in your web browser, those are useful for websites you visit every day, because they're right there.
Speaker 0: So, no matter what web page you're at, you go bookmarks, you click on the link, and you're there.
Speaker 0: Stuff like Dig, which you would read every day, or Gmail, which you would go to all the time, are good things to put in your web browser bookmarks.
Speaker 0: Back in the day before Delicious existed, when you found an interesting site, maybe an article you wanted to read later, or perhaps a site with a how-to guide, or a cheat sheet for a particular programming language, or a technology piece of software, or a site with a funny video on it.
Speaker 0: Now, you want to bookmark it so you can remember it at some point in the future, but you don't want to clutter up your bookmarks in your web browser.
Speaker 0: Delicious is a site where you basically make social bookmarks, so it's even better.
Speaker 0: You use it, you get an account, and you add links to it.
Speaker 0: And you can add as many links as you want forever.
Speaker 0: And you can access those links, and all those bookmarks, from any web browser in the world, because you just go to the Delicious web page, you log in, and there's all your bookmarks that you've ever made.
Speaker 0: Now, you can also tag those bookmarks.
Speaker 0: So, if I tag a funny video, I put the tags "Funny Video," and let's say it's a video game commercial.
Speaker 0: I say "Video Game
Speaker 0: Commercial.".
Speaker 0: I put four tags on it.
Speaker 0: Now, people can go to Delicious and search for "Funny Video Game Commercials," and they'll find my link, and maybe link it themselves.
Speaker 0: And when things get a lot of links, they show up on the popular page.
Speaker 0: And it's all around very useful.
Speaker 0: And if you'll notice, if you go to dell.ico.us/apreche, or slash, I think, rim.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't know if he uses rim or shazar.
Speaker 0: I think it's slash rim.
Speaker 0: You can see the things that me and rim, and you can go to other people's Delicious and see what they're tagging.
Speaker 0: And you can also look for combinations of tags, and it's really great.
Speaker 0: If you're not using Delicious, you really, really should.
Speaker 0: Plus, it'll occasionally, or frequently, give you insight as to what the news and things of the day are going to be.
Speaker 0: So, that's Delicious.
Speaker 0: Next email.
Speaker 0: I'm only going to do a couple more of these.
Speaker 0: Let's try this one.
Speaker 0: Oh, this one?
Speaker 0: There was a guy from Bangkok, and he was troubled downloading our shows.
Speaker 0: We post this show on Libsyn, if there's any, the MP3s at least.
Speaker 0: The website is run by me.
Speaker 0: So, if you have a problem with the website or forums, that is an issue for me, Scott, and you should tell me about it.
Speaker 0: If there is an issue with downloading the MP3s, or emailing us, which shouldn't be anything you'll ever have to worry about, that's a problem with Libsyn or Google.
Speaker 0: And if there's a problem with our RSS feeds, that's probably an issue with FeedBurner, or it might be an issue with me, depending.
Speaker 0: But, we fix the problems on our end, so if there's any new problems, it's FeedBurner's problem.
Speaker 0: And if you're not using the FeedBurner feeds to listen to us, you probably should, unless you don't use feeds at all.
Speaker 0: In which case, maybe you should learn how to use the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: It's really useful.
Speaker 0: So, he had trouble downloading the episodes from Bangkok, and all I can say is that's a problem somewhere between Libsyn and Bangkok.
Speaker 0: And, I'm sorry, I can't help you.
Speaker 0: It's out of my hands.
Speaker 0: Libsyn isn't the greatest company.
Speaker 0: We only use them because there aren't any decent alternatives.
Speaker 0: And as soon as there is a decent alternative, we'll be sure to go jump on that.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's see if I got another interesting email here.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I'm losing air time because Rym isn't here.
Speaker 0: Oh, someone did email us trying to have us interview this guy and sell something, but we're going to do a special episode later about shilling, where we will cover all of that.
Speaker 0: So, don't you worry.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's a guy, Olaf Ahlberg.
Speaker 0: This will be the last email I read, then I'll do meta bits, and then I will spare you any more suffering.
Speaker 0: "I started listening to podcasts when he got his broadband connection a month ago.
Speaker 0: He listened to all our shows.
Speaker 0: He has some suggestions.
Speaker 0: At one point, Rym says he has some sort of special and in-depth knowledge of propaganda and/or commercial.
Speaker 0: That would be very interesting to hear
Speaker 0: about.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, we know a whole lot about that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: But if you really want to know about that sort of thing, there are plenty of books.
Speaker 0: One day we'll do a show about it.
Speaker 0: Maybe we can do a month where every Thursday we'll talk about... You know, that can go well with our shilling show.
Speaker 0: It probably won't be the same show, but it can be related in terms of a persuasion series.
Speaker 0: I remember Rym took a whole bunch of classes in persuasion in college, and I've read all of Rushkoff's books, Coercion and such.
Speaker 0: So we could, you know, maybe make a month where every Thursday is somehow related to persuasion and arguing and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: I think people would enjoy that.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea.
Speaker 0: I'll write that down.
Speaker 0: "Quite a few...".
Speaker 0: Oh, this email is pretty old.
Speaker 0: "Quite a few shows.
Speaker 0: back, you mentioned something about doing a show about computer securities.
Speaker 0: Looking forward to it since.
Speaker 0: The fact that I've gone through all your shows should be evidence of enough of my appreciation of it, but just to make sure I'm going to say it straight out, I really like your show.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward to the next
Speaker 0: episode.".
Speaker 0: Well, that's awesome.
Speaker 0: Ooh, he's from Sweden.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Sweden's awesome.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: I think they actually won some big hockey, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like the hockeys.
Speaker 0: We did mention something about doing a show about computer security.
Speaker 0: There is a show, a podcast out there called Security Now.
Speaker 0: It's pretty popular.
Speaker 0: And all they do is talk about security on that podcast.
Speaker 0: So if you're really, really interested in computer security, I recommend you listen to that show.
Speaker 0: I used to listen to it and then I stopped because it really speaks to a lower level than the level that I'm at.
Speaker 0: But it was a good refresher for while I listened to it.
Speaker 0: It just got kind of boring.
Speaker 0: Also, the guy who does the podcast is a security professional.
Speaker 0: He knows his shit.
Speaker 0: But sometimes he can be a little off the mark in some cases.
Speaker 0: We will do a show... The problem with computer security is that it's a really broad topic.
Speaker 0: But we will do a show in the future probably about... Maybe we'll do it in our series of how computers work.
Speaker 0: But we'll definitely do some sort of show about how to keep your personal computer secure.
Speaker 0: And another show about how to keep your home network secure.
Speaker 0: Or maybe we'll combine them into one show.
Speaker 0: Just, you know, practical security things you can do as a normal computer user and not as a professional.
Speaker 0: Alright, that's enough emails.
Speaker 0: Let's cover the meta bits and be done with this.
Speaker 0: The first meta bit, we have a website.
Speaker 0: Yes, if you've never listened to Eatnights before.
Speaker 0: Or if you've never been to our website because you subscribe to us in iTunes.
Speaker 0: And you never have gone to see what we're about.
Speaker 0: If you go to FrontRowCrew.com, F-R-O-N-T-R-O-W-C-R-E-W.com If you go there, there is an awesome, awesome webpage awaiting you.
Speaker 0: Not only are there links to all our feeds and all sorts of other goody, goody stuffs.
Speaker 0: Every single episode is listed there.
Speaker 0: You can search through our episodes.
Speaker 0: Maybe there was something we talked about.
Speaker 0: You can see.
Speaker 0: there are links to My Flicker, My Delicious, My Lestalle, RimsDelicious.
Speaker 0: You can browse episodes by category.
Speaker 0: And also, there are notes for each show.
Speaker 0: So, in each show notes, there are links to the news stories, links to the episode, and links to the things of the day.
Speaker 0: A lot of people, you know, hear us talk about the things of the day.
Speaker 0: And I'm not sure if they actually go look at the things of the day.
Speaker 0: I will sit here describing some funny Google video.
Speaker 0: And people don't go out and watch it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You should go to FrontRowCrew.com and you will find the link to the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: And you can go check it out yourself and be entertained.
Speaker 0: If you're not doing that, you're really not getting the full Geek Nights experience.
Speaker 0: Also, on FrontRowCrew.com are our RSS feeds, which I just said.
Speaker 0: And in case you didn't know, there are one, two, three, four, five, six feeds.
Speaker 0: One feed is the blog feed.
Speaker 0: That has an orange icon next to it.
Speaker 0: All the feeds are on FeedBurner, by the way.
Speaker 0: You should not be using any, except for the blog feed.
Speaker 0: You should not be using any non-FeedBurner feeds for the purposes of podcast subscribing.
Speaker 0: If you do, it's not going to work.
Speaker 0: So if you are trying to download our episodes automatically, only use the FeedBurner feeds, which we link to on the right side of FrontRowCrew.com.
Speaker 0: There's also the blog feed, which is all the stories on FrontRowCrew.com.
Speaker 0: Some of those don't actually have episodes in them.
Speaker 0: For example, the top story on FrontRowCrew.com right now is Rym saying he's going to Animazement and that you should find him there.
Speaker 0: If you only subscribe to the podcast feed and you didn't listen to yesterday's episode or today's episode, you probably won't know that.
Speaker 0: So subscribing to the blog feed is a good idea for seeing the stories and things we post that aren't podcast episodes.
Speaker 0: Also, in the future, there might be more FrontRowCrew productions other than Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: In fact, I'm positive.
Speaker 0: in the long run there will be multiple FrontRowCrew productions.
Speaker 0: And subscribing to the blog feed is a way to keep informed of everything that we and our friends do and not just Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: The other five feeds are the all Geek Nights feed and then the daily feeds.
Speaker 0: I'm sure everyone knows about these, but I'll talk about them again because our podcast is a little different from everyone else's.
Speaker 0: If you want to listen to every episode of Geek Nights, you just subscribe to the all Geek Nights feed in your podcatcher and you're all set.
Speaker 0: You'll get every episode.
Speaker 0: There are four other feeds.
Speaker 0: One of them will just get you the episodes on Monday.
Speaker 0: One will just get you the episodes on Tuesday, just Wednesday, and just Thursday.
Speaker 0: There are four feeds, four days of the week.
Speaker 0: You can listen or choose to listen to only one day of the week.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of people only care about gaming, so they only subscribe to the Tuesday feed.
Speaker 0: Of all the daily feeds, the gaming one is the most popular.
Speaker 0: The anime one's a close second.
Speaker 0: The Monday and Thursday aren't as popular, really.
Speaker 0: Of course, nothing really compares to the all Geek Nights feed, so I guess that's a good thing.
Speaker 0: Also, on FrontRowCrew.com is our forum.
Speaker 0: Now, a lot of people have been joining our forum.
Speaker 0: We've had a steady income of users pretty much constantly.
Speaker 0: Every day, maybe a couple times a day, I'll see a new person say, "I want to join the
Speaker 0: forum.".
Speaker 0: I say, "Okay, you can join the
Speaker 0: There seems to be steady discussion going on in there.
Speaker 0: You can't check the forum twice without seeing a new article, or a new thread, or a new comment in an existing thread that you care about.
Speaker 0: It's really hopping.
Speaker 0: It's not easy to get a community started like this, so the fact that this one is thriving pretty well makes me kind of happy, especially since it's really fun in there.
Speaker 0: If you want to get the full Geek Nights experience, again, you should also join our forum.
Speaker 0: Now, just as a note, if you use Hotmail, the way the forum works, it's not like other PHP BB forums that you're used to, or VBulletin forums that you're used to.
Speaker 0: The way our forum works is there's all sorts of fancy features, which is cool, but the way it works is you sign up, and then I or Rym, probably me, will manually approve your application.
Speaker 0: I have never, ever, ever rejected an application.
Speaker 0: We've banned only one person ever after approving their application.
Speaker 0: So if you have Hotmail, you're not going to receive the email that tells you your application was approved, because Hotmail blocks it like spam.
Speaker 0: So if you have Hotmail, still sign up for the forum, and just wait maybe a day at most.
Speaker 0: I usually approve these things within hours, if not minutes, because I get a little email when someone applies.
Speaker 0: Just come back to the forum and sign in with your name and password, and it will probably work, because I hardly ever reject anyone, unless they're obviously a spammer or a bot.
Speaker 0: We haven't had too many spammers or bots, although it does seem like there's a lot of lurkers, people just going around the forums reading and posting very rarely.
Speaker 0: You can tell, looking at the Identify Yourself thread, there's a lot of people who went in there and talked all about themselves, or gave enough of a bio, and then don't actually participate in too many of the threads.
Speaker 0: That's fine, you can do whatever you want, but the more people talk, the merrier.
Speaker 0: If there's nothing in the forum that you're really interested in talking about, well, you're listening to Geek Nights, you must have something to say about the things we're saying, so even if someone's already stated your opinion, at least say, "Hey, me too,".
Speaker 0: or if there's something you want to talk about that isn't in there, post and don't be afraid to start a new discussion in the forum.
Speaker 0: The more activity, the better.
Speaker 0: And of course, if you haven't joined the forum, go join it.
Speaker 0: Um, let's see, forum Frapper.
Speaker 0: Ah, Frapper.
Speaker 0: Seems like every podcast in just about every blog in the world now has a Frapper map.
Speaker 0: We do too!
Speaker 0: It's kind of fun to look at, actually, because it's this map of the world with little pushpins wherever there's a listener of Geek Nights, which is way cool.
Speaker 0: Um, you can go there, and not only can you post yourself, you can post a location of a geek house, a location of a geek convention, or any other sort of geek place.
Speaker 0: So, go to our Frapper map, and join the list, and everyone will be able to see where all the cool Geek Nights listeners and whatnot are in the world.
Speaker 0: It's a whole lot of fun.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really cost anything.
Speaker 0: It's just you go to this map online, and you put a little pin on it saying, "Hey, I'm a Geek Nights listener, and this is where I am.
Speaker 0: How you
Speaker 0: doing?".
Speaker 0: Definitely fun, and the more pushpins on there, the more fun it is, especially when those pushpins are in foreign countries.
Speaker 0: Uh, let's see.
Speaker 0: Ah, the logo contest.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many people know about this or don't know about this, but we've been having a logo contest that's been ongoing, and we just keep forgetting to mention it, which you really should mention in every episode.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights does not have a logo, nor does the Front Row Crew.
Speaker 0: We need a logo so that we can put it in our podcasts and our feeds so it appears in iTunes, and to put it on the top of our web page, and to put it on merchandise.
Speaker 0: If you make a logo, it should be a square, and it should look good at the top of frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: So if you go to frontrowcrew.com, you'll see the top of the page is this blue color.
Speaker 0: It's sort of this gradient that goes from dark to light blue.
Speaker 0: Your logo should look good if we put it up there.
Speaker 0: It should also be a square so that it works well in iTunes and all that.
Speaker 0: If your logo is good, we will give you $50, and you will give us the logo.
Speaker 0: You won't own the logo, sadly, but you will receive mad props, $50, and mad credit.
Speaker 0: So every single episode of Geek Nights at the end, we will say, "Thanks to so-and-so for the
Speaker 0: logo.".
Speaker 0: And on all the t-shirts and all the websites where we will sell t-shirts, who knows, we can't give you any more information about that, and it won't be just t-shirts either.
Speaker 0: There will be things that say, "Thanks to so-and-so, whoever you are, for creating the awesome logo," or, "Logo by
Speaker 0: so-and-so.".
Speaker 0: And even if you don't care about getting recognition, that's a great thing for a resume.
Speaker 0: Like, "I created an awesome
Speaker 0: logo.".
Speaker 0: So we're probably going to -- time is running out on this.
Speaker 0: We've really taken too damn long finding a logo.
Speaker 0: So you've got -- I'm going to give you, at most, one more month to submit logos.
Speaker 0: Maybe not even that long, maybe just a couple weeks.
Speaker 0: And then we're going to pick whatever we like the best, probably ask the artist to modify it in some way, you know, because so far nothing has been 100% perfect.
Speaker 0: So we'll probably take something that's 90% perfect, ask the artist to modify 10% of it, and then go with that.
Speaker 0: So time is running out.
Speaker 0: If you want to make us a logo, hurry yourself up.
Speaker 0: You're running out of time.
Speaker 0: Uh, e-mail.
Speaker 0: Yes, I just did a whole show where I read e-mails.
Speaker 0: If you want to send us an e-mail, which we may or may not read on a show, but we probably will reply to it by e-mail, send your e-mails to geekknights@frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: I think you can figure out how to spell that based on the other things I've said.
Speaker 0: Okay, I think I've tortured you all long enough.
Speaker 0: This show's over.
Speaker 0: On Monday we will resume normal, mildly edited podcasting, as opposed to this completely unedited crap.
Speaker 0: audio quality nothing podcasting.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Shutting up.
Speaker 0: Monday.
Speaker 0: Bye.