Speaker 1: It's Wednesday August 2nd, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: This is not a normal episode of geek nights because we are very shortly as in in the morning driving to Baltimore for Otacon Hooray.
Speaker 1: as a result tonight is nothing more than our Otacon pregame.
Speaker 1: You're lucky even get an episode at all pregame show.
Speaker 0: So who do you think is gonna win the game tonight?
Speaker 0: I don't know the strong offense, but the other team.
Speaker 0: they won their last five games, and they've been rested up for last week.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be Kimi Raikkonen.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right the point of this episode is two things.
Speaker 0: number one to give people going to Otacon.
Speaker 0: you know the times and places.
Speaker 1: they'll be able to see us and Hang out with us and do whatever and we're gonna give a very brief overview of all the things on the schedule that was just Released.
Speaker 1: that might be interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, kind of like a you know pre-con report like oh this panel looks good.
Speaker 0: You might want to go to that.
Speaker 0: you might want to stay away from this.
Speaker 0: it looks scary.
Speaker 0: You know here's a good idea.
Speaker 0: you might want to.
Speaker 0: you know do this to make sure you get the most out of your con Experience.
Speaker 0: you know looking at the schedule of Otacon which came out Sunday morning plus.
Speaker 1: You know stuff.
Speaker 1: We're looking forward to all that.
Speaker 1: this will kick off our Otacon coverage.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 1: So first off with the goods.
Speaker 1: in case you're listening to this just before you go to the con Or you're trying to find us the places we can guarantee Garing fucking tea that you will be able to find us at this con on Friday the first day of the con at 11 a.m..
Speaker 0: We are going to have an Geek night's listener meetup thing kind of.
Speaker 0: it's not official It's not on the con schedule, but if you go to the Baltimore Convention Center, and you go upstairs You know there's a place with the escalators.
Speaker 0: You know the.
Speaker 0: it's not the Pratt Street Lobby It's the other one right the Otter bean.
Speaker 0: no I forget which Lobby the name is.
Speaker 0: if I had a BCC map I could tell you the name of the Lobby.
Speaker 0: It's the lobby with the water and the escalators the cosplay Lobby.
Speaker 0: Exactly you go up the escalators, and you turn right you go right, and you'll see this like BCC kind of directory kind of thing and there'll be a slight open area in front of some panel rooms And then there'll be some doors that go out to a patio on that patio.
Speaker 0: We're gonna hang out at 11 a.m Yes, you will.
Speaker 1: it will not be difficult to find us.
Speaker 1: We may or may not have some small matter of equipment set up recording or something yep.
Speaker 0: So at 11 a.m.. On Friday if you want to find us right away Especially if you should find us right away because you're gonna hang out with us a lot, then that's the place to go.
Speaker 1: Yep, the only other place we will guarantee that we will show up is the concert on Friday at 8 p.m..
Speaker 0: In the Concert arena the power plant the Rams head place at the power plant.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, the thing is if you want to meet us at that concert It's going to be nuts and you probably won't find us unless you found us ahead of time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's going to the way.
Speaker 0: the concerts working at Otacon this year Which is different from every place before is that there's actually a concert hall place near Otacon at the power plant Rams head whatever.
Speaker 0: it's like a normal small concert joint where bands play and They've rented it out.
Speaker 0: I guess Friday night and Saturday afternoon for the same concert But twice.
Speaker 0: so the concert is not a katah day and muck which we've talked about in the past, so We're going to go to it on Friday because on Saturday it conflicts with something else that we have to do.
Speaker 1: Yes now moving on to Saturday You can definitely without question find us at the anime club summit at 3 p.m.. In panel number 3.
Speaker 0: Yes, rim and Scott Johnson who is not me they run the anime club summit And it's an hour-long panel from 3 to 5 and I not to our long pen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's we think.
Speaker 1: well the panels been getting really popular so they made it bigger and they put it in a bigger room this year.
Speaker 1: hmm and We have you know we have some industry on the panel in addition to us, and it's always a good panel.
Speaker 1: I mean we really do know what we're talking about when it comes to running anime clubs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they gave you two hours.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah Usually you get one hour because a lot of the higher-ups Otacon really liked the panel and the industry really likes the panel and the Always gets a lot of people.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm see we are guaranteed to be at the anime club summit and a good place.
Speaker 0: if you just want to see us and you don't care about the Anime club summit if you go outside of panel 3 at around 5 when it the panel gets out We'll be there, and there's a decent chance at that point.
Speaker 1: We'll all go out and get some food.
Speaker 0: There is a decent chance.
Speaker 0: That's usually the strategy.
Speaker 0: now if you look at your Otacon schedule you will note that at 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: On Saturday in theater 1 which is I guess used to be main events There is a. it's called.
Speaker 0: There's a panel called podcasting the right stuff.
Speaker 0: that is not geek night That isn't.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to say what my opinions of the right stuff podcast But suffice to say that is not our panel.
Speaker 1: we may or may not be there to talk to them But don't count on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the right stuff international is a company that you know distributes and sells anime in the United States And they have an official company podcast and they must have unbeknownst to us until now Asked Otacon for a panel for that podcast and they have it and that has nothing to do with us.
Speaker 0: They're probably not even going to talk about podcasting in general I would guess.
Speaker 0: I would guess they're mostly going to talk about their podcast.
Speaker 0: you know for the right stuff at least That's the title of their panel implies Our panel is on Sunday at 10 a.m.. In panel 4 if you come Sunday 10 a.m.. Panel room number 4 Geek nights has an hour-long panel called podcasting internet radio.
Speaker 1: We are going to be talking about Podcasting and internet radio and geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It'll probably be a very good panel.
Speaker 1: We did a similar thing at torque on.
Speaker 1: it went over very well.
Speaker 1: I expect it will be hilarious and awesome And I expect there will be much hijinks as we take everyone from the panel directly afterward to the con feedback session And then the closing ceremonies in one big blob.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: So if you come and see us at no other point in the convention come to our panel on Sunday at 10 a.m.. In panel room number 4.
Speaker 1: not only is that the absolute guaranteed place to find us unless we get killed or Something ahead of time, but since we'll be recording the panel most likely live.
Speaker 1: That's your chance to appear on geek nights and ask us a question.
Speaker 0: possibly yes that episode where of the recording of that panel Will likely air not next Monday, but a week from next Monday.
Speaker 1: yep now aside from all those places you can see us.
Speaker 1: The things I'm excited about this year other than the usual stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean I want to go to the dances.
Speaker 1: I didn't get a chance to dance so much last year.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm The FMA movie is being shown and while I've heard a lot of bad things about the movie if I can watch it in the Theater at Otacon for free yeah, it looks like it starts though as soon as the Friday night concert gets out.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: we're probably not gonna.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to see.
Speaker 1: remember we don't have descriptions of these panels.
Speaker 1: the only things we have to go on right now are Their names.
Speaker 1: yep that said I'm interested in your favorite anime sucks.
Speaker 0: Hey, that sounds like a funny panel.
Speaker 1: Science and anime.
Speaker 1: only because we think it's possible that Mike Pfeffer might be running it just cuz it sounds like the kind of Well because last year he ran anime at politics in anime.
Speaker 0: So if he if it's science and anime or anime and philosophy Which is another panel that is running at the same time as the concert now of course chance He might be running it.
Speaker 1: every year.
Speaker 1: We go to the con feedback session and closing ceremonies because they are without exception awesome.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm the opening ceremonies you can skip but closing ceremonies and con feedback are great because one Otakon is very well run.
Speaker 1: But to the con feedback session is usually at most cons where people come and complain about the things that weren't run.
Speaker 1: well The way Otakon runs it is so awesome and that one.
Speaker 1: well I keep saying giving numbers to these things.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna stop that.
Speaker 1: when people have a complaint the Otakon staff always have had either a direct answer as in that happened because of X and it was out of the control out of our control because of why or That's a great idea.
Speaker 1: talk to us, and we'll do it your way next year.
Speaker 0: So basically no one comes up and puns them with questions.
Speaker 0: They basically put anyone who comes up with negative.
Speaker 1: I mean I remember one year some guy I think he was from cosplay.com came up And he was complaining about the way and Otakon runs their cosplay the masquerade.
Speaker 1: they don't follow cosplay.com's rules some arbitrary non-binding organization and the staffers basically said This is our con and we run it the way.
Speaker 1: the people who come to our con want it And we don't really care how other people say we should run our masquerade because everyone seems to really enjoy it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean I didn't have a problem with it.
Speaker 0: only crazy cosplay people had a problem.
Speaker 1: not even crazy cosplay people.
Speaker 1: crazy Cosplay people on cosplay.com who like to complain about things.
Speaker 0: yep Another time, but the year that they had the the Larkin CL concert.
Speaker 0: I don't know TMR.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm sorry the TMR can add TM revolution.
Speaker 0: was it really yes?
Speaker 0: Oh, I think no it had to be both.
Speaker 1: No you could you it was specifically that one because the chairs It was the chairs both time.
Speaker 1: no because the chairs in the arena can't be removed Scott.
Speaker 0: No the chairs in the arena were the chairs that we were on in the arena could be removed.
Speaker 1: It was the chair yeah, but most of them couldn't.
Speaker 1: and besides you asked the question during the TMR concert.
Speaker 1: I'm 100% sure that that is what that is.
Speaker 1: when this happened I don't know.
Speaker 1: I am sure because they were two separate years, and you wouldn't ask the same question two years in a row.
Speaker 0: But I don't think we went to the.
Speaker 1: yes we did.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I went to the.
Speaker 1: in fact you asked about it specifically because people behind us at the TMR concert Yelled at us because we were standing up during the concert.
Speaker 0: Anyway at one of the two concerts.
Speaker 0: I had the closing feedback session I asked how come there wasn't any you know general admission standing area.
Speaker 0: How come there are chairs from the front to the back and The guy was like yeah, we couldn't get that for security reasons, and I'm like well You know if you couldn't get it for security reasons Maybe you should just you know get more security or something.
Speaker 0: uh and then they're like this big guy stood up And he's like ah I'm the security blah.
Speaker 0: And then it was funny.
Speaker 0: and then I sat down.
Speaker 0: But then the guy who did who you know who was in charge of that for Otacon came over And he was like oh, I wanted general admission so bad, but I couldn't get it.
Speaker 0: And I was like it's cool.
Speaker 0: It's cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Otacon really has their stuff together.
Speaker 1: They.
Speaker 1: this is probably the best run convention ever
Speaker 0: yep,
Speaker 1: and also a really cool thing is the new thing They started doing recently is that they show The winning anime music videos at one of the two which means you don't have to sit at
Speaker 0: the closing ceremony You
Speaker 1: don't have to sit through the anime music video contest.
Speaker 1: yeah the anime music video contest if you really like AMVs go to it, but I do and I at other cons I always go to it, but I don't have time to go to it at Otacon.
Speaker 0: yeah It's just it takes too long, and it's conflicts with the Friday concert.
Speaker 1: it conflicts with everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not the greatest usage of time.
Speaker 1: now There's some things on the schedule that scare me this year.
Speaker 1: one There is a 18 plus meaning you have to be 18 And they'll check ID to get into this panel called Let's get social Friday afternoon, and that can't be anything other than hookups.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell I know It has to be the hookup panel.
Speaker 0: It's actually a workshop.
Speaker 0: So it's a hookup workshop.
Speaker 1: I guess it's got to be.
Speaker 1: as far as I can guess it's probably just people who want to get with other people at the Con which seems to be the primary goal of a lot of people who go to Otacon.
Speaker 0: yeah But it's mostly the less than 18s who want to hook up But this is 18 plus only.
Speaker 1: so this is people who want to hook up But it's guaranteed that no one they hook up with will be illegal and underage.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess that's okay.
Speaker 1: I think that's great, but maybe we should go to it And I want to go to it just to interview some people about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah One the 4chan panel is not 18 plus, but the panel both before it and after it are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the general gist is that the 4chan people agreed to follow some certain guidelines To prevent their panel from being 18 plus, but they put it late at night So the likelihood of under 18s going to it is kind of low.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that Otacon has a hammer hanging over the 4chan panel And if anything happens this year, they are never coming back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm pretty sure
Speaker 1: because last year They staged a fight between a guy who pretended to be a furry and a guy who pretended to be like a 4chan thug And they staged a fake Fight at the panel that almost got the police involved before they admitted that it was fake Mmm, and Otacon was like.
Speaker 1: you can't pull that shit here.
Speaker 1: Now right before it is the hentai doujinshi panel Which no Great.
Speaker 1: right after it is a panel that if I'm not completely dead how to survive the zombie apocalypse Which is probably going to be hilarious
Speaker 0: and at the same time as the 4chan panel In fact so long that it starts before and ends after the 4chan panel is a workshop 18 plus do-it-yourself bukkake this.
Speaker 1: this scares the living hell out of me.
Speaker 1: if you don't know what bukkake is good first What I want you to do is go to Google Images and turn off safe search then type the word bukkake B-U-K-K-A-K-E.
Speaker 1: Into it.
Speaker 0: hit enter, but then don't do this if you're under 18.
Speaker 1: no no do this.
Speaker 1: do this right now.
Speaker 0: If you're under 18 don't do it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, cuz I we don't get in trouble now.
Speaker 1: before you click enter Find everyone in your family if you're at work find every find your boss, and then it enter.
Speaker 1: Don't actually do that.
Speaker 1: No bukkake is a horrible thing.
Speaker 0: So this is a frightening panel immensely frightening.
Speaker 1: I am going to this because I want to see what kind of freaks go in and then I want to interview them and ask Them what the hell they're thinking.
Speaker 0: yeah, I think that's about pretty much the only scary stuff.
Speaker 1: Well the only other thing is that there is a yuri panel that not only does it not say 18 plus But it specifically says not 18 plus.
Speaker 0: Maybe they.
Speaker 0: you know they.
Speaker 0: they fought hard to get it to be not you know.
Speaker 0: what I wonder is that Shouldn't they just call to the shoujo eye pan?
Speaker 1: That's what I was about to say because yuri is a much more specific word than a lot of American fans seem to think.
Speaker 1: just Like yaoi yaoi doesn't mean boys liking each other.
Speaker 1: yaoi means boys doing things to each other.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, all right now.
Speaker 0: as for our traditional incredibly violent late-night live-action movie You will note that video room 5 at Otacon is showing only live-action Asian cinema Which is awesome and a lot of the movies in there are awesome and a lot of the movies in there are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a half-hour movie.
Speaker 1: That's just called South Asian horror.
Speaker 0: yep well I looked in at the what movies are playing late at night Friday and Saturday to figure out which one was ridiculously violent And I've checked out four of them that are look like good contenders.
Speaker 0: IMDb and I have short summaries lady Terminator is at like 1030 in video 5. of course on Friday.
Speaker 0: the only thing I have to say about this is She mates, and then she terminates After.
Speaker 0: that is art of the devil 2 which is supposedly a movie That's kind of slow for 40 minutes But then after 40 minutes because it's no it's an hour and a half 90 minute movie.
Speaker 0: So the second 50 minutes are ultra-violent.
Speaker 1: Yep, so maybe we'll go.
Speaker 1: we haven't decided which one we're going to yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we are to the devil - looks like a good contender because it feels like one of those horrible horrible movies.
Speaker 0: It's not good Saturday night at 9 they're showing G goku which is there are like three movies and IMDb named G goku and G goku I'm pretty sure means hell in Japanese and They are all had to do with Japanese hell, so I'm not sure if it's gonna be ultra-violent if it's gonna be about you know learning a lesson or anything like that.
Speaker 1: of course the One after it is called sex and fury.
Speaker 0: yeah now sex and fury was described on IMDb as being a specific genre of pink violence.
Speaker 0: Basically the movie is full of not ultra-violence, but just kind of normal over-the-top violence with lots of TNA.
Speaker 0: So that's also a pretty good contender.
Speaker 0: You know because you got the TNA combined with the better than American cinema violence It could be good that could be the one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll basically make the decision at the con.
Speaker 1: So you'll have had to track us down at some point to figure out what the ultra-violent movie is that we are all going to Go to and yell about.
Speaker 0: and of course you know if at any time There's a good chance that we randomly hang around video 5 when the con is at a low point.
Speaker 1: Yes, also if you don't go to the concert on Friday You must must go to video 4 at 7 30 p.m.
Speaker 1: And watch Lupin the third strange psychokinetic strategy.
Speaker 0: That's a live-action.
Speaker 0: Lupin the third movie.
Speaker 0: that's awesome.
Speaker 1: It is badass And I even missed the first 15 minutes of it because I was asleep in the hotel room a little hungover and Scott Johnson Comes back from the movie wakes me up and forces me to get dressed to come down and watch it.
Speaker 0: I think it might be available on DVD though.
Speaker 0: I think that's why it's being shown at all these cons that someone's selling it and if I see in the dealers room I'm gonna get it.
Speaker 1: if the movie hadn't been good.
Speaker 1: I would have killed him, but the movie was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also at 2 o'clock and video 4 on Friday They're showing perfect your earth defense force, which is supposedly hilarious.
Speaker 0: Anime world order bets their lives on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll say and if I don't buy in the dealers room.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go watch it there.
Speaker 0: All right, what else looks really interesting at this con?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: everything else is pretty standard con fair.
Speaker 1: I really need to read the descriptions.
Speaker 1: I mean video 7 is gonna have a bunch of premieres Saturday from all the companies.
Speaker 0: But yeah, there's a Voltron special in video 7 from media blasters.
Speaker 0: Who's putting out all those Voltron DVDs.
Speaker 1: at 9 o'clock on Saturday They're showing Cromartie the movie Which I missed at several other cons.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll have to go see that but overlapping that is animal treasure island and the transform.
Speaker 0: Oh, I got.
Speaker 0: I really want to see animal treasure island.
Speaker 1: That's a classic old-school anime panel and the masquerade.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think mother animal treasure island might win.
Speaker 0: That's an old-school Tezuka thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you need a census to the scale of Otakon consider this.
Speaker 1: most cons would never put major events Conflicting with each other at all.
Speaker 1: Like to have the ANV contest at the same time as a concert would be crazy because everyone goes to every big event Otakon so big that they have to do it that way because there's so many people.
Speaker 0: yeah, imagine if you have like a your main the main events room at your convention is as holds 5,000 people and so at your Cosplay everyone shows up and you have an ANV contest.
Speaker 0: That's where most people are gonna be.
Speaker 0: so if you put them both at the same time You're gonna force people to choose between one and the other and you're basically gonna split your con in half And a lot of people are gonna be angry.
Speaker 1: There is no room at Otakon that can hold all of Otakon.
Speaker 0: well except for the arena Yeah, but even that which is why they got the arena for the cosplay.
Speaker 1: Yes, if everyone wants to go to the cosplay they can arrange it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But other than that, there is nothing at Otakon that can accommodate everyone.
Speaker 0: So they put as many awesome things simultaneous to each other to keep the people spread out.
Speaker 0: You know fill up everything as opposed to having one overflowing bucket.
Speaker 0: They have you know, so much water.
Speaker 0: They get a lot of small buckets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Otakon does provide a lot of water which is very key.
Speaker 0: Lots of what.
Speaker 0: there's free water everywhere.
Speaker 0: Make sure you take advantage of it or else you will dehydrate because you're being air-conditioned in the convention center and it's hot as hell outside.
Speaker 0: You don't realize.
Speaker 0: you're dehydrating in the air conditioning.
Speaker 0: drink water a lot.
Speaker 0: you're doing a lot of walking.
Speaker 1: Yes Also, don't forget to eat.
Speaker 1: eat a lot of food.
Speaker 1: eat more food than you think you need because you go to eat.
Speaker 0: You should become full After you eat.
Speaker 0: every single time you eat lunch and dinner.
Speaker 1: now We'll have a lot to say about the food because this year the food situation might be a little different.
Speaker 1: But if you have at all any problems with food at the con.
Speaker 1: go across the street to the mall.
Speaker 1: They have amazing food and they give discounts to Otakon people they know.
Speaker 0: Yeah remember when I talked about those escalators.
Speaker 0: if you go up those escalators in the the water and The fountain room the big giant lobby the cosplay lobby Yeah, you turn left and you go out the con out those doors and keep going.
Speaker 0: You'll eventually go across the sky walk.
Speaker 0: You'll see everyone's going this way to a mall and a food court and that is the best place to get Normal kind of food.
Speaker 1: be warned There is nowhere to sit there.
Speaker 1: that place will be as crowded as Otakon for the entire Convention and there'll be a lot of normal people who are just in the inner harbor for the weekend Just not knowing what to do and freaking out.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you don't show up there to eat at strange times, like if you don't want to eat at like 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: And 3 p.m You're not gonna find a seat there and let without you a fight Especially if you bring a large crew with you.
Speaker 0: if you go alone You'll probably might find a chair somewhere if you bring your friends.
Speaker 0: give up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically don't expect to eat lunch with the front row crew.
Speaker 1: In fact, the front row crew does not eat lunch with the front row crew.
Speaker 1: We go in groups of one to three at random times all day for breakfast and lunches.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sometimes we just grab our breakfast before the con starts in a small breakfast nook.
Speaker 1: Yep However, generally Saturday night.
Speaker 1: at some point though, maybe this year because of all the stuff going on Saturday We'll do it Friday night.
Speaker 1: We get the everyone involved and associated with us.
Speaker 1: last year We had like 19 or 20 or maybe I'm more than that.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Go to fud Rucker's in a giant blob.
Speaker 0: Yes, if you walk down the road towards the ESPN Whatever it is, you know the power plant concert place is down that way.
Speaker 0: Also, you will see a fud Rucker's eat there.
Speaker 0: eat there at least once during the convention sometime.
Speaker 1: don't order a milkshake Why not?
Speaker 1: they will not be able to accommodate you.
Speaker 1: that place Cannot accommodate the number of people from Otacon to try to eat at it.
Speaker 0: Well, if it's not crowded when you go you can get a milkshake.
Speaker 0: It just takes a long time for them to make them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless they forget your milkshake and also they have a one-pound hamburger, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh don't eat that unless your stomach's real big now.
Speaker 1: The other thing we usually do is we go to a fancy restaurant one of the other days.
Speaker 0: Don't come to us at the fancy restaurant if you don't know us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but well if you try to follow us to the fancy restaurant You'll know if we're going to the fancy restaurant one.
Speaker 1: You probably won't have enough money because even our friends don't have enough money.
Speaker 1: We barely squeak by every year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and two that is like the front row crew like private dinner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't you don't get to come.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless we invite you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're invited you can come.
Speaker 1: I mean last year we had a good 18 or 19 people just at that one and we took up like the entire.
Speaker 1: we took up an entire giant table to the point that Like we were separated at this one table into like eight groups that were each Individually talking in a small conversation unrelated to everyone else.
Speaker 1: It was that many people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, usually, you know you go to eat somewhere and the whole table is one conversation or two conversations.
Speaker 0: this one was like six or seven conversations.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I was sitting on the end talking to Ido and Brian and Completely independent of that there were other conversations going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's crazy big table Let's see.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there was something else on here.
Speaker 0: That was interesting and I missed it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess the thing is I I highlighted events I'm interested in going to and I have highlighted something at every single point in the entire convention.
Speaker 1: and This does not even include The video game room the dealers room the artist alley the art show everything else we're doing at the con.
Speaker 0: You're probably not gonna see us in the video game room more than maybe once just so we can look at the video game room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, generally what we tend to do at Otacon is look at the video game room once and then leave it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I like to play DDR at cons But we're going to Wildwood to play on the brand new ninth mix machines that you
Speaker 0: are supernova that
Speaker 1: just came from Japan Recently, so it's
Speaker 0: like I can play video games any time While I'm at Otacon, I have to do things that you know are awesome to Otacon.
Speaker 0: So I'm not gonna spend my time playing video games or I would enter tournaments if they were interesting tournaments and not the same typical Halo Smash Brothers tournaments that you see everywhere
Speaker 1: and also I guess one kind of final kind of warning to all of our fans Hang out with us at the con.
Speaker 1: I definitely we want to hang out with you But if we all head back to our hotel room to plan something unless we specifically invite you to come We've had situations in the past with people.
Speaker 1: We don't really know just trying to follow us back to the hotel room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if we if you're invited to the hotel room You'll know it because we'll specifically invite you probably because we want to interview you or do something.
Speaker 0: If no one says to you, hey you come with us then don't come with us to places.
Speaker 0: But any place
Speaker 1: any place outside of the con
Speaker 0: exactly if we're at the convention, you can do whatever the hell you want Yeah, unless I say because then if you annoy me, I'll say go away
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also you can try to hang out with us at lunch But we're not going to save you a seat because we don't even save each other seats.
Speaker 1: It is definitely a fight to the death over food indeed indeed.
Speaker 1: So this is the last normal episode of geek nights until we get back from Wildwood and Otacon and everything.
Speaker 0: So after next week we will return.
Speaker 1: of course there will still be episodes every day next week But there will be specials and such.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So think about that work ethic.
Speaker 1: even when we're on vacation There are still podcasts going up.
Speaker 0: fear that.
Speaker 1: so don't any of you bastards ever complain if we miss an episode And hopefully we'll see you at Otacon 2006 or you're a loser.
Speaker 1: and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 1 5 3 7.
Speaker 1: geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is accorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.