Speaker 0: It's Tuesday September 5th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We complain about that old classic hero quest.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, we're back from a wonderful labor day weekend where we pretty much just labored over board games.
Speaker 1: Ah Sweet laboring.
Speaker 0: I got to say labor day used to mean a lot more to me when I had school the next day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I mean I did a lot of.
Speaker 1: actually if I figure Mathematically I did more work on Labor Day than on today.
Speaker 0: Though the thing is I mean Emily is back now, which is wonderful But she was talking about how like she was getting ready for classes because she started school today.
Speaker 1: Yeah I drove I drive by this high school on the way to work and There haven't been cars at it for months.
Speaker 1: and today there were cars at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Emily was telling me about.
Speaker 0: you know I took this class.
Speaker 0: in this class you shown him her schedule and I was.
Speaker 0: it's weird to think that I would ever even Dream of thinking something like this, but I was a little jealous cuz I kind of miss starting new classes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you remember You know the kind of feelings you got on the first day of school and around the country perhaps the world There are kids like that having those kind of feelings all this week and last week and next week.
Speaker 1: and well for us It's normal days.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: My Tuesday was no different than my previous Tuesday.
Speaker 0: I got up and I drove to Yonkers.
Speaker 1: I think part of why you know, I'm not a hundred percent satisfied with my current job is like, you know previously in life I'd have constant changes and things like okay.
Speaker 1: I'm at school.
Speaker 1: I'm at summer camp.
Speaker 1: I'm at school now.
Speaker 1: I'm somewhere else.
Speaker 1: I'd keep changing changing up every you know twice a year even just in college.
Speaker 0: different classes every 11 weeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all over the place different classes breaks, you know going on trips to places, you know going on family vacations friend vacations You know.
Speaker 1: now it's like sure I go to conventions here and there but I always return to the same thing and my Baseline is static and I need a baseline that goes all over the place to keep myself interested in life.
Speaker 0: problem is baselines that go all over the place either aren't conducive to the lifestyle we live or Don't make enough money for us to live.
Speaker 1: I know it really sucks.
Speaker 1: I need to find a way to make money and also have a moving baseline Because really a moving baseline is is the kind of life I like.
Speaker 0: Yeah Just I actually got a little jealous when she was explaining her classes to me like what she was taking because I remember I always Hated by classes at RIT because well I'd like signing up for classes and I like the first week of class because the first week nothing bad happens Nothing was assigned.
Speaker 0: You just meet your teachers and basically get to leave class early and hang out a bit Yeah, and then you know All the slacking off but I pretty much spend the rest of the quarter Hating my classes doing anything I can to get out of them early show up to them late Yeah, and
Speaker 1: the description of what you're gonna learn and the anticipation of what you're gonna learn is great.
Speaker 1: Then actually learning it is not so great except for like the few classes that are actually interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is like is there's nothing I like more than learning.
Speaker 1: but learning, you know The stuff they teach me in most of the classes is not stuff.
Speaker 1: I enjoy learning or want to learn.
Speaker 0: Scott I think I can name something that you possibly enjoy more than learning the one Form of learning I Enjoy learning.
Speaker 0: See learning is a mad as a euphemism here.
Speaker 0: Yeah for for autoerotic stimulation.
Speaker 1: Hey, I enjoy things more than that.
Speaker 1: Also speaking which I don't you're assuming that that doesn't involve learning New things.
Speaker 0: Whoever it was who posted in the forums a little while ago about some kind of story that involves some kind of monkey biting some child's um sexual member?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I believe it was already posted as advice but you need to call Penn Jillette right now because I guarantee he'll put you on The radio.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you need to do that quick.
Speaker 0: And then when you're on the radio and you're telling the story You need to relate in the story that the only reason you called is because your friends over at geek nights told you to All right, I'm not gonna be so shameless.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to actually say you should do that because I have.
Speaker 1: I want to you know Keep my shame or not have not have shame but cover.
Speaker 1: I really really want you to do that.
Speaker 1: That'd be awesome.
Speaker 0: I mean the only thing it wouldn't be as useful But it'd be funnier if you just said all as many internet catchphrases as you possibly could.
Speaker 0: oh really while you're on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really every time pen says ha ha like oh really like yeah, really?
Speaker 1: Oh my god See the thing is I don't know if I could do that without just laughing hysterically.
Speaker 0: Talking Penn would be like something something something and I'd be like, yeah And then he'd probably ask why you're laughing and then you try to explain it.
Speaker 0: Alright, we'll do something.
Speaker 0: if you just call Penn Gillette and tell him about it on the show That'll be good enough.
Speaker 0: If the word geek nights comes up in your conversation.
Speaker 0: You'll get a t-shirt when we make t-shirts yeah, and if if you do if you say geek nights and You get in at least like five catchphrases.
Speaker 0: I'll kiss you on the mouth.
Speaker 0: You also got.
Speaker 1: try to say front row crew calm Yeah.
Speaker 1: if you don't say WWW though not because I don't think you should say it because I think you should but because Penn Gillette will yell at you and That'll kind of ruin it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course, you could say it and the moment he says anything you say nope.
Speaker 0: Shut up Penn WWW yeah, and that would be funny.
Speaker 1: And then they'll find out that the guy who's are he gets WW is the guy that he's promoting.
Speaker 1: and yeah It'll be this guy Michael Godot.
Speaker 0: be like wait a minute Ram.
Speaker 1: some guy keeps sending me angry emails about this Like yeah rims the guy who does this geek night's thing.
Speaker 1: Oh What's up with that?
Speaker 0: That would be.
Speaker 0: or if you just said baba mooey baba mooey Rimming Scott's penis, you know what if he does?
Speaker 1: if it's not if I don't hear it on the next monkey Tuesday or the one after That I'm going to call it in and pretend.
Speaker 1: It's my story.
Speaker 1: You know what make up a good story about a monkey biting a penis.
Speaker 0: I will too and we'll both call in.
Speaker 0: Yeah so fair anyway Because we don't have awesome new classes to take or school is starting or anything.
Speaker 0: Today is just another day and All we did today was play or games.
Speaker 0: Well one board game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which uh, hey to brag would.
Speaker 0: no I don't absolutely love to freakin brag, but I'm on a goddamn roll when it comes to board games that involve bidding.
Speaker 0: I've won like every game we played.
Speaker 0: I bitch.
Speaker 1: He doesn't really involve that much bidding.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: Every game it's always been me Scott and Alex because now that Alex lives with us we can play board games constantly Every game.
Speaker 0: it's me and Alex and pretty much neck-and-neck.
Speaker 0: and then Scott is way behind.
Speaker 1: I wasn't way behind yesterday.
Speaker 1: Yes you were.
Speaker 1: No I wasn't.
Speaker 0: Oh no you weren't.
Speaker 1: I wasn't way behind the last time.
Speaker 1: this two times ago We played Vinci.
Speaker 0: Well you were way behind in raw at the very end when I got all those extra points.
Speaker 1: No Because Alex is so far more behind.
Speaker 1: like you had like 60 I had like 40 something and Alex had like 15.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Vinci you're not doing so well.
Speaker 1: The latest Vinci I was to suck.
Speaker 1: next time I will not to suck.
Speaker 0: You were more than half a board away.
Speaker 1: I was slightly less than half a board away.
Speaker 1: I Just didn't add my points from the final turn.
Speaker 1: wouldn't have been so many It wouldn't have been but it would have been less than half a board away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but in general it's weird because like I always win the games but Alex Oh, I mean he loses by like one point or like two points every time.
Speaker 0: Yep, we're trying to figure out is because we're kind of converging on like being as good at the game as we can be or If it's just randomness because we are playing one?
Speaker 1: He was actually good and one of you takes all my points and the question is how many points did you take away from me?
Speaker 0: You realize in most three-player games, but you're involved in I usually think all right, how can I manipulate Scott?
Speaker 0: Because you try and I do.
Speaker 0: The only reason it works because you try so hard to not be manipulated by anyone That you tend to end up being manipulated by everyone.
Speaker 0: It's no good because everyone will always say things knowing you'll do the exact opposite and that just becomes.
Speaker 1: I just don't take what anyone Says into account and making my decision.
Speaker 1: I just go by what I think is the Worst move at least in this game.
Speaker 1: I did good two times ago.
Speaker 0: You did well, I didn't know you didn't.
Speaker 1: I did good deeds.
Speaker 0: No, you didn't hit it.
Speaker 0: You did nothing but conquer barbarians.
Speaker 1: That's a good deed.
Speaker 0: The barbarians a bad guy, but the barbarians in that game are nothing but peaceful.
Speaker 1: No, no, they're very not peaceful.
Speaker 0: They sit there.
Speaker 0: They got one guy.
Speaker 0: No There were eight people.
Speaker 0: Thank God All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we got some news.
Speaker 1: So there is a game a very somewhat old game called mech commander.
Speaker 1: now we like them battle techs.
Speaker 0: We used to play battle tech as often as we could at our IT which wasn't often.
Speaker 1: No, but battle tech is awesome and The closest you can get to battle tech on the computer is well, there's a thing called.
Speaker 1: What's it called?
Speaker 1: It's called like something mech.
Speaker 1: I forget I forget the name of it But it's like an open-source thing with a poor interface that lets you play battle tech on the computer.
Speaker 1: Not the greatest thing in the world.
Speaker 1: but there is mech commander which is a game made by Microsoft who owns the video game rights to battle tech because they bought the faster corporation and They made mech commander, which is essentially turn-based battle tech strategy kind of for the computer and It is now free.
Speaker 1: So go to mech commander org and you can play mech commander for free.
Speaker 1: download the full version.
Speaker 1: Just there it is.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 0: Now these sorts of like playing these cut, you know robot fighting games tend to be very Realistic in the sense that that's how war kind of goes because it's mostly just kind of random.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing battle tech is sort of a sci-fi.
Speaker 1: What if we there, you know, we really did develop, you know, bipedal walking war machines What would they be like?
Speaker 1: and this is it's a lot more realistic than say Gundam or Evangelion.
Speaker 1: now Evangelion is perfectly real is not even close If the Christians are right, maybe yeah, this is likely the Jews Yeah, but it also has you know a crazy sci-fi outer space super futuristic universe with clans and things and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But that is only the story and it doesn't involve in the game.
Speaker 0: It's no gassaraki.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: but Battle take a school mech commanders cool and it's free.
Speaker 1: Hey grottus free not libra free.
Speaker 0: All right This isn't video game related news.
Speaker 0: But and I'm not getting this I'm this is now going to be subject to Jack Thompson syndrome.
Speaker 0: in That I can't.
Speaker 0: I won't talk about this again unless something crazy happens But I have to talk about this one because this is pretty much the final Straw that was nailed into the coffin that that broke the camel's back.
Speaker 0: You know, the d-bold voting machines are totally broken and easily hacked.
Speaker 0: everyone knows that.
Speaker 0: it's been reported widely.
Speaker 0: There are videos everywhere showing how absolutely trivial it is.
Speaker 1: They had a monkey do it.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: That is not a joke.
Speaker 0: They trained a monkey to manipulate the results of a d-bold voting machine Just now.
Speaker 0: well a little while ago someone did a little photo blog and they got a hold of some d-bold equipment and There's this little seal thing that's supposed to show that no one was able to physically tamper with the memory card that holds the results.
Speaker 0: And they were able now keep in mind.
Speaker 0: This isn't anyone special.
Speaker 0: This isn't an engineer or anything with no training or skill or really anything whatsoever.
Speaker 0: What about tools like a screwdriver?
Speaker 0: They were able to trivially remove the seal do whatever they wanted to the memory card Put the memory card back and replace the seal as though it had never been removed Thus completely defeating the purpose of the seal.
Speaker 0: it could be done one-handed in less than five minutes Awesome.
Speaker 0: Now I'm wondering because a lot of places use these machines.
Speaker 0: There's elections coming up and there's a lot of geeks who are pissed off about politics.
Speaker 0: now I am NOT advocating that anyone do anything.
Speaker 0: far be it for me to tell you to do something horribly illegal.
Speaker 0: But wouldn't it be funny?
Speaker 1: I mean you're behind a curtain in with voting.
Speaker 0: wouldn't it be funny if a whole bunch of geeks all over the place just screwed with the results of every election they could and Some crazy third parties won?
Speaker 1: not bad crazy third parties only good crazy.
Speaker 0: There's the problem.
Speaker 0: It's the internet.
Speaker 0: So one activist would make like I don't know the Green Party win and then the next four guys would all make Chuck Norris win.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah That'll be the right in but that's it.
Speaker 1: If everyone in the whole town wrote in Chuck Norris for mayor.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, that would be the best thing ever.
Speaker 0: Either that or I just make 10 million.
Speaker 0: by make it I mean, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: if I were to do something like this Which I'm not and I'm not advocating that anyone do this because it is horribly illegal.
Speaker 0: Yep I would make it so it showed I don't know a billion votes for like Ford Prefects.
Speaker 0: That would be awesome because you don't want to actually manipulate the election.
Speaker 0: You just want to show people that yeah, that machine was broken and it got hacked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if they if you do it to every voting machine in there.
Speaker 1: so let's say your vote your local voting place has five d-ball voting machine.
Speaker 0: in this hypothetical world five nerds.
Speaker 1: one goes in each booth and you hack each and every one of them and then You know that place will have to redo their election and they'll not use those machines the next time.
Speaker 1: and if they redo the election Go in and hack it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just it bothers me.
Speaker 0: they don't change.
Speaker 0: it doesn't bother me so much that these voting machines are so bad.
Speaker 0: What bothers me is that it's widely known among geeks and technologists that the voting machines are completely broken and hackable But the rest of the country has no idea and the news doesn't report on this at all.
Speaker 1: Well, we don't.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the news reports because I don't watch.
Speaker 0: no one knows.
Speaker 0: No one knows.
Speaker 0: I defy you to find someone who doesn't read.
Speaker 1: I think that this is finally time.
Speaker 1: We should just take advantage of it and the geek should take over the country.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 0: They probably just shoot us with their guns.
Speaker 1: I mean we've all but if we vote We've all played a lot of counter-strike.
Speaker 0: don't think that's gonna help so much.
Speaker 1: But if we voted into power then one of us would be in charge of the armies and then we'd win.
Speaker 0: Somehow I see the hypothetical plan that we're not in any way advocating failing exactly.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Once again, I'm not advocating that you in any way tamper with lecture results but go to You know the website that shows how to do it and watch it and carefully, you know.
Speaker 0: What really bothers me is that it's so easy to make an electronic voting machine that works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you and I in a few days could make a complete voting machine.
Speaker 0: That was absolutely untamperable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably Let me the hard part would be machining it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the software part is nothing.
Speaker 1: the software part is trivial.
Speaker 1: It has some memory enough to store two really big numbers, you know, well a bunch of really big numbers for all the candidates and It increments them whenever someone pushes a button Yeah and then digital signatures to make sure it hasn't been tampered with.
Speaker 0: yeah and then you print out what someone voted for and it appears under glass and Then when they make their vote that piece of paper also gets stored in the machine.
Speaker 0: So no matter what there's a perfect physical record.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Just a big metal bucket.
Speaker 0: Oh Deebold if you're listening, uh, I'll work for half whatever you paid your lowest paid engineer.
Speaker 0: Yeah on your voting machines.
Speaker 1: Yeah I would work for Deebold to design the voting machines that they paid me enough and They admitted that there are other voting machines are crap and took them back.
Speaker 0: You don't even have to admit it publicly just admit it to me and I'll be happy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's all I want.
Speaker 0: I don't care if you lied everyone else, but don't lie to me.
Speaker 1: and Also, let us know if you break the elections before that way, you know, yeah, I'm curious.
Speaker 1: you can blow the whistle.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't care cuz John Kerry probably wouldn't have been the best president either.
Speaker 1: They both suck, but it's not the point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not the point at all.
Speaker 0: And for everyone who's been kind of asking what our political affiliations were if you can't figure that out.
Speaker 0: I know Anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: All right now the Mississippi State drum corps Did a pretty cool little?
Speaker 0: Video game related show recently that made it to a Kotaku and there's a terrible barely watchable video of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at first I thought they're real cool and it is really cool.
Speaker 1: But the video does not do the justice.
Speaker 1: In fact, it doesn't injustice.
Speaker 0: well, basically the guy who filmed it is on the wrong side of the stadium and He's got a crappy camera with a crappy microphone and he's kind of far away.
Speaker 0: Yeah However, you can kind of tell what's going on And once you realize what's going on you realize that had you been there it would have been pretty badass.
Speaker 0: And Mississippi their marching band their core is very large as in 300 plus.
Speaker 0: That is a lot of people marching and it's they can make very complex very detailed marching forms.
Speaker 0: It's really cool to see.
Speaker 1: I mean the buttons on there any as controller move.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they had a cord on it.
Speaker 0: They actually made a cord out of.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to use the term we used for them when I was in high school But the flag car people Mm-hmm the flaggies.
Speaker 0: No, no, no eggs.
Speaker 0: now Okay, it's far worse than that.
Speaker 1: Anyway So I found this cool game like it's funny that yeah It's funny that both of my I news and my thing of the day today are free games.
Speaker 1: But so what's free now?
Speaker 1: Well, it's not a game.
Speaker 1: That was all that was not free and is now free.
Speaker 1: But it's actually a game that is free and might become not free.
Speaker 1: but There's a game some guy made called zombie city tactics and you can download the zombie city tactics For free from this guy's website.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Zombie city tactics is like this incredibly simple Turn-based strategy game for the PC on Windows.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we'll run into wine just fine because it's just so simple and all you do is they start you in a scenario in which there are zombies and they're your guys and you basically you know you take your turn is a square grid and you move your guys and You can move them one space north south east west or diagonal or you can make them stand still and then the zombies move one Space and then you move one space now if a zombie moves on to your guy you die.
Speaker 1: If you move on to a zombie it dies.
Speaker 1: So the idea is you want to move your guys on to the zombies?
Speaker 1: But you want to end your turn not being adjacent to zombies.
Speaker 1: Now it gets a little interesting because you have some guys who can kill Zombies from one space away without moving on to them.
Speaker 1: You have guys that can move two spaces and there's a zombie generator making a constant stream of zombies.
Speaker 1: So I actually haven't figured out the pattern to beating the very first level yet.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'm an idiot or what.
Speaker 0: I think you should apply your much vaulted skills at Vinci Yeah to solving this problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just I only tried it three times.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure with a little more effort I would have figured it out, but it's pretty hard until you figure out what to do.
Speaker 0: See now Scott It's really interesting and simple.
Speaker 0: I haven't played this game and I'll bet many of our listeners haven't played this game.
Speaker 0: if even one of them solves it Right away.
Speaker 1: I don't think you will do it on the first try.
Speaker 1: However, I have one piece of advice.
Speaker 1: read the.
Speaker 1: read me because I didn't realize you could buy more units and stuff like that right away.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, but it's a cool fun free game.
Speaker 1: You should try it out.
Speaker 0: You have learned.
Speaker 0: well, my friends now is come the time of your first trial.
Speaker 0: You must first enter the catacombs which contain foul mugs - you must seek out and destroy there Foul gargoyle who hides in these catacombs.
Speaker 0: This quest is not easy and you must work together in order to survive.
Speaker 0: This is your first step on the roads to becoming true heroes.
Speaker 0: trade carefully my friends.
Speaker 1: Hey, what if I don't go?
Speaker 0: Well, then that just kind of fucks the whole game in the veritable ass now, doesn't it?
Speaker 1: I think it does.
Speaker 1: I don't see too much motivation for the characters here.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: of course you should go into this catacomb and fight a gargoyle who never bothered them.
Speaker 1: It doesn't even know who they are for no reason.
Speaker 0: now Here's the important part that Alex did not read to us when we played the first time.
Speaker 0: Okay, Zargon You may tell everyone that there are no traps or secret doors in this quest.
Speaker 1: Oh, how did they know if that that means someone was down there already?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know that there's no secret doors or traps.
Speaker 0: I got to say the best part of this game is the flavor text.
Speaker 1: Yeah, wait, if we knew that that means someone's been down there Which means why do we have to go and fight if someone can already go down there survive and come back?
Speaker 1: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: The game's not that well thought out.
Speaker 0: the game it isn't.
Speaker 1: I think that is the number one thing that can be said about this game.
Speaker 0: The game is hero quest.
Speaker 1: Yes hero quest is.
Speaker 1: it's a Milton Bradley, right?
Speaker 0: It is a Milton Bradley.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's an old Milton Bradley game that they I'm pretty sure they don't make anymore because they make hero escape now Which is something else entirely.
Speaker 0: now the way hero quest works It is a game that's kind of like old-school beer and pretzel style D&D, but it comes in a box with everything you need.
Speaker 0: One person plays god.
Speaker 0: What's the stupid thing's name?
Speaker 0: Zargon, you're basically the Dungeon Master.
Speaker 0: you control all the monsters.
Speaker 0: You have the book that I'm holding in my hand right now that shows you know where everything is and how to deal with everything Mm-hmm, and then You are basically adversarial to the party which consists of up to four people who play four different characters the elf the dwarf the barbarian and the wizard and
Speaker 1: All you do really is there's a square grid and your old dice to see how much you move.
Speaker 1: so every character moves and then The monsters move and then the characters move in.
Speaker 1: the monsters move and if they're adjacent They can fight.
Speaker 1: and your old dice to see how you fight.
Speaker 1: and there's no levels or anything.
Speaker 1: There's just equipment and you can search for treasure to get more equipment and gold.
Speaker 1: and in between levels you can use gold to buy equipment.
Speaker 1: and That's about it.
Speaker 1: It's the players versus the Dungeon Master in a just dungeon crawl With.
Speaker 1: and if there's gonna be any role-playing the game isn't gonna help you at all with that.
Speaker 1: It's all you.
Speaker 0: the game.
Speaker 0: In fact kinda really prevents any sort of role-playing.
Speaker 0: There's no way to talk to anyone you meet.
Speaker 0: There is no way to bargain with anyone.
Speaker 0: There is no way to in any way interact with anyone by any means other than your sword.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty much the only things you can do in this game are walk search for treasure search for traps search for secret doors and Fight.
Speaker 0: now fighting is composed of attacking with a weapon or casting a spell possibly if you were at the kind of person who can cast spells and All of it pretty much comes down to randomness.
Speaker 1: I mean you either play a card, you know And it just works or you roll some dice to see how much damage goes down.
Speaker 0: Well, but it really comes down to is that it is a fun game for like a father to play with his kids Or a mother to play with his with her kids.
Speaker 0: or Like if I'm uncle rim someday to someone's kids I'll run this game for them because little kids can have a lot of fun with this game.
Speaker 0: and when I was a kid I actually played all of hero quest with my dad and my little brother and occasionally my mom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't play until college.
Speaker 0: Wow, see when I saw hero quest at our way I thought oh and this whole flood of memory came back because I played the barbarian and my little brother played the elf and occasionally my mom would play.
Speaker 0: and when she did she was the dwarf.
Speaker 0: and We went through the entire thing where my dad was the DM and he won played the game much more Evily than he probably could have.
Speaker 0: he made basically the game.
Speaker 0: the monsters are all complete chumps Except for the super badass monsters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically every monster has one hit point.
Speaker 1: So you just to hit it once and it dies.
Speaker 1: a few monsters have more hit a couple monsters have two and pretty much in Any dungeon most of the monsters you're gonna meet have one.
Speaker 1: So you just kill them all and then this one boss who has more than one hit point I just gang up on him to beat him in like one or two turns.
Speaker 0: now The only way the game is not broken really is if you play it with people who aren't gonna play the game Optimally like a bunch of kids.
Speaker 0: They won't know the optimal way and they won't figure out the optimal way to beat this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'll have fun.
Speaker 1: Just walking around exploring a dungeon rolling dice and moving a guy.
Speaker 1: I mean if you like Candyland hero questions is that much better?
Speaker 0: well, also the game is really well done in that it has a big board with a bunch of rooms on it and The game is revealed to you and each setup is different as you walk around
Speaker 1: Yeah, and as things are revealed like this cool plastic furniture that comes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the props that come with this game are numerous.
Speaker 0: However, I will note that the props while they're all fairly well done have absolutely no gameplay purpose whatsoever.
Speaker 1: However, they can sometimes get.
Speaker 1: well, no, that's not true.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they give hints as to the treasure that is in the room and sometimes not as in there's a Treasure chest in the room.
Speaker 0: if you search for treasure, you'll probably find something.
Speaker 1: but sometimes the treasure chest in the room and you search the treasure and there isn't any and sometimes they'll be like a. You know a cabinet in the room and you'll search your treasure and it'll say in the in the bookcase you find whatever And it's like oh my god the flavor text match the furniture.
Speaker 0: Yeah now I know later in the game because I don't remember everything but later in the game There's like one a fireplace and when you pull it it moves away and it makes a secret door and there's stuff back there.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now the game is.
Speaker 0: it's really only fun if you're a little kid and the game is made to be adversarial.
Speaker 0: It's basically the Dungeon Master against the players.
Speaker 0: It's not really balanced.
Speaker 0: So the Dungeon Master is probably gonna lose It's not unless he cheats.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: when I played it was just me and my brother most of the time as a kid.
Speaker 0: So my dad basically had to play sub optimally or we would have just died.
Speaker 0: So he just kind of made it fun for us kids.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I think that's it either has to be that way or it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: because I mean there's some games that are you know Just like this kind of like Dracula where?
Speaker 1: Fury of Dracula.
Speaker 1: Dracula is sort of like the evil wizard and that you know, it's him versus the players but really he's just making the game interesting for the players.
Speaker 1: or what's the doom?
Speaker 1: where one guy controls the demons and the everyone else controls doom guys and you're controlling the demons you can win.
Speaker 1: and Mutant Chronicles and all the other similar type games, you know.
Speaker 1: But in hero quest the DM really can't win and the other games he can.
Speaker 0: now There are a lot of expansions to this game.
Speaker 0: There was a barbarian and an elf solo quest Whoa that Ryan as a kid.
Speaker 0: there are also a whole bunch of other expansions that Alex has and I also had.
Speaker 0: and then there are Things like advanced hero quest which we won't talk about.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about it.
Speaker 1: So we can't talk about it.
Speaker 0: I never actually played it or saw it in person, but it looked real fancy.
Speaker 1: Yep but generally the problem with hero quest is that if you are an intelligent person you will realize that number one monsters can't open doors.
Speaker 1: so in any given map if There aren't any you know monsters about like you've killed every monster that's you know Roaming the hallways and every monster in all the rooms You've already opened then there can't possibly be a monster unless you decide to search for treasure.
Speaker 0: So I guess at this point what we'll do is we'll describe how we caused Alex to pull all of his hair out.
Speaker 1: Yes, and so you have a map.
Speaker 1: every door is closed and there are no monsters and which means Nothing can happen to the players unless they search for treasure or open a door.
Speaker 1: Now you roll dice to see how many spaces you move.
Speaker 1: well, if there are no monsters and you don't search your treasure and the only you know, you basically Roll a bunch of.
Speaker 1: you don't have to roll dice You just go wherever you want to go for free.
Speaker 0: because essentially what you do is you roll the dice move roll the dice Move roll the dice move and it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Yeah You can just keep rolling forever and ever and ever and nothing can ever happen to you or change you can.
Speaker 1: you can do That till the end of time until you have your little.
Speaker 1: you know Your adventures in the exact squares you want them to be in.
Speaker 0: So what did we do?
Speaker 0: We arranged ourselves seating wise in the optimal player order.
Speaker 0: we would then arrange ourselves perfectly outside of each door.
Speaker 0: I would then say I take 12 meaning I'm informing Alex that I'm going to sit here and roll 2d6 Continually until I roll a 12 and everyone is just going to stand still outside the door until they roll a 12.
Speaker 0: Yes, and then once I and then basically I said we didn't have to actually roll it out because obviously it's going to happen at Some point.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So then we'd kick open the door rush in and kill everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah basically Because we choose what order we go in we can kill all the monsters because you only have one hit point before they have a chance to even hit us.
Speaker 0: occasionally a monster would survive long enough to hit at us once and it might not hit because we Collect all the equipment.
Speaker 1: I mean then we would arrange ourselves in each and every room perfectly.
Speaker 1: Search your treasure once to make sure there wasn't any default treasure and the worst that would happen is one monster would show up.
Speaker 1: You'd immediately kill.
Speaker 0: I Just wonder where that monster came from.
Speaker 0: We're in a tiny room.
Speaker 0: It's completely empty.
Speaker 1: He was he was like the predator.
Speaker 1: He was invisible and then it ran out.
Speaker 1: So then he's like, oh shit, and we got him.
Speaker 1: You know That's where that monster came from and we would do this for each and every room in the game until we collected all the treasure And beat all the bad guys.
Speaker 1: rinse and repeat the game is boring.
Speaker 1: if you know what you're doing.
Speaker 0: three treasure chests have been stolen while being taken to the Emperor.
Speaker 0: a reward of 240 gold coins has been offered to any group of heroes who can return the chest and all of the goals.
Speaker 1: You know, it would be much cooler if it was say two groups of two heroes competing to get the treasure or if it was Like you met other adventurers down there who are NPCs who you'd fight to get the treasure or something like that.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing one of the things that bothers me about the game.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna complain about the game because the game is made for little kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I remember there's Milton Bradley people.
Speaker 0: now I am a reading ahead in the book Which if Alex ever wants to run the game for us, I just spoiled something.
Speaker 0: But I'll note that I've played through all of your requests before.
Speaker 0: you don't remember it though But I remember this one and that's why I want to talk about it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Now think about what I just said.
Speaker 0: a reward of 240 gold coins has been offered any group of heroes who can return the chest and all the gold.
Speaker 0: So I we go off to get the chest and if you beat this dungeon, you find that there are three chests each of which contains 250 gold coins, so why would you?
Speaker 0: 750 gold plus a whole bunch of other items of value to the prince and Emperor.
Speaker 1: So why would you give it back to the king?
Speaker 1: Just keep it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: All right here.
Speaker 0: I'll read the text under here.
Speaker 0: There are three chests.
Speaker 0: They are marked with the prince's royal symbol.
Speaker 0: each chest is locked and contains 250 gold coins and other items of value to the prince and Emperor.
Speaker 0: a Hero can carry only one chest at a time.
Speaker 0: when carrying a chest the hero may only roll one red die for movement.
Speaker 0: All right, the heroes cannot keep the gold inside the treasure chests, huh, why not?
Speaker 0: The heroes cannot keep the gold inside the treasure chest period then why even specify how much is in there?
Speaker 1: Why not make it some other McGuffin?
Speaker 0: because they're sadists Because I remember when I was a kid and we we were kind of weak and my dad won.
Speaker 0: My dad kind of cheated and he gave like all the monsters magic and he was just putting us.
Speaker 0: Well, we ended up like getting the monsters in the chest room to chase us away.
Speaker 0: Then we ran back in and grabbed the chest and kind of bit by bit got the three chests out.
Speaker 0: And then we had the dwarf pick the lock and we opened him and we were like, we're just not going back We're keeping the gold.
Speaker 0: and my dad says you can't keep the gold.
Speaker 0: and I said why not?
Speaker 0: And I said you just can't keep.
Speaker 0: and he said you can't keep the gold Yeah, and my brother and I raised holy living hell over there.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh Rim what breaking news for rim.
Speaker 0: breaking news breaking news.
Speaker 1: You're ready.
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: Capcom classics minis mini mix screenshots.
Speaker 1: on September 19th Capcom will release Capcom Capcom class classics mini mix for the GBA.
Speaker 1: the game re-releases the NES versions of Strider and mighty final fight and Bionic commando GBA cart for 1995 that is already purchased.
Speaker 1: I September 19th 2006 look his screenshots look a good fucking guy.
Speaker 1: It's just an emulator of how to commando.
Speaker 0: I Hope they don't dumb down bionic commando.
Speaker 1: It's it's the NES game just default.
Speaker 1: It's an emulator.
Speaker 1: You're basically buying, you know an NES emulator and a ROM on a GBA cartridge.
Speaker 0: That game bionic is also mighty.
Speaker 1: final fight in Strider.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Strider was okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but bionic commando is probably my second favorite Nintendo game ever.
Speaker 1: All right here request.
Speaker 1: but that was breaking news that could not be denied.
Speaker 1: I just found it.
Speaker 0: It is gaming day.
Speaker 0: So it fits.
Speaker 1: Yep Okay here.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Not as good as bionic commando.
Speaker 0: heroes cannot keep the gold inside the treasure chests.
Speaker 1: No, they can but bionic commando can steal your coins.
Speaker 0: The other thing I find fascinating about this game is that the way it's set up.
Speaker 0: there are a whole bunch of quests and The second quest is really easy.
Speaker 0: The third quest is really easy and they get progressively more difficult as you go on but not unmanageably.
Speaker 1: So yeah It's like the first quest is way harder than the second third fourth.
Speaker 0: That's what I was gonna say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you kind of ruined it.
Speaker 0: I was gonna build it up and do something funny.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, but instead you just came out with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just I just dumped right out there.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna pretend Scott didn't say that.
Speaker 0: Okay now.
Speaker 0: Then you go back and you realize that there's you know quest one because I said it starts at quest two and gets easier.
Speaker 0: quest one is Harder than any other fucking quest in this whole game.
Speaker 0: Oh my good God Do the monsters just rape you in the ass repeatedly?
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of it is that in the first level you have no items and no equipment.
Speaker 0: Also, there are more monsters than in like any other dungeon in the first one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I think what they want to do is you know, the first time you're playing the game That's what you're gonna do.
Speaker 0: So, you know, they want to make sure that it's a no They want to scare you because what one of these rooms probably the most bitching room in the game is.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's.
Speaker 0: there's a room with a tomb and a whole bunch of crap and there's stuff all over the place.
Speaker 0: But and there's really really dangerous things to fight everywhere and the heroes are barely gonna survive.
Speaker 0: One room has two chaos warriors, which are pretty much the badasses of this game.
Speaker 0: in that room It's a treasure chest.
Speaker 0: in that treasure chest is bupkis.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: bupkis, okay.
Speaker 0: Also There's an armory.
Speaker 0: in the first dungeon you go into this armory and there's monsters defending it you kill them.
Speaker 0: What would you think you would do if you just killed monsters?
Speaker 0: and there's an obvious prop of a whole bunch of nice shiny weapons.
Speaker 1: Take the shiny weapons.
Speaker 0: the weapons on this weapons rack are chipped rusted and broken.
Speaker 0: There is nothing here that the heroes would want.
Speaker 1: they're better than my nothing.
Speaker 1: I'm using nothing.
Speaker 0: at the beginning of the you know, you had a serviceable short sword and I had a serviceable long.
Speaker 0: So no, I didn't even have a long sword.
Speaker 0: I had a broad.
Speaker 1: So I would rather take a chipped and rusted bastard sword than a serviceable short sword.
Speaker 0: Well, hey, at least you bought that stick and then immediately found a stick.
Speaker 1: I know it's like I paid how many gold for a hundred.
Speaker 1: I paid a hundred gold pieces, which is like God $10,000.
Speaker 1: All right for a stick that I could have gotten in the woods for free.
Speaker 1: And then I'm in a dungeon killing things with my stick and you know what?
Speaker 1: I find a stick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: There's a stick.
Speaker 1: Oh great,
Speaker 0: ooh I probably shouldn't look at this so much but and I just flipped through and I was gonna say that the nice thing about this Game that I thought was really cool, especially as a kid is that it gives you in the back a template Where you can make your own dungeons.
Speaker 0: They they urge you to photocopy these two pages and then cut and paste with you know Your little paste and scissors and make dungeons and continue playing the game.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So the game is basically infinite playtime.
Speaker 0: Yeah And I see here that Alex or someone in his family has at some point made in pencil a dungeon and the goblins look Really really happy really?
Speaker 1: Let me see.
Speaker 0: the goblins are cute little happy goblins.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'll have to give me the little paper.
Speaker 1: Let me check the goblins out.
Speaker 1: Oh happy goblin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think Alex did this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder if he even knows it's in there.
Speaker 0: maybe Alex by the way is our Dungeon master.
Speaker 0: among other things he is one of our staunchest board game players and he's currently downstairs playing Final Fantasy legend, too.
Speaker 0: He may or may not be listening to us while we record the show live.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know but he drew happy.
Speaker 0: He did mention at one point that he feels like listening to geek nights is redundant if you live with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess that would be exactly true because this is what we say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you realize when we start recording.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much in the middle of a conversation just like this and when we stop recording we Continue this exact conversation.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm geek nights could go almost 24/7.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, there really aren't that many dungeons in this game.
Speaker 1: No, no, oh wait, if you look at the size of dungeon one and just compare it to the sizes of the other dungeons Yeah, and the number of green guys and furniture is just way more In.
Speaker 0: just remember one hero quest is really fun in College to play a little bit with people who don't know what this game is about.
Speaker 1: Hero quest is good.
Speaker 1: If people don't know how to play the people are little kids or people are drunk.
Speaker 0: It's also really fun If you played it as a kid to play it again just enough to realize how much smarter you are now.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a castle of mystery.
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Okay, so this game can get a little creative, but it still doesn't fix it entirely and I hate to say it But that's it.
Speaker 0: I would have read the flavor text from beating hero quest, but that's a spoiler.
Speaker 0: It's so anti-climactic that I could not bring that pain upon you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway in terms of meta bits The only thing I think is if you apply for membership to the forums Which you should if you're not already a member of the forums then you do not receive an email that says Congratulations.
Speaker 1: You are now a member of the forums.
Speaker 1: You got that email.
Speaker 1: your spam filter just filtered it out especially if you're using hotmail, so If you apply to the forums just come back like a day later and just sign in and it'll work.
Speaker 0: and of course the forums Are rocking.
Speaker 0: as always the forums are practically an entire separate show at this point.
Speaker 1: Yes, so go to front row crew.
Speaker 1: calm everybody.
Speaker 0: Oh, here it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just realized here's the real flavor text which I won't read because it's an entire page.
Speaker 0: Okay, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at Www.front row crew.
Speaker 1: calm.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206 1 5 3 7.
Speaker 0: geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.