Speaker 1: It's Wednesday September 6th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We review mobile suit Gundam.
Speaker 1: see Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know more and more.
Speaker 0: I'm starting to be of the mind that if you cause a car accident And it's rush hour the police should just bulldoze your car off the side of the road and they'll deal with you after rush Hours over.
Speaker 1: yeah, I think that's what they should do.
Speaker 1: you know what actually I thought about this some more in the a1 grand Pre not the f1 grand pre.
Speaker 1: the a1 grand pre if a car crashes You know how they get it off the track.
Speaker 0: with the giant crane.
Speaker 1: no with a giant helicopter A helicopter comes over picks up your car and goes away.
Speaker 1: It takes like a minute, but it's because the helicopters right there.
Speaker 1: But you know a helicopter you get there pretty quick, and how expensive that would be.
Speaker 1: it is that the a1 grand free is very.
Speaker 1: What's the the words expensive?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: It's all froofy and rich people, but you know hoity-toity Heard of that kind of raising.
Speaker 0: how does it make money?
Speaker 1: The a1 grand free is sort of like the international Race of whatever where everyone gets the same car, and there's not every.
Speaker 1: no no no I mean since a different country I'd never heard of it because everyone outside the US actually cares.
Speaker 1: I'm sure especially lots of rich Arab guys in Dubai.
Speaker 1: Aha Who own it all right?
Speaker 0: Anyway, I just found it funny that I was once again five miles from my house And then there was an accident somewhere off in the distance on Interstate 84 Which since it's one of the two roads that goes east-west in the Dutchess County Completely stopped all traffic within about 40 miles.
Speaker 0: No of course being clever I Pulled a bit of shenanigans.
Speaker 0: I turned away from where this was and then I went around a loop-de-loop.
Speaker 0: And then I know and I end up skipping all of these people and all this crazy traffic That was stuck trying to get out of the street.
Speaker 0: I needed to get on thus saving myself about 40 minutes.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 0: I can't believe no one ever thinks to do anything like that.
Speaker 0: I didn't do anything illegal.
Speaker 0: I just turning left.
Speaker 0: There was like a dumb two mile line to turn left and That you couldn't turn left because the road was blocked.
Speaker 0: so it went really slow and like one car get through every light cycle if That so I went up with no resistance at all past all these cars.
Speaker 0: I turned right and Then I just did a u-turn on the street right there and now I'm on the street I need to be on and I just go straight through the next light.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah I Couldn't believe no one thought of that and I looked and the same car that was sitting there at the front of this trying to Get in was still sitting there by the time I had made it back to the road and then I went past him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is if everyone did do it, it probably It would.
Speaker 1: it would free up one part of the road, but then it would go.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not saying everyone should do it.
Speaker 0: That'd be terrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just wonder why no one ever thinks to do anything like that.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I think to do things like that But you know really depends on the road and where you're trying to get to is always a big factor because it's like yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I know like before we were both stuck in a traffic jam once and I remember you Were sitting there gurgle girl.
Speaker 0: I cut off to the left and it drove around crazily and all these side streets and ended up at you Yeah by two cars.
Speaker 0: I knew that that wouldn't help that much, you know, you know what it would have if I would have had Balls to drive up a one-way street.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I didn't.
Speaker 1: I sat there and I thought about it and I didn't have the cajones I know because I knew that that didn't go as far enough to be useful.
Speaker 1: and then we got to another part where it was Essentially a gamble.
Speaker 1: I could either I knew that I could go straight or turn right and I figured okay going right is probably more Road, but there's probably no traffic on it.
Speaker 1: going straight is less road But if there's no traffic, I'll get there quicker and if there is traffic, I'm screwed.
Speaker 0: So I went right and and then uh, yeah, I went straight and there was no traffic at all.
Speaker 1: Hey, it was a gamble, you know, and it didn't get there much later than you maybe like five minutes.
Speaker 0: Don't worry Atlantic City paid for that gas.
Speaker 1: Yeah Gas is going down now.
Speaker 1: So it's not so bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's funny that it's really affecting me and I have I'm losing much more much less money per week.
Speaker 0: Suddenly.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean a difference of 30, you know, 20 30 cents really matters.
Speaker 1: Well difference of for me like when I bought gas in New Jersey, I saved like six bucks, you know And that's like six bucks a week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not bad.
Speaker 0: I use more than a tank a week.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know I use like a tank in some a week.
Speaker 1: I Didn't go to work today though.
Speaker 1: So I use less.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway in the news now I can't wait till next week to talk about this and I I didn't think I'd ever have any more news about Sony until they released the PlayStation 3 and I can't believe That they got not one but two Double horrible whammies of death in the news today.
Speaker 1: But I can believe it because that it happens every single day.
Speaker 0: Why hasn't the CEO of Sony committed seppuku yet?
Speaker 0: This is like it's not even to the point of yeah, so he's getting what they deserved.
Speaker 0: if they're just being there I don't know what's going on anymore.
Speaker 0: I can't believe they would be this incompetent.
Speaker 1: They I mean if only they weren't Japanese we could interview them.
Speaker 0: I mean I rip on Sony all the time for you know, the things they've been doing lately.
Speaker 0: But they're not.
Speaker 0: at least I didn't think that they were run by stupid people because the PlayStation 2 and the PlayStation 1 Made crazy amounts of money when no one really expected them to originally.
Speaker 0: I mean they went up against the monopoly.
Speaker 1: the ultimate Nintendo Maybe that's the trick is when you know when you're the underdog in an industry where there's actually competition you actually try and end up doing well and When you're so high up you just think ah ha ha ha and then you fail.
Speaker 1: I mean if you look at video game consoles over history, you know people it's basically someone becomes dominant But they never stay dominant.
Speaker 1: Everyone goes up and then crashes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least recently I mean when Nintendo went up it was the undisputed king for a long time and then it came down But it managed.
Speaker 1: it was up for so long that it was able to hold out through the long course.
Speaker 0: Everyone Sega didn't say it didn't but everyone always forgets that the GameCube was number two for a long time.
Speaker 0: And while the Xbox eventually edged it out by a tiny bit in the u.s.
Speaker 1: It didn't edge it out anywhere else.
Speaker 0: Yeah worldwide the GameCube is number two not number three.
Speaker 0: Well, if you don't count like the Xbox 360 or whatever Well, yeah, but I wouldn't count the Wii either or the PSP.
Speaker 1: I know in terms of the pre the Generation the ending generation the presently ending generation the GameCube was number two in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so take that even though you're up in places.
Speaker 0: No one gives a shit about the GameCube yeah, but anyway the news about Sony first was that they've decided to Cut back on their release and instead of releasing it worldwide this year.
Speaker 0: They claim sometime in November possibly They're only releasing it in the US and Japan now and the rest of the world isn't getting it until at the earliest March of next year.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much standard fare.
Speaker 1: I mean the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah doesn't get anything.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is alright.
Speaker 0: I'm fine with that and originally they said it was gonna come out quarter one of next year.
Speaker 0: But then they said no, we're gonna have a worldwide release this year.
Speaker 1: When did they say that?
Speaker 0: a while ago?
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, and then they came back and said nope We pushed back the release for everywhere.
Speaker 0: That isn't us in Japan.
Speaker 1: I think it's just hard for me now to follow like which things are Sony press releases or Sony and people saying something You know and some guy just saying something he found out and I just really don't care anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, then almost immediately and slash shot picked this up right away.
Speaker 0: It was reported just why they had done this.
Speaker 0: Remember that blue laser diode thing.
Speaker 0: Yep There's basically this thing that blu-ray needs and it's for some reason either difficult to manufacture or something happened.
Speaker 0: But there aren't enough of them in the world and they can't be made fast enough.
Speaker 0: as a result instead of having two million PlayStation 3 is ready for the launch.
Speaker 0: They're going to have maybe 500,000. well, that's not enough.
Speaker 0: 400,000 of them are going to the u.s.
Speaker 0: And 100,000 are going to Japan.
Speaker 1: Wait, why would they give more to the u.s When Japan?
Speaker 0: that's what I was about to say.
Speaker 0: because while the u.s.
Speaker 0: Is a larger market the Japanese Despite the fact that Sony isn't doing so well.
Speaker 0: There is this loyalty towards Sony that is somewhat fierce over there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would just sell them all in Japan and not only will will.
Speaker 0: this probably generate a lot of ill will for Sony in Japan.
Speaker 0: But I don't even know anymore.
Speaker 0: I have no more useful commentary about Sony other than that you have pulled a Jack Thompson.
Speaker 0: you caused me to talk about you again.
Speaker 1: I think the the thing is with Sony is that you know, because they screwed up a whole mess of things, right?
Speaker 1: You know the price is too high on a giant overheating system that people don't really want and etc, etc.
Speaker 1: A lot of this.
Speaker 1: things now are like bashing for the sake of bashing like the people who are like Oh, it doesn't come with the cable.
Speaker 1: Well, the Xbox 360 doesn't come with the cable.
Speaker 0: What is the game cue?
Speaker 1: or did nothing comes with the cable?
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's like they're bashing Sony for things that everyone does, you know as if Sony's even worse than it is.
Speaker 0: You know what though?
Speaker 0: I think they deserve bashing for these two bits of gem ish news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if that's real news, hey, you know, but it's sort of like they had.
Speaker 1: you know, it's Like you're bashing them for returning to the status quo.
Speaker 1: It's like they may.
Speaker 1: they made a grandiose promise like we're gonna do better than usual.
Speaker 1: See, but I don't know.
Speaker 1: we're gonna do what people normally do and then you're like, oh you suck You're gonna do it.
Speaker 0: know people normally but Sony seems to do this a lot.
Speaker 0: They always seem to say things are gonna be great and things are gonna be awesome And then when it comes time to actually say as in here it is.
Speaker 0: We're releasing it Suddenly half the things they said before just kind of get forgotten or yeah We can't actually make that many here.
Speaker 0: No, it's not gonna have two HDMI ports.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the complaint everyone made.
Speaker 1: You know when they first showed the ps2 at the e3 long ago They had like, you know the emotion engine and all this fancy shit They talked about.
Speaker 1: and yeah people pointed out at last e3 that none of that stuff ever came to be.
Speaker 0: I think the rule is you can only overhype yourself once and it'll only work once.
Speaker 0: Because if I say that my hundred dollar bill is worth a hundred and ten dollars and a bunch of people buy my Hundred and ten dollar hundred dollar bills and then they realize they got ripped off They're not gonna listen to me next year when I say I'm selling 115 dollar bills Well,
Speaker 1: I think what it really is.
Speaker 1: the problem is back in the days even when the ps2 came out the video game magazine was still the king over the video game website and people would get a video game magazine or two and they'd read them once a month and There'd be lots of stuff in there like oh, this is gonna happen.
Speaker 1: This is gonna happen.
Speaker 1: it's gonna have this and that and what now and screenshots and everything and People wouldn't remember all the details in those things.
Speaker 1: So if you said something like oh, yeah, we're gonna have a thousand gigahertz and you add 500 gigahertz in the end Probably very few people would notice or care true.
Speaker 1: But now people are reading the video game news every single day.
Speaker 1: They're reading the same news and every single piece of information you release there Getting told time and time again as links show up again and again and all the different websites They read.
Speaker 1: so you basically can't lie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I noticed that Nintendo and Microsoft are doing real well in this regard.
Speaker 0: I mean Nintendo hasn't lied yet about anything because every time they say something they're smart enough to where if they don't know.
Speaker 0: I think they qualify everything so much.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is that it won't be more than $250.
Speaker 0: it'll come out before the end.
Speaker 1: I think Nintendo's strategy is alright to avoid lying and also because you don't want to tell the truth That's the worst thing you can possibly do is to give out all the information too soon or at the wrong time.
Speaker 1: Nintendo is just either they say nothing or they're super vague or it all comes out suddenly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, they tell everything they have exact like dates and times what information they're gonna say when and they figured it out with All sorts of science.
Speaker 1: and while it's annoying for us because we're just like.
Speaker 1: tell us tell us you know.
Speaker 1: like Apple You know a lot of people like tell us yeah Well goddamn but to the to the.
Speaker 1: uh and it creates lots of rumors, but better than lies You know.
Speaker 0: yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: It's not like Apple where people believe some of those crazy rumors.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone believed the rumor that the Wii back before it was called the Wii was gonna have a hole.
Speaker 1: I think the reason people believe a lot of Apple rumors is because the think secret and Apple insider You know have sort of this track record of being like you know Mildly accurate on the rumors like they're like between 25 and 50 percent accurate.
Speaker 0: You know oh great Yeah, so less than drudge.
Speaker 1: well I know, but the point is is that you know they get a lot of stuff right you know.
Speaker 1: and when you're shooting You know machine gun bullets everywhere.
Speaker 0: You're gonna hit something That Apple is going to come out with a product.
Speaker 1: the point is is you know you read a site like that And it's the same thing psych.
Speaker 1: You know way psychics work is.
Speaker 1: you read a bunch of facts And then if a bunch of them turn to be true you remember the true ones you don't remember all the wrong ones.
Speaker 1: You know it's like a no B. No see I go through the whole alphabet.
Speaker 1: if I got the letter right eventually You'd be like oh my god.
Speaker 1: He got it, right.
Speaker 1: Okay, so my news In Japan unlike the u.s.. People revere video game music.
Speaker 0: Yes, something that should be more revered here.
Speaker 0: I mean yeah, I was no see remixes constantly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean in the u.s.. You're only gonna get a soundtrack for a major motion picture.
Speaker 1: You know you can get a soundtrack for some non-major motion pictures if you hunt around.
Speaker 0: Well Alex went around and found the original rip soundtrack from a Gameboy game be like and then he found a way to play That soundtrack just so you could listen to it.
Speaker 1: Yep now In Japan they put out soundtracks for everything.
Speaker 1: in fact they put up multiple soundtracks for everything.
Speaker 1: in fact they put out image albums.
Speaker 0: Yes an image album is essentially a soundtrack that contains music that was never actually in.
Speaker 0: whatever it was you bought the soundtrack to.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: So let's say there was an image album for the Lord of the Rings movie.
Speaker 1: That's like that would be.
Speaker 1: so there's a guy who's composing music for the Lord of the Rings movie and while he's doing that he composes some other music and He also you know.
Speaker 0: so it would be like the battle song they didn't use.
Speaker 0: and then the song they wrote about Aragorn because they felt like writing a song about Aragorn that they knew they wouldn't use.
Speaker 1: yeah And a song that like you know they'll that captures a certain mood But you know they didn't actually use that song for them.
Speaker 0: the hobbits are walking Yeah, and that's an image album.
Speaker 1: so in Japan they put out albums for everything including Phoenix Wright.
Speaker 1: Oh God no wait wait and not only did they put out albums for everything, but who's gonna buy a CD with just some Kind of GBA music?
Speaker 0: Is the answer here that they made an audio drama?
Speaker 0: no the answer is that usually they make an audio drama.
Speaker 1: the answer is that?
Speaker 1: They cut you know ye old orchestra to play on Phoenix Wright soundtrack Just like they do with.
Speaker 1: you know Smash Brothers and all those you know.
Speaker 0: I remember when I was God.
Speaker 0: This is pretty much before mp3s were widely available And I remember I ordered and it came
Speaker 1: the Final Fantasy from
Speaker 0: Japan this Final Fantasy concert and I paid like 40 bucks for this CD and I remember listening to an orchestra playing the music from Final Fantasy and being so blown away by this and Marveling at the wondrous nation that was Japan.
Speaker 1: I don't know where all the orchestras at if I ever get a lot of money.
Speaker 1: I'm buying an orchestra.
Speaker 0: There's orchestras everywhere.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: there are like four orchestras here Scott.
Speaker 1: We should buy one of them.
Speaker 0: We could donate enough money to where they'd.
Speaker 0: let us do things like tell them what to play.
Speaker 1: That's essentially buying them, which is good enough.
Speaker 0: You can do like what they did in that Marx Brothers movie.
Speaker 0: I showed you.
Speaker 1: yeah exactly No, but yeah, just be a wealthy benefit Phoenix.
Speaker 1: right music CD This morning when I got this link this thing of the day or not?
Speaker 1: It's not a thing of days.
Speaker 1: the news this morning when I found this news There was links to some mp3 samples of the album But they're not working now, so I'm unhappy.
Speaker 1: That's all I got to say about that.
Speaker 1: This was a better news when there were mp3 links.
Speaker 0: things of the day.
Speaker 0: Now as the most important issue of Death Note has come out in America And I'm sure you all who were reading Death Note have read it I have a very special Death Note related thing of the day that I'd kind of been saving and I'd also kind of forgotten about until a couple days ago.
Speaker 0: Okay, though also I have a clue because I said I'd do this as to what my thing of the day tomorrow will be and That it involves naked men.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, I think that someone we know is probably gonna get it based on just that paid better.
Speaker 0: Good God Though all of the guesses we received were completely incorrect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no I think that we could possibly make this thing come back because it was a huge thing like years ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then it hasn't returned and I've noticed this trend of old things that I've.
Speaker 1: you know We're awesome years ago returning and getting to the top of dig.
Speaker 0: So I'm waiting for Radis skull and devil doll to make it again Halloween man.
Speaker 1: That's when they're coming back.
Speaker 0: I think that should be our mission.
Speaker 0: I think it should be but anyway tomorrow I will reveal the mystery of the naked men.
Speaker 0: and no the naked men are not myself and Scott though That may be the case in the near future.
Speaker 0: I smell a cosplay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, my thing of the day today is Simply L trying to get a love potion from Snape the potions master and I'm not gonna ruin it.
Speaker 0: Just watch it.
Speaker 0: It's hilarious.
Speaker 0: I would rate it pg-13 for a slight amount of rape.
Speaker 1: Yes, this is.
Speaker 1: this is the kind of stuff that is usually reserved for the realm of fan crap.
Speaker 1: However, its production quality is over the line and its humor is over the line So it gets a pass.
Speaker 0: see I like these things a lot more than Scott does I mean, it's very similar to anyone who's seen the old classic bothering Snape ba ba ba ba ba ba.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway It's really well done.
Speaker 0: Check it out.
Speaker 0: The rapes not so bad.
Speaker 0: I think you can get past it.
Speaker 0: Plus remember it's a Cute boy character from Death Note doing something to another character from Death Note.
Speaker 0: It was also a boy.
Speaker 1: I'll just say that I like it.
Speaker 1: when people use copyrighted characters to make entertaining things to show that again Copyright laws BS.
Speaker 0: Oh It's not illegal in Japan.
Speaker 0: I'm a phone.
Speaker 0: It is technically maybe but yeah, but it's not nearly the way it is here.
Speaker 1: copyright and patent laws are hindering creativity not helping.
Speaker 0: Yes, because if you enjoy what we showed or what my thing of the day was bear in mind that that was totally illegal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're not allowed to use those copyrighted characters.
Speaker 1: anyway, it's not a parody, okay This is something that I think a lot of people have been asking for even though we kind of Sorted did an episode on it a little bit maybe.
Speaker 1: It is very detailed and complete instructions on how to throw a large room party at a science fiction Convention.
Speaker 1: now if you replace the word science fiction with anime or comic or gaming You won't have to change much else on the entire page because this is pretty much where it's at.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean Scott sent it to me and I was reading it and it read almost Exactly, like how we have planned parties in the past and how we continue to plan parties.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean even if you don't plan on throwing a party at a convention, it's pretty funny.
Speaker 1: I mean Especially when you look at the like party essentials list cheese and a veggie knife bottle opener corkscrew Cash preferably in small bills common sense a bottle of ibuprofen Willing minions, you know It's.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's funny.
Speaker 1: Even if you aren't going to take it seriously to throw a party but if you are gonna throw a party print this out and bring it with you and read it before your party and after your party and during your party and Make sure you do things, right?
Speaker 1: I Pretty much guarantee that if you follow these directions, you will have a successful good time because this thing is dead-on It is pretty much a bull's-eye.
Speaker 0: But anyway without further ado today We are going to go back to our typical show format of reviewing anime.
Speaker 1: Holy crap!
Speaker 0: Fancy that!
Speaker 0: Con season's almost wound down to the point that we can finally start doing something other than talk about cons Even though even though I still have Otacon content that we have not used yet Great the recording of the assassination attempt by certain unnamed forces.
Speaker 1: I thought you put it up already.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Oh, when would I put that up?
Speaker 1: I thought it was in another episode.
Speaker 0: No, because the whole panel we did was good and I just didn't get a chance to edit it because it takes Basically because of the way we recorded the stuff at Otacon do mostly to the fact that GarageBand is evil.
Speaker 0: Yep, it takes a lot of manual Annoying editing to make it not sound bad.
Speaker 0: as a result I haven't gotten around to actually putting that bit together yet But suffice to say someday in the near future You will actually be able to hear the moment at which Daryl Surratt so valiantly tried to slay me and Scott of geek night.
Speaker 1: Well, we are slain.
Speaker 1: I mean aren't we zamabis now?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I'm a more of a vampire Vampire, you know vampires aren't things that you realize.
Speaker 1: slain and come back.
Speaker 1: You realize you pretty much have a choice to do like zombie and ghosts.
Speaker 0: you realize the moment I said I'm a vampire Scott Johnson Got his cross and his steak and already in the car on the way to beacon Well, I'm a ghoul.
Speaker 1: So that's a much better choice.
Speaker 0: cool smell like asses.
Speaker 1: I know that's the point.
Speaker 1: No one will want to come and slay me.
Speaker 0: Okay, though I will say we often have debates among our group.
Speaker 0: as to you know The question was always if there was evil power Would you take it?
Speaker 0: and the fact that I said possibly means that I'm on Scott Johnson's bad list and if evil power ever appears He's gonna make sure.
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 1: I'm all about the evil power.
Speaker 1: maybe cuz I would use the evil power for not evil.
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 0: I could deal with being someone like Zellows.
Speaker 0: Maybe I could deal with that real well, maybe anyway.
Speaker 0: anyway tonight We are going to review a very good show that we both enjoyed very much.
Speaker 0: It was also very popular Gundam seed.
Speaker 1: we're not talking about Gundam see destiny God.
Speaker 0: Gundam see destiny does not exist Never seen it.
Speaker 0: Imagine that I am Gundam see destiny's father.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have no son Yeah, and now we're not gonna talk about Gundam seed manga.
Speaker 1: We're not talking about Gundam seed movies.
Speaker 1: We're not talking about Gundam seed OAVs or O and A's.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the original 50 episode TV series Gundam seed.
Speaker 0: it was put out by sunrise in late 2002. a Bandai Yeah, well in Japan, yeah, yeah, and it was directed by a Mitsuo Fukuda who is also known for gear fighter Dendo Which I've never seen and know nothing about.
Speaker 1: he's basically some robot director I think.
Speaker 0: apparently he put a lot of references to gear fighter Dendo in Gundam seed.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep That's apparently what the trivia and the anime news network encyclopedia says.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: That is also what I got out of Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: It must be true if it's in two separate user editable Encyclopedia some information see.
Speaker 0: you'll note that we're very much trying to sound erudite like anime world order.
Speaker 1: We're gonna fail miserably because we don't know shit about.
Speaker 0: I just I just said what company put it out What year they put it out in and who directed it and something else he directed.
Speaker 0: Holy shit, that's more than we've ever done.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I Mean when we talk about other shows were like, yeah this show came out I don't know ten years ago and then you look it up like now.
Speaker 0: it came out last month.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the show came out in what 2000 late late 2002 to early 2003 and it was in the u.s.
Speaker 0: When Oh later, I don't know you watch the fan subs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I watched some of the fan subs.
Speaker 1: then I stopped and then I bought it all on DVD.
Speaker 1: I think the DVDs must have come out 2004 2005.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz we finished it last year.
Speaker 1: So at 2004 2005 is when the DVDs came out in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Now Gundam seed is notable for a number of reasons and that it breaks away from the previous Continuity of Gundam drastically.
Speaker 0: Yes
Speaker 1: the original mobile suit Gundam takes place in a timeline called Universal Century and there there are a lot of Universal Century Gundams, I mean Zeta Gundams Universal Century Gundam Char's counter-attack All those things, you know that the original Gundam series
Speaker 0: Yeah, but not Gundam wing
Speaker 1: not Gundam wing.
Speaker 1: Gundam wing is on its own in this other area.
Speaker 1: Double o 80 double o 83 double 87 f 91.
Speaker 1: Those are all Universal Century Gundam in the original universe.
Speaker 0: God f 91 was terrible.
Speaker 1: yes, a Gundam wing was in its own universe.
Speaker 1: with some manga and Gundam seed begins a new timeline of Gundam that's separate from all other Gundams called the cosmic era.
Speaker 1: So Gundam seed and everything else Gundam seed related are all cosmic era Gundams.
Speaker 0: now The interesting thing is that a lot of people have noticed that Gundam seed very much parallels the original Gundam.
Speaker 1: Yes, it does like.
Speaker 1: if you've seen the original Gundam, which I haven't just because I haven't gotten it and had the time to see it a Lot of it is pretty much.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's the same thing only updated now.
Speaker 0: There are pros and cons to this because some fans said wow They took this awesome old show and they redid it modernly and now it's more awesome.
Speaker 0: But other fans said they have ruined the pure and transcendental nature of my robot anime.
Speaker 1: Yep, well some other people said man the show would have been more awesome if I didn't spoil it for myself by watching original.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta say seeing Gundam seed without knowing how it's going to end is one of the primary reasons to watch it.
Speaker 1: because yeah I mean if you've seen the original Gundam You're basically gonna easily predict a lot of things that go on and who's who and all sorts of secrets making the show Slightly less enjoyable even if you're not a fanboy.
Speaker 1: If you are a fanboy, you will not like Gundam seed if you've seen the original gun now.
Speaker 0: Fortunately for most of you though I'm sure there are many people out there who will consider this a bad thing and I'm indifferent to the matter.
Speaker 0: I'll bet that the majority of anime fans have never seen the original Gundam.
Speaker 1: Also, I'm willing to bet that just because it's not easy to get.
Speaker 0: no really isn't.
Speaker 1: it was easier to get.
Speaker 1: I'd have it.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, they're not selling it in $40 boxes at Otacon.
Speaker 0: I think we could get it in Netflix.
Speaker 0: I haven't looked.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe we should try.
Speaker 1: we should cuz I got probably something where even if it's not good We should.
Speaker 1: you know, you're still like you should watch it.
Speaker 1: Even if it's not good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just cuz it's the original Gundam.
Speaker 1: every anime fan should see it.
Speaker 0: But anyway the plot of Gundam seed in case you haven't seen the original Gundam, which will assume that you all have Is the actual plot is somewhat simple and it's typical Gundam plot.
Speaker 0: There are people who live in space.
Speaker 0: There are people who live on earth.
Speaker 0: There is conflict between the people in space and the people on earth Kids and people who don't want to be involved in the war get involved in the war.
Speaker 0: There's a whole bunch of crying and angst and shooting and in the end everything's kind of resolved.
Speaker 1: Yep, that sums it up pretty good.
Speaker 1: I mean to give a little more detail.
Speaker 1: there are these people called zaft.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll just say zaft They're coordinators and coordinators are like advanced super people.
Speaker 1: They're genetically engineered people who are smarter better faster stronger than everyone else.
Speaker 0: They're kind of like the people in a crest of the stars except not blue or more important.
Speaker 0: They're kind of like the new types.
Speaker 1: Yes, that's exactly what in fact little bit of trivia.
Speaker 0: new type magazine is called new type because that's what coordinators were called back in The day and those other guys in the Universal Century in those other Gundam shows, right?
Speaker 1: and Everyone else is a human They or a robot.
Speaker 1: you could be a robot also Or like a human clone or a robot clone or a coordinator clone and it was crazy.
Speaker 1: but and These coordinators, you know were they basically?
Speaker 1: they were discriminated against by a lot of humans, you know Because people are like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, particularly like the x-men if you think about it, particularly there's a group called what a blue cosmos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, blue cosmos are like the anti x-men.
Speaker 0: they're the KKK only they're against Coordinators instead of you know, brown people.
Speaker 1: Yeah It kind of it's.
Speaker 1: I don't know how that works out because if you're racist against someone who actually is Smarter better faster stronger wouldn't you just get your ass kick?
Speaker 0: See the problem is now.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to go a lot into where coordinators came from but suffice to say the show starts Out and you know, oh there's coordinators and they just kind of go with it.
Speaker 0: Don't worry later in the show There is old news things and flashbacks and you learn exactly the sci-fi business that is a coordinator and it's not just some hackney Plot point.
Speaker 1: Yeah that I think that sci-fi business is actually a lot of the good part of the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean there's a point where they go back and they kind of do this like news thing of and they have that fossil of The whale with wings.
Speaker 1: Yeah proves this extraterrestrial life, which they don't talk about it so much But it has a really deep sci-fi meaning.
Speaker 0: but suffice to say the while the show appears to be a typical gundam show There is a lot of very good sci-fi in there all over the place and it's not the focus of the show But pay attention to it because it adds so much.
Speaker 0: without that the show would have been barely watchable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean and we're not talking about just the you know robots fighting in space sci-fi action.
Speaker 1: We're talking about hard sci-fi like it's sort of between the lines.
Speaker 1: But if you look you can see it there and it.
Speaker 1: it makes everything else stand out pretty nicely.
Speaker 0: Like when they go back and they explain, you know The first coordinator and what happened to him and his business and why all the people in space are mostly coordinators.
Speaker 0: and yes They are better.
Speaker 0: but because they're so good and so perfect.
Speaker 0: They've been so engineered They can't breed so quickly and also living in space with limited resources Many of them don't want to breed.
Speaker 0: so as a result while they are vastly superior both in technology and ability and intelligence There are just so many more humans and humans are on a planet.
Speaker 0: So they have such a more stable base of resources that the two forces are pretty much at a dead heat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and basically the plot is you know a long time ago the humans blew up But one of the space colony things of the coordinators.
Speaker 1: Yes, which is sort of like the 9/11.
Speaker 0: They mention it a lot in the show.
Speaker 1: They mentioned in the opener, don't they?
Speaker 0: Yes, but later in the show, they actually explained specifically what happened and and a lot of bad stuff happens.
Speaker 1: It's really important to understand the bloody valentine massacre.
Speaker 0: It's basically this horrible tragedy where the earth forces used nuclear weapons to kill an insane amount of people in space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was basically 9/11 for the coordinators, which is why they're at war.
Speaker 0: Yes And the core and the original conflict seems to be that the coordinators are fighting to make sure that they aren't effectively Genocided.
Speaker 0: Yep, because that is what they are afraid of and the earth forces are Nominally fighting to protect themselves from the coordinators.
Speaker 0: But there are a lot of elements in human society that are hijacking these military people.
Speaker 1: Well, that's that's really what the whole conflict is is that you have coordinators on one side saying let's kill all humans.
Speaker 1: You have humans saying kill all the coordinators.
Speaker 1: then you have coordinators saying I just don't want to die by you crazy humans with nukes.
Speaker 1: And you have humans saying I just don't want to feel threatened by these people who are smarter better faster and strong.
Speaker 0: Think of it this way because this is a good way to put it in like modern-day realistic terms you have two Political factions that are also nations and they're at war now Officially and for all intents and purposes.
Speaker 0: they are at war because of these economic and social problems, you know They're afraid of each other.
Speaker 0: There was this massacre Military buildup brinksmanship all of that and they're fighting as two powers fighting of you know a war.
Speaker 0: But then the and this is really just the pretext because the reason they're really fighting is because there are a lot of coordinators who run the country who want to destroy all of the humans because they're inferior and take their land and There are a lot of humans who want to destroy all the coordinators because they're an abomination.
Speaker 1: Generally all the people who were high up want to destroy the other guys and all the lowdown people don't.
Speaker 1: I think it's set up That way.
Speaker 1: however, it may not be a hundred percent realistic, but that's how it set up.
Speaker 0: Well, it seems that the like the in the earth forces There are nominally powerful people who they're the ones who are technically in power and technically running this war for all of their reasons.
Speaker 0: but blue cosmos has kind of Infiltrated the government and blue cosmos represents the way a lot of people actually feel and they just justify the war with all of their Bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Now, let's let go with the robots a little bit Well before we get that that.
Speaker 0: one of the other main points of conflict here is that Nuclear weapons were what was used to destroy this column.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: I forgot so it's huge.
Speaker 0: So what the coordinators did with their vastly superior intelligence and science is they made end jammers.
Speaker 0: Now an end jammer is a device that they don't explain in great detail But it is effectively a device that can prevent nuclear fission and fusion.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: so in
Speaker 0: a local space
Speaker 1: What they did is they shot a bunch of giant things Into the deep deep deep into the earth where no one could dig like
Speaker 0: thousands and thousands and thousands and the humans of it and the earth Forces have been trying to dig these things up and there's just so many they can't do it.
Speaker 1: Yes, so the basically no nuclear reactor will work.
Speaker 1: You can't have a nuclear submarine.
Speaker 1: You can't have a nuclear-powered robot You can't have a nuclear missile and all the radios kind of suck anywhere near the earth because these end jammers are Preventing nukes from working
Speaker 0: now as a side effect of you know, protecting the coordinators from the nukes and from the barbaric humans.
Speaker 0: It also causes a lot of people on earth to die because suddenly there's no more nuclear power.
Speaker 0: There's an energy crisis.
Speaker 0: mass chaos ensues.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's a whole bunch of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: So both sides have perfectly legitimate gripes with each other, but then the actual reason they're fighting is just for this ideology.
Speaker 1: Yep, so as I said, there's no nukes.
Speaker 1: So the robots are kind of weak.
Speaker 1: They can't have nuclear-powered robots.
Speaker 0: No, yeah, despite all this there are neutral places.
Speaker 0: There's the nation of orb on earth Which is very technological and is comprised of a lot of coordinators and a lot of humans Yep, and there are outer space colonies that are neutral.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is where the story begins?
Speaker 1: the story begins in Heliopolis Which is a outer space colony and what's happening is the ZAF.
Speaker 1: people have robots.
Speaker 1: they have Gundams.
Speaker 1: well not Gundams but mobile suits and that's a extreme advantage in the war Compared to the mobile armors, which are basically x-wing type devices, you know or flying little space jet guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's pretty much as far as I can tell only one human who can actually fly one of these things effectively in his name Is moolah flaga.
Speaker 1: moolah flaga is the best character in the show, but the point is I don't know I'll have to raise you a lock is Klein?
Speaker 1: Yeah The only advantage the humans have in this war is their numbers and if they could somehow get mobile suits They could turn the tide,
Speaker 0: you know in D&D terms It's a lot like the orcs versus the humans or the humans versus the elves or the elves versus the drag.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like battle take with the clan versus the inner sphere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's exactly like that.
Speaker 1: So the story begins on this space colony where Orb or the military like factory of orb, which is called Morgan Ray D Is developing some robots that will be able to be piloted by humans.
Speaker 1: They're also badass robots.
Speaker 0: See the reason humans don't have mobile suits is that humans just don't have the physical agility and the mental power To be able to pilot one of these incredibly complex things.
Speaker 0: But coordinators because of their massively augmented intelligence have absolutely no problem.
Speaker 1: Well, they don't have no problem.
Speaker 1: Well, no, they did they can do it.
Speaker 0: They can do it.
Speaker 0: It is not an impossibility.
Speaker 1: No, it's not not at all.
Speaker 1: But for humans, it's basically just beyond human ability, you know It's like maybe the best human there is could kind of do it.
Speaker 1: shit Lee Yeah, but a really good coordinator could do it awesomely.
Speaker 0: so now the story starts in Heliopolis and it follows a whole bunch of kids and I'll warn you that the first about three or Four episodes are Typical Gundam opening crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you can't really see where the show is going because what it is is Oh, there's.
Speaker 1: they were making robots, you know, which on a neutral area where they shouldn't have been.
Speaker 0: Oh, does that?
Speaker 0: Oh figured it out?
Speaker 0: is that people figured out.
Speaker 1: they're coming to take the robots.
Speaker 1: There's some kids who accidentally get involved with the robot.
Speaker 0: You know, at least that makes sense because they're like at University and high school and studying this stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, oh some kids some you know, it's neutral.
Speaker 1: so some of them are coordinators some of them are and you know in there they get the robot and they get in a Spaceship and all of a sudden they're in the military and then the story begins.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean that it's they're such a pretext to get these people into the story that the first few episodes are kind of rushed in.
Speaker 0: That it goes from we're kids - oh my god.
Speaker 0: that kids piloting the robot.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: He's a coordinator.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh my god.
Speaker 0: He saved us.
Speaker 0: Oh my god around the ship.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, the Heliopolis exploded.
Speaker 1: yeah, I think what it is is, you know, they design characters and that they want, you know to appeal to the audience.
Speaker 1: and then They make a plot and those characters don't fit into the plots.
Speaker 1: They need to have this beginning part.
Speaker 1: That's a little bit hackneyed to you know, mix the two together now or else you would go What the hell are they doing there?
Speaker 1: That makes no sense.
Speaker 0: don't discount the show based on the first four maybe five episodes because once the characters are set once they're in the ship and The plot starts going the show is Incredibly well done.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I mean at least compared to other Gundams I've seen and a lot of other robot shows in general, you know It's just fantastic because they don't concentrate so much on the robot stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's there and you know, they say lots of spaceship be robot stuff.
Speaker 0: Yes, they're definitely nods to the fanboys in that I mean, there's the robot fighting which is well done, but it's not repetitive.
Speaker 1: It's sometimes it's repetitive when they use they reuse some footage over and like yeah A fight will happen at the end of an episode and the beginning of the next episode will show you the same Animation from the end of the last one.
Speaker 1: so it kind of it's a little eh if you're watching it straight through on DVDs.
Speaker 1: But if you watch the episode spaced out, it's all good.
Speaker 0: But they do the thing of they.
Speaker 0: I mean the fanboys really want all the technical stuff Like they want to hear like a bunch of made-up technology.
Speaker 0: They want to hear what formation the Gundams are in or what gun they're firing or what part of the ship just got damaged or what the rank is of that officer.
Speaker 0: and The beauty of the way Gundam seed is pulled off is that all of that is there but it doesn't get in the way They don't.
Speaker 0: they don't bother explaining like this extra lung Whatever gun is this kind of weapon, but this gun does this thing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this gun does.
Speaker 1: all that stuff is explained in the DVD extras and stuff if you want to read it.
Speaker 0: But more importantly in the show the captain or the XO will just order, you know Buyer the blah blah blah and it just happens and the fanboys can figure it out and drool about it.
Speaker 0: But all it does to people who don't care about that is add authenticity that yeah, they're using military jargon and it works.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's like, you know at the other robot shows What they'll do is they'll explain what every single thing is and it's like these people are in the military Shouldn't they already know?
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 1: why are they explaining it to?
Speaker 1: you know?
Speaker 1: It's like they're.
Speaker 1: you realize that it's only there for the audience and it kind of ruins the show a bit.
Speaker 1: and Gundam see they don't bother.
Speaker 1: people know what they're supposed to do and You know if there's any fancy words.
Speaker 1: They just say the fancy words without defining them.
Speaker 0: now the primary conflict of the plot of the show The overarching plot is this conflict between zaft and earth and the neutral territories like orb.
Speaker 1: But the story doesn't focus on that.
Speaker 1: I mean it does but it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: that's like the environment in which the story takes place.
Speaker 0: And now that alone would have been an okay show, okay So but what they did is they they took.
Speaker 0: basically I don't want to trivialize it, but it was effectively teen angst.
Speaker 0: It's a teen angst soap opera in space, but at least it's a well done teen angst soap opera.
Speaker 1: Well, the teen angst soap opera has different phases and different segments, you know It's like certain characters have certain conflicts which all seem to all tie into the main character Kira Yamato somehow.
Speaker 1: But some of them are annoying like early on all the stuff with Flay, it's really just flay is annoying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, flay all-star is annoying, but that's important.
Speaker 0: I don't want to ruin anything, but it's important that she's annoying.
Speaker 1: It is important that she's annoying but she's there and that's annoying.
Speaker 1: teen angst But all the other teen angst is pretty good, you know, it's like oh we used to be friends And now we're on opposite sides of the war.
Speaker 1: or oh no so-and-so died.
Speaker 1: I crying.
Speaker 1: Why you know should I stay in the military or should I go?
Speaker 0: the characters are really in my opinion, especially for a show like this very realistically portrayed and Very multi-dimensional in many cases.
Speaker 0: I mean no character is just straight-up.
Speaker 0: I am the angsty guy who doesn't want to pilot the robot or I am the strong woman who will stand here.
Speaker 0: Everyone who is strong is moments of weakness.
Speaker 0: Everyone who is weak has moments of strength.
Speaker 0: The show is very human.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's another thing.
Speaker 1: I really like about the show is that you know, there are a lot of characters a lot But somehow you can keep track of all them pretty easily because the designs are really recognizable.
Speaker 0: I mean even characters that die, I mean characters die.
Speaker 0: The show is not all.
Speaker 0: there's a guy.
Speaker 1: This isn't a spoiler.
Speaker 1: There's a guy named rusty.
Speaker 1: Rusty dies in like episode one or two.
Speaker 0: You never see his face.
Speaker 0: all you see is him getting shot.
Speaker 1: and then another guy who is a very like a main main character goes Rusty and you hear Rusty's name later when they're remembering people who died.
Speaker 0: He's like rusty and it's like it's the great, you know at the end of this episode when we're done talking about the show Seriously, we're gonna go through all of the funny cliches in the show.
Speaker 0: Okay, because there are many.
Speaker 1: there are many.
Speaker 1: but another thing what I'm saying is there are a lot of characters in the show Who may or may not have names and they may or may not get a lot of screen time.
Speaker 1: But they're not in other shows.
Speaker 1: they would just be extras.
Speaker 1: but in this show There's something a little bit like the guy who's the maintenance guy and the robots You know in on the ship.
Speaker 0: if a character has a line ever they are fleshed out as much as they can be.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like the guy who is the navigator on the ship, you know, you you don't even get his name Really?
Speaker 1: I think maybe you do once or twice, you know.
Speaker 1: But while he doesn't say a lot you see him there and you keep seeing the same guy.
Speaker 1: They draw the same guy in the same seat and they have him show up at appropriate times and say appropriate things.
Speaker 1: So you kind of get to know him even though he's not involved in the main plot in any way Except for he's a guy who's there.
Speaker 1: He's the navigator.
Speaker 0: Well a lot of shows when they do something like that They'll just draw a generic guy like a faceless guy in the background working on the robot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and not only that but whenever like whenever something happens and people are around There'll be a lot of reaction shots and a lot of the reaction shots are of characters You don't know just like the crowd of officers standing there just kind of watching something happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, they'll have like a a council or like a military tribunal And you'll know like the two head guys of the tribunal and you've never seen the other eight care You've never seen the other eight guys.
Speaker 1: But instead of just having the main two guys talk while the other eight guys sit there They'll have some of those other eight guys say like one line each so that they're actually not just extra fact.
Speaker 0: I think I remember one point at which there is a scene where there were two character.
Speaker 0: two of the people arguing were neither of Which were characters I knew in any way Yeah, and yet it was their scene and the characters I knew we're just kind of watching
Speaker 1: Yeah And they have no qualms about just introducing characters and taking them out and putting them back in and all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you really can't skip around in the show You gotta watch it straight through.
Speaker 0: like there's a point at which because the basic driving force of the show in terms of plot As opposed to character is that all of the characters are on this ship the legged ship and They're on their archangel.
Speaker 0: Yeah they're in this ship on their own and a Somewhat elite force of zapped and is trying to track them down.
Speaker 0: it's like the first half of the show in addition to the war going on and They're just trapped alone trying to avoid being killed and that's the whole first half of the show.
Speaker 0: They're just trying to get somewhere safe and that's really hard to do.
Speaker 1: Well, they're trying to get back to earth.
Speaker 0: Well, they're trying to get somewhere safe, but we know how that ends.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Remember when they go to Artemis?
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, they were just trying to get somewhere safe and no no good But the driving can't go somewhere safe then there wouldn't be any robot battles.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with the driving force?
Speaker 0: character wise is that?
Speaker 0: I mean I'd say the primary conflict is that the two characters that are main ish are Kira Yamato and Othran of Zale Zala.
Speaker 1: they mess it up because like if you buy a toy that has Othran's name on it It says A S U R A N, which is Asudan, but in like the fans in the bandai subtitles It says A T H R U N Othran, you know.
Speaker 1: And then like some places get the R and the L mixed up in the last name.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure which one it is, but it's either Z A R A or Z A L A but either way it's Zara.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they're both coordinators and Othran is a member of the military of this elite force for Zaft and Kira Yamato ends up even though he's a coordinator Piloting this one Gundam that they've got on this ship and all he's trying to do is defend all of his friends and it ends Up that Othran is sent to kill the people on the ship and then he finds out that Kira's on there and the whole show Is these two, you know meeting in the midst of combat or you know Just crossing in the wind and trying to deal with that the fact that they're both on opposite sides of a war.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: it's like if rim was an Iranian soldier and I was a US soldier and there was a US-Iranian war and I was on a boat with the rest of the front row crew and I was the robot pilot and rim was also a robot pilot and he Was coming to blow up the boat and I'd be like you're my you're my friend and I don't want to kill you but I have like ten friends on this boat and I have to defend them from you.
Speaker 1: who is going to kill them?
Speaker 0: and If you think that's it.
Speaker 0: No, there is.
Speaker 0: so every character drives the plot in some way.
Speaker 0: I mean every character has their moment everything.
Speaker 0: the character relationships are very complex Very complex.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to ruin anything other than that They.
Speaker 0: this show is comprised of many very powerful scenes that are very obviously Important.
Speaker 0: scenes like.
Speaker 0: the show will be going fine.
Speaker 0: And then you know some musical start and there will be a scene like a 10-minute scene.
Speaker 0: Yep, and Like there's the Opera House scene, there's the scene where two characters are standing on opposite sides of a fence outside.
Speaker 1: That was also lots of symbolism like they'll put little tiny things like.
Speaker 1: Kira has this bird That you know Asuran made for him a long time ago before the show started and they'll have the bird kind
Speaker 0: of like Darth Vader
Speaker 1: kind of like Darth Vader and You know, they'll have this bird show up and land on people's shoulders or fly into different scenes.
Speaker 1: You know to like remind you and teach you that, you know and remind you of things and be symbolic, you know, and they'll have Lacas Klein who's Asuran's woman.
Speaker 0: Lacas Klein is Awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah is rims favorite character, you know, she has these little Haros which you might notice.
Speaker 1: there There's a lot of toys of these.
Speaker 1: they're little balls with the wings and the eyeballs.
Speaker 1: They're cute.
Speaker 0: I got a little auto washcloth in a little Haro bag for Emily.
Speaker 1: yeah, these things will bounce around and say cute things and and generally interfere in scenes to say things that are Poignant or silly, you know, yes often very poignant though.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like, you know They just throw little things into every scene to remind you of stuff and and be symbolic all over the place Or they'll show you images of things like that whale with the wings, you know to remind you.
Speaker 0: and now there is.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of romance among the interpersonal relationships of the characters and without ruining anything because there's a lot to ruin I would just like to point out that all of the relationships are very realistically handled and They aren't used Too badly for the plot.
Speaker 0: like characters don't get together and then the whole plot result revolves around it.
Speaker 0: things just kind of occur naturally and you really a lot of things that you expect to happen don't.
Speaker 0: and Characters that you wouldn't think would have any reason to know each other end up getting together and It's hard to predict what the show is going to do unless you watch the openers carefully.
Speaker 1: Yeah a lot of it though You know.
Speaker 1: what happens is all the relationship.
Speaker 1: stuff goes like unspoken, you know, yeah Yeah, it's like no one will say hey, you're hot.
Speaker 1: Hey, I want you.
Speaker 1: Hey, you know me and him are going out me and them or you know, it's all just kind of you know.
Speaker 1: You'll get a shot on someone's face and a shot on someone else's face.
Speaker 1: Then they'll show you two people looking at each other, you know or they'll show you like two people waking up in the same room and everything is sort of implied.
Speaker 1: and You know at first when I watched the show the first time I was always kind of like, huh?
Speaker 1: Is it really going on?
Speaker 1: because they don't you know, they never put it in concrete.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you're not.
Speaker 1: I wasn't a hundred percent sure just how involved until a few scenes in the end where?
Speaker 0: Some very obvious things happen.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah there there there are very obvious things towards the end and in the openers.
Speaker 1: That's another problem is the openers are very spoilery.
Speaker 1: Yeah Take them at face value.
Speaker 0: watch the openers because they're good but don't think about them because I kept pissing Scott off while we were watching the show because he'd seen a Much of it and I hadn't.
Speaker 0: and as we're watching like I'd noticed in one opener Two characters are on opposite sides of the screen pointing guns at each other.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, alright those two characters are gonna fight each other somehow.
Speaker 0: and he's like.
Speaker 0: and then they did.
Speaker 0: But then the opener changed one episode and the same two characters are in the same poses But instead of coming across the screen aiming at each other.
Speaker 0: They come across the screen backwards and they end up standing back-to-back and I said, holy crap That got one of those characters is gonna join the other character side and they're gonna be allies and scouts like what the fuck.
Speaker 0: And I said it's all in the opener.
Speaker 0: Look the opener shows me that those two characters gonna get together that carriage is gonna die that carries gonna do this and it was All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you don't pay too much attention the opener you might spoil the show for yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you if you think you're smart don't watch the openers Even though you should listen to the awesome awesome music in the opener.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: The music in this show is very good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like they got all this great TM revolution music and what's the?
Speaker 1: what's her name?
Speaker 1: They got TM revolution and Nami Tamaki and all these other people to do awesome openers and closers and Awesome, like this, you know original orchestral score During the show and it's wicked awesome music is used to very great effect to augment your emotions.
Speaker 0: I mean, there'll be a scene and the scene itself would have been heart-wrenching or Incredibly full of just like fair and anticipation and then the music just kind of drives that home doubly.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like what they'll do is they'll have the same music for the same things that happen because there are things that happen often and repeat Oh,
Speaker 0: yeah They're kind of like leitmotifs like certain characters will have certain songs that play when they come or so
Speaker 1: It's like if so and so is sad.
Speaker 1: and they're dealing with this section of the.
Speaker 1: you know The overall plot like this relationship.
Speaker 1: you'll always hear that music.
Speaker 0: But but as a result They also use the music to kind of show characters emotions in ways that you couldn't show so easily just by animating Especially since so much of it is left unsaid if people just look at each other.
Speaker 1: so a lot of it is people look at each other and they play a music to let you know
Speaker 0: or like a character standing somewhere and His eyes narrow and suddenly some music comes in and the music kind of shows you his resolve growing as he's about to shoot someone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and changing that music would just completely change the whole thing.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like the animation isn't so much the music is what really does it?
Speaker 0: I mean all in all because I don't want to go too long about this and yeah We've been dancing around spoiler lines a lot.
Speaker 0: We're going to at some point in the future do a final thoughts episode on Gundam.
Speaker 0: see but this is just a review So we're not going to spoil anything.
Speaker 1: The point is that Gundam seed is a really good show.
Speaker 0: now if you think you wouldn't like Gundam seed because you don't like Gundam Shows you don't like robot shows Gundam seed is Probably the perfect robot show for you because there is so much more to it than the robot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's soap opera It's a sci-fi and it's robot.
Speaker 0: It's not like Ava or Big O where it's.
Speaker 0: hey, the robots are just here to get you to think about this existentialist crisis.
Speaker 1: Yeah here look at the genres listed on anime news network.
Speaker 1: Drama is mecha military romance science fiction shonen That's that's quite a bit there.
Speaker 0: All right, so on to the funny cliches in this show.
Speaker 1: The first one is the split screen.
Speaker 1: It's not just the split screen.
Speaker 1: the I'd like to call it the breaking glass screen.
Speaker 1: You know when you break a piece of glass it gets a bunch of triangles.
Speaker 1: Yep, what they'll do in this show is like something will explode in a space battle.
Speaker 1: Maybe someone dies, you know, and then what they'll do is they'll break the screen up into you know Like rhombuses and triangles and they'll show you the faces of a different character in each spot.
Speaker 1: So big You'll get like a one-second reaction from each character.
Speaker 0: now it starts out alright.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of shows do something like that.
Speaker 0: and because there aren't so many characters Towards the end of the show when pretty much all the characters were still alive are involved in scenes
Speaker 1: They're involved in one giant space
Speaker 0: And Then a whole new Swipe and then a whole nother set of people reacting to something and
Speaker 1: then the person who cares the most about what just happened We'll get a full screen, you know scream going on, you know It's.
Speaker 1: they got to show you the reaction of every single character for like a fraction of a second.
Speaker 1: So they break the screen up and show you everyone's face.
Speaker 0: It works really well.
Speaker 0: But if you watch the show pretty much straight through like we did you really start to notice that that happens all the time And you start laughing even though it's a serious scene.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if you had a Gundam seed drinking game, it's like oh man.
Speaker 1: Another thing that's a problem I think with Gundam seed is that there are a lot of recap episodes Which if you're watching it on TV, or let's say you're picking it up in the middle.
Speaker 1: That's a great thing because the recap episodes There's many of them and they're thorough and they actually have a little bit of new stuff and they kind of make sense in the plot And they're interesting.
Speaker 1: It's not just like here's a recap.
Speaker 1: It's like but god It's like we're gonna do it military debriefing and they you know, they talk they speak and there's a recap.
Speaker 0: now I wouldn't mind except that there seem to be about twice as many recaps as there need to be and Some shows do recaps really well like Nana.
Speaker 0: the recaps are totally new episodes effectively Yeah, because they show you the same thing for different perspective and they add things and it's really worth it to watch Gundam seed the recaps.
Speaker 0: I just feel cheated like damn it.
Speaker 0: They just stole 15 minutes of my life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're watching on the DVDs straight through you can pretty much skip the recap episodes or at least fast-forward them to see like The 10 seconds of new animation, but if you're watching slowly, you know over time I think the recaps would help you a lot because you'd forget details that you know are important later on or You maybe missed an episode here or there but even then if you watch it say one episode a week There's still too many recaps, you know, they could have cut out one or two of them and been okay.
Speaker 1: All right, especially since the recaps often come right before very important episodes So they just delay.
Speaker 1: you get into the good stuff now.
Speaker 0: the other big thing that happens often is Kira Yamato starts crying or Another character cries.
Speaker 0: a lot of people cry a lot in this show And the thing is normally when you have a voice actor doing crying it sounds like a voice actor doing crying.
Speaker 0: You know, it's just someone doing like a movie crying and for whatever reason and I'm actually very glad they did it this way.
Speaker 0: But it's also sometimes hilarious.
Speaker 0: Characters cry realistically because if you've ever seen someone crying after something absolutely terrible happens to them They don't cry like people cry in the movies.
Speaker 0: These people cry in like these horrible moaning like Gasping sounds it's.
Speaker 1: it's actually pretty painful to listen to.
Speaker 1: it's like oh Make it stop just stop making those noises.
Speaker 0: The worst is Kira cries a lot and they even make fun of him for it like they call him a crybaby at one point seriously, like it's a good scene, but they mentioned.
Speaker 0: he's a crybaby, but one character at one point for various reasons a character tries to pilot a robot that that character shouldn't have tried to pilot and It the scene ends with that character crying and it's kind of this.
Speaker 0: It's the worst thing ever.
Speaker 1: it's really really bad.
Speaker 0: like I Felt I almost wanted to vomit.
Speaker 0: It was so terrible.
Speaker 0: I felt so bad and yet so disgusted like I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like regardless of what happened in the show.
Speaker 1: Just the noises coming out of the speakers, you know, just make you feel.
Speaker 0: One other thing I just realized I forgot to mention this because I think this is really cool.
Speaker 0: That really made the show good for me was that it really humanizes The robots in that when you see when there's a big robot fight There are almost never just generic robots fighting or background robots fighting every robot you see fighting.
Speaker 0: They make sure you are fully aware that there is a person in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they go to great lengths to make sure that you know, every time one of those blows up someone just died.
Speaker 1: They always give the road.
Speaker 1: They always refer to the robots by the name of the robot, you know, and they make sure that you know Who is in each one?
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, they'd be like, you know, buster duel blitz go and you know Who's in buster duel and even extras.
Speaker 0: like, you know Like a lot of shows if a robot gets blown up like either a parachute comes out or something or they just don't say anything Like oh the robot blew up, but this show go make sure it goes out of its way.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: There was a person in there.
Speaker 0: Yes, you just heard him scream now.
Speaker 0: He's dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like even if like the random generic guy who has no name, you know is flying an airplane and blows up It's like they make sure you know that it wasn't just a blowing up plane It was oh my god That guy just killed a person.
Speaker 0: because of course this show Like any Gundam show has a couple of very basic morals and without spoiling anything I think it's obvious to say that the primary moral of Gundam seed is War is bad.
Speaker 0: Don't do it ever.
Speaker 1: Racism is bad.
Speaker 1: War is bad.
Speaker 1: Science is good.
Speaker 1: As long as you use it for good, you know, it's okay to you know use Some sort of force to protect your friends from imminent death and save lives But kill as few people as possible, but don't be averse to killing if you need to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't be a wuss.
Speaker 0: Also be smart.
Speaker 0: you'll notice in the show that any character that is stupid bad things happen to them as a result of their stupidity and Throughout the show.
Speaker 0: It's like one by one.
Speaker 0: all of the characters that don't die Suddenly become smart like it all clicks and they stop acting like idiots or like or they die.
Speaker 1: well, the only time characters die is Because they either try to do something, you know way heroic Like I'm going to sacrifice myself for the greater good or I'm gonna go all out.
Speaker 1: You know to say help my friends even at the risk of my own life and that they'll die because of that.
Speaker 1: You'll also die if you're stupid and you do some you know, you take stupid risks or your inexperience You don't know what you're doing.
Speaker 1: You'll also die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the show is not afraid.
Speaker 1: Also die if you know your ideas are wrong.
Speaker 1: if you're a bad guy you're gonna die.
Speaker 0: Yeah for the most part good guys die too.
Speaker 1: Yeah good guys die, too.
Speaker 0: But for the reasons I stated a lot of people die in this show.
Speaker 0: a lot of people die.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of characters dying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the show all your favorite characters Will die.
Speaker 0: the show is not afraid to kill characters that are popular at all.
Speaker 1: No, they'll die in the middle They'll die at the beginning.
Speaker 1: They'll die at the end.
Speaker 1: rusty die.
Speaker 0: God the fact that there's a scene near the very end of the show where one character who is still alive is Going through in his mind all of the people who have died for what he is about to do.
Speaker 1: He remembers rusty who died in the episode.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 0: he remembers rusty and I can't believe that.
Speaker 0: in fact We had a contest to sit to guess between the two of us which character who died Name would be said by other characters in that Rusty.
Speaker 1: yeah other character like if someone's dead if someone's dead They'll mention them again and again in the show for many many episodes as they you know Look fondly back on that person's life or they're still upset about that person dying.
Speaker 0: It's a very try gonna ask Yeah, that person died.
Speaker 0: They are dead.
Speaker 0: They're not coming back and they're dead because of your stupid war.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the last episode they'll remind you of every single named character who lost their lives and at that point you'll realize that a Lot of fucking people got axed in this show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's some that are mentioned more than others and that's how you tell who is really important.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna ruin who won on the getting mentioned the most cuz that would be a number of spoilers.
Speaker 1: It would be a number of spoilers.
Speaker 0: I think we're done for now.
Speaker 0: Um, I encourage all of you to see Gundam seed even if you don't think you would like it.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, if you don't watch it on TV Oh god.
Speaker 0: Very briefly Cartoon Network butchered it in ways that I cannot express in the time I have left tonight.
Speaker 1: if you watch it on Cartoon Network, no one dies.
Speaker 0: not I mean characters die But they remove all the scenes that let you know.
Speaker 0: They die and whenever possible they remove the words kill or die from the dialogue.
Speaker 0: They also replace all of the handguns with neon laser guns.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz and Characters don't just die in robots people get shot people get stabbed people get crushed people get exploded Rocket launcher terrorists.
Speaker 1: Yeah all kinds of crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: So It's really the show is good.
Speaker 0: watch it.
Speaker 0: I think you'll like it.
Speaker 0: give it at least like ten episodes.
Speaker 0: and if you don't like it after ten episodes Let us know and we're curious why.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean there are 50 episodes in the show and I could understand it.
Speaker 1: If someone like one story arc and then didn't like another story arc There's like four or five.
Speaker 0: judge the show on the first four episodes.
Speaker 0: They start like any Gundam.
Speaker 1: yeah, there are like four or five or six story arcs in this thing depending on how you break it down.
Speaker 1: and There are like four or five openers to the show and closer sets, you know, it's pretty big.
Speaker 1: So if you don't like one part, maybe you'll like the next part.
Speaker 1: I really don't think very few people will not like it judging by the ratings on anime news network.
Speaker 1: But this big green line and the very small red line Yeah,
Speaker 0: and of course sometime in the future We will do a final thoughts episode where we talk about the actual plot in terms of all the spoilers and the big scenes I'd really like to talk about for all of you.
Speaker 0: but I can't spoil the show because seeing these scenes unfold and Realizing what's going on is one of the biggest things about this show and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.