Speaker 1: It's Monday November 20th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and I'm Rin and this is Geeknet.
Speaker 1: Tonight we have a short episode and we're tired and sick, so I respond to one email about the Linux and the TS3.
Speaker 1: Let's do this!
Speaker 0: You know, you're probably not going to believe us, but we're gonna have a short episode tonight.
Speaker 0: Now you might be thinking "Gab, because you guys have a Wii and you want to play it well while that was going to be true it ended up not being true.
Speaker 0: we're actually not doing so well because we both got a little sick yeah and it didn't help that our friend Yuko was over and Emily was over and all our friends were in Philly at a party.
Speaker 0: meanwhile we were in our house along with my little brother who I hadn't seen in like three years and his friend yeah.
Speaker 0: so it ended up being an awesome but not very relaxing weekend.
Speaker 1: all you have to know about my weekend was on Saturday I beat Resident Evil 4 yeah and then Sunday morning Sunday morning I went to the city and waited in line for four hours to get my guaranteed Nintendo Wii at the Nintendo World Store.
Speaker 1: but the only reason I had to wait for four hours was because they couldn't.
Speaker 1: they didn't have enough cash registers and they couldn't check people out fast enough.
Speaker 0: yeah so props to Scott for braving because Scott was already a little sick and he had to stand out there.
Speaker 1: yeah but I got one guaranteed the only thing they would.
Speaker 1: we'll talk about it tomorrow.
Speaker 0: yeah we'll have a detail.
Speaker 1: but all you have to know is we got we.
Speaker 0: so this week will be a little short as in today we're not doing much and not to mention like Wednesday.
Speaker 1: I'm going to my parents house for Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: yeah there might not be an episode Wednesday Friday I probably won't work.
Speaker 1: so it's like this week.
Speaker 1: is this week might be shot?
Speaker 0: yeah well there's gonna be no episode Thursday.
Speaker 0: fuck you guys.
Speaker 1: I mean we almost didn't do an episode today just because there's no news except we and ps3 news.
Speaker 0: yeah well there's there's a bunch of real-world news.
Speaker 1: oh yeah we don't talk about.
Speaker 0: well no I wanted to talk about it but I kind of feel a bit shit right now.
Speaker 1: yeah I definitely feel some shit.
Speaker 1: so I think the plan for this week actually is if we just make a really long like a we episode tomorrow then we won't have to make anything else this week something like that.
Speaker 0: all I got to say is I have a lot of words about the we.
Speaker 1: we got lots of words so we're gonna let that episode go.
Speaker 1: yep and we're gonna in order to make you know it make it all work.
Speaker 1: we just don't do some other episodes and it doesn't hurt us.
Speaker 0: man I would have been okay except last night really didn't?
Speaker 0: it turned into a slumber party of staying up all night playing we boxing and talking about dumb stuff and I only got like three hours of sleep.
Speaker 1: yeah I actually went to sleep a little earlier and didn't go to work today.
Speaker 1: but yeah yeah in this episode I might like cough sometimes.
Speaker 0: yeah Scott's been hacking up a dead something.
Speaker 1: I think I'm at the stage of being sick or I'm not actually so sick anymore.
Speaker 1: it's just I got a cough up all the mucus.
Speaker 0: yeah I'll bet you have some sort of viral thing.
Speaker 1: who knows?
Speaker 1: it'll be gone in a day or two.
Speaker 0: all I gotta say is I'm taking some NyQuil real soon.
Speaker 1: do we still have NyQuil?
Speaker 0: I have some NyQuil.
Speaker 0: is it still good?
Speaker 0: it might be.
Speaker 0: does it have isn't you know what I have?
Speaker 0: some Sudafed real Sudafed with Sudafedrin.
Speaker 1: see I don't like Sudafed but like I like NyQuil take them both.
Speaker 1: oh no that's dangerous.
Speaker 1: if you have real NyQuil that not the meth free NyQuil then I'll have some.
Speaker 0: why not just have the Sudafed?
Speaker 0: it works just as well.
Speaker 1: I don't like Sudafed.
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 1: because it's it's not it's a it's a swallow thing.
Speaker 1: what I mean?
Speaker 1: I can't swallow a pill?
Speaker 1: no I can't.
Speaker 0: I just prefer not to okay but the pills tend to work a lot better.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah what are you gonna do if you ever have to take drugs if you're forced to take an antibiotic or something?
Speaker 1: I've done it before cuz bioxin pills are gigantic.
Speaker 1: I've done it before and I've taken them.
Speaker 1: I just don't like it.
Speaker 0: Sudafed pills are tiny.
Speaker 1: how tiny is it?
Speaker 0: it's like a little nub and I still don't like doing it was.
Speaker 1: I mean I will if I have no other choice but I just don't like it.
Speaker 0: see maybe it's the same reason why for some here I have another choice which is awesome NyQuil.
Speaker 1: so why would I bother?
Speaker 0: yeah I think it's the same reason.
Speaker 0: you can't drink soda cuz it hurts your throat.
Speaker 0: I think your throat's got a problem.
Speaker 1: no the soda doesn't hurt my throat it's my mouth.
Speaker 0: why so doesn't hurt your mouth?
Speaker 0: it's psychological it's psychosomatic.
Speaker 1: it could be but it's still gotta be.
Speaker 0: who knows we'll do a double blind.
Speaker 0: all right we really can't do a double blind.
Speaker 1: well I'll just drink a beverage without knowing what it is.
Speaker 0: there's no placebo though because that's like saying yeah we're gonna see if you can taste the difference between orange juice and an empty glass.
Speaker 0: what are you gonna use for a placebo?
Speaker 0: a orange empty glass flat soda an empty glass with a flat ginger ale.
Speaker 0: anyway I'm not even gonna bother with the thing of the day music.
Speaker 0: we're just gonna have some things of the day and get the hell out of here tonight.
Speaker 1: yeah we're cutting it real short aren't we?
Speaker 0: you know what that's fine we do.
Speaker 0: how many episodes have we done?
Speaker 0: we're allowed to have a good one.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about something like for technology for like five minutes.
Speaker 0: what do you?
Speaker 0: what are you gonna talk about other than the we?
Speaker 1: someone asked me a question on the.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna look in an email.
Speaker 1: I'll answer.
Speaker 0: so you don't even know what the question was hold on and now I got a stall for time.
Speaker 1: well you're like doll just talk about your thing of the day all right.
Speaker 0: so you go was over here hanging out with the rest of us over the weekend the we can and she mentioned that there is a video called unicorn versus narwhal.
Speaker 0: now unicorns are known for having horns as our narwhals and this is some students a project.
Speaker 0: it's an animation but about half of it maybe a little more ends up being animatics because obviously the kid didn't have enough time to finish it.
Speaker 0: so we only animated some of it and the rest is just you know animatic like still shots and then the audio was dubbed over it.
Speaker 0: it's kind of quirky kind of funny.
Speaker 0: it's really cheesy but it's cheesy on purpose for comedic effect and I really can't say much about it except that you need to watch it.
Speaker 0: it's hilarious and the horses look exactly like Ren and Stimpy horses.
Speaker 1: I like the ending a little bit.
Speaker 0: I like that a lot.
Speaker 1: I like the dragon.
Speaker 0: I like the drugs.
Speaker 0: I put my little dragon wings as fast as I can.
Speaker 1: yeah good voice actor on the dragon because it doesn't fit in.
Speaker 1: so and it's hilarious.
Speaker 0: they're pretty much everyone voice acting and this is great.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean you don't bring it wasn't?
Speaker 1: I think the reason it wasn't done is it's one of those over-your-head things that happens in CS a lot is you get some guy who says all right for this project for this class.
Speaker 1: you know the teacher lets you do whatever you want so he goes all right I'm gonna make a mush from scratch.
Speaker 1: and he tried.
Speaker 1: he goes for it and he's got ten weeks and of course he comes up short.
Speaker 1: the work he's done is great but the reason doesn't finish is because the scope of his project was too large.
Speaker 1: for you know the target.
Speaker 1: yeah but it's like I got ten weeks in this class and there's a final project.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make an entirely new operating system.
Speaker 1: let's go and we bet it in Linux it's gonna have this and this.
Speaker 1: you know it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: yeah but mad props for this thing.
Speaker 0: I mean the winds of change are changing all right.
Speaker 1: my thing of the day is the spoof.
Speaker 1: you know jackass those guys who hurt themselves.
Speaker 0: yeah I think this is kind of based on because there's been a couple of black comedians who have made jokes to this effect.
Speaker 0: I think Bill Cosby even used to.
Speaker 1: maybe anyway jackass I actually think it's kind of okay.
Speaker 1: like like the first time I saw it I was like a guys in a porta potty got tipped over.
Speaker 1: these guys are making videos.
Speaker 1: they're making owned videos of themselves.
Speaker 1: basically yeah and you know I like owned videos.
Speaker 1: so I like that even though it's forced but it's not quite as good as a real owned video.
Speaker 0: you know I guess to me it's.
Speaker 0: it's almost better in that it's not painful because it's not someone you know accidentally getting hurt or someone you just like actually really getting hurt.
Speaker 0: it's just a bunch of guys.
Speaker 1: well they do really hurt themselves but they want to.
Speaker 1: well yeah it's like that video of people shocking each other with a taser they bought.
Speaker 0: it's a bunch of guys who decided we're going to hurt ourselves for your amusement and you know what they make.
Speaker 0: enough money to wear more power to them.
Speaker 1: yeah it's it's like that.
Speaker 1: what's that joke?
Speaker 1: they always say like someone pretending to be an old lady falling down the stairs is funny but if you're a comedian it's got to be a real old lady.
Speaker 0: huh you must listen to pen radio must must possibly Gilbert Godfrey?
Speaker 1: yeah so yeah cuz I'm just so hip jaded.
Speaker 1: yeah seeing so many funny things on the internet that I need to I need it to be a real?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: over this weekend I saw about five funny things on the internet I hadn't seen before one of which was my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: most of them were people waiting in line for the ps3?
Speaker 0: yeah okay now there's this other video of.
Speaker 0: it's basically a bunch of kittens versus a bunch of bananas on strings.
Speaker 1: so the video for my thing of the day is a guy named Tracy Morgan who I know.
Speaker 1: that name is a famous name and now I know what he looks like but I have no idea what he does.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I could look it up on Wikipedia but I don't care.
Speaker 1: I'm doing a show right now and he pretends that he's on jackass but he calls it black ass.
Speaker 1: he does what a black man would do?
Speaker 1: well what a stereotypical humorous black man would do if forced to be in a you know jackass movie?
Speaker 0: see I've seen multiple black comedians where because a lot of black comedians can make racial jokes that if a white comedian tried to make
Speaker 1: sort of like the dentist who pretends to be Jewish to say just for the jokes yeah
Speaker 0: yeah but I've seen numerous comedians who will do a whole bit about how black guys do stupid things and white guys do stupid things.
Speaker 0: but the kinds of stupid things white people do are way more dangerous and stupid and the jokes are always like black man wouldn't do that.
Speaker 0: well that's what this seems to be.
Speaker 1: that is what this is.
Speaker 1: it's actually pretty funny.
Speaker 0: the white the guys are like all right like they show it like he's standing there and they're like all right.
Speaker 0: you got to do this thing.
Speaker 0: he's like I ain't doing that.
Speaker 1: what the fuck?
Speaker 0: yep yep the part of the end is what really got me.
Speaker 1: yes the best part okay yeah.
Speaker 0: so we're gonna kind of ramble a bit and then wrap this show up.
Speaker 0: yeah very fast karate style this whole show.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I found the email.
Speaker 1: it's I'm gonna do this quick geek back.
Speaker 0: I actually reply Oh a geek bag.
Speaker 1: yeah I replied to this guy with a pretty long email but I'm gonna just do a little summary.
Speaker 0: is this the one that went to the geek nights email that I saw the one about Linux on a ps3?
Speaker 0: yep yep yep okay.
Speaker 1: so I'm gonna read this guy's email cuz pretty short.
Speaker 1: it's a guy from Taipei guy from Taiwan.
Speaker 1: what's up Taiwan?
Speaker 1: he says yo I know you guys don't do reader mail or anything.
Speaker 1: we do just not often.
Speaker 1: but there's a question.
Speaker 1: maybe you could just answer or address in on a tech night or something.
Speaker 1: so Terra software release a version of yellow dog Linux version 5.0 to run on the ps3 say I have the 60 gig version and USB mouse and keyboard.
Speaker 1: what programs media applications games and etc.
Speaker 1: would I be able to run?
Speaker 1: how user-friendly is yellow dog?
Speaker 1: I have no Linux experience and is there any actual benefit at all?
Speaker 1: or is this just a thing to do to market the ps3 as a computer?
Speaker 1: well let's see if I can sum this up pretty quick.
Speaker 1: if you install Linux on your ps3 it's no different than installing Linux.
Speaker 1: well it's mostly no different than installing Linux on a normal computer.
Speaker 1: you can do anything that you can do with a Linux computer.
Speaker 1: the trick is that the ps3 is missing some components that a normal computer has and some of the components of a ps3 are different than what a normal computer has mainly the processor.
Speaker 0: yes you see all computers that you have ever used to pretty much either been a power PC very rarely only if it's an old Mac or an x86 most likely and those are pretty much the standard.
Speaker 0: everything else out there you will never run afoul of in your small life unless you are a technology professional and even then you'll rarely run afoul of anything else unless you are working with mobile devices.
Speaker 1: yes yes or giant giant big iron but even big iron these days uses power PC.
Speaker 0: yeah x86 because IBM still makes power PC and all that.
Speaker 0: but anyway yeah yeah the ps3 has the cell processor which we're not going to talk about in detail now we can do a show on it cuz it's pretty close to the power PC but not exactly well.
Speaker 0: I used to work in the factory at IBM that made him and in fact the people who made them were some of them used the computers that I designed and deployed and all that.
Speaker 0: so that's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: yeah but the cell like all things that are new and powerful and complicated is somewhat difficult to utilize fully.
Speaker 1: well the only thing that really matters to someone using Linux on a ps3 is the fact that cell is not power PC and it's not x86.
Speaker 0: you have to compile anything you want to run for cells.
Speaker 0: right the assembly instructions are for cell processors and not for x86 process.
Speaker 1: yes compiling is when you take source code and turn it into assembly instructions.
Speaker 0: instructions are just strings of ones and zeros that in the raw the processor sees and knows what to do with.
Speaker 1: yeah that's the actual you know if you take an exe file that's the stuff in there that talks to the processor directly.
Speaker 1: so if you have a different kind of processor you need to talk to it differently.
Speaker 1: so the Linux that they're giving you for it to run on the ps3 is already compiled into assembly instructions that can talk to a cell processor.
Speaker 1: so any software that is given to you by yellow dog Linux or whatever ps3 Linux they want to give you you know is going to work.
Speaker 1: but if you want to get some software like I don't know myth TV or your favorite NES emulator or something like that to run that normally runs on Linux on any of the computer you're gonna have to recompile it or find someone else who's already done it and is giving it to you.
Speaker 0: the other issue you're probably gonna run into is that yellow dog feels and works at least as far as I've interacted with it in recent memory like red hat.
Speaker 1: that's what yellow dog originally was red hat for power PC.
Speaker 0: that's all.
Speaker 0: it was not even like the new enterprise red hats.
Speaker 0: I'm talking like red hat nine where stuff just didn't work and if you want to do install software you had to find RPM.
Speaker 1: I think now it's more like a fedora closer to fedora.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: it's changed a lot over the.
Speaker 0: I hope so because I've never heard anyone say anything good about yellow dog.
Speaker 0: no I mean I don't want to sound well.
Speaker 1: originally yellow dog Linux was the only Linux that worked on desktop.
Speaker 1: you know Mac power PC computers.
Speaker 1: now every distro under the Sun has done power PC.
Speaker 1: so yellow dog it makes sense that their new niche is going to the cell for the core processor not the cell not the core.
Speaker 1: the cell core it cores the Intel core.
Speaker 1: it's an x86 anyway.
Speaker 1: so that's the first problem.
Speaker 1: the second problem is the weird peripherals of the ps3.
Speaker 1: now I don't know the answers to these questions.
Speaker 1: but will the blu-ray drive work in the Linux?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: but if it does then you're gonna have a good time watching blu-ray DVDs on your Linux powered ps3.
Speaker 1: if it doesn't you're gonna have a hard time because you can't put other stuff in there and make it work.
Speaker 0: I imagine it won't work or it'll take a lot of effort to make work because they really are probably worried about people ripping blu-ray movies and piracy and all that.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: now the question number two will the wireless success controller work in Linux?
Speaker 1: if it does good times cuz you can use that controller to play all kinds of emulated games.
Speaker 1: if it doesn't work then what's really the point?
Speaker 1: you might as well use a computer.
Speaker 1: why is ps3?
Speaker 1: will the HD output work?
Speaker 1: you know if you have a ps3 plugged into a TV and you want to use it as a computer you would hope that you would have HD output.
Speaker 1: seeing as the whole thing revolves around HD.
Speaker 1: if it only outputs in normal TV resolution when running Linux then really you could use a computer.
Speaker 0: my guess is going to be that again anything HD is going to be internally encrypted with bullshit and it'll be really hard to make it work with your Linux.
Speaker 1: yeah who knows what else there's questions of?
Speaker 1: like the net is this have a wire ps3 of wireless?
Speaker 0: yeah yeah something like that.
Speaker 1: it has a network card of some sort wireless or wired.
Speaker 1: you know is that gonna work?
Speaker 1: probably if it's wired it probably does.
Speaker 1: the real answer is who knows?
Speaker 0: you want to know what you should really do.
Speaker 0: just wait if it's feasible.
Speaker 0: if this is gonna work they're going to make it work and someone on slash now to say hey we got it to work and at that point get your ps3 install Linux on it.
Speaker 1: until then you're because his is where I'm kind of torn the ps3.
Speaker 1: you look at it and you say $600.
Speaker 1: look at those crap games.
Speaker 1: it looks like the PSP all over again only not portable all right and people are going crazy over it.
Speaker 1: whatever but as a computer running Linux if it has HD outputs if the blu-ray drive works if the network card works if the six axis controllers work if all those things work and their people start porting lots of software over to the cell processor and you it becomes very easy to cross compile existing open source software to the cell processor for 600 bucks.
Speaker 1: that's a pretty fast computer.
Speaker 0: you got there except that it's not upgradeable that's true.
Speaker 0: it's probably not that powerful we don't know yet.
Speaker 0: we got to wait for more information.
Speaker 1: but I think the real problem with the power is you have to wait for GCC to know or code for what.
Speaker 0: I've been reading a lot of articles about but I want to get more articles because I haven't seen enough to convince me yet.
Speaker 0: but a lot of developers have been talking about how the way the cell processors work.
Speaker 0: there's a really big memory access constraint.
Speaker 0: that's causing a lot of trouble for them and I saw a few websites claim that one of the reasons a lot of the earlier games coming out are 720p instead of 1080 is because they can't make the game run smoothly in 1080 because the textures are too big to use them properly in the RAM and also that a couple of the cell processors are pretty much always busy dealing with internal ps3 shit and all sorts of problems with the whole parallel architecture.
Speaker 1: well the other oh here's another thing.
Speaker 1: will the 3d powerful you know the 3d chip work in Linux you know?
Speaker 1: will you be able to run GLX SDL type things or will you just be stuck with 2d?
Speaker 1: and also computer processors are getting faster at a very fast rate still yeah so it really comes down to how much of the hardware in the ps3 does the ps3 Linux support?
Speaker 1: and if the if it does support all the hardware is that worth $600 compared to a $600 computer that you can buy a new egg?
Speaker 1: in
Speaker 0: my professional opinion as an IT guy who was worked for large companies for many years I would say this is my opinion that by the time people have figured out the ps3 enough to utilize it to its fullest regular computers will already be far faster than the ps3.
Speaker 1: yeah but there are a few things though that it still might be worth it even if it's not faster because you do have that HD output and you do have the blu-ray drive one.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone will get those to work in any reasonable span of time.
Speaker 1: they might already be working.
Speaker 1: I haven't done the research well.
Speaker 0: more importantly even if they work most people don't care about that.
Speaker 1: and well those people don't care about a ps3 in the first place because ps3 is all about HD.
Speaker 1: if you don't have an HD TV and you don't care about HD you don't care about ps3.
Speaker 0: but what most most people don't have HD yes I don't care about ps3.
Speaker 1: yeah this is only for people who care about ps3.
Speaker 0: there aren't that many people trying to make all this stuff work because I don't think that many people care.
Speaker 0: and I really think that blu-ray is not going to make it in the end.
Speaker 1: I don't think either.
Speaker 0: one of those things I'm not saying HD DVD will.
Speaker 0: I think it has a better chance.
Speaker 1: but the thing about blu-ray is it even if it doesn't quote make it as a movie disc or even as a popular disc at all for any use.
Speaker 1: it is useful even if you're the only one in the whole world to use it for storing shit tons of data.
Speaker 0: the ps3 doesn't burn blu-rays it only plays them and if you get a drive that burns blu-rays for your computer then you can read them on your computer.
Speaker 0: now if the ps3 could burn blu-rays you're totally right.
Speaker 0: I'm with you a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: but well you know no cuz here's the one thing right.
Speaker 1: hmm the ps3 is cheaper than a blu-ray player.
Speaker 0: right not by much.
Speaker 0: blu-ray players are pretty cheap yeah.
Speaker 1: but if you had something to burn blu-rays and you burn them but in a mesh in a computer you could then put them in your PlayStation 3 to watch them on your HD TV but you could watch them on your HD computer.
Speaker 1: yes you can watch blu-ray discs on the ps3 without Linux.
Speaker 0: so yeah yeah yeah plus I mean for all this talk of HD.
Speaker 0: everyone needs to remember that computers have effectively been HD for a long time.
Speaker 1: yes but the only way to actually get a computer to display an HD on an HD TV is instead of a computer monitor is if your HD TV has DVI input which some do.
Speaker 1: oh yeah only the good one.
Speaker 0: but you know what for us especially if you're living in a small house or a dorm.
Speaker 0: just get a 21 inch CRT and use that as your television and it'll be awesome.
Speaker 0: HD it will be awesome and it'll be a fraction of the price.
Speaker 0: there won't be any DRM.
Speaker 1: oh wait here's a reason to use the ps3 with the HD outputs.
Speaker 1: you could download using the ps3 in the network connection and Linux onto the hard drive HD stuff from the internet and then watch it on the TV.
Speaker 1: but the only way you can do that now is with the tricky myth TV setups with like hop edge car or or just watch it on your computer.
Speaker 1: yeah but even I don't.
Speaker 0: the only HD content.
Speaker 0: you can download our stupid movie trailers now.
Speaker 1: you can download lots of HD content not anything worthwhile.
Speaker 0: yeah lots of what what's worthwhile?
Speaker 1: all kinds of movies on bit torrent TV shows on bit torrent whatever.
Speaker 0: most I mean things on bit torrent most people they really.
Speaker 1: if we didn't have the Mac plugged into the TV I probably wouldn't watch anything we downloaded.
Speaker 1: I can't watch stuff on a computer screen one I can't.
Speaker 0: just fine cuz I got a pretty big computer screen.
Speaker 1: yeah even so it's not.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna like sit around a computer screen those days.
Speaker 1: that's for the college days.
Speaker 1: if you're in college it's great nowadays.
Speaker 1: no way.
Speaker 0: I just I think any buying the ps3 for any reason other than playing ps3 games in my opinion is really dumb.
Speaker 1: yeah it's pretty dumb but I'm just.
Speaker 1: I'm just giving people the facts about ps3 on Linux.
Speaker 0: I just don't think there's any useful purpose to doing that.
Speaker 1: there is a useful purpose for a few people who care anyway.
Speaker 1: yeah we're going to bed the info about the ps3 in Linux.
Speaker 0: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays we have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: you can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew dot-com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.