Speaker 1: It's Wednesday December 13.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we talk about the rise and fall of anime music videos with special guest Jeff to Tarik.
Speaker 2: Let's do
Speaker 1: this
Speaker 2: alright, so today we're here and we're gonna talk about anime music videos and To entertain everyone to the maximum potential we have brought on an anime music video expert So no longer will you put us in the forums after the show, but we will be punned.
Speaker 2: live for your listening enjoyment.
Speaker 2: So here we have with us Jeff to Tarik anime music video expert.
Speaker 2: Hi Jeff.
Speaker 2: What's?
Speaker 0: yes, that's me.
Speaker 0: Hey, how's it going guys?
Speaker 0: I guess I should establish my geek credentials to begin with.
Speaker 0: I've been doing anime music videos since 1989 Which is right on.
Speaker 0: the birth of the entire movement Was a fan right about that period in time as well, so I'm firmly entrenched in the Voltron Transor Z Robotech stage of fandom.
Speaker 0: I Have because I've been doing it since 1989 It's what my college degree is in mass communication broadcasting.
Speaker 0: So and I've got like 10 years experience professionally editing for TV news stations and at the local affiliate level I'm still active in video production duplication these days.
Speaker 0: So as far as the technical aspects go I got it down And I've been doing this longer than I think most people have doing them these days.
Speaker 0: They've actually been alive, which is a frightening thing.
Speaker 0: I started saying I was old school when you were in kindergarten and I think with each passing year that becomes Sadly more and more true.
Speaker 2: Let's see, we were born.
Speaker 1: I was seven when you were making music videos.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I think that's right.
Speaker 2: Cuz we were born in 82, right?
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm the other 16 years old.
Speaker 0: Wow, there are people 15 16 years old who are making videos now and consider anything from 2000 to be old school, which is painful.
Speaker 2: Wow Yeah, well at least we were both watching Voltron at the same time.
Speaker 2: I Didn't even know there was a vehicle team Voltron.
Speaker 0: until college I didn't know what the hell about with you vehicle team all the way could mainly because the Lead pilot was named Jeff.
Speaker 1: So that's See I had to admit it.
Speaker 1: I was more of a mask fan and I regret that to this day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you saw oh don't regret that mask was good.
Speaker 1: Hey, I have all.
Speaker 1: I have all the toys.
Speaker 2: go try go try and watch mask.
Speaker 2: It's not good anymore.
Speaker 2: It's like go back and try to watch he-man.
Speaker 2: not good anymore It does.
Speaker 0: he was good to make fun of?
Speaker 2: I guess true, you know, but that's not the thing to brag about.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so anime music videos.
Speaker 1: I mean we have often complained that we hate all current anime music videos and we like to think oh well back in the day It was good, but your back in the day is long before our back in the day.
Speaker 1: so I guess yes, we're not too up on exactly how the anime music video scene started or what it was like before YouTube and Computers that could just edit video on the fly and all that stuff.
Speaker 2: digital video cameras that were readily available in stores And of course Naruto.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: and an internet capable of Distributing the videos or FTP or BitTorrent.
Speaker 1: the first AMV I ever downloaded was literally an AVI That was like a hundred by a hundred and fifty pixels to Sailor Moon.
Speaker 2: The first AMV I saw was at the first anime club.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah Wow.
Speaker 2: I didn't even know they existed.
Speaker 2: I was I was confused.
Speaker 2: I thought they were showing real music videos cuz they showed white reflection.
Speaker 2: They threw me all off.
Speaker 0: The first AMV I saw was back in 1988 or 1989 the camera which and one of the first conventions I went to Called Dixie Trek in Atlanta, Georgia.
Speaker 0: It was done by a guy that I became fast friends with ever since.
Speaker 0: name is Matt Murray.
Speaker 0: He's with corn pone flex, which is a fan run Parody film site.
Speaker 0: they do a lot of live-action Fake trailers for movies that will never be made.
Speaker 0: They also made anime.
Speaker 0: one of the first anime parodies called star dip lots, which is sort of a retarded retelling of star blazers.
Speaker 0: Matt is good friends with Dave Merrill who a lot of fans will know is the man who gave birth to anime weekend Atlanta, which is now ironically one of the Largest if not the largest Convention that has anime music video programming in it.
Speaker 0: Matt had a room party.
Speaker 0: He was showing started watts and he also had some music videos.
Speaker 0: He's done.
Speaker 0: Try to remember the exact Things that he did.
Speaker 0: he had a couple of weird out videos.
Speaker 0: one was to Christmas at ground zero with a whole bunch of hot collective footage.
Speaker 0: the other one was slime creatures from outer space with you know, a lot of monsters.
Speaker 0: and The last one I remember seeing was the bird by The trash man, you know everybody, you know, the bird is the word that's not using footage of the Dory bird which is this sort of Black bird with a tiny little neck that sits on the shoulder of Captain
Speaker 2: Harlow.
Speaker 2: Oh, I know that bird.
Speaker 2: Yeah Now I know the name of it.
Speaker 1: We're slowly working our way through all that is Harlock and it is both joyous and horrible at the same time.
Speaker 0: So, I guess you've seen the dubs.
Speaker 2: Well, I mean one of the first anime I saw was galaxy three nine on sci-fi channel.
Speaker 0: So, oh, so is that?
Speaker 0: was that the new dub or the old that worries called Captain Warlock and he sounds like John Wayne.
Speaker 2: I'm pretty sure it was Captain Harlock when I saw it.
Speaker 0: Oh, you were lucky.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not that old.
Speaker 1: We never actually saw things like warriors of the wind.
Speaker 0: Yeah That is good that Scott.
Speaker 0: that's the subject of one of my best music videos really really yeah If anyone wants to check out my profile on anime music videos not of work.
Speaker 0: It's you can go to shrinkster comm CHI Charlie hotel indigo and video in question is called.
Speaker 0: I Think it's now sugar.
Speaker 0: They reluctant warrior.
Speaker 0: It's set to Mike and the mechanics.
Speaker 0: Why me?
Speaker 0: It's a fairly long video.
Speaker 0: by today's standards, it's over five minutes long But back in the day my day which should be I guess around 1993 or 1992 You guys are familiar with New York City, of course.
Speaker 0: So have you ever heard of a convention called icon on Long Island?
Speaker 2: Yeah, I've heard of it, but I don't.
Speaker 2: I don't know much about it.
Speaker 2: People keep mentioning.
Speaker 0: Yeah a good while back There was an icon that had a mini convention within it called chibi con And they had one of the first music video contests and they only had one prize which was best video of the year and the why me video took that prize and it still hold held as Favorite for a lot of people who've grown up with music videos for longer than the mid 90s.
Speaker 0: Trying to get back to I'll give him back to where I started with talking with Matt Murray.
Speaker 0: I saw his stuff really liked.
Speaker 0: it came close friends with him because his stuff was tight it matched the beat it went on the lyrics and This is still when he's just using two consumer grade VCRs to edit this thing, you know, you have the tape pause Press record.
Speaker 0: Oh wait, it didn't work.
Speaker 0: There's a rainbow.
Speaker 0: Recue both the tapes.
Speaker 0: try it again on pause.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a flash ring.
Speaker 0: Can't use that?
Speaker 0: So if you imagine doing that process trial and error over and over again without trying to bust your VCR Turn out something that looked as good as what he had.
Speaker 0: It really inspired me and Got back home started college that that same year where they had a JVC Professional grade VHS editing deck.
Speaker 0: It's just two decks.
Speaker 0: They could do assemble at it and Video insert and two tracks of audio insert.
Speaker 0: and that's all it was.
Speaker 0: and I had my first music video Done within a couple of months after I started college.
Speaker 0: It took like two days to edit and that was on my profile.
Speaker 0: It's the one that is the Akira music video set to twisted sisters.
Speaker 0: The kids are back and I recently remastered it with DVD footage, which is amazing.
Speaker 0: It's like it's so easy to do it on the computer at home without having to you know Sneak into the TV studio at the university and make sure no one's using it for something.
Speaker 0: It's actually worthwhile.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that really seems to be kind of the biggest I guess complaint or anything about people who talk about AMVs that as it's gotten Easier to make them there have been more of them
Speaker 0: There have been more people doing them there are considerably more videos and there are considerably more people who should have no music videos Because it is so easy.
Speaker 0: I mean with great power it comes great responsibility And I don't think a lot of people understand that they stay to see is the new hot thing.
Speaker 0: They see a lot of people doing it.
Speaker 0: They wander past a contest going on a convention.
Speaker 0: seeing that seeing all these people Laughing and cheering at what they're seeing on screen.
Speaker 0: They think hey, there's a little thing on my computer.
Speaker 0: It's called Windows Movie Maker.
Speaker 0: I wonder if I can do something with that.
Speaker 0: So they'll download and hover however many crappy encodes they can get off Kazaa or Lime wire or whatever.
Speaker 0: and it's got like it's all chunky.
Speaker 0: It's probably in real media format and It just looks terrible anything.
Speaker 0: Hey, I can just take any music I want and slam three minutes worth of stuff on top of it.
Speaker 0: And hey, I got a music video and it couldn't be more wrong in my estimation.
Speaker 1: Well, then kind of a two-part question here.
Speaker 1: But what would you think was kind of the Golden Age?
Speaker 1: or when did the best AMVs overall come out?
Speaker 1: And I guess in pursuant to that what makes an AMV good in your opinion?
Speaker 1: Like what is it that makes one click versus one?
Speaker 1: that just doesn't.
Speaker 0: I would say the Golden Age is any time between Just more or less arbitrarily between 1989 and 1993 or 1994 because that is the point where it would.
Speaker 0: if you wanted to make an AMV music video you were stuck with videotape and only Videotape.
Speaker 0: and if you had the patience to sit there Whether it in a university setting with a professional deck or at home with two VCRs to high-five forehead flying a race VCRs Then you probably wanted to do it in some professional capacity or else You're just really obsessive and willing to take the time to do it.
Speaker 0: And I think as a result there was.
Speaker 0: there was some crap.
Speaker 0: sure there were some crappy videos back then But by and large the community was much smaller.
Speaker 0: It was made of more dedicated people and Fandom was still small enough that I think It got more appreciation just by the number of people that were around I. They didn't get lost in the shuffle of the big conventions of today.
Speaker 0: They didn't get lost in the shuffle of everyone else's music video.
Speaker 0: There weren't contests in the first few years that I started doing them.
Speaker 0: It was simply something that you might show a couple at opening ceremonies or you might try to sneak one in during some dead space between stuff that was shown in the video room.
Speaker 0: it wasn't really something meant to be made as a Competitive video.
Speaker 0: it was something you did for fun that you just want to say hey take a look what I did.
Speaker 0: This is pretty good for anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah My first music video premiered at a Christmas party with maybe You know five or ten people and had no aspirations of trying to get into our contest Just to see if I can win something.
Speaker 0: It was just like I did this.
Speaker 0: It looks pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Tell me what you think.
Speaker 1: Yeah definitely compare that to today where Every con has the AMV contest just like they have the cosplay and people go from con to con and it's this huge deal.
Speaker 1: You know who won what where and I've won this many awards.
Speaker 0: therefore blah And therefore I'm excellent, you know, maybe not.
Speaker 0: What was the second part of your question?
Speaker 0: again, what makes it?
Speaker 0: what do I think makes a good music video?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess tell some of our listeners the videos you think.
Speaker 1: like a couple of them three or four Maybe that are really really good and what you like or at least what would make a video that good to where you'd remember it And it wouldn't get lost in the shuffle.
Speaker 0: Yeah right now something my very favorites I have to go with failed experiments in video editing by EK Simply because she's a really good artist and Took some of her actual failed attempts at trying to make a music video They like.
Speaker 0: yet She had a good concept but couldn't really get into the editing past the first part or had a really good song.
Speaker 0: But the editing didn't really work.
Speaker 0: and then she linked all these together with cartoons that she had done about the process.
Speaker 0: editing on premiere.
Speaker 0: and you know the the edit edit edit beer edit edit beer and Render.
Speaker 0: That one's is really good because it's genuinely funny.
Speaker 0: It's well paced and the effort shows another one of your shameless rock video by Absolute destiny which uses footage from foodie foodie flcl And a cut down song.
Speaker 0: I can't remember the name of the song now, but it's a really good song.
Speaker 0: A lot of good digital effects in there that don't overwhelm the video.
Speaker 0: They fit in very nicely.
Speaker 0: It's very tightly edited.
Speaker 0: It's It's just a beautiful thing to behold Tainted donuts, which is one of the first videos.
Speaker 0: I think that really took compositing to a new level taking two dissimilar titles try gun and cowboy bebop and managing to stick a character from one into a scene with the others like spike and jet are looking at It's Vash the stampede and it looks pretty good.
Speaker 0: I think that one set a new standard that everyone tried to eight from then on out.
Speaker 1: it did I remember right at like right before it came out or at least right before everyone started to be aware of it.
Speaker 1: I remember seeing a similar video someone tried to do to the same two anime and it was.
Speaker 1: I Won't mention who did if it was god-awful.
Speaker 2: I don't think I remember who did it but I do remember a time when everyone you know had the idea That you could make a music video where you combine different shows together But no one had actually been able to do it technologically speaking Until wasn't aside.
Speaker 0: as an aside one thing.
Speaker 0: one other thing that I did in addition to music videos is I was Among the pioneers of fan parody films along with Matt Murray CP Smith and the rest of guys with corn bone flicks.
Speaker 0: I did animation versus live-action.
Speaker 0: Granted it was cutting back and forth between the two sources, but it was without any kind of real compositing.
Speaker 0: But it was my homage to the great flame Wars that happened on BBS systems across the country in the early days of using that who'd win in the fight the Space battleship Yamato versus a Star Destroyer Captain Harlock versus the Enterprise who would win?
Speaker 0: and my films X23 and x20.
Speaker 0: now the full titles super hyper mega bloody ultra cosmo death extravaganza x23 And it's its sequel x23 to electric boogaloo.
Speaker 0: just the co-production with Matt Murray Ended up being two and a half hours long, but man we told so many jokes in there was impossible It literally impossible to edit it down.
Speaker 0: Yes, so yeah, I look at the but so that was.
Speaker 0: you know I was able to cut back and forth between animation and live-action sources there and still able to tell a good story.
Speaker 0: but then along comes tainted donuts and Maybe there's one or two things ahead of that, but everyone remembers tainted donuts where it's composited very nicely and people hold that as a Good standard.
Speaker 0: One of what else do I think makes a good music video being able to appreciate?
Speaker 0: Your source material both your audio and your video.
Speaker 0: Take a song that Has lyrics that you can match a video to being able to edit on the beat.
Speaker 0: There's a video that got a lot of hype on the west coast.
Speaker 0: It was footage from X or one set to Metallica's enter Sandman and Mostly real listeners and you guys have probably heard the song where there's that there's a guitar solo.
Speaker 0: And then right in the middle of a James Hetfield cells boom and in that music video the editor Completely failed to put anything at that very natural sync point.
Speaker 0: and that bothered me everyone.
Speaker 0: and it bothered me more That people thought this was a fantastic video.
Speaker 0: and here I am pointing out.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: look He missed this very crucial point did actually nothing with it.
Speaker 0: So that's something I look for as well.
Speaker 2: I do have to agree that when videos don't match up like with the beats that gets on my nerves more than anything.
Speaker 1: Actually, what bothers me even more than that is when they try when they match up the lyrics to what's going on to the video in a direct non metaphoric stupid way.
Speaker 2: Yeah, well sometimes they do it in a way that really takes you out of the video and they go and you're like wow That's dumb.
Speaker 2: But sometimes they do it in a way that's you know, it's alright.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm talking about like.
Speaker 1: they said the word hand.
Speaker 1: Oh, but here's a picture of someone holding their hand up.
Speaker 1: Oh, they said the word TV.
Speaker 1: Look there's a TV.
Speaker 1: I'll candidate.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it works if the little stuff like that works if it flows If the stuff they're showing ends up flowing together.
Speaker 0: They're showing random shots like ooh TV ooh hand ooh face ooh eyes.
Speaker 0: then no not so much.
Speaker 0: I mean they're showing some technical Acumen by doing that but they haven't polished it.
Speaker 0: I think that's a complaint that I have a lot about a lot of Music videos these days and their editors is that they've got the technical expertise.
Speaker 0: They've moved beyond just a basic say a basic Lincoln ball video which for some of your listeners who don't know Fusion You're sleep.
Speaker 0: I Lincoln Park set to Random fight footage from Dragon Ball Z and there are literally thousands about.
Speaker 2: why there are thousands of those.
Speaker 2: Didn't the 999th guy say hey, there are 998 of these.
Speaker 2: maybe I should make something else.
Speaker 1: No, he thought I'm gonna make it so much better than all of those fools who don't understand Goku's true pain.
Speaker 0: Perhaps They're probably both thinking also.
Speaker 0: I want to be number 1,000.
Speaker 0: That'll mean something.
Speaker 1: Actually at RIT anime for April Fool's showing we because we always showed a bunch of anime music videos before the show or before The you know the showing every week Which honestly as the years went on got harder and harder because we just couldn't find New good ones that hadn't already been shown in past years and they were probably out there.
Speaker 1: We couldn't find them.
Speaker 1: But what we did is we showed I think five or six videos and they were all to Dragon Ball Z Linkin Park in the end.
Speaker 1: And then to top it off we bring out the last video and I promise you guys this isn't to Dragon Ball Z and then Linkin Park in the end starts.
Speaker 0: It was like Gundam wing And then you woke up in the hospital.
Speaker 2: No, you would be surprised how?
Speaker 2: Not angry.
Speaker 2: the club was.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean 150 200 people in the room and they'll pretty much sit there until the lights come on.
Speaker 1: then they'll kill you.
Speaker 1: Stay until the lights come on.
Speaker 2: So before you mentioned that the Golden Age was like way in like the early 90s But a lot of videos you mentioned as your favorites came way later.
Speaker 2: So Yeah
Speaker 0: Mostly because that's the ones that I mentioned are ones that actually be downloaded these days Some of the ones that I remember as being really good in the Golden Age stuff done by Matt Murray by the Seiko beaver Derek Jackson goes by the name Jenga row and there are others that I can't but I can't remember
Speaker 1: off the bat.
Speaker 0: They simply aren't available for download.
Speaker 0: They exist maybe on VHS and the corner of someone's closet and that's about it.
Speaker 2: Why they were never uploaded and why doesn't someone do that?
Speaker 2: Is it just laziness forgetfulness not caring or not knowing?
Speaker 0: Not not knowing be the main thing.
Speaker 0: They're animated music videos.
Speaker 0: org does to have a proxy service.
Speaker 0: some stuff has been at least Documented if not uploaded.
Speaker 0: In fact, I've probably got a lot of Matt's music videos hanging around here.
Speaker 0: He's at the point in his life where he doesn't really care much about Anime anymore and he cares even less about what fandom has become.
Speaker 0: So he doesn't care about his music videos anymore.
Speaker 0: So I might have to take him up and Upload them to the org as a proxy because this stuff needs to be shown.
Speaker 1: I would say in addition to that How would what if say you got together a panel at a con or a showing room at a con and it was the old?
Speaker 1: School anime music videos.
Speaker 1: There's no way you could have ever seen before thing unless you're real Or actually did them.
Speaker 0: Respect your elders just because I don't think that it.
Speaker 0: In a way it's a handicap because You know The Internet is the monster that it is now and anything before then has been left and by the wayside it clearly forgotten.
Speaker 1: See, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I do see a lot of people on the internet now who if they find out there's something out there That they could have seen that isn't on the internet like an anime that no one ever even Got from TV onto a digital medium a lot of them will.
Speaker 1: they have this collector Compulsion and they'll freak out and do anything they can to get it and watch it and distribute it just to say that they could Any.
Speaker 2: just today?
Speaker 2: I saw a website full of 80s commercials all on YouTube and it was the most fantastic thing ever.
Speaker 0: Throw some most into the mix and anime hell.
Speaker 0: That's perfect.
Speaker 0: I I think that and I'm gonna be mean here.
Speaker 0: So I'm speaking in I. I Think that the anime music videos community is split into The hopeless consumers and the hapless creators people who are too busy making their next world beating anime music video that may or may not be that great and the people who Exist to do nothing but consume it.
Speaker 0: And then you've got the subset of on both sides the the people who come on to the anime music videos Forums and For all intents and purposes Blair through a megaphone.
Speaker 0: How do I download these videos?
Speaker 0: How do I watch them despite the fact that there are stickies right above their heads on the forums that say hey How do I download this?
Speaker 0: or how do I get a single player?
Speaker 0: So the people who say the people who have obviously by the little date next to their name have registered that very day and Probably haven't done any kind of lurking or looking around on the forums or the main site that has all sorts of informative guides and post.
Speaker 0: How do I make a music video despite the fact again that there's a sticky above their heads.
Speaker 0: It says how do I do this?
Speaker 0: More often than not they're gonna get flamed to hell and back.
Speaker 0: Some people are Helpful and try to help but I think these people are pretty hopeless to be in with And maybe maybe this is a role I can fill.
Speaker 0: there really needs to be Someone.
Speaker 0: who's the combination of American idols?
Speaker 0: Simon Cowell?
Speaker 2: We don't know about that.
Speaker 1: I know I'm not totally divorced from pop culture unlike you Scott, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's the really caustic British judge who if someone sucks will come straight out and say you suck and you should never sing ever ever again.
Speaker 0: Simon Cowell crossed with Al Square engine from Deadwood.
Speaker 0: I Someone who's not again not afraid to tell someone that they suck and probably stick a knife in the back at the same time.
Speaker 1: See to us you're preaching to the choir.
Speaker 1: we've always wanted a site kind of the way OC remixes is for AMVs where They look at him and they only put up the ones that they think are good like kind of a filter.
Speaker 1: Because I mean, I guess I'll ask you this question, but the technology is better now It's so much easier to make music videos.
Speaker 1: So you'd think that the people who are good could be making just even more amazing videos.
Speaker 1: So are people making amazing videos and we just can't find them in the chaff?
Speaker 1: or did the good people just disappear?
Speaker 0: Some of the good people disappeared some of the other good people do nothing But work all year on the music video the single music video that they're gonna put into the contest at AWA.
Speaker 0: I think those are the big things.
Speaker 0: There's no one person who's turning out several good music videos a year or even several people doing that.
Speaker 0: I think it.
Speaker 0: I think it really falls into The people who just churn out garbage and have all this amazing Technology at their disposal and and just throw stuff up randomly because hey, it looks good you know doesn't really fit and as I said the people who are in fact really really good and Really are just working on their next killer
Speaker 1: app no matter how long
Speaker 2: it takes.
Speaker 2: I mean the technology though must enable the people who are really really good to make, you know more better videos.
Speaker 2: I mean if they made you know ten good videos with the old tech you can't make ten good.
Speaker 2: They should be able to make you know, twenty even better videos with the new technology.
Speaker 2: So while you know, you've added, you know, this giant mountain of crap.
Speaker 2: There must be you know, the Total sum of good stuff must have increased or as it not Yeah, the good stuff has increased but the crappy stuff has increased exponentially more.
Speaker 0: There's just a lot of stuff out there that should never have been made or at least never released to the public.
Speaker 0: It's it's one thing to make a music video just to practice and see if you're any good at it and show to your friends And they say hey, that's really good.
Speaker 0: That's really good.
Speaker 0: And then they release it to the org and it is lost amongst Hundreds of literally hundreds of other videos that are almost just like it.
Speaker 1: Well, I get but I've got.
Speaker 1: I've got kind of two ideas that I've been bad around for a long time as to Why it's so hard for the good videos to get Distributed versus the crowd.
Speaker 2: I know what your two ideas are.
Speaker 2: Yeah, because we pretty much agree with third idea.
Speaker 1: All right, but just we'd like to hear your thoughts on this one.
Speaker 1: It seems like most cons now will show any video you send them and they'll have a room where they'll just show Anime music videos and anime music videos and anime music videos and anime music videos forever.
Speaker 1: or even if it's not all dedicated room They'll still have you know, two hours worth of a MVs to show even if there were only 40 minutes worth of Not not saying great music videos but videos that are above the line of being being worth showing.
Speaker 1: Like it seems like they feel so bad about telling someone they're not going to show something that they show everything.
Speaker 1: and right along with that Most cons now have rules that if your video is already won an award anywhere They don't want you to enter it.
Speaker 1: so it seems like once a video succeeds it immediately disappears and Then people at Otacon never see it because it already won an award at AWA.
Speaker 1: And I guess Scott's got a third thing.
Speaker 0: I think you're right?
Speaker 2: Yeah, well my thing is, you know I remember his time back at RIT that some guy Was watching an AMV on his laptop that his friend was in the process of making and it was a really good macross video.
Speaker 2: But you know, I was like, hey, can you can you send me that?
Speaker 2: or you know?
Speaker 2: when is that, you know, because I wanted to see it because it was really good and The attitude of the guy who was making it and the guy who was showing it to me were both, you know Like no, we're gonna show it once at a convention and we're never gonna put it on the internet or anything because we're all you know assholes.
Speaker 2: so And I remember looking for anime music videos to show at anime club and I often found that you know Not everything was out on the internet to download even stuff that was you know already out.
Speaker 1: and yeah I mean not stuff like oh It's an awesome video from the early 90s.
Speaker 1: that's on a VHS tape and no one bothered to put it up But people who have the digital format and specifically refuse to distribute it.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 2: I mean I get the feeling that The part of the reason why the good stuff doesn't come out is because the people who put so much time are less willing to Freely distribute them while the people who whipped up some crap, you know, Lincoln Ball in five minutes They want all their friends to see it.
Speaker 2: So they put it up on BitTorrent and everything for everyone in the whole world.
Speaker 0: I guess I haven't really run into many too many people who feel so possessive of their work.
Speaker 0: They want to keep it to themselves and make love to it and that might really be a northern thing.
Speaker 1: It might be cuz Daryl and Gerald is also to a degree said that they don't see that so much and we've seen it a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm totally going on anecdotal evidence here, which is why I'm asking Yeah, cuz to to your to your credit the guy we're talking about at anime club was kind of a scary fanboy in and of himself indeed.
Speaker 0: But Yeah, going back to one of your other points About how there are rules that say if your anime music video has already won an award you can't enter it in this contest and I agree that I think a lot of good stuff doesn't get shown because People are.
Speaker 0: some people are just simply chasing the next contest and probably aren't willing to send their stuff to a general As willing to send something to a general showing and I agree that you know.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's it comes down to the stuff that makes the cut and the rest that could get shown in a general showing.
Speaker 0: and I think that's where you see a lot of junk Going to think now Yeah, that yeah that pretty much covers it as far as I can tell unless I think of something else.
Speaker 2: What would you think if there was a convention that wouldn't show a music video unless it had already won something in the previous year?
Speaker 0: I would probably go for that.
Speaker 0: I think it would probably bring a lot of good competition into it sort of a you know a royal rumble of enemies music videos.
Speaker 0: not to steal a thunder of Iron editor which is doing a royal rumble type thing at Ohio con which I just found out I'm a part of Yeah, but I'd like to see that sort of like, you know the best of the best and maybe hold it at AWA as opposed to simply the AWA contest.
Speaker 0: have like gather all or We probably wouldn't be able to do all because there's so many conventions now, but a relative sampling of maybe the winning music videos from what I guess what you consider be the major conventions Otacon and Anime Expo and Akon and Anime Central AWA, etc, etc, and then pit those against each other?
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically, that'd be a good idea.
Speaker 1: I'm just for anything that'll make it easy for people to see good videos and recognize that They're good videos because then maybe people will I don't know either not make crap videos or at least the crap videos will kind of Exist, but they'll be static.
Speaker 1: They won't be out on the forefront like they are now because it's so hard to find good.
Speaker 1: And these I've seen maybe two that were new that I've liked in the past.
Speaker 1: what seven years.
Speaker 2: Yeah How do you find new good music videos short of going to all the conventions and looking at the winners?
Speaker 2: I mean, you know, I've been to enemy music videos at org not recently.
Speaker 2: I'm sure you use that site a lot more than I do.
Speaker 0: But well, I usually when it's like an I can stand to use it.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it just becomes a cesspool and I have to step away from.
Speaker 2: it's exactly what I'm trying to get at.
Speaker 2: is when I used It you know in years past it was always very very difficult to search and there was no way to say Show me the most popular video right now, you know, give it to me.
Speaker 2: Show me something.
Speaker 1: I can honestly say that whenever I went to an V's org and I was looking for music a specific music video It was great.
Speaker 1: But if I was just browsing by song or by anime or by whatever I don't think I ever found anything by accident.
Speaker 1: That wasn't horrible.
Speaker 0: That's that's the sad thing.
Speaker 0: we're using the quick search or using the super powerful super Nice.
Speaker 1: I was searching because I was looking for stuff to show to clubs.
Speaker 1: I remember I would search like very specifically like I want this anime without Spoilers and I'd pick like different genres of music.
Speaker 1: I'd poke around Just looking for something we always had to pick like something high-energy something slow something sappy maybe something funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I'm looking at the main page for the org right now and on the right hand side There's the top list the top 10% videos the top star scale the top favorite videos the most commented videos The most used anime the most used music most underrated which I'm not sure how they figure that out.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's the one that's got the.
Speaker 2: maybe it's well, you're the simple watch but no one votes on or anything.
Speaker 0: I know that's exactly right here.
Speaker 0: here are the 50 most downloaded videos with the fewest opinions left for them.
Speaker 0: No, I would suggest giving that another shot if you haven't been there in a while.
Speaker 1: It has been four years since I went to anime music videos org on purpose.
Speaker 2: Well, I went to it to look at your profile and that way Smart man Alright.
Speaker 2: so why don't we talk about Like the process of making a music video?
Speaker 1: because without technical detail technical details that will put everyone to sleep Just like what I guess to break it down.
Speaker 1: What's what's the core things you need to do to make a music video?
Speaker 1: That isn't just utter ass.
Speaker 0: Well, I try to just go through the process in which I do it.
Speaker 0: I'll usually hear a song that I really like and Think that hey this might go with a particular anime that I've got or I can get a hold of And then just start.
Speaker 0: my process is probably different than other people, but I start story about storyboarding it out in my head.
Speaker 0: I'll take specific lyrics and then think that this particular scene from episode three would work really well here.
Speaker 0: and Well see Nowadays I'll just open a premiere.
Speaker 0: have the timeline.
Speaker 0: sting that right in front of you blank.
Speaker 0: lay the music down.
Speaker 0: Get all of my footage converted from DVD to a format that is easier to edit with and then just starts plunking down scenes in Maybe about two second increments or so until I've and then just Preview it and play it.
Speaker 0: preview and play and then fix it and then preview it and play it again.
Speaker 0: And that's why nonlinear editing on the computer is so much more fun than doing it on videotape.
Speaker 0: And then just and I don't consider putting effects in until I get everything More or less laid down unless I know specifically I want to have a dissolve.
Speaker 0: here I want to go from.
Speaker 0: I want to transition nice and slow from this two shot of The two students in love to a close-up of the guy and then dissolve again to the close-up of the girl.
Speaker 0: If I don't have anything like this specifically in mind, and I'll just lay everything down cut to cut to cut and once you get all that laid down if I can make my yardstick is if I can get the whole thing finished and rendered and Play it out if I can sit there, and I'm smiling by the end just by like Thinking that yeah that that went really well together, then I know it's a pretty decent video But you gotta have the.
Speaker 0: I'll just go back to it.
Speaker 0: You gotta have respect for your sources.
Speaker 0: You got to know what it is you're editing with what video it is And that's why it's so dangerous to tackle big TV series sometimes that unless you've watched it several times I know it inside and out then You're gonna be strapped for footage And then you start grabbing random stuff and throwing it in just to fill this little one second told you got.
Speaker 1: Well, I actually never thought of that.
Speaker 1: But it makes sense because I think a half the videos I see at cons now And they only cover like the first nine episodes of a show because someone seemed like they wanted to Get the video out as soon as the show finished, and they didn't actually pay attention.
Speaker 2: I've also noticed a lot more Various videos whereas back in the day.
Speaker 2: There were usually a lot more single show videos.
Speaker 0: I think that for me anyway, that's that speaks to the shortening attention span of people these days.
Speaker 0: one of the things that I was taught in College was that it's called a four-second rule and this probably applies more towards general video production.
Speaker 0: But you never hold a shot for more than four seconds unless it's really justified because by that time you're going It's getting bored and what wants you to move on?
Speaker 0: I find that nowadays for general editing That's which one like a two-second rule and when you get down to the nitty-gritty with enemy music videos It's even smaller than that.
Speaker 0: you gotta have cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut and keep moving on to the next new thing And I think that's why there are more various videos is that People can't hold an idea for two and a half to three minutes or three and a half minutes.
Speaker 0: They've just come up with a bunch of short gags and short things that they can string together to One song.
Speaker 0: or in the case of the AMV hello projects Dozens of little snippets that are unconnected and unrelated and put together into one monstrous video and those are good.
Speaker 0: But I think that speaks to why there aren't as many good music videos these days.
Speaker 0: is because people just can't hold their attention Long enough to edit it.
Speaker 1: I agree with you so much.
Speaker 1: It hurts.
Speaker 1: Well, not just lazy time we won't get into that but just in the four years I was RIT in the anime club when I was a freshman I wasn't running the club or anything.
Speaker 1: Just watching it the average music video.
Speaker 1: They showed was between three and five minutes long and some of the I mean there were literally ones I remember where it would just show a character kind of sitting there or like one Shot of a character walking for eight nine ten seconds, and they were good videos but they were just long and sentimental.
Speaker 1: and In the four years until when I was eventually president of the club The videos that people hated those videos they boo if a video went on for more than two minutes and they bored They want it.
Speaker 1: The only videos they liked were robots fighting very quickly with effects or something.
Speaker 2: That was incredibly hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like.
Speaker 0: yeah funny funny is good, but action and well not actually effects.
Speaker 0: Overuse of effects for simply effects sake is another one of the downfalls of modern music videos in my estimation.
Speaker 0: Is that it?
Speaker 0: The getting back to the technology that human you guys mentioned know.
Speaker 0: there's so much of it out there now between premiere after effects Photoshop Sony Vegas and all the other professional stuff that's out there.
Speaker 0: It puts so much power at your disposal.
Speaker 0: There's someone you can literally just throw an effect down Every second and of your entire song and probably not exhaust all the permutations that are available to you not and I'd be willing to bet that some people have actually tried that given the way things are these days, but Effects for effects sake are not good.
Speaker 0: Even if you're making a dance video, that's okay because you want to have something flashy and upbeat.
Speaker 1: that is yeah like Mambalayo, which is one of my favorite videos.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a tight video.
Speaker 0: I like that one a lot because it's it's it's so tight.
Speaker 2: It seems like I think he used flash to make that a lot of it.
Speaker 2: Really, at least that's what it seems like.
Speaker 2: with like the I'd like the little stars going across.
Speaker 2: That's what someone told me.
Speaker 1: yeah, are you sure it wasn't no one.
Speaker 2: I'm sure someone told me that they use.
Speaker 0: Now you're gonna make me go to.
Speaker 2: It's not necessary?
Speaker 0: No, it isn't really.
Speaker 0: it was made in 2001.
Speaker 0: So I don't know flash was really that powerful at that point.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, no, I mean, I know it was around because I used it in classes at our IT.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 2: yeah,
Speaker 1: but at least in terms of you know People booing the five-minute videos in anime club by the time I was ready to leave I can tell you there's a glimmer of hope because even though the crowd got really uneasy and kind of restless during the long videos.
Speaker 1: They always stayed and watched him anyway, and a lot of times they would say things later to the effect of man.
Speaker 1: I started to realize that some of those things were good or they'd start to Recognize what a good video was.
Speaker 1: as long as we force them to watch them whether they wanted to or not It's like you give them the bad medicine and then they realize that the bad medicine makes them feel real good.
Speaker 2: And we always put whatever AMVs we showed on an FTP for people to download.
Speaker 2: if they came to the meeting.
Speaker 2: Yeah, they would always download them.
Speaker 1: they bitchin bitchin bitch Like.
Speaker 1: why'd you show that ten minute long full not ten minutes long?
Speaker 1: But the five-minute thing to kimigiri orange road.
Speaker 1: that was totally sentimental and lame.
Speaker 0: and then they download that one more than anything Because they've had a chance to think about it and watch it again and digest it instead of simply trying to bolt it down.
Speaker 2: Or they're just crazy fans who like to collect every single possible video on their hard drives And then they have a stack of CDs or DVDs next to their computer.
Speaker 1: Hey anything that tricks them into watching good stuff and appreciating it is fine by me.
Speaker 2: Yeah Yeah, I just remember all those guys who would just they'd be like, oh I have seven bajillion music videos Am I in hard drive?
Speaker 2: Ha ha ha.
Speaker 1: Well, it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: We'd always trick people who didn't want to watch an old show to come into club by showing them flashy music videos and giving them Prizes and crap.
Speaker 1: but then we'd show them this old old old show that they'd talk about how much they thought they'd hate and then They'd love it and then they'd want to see more and a new anime fan would be born.
Speaker 0: Yes, but then you got to be a good parent.
Speaker 0: You've done it now Honestly, yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: it did get annoying what eventually people would keep asking the people who ran the club.
Speaker 1: Well, what should I watch now?
Speaker 1: I just watched all the Harlock.
Speaker 1: It wasn't it awesome when Captain Harlock did the block.
Speaker 2: Oh my god.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's rather annoying fanboy people.
Speaker 0: If you saw him on Harlock, that's that's a pretty good start.
Speaker 2: I Think what the biggest showing ever was like the Macross Plus movie, right?
Speaker 2: Yeah, but then we showed that in 2000 So it wasn't too new back then it was still.
Speaker 1: There wasn't the biggest showing ever but it was definitely the biggest showing for many years in both directions at the club.
Speaker 0: Yeah There are a few there not too many things you can go wrong with.
Speaker 0: as far as Macross Plus is concerned I thought was Macross - Then you got a problem.
Speaker 2: I Took a tape of Macross - out of the club library.
Speaker 2: why I had to see what it was.
Speaker 1: I could have told you what it was.
Speaker 1: No, cuz Scott Johnson told me not to get it when I picked it up one day.
Speaker 1: I didn't know what it was either.
Speaker 2: Oh, hey, you know, no one told me that was before.
Speaker 2: it must have been before.
Speaker 2: so it was like one of the first things I took.
Speaker 0: so all right the opening theme kicks in is yeah, this is pretty good.
Speaker 0: And then you get to the dubbing and they speak.
Speaker 2: Oh, this was with something.
Speaker 2: This is a. this is a fan.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, you're lucky that the dub the dub is a no terror notoriously bad.
Speaker 2: It was bad even with the fans up.
Speaker 1: Yes, true Alright, I think we can pretty much wrap up the AMV discussion.
Speaker 1: It was wonderful to have you on the show.
Speaker 1: God and to all you listeners out there who disagree with us suck it This guy's an expert and we agree on a lot of things.
Speaker 2: So anyone who comes back your elders kids comes on the forums and says blah blah blah.
Speaker 2: you guys are wrong about X Y or Z. well Sorry, we win.
Speaker 0: So I guess I'm on the forums too.
Speaker 0: So I'll know that he will.
Speaker 1: he's there.
Speaker 1: watch out though I guess for fun.
Speaker 1: We always like to do this.
Speaker 1: We'd like to ask one final question not related to anime music videos.
Speaker 1: But what would name your top three favorite anime?
Speaker 1: not anime you think are good But anime that you love just to get a perspective as to what kind of fan you are.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, it's a question.
Speaker 1: The whole internet is going to judge you based on this.
Speaker 2: You don't have to give a particular order or anything, you know, just okay.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll leave it.
Speaker 1: I'll go forth.
Speaker 1: I'll say very right up that captain Tyler and utenna are some of my favorite shows ever in earth.
Speaker 0: Hey, Atsara The second I know it's good.
Speaker 0: You've never seen.
Speaker 0: I really enjoyed.
Speaker 0: Oh, I know I Good friend of mine Ryan Gavin is a big Tyler fan.
Speaker 0: So I need to get it from him.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I know it's good.
Speaker 0: I just haven't had a chance to see it yet.
Speaker 2: like that for me Way too many.
Speaker 0: I I love cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I am a big fan of giant robot shows, but if I had to narrow it down to one I would probably have to say Mazinger's D because it is so over-the-top.
Speaker 1: you want to know something real special.
Speaker 1: Mazinger's D is the logo of the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: No, it's.
Speaker 2: it's the great the great man the great man.
Speaker 2: The great messenger is the official club mascot that it.
Speaker 2: that is what it is.
Speaker 1: It's a tiny little logo so Close enough.
Speaker 2: I can't tell you how many times I'll wear the RIT anime club shirt to conventions and people won't say Oh RIT anime, they'll go.
Speaker 2: Oh great messenger, even though it's as poorly drawn as D version of them people know what it is.
Speaker 2: You're like, oh my god.
Speaker 2: There you are.
Speaker 0: I'm also a big fan of mobile police pad labor.
Speaker 2: Oh, I love that.
Speaker 2: live or no rim doesn't pass.
Speaker 1: It's not that I don't like it.
Speaker 1: Is that I don't love it.
Speaker 2: I love it a lot.
Speaker 1: I definitely respect those movies for being all ten sides of awesome.
Speaker 2: I got screwed watching it though Cuz I tried to watch it in club on the tapes and the way they had the tapes at club was the first episode of the tape would be like OAV episode 1 and Then the other three episodes in the tape would be TV 1 2 3 and then tape - oh, yeah
Speaker 0: Tape
Speaker 2: 2 was OAV episode 2 TV 4 5 6.
Speaker 2: So I have.
Speaker 2: I didn't watch all the tapes cuz the year was over by the time, you know, I got halfway through.
Speaker 2: and So now I've seen like half of the OAV and half of the TV series.
Speaker 2: But I've seen all three movies which are which are probably the best part of it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, well, I don't know about the third one.
Speaker 0: I never seen the third one.
Speaker 0: I've heard it's not very good but the first and the second are good.
Speaker 0: and I finally got the Limited collector's edition DVD that Daryl Surratt has owed me for months.
Speaker 2: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 2: You're the one who was supposed to get them.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's like the fun.
Speaker 0: It's a fantastic movie.
Speaker 2: You know music is a box thingy Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm gonna exercise some executive privilege and throw out a couple more titles that I like.
Speaker 0: go nuts Project project a co.
Speaker 1: that was one of the first anime I ever saw.
Speaker 1: I'm all about project a co.
Speaker 2: I know something.
Speaker 2: I never saw it.
Speaker 2: Why there's really really.
Speaker 1: I'll put it in Netflix at the time.
Speaker 2: I have project a co the comic book like episode issue one that I bought.
Speaker 2: did that crap cut?
Speaker 1: forget that You don't want to read the comic.
Speaker 0: Was that the one that Tim elder to the art for it?
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: I bought it at that crappy, New Jersey Shore convention thing in a 25 cent bin.
Speaker 2: I'll go take a look at.
Speaker 2: I also bought Pete a copy of the lens min comic.
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, I bought that empty Geist comic.
Speaker 2: Oh you did didn't you?
Speaker 1: Yes, I did.
Speaker 0: Oh the pain I Was on the block episode one.
Speaker 0: Are you doing what's wrong with you?
Speaker 2: It was five cents.
Speaker 2: It's hilarious to have.
Speaker 0: You can't spend ten cents on.
Speaker 0: Let me throw out a few more titles for you.
Speaker 0: a bubble gum crisis the original not 2040.
Speaker 2: the original I think you and even it's only people who like that.
Speaker 1: I Haven't actually seen any bubble gum crisis, but you always put it down.
Speaker 2: No, I don't you do.
Speaker 1: When have I put it down many times?
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I put down a lot of things.
Speaker 1: I don't put down bubble gum crisis.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't even know what need to watch.
Speaker 0: all eight start do like the first two of the first three and you'll be good of course.
Speaker 0: Akira Miyazaki films the whole gamut of Miyazaki films I love.
Speaker 0: one of the very first scenes I ever saw as a budding anime fan was the car chase from the beginning of Castle Cali Ostro and it remains one of my favorite scenes of all time.
Speaker 0: Second maybe to the other car chase that takes place in one of the other lupin films.
Speaker 2: Conspiracy is by far the best.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that in Cagliostro are neck and neck for the best Lupin in my eyes.
Speaker 2: That's right.
Speaker 2: We gotta buy that box that house the Lupin movies in it that just came out.
Speaker 2: Yeah shit.
Speaker 0: And finally Finally let me just throw out dirty pair TV series and especially the project even will be.
Speaker 2: I Know that's the show with the girls boobs, but I never saw.
Speaker 0: yeah but dirty pair the original dirty pair not dirty pair flash, which is a pale imitation that came later, but the original dirty pair.
Speaker 0: And this probably has nothing to do with the fact that two of my friends from long ago the Forester sisters Were one of the first to one of the first in the United States to do dirty pair cosplay.
Speaker 0: and Let me throw out an old fart memory for you.
Speaker 0: I think in project a project a con three or four They did a panel on how they built their how they constructed their costumes and so them.
Speaker 0: it was held in one of the hotel rooms.
Speaker 0: It was packed to the gills with sweaty fanboys and you could literally Feel the temperature in that room at least 10 degrees hotter than it wasn't.
Speaker 0: The air conditioning could not keep All the DVR rooms.
Speaker 0: So there you go guys.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 2: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 2: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 2: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.