Speaker 0: All right, welcome to Geek Nights Special #1.
Speaker 1: As promised, we're doing a special weekend podcast because we didn't do one on Thursday.
Speaker 0: Now, we didn't do one on Thursday for, well, we said we had a certain reason, but we ended up having a completely different reason, which we'll talk about on Monday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, two or three reasons, yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, since this is the first one, I'll do a little bit of explaining.
Speaker 0: Now, normally Geek Nights is four nights a week, Monday through Thursday, and every day is a different topic.
Speaker 1: If this is your first time ever listening to Geek Nights, go back.
Speaker 1: Listen to something else.
Speaker 1: Anything else but this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a special, meaning it's in the unscheduled category in addition to the podcast category.
Speaker 1: Meaning it's also crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is not Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: This is whenever we screw up or don't have an episode or whenever something crazy happens and we have to do an extra episode, it'll be a special.
Speaker 1: Which means it's half-assed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not only is it half-assed, but I'm using hardware that's barely functioning.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Which I'll talk about on Monday in great detail.
Speaker 1: Alright, enough of that.
Speaker 1: So, for our little special to make up for no episode, we're gonna tell you a little, well, story slash, I don't know, rant, kind of?
Speaker 0: Yeah, kind of a little bit of- Informative action?
Speaker 0: Something.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, if any of you watch Seinfeld, you might have known the joke about Jerry's no-vomit streak.
Speaker 0: Yep, it was destroyed, I believe, by a black and white cookie.
Speaker 1: Yes, and he hadn't vomited for a very long period of time, many years, and then he ate a black and white cookie and vomited.
Speaker 1: Well, me, Scott, has a similar vomit streak, where I haven't vomited in years and years and years and years.
Speaker 1: Now,
Speaker 0: contrast this to about six months ago when Scott had to deal, well, he's in his room and I have the master bedroom, which is on the other side of the, it takes up the whole half of the house, and then there's a hallway, and then the other half of the house is Scott's room, his walk-in closet, and the walk-in closet is directly adjacent to the upstairs bathroom.
Speaker 0: So he heard me, and I had food poisoning, horrible food poisoning.
Speaker 1: Or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was food poisoning.
Speaker 0: It was bad.
Speaker 0: I'm reasonably certain.
Speaker 0: And basically every 10 minutes for most of that night, I bargled, vomited violently and loudly.
Speaker 1: It was so loud.
Speaker 1: God, it was so loud.
Speaker 1: Now, it had happened so many times, he just kept waking my ass up.
Speaker 0: Oh!
Speaker 0: Ugh!
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Followed by the ritual of, you know, rinse mouth out, flush toilet, wash teeth, go to bed.
Speaker 1: Now, I hadn't vomited in years, until Friday.
Speaker 0: Now, he'd come close, but he didn't, actually.
Speaker 0: I remember one time he got really sick with some other, the opposite vomit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see, I really don't get sick.
Speaker 1: The only thing that ever happens to me, is sometimes I'll eat bad food, or sometimes I'll eat the wrong mix of foods, or sometimes I'll eat too much food.
Speaker 1: And then my stomach will go, "What did you do?
Speaker 1: What did you do?
Speaker 1: Why did you do
Speaker 1: that?".
Speaker 0: You tried to do too much with it.
Speaker 1: You tried to do too much.
Speaker 1: Now I will make you very unpleasant.
Speaker 1: And then after like a day or two, I'm back to normal.
Speaker 1: But that's the only real illness I ever get.
Speaker 0: So this weekend, we had almost all of the core front row crew over for a crazy board gaming weekend.
Speaker 0: In fact, we're going to spend all of Tuesday covering, in order, all the games we played this weekend.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: And it was the core group, except for Katsu, he was busy or something, but he was the only one who wasn't here, of the like chorus, chorus, original front row crew.
Speaker 0: There are a lot more people in the front row crew, but that was like the original.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And we played a million board games, and we'd had to, Pete, his Amtrak was late.
Speaker 0: We never would have seen that coming.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: That is a big surprise.
Speaker 0: So we had to drive, he missed his connecting train to Beacon, so we had to drive up to Poughkeepsie to pick his ass up.
Speaker 0: And we were real hungry, and there weren't so many restaurants up there that we wanted to eat at.
Speaker 0: Well, many that Scott wanted to eat at.
Speaker 1: But you were, the only places you picked are places you knew I don't like.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Like, hey, let's go to the fish place.
Speaker 1: Hey, let's go to the nasty ass Uno Pizzeria.
Speaker 0: Name another place up there.
Speaker 1: That's my point.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So eventually we pass a coyote grill, which we decide, all right, let's go there.
Speaker 0: Coyote.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's coyote to all you Easterners here.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: It's coyote.
Speaker 0: to people in the West who actually know what the hell that dog is.
Speaker 1: No, it's a coyote.
Speaker 1: It's a coyote.
Speaker 1: Like Wile E. Coyote.
Speaker 1: It's not Wile.
Speaker 1: Coyote.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: People mispronounce a lot of words.
Speaker 1: It's not Wile O. Coyote.
Speaker 1: It's Wile E. Coyote.
Speaker 0: Now, while the team is called the Celtics, the word is Celtic.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing.
Speaker 0: The word...
Speaker 1: But the basketball team is the Celtics.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If you try to say Boston Celtics, I'll kick your ass.
Speaker 0: Though I will say...
Speaker 1: Probably not, because I don't care that much, but...
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even then, when I hear someone say Celtics, it's still a great sound to me, because I know it's a mispronunciation, even though it's accepted.
Speaker 0: Kind of like Garymandering versus gerrymandering, but that's a whole other show.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we go to the place.
Speaker 0: The place was good food.
Speaker 0: It was real good food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was pretty good food.
Speaker 1: It was sort of a fancy hip place, like something you'll see in a spy movie or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like take stuff on the walls and upgrade it like two categories.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was still a chain of some sort.
Speaker 1: But it's one of those chains that there aren't so many of them.
Speaker 1: Kind of like Smoky Bones.
Speaker 0: But the food was a weird combination of Asian food and Western food and just a whole... Italian food.
Speaker 1: It was Mexican, Asian, Italian, and American food all mixed up.
Speaker 0: And a lot of them, like dishes, were two different kinds of food mixed together, and it was all really good.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And Scott got...
Speaker 1: I got this barbecue chicken sandwich that was really good.
Speaker 0: Now you ate the second half of it for dinner today, and it didn't make you bargo.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm really not feeling...
Speaker 1: I think... All right.
Speaker 1: So around Thursday, like I didn't... Thursday I went to the city, and I didn't really eat much on Thursday.
Speaker 1: I ate like a bagel, and then I got home and ate dinner, and that was it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Friday you didn't eat so much either.
Speaker 1: Friday I didn't eat too much until we went to this grill.
Speaker 1: So I had gone two days without eating, but for some reason I didn't feel real hungry.
Speaker 1: Like my body didn't say eat a lot of food.
Speaker 1: But I knew I hadn't eaten, but my stomach didn't say fill me up, but I ate anyway.
Speaker 1: And I think that's... There was something going on before.
Speaker 1: I got... I don't think it was the food from that grill.
Speaker 1: I think it just happened to be that's where I ate, and there was something wrong beforehand.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it was.
Speaker 0: Sorry to interrupt, but while we're recording the show right now, the Geek Night special, and I just got messaged by someone, one of our listeners, Brian, the person who won the design contest, bugging us about the fact that we didn't upload the Geek Night special yet.
Speaker 1: Okay, Lowell.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway, we ate at this place after two days of me not eating and not feeling very hungry, and then that night I wasn't feeling 100%, but I didn't feel too bad, went to bed, and I don't know, when did we go to bed that night?
Speaker 0: Oh God, it was like two.
Speaker 1: No, because I woke up at two.
Speaker 0: No, no, we went to bed early.
Speaker 0: We stayed up late Saturday.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we went to bed early, like midnight.
Speaker 1: All right, so around two hours later at two, I woke up with a mad stomach pain.
Speaker 1: So I went to the bathroom and I had me some wet, wet number two.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was bad.
Speaker 0: Now, I remember the last time that happened to you.
Speaker 0: Didn't you cure it by laying naked on the bathroom floor?
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 1: The last time I cured my stomach illness.
Speaker 0: I thank the demon lord that I didn't stumble in upon that.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I think we talked about this on an early episode.
Speaker 0: I think we did.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So if you want to hear the story of Scott lying naked on the bathroom floor after diarrhea-ing for quite some time, search through the archives.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Now, here's another story about Scott sitting naked on the bathroom floor.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: I had a diarrhea.
Speaker 0: Do I need to add a category for this?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Scott naked on the bathroom floor, episode four.
Speaker 1: And then after I was done, it was still pretty painful, like worse than the last time.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, you know what, I'll try that again.
Speaker 1: It worked the last time.
Speaker 1: And I was sweating balls.
Speaker 1: God damn.
Speaker 0: Now, to elucidate that point, now on Thursday at my work, I saw the forecast for the weekend and it said that it was going to rain nonstop.
Speaker 0: The percentage chance of rain was 100.
Speaker 0: Friday, Saturday, Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday to the following Thursday.
Speaker 0: It predicted up to eight inches of rain in Beacon over two days.
Speaker 0: That is insane.
Speaker 0: Now the actual reality is that it didn't rain at all.
Speaker 1: It rained a bit today.
Speaker 0: It rained a tiny bit.
Speaker 1: Not as much as it could have and should have.
Speaker 0: Instead, there has been this constant haze as clouds descended upon us and it didn't rain.
Speaker 0: The humidity was 100 billion percent and it's like 80 degrees, my air conditioner could barely keep up, I'm running the air conditioner super cold just to keep the humidity out of my room.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: In fact, you might hear the audio sound a little odd.
Speaker 0: That's because the air conditioning in the fan is going full blast in the background of the studio.
Speaker 1: And we're not turning it off.
Speaker 1: So, I had a diarrhea and I was still in a lot of pain, unlike usually it's a relief.
Speaker 1: It wasn't so much of a relief.
Speaker 1: Some feverish.
Speaker 0: Now, at what point did you think, wait a minute, is the streak over?
Speaker 1: You know what, every time this happens, I think it might be the end of the streak.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like I wake up in the middle of the night with pain and I say, I hope this isn't the end of the streak is the first thing I think.
Speaker 1: I'm perfect.
Speaker 1: That's completely honest.
Speaker 1: That's the first thing I think is, ah, this might be the end.
Speaker 1: Please let it not be the end.
Speaker 0: So you contrast this with me.
Speaker 0: Now, when I do get sick, which honestly, once I left Rochester and college and started getting sleep and eating properly, I almost never get sick anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, you did get sick that night when you were just vomiting 20 times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: But I mean, compared to when I was in college, I get sick maybe two or three times a year at most now.
Speaker 1: I have very good health.
Speaker 1: Since around, ever since I had the pneumonia, I think I was in middle school for like a week.
Speaker 1: My rate of sickness has really not changed at all.
Speaker 1: It's like once every few months, stomach problem for a night.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's the only sickness I've had for years and years and years and years and years.
Speaker 0: But when I do get sick, my body for some reason is on a vomit hair trigger.
Speaker 0: It's like my body.
Speaker 1: You have built in Ipikat gland.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: If all you have is a hammer, every problem looks like vomit.
Speaker 0: So if I get sick, I just vomit.
Speaker 0: If my stomach is, I just vomit.
Speaker 0: In fact, I think I told the story of when I got food poisoning in New York City and I vomited so much I'd go to the hospital and I might have died.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I'm laying on the floor in pain and the cold floor actually kind of helped even though I was completely covered in sweat.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was as if I had been in a sweat swimming pool.
Speaker 1: Like it was dripping out of my hair like a faucet.
Speaker 1: It was crazy.
Speaker 1: I was all feverish with stomach pains, lying on the bathroom floor.
Speaker 1: You know?
Speaker 1: This is about the only part of me that wasn't nasty was my ass because I just wiped it after having calorie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wanted to know about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you want to continue with that, I can go into great detail.
Speaker 0: Every time I vomited when I had food poisoning.
Speaker 0: The difference as time went on in what was coming out of me.
Speaker 0: because just when you think there's nothing left in my body, there's absolutely nothing that can come out.
Speaker 0: Something new would come out.
Speaker 0: Something new and frightening.
Speaker 0: A new frontier of vomit.
Speaker 1: So it didn't really feel nauseous, like whoa, dizzy, nauseous.
Speaker 1: And I didn't really feel anything except the pain in the stomach.
Speaker 1: And then I finally decided, yeah, you know, I'll go up to the toilet there.
Speaker 1: It didn't really feel like I had to vomit that bad.
Speaker 0: No, I've done that before.
Speaker 1: Not any more than any other time I was sick.
Speaker 0: You know, when you get over the toilet, like if it's going to come, I want to be ready.
Speaker 0: And then you see.
Speaker 0: And then if it doesn't happen, you go back to bed.
Speaker 0: That kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like I didn't, you know, other times that I had the stomach sickness, it's like vomiting was there as an option.
Speaker 1: Like if I tried a little bit, I could have vomited easily, but I held back for the sake of the streak.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: If my body wants me to vomit, I figure it knows what it's doing.
Speaker 1: Well, it didn't want to vomit super bad.
Speaker 1: It only said you can vomit if you want to.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like a super strong bardole.
Speaker 0: In fact, one time I've made myself vomit prematurely to prevent future problems.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That was when we got that orange juice that went bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about that someday.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So I get up to the toilet and I'm like, all right, yeah.
Speaker 1: And I bargled.
Speaker 1: Oh, then I bargled.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: It was so bad.
Speaker 1: Well, it's kind of weird because it wasn't, I haven't bargled in a long time, you see.
Speaker 1: So I didn't quite remember a hundred percent the feeling of vomiting.
Speaker 0: You know, it always feels really good after you're done and your body says, your body says, all right, you did me good.
Speaker 1: It sure does.
Speaker 0: That'll do pig.
Speaker 1: But, uh, you know, what came out was pretty much that sandwich I ate for dinner and it was happy.
Speaker 1: You can see, you can see like, okay, there's some bread, there's some onion, there's some chicken, there's some barbecue sauce.
Speaker 0: Now see, the only times I've ever vomited like that where undigested food came back was when I had done something wrong, like not slept in several days or not eaten for two days and then eaten.
Speaker 1: The only time I remember vomiting where what came up was like not just, didn't look like the fake puke you buy at the store was when I drank too much grape juice and I barfed up purple shit out my nose and my everything.
Speaker 0: One time I had the flu.
Speaker 0: I was a little kid and my little brother, all I remember is that he ran out of the room screaming.
Speaker 0: Now I was really sick.
Speaker 0: I had the flu and I was staying home from school and we had a vomit bucket.
Speaker 0: It was this old popcorn bowl that we used whenever a kid was sick in the house or whenever the parent, whenever someone was sick and it laid next to the couch and I was laying there watching like mask or something on TV on a tape and I had eaten a whole bunch of green jello and I hadn't vomited yet.
Speaker 0: So we didn't think this was a vomiting flu.
Speaker 0: It was just a flu flu and there was no warning.
Speaker 0: There was no nothing.
Speaker 0: I was sitting there.
Speaker 1: So you should have made jello.
Speaker 1: God damn it.
Speaker 1: You should have made a jello.
Speaker 0: Hey, at least you had the lassi.
Speaker 1: The what?
Speaker 0: The lassi.
Speaker 1: Lassi.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was like lassi.
Speaker 1: That's a dog.
Speaker 0: But I was sitting there and suddenly I just felt this horrible urge and I turned and a force and it filled the bucket and overflowed and
Speaker 1: my little brother had to have
Speaker 0: been like four or five and he ran out of the room screaming and my mom runs in like, what?
Speaker 0: What is busy?
Speaker 0: Dead.
Speaker 0: What's going on?
Speaker 0: I'm just, there's a pile of vomit.
Speaker 0: Just green.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I vomited, you know, a couple of times.
Speaker 1: It wasn't, you know, I guess you could lump them all into one vomit.
Speaker 1: It was like vomit, stop, vomit, stop, vomit, stop.
Speaker 1: Vomit, stop.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 1: And that was it.
Speaker 1: Didn't vomit anymore.
Speaker 1: Then I took a shower immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I always do that.
Speaker 1: And while I was in the shower, I felt some vomit still at the back of my throat and in my nose.
Speaker 1: So I kind of blew my nose and like a piece of chicken came out.
Speaker 1: It was a piece of chicken sitting in the drain of the shower and I was looking at it.
Speaker 1: I was feverish, slightly delusional.
Speaker 1: I'm feverish, slightly delusional in a slightly cold shower looking down at the drain at this piece of chicken.
Speaker 1: And I stood there for a few minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I know that delusion state where you just don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like LSD delusional, but it was fever delusional.
Speaker 1: So after I decided I was no longer covered in sweat, I dried off.
Speaker 1: It's nice and cool.
Speaker 1: Went back to bed, still had a little grumpiness.
Speaker 1: I got up a few hours later for just a little bit of diarrhea, but that was it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: And I haven't had a bowel movement since Friday night and it's Sunday.
Speaker 1: Yay Petal Bismol.
Speaker 0: Have you been still taking that?
Speaker 1: No, I took it once.
Speaker 1: And I barely ate anything.
Speaker 1: Remember?
Speaker 1: What did I eat since then?
Speaker 0: I ate- Well, we went to the Indian place for dinner and all you ate was like one piece of bread.
Speaker 1: No, I ate like three pieces of bread and a mango lassi.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It was real thin bread though.
Speaker 1: And I had a muffin and some toast and French toast.
Speaker 1: Lots of bread.
Speaker 0: Of course, then today we had the food.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: I ate the other half of the sandwich that I bargled up.
Speaker 0: So we'll see if you bargle tonight because- I really don't think I'm going to bargle.
Speaker 1: I think I'm good now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was the sandwich.
Speaker 1: I think tomorrow, like this very- You know, I don't think it was the- There wasn't anything in the sandwich that was like poisonous or toxic or anything like that.
Speaker 1: If I had eaten anything, it would have done it.
Speaker 1: If I could have eaten a steak or a hamburger at a different restaurant, I would have barfed that up.
Speaker 1: You know?
Speaker 1: It was the fact that how much I ate and the timing of the eating that did it, I think it was very much a condition from before that caused it.
Speaker 0: Now I like how when any one of us woke up because I was asleep in my giant bed and Pete was asleep on the giant futon and Alex was asleep on my giant uncomfortable chair because my room was very large and the door was shut and locked and the air conditioning was on.
Speaker 0: So we had no idea this happened.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: The first time- If I didn't say anything, they would have thought the streak was alive.
Speaker 1: The first time he sees any of us- I could have lied about it and kept on.
Speaker 1: So if anyone questions my honesty again, they can shove it.
Speaker 0: The first thing he says to me when I wake up is, "Rim, the streak is over.
Speaker 0: I bargled.
Speaker 0: I bargled all
Speaker 0: night.".
Speaker 0: And I was like,
Speaker 0: "What?".
Speaker 1: It wasn't all night.
Speaker 1: That's not what I said.
Speaker 0: You said something like that.
Speaker 0: You were like, "I bargled last
Speaker 0: night.".
Speaker 1: That's what I said.
Speaker 0: And I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick
Speaker 1: and I was sick
Speaker 0: and I was sick and I
Speaker 1: was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I
Speaker 0: was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick
Speaker 1: and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick
Speaker 0: and I was sick and I was sick and
Speaker 1: I was sick
Speaker 0: and I was sick
Speaker 1: and I
Speaker 0: was sick and I was sick and
Speaker 1: I was sick and I
Speaker 0: was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and
Speaker 1: I was sick
Speaker 0: and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick
Speaker 1: and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and
Speaker 0: I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick
Speaker 1: and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick
Speaker 0: and I was sick and I was sick and I was sick.