Speaker 0: It's Tuesday January 3rd, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We talk about dungeons and dragons with our special guest and dungeon master Alex Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I fell asleep at my desk not once not twice, but three times today.
Speaker 1: Is that a record?
Speaker 0: It's not a record, but actually I fall asleep I just fairly often.
Speaker 0: but it was particularly auspicious because I stayed up all night geeking and that was why I stayed up all night geeking.
Speaker 1: but it was so weird that I just kind of woke up this morning better than Usual better than average honestly when I woke up.
Speaker 0: I didn't expect you to you know actually be at work.
Speaker 0: I expect you to look out the window see the sleet and just give up.
Speaker 1: See I probably would have given up except for the fact that when I went to push the snow off my car It just kind of went right off.
Speaker 1: It was heavy, but like it didn't I didn't have to scrape.
Speaker 0: well The snow got worse later as opposed to earlier, which was odd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not what the weather said But anyway, we are crazy.
Speaker 0: party as you all know is over But the last survivor is still here.
Speaker 0: So we have a special guest Alex our dungeon master who will be joining us after the interlude and things of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and not dungeon master like actual dungeon of torturing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not the sadomasochism thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah the other kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the dungeons that have dragons in them kind But not real dragons.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're real enough.
Speaker 1: Oh, that would hurt.
Speaker 0: They do various D's worth of damage.
Speaker 1: Mmm D's All right, so Intel you know those people who make chips that we don't buy so often or you know ever there.
Speaker 1: Well, not only are they gonna be in the new Apple computers supposedly, but they finally got rid of Intel inside.
Speaker 1: really I mean like when's the first time you heard Intel inside like Pentium ones?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it was Pentium ones.
Speaker 0: I remember seeing the commercials and seeing the stickers on computers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're changing the logo, too.
Speaker 1: It's still a blue swirly, but it's a different blue swirly and the.
Speaker 1: they're even saying they're gonna get rid of the word Pentium.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I know a lot of people who they the word Pentium to them means processor.
Speaker 1: Yep But that's not how it's gonna.
Speaker 1: it's kinda like band-aid.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I guess that's gonna change.
Speaker 0: now I wonder if there's anything to do with the fact that Apple doesn't want the Intel logo on their pretty not square not beige boxes.
Speaker 1: Some people are saying is that Intel, you know Intel would love to have Intel inside all over every freaking Mac.
Speaker 1: But I don't think Apple's gonna let that happen.
Speaker 1: and that's one thing people are pointing out.
Speaker 0: You know I'd love to see like the actual agreement between Intel and Apple that led to this switching to Intel.
Speaker 1: I really think that all agreements between all major corporations need to be like public things that everyone can see.
Speaker 0: I Imagine there are parts that are hilarious because people like us don't get to read them.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: There might be Another thing a lot of people pointed out that's not so well known.
Speaker 1: is that Microsoft and Bill Gates?
Speaker 1: Really don't like Intel and Intel really doesn't like Microsoft.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it's not the reasons you'd expect.
Speaker 1: it's mostly the.
Speaker 1: Intel doesn't like Microsoft because You know Intel makes a chip and they like to add features to the chip like they added MMX then they added SSE Then they added SSE to right now.
Speaker 1: think back in time when Intel had a 32-bit chip the Pentiums, right?
Speaker 1: The MS the Microsoft operating system Windows was a 16-bit operating system.
Speaker 1: then Microsoft made a 32-bit operating system.
Speaker 1: Then Intel made a 64-bit chip that Itanium.
Speaker 1: that didn't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: Did Microsoft make a 64-bit operating system kind of.
Speaker 1: But they got one that's gonna work with the AMD's that's gonna come out.
Speaker 1: I don't even know the status of that.
Speaker 0: AMD did it right?
Speaker 0: I mean basically Intel decided.
Speaker 0: All right x86 has been extended to the point of stupid and we're gonna make a new architecture kinda.
Speaker 0: and AMD said, you know what?
Speaker 0: We're just gonna extend x86 to 64-bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you ever actually code an x86 assembly language, you're kind of on Intel's side.
Speaker 0: But other than that, you know from a business sense or just from a realistic point of view It's really hard to introduce a new chip.
Speaker 0: That's not at all backward compatible with the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah But actually I I heard that Bill Gates once or currently still owns many many shares of AMD You know, so there's something going on there.
Speaker 0: Well, think about it.
Speaker 0: buying a computer with an AMD processor gets you a faster computer for a lot less money.
Speaker 0: so you have a lot more money to spend on a Windows license and Windows seems faster and you feel like you got a better deal.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, the final piece of the puzzle is that apparently like Dell and Microsoft are kind of fighting a little bit, too.
Speaker 1: So it's like if Intel and Microsoft are fighting and Dell and Microsoft are fighting, you know, who knows that whole Dell Wintel kind of action might all break apart in a few months.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wouldn't be hilarious if we ended up back on power PC.
Speaker 0: That would be so great Except we won't because power PC chips are really expensive.
Speaker 1: I see a future where Dell releases computers with AMD chips in them and you have a choice of getting Windows or not.
Speaker 0: I could see that.
Speaker 1: I could definitely see that and I could see Apple with the the Intel's.
Speaker 1: I could see people running Windows on those.
Speaker 0: Yeah I also see a lot of people running Linux on new Apple hardware.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, you ran Linux on old Apple hardware with PPCs.
Speaker 1: They're gonna run it even easier on the new stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, more importantly things like wine will work As opposed to before.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of talk about that.
Speaker 1: It seems sort of rumorish though that You're basically gonna be able to run Windows applications on the Intel Macs Just like you double-click them and they run the same way that OS 9 applications seem to just run in OS X.
Speaker 0: Wow, that would be kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: Yep, I might get a Mac if they do that because maybe I'll be first in line for a power book if it does that.
Speaker 0: If anyone's ever tried to use wine to make programs work like Windows programs work in Linux It's pretty much just completely hit or miss and there's very little you can actually do.
Speaker 0: It's either it works or just crashes with random obscure like stack dumps.
Speaker 1: Yeah right now you can do it with virtual PC But that's like a money thing and you need a Windows disk and you need Windows license and all that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or VMware, but it's the same deal.
Speaker 0: You also have to pay for VMware.
Speaker 1: Who knows what Apple's working on back there?
Speaker 0: So, you know what we'll soon find out might be a rumor like the infinite number of rumors They're just completely made every day about all this.
Speaker 1: Yeah none of the stuff that we say on this podcast is a hundred percent guaranteed because we Get most of it just by reading websites.
Speaker 1: and who can trust any of that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, look we linked to slashed out more than any other site.
Speaker 1: Do we really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we do.
Speaker 1: We should go do some statistics on that now we could anyway.
Speaker 1: So in the escapist this week Which seems to have gotten better a little bit even though I didn't read the full articles
Speaker 0: Like we did we neither one of us read it today and we were talking about it and we were making fun of the escapist like you know what.
Speaker 0: there's gonna be an article about a girl gamer who's oppressed and then there's gonna be an article about Eve online and Then there's gonna be an article that makes a good light of some stupid subculture that no one else cares about.
Speaker 1: Well, there was one of those.
Speaker 1: Oh great, but it was about game stores.
Speaker 1: this week.
Speaker 1: you know the game stops in the EBS and the independent guys and Yeah, a lot about how.
Speaker 0: the margins are real tight for these stores.
Speaker 0: They really make all their money off the use game.
Speaker 1: Now I knew the margins were tight and that's why they love the pre-orders because when you pre-order a game They know they've sold it and it's a guaranteed profit.
Speaker 0: plus you're gonna be in that store Not once but twice and you might buy a used game in that interim.
Speaker 1: Yep, you go you're gonna pre-order it Then you're gonna leave then you're gonna come back and you're gonna buy the game.
Speaker 1: That's two visits.
Speaker 1: Who knows what you're gonna buy during those two visits plus?
Speaker 0: a lot of people are real dumb.
Speaker 0: They'll buy like ten new games and then after they beat them all they'll take them all over to EB Sell them back for a pittance to buy like one more new game.
Speaker 0: Yep, then EB sells all those games for like Ten percent off of the original retail price.
Speaker 0: They make a pile of money and then they someone sells it back to him again.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm as someone who doesn't sell games back ever no matter how crappy they are but buys used games I don't really care if the game store makes money.
Speaker 1: I get the used games cheap and you know, yep I think you're dumb if you sell them back.
Speaker 0: Remember funko land back in the day?
Speaker 0: It was the first game store that was kind of like.
Speaker 0: it's like it was the the predecessor the precursor to like modern EBS and game stops, yep, and Basically like the whole gimmick was the funko land had consoles out and you could just try games before you bought them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm that piles of games you just walk up like I want to play blah and they'd put it in for you.
Speaker 0: You could play it for as long as you wanted.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only place you could do that was Toys R Us that had the demo machines that would go for five minutes.
Speaker 0: Yep, but this was like the real deal.
Speaker 0: just consoles like.
Speaker 0: that's the only way I ever played a Sega Saturn.
Speaker 0: Wow, because they had one and I played.
Speaker 1: I played a Sega Saturn and a Toys R Us a couple times.
Speaker 1: That was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: But I remember I had Final Fantasy 1 for the NES Mm-hmm, and they always.
Speaker 0: they always had this sheet in the store.
Speaker 0: That's like the bounties on games and I looked and they were willing to pay $35 for a Final Fantasy 1 cartridge.
Speaker 0: Wow, so I Went home and I got it.
Speaker 0: I sold my Final Fantasy 1 cartridge to him for 35 bucks.
Speaker 0: Okay, and then like a month later I was in that same funko land and I saw Final Fantasy 1 for 15 bucks and you got it and I bought it back.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why funko lands gone.
Speaker 0: Yep Well that and funko land was really kind of ghetto.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he didn't notice his kids because we just wanted to play the games.
Speaker 0: We never actually bought anything really.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we never really went to funko land my family.
Speaker 1: We're just all.
Speaker 1: Toys R Us action mostly which was cool Because Toys R Us, you know had likes a little piece of paper
Speaker 0: Yeah the wall of pieces of paper and you pick it up and then you'd go and pay and then you go to that little booth behind The checkout and you give me your little slip and then they gave you the
Speaker 1: game and all the consoles and the hardware is in this glass case and you walked over to the glass case and it was like
Speaker 0: Man.
Speaker 0: my parents hated my little brother and I because like once a month they take us to Toys R Us.
Speaker 0: They're like you guys can buy one game and we would stand there and debate for like four hours.
Speaker 1: I was standing there for like an hour walking back and forth trying to find the right game.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it was hit Sometimes it was missed because I really didn't have much to go on because I wouldn't buy a game that I you know My friend had and I didn't really know what to look for and I didn't get a magazine to tell me what to get because
Speaker 0: I remember one Super Mario 3 and Zelda 2 were both out and we didn't have either one.
Speaker 0: We could only get one game.
Speaker 0: Mmm, we there was no way to decide.
Speaker 1: I remember having to decide between like Kirby's adventure and something else.
Speaker 1: kind of glad I got Kirby's adventure.
Speaker 1: So if you played counter-strike before you know all about the dust maps dust and dust.
Speaker 0: that map called dust Dust dust.
Speaker 1: You s T as in the tea you drink.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, if you haven't played counter-strike, you have no idea what the hell we're talking about.
Speaker 1: But let me just say it's no.
Speaker 0: there's no one in the world who hasn't played counter-strike.
Speaker 1: All right, then It's that map, you know where it's a die.
Speaker 1: It's a bomb map and not a rescue.
Speaker 1: the hostages man the math.
Speaker 0: everyone plays on the freaking crates in the desert.
Speaker 1: To this day from the earliest counter-strike beta 5 to the current counter-strike source it is still the number one map that is played more often and Usually map makers are weird people or they're hard to find people, you know And they don't really talk so much and you don't hear about them or they kill themselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like there was one math and I really won't get into it but it was a stupid map like.
Speaker 0: it was the worst counter-strike map I'd ever played and The guy who made it committed suicide and Because of that the map got really popular and people like really talked it up like in homage to him And you know what the map was crap.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: I think it's homage but whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Usually don't see too much about map makers even though it's a really hard job And I've tried to make maps and it is really difficult and it takes mad skill.
Speaker 1: Mostly cuz a lot a lot of documentation on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not like the doom two days Just whip one together, but the maker of dust and dust two and some other maps on his website.
Speaker 1: I think his name is Dave Johnston.
Speaker 1: It's John stow code at UK as the making of dust and the making of dust two.
Speaker 1: and If you've ever played counter-strike and you know, you know about the dust maps.
Speaker 1: This is a month.
Speaker 1: Burp is a absolute must read absolutely must read.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not very long and Just looking at the pictures is like holy crap.
Speaker 1: he shows you stuff that you didn't even realize like here's a picture where on the left is beta for and You can see on the close bomb spot like the two crates where they're positioned and on the right is cs 1.5 and you can see that two crates have been moved and been rotated Diagonally so that when you're planting the bomb you have more cover.
Speaker 1: And it's like oh wow You don't even.
Speaker 1: it's something you don't even notice even if you play the two games one after the other.
Speaker 1: But you look at the picture and you're like wow a lot goes into map making.
Speaker 0: that is like, you know, totally complicated Yep, and tiny little things completely change how a map works.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean look he even shows the ins in beta for and Earl.
Speaker 1: in such times They didn't really have shadows and then you can see his say to see us one and a half they had shadows.
Speaker 1: So now all of a sudden you you know The whole map changes because now what used to be just normal places are now like optimal hiding places And that might change.
Speaker 1: the whole dynamic of the map is that you can hide in certain places and things.
Speaker 0: So if you've ever played counter-strike read this, it's cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's very very cool.
Speaker 0: so I was on FARC today like I do and Lo and behold there was a religious flame war as there always is because those never happen on far.
Speaker 1: No, it's like that's like the rarest thing.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Now this one came up.
Speaker 0: it was some funny story about a judge in Italy is basically Basically some guy sued and a judge in Italy is ordered a man to prove that Jesus exists.
Speaker 1: Way to go.
Speaker 0: I can't wait to see how that trial goes But in the thread about three-quarters of the way down.
Speaker 0: someone posted a funny little comic that basically sums up every FARC flame war about religion ever and I won't explain it because it's a comic and you can read it and I found it funny and It kind of sums up my beliefs regarding that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: I Think it sums up the beliefs of every rational human being.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the brights.
Speaker 0: Yep, not bright as in I'm a bright person but bright isn't that movement of naturalism?
Speaker 1: Mmm naturalism.
Speaker 0: we should talk about that some Thursday.
Speaker 1: the brights we should they're cool.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I'm one.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm not one, but I agree with them.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm To be one.
Speaker 1: Oh, it really is felt their website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: But Like I said at the beginning we have our guests.
Speaker 0: Alex are for our current dungeon master our former live dungeon master But he doesn't live near us anymore.
Speaker 0: So we play online and we've got him here too.
Speaker 0: Well first do a thing of the day Greetings.
Speaker 2: Well if you're like me or in which you're a Computer science student or recently ex computer science student or maybe just in general Working at Google has this semi legendary aura.
Speaker 2: It People make up all sorts of stories about how hard it is to get in there There was the story going around for a while.
Speaker 2: You need a PhD to actually get hired by Google as a programmer.
Speaker 2: not really true, but So among of the things that Google workers actually get up to is they order quarter quarter tons That's 250 pounds of silly putty.
Speaker 2: Apparently you can order it in bulk directly from the manufacturer.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: How much does it cost?
Speaker 1: Google money or can you use normal money?
Speaker 2: I actually don't know but I suspect normal money.
Speaker 2: This was just a couple of the employees decided to do this.
Speaker 2: Well by a couple I mean a couple dozen.
Speaker 2: Oh and when a couple dozen people place a bulk order for silly putty what you end up with is a Quarter ton of silly putty in the form of about six bricks the size of my torso laying on a guy's desk.
Speaker 0: Great Wow.
Speaker 2: now these bricks all stacked up, but you can't take that much silly putty home at once.
Speaker 2: You got to split it up among all the people who ordered.
Speaker 2: Problem is as anyone who's played the silly putty knows It's much easier to stick together than it is to take apart Haha, and the problem is only magnified when you've got 250 pounds of it.
Speaker 2: so Scissors didn't really work knives.
Speaker 2: Not so much Wrenching and tearing kinda but that's like taking fingerfuls off of the mass.
Speaker 0: They obviously didn't think this through.
Speaker 1: No, they didn't what it that you think they would being the smart Google people.
Speaker 2: Perhaps they would.
Speaker 2: they try to but it was overruled by the whimsical impulse to see 250 pounds of silly putty in one place.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna admit I'd pay a decent sum of money to see that in person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, wonder how the silly putty company does it at the factory?
Speaker 1: Maybe they just make it in smaller bits so they don't have to take it apart.
Speaker 2: In any case this has a happy ending.
Speaker 2: all the employees involved the couple dozen of them hacked and Nawed away at this.
Speaker 2: Hopefully not literally for a couple hours and they all got their handful of silly putty, huh?
Speaker 1: You know, it probably would have worked Either like freezing it and then going at it with like a chainsaw or an axe.
Speaker 1: I think an axe would have worked really well actually putty shards everywhere.
Speaker 1: Hmm, let me minus the freezing plus the axe.
Speaker 0: How about one of those water cutters where it shoots a stream of water?
Speaker 0: That's really sharp because it's moving fast when silly putty gets mad slimy and scary.
Speaker 0: Those water cutters don't make things wet Really?
Speaker 0: Basically, it shoots a sheet of super pressurized super concentrated water that acts like an extremely sharp Nano knife.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: They use them to like cut pipes in industrial settings.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're really cool All right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I have to do things of the day.
Speaker 0: we move on to the main bit which is Dungeons & Dragons And the three of us have been playing Dungeons & Dragons for most of our sentient lives.
Speaker 0: So we thought we would be a good group to talk about Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've been playing for most of my sentient life.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, you're really honestly in our group.
Speaker 0: You're kind of the newbie.
Speaker 1: I played it in middle school times, which is like seventh grade.
Speaker 1: So I was 13 and I'm now 20 so almost half of my sentient life.
Speaker 2: Wow I played it a little in my younger days But actually I didn't get seriously into it until I got to college when I finally got together a serious group to play in.
Speaker 0: Are you making me feel old?
Speaker 0: because I like played first edition?
Speaker 0: Well, I played Dungeons & Dragons and then I played a advanced Dungeons & Dragons first edition And then I I converted to second edition and then I converted to third edition And I went to cons when I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I was like this little little kid.
Speaker 0: I went to like little cons in Michigan and there are all these big scary guys and they all drank Mountain Dew and they were Creepy.
Speaker 1: see we would have done that but there just weren't enough nerds in my town to do it.
Speaker 0: Oh there weren't.
Speaker 0: I had to drive like hours to get to these little tiny cons.
Speaker 1: Well, I meant for like to play D&D at all.
Speaker 1: Like if there are three nerds you really that's not enough Yeah, and you really even if you had five nerds, you couldn't get them all together at the same time.
Speaker 1: This didn't happen.
Speaker 0: So we figured we'd start with the obvious question.
Speaker 0: What is Dungeons & Dragons?
Speaker 1: Because a lot of people have a little misconception about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah a lot of stereotypes and Yeah, yeah and I mean there are different ways to play it.
Speaker 0: Dungeons & Dragons is really just a way of Role-playing as in pick a role and play it and there are rules to moderate that role-playing Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I guess the simplest simplest way to describe it is you say what your character does.
Speaker 0: That's all you really have to do.
Speaker 0: Everything else is just semantics.
Speaker 1: it's like You know how kids will have make-believe and they'll just imagine whatever they want to imagine, you know, they'll read a story They'll imagine themselves being the character.
Speaker 1: They'll change the story.
Speaker 1: You know, who knows what little kids imagine or what anyone imagines?
Speaker 1: D&D is just a way where you can imagine in a group and you put a set of rules to limit your imagination and if you know anything about imagining you'll know that creativity is Increased when limits are placed on the thinking.
Speaker 2: those limits act as guidelines and it forces you to think harder about them.
Speaker 2: Yes, the two major limitations guidelines whatever you want to call them in D&D are the dice.
Speaker 2: you can declare your characters actions, but there's not always a guarantee of success.
Speaker 2: and the dungeon master who if he or she is doing his or her job would should hopefully be Guiding you all towards some kind of plots or providing opportunities for plots.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean basically the way the game works for any of you have never played it or have only seen like television representations of it is a bunch of geeks sit around in a room and Each one of them is playing a character and there's one guy who for us was usually Alex who was the dungeon master or the game master and all they do is adjudicate they.
Speaker 0: they Resolve every situation that can't be resolved like just with dice automatically or they just can't be resolved.
Speaker 0: Obviously Like if Scott is play.
Speaker 0: Scott is a thief and he tries to steal my purse for some reason and coin purse not woman purse Merce Merce.
Speaker 0: and Now the dungeon master decides what must be done to decide if that actually happens or not.
Speaker 0: Maybe he succeeds maybe fails.
Speaker 0: Maybe I kill him.
Speaker 2: The dungeon master also decides to provide the players with other challenges so that they're not just trying to steal from each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it'd be pretty boring if it was just four people, you know That's why you you imagine an entire world around the characters.
Speaker 2: unlike most games D&D isn't really competitive which is That doesn't really fit with the conventional definition of a game.
Speaker 2: But we've got nothing else but nothing else better to apply to something that involves all these rules and dice and paper.
Speaker 0: They're saving a lot of people who don't get that aspect of it.
Speaker 0: Like they always ask.
Speaker 0: So, how do I win?
Speaker 1: Yep, it's always kind of scary when you see someone like They're angry about dying or you know They feel like if they're not winning a fight in D&D that they're kind of losing a game and it's like alright, you know I really don't care which way things go, you know, I try to make it go the most interesting way not necessarily Or the way that my character would want, you know things to go Not necessarily towards any winning or losing condition that I might imagine that doesn't exist.
Speaker 2: See, it's what it's one thing to get emotionally involved with your character and that that can actually be a good thing because that's Makes your role play a little more strongly and also be a very bad thing If you get too far.
Speaker 2: and it can be very bad thing because you can't accept that This person was ultimately badass in your heads can lose.
Speaker 2: Yes, they're not ultimately badass.
Speaker 2: if they were ultimately badass They wouldn't need to wander around doing the piddly little mercenary jobs that make up your standard D&D.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why those kind of people play those epic games which are just silly.
Speaker 0: yeah now we say we kept seeing Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 0: That's just because that's the game we play.
Speaker 0: I mean role-playing is a really broad very just Ephemeral genre of gaming where there's a million different systems and a million different ways to do it.
Speaker 0: We just happen to use the Dungeons & Dragons system.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And so we're kind of we're really avoiding these things specific to that system.
Speaker 0: So we're saying Dungeons & Dragons but take that to mean role-playing in general.
Speaker 1: I suppose you can play gurps or what white wolf or amber.
Speaker 0: amber was cool because it didn't use any dice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or any of those other systems are all pretty much played in the same way.
Speaker 1: It's just a different set of rules and limitations and that can modify The way the games come out.
Speaker 1: In fact, it usually does.
Speaker 1: But in essence, it's just the same thing, you know There's a master or game master of some sort and a bunch of characters and you act out some sort of Imaginary world to entertain yourselves.
Speaker 0: So why do we play Dungeons & Dragons?
Speaker 1: I Can tell you why I play Dungeons & Dragons because you get to play things like mind.
Speaker 0: flayers need people's brains.
Speaker 1: Well, that's fun.
Speaker 1: But the thing is it's like there really isn't so much adventure going on in the world these days.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess there is technically opportunity for adventure.
Speaker 1: You can like join the Peace Corps or something, you know and go crazy but not so much when you want to do computers and things.
Speaker 1: so With D&D it like lets you and your group of friends Like create stories and have things happen to you that even though you all know they never really happened?
Speaker 1: like you talk about them as if they happen.
Speaker 1: like remember that time you did something crazy and You play D&D so that those crazy things will happen.
Speaker 0: because we seriously do it.
Speaker 0: We'll be sitting around at dinner talking about the time the characters like had a free crazy fun adventure did something.
Speaker 0: We tell it just like it's a real story.
Speaker 2: Mm-hmm People's stupid mistakes laugh at laugh at people's successful things Stupid mistakes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, I think Scott when even played Alright, I'm gonna do the like the unholy thing and tell a story from a Dungeons & Dragons game.
Speaker 0: Now normally in polite company one does not do this because the one thing that is the least Interesting to anyone else in the world other than telling someone about your own dream is telling someone about your Dungeons & Dragons Character.
Speaker 1: unless it's the other people who are playing in that game then I love to hear it.
Speaker 0: But to sum up very broadly we're a bunch of undead people and we're in a desert Desert desert wasteland for as far as the horizon goes in all directions And it's night and half the party's vampires and Scott is playing a vampire who is not so bright.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that was a function of Scott or a function of the character.
Speaker 2: I think some of each.
Speaker 1: it was definitely some of each.
Speaker 0: but he ticked off the party to the point that we tried to kill him and he decided to run away into the desert where there was no shade and eventually the Sun came up and Vampires don't like the Sun so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that wasn't too good.
Speaker 1: No See I was.
Speaker 1: when I did that I was under the false impression that I would be able to make it somewhere before The Sun came up and I was wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the emphasis on the miles and miles and miles of desert wasteland.
Speaker 2: Yeah sort of the punchline of that situation was that According to the D&D rules a vampire who dies turns into this mist and goes back to his coffin the coffin that was still with the party.
Speaker 2: So, you know about half an hour after sunrise you have this vaguely sullen looking mitt cloud of fog scream Scrambling along the ground and going into a box to sulk.
Speaker 0: I mean we have a million stars like that.
Speaker 0: We won't tell them all but that's part of that's really one of the big reasons why we play.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: it adds a dimension To our friendship that couldn't exist because like we all can play video games together, but we can't all kill a dragon together.
Speaker 1: Mmm with D&D we can yeah, and it doesn't take very long either.
Speaker 1: I mean you can sit around one night for like five hours and go on like a million mile Multi-month quest of Grand Adventure and it's as if you went on a million mile monthly month Quest of Grand Adventure, even though you sat on your ass on your couch and rolled some plastic rocks around.
Speaker 2: Yep It takes a little longer for my ants to actually come up with the adventures and the challenges and all that But not a whole lot longer.
Speaker 2: and to be honest, I like that kind of stuff.
Speaker 2: I like coming up with alternate worlds and alternate characters and Writing this little story of my own and then you guys can surprise me with it.
Speaker 2: So I have all the benefit of both reading and writing a story.
Speaker 0: Like to me that's the best part of it.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like you've got a group of friends and together you're all acting out and writing a novel and You know what you want to do But you don't know what everyone else really wants to do and you can't always predict how people will react or how things will turn Out.
Speaker 0: so you're taking part in this like play, but you don't know how the play is going to end.
Speaker 0: So it's like you're reading a book, but you're writing it at the same time.
Speaker 1: It's not even that you're writing a book.
Speaker 1: It's that you're writing a book.
Speaker 1: You're writing many books.
Speaker 1: You're writing the number of books equal to the number of players plus one.
Speaker 1: The plus one is the DM who's writing a narrative book for the third person and each player is writing their own First-person book and they're all separate, but I guess you can put them all together and it'd be like one giant book.
Speaker 1: You know because like I know like the images in my head from you know Whatever the world was like or whatever adventure looked like but it's not even close, you know in words or pictures to what?
Speaker 1: You know anyone else thinks of the same exact game.
Speaker 1: You know, it's just completely different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time we can all talk about it and it's the same but different.
Speaker 0: I Suppose we could consider like how we actually found out about Dungeons & Dragons or actually got into it in the first place Because until recently it's not like Dungeons & Dragons Advertised itself.
Speaker 0: It was just there and if you knew about it you knew about it.
Speaker 1: I Don't even think it advertises so recently.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 0: lately Wizards of the Coast isn't putting a lot of stuff that well.
Speaker 2: hasbro now Wizards has really tried to popularize it and with some degree of success.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean it was doing real well until Everyone who bought the books realized that they never need to buy the books again, and there was no more market for the books.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean once you know the rules you don't really need to buy the rules again.
Speaker 1: it doesn't.
Speaker 1: you can't really make money off of it because the supplies are non-renewable and The supplies don't go obsolete I think and also you'd be surprised how many pirate sites there are out there.
Speaker 0: They just have like PDF scans of every book ever.
Speaker 0: hmm But like how we got into it, I mean I remember the first D&D I ever played.
Speaker 0: I was real real real young like it was either my lat it was like the end of elementary school or the very very beginning of middle school.
Speaker 0: and Like I remember my uncle used to talk about he used to play Dungeons & Dragons And I didn't really know what it was and he didn't play anymore.
Speaker 0: he didn't have any books didn't talk about it a lot, but every now and then talked about it and I was curious and I met some people.
Speaker 0: I met this kid named Sidroni and yeah, his name was Sidroni and He was like you want to play some D&D and I went over to his house and he gave me this book.
Speaker 0: he was like make up a character and we'll play.
Speaker 0: and I guess this was an example of bad D&D as opposed to good D&D which we'll probably get into later.
Speaker 0: Because basically what D&D consisted for these guys was make a character and then kill things with it and make poop jokes.
Speaker 2: Wow, yeah, no one in this company makes poop jokes.
Speaker 1: Mmm At least I don't think anyone's ever made a character that makes a poop joke in character.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah I couldn't think of one which was surprising to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I want to find one but uh, I think I think it's time to make a character who's a little mature.
Speaker 0: So Scott, how did you get into D&D?
Speaker 0: We never really talked about this not even outside of the podcast.
Speaker 1: Well, let's see When I was a little way little like elementary school ages There was a I knew the words Dungeons & Dragons and it was some sort of game.
Speaker 1: I didn't know much about it at all.
Speaker 1: And I didn't wasn't really interested in seeking it out but I was friends with the nerdy kid who lived down the street and One day he got a game.
Speaker 1: It said Dungeons & Dragons on it.
Speaker 1: I was like, alright, whatever It's a big black box and inside there was like a bunch of cards and this big board and the board was like this dungeon made of squares and We never actually played the game.
Speaker 1: But it wasn't real Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 1: it was like Dungeons & Dragons Something something.
Speaker 1: I remember when that came out and it was like you would do something and then he someone would take the card out of the box.
Speaker 1: anyway, the box of cards was the Dungeon Master and You know, it wasn't really so much the role playing as some sort of walk around a dungeon Crawl game on a board with little figures.
Speaker 2: It was your quest with vaguely D&D inspired.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm not we never actually played it.
Speaker 1: So I'm not a hundred percent sure but that's just my memory of elementary school.
Speaker 2: I think I know the game you're talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then in middle school I went to this nerdy summer camp and I was big into magic in those days.
Speaker 1: Aha magic Yeah, which I soon learned my lesson on but anyway.
Speaker 1: So we play magic at adventure games, which was after dinner every day.
Speaker 1: But after lunch every day, there was a quiet time in the bunk And I don't know how many bunks did this but every bunk that I was in when I went to this camp all the kids played.
Speaker 1: each cabin had their own little D&D game after lunch and I remember the the first time I played.
Speaker 1: they're like play the Dungeons & Dragons and I was like, alright I'm finally gonna play this freaking thing for real.
Speaker 1: It's like, alright, how do I play?
Speaker 1: they're like First you make a character and they gave me a second edition PHP and I was like, alright this tells me nothing.
Speaker 1: So then someone walked me through the whole thing and I had like a scrap of piece of paper with some numbers on it.
Speaker 1: I didn't understand it all.
Speaker 1: And then I'm like, alright now, how do I play?
Speaker 1: they're like.
Speaker 1: you say what you do?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, oh, that's it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: And then after about two times of saying what I did I was like, ah And that was that.
Speaker 1: The next time I played was I think when I went back to the camp again and then I played it pretty sparsely in high school and then when I got to college we went to the R Wagon, well that was it.
Speaker 0: Ah, see I played it in high school more than I played it any other period in my life including college.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Guess that's what happens when you have people.
Speaker 1: It's all about having people.
Speaker 2: The first D&D product I bought when my first real exposure to the game was actually the second edition Monster Manual.
Speaker 2: Prior to that I had this sort of vague conception that the game existed and I knew very roughly what it involved but not the details.
Speaker 2: But I was in a comic book store which often happens to sell D&D products as well and I happened to see this book and what I saw was a book full of a bunch of neat pictures of monsters and descriptions of them.
Speaker 1: That's a great book.
Speaker 2: And I like monsters for their own part.
Speaker 1: I love that book.
Speaker 2: So I bought it because I was a kid with apparently too much disposable income at the time and over the next few years that actually became sort of a source book for the informal half BS role playing that kids do.
Speaker 2: I would have been in I think middle school possibly younger around this time.
Speaker 0: While we're getting old we can't remember when things happened in our lives anymore.
Speaker 2: And over the course of that I would gradually meet people occasionally who actually knew the game and would do these occasional one or two player games.
Speaker 2: There was one friend of mine in high school times who actually would do sort of one-on-one D&D which unless you can have no other kind, just kind of sucky, that's when I actually learned the second edition rules and how that actually was supposed to work.
Speaker 2: And then when I came to college suddenly I was with a group of 15 other people at RWAG all in one D&D game.
Speaker 0: Yeah we told you guys that story at least a month or two ago about the crazy D&D game with Dwayne the Dungeon Master.
Speaker 1: Yeah where I discovered oh there's a third edition because it had just come out at that time and I didn't even know.
Speaker 1: and yeah.
Speaker 1: And our third edition is what we still play, kind of.
Speaker 2: So it was after the Dwayne game kind of fell apart and we were all sitting around in the cafeteria talking about.
Speaker 2: we were talking about D&D in some fashion or another and I basically said screw it I'll run a game.
Speaker 2: I've never done this before but I'll see how it goes.
Speaker 0: And it went real well I'll tell you what.
Speaker 1: That was some good D's and D's and D's.
Speaker 0: Because actually I mean like my first experience with D&D came early but I didn't play good D&D like I played it and it was fun but I didn't get it as in play it with really good people and actually role play well until high school or maybe it was right before high school and middle school I don't remember.
Speaker 1: That D&D that I played at that summer camp was not good D&D by any stretch of the imagination.
Speaker 1: Well I mean the first the first year I was there that we played.
Speaker 1: it was pretty much just terrible.
Speaker 1: it was like you know I was just some cleric and I did healing and that was pretty much it.
Speaker 1: there wasn't really so much role-playing going on so much as like there are some monsters we all roll dice.
Speaker 1: you walk there's some monsters we all roll dice.
Speaker 1: but then it got actually sort of involved when I died and I was reincarnated as an ogre and then I was like oh and then the game kind of changed from there yeah into something a little better.
Speaker 1: and that's when I got the idea of what it was supposed to be like.
Speaker 0: Because like the first games that were like really really good is.
Speaker 0: I started playing with a bunch of my friends in high school and basically we played every Sunday meaning we'd all like meet around 10 a.m on Sunday and then we'd all go out shopping for food and then we'd play until like school started on Monday.
Speaker 1: Well that's real long.
Speaker 0: Yeah like we'd do 12-14 hour sessions just non-stop and then we'd watch anime like right after we were such geeks.
Speaker 0: but we really felt like our games really focused on the role-playing and very little on game mechanics and combat like it's kind of.
Speaker 0: this might sound too nerdy or geeky but we actually had an entire gaming session where it based.
Speaker 0: the whole thing took place within a ball that someone was putting on.
Speaker 0: our characters were just kind of hanging out and chatting.
Speaker 1: That's real geeky.
Speaker 0: Yeah it is.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of D&D I like.
Speaker 0: I like playing a character.
Speaker 1: Well the thing in D&D is that most of the book is the rules of fighting because those are the most complex rules you know.
Speaker 0: Well that and because the origin of D&D is a pure fighting game and they've kind of hammered it and pushed it into this mold of other things.
Speaker 1: Yeah but you know a better way to play D&D.
Speaker 1: that I think is to you know you fight when fighting makes sense and then there are rules for it.
Speaker 1: but yeah that doesn't mean you always you know just need to make it a game of fighting.
Speaker 1: you make it's a game of role-playing and when you role play in adventurey world which is usually what you want to play and you don't want to play in some boring world like this one.
Speaker 0: I mean I guess it's subjective.
Speaker 0: I mean everyone.
Speaker 0: If you enjoy playing D&D however you play it.
Speaker 0: that's great because the best thing about the game is you can play it however you want with whoever wants to play it with you.
Speaker 0: So I might be up for the game of all talking where no one ever fights and just people talking to each other and Scott might like the game that's like a mix and some fanboy might like the game of I'm an ogre and I smash things in dungeons forever until I stop playing.
Speaker 2: Yeah at least at least to me if you mean if you want to play that kind of thing you want to play something a little tactical game.
Speaker 2: D&D is not the best way to do it.
Speaker 2: there are better games for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: But if that's your thing go for it.
Speaker 1: I mean there are plenty of tactical like war games that are not you know suit the more extract or games because D&D is not an in-depth war game by any stretch.
Speaker 1: but very few of them have all the creative options of D&D which is why I think people like to play it.
Speaker 1: I mean you play something like battle tech or whatnot and your options are pretty much like move shoot jump turn that sort of thing and D&D.
Speaker 1: you can come up with crazy stuff because especially if you're a wizard you have so many spells you know you can and you have the terrain and you know you can really stretch your imagination within the words of the rule book to do all kinds of things that you can't do in a normal tactical game and
Speaker 2: in combat.
Speaker 1: that really comes out.
Speaker 2: And not just the words of the rule book.
Speaker 2: and this is something that I think often leads to the bad versus good D&D.
Speaker 2: in my opinion and at least in the opinions of other people I've talked to.
Speaker 2: take that for what it's worth.
Speaker 2: the DM is your final arbiter.
Speaker 2: the rule book is a guideline and as a DM I often will just scrap a rule if I don't like the way it's gonna if I don't like the way it's gonna work.
Speaker 2: I prefer drama over accuracy.
Speaker 2: that said the rules are a starting place.
Speaker 2: they're a common language that everyone speaks so everyone knows what they're capable of and what the things they're dealing with are capable of.
Speaker 2: so I don't try to break them without reason.
Speaker 0: Because I see you get like a lot of people who like I have friends who say they hate Dungeons and Dragons and I ask them why and they explain these games where their Dungeon Master was like a jerk and he basically just played a game of.
Speaker 0: I will never let the players win and everything they think of.
Speaker 0: I'll come up with a way to stop it.
Speaker 1: So that's hero quest.
Speaker 1: that's not D&D.
Speaker 2: Yeah it is not the players versus the Dungeon Master.
Speaker 2: that's silly.
Speaker 2: the Dungeon Master has absolute control over the world.
Speaker 2: it's not a challenge for anyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah if the Dungeon Master wanted you know all right fine I'll.
Speaker 0: Brock falls from the sky and kills all of you.
Speaker 1: Dragon eats you.
Speaker 1: If you want to play the Dungeon Master versus the players there's things that do that and they're not Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 0: Scott mentioned hero quest.
Speaker 0: it's an old board game that is very much designed to be the Dungeon Master versus the players like specifically and it's actually kind of fun.
Speaker 1: Yep but it's not D&D.
Speaker 0: Even though the last time we played it we all died because Scott in his infinite wisdom decided to run around a dungeon opening all the doors and waking all the monsters up before we finish fighting one monster.
Speaker 1: That's greatly exaggerated story.
Speaker 0: Not so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah so much.
Speaker 0: All right fine the specific story.
Speaker 0: we were fighting a chaos knight which is this big bad mofo with an axe and he was chopping us up but we were just about to beat him.
Speaker 0: Scott decided to run off on his own to look for treasure and he opened a door and in that room there were two more death knights and they killed him and then they've tracked us down and killed us.
Speaker 1: See it made sense to me that behind that guy see I didn't run around all over the dungeon opening doors.
Speaker 1: I opened a door because it made sense to me the way the dungeon was laid out that this monster was guarding a treasure in the next room and I was wrong.
Speaker 0: No it was guarding two more monsters.
Speaker 1: Yeah what a great monster guarding two more monsters.
Speaker 1: So that was just a case of bad luck but I did not run around opening doors willy-nilly getting monsters to chase me around to where the party was.
Speaker 0: You caused directly all of our deaths.
Speaker 1: You know in a game that would have made sense like D&D those monsters would have heard us fighting in the next room and come in anyway.
Speaker 0: No no it makes sense because in a hero quest all the walls are made of uh magic lead.
Speaker 0: Oh great.
Speaker 0: Yeah yeah.
Speaker 2: Yeah absorbs all sound and energy.
Speaker 2: Cannot be breached by any means.
Speaker 0: Or you know what they're chaos knights or death knights.
Speaker 0: I imagine the two in the other room probably didn't like the third one and they left them out there.
Speaker 0: but then when you open the door they couldn't hide anymore.
Speaker 1: That's another thing I really like about D&D is when you get these tiny bits of flavor that you know.
Speaker 1: sometimes you read a fantasy novel or something and you'll get those the bits of flavor but usually not so much because a lot of them are you know focused on the main plot and the main characters and D&D you can get like you know like you're fighting a couple orcs and maybe one of them is a little silly or like maybe like you'll you'll go into a shop to buy something and the the owner will have a silly pet
Speaker 0: or the store
Speaker 1: will be arranged in a funny way.
Speaker 0: Or just like the dice will come up with something improbable like someone who should have like some peasant who just should have been whacked doesn't get whacked and creates like this funny ongoing joke or this ongoing story that you didn't expect.
Speaker 1: Yep those are always great things because it's like somehow as a group you imagine something without any of you imagining it.
Speaker 1: yet there it is.
Speaker 1: it's way cool.
Speaker 2: The unpredictability keeps it interesting.
Speaker 0: Yes of course you really have to play D&D with like good people who are going to get into it.
Speaker 0: Because one jerk in the group can just kind of ruin it.
Speaker 0: of course you can always just kick them out.
Speaker 1: Yeah it's real hard to manage a D&D game and you can find all sorts of things online about how to keep it good how to tell which people are good and bad all this kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: but it really helps if you do it with a bunch of friends and all the friends are good.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: If you're doing it with people you don't know but they're good it can still be kind of awkward.
Speaker 1: and if you're doing with their friends and they're no good that can you know it's it's a guarantee has ruined at least one friendship in the history of the world.
Speaker 2: Minor rant it's rather unfortunate how little of the published material by Wizards of the Coast TSR whatever TSR was a little better at this but not a whole lot actually is about how to role play or how to run a good game.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: You get some of that in the magazine articles but it almost never appears in the actual books.
Speaker 0: See I guess I never needed instruction.
Speaker 0: I just like I got it like all right I'll play a game I'll role play.
Speaker 1: The only instruction I ever got was say what you do and then it's all you have to do is realize that you're not you you're the whatever you made and then it all.
Speaker 1: that's it.
Speaker 1: and if you can't do that then you're you're really.
Speaker 1: you know it takes practice.
Speaker 1: once you get it no matter what.
Speaker 1: but if you if you don't get it you know ever then this really it's kind of like a no hope sort of thing.
Speaker 0: I mean I guess it's if you're one of those people out there who played D&D once and it sucked and you hate it just try to give it a chance and try to find.
Speaker 0: try to find some people who don't suck and I think you'll like it a lot.
Speaker 0: I mean I can't imagine many people who wouldn't like Dungeons and Dragons if they actually played it with cool people.
Speaker 1: It's not like a video game where you play the video game and if you play it again it's going to be the same because the video game is the same every time or a song where if you hear the song again it's not going to be different.
Speaker 1: this you know if you listen to it with different people.
Speaker 1: but D&D can be is like a thousand different things even though it's all based roughly on the same set of books and such and literature so that depending on where you play it with whom you play it you know what kind of D&D you're playing.
Speaker 1: it can be a completely different thing and you know a lot of people are put off of it based on a first experience or a bad experience and that's kind of sad because they're missing out.
Speaker 0: Even though we're kind of missing out right now since we've we don't all live near each other anymore and it's real hard to play long distance like we've been experimenting with playing online in forums and it's working really well.
Speaker 0: but it's not the same as the experience of sitting in a small dank college apartment with like nine of your closest friends for six hours in a row eating Chinese food and killing dragons.
Speaker 2: It's not the same experience as watching your dungeon master sweat as you do the improbable thing that he didn't think of and he tries to come up with a plausible outcome.
Speaker 0: Oh you mean like three sessions into a giant epic campaign naming who the secret bad guy was accidentally?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Yes I learned to keep a very good poker face.
Speaker 1: Or coming up with a crazy crazy scheme to just jump to the end of the game and skip all the carefully prepared plot of the dungeon master making his efforts wasted in vain.
Speaker 0: Like we were playing in Alex.
Speaker 0: Alex ran this awesome requiem game.
Speaker 0: I don't really get into it but there was this giant like epic artifact building thing and it was this huge powerful thing and it was just a plot device.
Speaker 0: We were supposed to like see it and like look at it and figure out what it was and then it revealed a lot of the plot and we ran off to do our other things.
Speaker 0: So way later in the game we're in a tough spot and instead of doing the obvious like all right fight your way through or do whatever we freaking traveled all the way back to this tower and used its awesome power that he didn't think we'd remember to completely circumvent part of the game.
Speaker 2: Yeah showed a little bit of a lack of foresight on my part.
Speaker 1: My favorite story.
Speaker 2: On the other hand it all turned out well.
Speaker 0: Yeah it did.
Speaker 0: See that's the thing.
Speaker 0: no matter how weird it gets it always works out because the story concludes itself somehow.
Speaker 1: My favorite story of D&D where something like that happened was the story of the very powerful druid versus the evil count in the castle.
Speaker 1: Basically this evil count in a castle had a evil castle on the like a cliff over an ocean and the party consisted of a bunch of people and a very powerful druid and they were going and there was suppose the DM already planned out what the inside of the castle looked like and the whole plot with the evil wizard and these traps and all this great stuff that was gonna go on in their quest through the castle to defeat the evil guy.
Speaker 1: The druid being very powerful probably too powerful for this campaign summoned two very very large earthworm type things that ate all the dirt under the castle and the castle fell and sank into the ocean.
Speaker 0: I imagine the dungeon master crying.
Speaker 1: That's about what happened right there.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And that's just great.
Speaker 0: See I guess that's the best thing about D&D.
Speaker 2: Well it's improvisation and the fact that don't let the fact that there are those rules there make it seem otherwise.
Speaker 2: The rules inspire improvisation much more than they limit it.
Speaker 0: I mean plus if you play with a good adjudicator or a good dungeon master you really don't need to know the rules so much as just know your character and explain what you want to do and he'll take care of all the rules and he'll work it all out for you and they'll tell you what happens.
Speaker 1: So if you're one of those people who has a stereotype of D&D about attacking darkness or drinking mountain dew and eating cheetos.
Speaker 0: If there are any girls there I wanna do them.
Speaker 0: A cast magic missile.
Speaker 1: Yeah okay it's overdone but if you're one of those people you're only half right because only half the D&D in the world is played like that.
Speaker 1: The other half is really harder to find because it's hiding from the first half and it's good and don't be afraid of it.
Speaker 2: Even we who make those inside jokes occasionally really that's a minority of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah even though there is a lot of mountain dew drinking that is that is very prolific among Dungeons and Dragons players for some reason.
Speaker 2: In my case my first D&D the D&D campaign I ran for you guys.
Speaker 2: the first one was powered almost entirely by Snapple Lightning.
Speaker 2: I think because it had the highest caffeine content per volume of liquid I could get and still stomach.
Speaker 0: I remember I went to the Michicon a gaming convention in Michigan and I was young and I was there and I played in a tournament D&D which it was just normal D&D but like there was an epic plot and it went on for like multiple days and the final session was like this eight hour long session in one room and it was kind of live action kind of Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 0: but I remember there was like a soda machine in the room and it had mountain dew in two of the slots and by the end of the session not only was the machine empty but there was an entire tower constructed of mountain dew cans surrounding the room.
Speaker 1: I remember I played in one D&D tournament once at the summer camp.
Speaker 1: actually it was a like a contest held sometime near the end of the session and it was sort of a solve the puzzles and get to the end of the dungeon the fastest tournament where you know they had the same dungeon and they you know there were different groups and it was.
Speaker 1: you know if your group could get to the end of the dungeon faster than the other group then you won.
Speaker 1: and you know there are a bunch of puzzles and things.
Speaker 1: so it wasn't really so much the role playing as much the puzzle solving but it was still kind of fun you know.
Speaker 1: and and that's just another way that you know you can use D&D to do cool stuff I remember.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: so we've gone on about D&D a lot and this might set the record for the longest podcast ever.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 1: That's why you should play D&D because it's it's so great that you could just talk about it forever and even though you spent maybe.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't know I don't think you realize out there how hard it was for us to not like actually tell all those stories we were making reference to or thinking about in great detail.
Speaker 1: Wouldn't you love to have your own stories?
Speaker 0: And that was Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 1: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds.feedburner.com/geeknights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Speaker 1: Also please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussions.
Speaker 1: And whether you love or hate our podcast we won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geeknights@gmail.com.