Speaker 0: It's Monday June 12th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We continue our series on how computers work with part 2 binary logic and logic gates.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know I don't think we're ever gonna.
Speaker 0: Have a free weekend again in the rest of our lives According to Google the Google Calendar.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna be free for a month, but the weeks preceding Otacon We don't have anything yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so anyway for anyone who didn't listen to Thursday's episode when we decided to do this We had her friend Yuko come over this weekend, and then we went to the mocha art festival in the city hooray.
Speaker 0: and now someone in the forums posted after our Philly wizard world coverage and he had kind of a scathing rebuttal which I kind of disagree with.
Speaker 0: well actually I really disagree with and All I really want to say now is that the mocha art festival was a complete 180 from Philly wizard world and We'll talk about this more on Wednesday when we cover that convention and all the fun things we did there and all the awesome.
Speaker 0: Not really a convention.
Speaker 1: It's more of an arts festival.
Speaker 0: Imagine a comic convention that is nothing but an artist alley.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: It was not a superhero to be seen.
Speaker 0: There were a few.
Speaker 0: there was one guy drawing some Colossus things.
Speaker 1: Well was there?
Speaker 0: I didn't say yeah He had an area where he was drawing like Marvel sketches.
Speaker 1: It was mostly artists who don't really work for the big comic companies showing off their stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean you saw stuff ranging from a guy made some copies of a stick figure at Kinko's literally To you know Scott Pilgrim type stuff.
Speaker 0: Scott Pilgrim is awesome.
Speaker 0: the owly guy Ollie is also awesome and awesome web comics of awesome, but suffice to say it was awesome.
Speaker 0: and I really the only comic culture.
Speaker 0: I seem to dislike is the underwear pervert culture.
Speaker 1: Everyone's ever know about underwear perverts.
Speaker 1: Okay, this is a. this is a joke from the website Boing Boing Where there was a news story that DC and Marvel had sort of trademarked the word superhero and super hyphen hero.
Speaker 1: And this actually was a news story from like the 70s.
Speaker 1: But it was rediscovered recently and spread around the internet.
Speaker 1: So it became common knowledge.
Speaker 1: and when Boing Boing found out about it.
Speaker 1: They said fine.
Speaker 1: We won't say superhero We're gonna say underwear pervert and it really stuck with us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they just keep saying underwear pervert on that website.
Speaker 1: So now we're gonna say underwear pervert instead of superhero.
Speaker 0: Now, of course some superheroes do not fall into the underwear pervert category like the guy at Ex Machina or the watchmen.
Speaker 1: Yep, they're all.
Speaker 1: some of the watchmen are underwear perverts.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah But in a more literal sense, yes, yes very much so.
Speaker 0: anyway, we'll ever coverage of that on Wednesday plus Manga is not without its underwear perverts.
Speaker 1: No, it is actually mega Tokyo, which is hardly about underwear perverts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used the words in both meanings.
Speaker 0: We have quite a pile of swag.
Speaker 0: We.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually do any interviews at the convent at the art festival mostly loud and too crowded.
Speaker 0: It was loud and crowded and the funny thing is unlike Philly wizard world where no one would interview with me People were practically begging me to be interviewed.
Speaker 0: They'd be like, let's do it now.
Speaker 0: Let's do it now.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: Oh, let's just do it now.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: Let me say something, but it's not that day.
Speaker 0: So we'll hold off.
Speaker 0: I mean it's tech day.
Speaker 1: I got so much news.
Speaker 1: I don't know which news to do.
Speaker 1: So we might be loaded for a few weeks.
Speaker 1: Hopefully nothing will happen in the upcoming days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll be able to unload all this news.
Speaker 1: the news.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about today has to do with Apple iTunes and Northern Europe.
Speaker 1: ah Northern Europe that bastion of freedom, you know Sweden Denmark Norway mostly those three.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wasn't being sarcastic.
Speaker 1: Yep apparently the iTunes agreement, you know the thing that says I agree You know the EULA and user license agreement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing you click on every time you install software that none of you read and no one cares about.
Speaker 1: Apparently the people are arguing that the end-user license agreement of iTunes and the iTunes music store is illegal in Norway Sweden Denmark.
Speaker 0: now why Scott is that?
Speaker 1: well as you know some contract there are some things people cannot legally Contractually agree to do.
Speaker 1: I could not write a contract that says rim agrees to be my slave and if rim signs it He doesn't become my slave because it's illegal to hold a slave.
Speaker 1: in the same way These people are arguing that in these countries it is okay to circumvent DRM in the way that the D the DMCA prevents.
Speaker 1: and The iTunes music store says you agree not to circumvent the DRM.
Speaker 1: So you cannot legally agree to give up, you know something you can legally do.
Speaker 0: now I don't know how the legal system works over there.
Speaker 1: I think it's a professional judge type of thing.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm just saying in terms of contract law here in the u.s.
Speaker 0: It is not illegal to enter into an illegal contract.
Speaker 0: The way it works is if you sign a contract that violates your rights as the signer It is illegal to enforce the contract.
Speaker 0: So basically if you know a contract is illegal and you go ahead and sign it They can't really do anything to you and they can't enact the contract.
Speaker 0: So if say there were a EULA situation where the EULA was illegal here, you know Say we got rid of the DMCA and we had some right to DRM breaking Then iTunes wouldn't be in any trouble because they can have that EULA and you're free to agree to it But they can't enforce it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the situation is over there, but it looks bad.
Speaker 1: I don't know either.
Speaker 1: I could probably go to crock-law and find all out all about it, but I'm not going to bother.
Speaker 1: The point is is that they might everyone basically the way it's happening.
Speaker 1: first They tried in France and they failed.
Speaker 1: what people are trying to do is they're trying to find some country in which the iTunes DRM And is crap and that way they can force.
Speaker 1: they can either force Apple to stop doing business in that country Or they can force Apple to disclose the DRM or Have an iTunes music store in one country that doesn't have DRM.
Speaker 1: and as soon as they do that We can all get Denmarkian credit cards and start using iTunes Denmark and get music that way Yep, which would probably not technically be illegal.
Speaker 1: So any of those results is a good one because they can force Apple out of a country.
Speaker 1: they can keep forcing Apple out of other countries until Apple either gets rid of the DRM or Is forced to disclose the DRM to some country.
Speaker 1: because soon as they disclose it to one country they disclose it to everyone.
Speaker 0: Yep, and even if it remains illegal to break it in countries like the United States I can guarantee that there would be a website in whatever country said it was legal that would have everything you need to break it.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean, it's already kind of broken.
Speaker 1: But the point is is you know, maybe in that country they'll sell iPods that don't have DRM and then they'll someone will take the firmware and put it online and we can all flash our iPods so that they don't do the DRM thing and There's all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep, of course in addition to that while we were in the city We didn't actually go to see it.
Speaker 0: But apparently there were protests about DRM and Apple and everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah there was a. it was like countrywide protests at all the Apple stores and Someone lied to me and told me that I knew was on Fifth Avenue because it's the Fifth Avenue Apple store.
Speaker 1: Someone lied.
Speaker 1: I don't know where or who and they told me it was near the Empire State Building on Fifth Avenue.
Speaker 1: Well, they were wrong.
Speaker 1: It's on 5th and 59th.
Speaker 0: So on Friday Microsoft announced that they are prematurely dropping support for Windows 98.
Speaker 1: Well, when were they supposed to do that?
Speaker 0: I don't actually know but technically Windows 98 and Windows Millennium are still supported.
Speaker 1: Alright
Speaker 0: now apparently one of the recent vulnerabilities that's come out I forget exactly which one and I'm not gonna bother look it up because none of you care but Microsoft basically said that it would be not worthwhile for them to go through the effort of rewriting extensive amounts of code in order to Fix it.
Speaker 0: Therefore as of Friday Windows 98 is permanently and irrevocably insecure.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean isn't Windows 2000 already in that situation?
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 0: There are still updates coming for Windows 2000.
Speaker 0: Oh not full updates not but there are still patches available for Windows 2000.
Speaker 1: I thought the Windows 1000 was no longer supported.
Speaker 0: Well, remember there's different levels of support with Microsoft.
Speaker 0: like Windows XP is fully supported There are companies that are still getting support for Windows 2000 Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: In fact like IBM was in that situation until very recently there was still support for OS 2 And now there's not.
Speaker 0: but Windows 98 is done.
Speaker 0: now I Urge anyone out there who is using Windows 98 to get off of it because there is no way to protect yourself from future vulnerabilities at all.
Speaker 1: Well, the only thing I can say is if you want to you the only use I see for Windows 98 and it really only Has one use DOS gaming.
Speaker 1: No DOS gaming can be done with free DOS or something like that or DOS box Which is almost perfect.
Speaker 0: All right, then.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: There are old games Windows games that really only work in Windows 98. there aren't many but there are some.
Speaker 0: Though I will note that almost any program that just works in Windows 98 natively will probably work.
Speaker 1: Okay, and why most of them work?
Speaker 1: Okay in wine most of them work.
Speaker 1: Okay in XP, but there are some that very few.
Speaker 1: but there's some that really only work in 98 95 a lot of times.
Speaker 1: They're ones that really work in Windows 3.1 And the Windows 98 is really good at playing those even if they can also work in wine or something.
Speaker 1: If you're doing that don't plug that computer into a network.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good God Just just have a little Windows 98 computer to play your games.
Speaker 1: Don't plug it into anything.
Speaker 0: and on a broader level I just want to note to people that this will always happen to Microsoft products.
Speaker 0: Yeah you will always reach a point in which the operating system you're using is not easily upgradable or if it might even be impossible to upgrade and It will no longer be secure or supported.
Speaker 0: and there's really no way around that.
Speaker 0: I mean there are Linux distros that died or that don't get their own updates anymore But theoretically you could find someone to write them for you or write them yourself.
Speaker 0: There's absolutely no way to do that with Windows.
Speaker 1: for an example the new Ubuntu dapper Drake Will be supported for five years on the server and three years on the desktop after its release.
Speaker 1: That means if you set up an Ubuntu server right now.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess since a few weeks ago when dapper Drake was released.
Speaker 1: So in 2011 there will still be updates for security on Ubuntu dapper Drake.
Speaker 0: not only that but every version of Ubuntu Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: now Ubuntu Ubuntu Will is always upgradable to the next version.
Speaker 1: Yes but the point is is that if you set up a system on a Server with Ubuntu dapper Drake Ubuntu Ubuntu dapper Drake you can stick with dapper Drake and have a stable Unchanging platform for five years with no worries.
Speaker 1: Previous versions of Ubuntu had a much shorter time of where there would be updates.
Speaker 1: Even the new Ubuntu desktop has three years of updates coming to it.
Speaker 1: And of course, you can always just upgrade to the next version beyond dapper Drake, which would probably be like, I don't know easy Something and then furry ficus ficus.
Speaker 1: I don't know can't be a tree I don't know what they are, but I could go look up what they're gonna be Something that begins with E and then something begins with F.
Speaker 0: but also the upgrade chain for will be mostly indefinite.
Speaker 0: I mean Windows.
Speaker 0: say you had Windows 98 your Windows 95 and you can upgrade to Windows 98 and you can theoretically upgrade that to Windows 2000. and You can theoretically maybe upgrade that to XP or not XP or Vista.
Speaker 1: I dare you to just take a clean computer.
Speaker 1: install Windows 95 use it with 98 upgrade CD Then use a 2000 upgrade CD.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: not even that.
Speaker 0: take a Windows 98 computer and upgrade it to Windows 2000 and see what happens.
Speaker 0: Many of you out there are younger and didn't live through that but it didn't work.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: He's you're switching from the win 32 kernel to the NT kernel.
Speaker 0: It just didn't work at all and things broke and it just made a mess.
Speaker 1: I mean the one that works best is upgrading a 2000 to an XP and even that's kind of crappy really crappy.
Speaker 1: Yeah It really just sucks.
Speaker 1: if you want to upgrade let's say you were using what was it the breezy badger.
Speaker 1: Yep If you want to upgrade that to the dapper Drake you type what one thing.
Speaker 1: well You might be like very few things and it just kind of happens and then you reboot the computer.
Speaker 0: Of course if you're using like a gen 2 Linux you just compile stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah gen 2 is basically updates for all eternity.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's not really versioned or anything.
Speaker 0: You just keep adding updates and there if you install it at a certain date and then a year later If you keep doing the updates, you'll have the same thing that someone who just installed it will have For the most part
Speaker 1: theoretically,
Speaker 0: yeah theoretically every now and then things change, but that's how there's
Speaker 1: some stuff with profiles.
Speaker 0: But I want to get into that Yeah, and we won't get into how Macs work other than the fact that Yeah, I'm probably going to buy one right after the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well coincidentally the main reason I was holding off is that until recently I was not terribly financially secure.
Speaker 1: So you mean something changed between yesterday and today?
Speaker 0: Well, I did something change that I didn't realize changed when I looked and noticed that my car is pretty much paid off which means my insurance is gonna go away and Coincidentally two days ago I won got a new credit card and to my old credit card doubled my limit randomly because they saw that I'm being prosperous.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and all of those factors could together Really are pushing rim toward buying all the gadgets He hasn't bought for a while because he was trying to be responsible and was for some reason talking in the third person.
Speaker 1: And it has nothing to do with you know, the the intensive peer pressure campaign camp, you know.
Speaker 0: It also has something to do with the fact that of my computers for USB ports One of them is still functioning.
Speaker 1: What happened to mister?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use this computer till it dies.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I am I'm turning this computer into a Windows terminal server, but that's beside the point.
Speaker 1: what happened to?
Speaker 1: As long as this thing works, I'll use it no matter what.
Speaker 1: Why should I buy a Mac when I could get a fast enough computer for less?
Speaker 0: well, here's the other thing.
Speaker 0: the Mac is real cheap and I can run GarageBand.
Speaker 0: and one thing that really got me was I wanted to buy an on mp3 player because it's about time for me to get one and The only advantage the iPod has is that it works cool with iTunes.
Speaker 0: does all that fun stuff?
Speaker 0: If I'm running Linux, there's no way to access any of that stuff.
Speaker 0: So I might as well buy some cheapo mp3 player.
Speaker 1: But then I happen to I'm gonna switch to Windows.
Speaker 1: screw Linux.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I've switched back and forth a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, why is that?
Speaker 0: because I waffle a lot.
Speaker 0: no waffler because I take my time making decisions And I'm always my own devil's advocate.
Speaker 1: I see I see we just got you would to admit to the waffling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm a waffle and you know what?
Speaker 0: I like waffle.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I'm a pancake.
Speaker 1: So fuck you.
Speaker 0: But yeah, there's a distinct possibility.
Speaker 0: by next week we'll be doing this on a Mac.
Speaker 1: hooray I didn't have to pay for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that means you don't get to play with it either.
Speaker 1: I don't need to play with it.
Speaker 0: You can just buy one too.
Speaker 0: You kind of need a new computer.
Speaker 0: They're real cheap.
Speaker 0: We could buy two.
Speaker 1: There's that.
Speaker 1: my computer has nothing wrong with it.
Speaker 0: It's slow.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: It plays half-life 2 fine.
Speaker 0: You can't use garage band.
Speaker 1: I don't need garage band if you have it.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: We can both have it.
Speaker 1: What am I gonna do with it?
Speaker 0: You could sometimes do the post-production when I go to bed.
Speaker 1: No, yeah How can I do that?
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Just learn how to do it.
Speaker 1: Why should I spend my time doing that shit?
Speaker 1: Busy playing half-life 2.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my perfectly working computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I saw that fan that wasn't spinning started spinning again.
Speaker 1: Yeah My computer is getting better not worse.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, my computer a while ago the case fan started making noise and I solved that pretty quickly by unplugging the case fan Good job, and my Northbridge fan started making some noise.
Speaker 0: So I solved that in the same way.
Speaker 0: Computers still okay mostly because I have an air conditioner, but Which isn't on.
Speaker 0: well cuz it's kind of nice.
Speaker 1: It's your computer's surviving.
Speaker 1: cuz you took the panel off the side of the case.
Speaker 0: Yep Let's see.
Speaker 0: The live drive is dead because the cable inside drive has been dead for years.
Speaker 0: Yes It has.
Speaker 0: the zip drive is dead Which is also been dead for years.
Speaker 0: the zip drive it ever used.
Speaker 0: the D the CD burner.
Speaker 0: now I bought a Plextorp SCSI CD burner before CD RW was available to the public.
Speaker 0: This burner is old as shit and it doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 0: My DVD ROM is so old.
Speaker 0: It can't read dual layer DVDs.
Speaker 0: It also cost me a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And of course, I'm running an overheating old Thunderbird gigahertz.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I love this computer.
Speaker 0: forget the Mac.
Speaker 0: I'll just keep this.
Speaker 0: I Talk Cola Suey.
Speaker 1: Gee, I don't know if you said that right at all.
Speaker 0: It sounded about right.
Speaker 1: It's close.
Speaker 1: It sounds close enough.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I probably isn't right.
Speaker 1: It's probably horribly mangled For all we know.
Speaker 1: you could have just said something like I rate babies.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure I got all the syllables, right?
Speaker 0: But anyway, this is a video of a whole bunch of Rube Goldberg machines from a Japanese children's show.
Speaker 0: They are of the highest quality And apparently they've been on the net for a while.
Speaker 0: But this weekend you go one freaked out when she realized that we hadn't seen them and then showed them to us.
Speaker 1: it really reminds me of The PBS kid shows that I watch and I was a little kid Like not the PBS shit they have on now.
Speaker 1: But old school says the stuff that would be in between the Sesame Street stuff on the old Sesame Street.
Speaker 0: You know now this may be a kid show but these Rube Goldberg devices are of the highest quality.
Speaker 1: Okay, so the security consulting company Which means what they do is if you have a business and you have computers and you don't know if they're secure you hire the consulting Company.
Speaker 1: they come and try to hack into you and they tell you what they did and if they succeeded and then they fix the Holes for you or at least tell you how to fix the holes.
Speaker 1: So one security consulting company was going to test I think a bank I don't know for social engineering weaknesses.
Speaker 0: now That is my favorite kind of hacking.
Speaker 0: that doesn't require any technical skill at all.
Speaker 0: That is when you convince other people to give you what you want.
Speaker 1: Yep So the company went to all the employees and said we're the security consultants.
Speaker 1: sometime soon We are going to socially engineer you be on the lookout.
Speaker 1: So now not only so that way You know, it's not just stupid easy.
Speaker 1: They're they're fixing the real Obvious gaping holes that prepared employees You know will fail.
Speaker 0: because usually when they do these tests they don't warn anyone and then they find out.
Speaker 0: you know They just basically do a secret sudden test to figure out who's stupid and who's smart Yeah, or figure out where the holes are and generally everyone's stupid.
Speaker 1: when you do that here They were trying to say alright if people are won't know we're coming.
Speaker 1: How are we gonna get in?
Speaker 1: Well, the answer is just as easily.
Speaker 1: Yeah Hey made it not any more difficult to get in.
Speaker 1: what they did is they took some USB drives and they put some software on the USB drives and they just kind of let him scatter on the parking lot and whatnot.
Speaker 1: and Sure enough.
Speaker 0: Most of those USB drives ended up in company computers rather quickly where they then immediately installed their virus payload And it will Trojan payload Yeah And sent all the personal data from the PC back to the security company.
Speaker 0: then laughs.
Speaker 1: so you put the thumb drive in the computer And immediately there's now a key logger and all kinds of evil shits and everything The person types is going to the guy who made the thumb drive, you know, and and that's it.
Speaker 1: You're done now.
Speaker 0: This is really I mean, it's a problem with people not realizing the security implications of doing things.
Speaker 0: It's also a problem with Windows Mmm, because if in Linux or even in Macs, I'm pretty sure if you just stick a thumb drive in it's not going to execute anything.
Speaker 1: No, but in Windows you can make an autorun boot or a thumb drive.
Speaker 0: that'll autorun yep like an autorun CD and Administrators often don't disable autorun and all the computers and in fact most people who are running a Windows computer are running it as administrator.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the Trojan now has full access to everything on the PC.
Speaker 1: thumb dumb dumb.
Speaker 1: in Linux You would have to put the thumb drive in Manually run the program.
Speaker 1: you would see that it was still running After you closed it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and after it does its fake thing.
Speaker 0: Well, unless you ran it as root and it set up a root kit Yeah, but if you run a strange file as root you get what you deserve.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and even if you're if you run the strange file executable as user All it can really do is mangle your user stuff which screws that user and no one else and that's really easy.
Speaker 1: Supposedly the company secrets would not be in the users my documents folder and they would be in some database where they would be well protected.
Speaker 0: But social engineering is the biggest danger to security and it's also the one that gets the least press and most people don't really realize It gets plenty of press.
Speaker 1: It's just people don't understand it.
Speaker 0: Well, they hear the word But they don't realize that.
Speaker 0: that means the guy calling on the phone Saying it's an emergency and he needs the password because the boss is pissed.
Speaker 1: social engineering means someone just walks into your company and asked for the password and Idiots just tell him everything he wants to know and you don't actually have to do any hacking.
Speaker 0: Yep or like dressing up as the janitor or dressing up as an IT guy Walking in saying you're with the support group and you got a call that there's something wrong with their computer or you detect it.
Speaker 0: There's a virus on their computer and you need your password so you can sit down and fix it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Mm-hmm and people just fall for it.
Speaker 0: Yep in fact when I worked for ITS information technology services at our IT which was the tech support and IT maintenance for the campus.
Speaker 0: We had badges that we were required to make a point of showing them to.
Speaker 0: the people were working on saying yes I am legitimate because apparently not too long before I was hired two kids walked into an office at our IT Said they were working for ITS walked off with a bunch of computers and disappeared.
Speaker 0: One props to them and two god damn.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it's really the weakest link in security.
Speaker 0: No matter how secure anything you make ever is you really can't account for the stupidity ignorance and most importantly just people not caring.
Speaker 1: If you're paying someone about trust, you can't trust idiots.
Speaker 1: This is why users must be given nothing Not even just idiots.
Speaker 0: say you you trust someone they're a smart person, but you're paying them seven fifty an hour.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna care so much about the security of whatever they're working on.
Speaker 1: Well, then you don't really trust them do you know?
Speaker 0: or you you trust them to be content with seven fifty an hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you deserve those bad trusting.
Speaker 1: you got to be good about trusting and you got to not have idiots.
Speaker 0: but anyway We would like today to continue our ongoing series on how computers work from the barest of bits to the highest end Complexities of awesome.
Speaker 1: now a lot of people gave us some useful feedback saying we went too fast.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna review.
Speaker 0: yes now in essence all we really explained on our previous segment of this This is segment number two is that computers are deterministic?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I that well eg that they are predictable.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Yeah, ie ie not eg ie.
Speaker 1: a computer is input Processing and output.
Speaker 1: the same input will always result in the same output with the same computer.
Speaker 0: If a simple computer only had one thing in it You could either you'd either push a button or not push a button and if you push a button a light comes on.
Speaker 0: if you Don't push a button the light doesn't come on.
Speaker 0: You know that anytime you push that button it will always come on.
Speaker 0: the light will always come on.
Speaker 0: The computer is the same way just has a lot more buttons and a lot more lights.
Speaker 1: now this has broad implications.
Speaker 1: Not only is it mathematically significant But it's also significant all the way up to the user level.
Speaker 1: if there is something wrong with the computer It is your fault because the computer will always do the same thing with the same input.
Speaker 0: So if it is not your fault Then it is the fault of whoever wrote the software or the computer is because the software is also input.
Speaker 1: But it will get to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but a computer is The same thing no matter what it doesn't change unless it's broken.
Speaker 1: it could be a broken computer.
Speaker 0: if you want some interesting reading try reading about Turing machines or Which.
Speaker 1: we will explain at some point in the future.
Speaker 0: Yes I was going to read a nice excerpt from diamond age that actually goes over it pretty well.
Speaker 0: But apparently Scott lent my copy of diamond age to our friend Kate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I told you I was letting her borrow it and I totally forgot.
Speaker 1: and then you forgot and I also forgot Yeah, so luckily she reminded us in the forums yep, but that's fine.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: We will get it later.
Speaker 1: It's a really good book.
Speaker 1: if you didn't read diamond age by Neal Stephenson read that yes, and snow crash also.
Speaker 1: Yes Require those are.
Speaker 1: those are the textbooks for rim and Scott's how to computers work.
Speaker 1: the textbooks are snow crash and diamond age.
Speaker 0: Yes, and every.
Speaker 0: let's see everything by Neal Stephenson everything by William Gibson.
Speaker 1: No, no, oh.
Speaker 1: the only other textbook besides those two is C programming by Richie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah No, don't bother with that unless you want to learn how to write C.
Speaker 0: But anyway, and then we talked about how input in a computer I mean everyone.
Speaker 0: it's binary.
Speaker 0: It's ones and zeros true and false yes or no on or off They're all the same thing.
Speaker 0: electricity or not electricity or some variation therein Mm-hmm, but it is all just yeses and noes.
Speaker 0: a whole ton billions and billions of yeses and noes.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's all that goes on in there.
Speaker 1: Yeses come in knows come out.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: Now The way that these yeses and noes become output or at least usable output deterministic output is by applying logic to them.
Speaker 0: We talked briefly about the transistor and now all that does is you can now use an electrical signal a yes or no in Order to determine whether or not a different electrical signal will be a yes or no Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so you can look at one bit or one piece of information or one wire and Based on what's on that wire you have a thing that says if there's something on that wire Then I will put something on this wire, too Yep.
Speaker 1: So there's a little transistor and it's got wires coming in and out of it and it looks at the wires coming in To see if they have electricity or if they don't have electricity.
Speaker 1: and if they do have electricity Then on the out wire it either sends electricity or doesn't depending.
Speaker 1: and if they don't have electricity it either sends Electricity or not depending.
Speaker 0: now if we break this down to the simplest form Imagine that on that you have two inputs two wires.
Speaker 0: each can have either yes or no Electricity or not electricity.
Speaker 0: from now on we'll always refer to them as one or zero.
Speaker 0: Yes, because that makes it easier.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just remember that one is not a thing one is just a word that we use to mean electricity.
Speaker 1: Yes, there are not little magic ones and zeros floating around in there.
Speaker 1: I think I explained that last time.
Speaker 1: Yes, but reiteration is always good, especially when people think you're moving too fast.
Speaker 0: Now these say we have two inputs two wires.
Speaker 0: either of them can have a one or a zero.
Speaker 1: Now that's four combinations total.
Speaker 0: now you can have logic there say we have a little back a magic box and the two wires come in and one wire comes out and say for every combination of Ones and zeros they can go in the two inputs a different output comes out or an output that we can determine.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That is logic No, but if if you say whenever both of the inputs are one Then the output will be one no matter what then that is Deterministic and it will always be one if the two inputs are one.
Speaker 1: Now there are many different logical operators you can use and those are all the different boxes or gates that you can use.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean a computer has Countless inputs and more inputs than you can fathom and more outputs you can fathom and we'll explain that in the future.
Speaker 0: I mean for the sense of scale.
Speaker 0: look at your computer monitor You see all those pixels.
Speaker 0: Imagine that each one of those is one output.
Speaker 0: It's actually more complicated than that.
Speaker 0: Every one of those pixels is a whole ton of outputs from a whole ton of Logical little boxes with little wires coming in millions and millions and millions and millions of millions.
Speaker 0: They just keep going.
Speaker 1: There's so many of them in there, but the basic unit is one single digital logic operator.
Speaker 0: Yep, because it turns out that despite the millions and countless infinite combinations of inputs that can produce different outputs You can break them all down into a tiny set of little two input logical magic boxes.
Speaker 0: that Combining these in various ways can create any logic you could ever imagine.
Speaker 1: Except you need one more thing which we'll talk about later.
Speaker 0: Yes, but in terms.
Speaker 0: well in terms of a one-step operator Yes one step in terms of one input one output in any given time.
Speaker 1: Well two inputs one output.
Speaker 0: Well one set of input one set of output, right?
Speaker 0: You can create any Boolean logic any logic in the world just from this small subset of gates Mm-hmm logic gates.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: The logic gate is just the magic box that I described.
Speaker 1: Yep Now let's talk about the different boxes.
Speaker 1: The simplest box to understand is the AND gate.
Speaker 1: The AND gate has of course two wires coming in and one wire going out.
Speaker 1: The one wire going out will never have electricity on it except if the two wires coming in both have electricity, so if input one if input a is one and Input B is also one.
Speaker 1: So if input, you know, it's one and one Then a one will come out see and gate one and one.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: The names are very descriptive Mm-hmm, so if let's say the two inputs to an AND gate where one and zero or zero and zero or zero and one Which is pretty much the only other three combinations you can have.
Speaker 1: A zero will come out of that AND gate But if two ones come into the AND gate then a one will come out.
Speaker 1: That is an AND gate.
Speaker 1: That is very simple.
Speaker 0: I've linked to in the post a nice probably Wikipedia description of All these gates with pictures and diagrams and all sorts of things.
Speaker 0: So I highly encourage you if you're listening at a computer to look over those diagrams while we speak.
Speaker 0: It'll make it a lot easier.
Speaker 1: There are also symbols for each gate.
Speaker 1: I think an AND gate is sort of a square with this rounded.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think trying to describe them over a podcast That's not gonna work now.
Speaker 1: But there is a different symbol for each gate and they're pretty simple and learning them will help you.
Speaker 0: now in terms of Understanding these gates.
Speaker 0: keep in mind that there's only two inputs to each one with one special exception.
Speaker 0: We'll get to that.
Speaker 0: Yep, therefore, there are only four possible inputs Total four possible combinations of input for each one.
Speaker 0: Yep So if you want to get them straight and learn them and understand them You can make what's called a truth table Where you list the four possible inputs on one side across the bottom and then across the top and a little square you list the possible outputs and then you can make a little grid and and the link.
Speaker 0: it shows exactly what these look like and You can use that if you don't remember what a gate does to figure out exactly how the gate works.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I just want I can't reiterate enough that everything your computer does with one time with one exception that we'll talk about another day It's just combinations of these gates.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So the next gate we'll talk about the OR gate.
Speaker 1: now the OR gate will only put out a one if Either input A is one or if input B is one or if they're both one.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's an OR gate.
Speaker 1: So the only time so an OR gate pretty much always has like a one coming out of the one output except if Both of the inputs to the OR gate are zero.
Speaker 1: then and only then will the OR gate output zero.
Speaker 0: now see it seems very intuitive and if if A and B are true then C is true or if A or B is true then C is true.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm These are just electrical representations of Boolean logic Which you can read up on Boolean logic in great detail online or you can take a discrete math course in school And then you'll learn to hate it.
Speaker 1: Now here's the real simple one is the NOT gate.
Speaker 1: the NOT gate actually only has one input and one output.
Speaker 1: What it does is it outputs the exact opposite of the input.
Speaker 0: It's often called an inverter Yep.
Speaker 0: Now the reason it's called NOT is you say is the input not one?
Speaker 0: if the answer is yes, then a one comes out.
Speaker 0: Yep, so if the input is not one, what is it?
Speaker 0: It's zero.
Speaker 0: And if the input is zero, then the output is one.
Speaker 1: Yep, the output is always the opposite of the input.
Speaker 1: zero comes in one comes out It inverses the signal zeros come out it flips the signal it reverses the signal.
Speaker 0: However, you want to think about it and it all it's the only.
Speaker 1: it's the only gate that has only one input.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have two inputs like the other gates.
Speaker 1: Okay, let's talk about the NAND gate.
Speaker 0: Yeah with the basic gates NOT and or yes.
Speaker 0: Well, there's also one more kind of basic gate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we'll talk about that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Now you can combine NOT gates with AND or OR gates to make two cool kind of gates Mm-hmm NAND and NOR NOT AND NOT OR.
Speaker 1: So it N N A N D NOT AND It basically is the same thing as an AND gate only it takes the output and puts it through a NOT gate.
Speaker 0: So imagine it in English if it is not and If the if it is not true in an AND gate then it is true here And if it is true in an AND gate then it is false here.
Speaker 0: So it only.
Speaker 0: it outputs a one as long as the two inputs are not both.
Speaker 1: one You don't remember an AND gate only puts out a one if both inputs are one.
Speaker 1: on a NAND gate It always outputs a one.
Speaker 1: Unless Both inputs are one then it will output a zero.
Speaker 0: now trivia with a NAND gate and I know someone answered in the forums Which I'm very happy and we talked about it last time too.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about it again.
Speaker 0: The NAND gate just happens to be electrically the simplest gate to make.
Speaker 1: it just happens.
Speaker 0: It is very very simple And in fact with nothing but the electronics from NAND gates you can create every other gate that exists.
Speaker 0: And part of that is because if you take the two inputs of a NAND gate and short them together It becomes a NOT gate.
Speaker 0: because think about it Say you have one input.
Speaker 0: that then splits into the two inputs of a NAND gate.
Speaker 0: if you put a one into that one wire No matter what a one goes into both sides Which then makes it false which does the same thing as a NOT gate.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That might make more sense.
Speaker 0: If you look at a picture of it.
Speaker 1: Yep There's also the NOR gate.
Speaker 0: not or it follows the same trend as the NAND gate.
Speaker 0: it's a NOT or gate.
Speaker 1: So if an OR gate would output a one the NOR gate outputs a zero and vice versa.
Speaker 1: So pretty much a NOR gate always puts out a zero unless both inputs are zero in which case it outputs a one.
Speaker 0: Now or for now has been either or or both.
Speaker 0: It's been an inclusive or when in doubt It's included.
Speaker 0: XOR is another gate where the X stands for exclusive meaning it'll only output a one.
Speaker 0: a true if One of the inputs is true one and one of the inputs is false.
Speaker 1: Yeah XOR is a tricky gate and It's like the advanced gate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know if you're programming stuff and you're using XORs It's like ooh, you were smart enough to use XOR.
Speaker 0: think of it like a radio button.
Speaker 1: Not really, but I mean any any programmer worth a shit knows when to use XOR.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but think of it like a radio button.
Speaker 0: You can only select one at a time It'll only be true if only one of the inputs is selected.
Speaker 0: if only one of the inputs is true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so imagine you have there are two inputs.
Speaker 1: if both of them are the same then nothing comes out but if they're different.
Speaker 1: so if one in if input a is one and input B is zero or if Input a is one and input B is zero then and only then will you get a one to come out of the output?
Speaker 0: So you can think of it as a. are they not the same gate?
Speaker 1: Yep, an XOR is if the inputs are not the same Output a one.
Speaker 1: if the inputs are the same output is zero.
Speaker 0: now, of course, there is a an XOR gate.
Speaker 1: Well, it's an X nor.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to make it easy because you know and and or and X or
Speaker 1: yep The X nor gate or the NX or gate the not X or gate if you will
Speaker 0: It will
Speaker 1: all put a one if both gates it if the inputs are the same as each other.
Speaker 0: So it's a check for sameness.
Speaker 1: Yeah If both inputs are zero a one comes out.
Speaker 1: and if the inputs are different a zero comes out.
Speaker 0: and if both inputs are one a one comes out and Of course your computer is just for each step that your computer does because you know You have a processor and it works, you know, a megahertz a number of times per second.
Speaker 0: It does something.
Speaker 0: every time it does something.
Speaker 0: It's just a crazy combination of all these gates.
Speaker 1: Well, that'll be more relevant when we talk about stuff next week
Speaker 0: true But just try to get it in your heads and remember that your computer is only doing and each iteration every time it does something It's just following a complex set of one of these gates of all these gates and then an output comes out.
Speaker 1: There are lots and lots of inputs to your computer from all over the place and they some of them are more than just one Bit or a couple bits.
Speaker 1: there are many many bits and bytes and megabits and gigabytes and there's a million inputs And it goes into all of them at once and there's a bunch of gates all linked up to each other and then at the end there's a whole mess of outputs all over the place and it's just this Sea of gates all linked up to each other all over the place crazy like and a mess of inputs and a mess of outputs and If you give it the same input you'll always get the same output every single time.
Speaker 0: and if you have a computer running by itself with Absolutely, no input from any source anywhere then it can never ever change what it's doing.
Speaker 0: Nope, unless it was coded to do so in which case it's not actually changing because it's doing exactly what it was told to do.
Speaker 1: Yep, the program is an input to the computer.
Speaker 0: Remember that if you tell a computer to add one and one and then subtract one in one and do that over and over and Over again, it'll never stop until someone unplugs it or stops it or it breaks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it didn't do that, then it would not be in fact a computer.
Speaker 1: All right, I'll ask the trivia question this time All right There is something we left out that we said we were gonna talk about next time and we will.
Speaker 1: Now you might have noticed that with this lot these gates we're talking about There isn't a way for a computer to remember something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you haven't.
Speaker 0: well if you have an input coming in then an output is coming out But as soon as you change the input the output changes.
Speaker 1: Yep now Nor if you just use these logical things you can only make a computer that does something.
Speaker 1: right now You can't make a computer that does something when there are many inputs in a different order.
Speaker 1: so let's say I had a computer and I inputted, you know, one two three and Then I had a computer and I inputted one three two.
Speaker 1: Do you see how the order of the inputs when there are many inputs in an order sequential input makes a difference?
Speaker 1: well in order for that to happen The computer would have to be able to remember a bit from before or many bits from before.
Speaker 0: It would have to remember if something was true or false.
Speaker 1: It has to store a bit.
Speaker 1: It has to take a bit of Information and hold on to it and not let it go so that when the inputs come through again That it'll be different.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: How do you do that when a bit is just electricity?
Speaker 1: Yep, how do you do that?
Speaker 0: Well, that's our trivia question and it's once again, you won't win anything.
Speaker 0: It is just a way to prepare yourself for the next segment of how computers work.
Speaker 1: Yep there are actually many ways to store information, but there is a Most basic one to store a single bit.
Speaker 1: that is the simplest electronic way to do so and don't just say RAM or a hard drive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or a CD or a floppy disk We're talking about on the lowest lowest electronic level.
Speaker 0: if you were soldering a bunch of things together, how would you store something there?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, if you were making a chip like a Pentium chip, what electronic thing would you put on the chip to store a bit?
Speaker 0: Now we announced last week.
Speaker 0: We're done with the computer segment for now that we were finishing up the logo contest and what I can say now is that we have Started and then ended a different contest the banner contest for the top of the website.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not really so much a banner contest as in make the website look a little better contest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm sure you all saw classic brah's Submission in the forum.
Speaker 0: if you haven't you should go to the forum because the website is probably going to be looking like that in Short order.
Speaker 0: he is one and we're going to do something awesome for him in return.
Speaker 1: Yes now His submission did not really include a logo.
Speaker 1: we are going to need to do some work on our end to select a logo and Incorporate it into our you know and feed images and mp3 images I mean basically and image.
Speaker 0: we we started the logo contest and we were real vague about it.
Speaker 0: And now especially now that we've talked to more people who know more about this than us We've realized that we wanted art for the website.
Speaker 0: That's really cool that you know, this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: But we then I mean that has to be something somewhat complex something that'll look good on the site We still need the logo which has to be simple.
Speaker 0: It has to be like almost as almost a gestalt a thing that you'd look at and it's that is geek nights.
Speaker 0: It's very simple very compact like the logo of a company.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like McDonald's golden arches We've got it.
Speaker 0: We've gotten a bunch of awesome submissions, obviously, and we'd like to have more.
Speaker 0: we're gonna extend the contest But we do no longer really need art for the website itself.
Speaker 0: Yep, so think simple.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna go on much longer though.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: I mean, you should see how many submissions we got right after we said the contest is almost over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's get you got Two weeks.
Speaker 0: I was about to say two weeks.
Speaker 0: So that's your weeks is good.
Speaker 0: into within two weeks We will have decided on a geek night's logo.
Speaker 0: So once again think simple.
Speaker 0: if you can't draw I don't know.
Speaker 0: just make a mock-up what you think it should look like and then someone else will dry like.
Speaker 0: don't even worry about Coloring it.
Speaker 0: just come up with the idea and I'm sure we can cover the rest.
Speaker 0: and that was geek nights with rim And Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: you can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.