Speaker 0: It's Wednesday March 22nd, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about Hansuki and tactical roar.
Speaker 0: Let's do this So every day this week.
Speaker 0: I'm going over a few reminders.
Speaker 0: the first reminder is You should go to our website.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of people out there like found our feed via some podcast director your iTunes or something and You're not actually going to our website.
Speaker 0: It's front row crew Dot-com.
Speaker 0: if you go there There's a forum where there's lots of fun talking going on and arguing and awesomeness.
Speaker 0: You could just join that.
Speaker 0: there's a little link there, but if you want to go right to it.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's www.front row crew.com slash forum.
Speaker 1: also Don't forget that we have five separate feeds one for each day of the week and one for all days of the week.
Speaker 0: Yep, so if you only like video games you can subscribe to just Tuesday And if you like video games and anime you can subscribe to Tuesday and Wednesday And if you like all of geek nights, you should just subscribe to the one feed.
Speaker 1: that gives you everything Yeah, and thus you can stop asking us for that feature.
Speaker 0: Yes, and Lastly we have this cool frapper map which lets everyone who listens to eat nights put a little pin on the map to show us Where you are.
Speaker 0: it's?
Speaker 1: www.frapper.com/frontrowcrew And we seem to have a listener in what.
Speaker 0: Norway Norway.
Speaker 1: so hello, Norway.
Speaker 0: Your timezone is very distant from our timezone.
Speaker 0: I wonder if it is night or day when you are listening.
Speaker 1: So anyway, we only have one actual news for the rest of the world today because the other news is more.
Speaker 1: Well, well, you'll see.
Speaker 0: So Google has this thing they're working on called.
Speaker 0: Well, you probably all use Gmail or know about it.
Speaker 0: and if you don't know about it Well, we have a zillion bajillion invites.
Speaker 0: so we can get you Gmail if you want.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much the best web-based email there is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're not evil like Yahoo.
Speaker 0: So yep, and Basically on our hosting I was running a real email server like real.
Speaker 0: The problem was that's not easy even for a technical guy like me and I couldn't get certain features to work Like.
Speaker 0: I have like three domains like this mod.
Speaker 0: This is my personal domain this front row crew.com.
Speaker 0: We got some other don't?
Speaker 0: we got two other domains on the machine.
Speaker 1: Yep, a thief rabbit.
Speaker 0: Yeah mid husband gamers Yeah, but we couldn't get email for all the domains.
Speaker 0: You can only get email to work for one domain now.
Speaker 0: It's not technologically impossible.
Speaker 0: It's just difficult and it's not worth the effort.
Speaker 0: So when Google announced they were gonna have Gmail for domains I signed up for that beta.
Speaker 1: now what that means is Instead of pointing our DNS record, you know, the MX record for those of you who know You add our email server.
Speaker 1: We point it at Google and then Google takes care of our email.
Speaker 0: so basically Google has the email server that runs Gmail and All the emails that are meant for us that would normally come to our server Instead goes to Google server and when they show up there Google puts them in our Gmail accounts.
Speaker 1: So now instead of geek nights at gmail.com We're geek nights at front row crew.
Speaker 0: calm as you would expect but on our end We're using Gmail even though you're sending the mail to front row crew.
Speaker 0: calm It's Gmail for us.
Speaker 1: Whoo.
Speaker 1: Now this feature isn't widely available to the public yet.
Speaker 1: We're inside of the beta.
Speaker 0: Yeah I signed up for the beta as soon as they announced it and that they just sent me the email allowing me access today and About a minute after he got that email we went nuts playing around inside it.
Speaker 0: It's basically just Gmail with a few little bits on top and the only thing wrong with it that I can tell so far Is that you can't use the Gmail notification thing though?
Speaker 1: I'm sure someone soon will write a new one or fix that one.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it'll be fixed rather quickly.
Speaker 0: This isn't you know?
Speaker 0: now?
Speaker 0: apparently this beta was expanded today.
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 1: And it just it has a lot of neat features.
Speaker 1: as far we can make aliases Meaning I can have my account and then I can make a whole bunch of different names that all point at the same account.
Speaker 0: Well, oh the all the all the advanced features are for the administrator of the domain, which is me.
Speaker 0: Yeah users of the domain of which I can make 10 total users because it's free.
Speaker 0: I guess if I wanted to be able to make more than 10 users out to pay money or something or maybe it's because it's A beta right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think in the future what they're gonna do is gonna charge money for more users and stuff.
Speaker 0: But the administrator the domain can do all sorts of fancy stuff and all the users are just users.
Speaker 0: but like you can rebrand the the mail and then like the idea is that you can sell it to You know other people as if it was your own mail type of thing, you know with your domain.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you had a domain that was worth selling Yeah, and I read the EULA carefully because there's a lot of potential for badness.
Speaker 0: But the EULA pretty much said this is the EULA of Gmail, but the only other thing we're adding to it is like all Users are considered customers of you and customers of Google and I'm like, alright sure Whatever who cares.
Speaker 1: and of course, this isn't really specific to this new Gmail domain thing But Gmail in general for those of you who use it, but don't really use it.
Speaker 1: Well There are a lot of very cool features in there that you can play around with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Gmail has fancy stuff like labeling and and yeah Like now if an email gets sent to geek nights at Gmail or geek nights at front row crew It goes to both Scott and I On our own email accounts.
Speaker 1: In fact for me, it goes into a special folder called geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Me too.
Speaker 0: Well, it gets labeled geek night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which works like a folder but also it you know what player.
Speaker 0: It's more like a tag and delicious than a folder.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's still cool.
Speaker 0: So if you're not using Gmail and you're using some crummy old-school email type of thing.
Speaker 0: what's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Oh also Gmail has chat you can and the chat in Gmail is hooked up to jabber which we use anyway.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of like ooh integrate everything It's all good.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now before any of you ask no, we're not giving everyone email addresses at front row crew.
Speaker 0: calm No, we only have ten and we've already used Two or three.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the original I guess actual front row crew Which I don't think we've ever actually explained what the front row crew is.
Speaker 0: You could do a whole episode about that.
Speaker 1: I think we will someday but I guess the actual members of the front row crew get first dibs on this.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right now I'm gonna use it mostly for business matters and not so much personal matter And once the business matters are taken care of then the other things can then you know.
Speaker 1: So in actual news, there's a group and this has been on slash down.
Speaker 1: It was actually reported a while ago, but it was reported again today, and I decided that it's something worth talking about.
Speaker 1: They are suing Target stores their online presence because they are not as Blind or otherwise disability compliant as these people would like them to be.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and it might sound simple, you know ADA and such.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, you should accommodate people with disabilities.
Speaker 1: The internet makes it a whole lot trickier than it is in the real world to enforce or manage that sort of thing and There's really no easy answer here.
Speaker 0: I mean imagine trying to use your computer where instead of a monitor you just have speakers that read stuff to you and then You have a Braille keyboard.
Speaker 0: It's not easy and you know when the internet isn't designed For not having a monitor and people don't specifically accommodate you.
Speaker 0: with your special situation It's pretty much nearly impossible to do anything efficiently.
Speaker 1: I mean the worst part is that a lot of people on both sides of the debate I mean there are half the people who say it's impossible and we shouldn't even try and a lot of people who say that you must it you have to accommodate people.
Speaker 1: and Actually, it's that latter group that I'm more worried about because they're trying to push forth legislation and they've been doing this for a long time that would require websites as in all websites to meet certain usability standards and it's my opinion that most of these usability standards are either impossible difficult or just stupid to force people to do I
Speaker 0: Think what they should do is if you're a company with a website that sells stuff, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like You have enough money that you can afford to pay someone to make like a different Usable version of your site or something like that or in the very least if you've got phone orders instead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you could just have.
Speaker 0: you know the website they go.
Speaker 0: if they go to it They can read them off what's there and then if they can't Successfully make an order because they can't click on an image link or some who knows, you know, they call on the telephone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but a lot of these laws people want pests that would force all websites to comply.
Speaker 1: I mean, what have you put up?
Speaker 1: an artsy cool flash animation site?
Speaker 1: There's no way a blind person can use that site.
Speaker 0: Yeah flash is pretty much impossible for blind people to use absolutely impossible flash.
Speaker 1: any site that uses a lot of JavaScript to move stuff around or navigate.
Speaker 0: Yeah blind people cannot use homestar runner now.
Speaker 1: actually there's a big problem now That's arising with captchas the little.
Speaker 1: now for those of you don't know You know a lot of times when you sign up for a forum or a blog or whatever when you're making the account It'll ask you to repeat some characters that are written in a text image.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll be like a picture with some letters in it But the letters will be all funky.
Speaker 0: so like a computer couldn't read the letters only a person can read the letters.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's great.
Speaker 1: It keeps spammers out and I'm actually a big fan of that.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: However What's a blind person to do?
Speaker 0: Actually, well on Google the Google has captchas But every Google capture has a little button next to it that will speak the words out loud if you click on it.
Speaker 1: And I've seen other places that have just have an email link where you can email the administrator if you are blind or whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yep, but there are a lot of sites out there that just don't implement anything.
Speaker 0: Actually, I have one forum.
Speaker 0: I'm in for the comic book comic geek speak podcast.
Speaker 0: Whenever you log in you have to do a capture.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty annoying.
Speaker 0: That's silly.
Speaker 0: the thing is is it okay?
Speaker 0: because Blind people can't read comic books.
Speaker 0: So there aren't too many blind people in the comic geek speak forums.
Speaker 1: Actually, I know there are a lot of blind people who are really into podcasting.
Speaker 0: Oh Podcasting is like the best thing ever for blind people because RSS feeds are really easy to read with.
Speaker 0: You know things for blind people and downloading in b3s and playing them is real easy for blind.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not so popular with deaf people.
Speaker 0: I hear no Like in the podcast.
Speaker 0: deaf people definitely much more liking the the video casts and the you know websites the blogs.
Speaker 1: See, I guess the my my main Idea here is that like the ADA?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's basically a yes You should try to accommodate as many people as you can wherever possible without undue hardship And people have to keep the undue hardship idea in mind.
Speaker 1: I mean just because if I make some fun website just for myself Should I be forced legally to spend the time and the effort to make it compliant to every possible disability out there?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it would be easier for me to just shut down the site.
Speaker 0: I mean if the ADA is kind of like PETA if they had their way Then like every single building and every single business in the entire world would have an accommodation for every single disability ever.
Speaker 0: It's just not feasible.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know what every single like Raised Building needs to have like a handicap lift the handy.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I think what's happening is the people who make like ramps and all those You know crutches and wheelchairs and all those sorts of handicap Equipment are like ADA lobbyists to try to get more.
Speaker 1: You realize the ADA is an act not a group.
Speaker 1: There may also be a group but I know the group
Speaker 0: that these
Speaker 1: players the the disabilities act and that's the main thing here because it One thing I agree with the many things the access because fronting it mandates that all new buildings have to include certain basic easy to Implement things like ramps wide doors wide elevators.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: I say that's great.
Speaker 1: The problem is when they if you try to enforce and luckily this hasn't been done on say you have an old building a historical Building there's no way to update a building like that.
Speaker 0: Nope without destroying the building or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, RIT got hit with that.
Speaker 1: There's a room at our college that's up a tiny spiral staircase and they used to have like dinners and ball Not really balls, but like fancy dinners up there.
Speaker 1: it's at the top of a tower and has a nice window out to the campus and They were forced to shut it down because they couldn't make it compliant because the building was built after the act and This room was not accessible via elevators.
Speaker 1: The room yeah, there's a storage room now for janitors.
Speaker 0: Why couldn't they just make the room something that handicapped people don't want to do like that.
Speaker 1: You can't that's how the law works.
Speaker 1: It's so silly Yeah, but then again It's kind of like the evidence laws in court.
Speaker 1: if there's no penalty for not following it then people just would say oops Sorry, we didn't mean to not follow it, but it's too late.
Speaker 1: Now the building's built ha ha ha.
Speaker 0: I mean it's okay if you don't have a handicap accessible ramp to get into the gymnastics room because They can't use the gymnastics room, you know It's not okay to have say no ramp to go to the bowling alley because handicapped people like bowling.
Speaker 1: Well, what about the gymnastics room?
Speaker 1: I mean, what if someone who's handicapped wants to watch gymnastics?
Speaker 0: Oh if it's like a Gymnastics, you know arena with seats and everything then of course they have to get it, you know I'm talking about like the gym where people go to practice.
Speaker 1: I guess I mean, I don't have an answer.
Speaker 1: either way it's just there's a very fine line between protecting the rights of handicapped disabled people to interact with society and Protecting the rights of people to do and build whatever they want to do.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the internet.
Speaker 1: this is a thousand times more because anyone it's not like anyone can't just build a building.
Speaker 1: you need money You need resources and you at you were forced to consider a lot of these things.
Speaker 1: You don't need anything to build a website and I'd say that at least 80% of the internet out There is not in any way accessible to handicapped individuals.
Speaker 0: I think what people should just do is You know if you decide that you want to make your stuff accessible to blind people and you know You're gonna get a lot of benefit from all the buying blind people who flock to your website.
Speaker 1: That's what I say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and so it's just.
Speaker 0: you don't need any law to encourage you to do it.
Speaker 0: It's just if you want blind people to come to your website do it.
Speaker 0: If you don't want them to come don't and you'll suffer or be better for it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess in my eyes the only websites that should be required by law to accommodate these sorts of things government websites public services websites or any website that maybe not be run by the government but like libraries the way the the postal services website Yeah, the.
Speaker 0: the financial aid website non-commercial products and services.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that sort of thing definitely has to be accessible and standards compliant and all that.
Speaker 1: I guess the only reason I bring it up is that I've been seeing this issue appearing more and more and one.
Speaker 1: most people who design websites for companies just don't care about it at all and then the company's get in trouble or The legislation keeps getting pushed and someday this sort of thing might get passed and then the Internet's in for a rude awakening.
Speaker 0: It's actually really Microsoft's fault because Internet Explorer and you know not being good about standards or anything, you know It just so happens that well-written websites that follow the standards and you know Have nice CSS and all that jazz are actually much easier for blind people to use than websites Made to work in IE and not any other breath.
Speaker 1: The problem is most corporate websites now at least most of the crap you want to splash crap all over either that or they're designed by some guy in Dreamweaver because Honestly, there really aren't any good gooey tools for building CSS.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's called hire a designer who doesn't suck.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of them.
Speaker 0: go around to like any of those CSS websites and you see the million amazing designs that are perfectly compliant.
Speaker 1: Hire those people but they don't want to pay for that.
Speaker 1: Oh But If there's no reason to pay for that I mean if the only people who care are nerds like us who raise a fury but nothing comes of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, we'll see.
Speaker 0: when ie7 comes out what happens.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Well, I did see the news that ie7 is completely separated from Explorer.
Speaker 1: now, apparently I didn't actually read the article.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll talk about that another day.
Speaker 1: Yeah So my thing of the day is a interesting study we found on eSolutions data.
Speaker 0: Yeah so check out this scientific study.
Speaker 0: eSolutions did.
Speaker 0: they took a bunch of old people and they brought them into a room full of Computers and they had them try out all these different operating systems.
Speaker 0: And when they tried them out, they filled out a little form You know that said what you liked about it and rated things from 1 to 10 and all that jazz.
Speaker 1: now one operating system came away with 72% of the users in terms of you know them saying it's the best one or the easiest to use.
Speaker 0: One really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, which one would that be?
Speaker 1: far and away senior citizens prefer.
Speaker 1: Prefer Linux.
Speaker 0: Wow, were they using gnome or KDE?
Speaker 1: It actually doesn't say.
Speaker 1: oh, that's kind of sad though Doss actually comes in with 14% right after it.
Speaker 0: really how did Doss come in?
Speaker 0: second?
Speaker 0: How do people even know how to use that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: They must have had it set up.
Speaker 1: They must have some old-school guy.
Speaker 1: I imagine it was at least off six.
Speaker 0: Maybe they had directions or something.
Speaker 0: maybe because it's so simple and you know A lot of flashy colors to scare the old people away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Windows 2003 server just barely edged out BoS.
Speaker 1: I don't know where they got a copy of BoS.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they even tried BoS.
Speaker 0: No one even considered using that for real.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe they got a BoS because the study was a BS.
Speaker 0: You think.
Speaker 1: well, you see this is why this is my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I Made this study up just now, but if you follow the link from our website There's a very professional looking site showing you all these statistics Really?
Speaker 0: So it's a little fake statistic generator to fool people.
Speaker 1: Yep eSolutions data is a site where you can put in whatever statistics you want and they'll generate a really flashy look in sight.
Speaker 1: that if you don't read the fine text all over because it says It's fake all over the place, but no one really seems to look.
Speaker 0: Everyone just looks at the picture of the.
Speaker 0: you know, Linux 72%.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it shows.
Speaker 1: it even shows like a picture of two people talking and it shows a graph and all these things But it's all made up.
Speaker 1: Wow people are just I got Scott with it this morning.
Speaker 0: I said cuz I got me for like a second.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got him for like a second, but it was worth it.
Speaker 1: I sent him one.
Speaker 1: It was like would you give up the First Amendment for you know money?
Speaker 1: and it showed that like two-thirds of Americans would give it Up for a thousand dollars or more and for like a second.
Speaker 0: I was like.
Speaker 1: he messaged me back like no way Yeah, and then before we can reply I sent him another study proving that a hundred percent of people think he is in fact a gullible penis penis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Everyone go make fun fake graphs and scientific studies and show them to your friends and fool them.
Speaker 1: The best thing is you can fiddle with the URL and look at all the studies other people have put in this site.
Speaker 1: And you know, what's scary?
Speaker 1: Most of them don't look like they're humorous.
Speaker 1: They look like someone was really trying to fool someone.
Speaker 0: I bet you it worked All right, so my thing today.
Speaker 0: It's this cool little website.
Speaker 0: it's flash and what it does is it gives you a picture of a part of a keyboard on a piano and You click on 10 keys any 10 keys and it ever.
Speaker 0: the first one you click is number one And the second one you click is number two and so on.
Speaker 0: you get to click 10 notes in total 10.
Speaker 0: Then what it does is it goes through all the digits of pi and for every digit of pi It plays the corresponding note.
Speaker 0: so the first note that will be played is the third note you pushed.
Speaker 0: then the first note you pushed then the four then the first again and so on for 10,000 some odd digits of pi And that result is some random sounding music.
Speaker 0: then that result is some random sounding music, but I think it'd be very interesting.
Speaker 0: if you know Is it true that maybe no matter what combination you entered at some point during pi?
Speaker 0: There would be good sounding music?
Speaker 0: or maybe you could Purposefully try to create some good sounding music based on known numbers in pi and then get to that point to hear it?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I could probably make fairly good music by picking sets of notes that form certain modal keys or chords.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure if you pick like 10 notes that go well together No matter what the order is you could probably make something that sounds actually.
Speaker 1: Scott made something while I was watching him Show me the site.
Speaker 1: that sounded all right.
Speaker 1: He took.
Speaker 1: he just hit all the black keys which was basically just a pentatonic scale which It I most people consider it.
Speaker 0: well I hit him.
Speaker 0: in order is what I did is I picked Like five low black keys in a row and then five high black keys in a row.
Speaker 0: So if the number was between it was one two, three, four or five It would be low.
Speaker 0: and if it so it's kind of either low notes or high notes.
Speaker 1: It was like Well Scott doesn't really know anything about music.
Speaker 1: I just thought it was funny that he picked the minor and major modal pentatonic scales.
Speaker 0: No one cares.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I thought it was funny, which I think that's the reason it sounded not bad, because that the thing about that kind of scale is that there's no way to hit a wrong note.
Speaker 1: There's no way to hit two notes next to each other that sound bad.
Speaker 0: I just picked some random keys.
Speaker 0: that, you know.
Speaker 1: You picked all black keys.
Speaker 1: There are only five black keys.
Speaker 0: No, there were, well, there were some more black keys.
Speaker 1: There's only five black notes.
Speaker 0: Okay, but there are more than five black keys on the keyboard.
Speaker 1: So tonight we're reviewing two anime to go back to our classic, well, technically no.
Speaker 1: We're reviewing one anime and previewing another one.
Speaker 1: Now the first one, I can't believe we actually had to do this, but Scott decided he wants to say the name of it in Japanese.
Speaker 1: So, Scott?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's "Hanbun no Tsuki ga Noboru
Speaker 0: Sora.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, "Under the Light of the Half
Speaker 1: Moon.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: Alright, we're watching that, and "Tactical Roar," which we watched one episode of, and, uh...
Speaker 0: We're not gonna watch another episode.
Speaker 0: That was enough.
Speaker 0: This is all you're gonna get.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: More.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get more.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, uh, "The Half
Speaker 1: Moon.".
Speaker 1: Well, we'll call it "Half Moon," just to be quick and easy.
Speaker 1: It's a show that I really didn't hear anything about, didn't know anything about.
Speaker 1: We downloaded it randomly, and I expected it to be the same as all that other crap anime we've been watching lately, because we've been watching a lot of crap anime.
Speaker 0: And starting out, when you first watch the first five minutes, it seems kinda crappy.
Speaker 0: You know, it doesn't seem crappy, like, "Oh, this is
Speaker 0: bad.".
Speaker 0: It just seems kinda average.
Speaker 1: It feels run-of-the-mill, and it feels a lot like those shows that are based on dating games.
Speaker 0: Oh, it feels a lot like that, yeah.
Speaker 1: The thing is, this show is actually good.
Speaker 1: At least as far--we've seen the first four episodes, and it's not the best show in the world, but both of us like it enough to where we really want to see what happens, and we're gonna watch it all.
Speaker 0: Well, it's 'cause there's only six--I just discovered five minutes ago, there are only six episodes.
Speaker 0: And once you know what the show is about, you realize that six episodes is good for this show, as opposed to, like, "Oh, it should've had more," or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like, at first, I was like--I mean, just earlier, we watched Episode 4 just during dinner, and I was like, "So what, is this show gonna be 26 episodes?
Speaker 0: It should be, like, 13 or maybe even
Speaker 0: less.".
Speaker 0: And now I find out it's six, which is perfect.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, I mean, I like shows like this, but this really isn't the kind of show I would've expect Scott to care about at all, yet he's watching it with me.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not, like, my favorite show in the world.
Speaker 0: It's pretty average, but it's better than a lot of other stuff that's out there right now, so... And it has a lot of redeeming aspects other than its main...
Speaker 1: This is definitely a show that you can watch alone and get a lot out of it, but it's also one of those shows where, if you watch it with a crowd and an anime club, it becomes a thousand times more hysterical.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, let's describe what goes on the show.
Speaker 0: The show is about this guy who's in the hospital.
Speaker 0: He's a teenage kid.
Speaker 1: He's got hepatitis.
Speaker 0: He has hepatitis, which means he can walk around and do stuff, but if he tries to do too much, he'll get sick.
Speaker 1: Oh, you tried to do too much with it.
Speaker 0: You tried to do too much with it.
Speaker 0: And, you know, he has to stay in the hospital till his hepatitis goes away.
Speaker 0: Not really life-threatening unless he, you know, disobeys the doctor too much.
Speaker 1: Or drinks the liquor the doctor tries to give him.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, what happens is, he misbehaves because, you know, if you're in a hospital, you're gonna be kinda bored.
Speaker 0: Especially, I don't know why he doesn't have a Game Boy.
Speaker 0: This is supposed to be Japan.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 1: Well, he always sneaks out and goes to his friend's house to play, uh, looks like a PlayStation.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, um...
Speaker 1: Now, there's this nurse who's taking care of him, and...
Speaker 0: The nurse is funny.
Speaker 1: She's kinda mean, and mean in a funny way.
Speaker 0: Stern, but fair.
Speaker 1: His friend, we call him "Zebra Mask" for reasons that are best left to you watching the show.
Speaker 1: Mhm.
Speaker 1: Now, the thing is, he's in the hospital, whatever, and it could've been a typical "Oh, he meets a girl in the hospital, and then there's some crap about
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: And he does meet a girl in the hospital, but it's not like every other show.
Speaker 1: This girl has a terminal illness.
Speaker 0: A really scary terminal illness.
Speaker 0: Like, she's going to die soon unless she goes to, like, Denmark to get this rare, expensive surgery she can't afford.
Speaker 1: And, like, the show basically tells you flat out that there's no way she's gonna be able to go and get this surgery.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this isn't, like, a spoiler.
Speaker 0: This is something they say in plain English in, like, the first or second episode.
Speaker 0: First episode, yeah.
Speaker 1: And even if this can succeed, she won't be able to live that long.
Speaker 1: Or she can not get the operation, and she's still gonna die fairly soon.
Speaker 1: There's really no happy way out of this.
Speaker 0: So the nurse says, "Hey, you know, if you go befriend her, then I'll be less mean to
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 0: So he does, and then, you know, over the show is sorta like this, you know, little romantic, friendly kinda thing going on.
Speaker 0: And that's the plot, is this guy and this girl, this guy with hepatitis and this girl who's gonna die, hanging with each other.
Speaker 1: The show is generally very low-key and very atmospheric, and it's more realistic than you'd think, despite the humor that crops up from time to time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought there was gonna be some unrealistic action, but there wasn't.
Speaker 0: Like, I was expecting there to be some in this particular scene, but they didn't really have any.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a scene, we don't really, there's not much to spoil, but there's a thing on a ledge that, you know, up on a high building, and, you know, you expect this classic anime scene of, "Oh, almost fall, rescued, crazy,
Speaker 1: whatever.".
Speaker 1: But no, none of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it goes pretty normally.
Speaker 0: And there's also the best is in, like, the first episode.
Speaker 1: Oh, the old man?
Speaker 0: There's a funny old man with a collection of porn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, the guy's name is Tada, I think.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they refer to it as the Tada Collection.
Speaker 1: He has, like, thousands of pornographic magazines and books.
Speaker 0: It's like this fantastic porn collection, like, amazing.
Speaker 0: And there's a plot surrounding the porn collection that I won't spoil, but let's just say the porn collection stays around for quite a while.
Speaker 0: And makes many important things happen in the show.
Speaker 1: As far as I'm concerned, the porn collection itself is a character independent of the people who have owned it.
Speaker 0: Well, if you're gonna say that, the porn collection is my favorite character in this show.
Speaker 1: I don't know, I like the nurse.
Speaker 0: The nurse is definitely the funniest.
Speaker 1: The only character I don't like is that frickin' doctor.
Speaker 0: Well, the doctor, I think, is supposed to be the bad guy.
Speaker 1: See, I don't know, 'cause I don't wanna, not to ruin anything, but I'm torn between believing that he's just this evil, kind of perverted guy, versus he's just really depressed and broken by dealing with what he's dealing with.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what the show's about, isn't it?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, the whole show is just dealing with, say you have a person who is going to die, and everyone knows this fact, and there's no question about it.
Speaker 1: How do you, how do people deal with their friendships and their relationships with this person, knowing that they're gonna die?
Speaker 1: And how does this person deal with their relationships with other people, knowing that they're not going to be around?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is what I really don't get, is like, if I found out, let's say I found out right now I had super crazy disease Z, and I was gonna die in a week.
Speaker 0: But, in the meantime, I mean, the girl who's sick can still walk around and do stuff.
Speaker 0: She can't do it, she's kinda in the same situation as the hepatitis kid.
Speaker 0: She can't go running around town willy-nilly, but, you know, she can walk around the hospital and talk to people, and that kind of stuff, you know.
Speaker 0: Maybe she's a little more restricted because of her crazy terminal illness, but it's not a catching plague or anything, so they don't have to lock her up in quarantine.
Speaker 0: You know, so, if I had a disease kinda like that, I knew I was gonna die, but I'm not in really immediate pain, and I can kinda go around and do stuff.
Speaker 0: I would be doing crazy stuff before I die, and not sitting in a hospital, you know, going bleh.
Speaker 1: I think the problem is that, from what I can gather, because they don't tell you much about what's going on, but I think it's some sort of congenital heart defect, or some sort of, something to do with the heart or possibly the lungs, and a large heart, it's really hard to tell.
Speaker 0: I think they're trying to be ambiguous on purpose, so that you can put any disease you want in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yet they're very realistic about it.
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, anime diseases, where the person's fine, except when they exert themselves for plot, and then they suddenly pass out magically.
Speaker 1: Like, the kid has hepatitis, and it makes sense, and it just works.
Speaker 0: I think it's actually a good choice to keep her illness sort of vague, because then the show becomes timeless.
Speaker 0: Like, if they said it was cancer, and then one day they had to cure for cancer, all of a sudden the show's kinda silly.
Speaker 0: But if they just say "disease," then you could put any disease in that spot, and the show will make sense.
Speaker 1: But I think the reason she can't leave the hospital anymore is simply that, I mean, you can tell that she is very sick, and she really can't do anything.
Speaker 1: And I think without the constant care of doctors, she would die in short order.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, I think that's pretty obvious.
Speaker 0: But, uh, another reason she probably shouldn't leave the hospital is that, if she suddenly, like, is almost dying, then they might as well do the surgery that has, like, the 1.1% chance of success or whatever.
Speaker 0: They didn't actually say 1% in the show, but...
Speaker 1: It's not like Ava, with a, you know, "0 0 0 0 0.1% chance of success, blah blah
Speaker 1: blah!".
Speaker 0: Or, like, Death Note, "I'm 5% sure you are Kira," you know?
Speaker 0: But it's like, if I had a surgery with a low chance of success, right, you wouldn't want to do it to me, you know, until the last possible minute.
Speaker 0: It just makes sense.
Speaker 1: I could see it being where the longer you wait, the lower the chances are.
Speaker 0: Oh, of course, of course.
Speaker 1: They don't really talk about it a lot, but it's a really tricky situation.
Speaker 1: And there are a lot of characters, I mean, the girl's mother is involved, and you see her, like, in the background periodically.
Speaker 1: And the show's very good at not telling you outright what's happening, but letting you find out.
Speaker 0: And each episode seems, it's actually episodic, like, each episode is about something different.
Speaker 0: And the general plot carries over, but each episode tends to be about something, you know?
Speaker 0: So, you can watch one episode and get, like, the mini-story, and then all the six mini-stories tie together into the full story.
Speaker 1: And the one thing I'd like to say is that the animation is very generic, and the show looks like your typical, you know, copy and paste random normal anime.
Speaker 1: And the characters at first might look very stereotypical and one-dimensional, but they're actually fairly well-developed, especially considering how few episodes there are.
Speaker 1: I mean, every character, the nurse and everyone, they're very distinct, and they have a lot of, I guess, character elements that don't play a big role, but they play a big role in terms of fleshing the character out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seems like the personalities of the characters come out, and, you know, they don't develop so much, except for, like, the main characters, but they're exposed in a nice way.
Speaker 1: But not in a stupid way.
Speaker 1: Like, the Doctor, there's a point at which, I mean, you really don't know what he's thinking, and no one just comes out and says what he's thinking.
Speaker 1: And you have to make a lot of guesses based on the way he's acting, and at one point, the Doctor, you run into him, and he's just, he's drinking himself into a stupor and kinda going nuts in the middle of the night, all alone.
Speaker 0: But, uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Another thing is, they don't have, the characters don't have a lot of, like, information-heavy history.
Speaker 0: Like, you don't have to know that, like, this guy has two parents and a sister, and the sister was in a war, and the dad was this and the who and the... A lot of that stuff they just don't even talk about, so you don't have to, you know, it's only six episodes, they don't have space for that stuff.
Speaker 1: So the show's very focused on the here and the now.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's very good.
Speaker 0: So, I know that, uh, our friends who are listening have seen the movie Night on Galactic Railroad, and they're probably all right now going, "Ah!
Speaker 0: Ah!".
Speaker 0: Well, if you've seen this movie, it's a really, really slow anime.
Speaker 1: It's really good if you watch it at about 4x fast-forward.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, it has a good story, it's really meaningful, if you, you know, you might not like the actual message, but the way the message is presented is very good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the way I would describe it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, you know, it has good, uh, it's just, it's like this... think of it as like the Polar Express, but for Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently it's based on a very well-known and very famous book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, the book of this movie plays a role in one of the episodes of the Half Moon show.
Speaker 1: Now, we didn't realize it right away, because they translated the title of the book a bit differently.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the DVD, the American DVD that I have, yes I have it, of Night on Galactic Railroad.
Speaker 0: That's what it says on the DVD.
Speaker 0: In the, in the, uh, anime here, the book the girl has says "Night on Milky Way Express" or something like that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it's one of those, you know, fan-subbers will translate a sign in the background or some text on the screen.
Speaker 1: It's not up there fast enough to see it, and we were too lazy to rewind and look at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not a, it's not the same translation, so it didn't catch on right away.
Speaker 0: I thought it might have been like "Galaxy Express 999" or something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then, and we didn't even think about it until the character, they start, actually there's this really neat, not really allegory, but the characters start referring to each other by the names from the story.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Uh, Giovanni and, uh...
Speaker 0: Campanella.
Speaker 1: Campanella.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, and the thing is, if you've read this story or seen this other anime that's, you know, called Night on Galactic Railroad, that has parallels to this show that, you know, it's like "Oh, it means
Speaker 0: something!".
Speaker 0: But even if you haven't seen it, they reveal what happens in the, in this other anime in this show, so you don't have to...
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much right away.
Speaker 1: I mean, we noticed the connection, and we're, and it was kind of profound, and it really gave us pause.
Speaker 1: And then five minutes later in the show, the character who didn't realize it yet figures it out on his own, and as a result, everyone in the audience now knows, whether you've read it or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically, if you already know what they're talking about, then it hits you like five minutes earlier than it hits everyone else.
Speaker 0: It's just a nice touch, I think, that they added reference to a real book, you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus the book actually fits really well with what's going on.
Speaker 0: Oh, really well, I think that's the point.
Speaker 0: Like, imagine if I wrote a story that was essentially Star Wars, and, but, it was all, I changed the whole setting and all the names of the characters and everything, but this guy was essentially Luke, and that guy was Darth Vader.
Speaker 0: And then I had a character reading, or like, watching Star Wars on DVD in the show.
Speaker 0: And then, they started referring to each other as, like, Luke and Darth, and that, and then that actually represented the story, because they were.
Speaker 0: You know, that's what it'd be like.
Speaker 1: Now, I guess in sum, I like this show a lot, and I have very high hopes for it.
Speaker 1: My final opinion's going to weigh very heavily on how the show actually ends.
Speaker 0: Once I found out that there were six episodes, my estimate for how good it's going to be, like, skyrocketed.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, the show's very heartwarming, it's very, I think it's very real, and very profound.
Speaker 1: Not profound in a change-your-life way, but profound in a give pause and think about what would you do if you were in this kind of situation.
Speaker 0: I just told you that, like, five minutes ago.
Speaker 0: I already figured it out.
Speaker 1: Well, everyone reacts to that differently.
Speaker 1: I mean, some people, I mean, the girl in the show is obviously resigned to her fate, whatever it may be.
Speaker 1: And it's more how the people around her are dealing with this.
Speaker 0: All I gotta tell you, if I know you, and you're in the hospital, and you're going to die in, like, a week, and you're not, you know, and you have the ability to come outside and live it up, and you're not doing so, I'm only going to visit you, like, once, maybe.
Speaker 0: You know, and I'll say, "Hey, you should come live it up.
Speaker 0: Sorry to see you go," et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: I'll go to your funeral, though.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: Now, we've talked about a show that we really like.
Speaker 1: Now, we're going to talk about one of the worst shows we've seen recently.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, this show is bad.
Speaker 1: Now, we didn't like Kagehime, and we went into great detail as to why we didn't like Kagehime.
Speaker 0: If you don't remember, Kagehime was the key rape show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the cute, happy, magical girl show where they rape each other horribly with keys, both physically and metaphorically.
Speaker 1: It's one of the worst things I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: I've seen worse things, but it was real bad.
Speaker 1: Now, this show is pretty much down there in terms of quality.
Speaker 0: Man, and the show was so tricky, too.
Speaker 0: Like, you didn't know right away.
Speaker 0: You had to watch a bit.
Speaker 1: All right, so tactical roar.
Speaker 1: The way it began is.
Speaker 1: it looked like it was going to be some sort of military thing.
Speaker 1: It starts with heavy military action.
Speaker 0: It looked like it was going to be a light-hearted Gundam.
Speaker 1: Yeah, our friend Katsu was laying on the floor while we were watching it, and he was basically, like, naming all the fighter jets and all the guns.
Speaker 1: And the show, at least in terms of military hardware, was somewhat realistic and based in reality, just future reality.
Speaker 0: It has appealed to military fanboys somewhat, especially if you also like, you know, girly anime-type action.
Speaker 1: Now, all right, that's cool.
Speaker 1: Then, after a few minutes, we realized something very important.
Speaker 1: The entire cast and crew up to this point is female.
Speaker 0: Hence the girly anime-type action.
Speaker 1: Like, everyone, there is not a male to be seen.
Speaker 1: There might have been one fat old, like, admiral somewhere, but other than that, it's all women.
Speaker 1: All very young women with very large breasts.
Speaker 0: Yep, every single crew member, and it's not just, like, a harem show with this one girl of each type.
Speaker 0: It's, like, a whole harem, and then a whole mess of other generic girls.
Speaker 0: Like, a giant crowd of them, literally.
Speaker 1: So, at this point, we've decided, all right, this show is crap, but whatever, let's keep watching.
Speaker 0: We watched it for about five more minutes.
Speaker 0: You didn't watch the whole thing, did we?
Speaker 1: We watched much of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we watched, like, 80% of the episode, and then fast-forwarded through the rest.
Speaker 1: So, it doesn't go in the direction you'd think.
Speaker 1: They do introduce one male character, so it is essentially a harem show.
Speaker 1: However, it's a yuri show, as far as we can tell, because, I mean, there's this one girl who appears, and she's, like, older-looking than all the rest, and they give you the impression that she has had sexual relations with every single other female character in this show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like a girl, you know, there's a normal sort of, like, woman, and she's talking to the guy character, and this girl comes up and is like, "Oh, why are you talking to
Speaker 0: him?".
Speaker 0: And then, like, a million start showing up, like, vying for her attention and stuff, and it's like,
Speaker 0: "Okay.".
Speaker 1: Then she appears later, covered in lipstick from various colors over various parts of her body.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And, again, I'll mention that every single non-male breast in this show is gigantic.
Speaker 0: It bounces, it's exposed, it's zoomed in, you got all the typical things falling on top of men, accidental extra cleavage, upskirt action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically infinite sea of panty shots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all the moe and yuri that you could ask for.
Speaker 1: This show, basically, I didn't see any redeeming qualities.
Speaker 0: At all.
Speaker 0: I saw one redeeming quality in the show.
Speaker 0: It's the only show that I've seen that combines military fanboy and perverted fanboy into one.
Speaker 1: I'll bet there are shows out there.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there are, but this is the only one that comes that I've ever seen at all.
Speaker 1: I mean, at least Kagehime had a cute opener.
Speaker 0: It did have a cute opener.
Speaker 1: This show has nothing.
Speaker 1: This show is just horrible.
Speaker 0: The animation had lots of bright colors.
Speaker 1: That seems to be the hallmark of bad shows these days.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, I like bright colors.
Speaker 0: I wish that there would be good shows with bright colors.
Speaker 0: Razifon was a good show with bright colors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Utena was good, but that was definitely all pastels.
Speaker 0: I'm talking more about the...
Speaker 1: Actually, Half Moon is very bright and well-defined.
Speaker 0: Part of it.
Speaker 0: It's in the hospital, I think, so it keeps a lot of the colors down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but whenever they go outside, it really shines.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: Anyone else can think of good shows with bright colors?
Speaker 0: Eva sometimes has bright colors, but it seems to be very industrial, so it's not... You know, the penciling isn't the same bright happiness.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus Eva was done old school.
Speaker 1: I mean, Eva's kinda old.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Azumanga Daioh has bright colors.
Speaker 0: Haha!
Speaker 1: And Azumanga Daioh is one of my favorite shows ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: Didn't even mention it in Favorites Week.
Speaker 0: No, no, we didn't.
Speaker 0: We'll have to mention... Maybe it'll make manga week.
Speaker 0: It's actually, I think the manga is...
Speaker 1: I don't know, because in manga, it's competing with Yotsubato.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think Yotsuba might win, but it's the same thing by the same guy.
Speaker 0: As far as I'm concerned, Yotsuba 1 is like Azumanga Daioh 5.
Speaker 0: Only, yeah, I think Yotsuba's better.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: It's all good.
Speaker 1: So in sum...
Speaker 0: This anime was so bad, we couldn't even talk about it anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, we stopped watching it.
Speaker 1: We watched Kagehime Episode 1 all the way through.
Speaker 1: In fact, we watched it a couple times because we showed it to other people who didn't believe us when we told them what was in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had to demonstrate what key rape was to them.
Speaker 1: 'Cause they... I remember Pete was sitting there saying, "Alright, you guys are obviously... This is gonna be like that naked car thing, and it's actually something
Speaker 1: else.".
Speaker 1: Now...
Speaker 0: Naked car is actually naked car, so I don't know what he's talking about.
Speaker 1: But anyway, Half Moon is a very good show, and it's only six episodes.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend all of you out there.
Speaker 1: watch it.
Speaker 1: It's well worth seeing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a torrent right now to get all six episodes at once.
Speaker 0: I'm getting it because we don't have the sixth episode, and I can't get the sixth episode on its own, so I'm getting this one through six torrent.
Speaker 1: I mean, don't drop anything.
Speaker 1: If you're in the middle of watching Cowboy Bebop, don't drop that to watch the show.
Speaker 1: But if you want anime... Hold on to the show and watch it someday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you want anime to watch, watch this.
Speaker 0: And I'm sure someday this whole thing will be released on a single DVD.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could definitely say that'll happen.
Speaker 0: Probably be like a $25 DVD.
Speaker 0: Six episodes.
Speaker 1: And of course, we're gonna talk about it one more time after we see how it ends in one of our final thoughts episodes.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Which we try to do few and far between, because we know that once we start talking about a show in that regard, you really can't listen to Geek Nights anymore, at least for that episode, because we'll just be spoiling the hell out of the show if you haven't seen it.
Speaker 0: Well, you can listen to the news and the thing of the day and then turn Geek Nights off or...
Speaker 1: The one thing about Geek Nights, we will always warn well ahead of time if we're gonna spoil things.
Speaker 1: Like, repeatedly and loudly.
Speaker 0: You know what happens at the end of, uh... Blah blah blah blah?
Speaker 1: Uh, blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Everyone dies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so at the end of, uh, Tactical Roar, I assume everyone dies.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Uh, that, that, fuck, that, that freakin' show.
Speaker 0: You know what, in Tactical Roar, that guy comes very, very close to fulfilling his multi-woman, lesbian, multi-way fantasy.
Speaker 1: No, because they're all lesbians!
Speaker 0: But he never quite makes it all the way.
Speaker 0: That's what the show's about.
Speaker 0: It's just about teasing to the edge.
Speaker 1: See, now normally if a show's bad, like Kagehime, we said, "Hey, watch it, because this is so bad it's hilarious.
Speaker 1: And
Speaker 1: horrible.".
Speaker 1: Don't even bother watching Tactical Roar.
Speaker 1: It's so bad, it's not even funny bad.
Speaker 1: Like, you won't sit there going, "Haha, this is
Speaker 1: terrible.".
Speaker 1: You'll just sit there in disgust.
Speaker 0: Unless, of course, you really, really, really like military fanboyism.
Speaker 0: Or, unless you really, really, really like up skirts and panty shots.
Speaker 1: If any of you out there actually like Tactical Roar, we have to have some words.
Speaker 0: Yeah, is there anyone out there who actually likes, like, T&A, like, sort of porny but not hentai anime?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not talking, like, Ghost in the Shell or anything like that.
Speaker 0: We're talking like-- Yeah, where the girls happen to be hot.
Speaker 1: Like magical booby fighter ex-something.
Speaker 0: We're talking, like, Burn Up with the, uh, or what's the other show?
Speaker 0: Dirty Pear.
Speaker 0: If you like Dirty Pear, tell us why in our forum.
Speaker 1: Dirty Pear's not that bad.
Speaker 0: It's not, there's actually some show in Dirty Pear, but there's also the Jiggle Meter.
Speaker 1: Alright, you know what?
Speaker 1: Tactical Roar.
Speaker 1: If you like Tactical Roar, I think we can unabashedly say we probably hate you.
Speaker 0: Yep, could be.
Speaker 1: And that was Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com.
Speaker 0: And if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights airs every weeknight, Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other talk shows, it's actually recorded at night.