Speaker 0: It's Thursday July 6th, and this is geek nights tonight oddly enough.
Speaker 0: We talk about dentistry orthodontics and teeth.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know for the first time in my life probably ever I I was given a day off from work that I wasn't sure I wanted.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that happens.
Speaker 0: it was because for those of you were paying attention I was here on Monday while everyone else was still at the beach and the boardwalk even though I didn't actually go to the boardwalk that day, but that's beside the point.
Speaker 0: and That was because my work made me come in on Monday But then I had Tuesday off to make up for the fact that that kind of sucked.
Speaker 0: I got Friday off now tomorrow, which is great, but I don't have anything in particular to do on a day off now.
Speaker 0: I took care of it all on the 4th of July.
Speaker 1: Why don't you do all that shit that oh you took care of it on the 4th of July?
Speaker 0: The only thing I could do is get a haircut, but I decided against getting a haircut.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna see how long I can grow my hair.
Speaker 1: That's scary.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's reaching the bottom like it's gonna hit the small of my back within another month or two.
Speaker 1: I think you should go get a haircut.
Speaker 0: Well what I'm gonna Do is I'm gonna talk to some stylists and learn how to make it look good now that it's really really long Because now I'm just tying it back like I've done because I mean women Have a million ways you can deal with long hair.
Speaker 0: do all these cool things.
Speaker 0: as a guy in the Western world I have basically like two options I can tie it back or I can let it not be tied back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you tried to make any other sort of haircut with it.
Speaker 1: It would be a woman's haircut now.
Speaker 0: There are male Styles.
Speaker 1: I mean just pushing it over the front of your shoulders is womanly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though I actually wear it like that fairly often.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and actually a lot of times if it's really if I'll wear it with like a tail like a ponytail But it's kind of hanging from the side And it's I don't get to post a picture of it or something.
Speaker 0: But I've seen styles that look good that aren't like that.
Speaker 0: I can't recreate them for the life of me.
Speaker 0: I have trouble dealing with my hair.
Speaker 1: I don't know why I think we're gonna have to go to someplace in the city.
Speaker 1: That's expensive.
Speaker 0: See that's what I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: Do I'm gonna go somewhere and be like all right?
Speaker 0: How do I deal with my hair and make it look awesome all the time?
Speaker 0: They'll say $300 please and I'll say sure cuz I got a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I've blown you what you'll spend $300 in a haircut But you won't buy a new freaking computer.
Speaker 0: I'd realize it's shopping.
Speaker 0: Remember how I said you can build a badass computer for less than 600 bucks.
Speaker 0: You can build a badass computer for less than 400 bucks now.
Speaker 0: Yeah a good God I'm gonna buy a computer real soon all right.
Speaker 0: I mean the thing is every like.
Speaker 0: last week I made a computer on new egg, and it was badass.
Speaker 0: It was like 480 bucks.
Speaker 0: this week I made the same computer.
Speaker 0: It was $440.
Speaker 0: hard drive got cheaper, so I'm gonna hold out until that levels off a little bit.
Speaker 1: It's gonna boost back up right cuz this new egg specials.
Speaker 1: That's why you gotta buy it now.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is those things weren't new egg specials, but now I'm watching the new egg specials.
Speaker 1: And if the moment I remember I designed a computer And it came out wicked cheap because they were like four new egg special items And then as soon as those disappeared the computer like increased in price a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: anyway Also, I'd like to give a nod and this is the benefit of going four nights a week is that we can respond Immediately when anything happens in the world.
Speaker 0: Now way back we mentioned that we sent some feedback to anime world order and just now They responded they did their episode and they cut out the part where they talk about our feedback and made a separate link for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they seem to whenever they do something incredibly long in their episode.
Speaker 1: They cut it out and make a separate mp3 of it and That's what they did with their response to our audio feedback.
Speaker 0: now one I like that and I think where I'm going to do that for like our how computers work series I'm gonna cut it out from the news and the things of the day and make it just a separate thing mmm, but anyway First off I love their feedback relinked to it.
Speaker 0: I suggest everyone listen to it because I was very happy with it.
Speaker 1: It was incredibly entertaining and humorous.
Speaker 0: Yes, cuz I will say now in the interest of full disclosure that About 20% of the things we said in the feedback were very specifically crafted to elicit anger And we were curious how they would react and they reacted awesomely
Speaker 1: uh-huh,
Speaker 0: and also I have one tiny clarification because He was paraphrasing me in the email, which is great because I wrote a frickin long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's one thing is that a lot of the things they said we had already rebutted in email But then they didn't always go to the email to get the rebuttal.
Speaker 1: I think we really need to arrange like a final showdown on Skype and do a cross podcast Thing.
Speaker 0: to finish this off now if we can't arrange that we're gonna have all of our equipment at Otacon and we'll do it And maybe depending on the panel we might be able to do some sort of live adversarial things.
Speaker 0: The panel is gonna be huge.
Speaker 0: All right, but that's all beside the poll.
Speaker 1: Hopefully it'll be huge.
Speaker 0: the one one part It could be just one guy showing up But we're so glad you guys responded in the way you did.
Speaker 0: you said a lot of interesting things.
Speaker 0: The guy Chris was his name who you had up there.
Speaker 0: He gets a million points for knowing what the hell big fire is.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's still around but as of five years ago, it was still going strong at Ohio con.
Speaker 1: I don't even know if that was technically a big fire But I think it was.
Speaker 0: it called itself big fire and the dude who told us about big fire Told us about it at that con and then disappeared knowingly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we'll see.
Speaker 0: if you know, who knows but I gotta say I want we're gonna talk more about this on the anime episode.
Speaker 0: But I had no idea that your cons in Florida don't have the after parties and I'm really sorry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems like a lot of the things are as you said we like something and you don't like it or it sucks for you in Florida or You just suck.
Speaker 1: So All the all the arguments that end in one of those three things I think we can eliminate but there are some leftovers that require further discussion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but seriously That your descriptions.
Speaker 0: I've been to party is like the ones you described.
Speaker 0: and yeah Yeah, the the part the good parties You just got to meet the people and find the cool people who will run them and know before you say Oh, don't be shit talkers.
Speaker 0: We don't run them anymore.
Speaker 0: We don't have time for that.
Speaker 0: No, though if you guys want to do something at Otacon We could lend the full backing of the front row crew and we have run some pretty badass parties in our day.
Speaker 1: I think we should start doing something like making the podcast party at every anime con where there are no enough podcast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, we've got that third hotel room.
Speaker 1: We do we can.
Speaker 1: it's not big enough for a real party though.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends.
Speaker 0: we could keep it for one night.
Speaker 1: Next you gotta get the Berkshire Suites if we want to do the party.
Speaker 0: Yeah No, maybe next year because now we have money we have to worry about it.
Speaker 0: We'll just get that giant penthouse suite and do something crazy.
Speaker 0: Yep, I think we will but I think we'll have some sort of minor on advertised party with all the podcasters.
Speaker 1: That would definitely be cool.
Speaker 0: Yep, because I mean what we disagree with you guys a lot, but you guys are still awesome.
Speaker 0: I can't stress that enough.
Speaker 0: Don't think that we're trying to?
Speaker 0: well, we are trying to piss you off, but that's a whole different issue.
Speaker 1: It's really fun for us to do that because we can't be pissed off.
Speaker 0: and yeah, yeah, it's kind of a hobby We're.
Speaker 0: sometimes we troll in the real real world just for fun.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep and to make a point.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we'll talk about that more on Tuesday, Wednesday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait, I keep.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I say Tuesday when I mean Wednesday all the time and Tuesday We're talking about some sort of game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what game I don't know either.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we got some news.
Speaker 1: Okay, I'll do my news first.
Speaker 0: All right, we actually had a lot of news for one So we had to pare it down to two stories.
Speaker 1: yeah, so there's been a lot of talk over the years of Microsoft trying to kill the iPod with some other device or Kill the iTunes music store with some service or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: We've talked in the past greatly about Microsoft's ventures into making hardware devices and the tricks they use and how many of those devices never actually see the light of day.
Speaker 0: now Microsoft now finally has something that just might work somehow and Scott's news is the one of the big reasons why it might work.
Speaker 1: now What they're gonna do is if you use the Microsoft music store thing.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the problem.
Speaker 1: Is that if you use the iTunes music store?
Speaker 1: You can only play those songs with iTunes or with your iPod and nothing else.
Speaker 0: I mean as cool as Apple is.
Speaker 0: they very much use DRM to lock customers in Which is a tactic that geeks around the world to cry Microsoft for yeah It's like DRM is a is really meant to keep you from pirating music that you digital music that you paid for.
Speaker 1: But the Apple DRM also the reason that Apple goes along with it is because they use it to keep you using Apple products And nothing else.
Speaker 1: Microsoft has another DRM scheme I think it's called plays for sure and Apples is called fairplay and plays for sure.
Speaker 1: work is you know, if you make devices you can make a plays for sure device.
Speaker 1: you just give Microsoft some money.
Speaker 1: I think and You know, there are a lot of plays for sure players and plays for sure, you know softwares and all sorts of things.
Speaker 1: There's only one fair play player and that's the iPod.
Speaker 1: So it's really hard to compete when people are using, you know the iTunes music store to try to sell songs that are plays for sure and Yeah, so and it's also hard to sell players that aren't iPods because people who buy things in the iTunes music store pretty much Have to use an iPod.
Speaker 1: the next Microsoft music buying thing, whatever they want to call it What they're gonna do is when you install that it's gonna look at your iTunes and it's gonna see what songs you've bought and give You those songs for free.
Speaker 0: Yes and it's really to the point where Microsoft is going to pay to have these songs licensed through their method and give them to pocket.
Speaker 1: basically Apple is.
Speaker 1: you're now going to be able to buy something on iTunes Then go to the other program get it for free because you just bought it an iTunes music store But and then put it on your plays for sure player instead of your iPod, but
Speaker 0: it doesn't violate any sort of terms of service or DRM or anything because they're not cracking Apple stuff.
Speaker 0: They're just giving you the same song from their system.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's in my eyes.
Speaker 0: I mean this is gonna sound strange But despite the fact that I'd really dislike Vista and a lot of things Microsoft does in the last year I have really gained a lot of respect as Microsoft is really.
Speaker 0: they're not stupid They don't.
Speaker 0: they realize that if they continued on their previous, I mean, they're putting open document in word now I think they realize if they continued on their previous track of evil evil evil.
Speaker 0: They really were gonna be destroyed and they're not stupid people.
Speaker 0: They know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: This is a brilliant brilliant idea that I never would have thought of.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like, you know It's really hard to crack apples DRM, you know, we cracked it once but since then the only real way to crack it is to burn a CD and then rip the CD and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: so, you know, finally we found a legitimate kind of way not to crack the DRM, but to you know get the songs that you paid for in some other format and This may or may not put a hurting to Apple.
Speaker 1: if people decide, you know How many people out there really don't want iPods but you know buy them because they use the iTunes music store.
Speaker 1: now Those people might be able to be set free if Microsoft can inform them and grab them Especially since non iPod mp3 players cost a fraction of what iPods cost.
Speaker 1: Well at the lower level yeah at the high space echelon where you know The iPods even if you just consider them as mp3 players they are high-level mp3 players.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's ever the shuffle and the shuffle really, you know doesn't Compare with things like the little cube thing and the SanDisk players and the Samsung players Yeah,
Speaker 0: but I mean the at the load like the nano 2 gig is very high quality But you can get two and four gig players for like a hundred dollars less
Speaker 1: more like $50 less
Speaker 0: Found some for $100 less.
Speaker 1: it's tough because some of those don't have all the same feet.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, they don't.
Speaker 0: one of them was actually an iPod nano bootleg.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was straight up a bootleg I thought about buying.
Speaker 1: like some of them don't have the color screen Some of them don't do all the other things.
Speaker 1: the nano does like show pictures and you know There are other things that make the comparison a little wonky.
Speaker 0: But I'm not saying that there's no reason to get iPods because one I got an iPod and two iPods have a lot of slick Stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other thing is that you know, of course no matter what players software combination You're using for podcasting iTunes iPod is the easiest Best way to do it with the least effort and the most slickness.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean for all the trouble we've had with other Mac things iTunes just works.
Speaker 0: It just works real well.
Speaker 0: Yep Okay All right now my news actually is very related to this in that and this actually came up when I worked for the IT department at the Rochester Institute of Technology the the the group that you know supports the network and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: What happened is that?
Speaker 0: RIT was considering purchasing from you know some outside entity access to a commercial mp3 or mute music download software service for the students and providing it to them for free and a Lot of universities have been doing this in order to one stave off RIAA lawsuits And in fact in many cases, it's been shown that the RIAA was behind closed doors Subsidizing and funding these things to try to get kids hooked.
Speaker 0: The idea is that if you give kids like the new Napster or all those things for free while they're in college One maybe they won't pirate things.
Speaker 0: That's removing liability from the school and two maybe when they leave they'll keep paying for these things.
Speaker 0: The news that has come out as these things have been implemented is that almost no one uses them now.
Speaker 1: Gee, I wonder why BitTorrent now?
Speaker 0: I find this interesting in that it proves a very valid and important point when it comes to buying online music.
Speaker 0: the only exception is So far iTunes and even the iTunes music store wall.
Speaker 0: I mean it's doing very well but it's not even putting a dent in illegal downloading.
Speaker 0: consider this the student now has a choice between free and free.
Speaker 0: the competition is between two free things one of which is Illegal and could put you in jail or jail but could cost you a lot of money.
Speaker 0: It could put you in jail depending on how you go about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah But it's most likely just going to cost you a lot of money if you get caught which is like a one in something chance According to that insurance company.
Speaker 0: Yeah But and the other system is a system that normally people pay for.
Speaker 0: now you'd think the system people pay for would work better But these systems with their DRM.
Speaker 0: it's at the point where even if these systems are free It's still more convenient and better to use the illegal bootleg pirate shady way and take the risk.
Speaker 0: So in that case what who do these companies expect to pay them?
Speaker 0: I mean iTunes is doing very well But all these other services are just crap.
Speaker 0: and yet the RIAA is bullying colleges Into paying for these services for their students even though the students don't want them in order to stave off lawsuits.
Speaker 0: and it's really it's.
Speaker 1: they're going around to colleges and Threatening them and then taking money from them.
Speaker 0: It's you know black a shame if something happened to your school here.
Speaker 1: Eh, it's almost blackmail.
Speaker 1: it's like they go to a school and they say give us money or else and the school gives them money and Then they get.
Speaker 1: they say here.
Speaker 1: Here's what you got for your money and then no one there uses it.
Speaker 1: now It's like if I come to your house with a vacuum cleaner and I say hey Did you steal any vacuum cleaners lately?
Speaker 1: I might report you to the police here.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna sell you this crap-ass shit vacuum cleaner that you'll never use and you're gonna take it or else I'm gonna call the cops on you.
Speaker 1: So the guy goes fine gives me ten bucks takes the shit-ass vacuum cleaner throws it out.
Speaker 1: And you know, you can't go to someone's house threaten them for money or force them to buy something from you.
Speaker 0: Well, you can.
Speaker 0: it's called racketeering and it's a. it's a very Profitable business.
Speaker 1: It's a very legal business.
Speaker 1: They're using illegal business to stop illegal business.
Speaker 1: You can't do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now because it's not even stopping illegal business it's just illegal business.
Speaker 0: the really telling thing that and this is just a complete aside and I got to be kind of vague because The the thing I'm about to talk about was in fact a closed-door discussion that I was involved in at RIT.
Speaker 0: At RIT that they have issues with you know, social problems, but when it comes to technology, they know what they're doing.
Speaker 1: Everyone at the school knows that they're doing.
Speaker 0: if you walked into the quarter mile and yelled I need help with Ubuntu 100 people would walk over there.
Speaker 0: a hundred people there maybe ten guys Yeah, and half of them would say now you should use Debbie in and now you should use Susie now And then they'd start an argument about kernels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and now when it comes technology, they're smart.
Speaker 0: They're the premier IT school.
Speaker 0: They were the first college to have an information technology program.
Speaker 0: They were the first ones to get it accredited.
Speaker 0: They basically wrote the accreditation process for information technology.
Speaker 1: at least they say they did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's a lot of merit to that.
Speaker 0: and when regards to computer science, they're very well recognized that they know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: So when the RIA approached RIT about all this and they were considering buying one of these services we had a closed-doors meeting of the staff of the IT group and the higher-ups of the IT group and Someone from the from the great high up beyond pre told this to us No, here's what we're thinking of doing.
Speaker 0: What do you think?
Speaker 0: and then at the end they asked?
Speaker 0: All right, nothing we say leaves this room, which I I'm not gonna give name names or anything.
Speaker 0: what are your honest opinions?
Speaker 0: because we know you all download and Unanimously all of these technology professionals said this is a stupid idea.
Speaker 0: This is racketeering.
Speaker 0: no one will go for it.
Speaker 0: the students will probably pirate more just to spite you.
Speaker 0: and RIT listen to all of us and as far as I know still hasn't bowed down to the pressure Despite the fact that RIT has been implicated numerous times in massive massive international piracy rings.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean the FBI came.
Speaker 1: there were kids who got like busted like you had customs officers coming and taking them away.
Speaker 0: That was a drink or die.
Speaker 1: I believe it might have been drink or die.
Speaker 0: was an International where's ring.
Speaker 0: that was shut the fuck down and the FBI and customs agents came and arrested kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was crazy.
Speaker 0: That is the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: that is the thing of the day All right.
Speaker 0: I found this kind of randomly All right, I guess there's an aside.
Speaker 0: if you haven't seen the movie snatch Yeah one fuck you to go see it immediately like the answer to the question that is this stone.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I found this kind of randomly.
Speaker 0: I didn't see anything better and I thought it was cute and cool.
Speaker 0: So it's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: For some reason.
Speaker 0: there's this crow and he's standing around in the grass protein robot.
Speaker 0: No, no There's black crow like raven kind of thing a black bird sitting there.
Speaker 0: and then there's this bunny rabbit and he's just sitting there And this rabbit doesn't seem to like this crow.
Speaker 0: So he rushes it and he attacks it.
Speaker 0: the crow goes Shit and backs like flies away and then lands right back down and then the rabbit attacks it again and the crow flies up and flies back down and it's just this Rabbit chasing after this crow and this crow running away, but he won't fully run away.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there was something around the crow Why might have been something they both wanted to eat.
Speaker 1: but then they're not animals that eat each other or can really fight now And they're not animals that eat the same things.
Speaker 0: No, what do you think?
Speaker 0: rabbits eat vegetables?
Speaker 0: What do you think crows eat?
Speaker 1: They might eat a vegetable they usually harass like, you know gardens or corn and shit.
Speaker 0: crows don't eat grass.
Speaker 1: No, they don't eat grass.
Speaker 1: But you know remember on Winnie the Pooh The rabbit guy would always have the crows in his garden eating his vegetables because the rabbit has a garden.
Speaker 1: There you go rabbit versus a crow.
Speaker 1: The thing is Winnie the Pooh.
Speaker 0: it's like this clean grass field and This rabbit and this crow are just kind of fighting.
Speaker 0: and then finally this other crow comes and the rabbits like oh crap and he runs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was just a weird video and you know make it really makes you think about different combinations of animals Like you never see together.
Speaker 1: Like have you ever seen like a monkey encounter a midget shark?
Speaker 0: I Really want to see a monkey encounter a shark Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or like a monkey versus an octopus or a snake Versus a.
Speaker 0: what you take a monkey you give him a knife you throw him in a cage with like a lion and a midget.
Speaker 1: Or like a snake versus an eagle or something like that.
Speaker 0: We saw a scorpion versus a much larger scorpion than Jarhead.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 0: I don't know why that guy bet on the really tiny scorpion.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think it's cuz.
Speaker 1: it was his scorpion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he was.
Speaker 1: he was really dumb.
Speaker 0: He was crying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Wish there were more scorpion fights in that movie.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: you're in the shower with the cricket.
Speaker 0: I was about to say the cricket fights in the shower.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's another movie.
Speaker 0: Everyone should see the show.
Speaker 0: In fact, there's a bunch of people who have asked to be added to my friends list on Netflix And I haven't added you because I'm lazy and I forgot I'll get to it as soon as I do and then immediately add the shower to your list and then watch it.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, Scott has also got an animal related thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Well, you see there's this.
Speaker 1: It's a video from the bottom of the sea.
Speaker 1: There's a hole in the bottom of the sea.
Speaker 0: It lives in a pineapple under the sea.
Speaker 1: No, that one's no good.
Speaker 0: I hate spongebob so much anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there's um, so at the bottom of the sea This is like this spongy coral mass and you're looking at it and then all of a sudden it's an octopus.
Speaker 1: Ooh It's all chameleon, but not just like a chameleon that's.
Speaker 1: you know, you've seen chameleons before.
Speaker 1: they're pretty good at Matching their surroundings by changing the colors and patterns on their skin, but they're not perfect.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're just kind of they get close.
Speaker 1: this octopus is like goddamn.
Speaker 1: They need to get some like military equivalents.
Speaker 1: It's like the freaking predator to this octopus the predator like seriously ghost in the shell action with the Invisibleness.
Speaker 1: You just got to see this.
Speaker 1: It's cool because in the video they show you the octopus appearing and then they show it in reverse so you can see the octopus Disappearing in slow motion backwards and it's way cool and I kind of want to be the octopus.
Speaker 0: That wouldn't be too bad a life.
Speaker 1: now you sit around the bottom of the sea got eight legs.
Speaker 1: You can camouflage with anything.
Speaker 0: I got a girl.
Speaker 0: There's got eight arms.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyone remember that?
Speaker 0: anyone out there?
Speaker 1: I think I know I'm getting an octopus of love.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the band was called.
Speaker 1: Oh God for this thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that me multimedia pack that came with like every multimedia computer back when 2x CD-roms appeared.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it was a music video of this band.
Speaker 0: and they have this music video to a song called octopus of love.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was just reminded of it which brought back a flurry of dark times and pre-internet.
Speaker 1: I'm reminded of all my OS to multimedia.
Speaker 1: miss things I had on my 486 and the the icon that said information superhighway that never worked because they didn't plug in my modem.
Speaker 0: remember the days when if you like you saw an animated thing or a Video like you sit there just amazed like holy shit.
Speaker 0: You'd show people.
Speaker 0: check it out.
Speaker 0: My computer made a beep.
Speaker 0: Wasn't that awesome?
Speaker 0: remember Microsoft Encarta, oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was the one I remember.
Speaker 1: you could watch a piece of Star Wars with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tiniest as little piece.
Speaker 1: Yep Anyway in real low resolution in a little tiny box.
Speaker 0: So our topic today if you listen to the beginning of the show, it's quite obvious is dentistry and teeth.
Speaker 0: Now you might wonder why we would talk about something like that.
Speaker 1: Well, it's for quite simple.
Speaker 1: you see it's I got back late And we couldn't think of something to talk about.
Speaker 1: and the reason I got back late is because today I went to the dentist Which is my uncle the dentist and then I went home and then I came here.
Speaker 0: now independently of that I got a call today Reminding me that I had a dentist appointment on Saturday, which I'd forgotten about because scheduled it like five months ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we will talk about dentisting.
Speaker 0: I had to cancel that appointment because obviously we're going to Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Yep, so, all right, I want to start with childhood.
Speaker 0: you want to start with our current dentisting.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should talk about some general dentisting like brush your fucking teeth.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: All right real briefly Yeah, brush your teeth Bloss if you have bad breath, there's something wrong.
Speaker 1: If you ever read breath brush your tongue You're.
Speaker 1: the bad breath is caused by bacteria that builds up in your mouth and release nasty smells after eating the food in your mouth.
Speaker 1: So you need to get rid of all of them which means brushing your tongue to get rid of all as more bacterias There's a it bacteria get on your tongue.
Speaker 1: They just go.
Speaker 0: Yep, also Surprisingly flossing your back two teeth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's like a huge bastion of nasty floss everything.
Speaker 0: I mentioned this mostly because there's a guy at my work who awesome guy But good God will his breath kill a fly at a hundred yards.
Speaker 1: And if your breath is still bad after brushing twice a day and Brushing your tongue and flossing once a day but floss before you brush by the way You floss and then immediately brush.
Speaker 0: actually I brush lost and then I do a real quick brush.
Speaker 1: The dentist actually told me today to floss and then immediately brush.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's what the dentist says.
Speaker 0: so because otherwise your your floss all the gunk out and then you leave it in your mouth.
Speaker 1: exactly You need to brush it away.
Speaker 1: Um Yeah, if that still doesn't eliminate bad breath get yourself some Mouthwash, no, no the greatest.
Speaker 0: get yourself to a dentist or a periodontist and tell Evan look at you Cuz there's something wrong there might be something wrong or you just might need some mints.
Speaker 1: cuz you're you know.
Speaker 0: Well, I can say that I do know that mouthwash is mostly BS.
Speaker 1: It is mostly.
Speaker 0: it is it is Hit.
Speaker 1: yeah mouthwash doesn't do a lot of the things it says it does but it will make your breath nice.
Speaker 0: To me whenever someone uses mouthwash for a long time their mouth just smells like mouthwash.
Speaker 0: So I know huh?
Speaker 0: They must have had a problem.
Speaker 1: Remember those are doing something about.
Speaker 0: remember at Ohio con when what's-her-name gave us those mouthwash strips.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, those things.
Speaker 0: but that was like putting a Clorox wipe on my tongue.
Speaker 0: They're real strong and painful and it served no purpose.
Speaker 0: My mouth tasted like Clorox.
Speaker 1: for like the next day go with an Altoid That works.
Speaker 1: Altoids work.
Speaker 1: double mint gum freakin works.
Speaker 1: gum actually works real well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, in fact gum has a lot of beneficial properties.
Speaker 0: if you chew it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean saliva does a lot to clean your teeth a lot.
Speaker 0: also the action of the gum and actually if you have Minor amounts of heartburn or indigestion chewing gum.
Speaker 0: Well mostly indigestion more so than heartburn.
Speaker 0: chewing gum can help because it stimulates the production of saliva and it stimulates the production of acid In the stomach.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm So you can because your body thinks you're chewing when you're really not.
Speaker 1: it's kind of the same reason that diet soda is bad.
Speaker 1: Because you drink diet soda your body thinks the calories are coming in and they're not and then you get hungry and you actually end up Eating more.
Speaker 1: Yep, but yeah chewing gum is great as long as it's not, you know Sugary candy gum which will not do anything good now unless you chew it until it loses all flavor.
Speaker 0: Yep, Scott and I use very different toothpastes.
Speaker 1: I use aqua fresh because it tastes good.
Speaker 0: I use any baking soda and peroxide toothpaste.
Speaker 0: I don't care what brand because it tastes good.
Speaker 1: yep, I actually asked the dentist today because Basically, I'm sitting there and they're like we recommend Colgate total and I'm like what.
Speaker 1: how much do they pay you to say that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're like.
Speaker 1: actually they didn't pay him to say that.
Speaker 1: the deal is is that the regular toothpaste pretty much is as good As any other regular toothpaste.
Speaker 0: don't use that whitening toothpaste.
Speaker 1: That's yeah.
Speaker 1: Most of that is just BS Toothpaste is toothpaste.
Speaker 1: it sir.
Speaker 1: It really doesn't do much.
Speaker 1: most of the brushing and cleaning is the brushing itself though The toothpaste just makes it taste good.
Speaker 0: Yep, though it also like if you have bad breath things like peroxide will kill bacteria.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they will.
Speaker 1: but actually the baking soda and peroxide is you know, it's okay.
Speaker 1: But then you know it fizzes and it's kind of nasty.
Speaker 0: and I like it.
Speaker 0: I really like the taste whatever Apparently the Colgate total.
Speaker 1: now the reason they recommend it is because it has some bacteria killing action.
Speaker 1: That's you know as good as if not better than the baking soda peroxide not the baking soda peroxide.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll switch it up.
Speaker 1: I got I got a little free sample.
Speaker 1: So we'll test it out.
Speaker 0: I'll try some.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean, I'm not gonna run out and buy a toothpaste because it was dentist recommended.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think I have a whole tube of acafresh.
Speaker 1: There's no way I'm buying new toothpaste until that's done.
Speaker 1: but You know if the Colgate total doesn't taste horrendous and I notice Cleanlier teeth.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know while I switch it up I've used baking soda and peroxide toothpaste for the last decade.
Speaker 0: So if so what I like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if there are any things living in my mouth that have developed immunity to it.
Speaker 0: this total whatever is gonna fuck him up.
Speaker 1: I'll gotta go read the little package.
Speaker 1: I got it in the other room.
Speaker 1: All right, we'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and oh as for floss, I personally recommend the oral B satin floss.
Speaker 1: It's more expensive But I'm not we weren't paid to say this.
Speaker 1: This is really my favorite floss.
Speaker 1: This isn't some joke He's not kidding.
Speaker 0: He got mad at me when I use some of it.
Speaker 1: once did I?
Speaker 0: you were like you used my floss.
Speaker 0: I was like, yeah, and you said pay me and I gave you a penny.
Speaker 1: I Remember that but okay, I was in colony.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway my that might have been me rapport.
Speaker 0: So yeah Yeah, cuz I ran out of floss.
Speaker 1: It's it's a slightly more expensive floss than you know normal floss But it slides on the teeth nicely, you know, it won't.
Speaker 1: it's not that unwaxed floss.
Speaker 1: Just uh so hard to get it between the teeth and it hurts and I'm indifferent.
Speaker 0: I use whatever floss I got now and also the satin floss.
Speaker 1: it, you know, not only does it feel really good But it's all minty and fresh and and it it's really sturdy and it can really scrape the teeth.
Speaker 0: really nice Yeah, I got to say one time because I got it's gone now.
Speaker 0: But I had a filling and the filling had a tiny sharp edge that eventually wore down.
Speaker 0: But at one point I was flossing back there and the floss was cut by this and broke.
Speaker 0: So now I had a piece of floss stuck between two teeth.
Speaker 0: There was almost no way to get it out.
Speaker 0: What was I gonna do?
Speaker 0: floss?
Speaker 0: I would have just that that did just push it in further.
Speaker 0: I just waited and eventually My body must have not liked it there and it slowly worked its way out.
Speaker 0: and like three days later I saw it and I grabbed it and ripped it out.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm just like I got teeth pains right now Thinking about unwaxed floss.
Speaker 1: Nah All right.
Speaker 0: All right now in terms of tooth health my teeth like my teeth are very good.
Speaker 0: They're very strong.
Speaker 0: My dentist always says that you know, everything's great, but I do have a lot of fillings mostly from my younger days.
Speaker 1: I have two fillings.
Speaker 1: My first one I got when I was 21 and the other one I think I got in 2003 or 4. so that was like a couple years ago and I had and I just went to the dentist today and X-rays, I'm fine.
Speaker 1: I didn't get any more cavities.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: What kind of fillings are they?
Speaker 1: Actually the way the kind of fillings these are they're not gold sadly.
Speaker 1: What they are is they first they drill a hole they drill out the cab.
Speaker 0: Because I read a Wikipedia a few days ago because I was I just happen to be bored and I know all about all the different Kinds.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: They put in this sort of goop.
Speaker 1: It's like a clay Ceramic sort of all right, so you got like the composite like the natural looking one and then they take this gun.
Speaker 1: It's not really a gun, but it's like this bright heat light thing the UV thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah Jamming in there and it cooks it and turns it.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like a little mini kiln You know.
Speaker 1: They put clay in there and then they point this thing at it for a while and it cooks it and turns it into something That's as hard as tooth if not harder.
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: now actually the one thing I've I've a lot of people talk about and I mentioned the type of filling only because I want to get a dig in here There are people out there who have got this bug up their butt about amalgam fillings now for the long long time and to this They're still used by far.
Speaker 0: the one of the best most versatile ways to fill a cavity is with amalgam which is a mercury compound and crazy people think that this is dangerous somehow even though for 40 years if not longer there have been countless studies showing that this is completely untrue and it's a fabrication.
Speaker 1: This is always.
Speaker 1: the problem is sometimes people don't have common sense and it's like God what's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: And sometimes people do have common sense, but the truth is contrary to the common sense because it sometimes is Yep, and then you're like God what's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Yep going with the common sense dental amalgam is perfectly safe You could have.
Speaker 0: you could swallow like a handful of those fillings and they would have almost no ill effects except for an upset stomach Yeah, as you would get if you swallowed any handful of metal.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cut up esophagus now actually because I had good insurance and for all the cavities I got which I can talk about why I got him later.
Speaker 0: But I had the choice between getting composite and amalgam for all the ones in the back.
Speaker 0: for the like two I have in The front.
Speaker 0: they gave me composite because I think else would look really ugly.
Speaker 0: You know my if one of my front teeth was just this gray thing.
Speaker 0: Amalgam lasts longer and it's more and it's more durable.
Speaker 0: It's also a lot cheaper.
Speaker 0: I forget the exact numbers.
Speaker 0: I saw a study that showed that amalgam fillings last an average of 15 to 20 years before they start to like need to be replaced and Composite last five to ten years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the the dentist did a good job of you know Pressing on all my molars to check if all like the fillings and the sealants were all intact.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I got some really old fillings like from shortly after my baby teeth fell out my new teeth.
Speaker 1: But replacing a filling isn't so bad as getting a new filling.
Speaker 1: Yes, you don't need really need the drilling.
Speaker 1: the filling just kind of falls out And actually they just put the goop more goop in there and cook it again.
Speaker 0: I thought this really interesting.
Speaker 0: the another different the composite fillings require less of the tooth to be drilled out To make an amalgam.
Speaker 0: they drill a bigger hole and they stick it in and it lasts a lot longer.
Speaker 0: But the composite while it falls out in five or ten years.
Speaker 0: possibly Do you only need to make a slightly larger hole to put a new one in?
Speaker 0: Yep I still prefer amalgam just because they're really durable.
Speaker 0: I want to go to the dentist as little as possible.
Speaker 1: I also want to go to the dentist as little as possible, but as little as possible is once a year to get a cleaning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I go every six months.
Speaker 1: I would go every six months.
Speaker 1: I don't think my insurance pays for twice a year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mine does and I do it only because I have a history of difficulty with teeth due to a number of reasons.
Speaker 1: I have a history of not difficulty with teeth because I don't drink soda.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't drink so much soda either and soda really wasn't the cause of my troubles.
Speaker 1: I didn't think it's cause of your troubles.
Speaker 1: the cause of many trouble it is.
Speaker 0: I'm not disagreeing But for an eight or nine years when I was young I had braces.
Speaker 1: I also had braces.
Speaker 0: I had braces for almost twice as long as any kid has braces.
Speaker 1: I had him for a long time.
Speaker 0: I had him You know for three years or so.
Speaker 0: Then they took him out and then it came to light that that orthodontist sucked ass and they didn't really work.
Speaker 0: I got new braces for another like four or five years and I got those out while I was a freshman in high school.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a little late.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, because it was a new set of braces.
Speaker 0: They had to start over and It sucked to have braces that long and as a result a lot of my teeth got a little bit discolored Which actually works out because from a distance they look a lot whiter.
Speaker 0: Then they normally would my teeth look really really bright and white but that's because they have these calcium deposits in the enamel Because of the cement from having braces for so long.
Speaker 0: and in addition to that I got a bunch of cavities early on when I was young and then I went to a different dentist finally and the dentist said Your molars are really deep.
Speaker 0: They've got these deep.
Speaker 0: They're not can't look their cavities, but they're not cavities.
Speaker 0: They just they had really deep crevices.
Speaker 0: It's a genetic thing.
Speaker 0: I think like 20% of the population has this.
Speaker 0: where this is the inside top part of your molars are really really deep and It's impossible to clean that and if you have that you'll get a crazy ton of cavities.
Speaker 0: So what he did is he filled them all in and then I didn't get another cavity for like 10 years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are called sealants.
Speaker 1: What they'll do is that they see a tooth that like a molar that's real deep that might get a cavity.
Speaker 1: What they do is they clean it out, you know, the dentist can clean it out you can't.
Speaker 1: and Then they just fill the.
Speaker 1: you know The giant pit in the molar with a bunch of stuff that's similar to the stuff that they fill the other teeth with But it's a little different.
Speaker 1: It's a chemical thing like they mix two things together and they you know they stir it up and it reacts with each other and sort of like a Glue thing kind of and it just makes your molar less deep by filling it up with stuff.
Speaker 1: It's called a filling not a filling a sealant.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's a great thing.
Speaker 0: It's my cavity stopped and I didn't get any for a long time.
Speaker 0: It's really hard to get cavities in the molars after you seal them Yep, unless you get one in the side which usually comes from not flossing.
Speaker 1: Yes Yeah, my braces situation.
Speaker 1: when I was a little kid They I went to one guy who gave me braces on the front teeth, you know Cuz I had him out sticking, you know the big giant overbite Yep, and then he gave me this other thing that like was against the roof of my mouth.
Speaker 1: It was all weird.
Speaker 1: and then uh You know what happened was is the wire on those braces like crept up into my gum and I you know I finally went to have it taken care of and like it was all bleeding everywhere.
Speaker 1: It's pretty nasty.
Speaker 1: So mom, I think she decided that that guy sucked and we didn't go back there.
Speaker 1: She said she said all right take him off and we'll leave.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: And then years later I went to the very very popular and wealthy orthodontist in the area And you know, he hooked me up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't go to an unpopular Orthodontist.
Speaker 1: go to the guy as much as you hate to go to him.
Speaker 1: go to the guy who's mad rich as a whole.
Speaker 1: mess.
Speaker 0: Offices all over the place has the doll like the special rewards like you get things if you get good grades and everyone's smiling.
Speaker 1: I was a bunch of before-and-after pictures all over his office and has like a room with 12 Dennis chairs and an army of you know dental guy people and Dental hygienists.
Speaker 1: Yeah and game boys all over the place for you to play while you're getting orthodontia.
Speaker 1: Those are the guys you want to go to.
Speaker 1: they're making a shit ton of money for a reason Yep, and actually the my braces.
Speaker 0: I had a very big difficulty with them because I had braces and I started playing the trumpet.
Speaker 0: God, that was a long freaking time ago.
Speaker 0: Now playing a trumpet with braces is fine.
Speaker 0: You can do it.
Speaker 0: And in fact, there's a a disadvantage in that there are braces in the way which screws up your embouchure.
Speaker 0: There's an advantage in that you can't put a lot of pressure on your lips without cutting yourself.
Speaker 0: as a result You will learn to play the trumpet properly as in not using a lot of pressure Which in the end will make you a better trumpet player.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm now fast forward to high school when I'm not really good yet But I'm as good as you can expect someone to be after four years.
Speaker 0: Like I'm pretty good.
Speaker 0: I'm okay I get to high school.
Speaker 0: braces come off.
Speaker 0: I can't play a goddamn thing now suddenly Haha, and I had to relearn to play the trumpet because I didn't have this thing in the way and it sucked ass.
Speaker 1: Let's just put some thing in the way.
Speaker 0: I did for a while.
Speaker 0: Oh, I had retainers that eventually stopped wearing.
Speaker 1: cuz didn't matter Yeah, I just stopped wearing my retainer.
Speaker 1: also it was supposed to be a nighttime only retain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mine was nighttime only for the rest of my life.
Speaker 0: And after about a year, I was like fuck this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wore it for like maybe some months and then I you know, it kept.
Speaker 1: uh, you know I'd forget to wear it or I didn't want to wear it.
Speaker 1: And then if you waited too long that it hurt to put it back in or it didn't fit Yeah, put it back in and like I think twice I went to get them to fix it.
Speaker 1: So it fit again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then after that, I'm just like fuck this shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was like I was supposed to keep doing it till I was 18.
Speaker 1: I did it for maybe a year.
Speaker 0: Yeah The best part of that is that the the ramifications of not wearing my retainer anymore were so minor that it was so worth it.
Speaker 0: I got a tiny bit of a snaggle tooth, which is no big deal and My bottom row of teeth curves in like a millimeter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my teeth are pretty straight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't mind there.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not like they all stay in my mouth.
Speaker 0: Yep I never lost a tooth.
Speaker 1: of course part of my orthodontia involved the pulling of four teeth.
Speaker 1: You see the you know the pointy teeth the canine.
Speaker 1: Yes, the tooth right behind the pointy tooth the first molar.
Speaker 1: I had all four of those removed.
Speaker 1: Oh all four of those are pulled out and then they use braces to pull all the other teeth Inwards towards the front.
Speaker 1: this had an advantage in that has made some room for the wisdom teeth.
Speaker 0: So you didn't have to go through that rigmarole.
Speaker 1: I got four wisdom teeth because I had four less than wisdom teeth pulled out.
Speaker 0: now I'd like to say one.
Speaker 0: my stepdad is an awesome, dude.
Speaker 0: He his wisdom tooth story is interesting because he had a fifth one.
Speaker 0: What now?
Speaker 0: no one out there could guess where this tooth grew.
Speaker 0: Oh, I remember now it grew in one of his sinuses in the middle of his head.
Speaker 0: There's just this tooth in there and it's like those guys.
Speaker 1: you see You know The freak shows were like there's a mouth growing on the side of the face or there's some hair coming out of a place There shouldn't be.
Speaker 1: or there's a. you know, there's like a little nose growing somewhere.
Speaker 0: He just has a tooth in there and the doctor said well does it hurt?
Speaker 0: and he said no.
Speaker 0: and he said well I'm not gonna try to take that thing out But anyway, I'd heard all these horror stories everyone had ever talked to in high school because everyone was getting their wisdom teeth out.
Speaker 0: About around the time I was gonna get him out, you know, there's the span of like 11th grade.
Speaker 1: Does he put food in his nose and chew it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not visible.
Speaker 0: Like it's totally subsumed by flesh.
Speaker 0: yep, but between about 11th grade and maybe sophomore year of college seems to be like the window when a lot of people get him out and Everyone had a horror story and it sucked it.
Speaker 0: It was painful painful painful and they were like out of commission for a week and I'm not looking forward to this.
Speaker 0: So I go in and I first of all, I have a dentist.
Speaker 0: Well, I had a dentist who used the gas.
Speaker 0: He was a big fan of the gas.
Speaker 1: All the dentists that my uncle's a big fan of the Novocain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like the Novocain gets a big giant ass needle and shoves it right in there He's like, aha.
Speaker 1: No, you can't feel shit.
Speaker 0: But what he did is he gassed me, right?
Speaker 0: And this is the first time I'd ever been under anesthesia.
Speaker 0: I've never been operated on other than I've never had anything but local anesthesia.
Speaker 0: I gotta say it was an interesting experience because they put this thing over me and they said Breathe it.
Speaker 0: and then I woke up in my house the next day like literally and I remembered these crazy dreams and I felt like I had been.
Speaker 0: I felt like I had been gone on Adventures for years and years and I woke up in this strange place.
Speaker 0: then I was like It's my it's my downstairs living room.
Speaker 0: Uh, and I was like, oh, yeah, this is my real life Not all that.
Speaker 0: and then I forgot all of it like I had all these crazy dreams and like this epic life and I all these details and They fled from my brain over the span of about two minutes.
Speaker 1: That's why people do drugs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what.
Speaker 0: the next day I went and played softball.
Speaker 0: I was fine There was no pain.
Speaker 0: Well granted there was no pain because I was taking a lot of painkillers that the dentist gave me But I wouldn't play softball the next day of course the.
Speaker 0: the drawback of that was I got hit in the forehead with a line drive while I was pitching and I didn't even feel it because of the painkillers.
Speaker 0: And they were like, are you okay?
Speaker 0: And I was like probably not but it doesn't hurt and I went and sat down for a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when I had those four teeth pulled, you know, I was I was a little kid and I was all like.
Speaker 1: And it really only hurt when they gave me the you know Local anesthesia.
Speaker 0: that did they give you the shot or they did that where they have the thing that looks like a needle But they just like push goop onto it But the goop still hurts.
Speaker 1: actually what they did is a q-tips of goop and they put the goop into.
Speaker 1: you know Anesthesia from the local anesthesia that's coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then is the thing that looks like a needle but it's not goop that it squirts It's a liquid.
Speaker 1: and you know They just they get real close and they squirt this liquid all over and it pretty much numbs you the fuck up.
Speaker 1: and they did Two teeth and they did the other two teeth.
Speaker 1: and yeah, it it was it was it wasn't pleasant having them pulled But that was cuz I was a little kid and it really didn't hurt any more than like, you know a filling You know because it's the same anesthesia basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the pulling was sort of strange and Just irritating and weird and kind of woo Like oh my god, he's pulling out my tooth like it's a you know a corn on the cob or something.
Speaker 0: Actually, I got a funny story from when I when my first baby tooth fell out.
Speaker 0: I remember this very clearly because this tooth was moving around all the time and Everyone was telling me my teeth were all gonna fall out and I was real young and I'm not sure I was cognizant of the fact That new teeth were gonna come in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the tooth like it kept moving around.
Speaker 0: I kept poking at it, but I was like afraid to pull on it because I was afraid it would actually fall out.
Speaker 0: and eventually it fell out one day and I was like, uh, and I stuck it back in and I kept it in there for a couple more days before I could.
Speaker 0: I kept putting it back in and like holding it there with my tongue And eventually it was just like it fell out.
Speaker 0: My mom was like, oh you do it fell out.
Speaker 0: I was like crap She knows.
Speaker 0: and then she was like now maybe your new one will grow in.
Speaker 0: I was like new one.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay, and then I didn't care and I was waiting for my teeth to fall out to get money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh Wow, I remember when certain teeth fell out like they would be dangling by a thread and I would like spin them around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, put my tongue in there.
Speaker 0: I would do that.
Speaker 1: I'd spin around and show people and they go Yeah Like I had teeth that I like a point like perpendicular 90 degrees to my face pointing straight forward and that was fun times.
Speaker 1: But I'm glad they're over.
Speaker 0: I remember there's a kid in my elementary school actually believed in the tooth fairy and whoa And it turned out that actually a lot of people did whoa and all I remember was that was the moment I thought wow, my friends are all dumbasses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't think dumbass cuz I was a kid and I don't think I even knew that.
Speaker 1: Term, I don't know what I thought but I think maybe the first time I was like, oh tooth fairy Yeah, whatever, you know and I stayed up to look and there wasn't one.
Speaker 1: and then you know I think I fell asleep though and that's when it you know, it came of course.
Speaker 1: I wasn't later.
Speaker 1: I was just like, oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I was a very incredulous kid in that I never believed in Santa.
Speaker 0: it was just at this thing I I actually pretended to believe for my parents because I kind of figured out what was going on and I thought that if I let him on that they know they won't give me presents or something or It'll suck.
Speaker 0: So I just pretended for a while and then eventually I kept pretending for my little brother.
Speaker 1: But yeah when I was super little I just kind of accepted things and went.
Speaker 0: I didn't right away.
Speaker 0: I remember when my parents explained Santa Claus to me and I was like But the thing is nothing has really ever explained to me.
Speaker 1: I just didn't really.
Speaker 1: And then like when I was maybe four I was like and you know I finally started to understand what exactly that, you know, people were say I was like, yes, and okay.
Speaker 1: And then we'd be like, okay this guy he flies around on a sleigh and goes in everyone's chimney But that the Jew chimneys and I was like, yeah, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: This doesn't sound real to me.
Speaker 1: It was before it was really explained.
Speaker 1: I just didn't care and just accepted things.
Speaker 0: I remember they explained he comes through the chimney and gives you presents.
Speaker 0: and I thought and the first thing I asked was What do you mean?
Speaker 0: the chimney our fireplace is fake.
Speaker 0: It doesn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: There's no chain.
Speaker 0: And then they said well if you don't have a chimney he comes into the front door.
Speaker 0: and I said the front door is locked.
Speaker 0: Does he have a key?
Speaker 0: And and as a kid, I remember setting up elaborate traps which nominally were to catch Santa Claus.
Speaker 0: But actually I was hoping to trap my parents.
Speaker 0: It's like you're coming out and really ha ha ha.
Speaker 1: We had a chimney, but it came out into like this little black stove.
Speaker 1: It's still there and it works.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: I would have done if how were your parents and you had the stove like that?
Speaker 0: I would have gotten a fake human skull and like our jolly red hat and burned it a little bit and left it in there.
Speaker 1: Thing is you're Jewish.
Speaker 0: So we yeah cause didn't come it doesn't matter and then open the door a little bit And then just make a funny joke.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was just like.
Speaker 1: here's your present day two.
Speaker 1: Here's another present day three.
Speaker 1: Here's another present.
Speaker 0: Yep I think part of the my incredulousness was that I went to a Catholic school because I lived in downtown Detroit where if I'd gone To a public school.
Speaker 0: I would have been killed like the schools were bad.
Speaker 0: So I went to a private school which happened to be Catholic and after the crap They used to try to tell me in that school.
Speaker 0: I didn't believe any adult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe like let's go back Let's go back to teeth.
Speaker 0: All right teeth teeth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, keep them clean.
Speaker 0: Yeah Things I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't like biting things unless it's food.
Speaker 1: I like to bite thing.
Speaker 1: I know it's good teeth exercise.
Speaker 0: I know you have.
Speaker 0: there have been many biting incidents with Scott.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually Kate bit me at the shore.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I forget why.
Speaker 1: Biter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're one to talk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bite McBite.
Speaker 1: Hey biter is like a compliment to you.
Speaker 1: Like hey biter, what's up?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we're gonna wrap this up.
Speaker 0: We're definitely running out of stuff to say about biting.
Speaker 1: Yeah Did you have any interesting dental incidents to talk about?
Speaker 0: Uh, no, I have a bunch of fillings from when I was young.
Speaker 0: I have one filling from when I didn't go to the dentist for like two years because my insurance situation was dicey.
Speaker 0: You
Speaker 1: know I think the best times on Thursday geek nights is when we have a story like if we had a crazy story about how Oh my god, I miss tooth broke in half and then it was glued back together and it was crazy But
Speaker 0: I got to like all right.
Speaker 0: I got a couple All right one.
Speaker 0: I was really big into science Olympiad in middle in high school.
Speaker 0: I have a box full of like 40 medals from all this shit.
Speaker 0: and like we went to the state competition saw that and one time we went to the state competition and A friend of mine.
Speaker 0: I remember her name anymore She we won of one of the medals in the state the first time we've ever been to States.
Speaker 0: and the state medals are giant.
Speaker 0: They're these massive bronze things.
Speaker 0: They're huge fucking pieces of metal and we were you know, young kids.
Speaker 0: We were in like eighth grade
Speaker 1: so
Speaker 0: We're out at a McDonald's celebrating and then we got to take the bus from Lansing back to Detroit well to sterling heights and she's jumping up and down and This metal bounces off her chest goes into the air and chips one of her front teeth in half.
Speaker 0: Whoa, like the front half of her tooth fell off and there's just like nerve.
Speaker 0: Whoa And oh good god that must have hurt.
Speaker 0: I felt I didn't.
Speaker 0: I couldn't be anywhere near her cuz she looked like she was in So much pain.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I would have just run away and called 911 and then yeah 911 was called.
Speaker 1: there you go and Surgering was done and good God I actually when I was sitting in the dentist office There's something that really makes me cringe is Reading all those pamphlets and brochures and binders about different procedures and which one is right for you.
Speaker 0: Oh, the disease is getting me more than the procedures.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is one I didn't realize this before But you can get these dental implants like let's say I lost a tooth like it just fell out.
Speaker 0: Oh where they put the screw in and then they screw the tooth on.
Speaker 1: you put us they take a titanium Screw and they screw it into your jaw.
Speaker 0: That's awesome.
Speaker 1: And then they put a tooth on top of that and you can actually change that tooth out, but it's not necessary.
Speaker 0: See, I'm fascinated by medical procedures and they never bother me.
Speaker 1: See it's actually it's a very good thing You know, I mean if you don't do that your job will start to disintegrate and you'll get that old man with the lower jaw Sticking out and all kinds of bad shit will happen.
Speaker 1: if you just lose teeth and don't put something in the jaw but at the same time think about a Titanium screw, you know what going into your jaw in a place of this a tooth missing screwing Screwing and grinding your jawbone.
Speaker 0: See, ah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I think I think awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be like the million dollar man.
Speaker 0: They're just gonna augment me all the one.
Speaker 0: I won't replace this joint while you're at it.
Speaker 1: All right Let's go pull all your teeth out and put titanium screws in.
Speaker 0: Well, the only reason I wouldn't is that currently natural teeth are still better than even the best artificial teeth.
Speaker 1: It's better than a titanium tooth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, natural teeth are really good for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: How are they better than a titanium?
Speaker 0: - god?
Speaker 0: I got to go dig up the Wikipedia and all that shit I read.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean if you if we're getting old like an old geezer The one argument is that putting things like that in your body Your body doesn't like it so much and it causes trouble.
Speaker 1: It's not perfect actually causes more trouble if you just lose.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, if you look the best answer is to not lose teeth.
Speaker 0: Yes, because also natural teeth are living things.
Speaker 0: They have feeling in them.
Speaker 0: There's little tiny holes in your teeth that go to the nerve and that's how you feel like hot and cold and things through them.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm and Yeah, anyway, but the thing is if you're an old geezer and you're not losing all your teeth instead of doing shitty ass dentures You can just replace the really important teeth with these titanium screw things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's awesome.
Speaker 0: now what bothers me is when I see pictures of like someone who had a gingivitis and then it turned into a peridont Ida bada bada bidi itis and then job itis, you know when someone's gum just like rots away or the dudes have like one yellow tooth left.
Speaker 1: the worst are the pictures of Like people who smoked or chewed tobacco and then their teeth get all screwed up.
Speaker 0: Oh god, the worst picture ever saw a guy's mouth was maggot II with maggots Because he had a gum infection and flies got in there and Good God Good fucking God.
Speaker 0: it was and it wasn't a Photoshop It's on Snopes somewhere and Snopes was like, yep, that happened.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, actually there's a worse picture than that.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna talk about cuz even good see no, no, no, no, no, no, I'll save it party.
Speaker 0: No, it's it's the it's the.
Speaker 0: it's the only thing other than this maggot II guy I have ever seen.
Speaker 0: that actually disturbed me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but see it's not so much the procedures themselves that bother me It's it's imagining the procedures being performed on me.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I imagine I'm gonna be drugged and knocked out.
Speaker 0: Then I'll wake up with an awesome titanium tooth.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: He has the part I don't imagine.
Speaker 1: I imagine being awake and having this tooth Crammed into my mouth.
Speaker 0: and now my mom way back got our radial carotenomy our case surgery.
Speaker 0: like before there was LASIK.
Speaker 0: she got the old Russian eye surgery and The way they did that is that they gave you know local anesthetic and special anesthetics to where they knock you out for the most part but you're conscious and aware and can respond to stimuli and they ask you to do things during the procedure and you're fully awake and you can Feel them like cutting at your eye, but it doesn't hurt.
Speaker 0: You just feel pressure.
Speaker 0: Uh, and Yeah Imagine that it's bad.
Speaker 0: or what about the rare cases where someone wakes up?
Speaker 0: someone becomes aware and conscious during surgery But they can't move because of the anesthetic but they still feel everything.
Speaker 0: It's rare, but it has happened That.
Speaker 0: that is a scary thing.
Speaker 0: I don't want that to ever happen to anyone.
Speaker 1: Oh god, except for bad people.
Speaker 0: But oh, yeah, no even then because you know regarding the death penalty.
Speaker 0: There's actually a news They almost did where the anesthesiologist of America are trying to band together and refuse to administer lethal injection on the grounds that the way we do lethal injection is Often horrible and painful and that there are much more humane ways to execute people.
Speaker 1: just fucking stab them in the neck now That hurts.
Speaker 1: I'm shoot him in the head.
Speaker 1: No, uh, cut him with a club carbon monoxide poisoning.
Speaker 0: It works that there's absolutely no gas chambers.
Speaker 0: No, those are cyanide gas poisoning.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're horrible and painful Because I there's this thing.
Speaker 0: basically I Say what you will about the death penalty.
Speaker 0: I am in a utopian world and in from an ideological standpoint I am an advocate of the death penalty.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just toss people into pools of acid?
Speaker 0: because I would really fucking hurt really strong.
Speaker 0: I said like it immediately disintegrates you regardless Regardless of any of our views on the death penalty because I could talk at length about this and I'm sure all of you could If you're going to do it let's assume that the death penalty is going to happen.
Speaker 0: I don't care what horrible things a person did.
Speaker 0: I I think that the the moment in which you realize that you were going to die because this isn't like being shot Suddenly or just dying somewhere.
Speaker 0: This is where you've known you're going to die for a long time and then you know the exact moment You're going to die.
Speaker 0: and then some men come and they do it and you're aware right up to the end.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine anything more to me not frightening but fascinating.
Speaker 0: but to normal people who aren't nuts like me I imagine this being the most frightening thing you can imagine and I don't care what horrible thing you did.
Speaker 0: I can't justify making that painful in addition to all of that fear.
Speaker 1: Maybe someone wants it to be painful.
Speaker 1: There were those pain likers.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I just I'm of the mind that we have the science to execute people a hundred percent painlessly and we choose not to do Stupid political reasons.
Speaker 1: maybe what we should do instead of having the death penalty or jail is If you get caught committing a crime We just perform a painful medical procedure on you so that you don't want to commit more crime.
Speaker 0: Ah I'm a constitution.
Speaker 0: cruel and unusual punishment.
Speaker 1: That's not cruel or unusual quite cruel.
Speaker 1: It would not be cruel if we started doing it all the time and then it wouldn't even be unusual either.
Speaker 1: I See it's only unusual if it's not done often I what was the comedian who was like unusual?
Speaker 0: what like?
Speaker 0: hit a guy with a ball peen hammer until he died?
Speaker 1: And that's not cruel either, you know, what's cruel?
Speaker 1: keeping someone locked up in a room alone for years and years and years?
Speaker 1: Yeah Are we pulling out a tooth or replacing it with the titanium tooth with no anesthesia isn't cruel?
Speaker 0: What if they gave me jetpack abs?
Speaker 0: All Right, we've definitely gone off topic and we've got a lot of new topics for Thursdays now.
Speaker 0: We got to talk about the death penalty.
Speaker 0: We got to talk about prisons in general and punishment and the ideas of punishment and crime.
Speaker 0: We got to talk about medical procedures.
Speaker 0: We got to talk more about anime world order, but that's more of a Wednesday.
Speaker 1: That's a Wednesday deal I think we have.
Speaker 1: I think the end result is that we have to Skype with them and do a team podcast Where we all discuss everything because otherwise it's just not gonna be capped off.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what I'm gonna do is and we're done with the episode.
Speaker 0: This is totally meta bits.
Speaker 0: Now I'm gonna read the email response I sent to them because right after we sent them the audio response I think was Daryl sent us a long kind of his feedback and just general feedback and All the points they were probably going to make and he made some of the points almost word-for-word and then I rebutted that with an extremely long email.
Speaker 0: and I just want to read the email because I think it was very well done and there were some points We made that they rebutted in the email But he didn't rebut in the show Which I was sad because I wanted to hear their rebuttal and then I wanted to rebut that rebuttal.
Speaker 1: rebuts, but but but sex.
Speaker 1: When something's up, it's probably the butts.
Speaker 0: And On final note if you want to see us come to Connecticut in Hartford, Connecticut Saturday we will be there.
Speaker 0: It won't be hard to find us.
Speaker 0: good God, is it not hard to find us at a convention?
Speaker 0: You could go to Otacon knowing nothing about us and I can guarantee that you would find us because we stand out in a crowd.
Speaker 1: All you have to do is say, you know, if you really can't find us just go around the con to like You know each different room and say I'm
Speaker 0: looking for Raymond Scott Yeah, or the front row crew or gig nuts or even just anytime you see a group of people like a especially at Otacon a large group of people in a bustle making noise or doing something or in any way standing out in the crowd or Anyone who's that guy like.
Speaker 0: here's a good example.
Speaker 0: say in opening ceremonies someone on stage Like has a thought bird moment where they forget the name of a panel and some guy in the audience yells out the answer.
Speaker 0: It's probably us.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: We're we're loud.
Speaker 0: We're there.
Speaker 0: We're around and you really can't miss us.
Speaker 0: Nope Okay, that's it.
Speaker 0: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.