Speaker 0: It's Thursday February 9th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about Legos.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Guess who sat through hours and hours of meetings instead of actually doing work today?
Speaker 0: Guess who sat through hours and hours of not doing work today?
Speaker 1: I'd rather just be sitting in front of my computer at work doing nothing than sitting in a meeting having to pretend I care about what someone's saying to me.
Speaker 0: I'd rather be doing something.
Speaker 1: It was a meeting that didn't really involve me in any way other than the fact that I was there.
Speaker 0: Then why did you go?
Speaker 1: cuz I had to?
Speaker 0: they make you go to a meeting that doesn't involve you.
Speaker 1: most meetings involve me And I have to go to him and I really do have a reason to be there.
Speaker 1: this meeting was just kind of Pointless oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: see I complained about not having to do anything But I really don't like meetings, and I'm very glad I have a job with no meetings And
Speaker 1: I don't get people who say they don't like meetings because I meet with people at work all the time to figure out What we're doing.
Speaker 1: I mean meetings are an integral part of what I do.
Speaker 0: I like doing.
Speaker 1: you know what I don't like.
Speaker 1: I don't like stupid meetings.
Speaker 0: I Just don't.
Speaker 0: I don't like jobs.
Speaker 1: with lots of meetings CS major coder you just sit there and type all day.
Speaker 1: I walk around and talk to people.
Speaker 0: as most of my job I'd like to walk around and talk to people, but I just don't want to have you know meetings in quotes.
Speaker 1: What do you mean meetings in quotes?
Speaker 1: all a meeting is is you talk to people?
Speaker 0: we have like an appointment.
Speaker 0: you go to the?
Speaker 1: Conference room and y'all sit down, and you know sometimes you got to talk to more than one person at the same time.
Speaker 1: So you schedule it.
Speaker 1: yeah most meetings.
Speaker 1: I go to our.
Speaker 1: I sit there with all the people who are working on the same stuff I'm working on and we talk about what we're gonna do.
Speaker 0: I just talk about what we're doing while we're doing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually we have to plan things out a little bit ahead of time.
Speaker 0: Someone writes a plan and then say hey everyone follows plan.
Speaker 1: no because it doesn't work that way.
Speaker 1: especially our person makes the plan Now because they need input from all the experts.
Speaker 1: I mean the one person doesn't know everything makes the plan.
Speaker 1: There's no expert who knows everything about everything.
Speaker 0: That's not good.
Speaker 1: I'll point out Scott that How many thousands and thousands of people work at the place I work?
Speaker 1: It's not a simple place to manage at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I couldn't work at any place that big.
Speaker 1: I mean there's benefits while you don't really stand out in a company like that.
Speaker 1: You don't really stand out, and I'm fairly convinced that if I just stopped doing work entirely No one would notice for at least a month.
Speaker 0: No one's been noticing that I don't do work.
Speaker 1: No one notices when I do work, so they wouldn't notice if I did.
Speaker 0: and I'm in an office all alone one person.
Speaker 1: They only notice when they want something that they haven't assigned me yet.
Speaker 1: And then they they decide they need it and they stop noticing after I give it to them.
Speaker 0: hmm Yeah, let's escape work and do something else.
Speaker 1: all right, let's uh do that barge idea.
Speaker 1: We'll have fights to the death on a barge in international waters And then publish the videos of the fights to the death on the internet and sell them not to mention allow rich people to fly Out to our helicopter thing.
Speaker 1: fly out to our helicopter pad on top of the barge and watch the fights and bet on the fights And then we kidnap the rich people Mmm, and we keep all their helicopters.
Speaker 1: nah, so anyway Halo 2 is coming out on the PC.
Speaker 0: Isn't Halo 2 been out for the Xbox like a zillion years I guess.
Speaker 0: didn't halo 1 come out on the PC like just about the same time it came out for the original Xbox?
Speaker 1: See the fact that Halo 2 is gonna be on the PC is not particularly interesting news.
Speaker 0: no The question why did it take so long is what I'm asking.
Speaker 0: I don't know I'm just pointing it out.
Speaker 1: I don't want to offend anyone out there, but Halo and Halo 2 are terrible games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I've played both of them.
Speaker 1: They're good for a console game as in a console FPS.
Speaker 1: They're all right.
Speaker 0: No, they're just goldeneye with updated graphics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is pretty good for a console game.
Speaker 1: FPS I guess.
Speaker 1: but I mean what as you can do all the people out there who seem to like love Halo 2 never really played The golden age FPS is on the computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I used to think it was young punk kids You know.
Speaker 0: but my brother who has played much counter-strike and still plays counter-strike and whatever He doesn't like halo so much.
Speaker 0: He's like yeah, halo crap.
Speaker 1: I've never met anyone who played quake 2 and all the mods of quake 2 and play just all even the modern one.
Speaker 1: like tribes 2 tribes 1 any of those FPS's and Actually liked halo.
Speaker 1: the only people who like halo seem to be people who have never played a real FPS.
Speaker 0: People suck at real FPS's.
Speaker 1: no no those people play UT.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but the news here is that halo 2 will only run in Windows Vista.
Speaker 1: alright I'm not sure if this is due to because they haven't said if it's going to be due to a technical specific limitation of Non-vista windows which seems highly unlikely unless maybe you know DirectX 10 considering.
Speaker 0: It's an Xbox one game or They're just gonna put some arbitrary.
Speaker 1: Oh, we've detected.
Speaker 1: You're not running Vista.
Speaker 1: therefore No, halo for you.
Speaker 0: This is just messed up because first of all who wants to play halo 2 on the PC?
Speaker 0: It's been out on the original Xbox for months and months and months and months and months and honestly That's where it shines.
Speaker 1: You can't really play a game like that with keyboard and mouse and expect it to be good.
Speaker 0: Oh, you can.
Speaker 0: actually you can play halo 1 with the keyboard mouse, and I've done it.
Speaker 0: The problem is is you just basically kick the shit out of everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's like it was the easiest thing ever played.
Speaker 0: it played the demo.
Speaker 0: It was so easy.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: It really only works when everyone's on equal footing with the handheld controller instead of a mouse and keyboard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't even know why they release it for the PC But maybe you can play it with the Xbox 360 controller that plugs into the PC or maybe Microsoft has an evil evil evil stupid conspiracy plot where they'll put it out on the PC.
Speaker 1: It'll sell like crap because it's also on Vista and then they'll just be able to say yeah PC gaming is dead.
Speaker 1: Xbox is the way to go.
Speaker 0: No, I think what they're gonna try to do is they're gonna try to sell copies of Vista by this way.
Speaker 0: Is that people who want halo 2 for the PC and are ultra super gamers who spend zillion dollars in video cards anyway?
Speaker 0: Putting halo 2 on the PC for Vista only will make all those people upgrade to Vista.
Speaker 1: see they may think that but honestly Anyone who wants halo already has an Xbox and is already playing the game as well as they're ever gonna play it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but from the thing that makes me disagree with that is what I heard on the PC gamer podcast today, which was scary is They were talking about upgrading PCs, which we've talked about like a thousand times and he's like is it worth it for me to upgrade?
Speaker 0: My you know PC to play this game and they did some math, which is the same math I would have done which is price of video card plus price a game Divided by hours of gameplay.
Speaker 0: and they were like, oh, okay so you play that if you played that for 125 hours, which is There are very few games.
Speaker 0: I've played for over 125 hours.
Speaker 1: Maybe like counter-strike I'd submit that natural selection is natural selection.
Speaker 0: Maybe yeah Not many.
Speaker 0: is the point That it would still be about three dollars an hour?
Speaker 0: and then they said that's a great deal.
Speaker 0: now $3 an hour.
Speaker 0: The only thing that costs more than three dollars an hour is playing games in the arcade.
Speaker 0: That's just insane.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean even MMOs.
Speaker 1: don't cost you that much.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean an MMO of 20 bucks a month if you play an hour a day, that's less than the dollar an hour you know, so three dollars an hour is insane for a game to cost.
Speaker 0: so Paying if you add the cost of Vista to the cost of halo 2 for the PC to the cost of the PC required to run that and Then divide by the number of hours.
Speaker 0: You're gonna play games that require all of that.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna.
Speaker 0: it's not gonna be good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there's a lot of not even just the cost of all that.
Speaker 1: but Windows Vista is in many ways a step backward From current versions of Windows that you can already buy.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I mean we've talked about it before.
Speaker 1: but Vista you can't install drivers unless Microsoft approves them and it's not like.
Speaker 1: oh It'll warn you.
Speaker 1: Hey, this driver's unsigned.
Speaker 1: don't install it.
Speaker 1: It really won't let you.
Speaker 1: you don't have root access to your own machine anymore.
Speaker 0: At least it'll really Bring down PC game cheating.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it'll also bring down playing my items of dubious copyright.
Speaker 1: job status Absolutely.
Speaker 1: I mean I want to be able to play all my mp3s.
Speaker 1: I want to be able to download all my devices.
Speaker 0: That's why I run Linux or a Windows XP.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had a firewall.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Um Somehow I don't think halo 2 for the PC is gonna be this giant draw that they think it is.
Speaker 0: I mean how well did halo 1 for the PC do?
Speaker 0: I don't think it did that.
Speaker 1: Well, well, I consider look at the list of the top games last year and they were all sims games and World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: so for a while now They've been planning on getting rid of analog television, you know when you stick the antenna on your roof and you just watch channel 3 4 & 5 with an old TV.
Speaker 0: and And There's been fights and they keep changing the date when they're gonna cut it off and all kinds of crap.
Speaker 0: today the President Bush signed a law.
Speaker 0: So this is set in stone.
Speaker 0: It's a law for real on February 17 So far into the future.
Speaker 1: I don't even give a shit.
Speaker 0: They're gonna turn off all the analog television.
Speaker 1: that that information is almost useless to anyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one cares.
Speaker 0: Well, all the people who plan on using antennas in 2009 do know cuz they don't even know and they won't know.
Speaker 0: They won't know until their TV stops working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: This is I mean, this is an issue that I really don't care about at all.
Speaker 0: That could be because we don't watch TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: But think about it.
Speaker 1: most people who watch TV in this country have cable because there's really nothing or satellite.
Speaker 1: Yeah They have some sort of pay service that will continue to work no matter what.
Speaker 1: This only screws the poorest of the poor who probably shouldn't be watching TV anyway.
Speaker 0: But that's the problem.
Speaker 0: is the people who watch the most TV or the poorest of the poor because they have no jobs And they sit at home all day?
Speaker 1: You'd be surprised because all that a lot of people who work or have jobs or just most people in this country Just watch a lot of TV.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah they sure do.
Speaker 0: but the point is is that The those people watch TV when they get home from work when they wake up in the morning and on the weekend.
Speaker 0: The poor people watch TV all day.
Speaker 0: That's why you see all those, you know cheap really low-class talk shows on during the you know Late morning afternoon times because that's when all the poor people are watching.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh Yeah, yeah way to uh paint poor people with a broad brush a little a little bit of a broad brush there You know painting them with it.
Speaker 0: It's mostly accurate then in America.
Speaker 1: See the thing is I'd be I'm all for this.
Speaker 1: I wish it happened sooner because maybe it'll force people when they can't watch the TV anymore to do something else for a little while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'd have to get a job in order to buy digital television.
Speaker 1: Well, no because you know, the government's gonna subsidize upgrades for everyone doesn't say that here.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the government's already said they will.
Speaker 1: they've earmarked a whole ton of money.
Speaker 1: a lot of the money that's gonna come from the sale Of the spectrum that TV is currently on is going to go towards subsidizing Digital converter boxes for everyone in the country who needs them so that people will still be able to watch TV.
Speaker 0: We'll see about that because you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go get me a digital converter box and do some nice hacks with it because it's a free electronics.
Speaker 0: I'll take it.
Speaker 1: They're gonna subsidize it.
Speaker 1: It won't be free.
Speaker 1: You'll just get like a rebate if you buy it.
Speaker 0: There's fine cheap electronics Great.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do with that?
Speaker 1: You'll be able to watch TV.
Speaker 1: whoo.
Speaker 0: I'll be able to do some other stuff with it.
Speaker 1: Like what you can barely solder.
Speaker 0: It's a digital analog converter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what are you gonna do with this specific piece of technology that is made to do one specific thing?
Speaker 1: I don't know but make magazine will tell me Yeah, I don't think I've seen you in the history of me knowing you so much as touch of soldering iron.
Speaker 0: I know how to use them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I made a burglar alarm like a few years ago a few years ago Yeah, a few years ago.
Speaker 1: You were still living with me.
Speaker 0: I didn't see any burglar alarm more than more than a few.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, we're talking.
Speaker 1: what high school?
Speaker 0: No, no, no talking always a me middle school.
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe high school Maybe high school.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I know what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: No, you don't.
Speaker 1: yeah do plus.
Speaker 1: you realize that these boxes are not going to be simple pieces of Electronics.
Speaker 1: they're going to be mostly digital.
Speaker 0: It's not like the project is gonna be totally worth the low price plus the.
Speaker 1: It's not like the projects you do in school where you know You make an oscillator and there's a giant resistor and a giant capacitor and big wires between them.
Speaker 1: You can see where everything's going.
Speaker 1: It's probably mostly pre-printed boards and pre-printed chips.
Speaker 0: There'll be some sort of firmware hack and then I'll get my computer to do something and then name anything.
Speaker 1: you think you could use a DAC for?
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: some sort of awesome myth TV hackers.
Speaker 0: No, you don't need that that I'd be able to pick up the digital tee the HD TV out of the sky and write it to my hard drive With an analog, you know, there's not get one.
Speaker 1: There's not going to be so much HD TV in the sky to begin with especially not where we live.
Speaker 0: Why not there?
Speaker 1: you realize I we don't have an antenna But I talk to people at work and because of the mountains where we live there are maybe Two channels that you can get over the air.
Speaker 0: currently aren't there any a TV station.
Speaker 0: local TV stations now Like a Poughkeepsie TV station.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't get it.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: Apparently there's almost no watchable television over the airwaves here.
Speaker 0: Well, even in Rochester, there was a TV station like right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but your grand total Even if we had an antenna in Rochester, there were only a few channels.
Speaker 0: I guess I kind of spoiled because where I'm from we got you know, two whole states worth of TV channels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was from in Michigan.
Speaker 1: We got about 20 channels just over the air.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we had like a zillion over-the-air channels.
Speaker 0: We didn't switch the cable for the longest time because they didn't need to thing.
Speaker 1: is I remember as a kid watching more Canadian TV Than American TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we need Canadian TV, but I watched mostly New York TV.
Speaker 1: Canadian TV was frickin awesome.
Speaker 1: There was two kinetic you realize instead of Saturday morning cartoons.
Speaker 1: There's this one Canadian channel channel 9.
Speaker 1: It was Saturday morning.
Speaker 1: learn science Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I remember watching all these just shows.
Speaker 1: that like remember mr.
Speaker 1: Wizard.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: These shows make mr.
Speaker 1: Wizard look like crap.
Speaker 1: These shows were like Like.
Speaker 1: I remember one specifically.
Speaker 1: it was this guy and he was just lecturing on Bernoulli's principle and how it worked and how airfoils work And it was an hour long and I was like six and I just ate that crap up Alrighty.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe that's why Canadians have fewer issues than we do down here.
Speaker 0: They still have their issues.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, they have their issues, but you know what.
Speaker 1: at least they debate their issues I guess in open forums, they may not come to good solutions, but at least they try.
Speaker 0: Supposedly at least they have a facade of trying and anything.
Speaker 0: we don't even have that.
Speaker 1: So things of the day.
Speaker 1: you all know and love spider-man from his various movie comic and book appearances in the u.s.
Speaker 1: spider-man, but spider-man has another incarnation a giant robot fighting incarnation.
Speaker 0: See you can only be Japanese.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Japan made its own spider-man and here it is our friend.
Speaker 1: Kate pointed us to this and oh my god.
Speaker 0: At first I thought it was just the 1960s live-action American spider-man TV show dubbed in Japanese and made funny.
Speaker 1: See, I don't know because it starts immediately with you know, various Japanese things that are obviously Japanese.
Speaker 0: I didn't I wasn't paying attention so much.
Speaker 0: I just saw a live-action spider-man dancing around.
Speaker 0: but then When you get to the giant robots and stuff and the plot doesn't match the plot of spider-man in any way whatsoever Well, there's a scene where the giant robot has got spider-man from a web and he's swinging him around.
Speaker 0: It's not even a web.
Speaker 1: It's a rope and then he just whaps him into a tree.
Speaker 0: is how he can.
Speaker 0: it's a mountain.
Speaker 0: He smacks him into a mountain.
Speaker 0: It's insane.
Speaker 0: And then spider-man just gets up.
Speaker 1: It's it's oh my god This is worth watching.
Speaker 1: The subtitles are all fake as far as we can tell.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like but many parts of the subtitles seem very inaccurate.
Speaker 0: Well, it seems like some parts were relatively accurate or at least kind of make sense, even if they're not accurate.
Speaker 0: But other parts are just made silly on purpose Which is I say it's better because you don't really want to know what they're saying.
Speaker 0: It might be painful.
Speaker 0: Actually reminds me of a story.
Speaker 0: My brother's friend had a job dressing up a spider-man and going to kids birthday parties.
Speaker 1: Wow, that sounds kind of creepy and shady.
Speaker 0: It's actually apparently like spider-man was like the number one thing to have at your birthday party or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think it was like that but then he got fired for not showing up.
Speaker 1: Well getting fired from a job like that is yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: There's another story about a guy who had the same job and a bunch of dreadlocks.
Speaker 0: But then you know He would go to get the money from the parents and you take the mask off and all these dreadlocks would come out and they'd Be like, whoa Whatever that's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah story didn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: No, it was just the dreadlocks didn't kill anyone.
Speaker 1: The dreadlocks really didn't matter.
Speaker 1: No, why even tell that story cuz they're hit?
Speaker 0: it doesn't look like he has them when he puts the spider-man mask on and then And you go They just kind of go rip and disappear if you don't want them out.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like a little secret identity thing going on, you know, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, so Today, what are we gonna do our show on?
Speaker 1: Don't you have a thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it has to do with the thing We can do a show on.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it kind of does.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so so, uh, yeah Yeah, Cthulhu photography.
Speaker 0: and so yeah, we got a little Lovecraftian thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Someone took a bunch of Legos and they made this can't call them Legos.
Speaker 1: You can't call them Legos.
Speaker 0: Someone took many Lego Lego toys.
Speaker 0: Yep at Lego bricks bricks Lego bricks and But they're not all bricks.
Speaker 1: Some of them are round you're right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they took a whole bunch of them and they made this giant scene.
Speaker 0: That is all Call of Cthulhu action.
Speaker 0: They've got little like a biplane.
Speaker 0: They've got.
Speaker 1: well, it's not really like canon from the books Call of Cthulhu action.
Speaker 1: It is definitely Playing the Cthulhu game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's definitely Call of Cthulhu the RPG action.
Speaker 1: a bunch of guys from the 30s with various crap pistols and Tommy guns going after Treasure on an island and Cthulhu comes and eats them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's.
Speaker 0: there's tentacles coming out of the water There's deep ones.
Speaker 0: There's boats.
Speaker 0: There's cars and Indiana Jones's and It's really cool.
Speaker 0: This is Zeppelin.
Speaker 0: It's like you look at this and you could use this as like your representation for when you play the game You know with your friends word.
Speaker 0: I Just really enjoy looking at all the different like parts of it like there's the one people picking mushrooms and You know the people near the phone booth or whatever the hell it is.
Speaker 0: there's the one guy who was like the tentacle going into him with this like these the red bush and The.
Speaker 0: the red bush actually looks like blood because they stuck it on his chest.
Speaker 0: So it looks like the blood is just exploding out of his stomach because the tentacle hit him in the back here.
Speaker 1: Look, I can see.
Speaker 0: okay.
Speaker 0: There's a skull on the ground.
Speaker 0: It's all details of it.
Speaker 0: They make it great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, peruse it in detail much like the pictures of Mexico City.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I wasn't lying.
Speaker 1: our show today is about Lego because basically we were doing that show on the toys of our geeky, you know nerd fest lives of children and We realized there's much more to that topic than we could do in one show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Lego which is like this major toy in everyone's life at least every geeky kids life.
Speaker 1: There were a lot of kids where I grew up who didn't have any Lego or thought they were stupid.
Speaker 0: none.
Speaker 0: Well, everyone I knew at least had some Lego if not much.
Speaker 1: I had an extensive collection.
Speaker 0: See I was big into the castle Lego and whenever we went to Toys R Us.
Speaker 0: We either got an NES game or Lego Start I started out real big with the real life sets like the race car type stuff like Race car set that came with two little race cars in the track.
Speaker 0: That was a good one.
Speaker 1: Yep that or any just like normal buildings and stuff and of course just big blocks and boxes like the houses and the Trees and yeah, yeah little town people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we weren't big into those sets.
Speaker 0: I think we had two of them.
Speaker 0: mostly I had castle sets.
Speaker 0: can they gets wizards dragons?
Speaker 0: castles Castles catapults.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I only had one castle and then I had some knockoff not Lego but kind of compatible with Lego castle And I had mostly the space stuff.
Speaker 1: I remember when the ice planet came out I got all that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the ice planet was wicked cool cuz they had those orange chainsaws and stuff.
Speaker 1: You know the orange jemmies?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I only got actually one.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got the frickin bass.
Speaker 0: I got only one snow planet thing which was this one guy who had a chainsaw and like a snowmobile.
Speaker 0: It was actually really fun But I had that guy.
Speaker 1: but I also had the full-on bass and like the big Magnetic thing and my brother had all this space stuff.
Speaker 0: He had like two snow bases in the snow a spaceship and whatever, but I was mostly into the castle.
Speaker 1: I think the best part of the the ice planet stuff was that all the little sleddy things had.
Speaker 1: the little sleds They worked really well on carpet.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but I got the bright idea one day.
Speaker 0: This is who all the guys had skis do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I went outside into the snow in our front yard with my brother.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you that was one of the best days of playing with Lego I ever had until you lost all your white Legos in the snow.
Speaker 1: Actually, I lost almost nothing.
Speaker 1: I was real careful almost nothing and you know what?
Speaker 1: I found the rest in the spring Before the lawnmower got him.
Speaker 1: you don't mow the lawn for quite some time after the snow melts.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, actually when I got castle stuff, we I mostly got they had in those days It was the Knights which are like actual guys with black castles and armor and swords and things.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then you had this Robin Hood set which was like these guys who are all elfish.
Speaker 0: They weren't elves, but they were like forest Rangers.
Speaker 1: There was definitely some animosity between these two groups.
Speaker 0: Yeah They had.
Speaker 0: they already were all green and they had hats and you could change the feathers in the hats and I had feathers of Every color and I would you could tell the rank of the guy based on how big his feather was and what color it was.
Speaker 0: so the guy with like the triple white feather was like Robin Hood and Every like little John had like the triple red feather and the people with like this single tiny little white You know like blue feathers.
Speaker 0: Those were normal schmucks and they had bows and arrows and quivers and you know all kinds of great stuff.
Speaker 0: They even had this giant castle with a trap with a with a portcullis that opened and closed with a rope.
Speaker 1: I never had their castle.
Speaker 1: I just had all their guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had all.
Speaker 0: I had that castle.
Speaker 0: I had their.
Speaker 0: the best set was the one where there's a river and this bridge that went over the river and they were like Little towers in either end of it.
Speaker 0: Ooh, that was a good one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then I would set that up and then I would sit the castles up on the other side and then the horses marched At each other and shoot arrows and yeah, you know that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Yep I had kind of epic battles with my little brother and me and we build each of us had it like pretty much identical sets of Legos and we build giant like Giant giant freaking complex bases for all our guys and every now and then we'd agree and we just kind of this ongoing kind of war.
Speaker 1: I Mean.
Speaker 1: we came up with a little.
Speaker 1: you know little kids like Calvin ball type rules.
Speaker 1: We're like he put a door in the front.
Speaker 1: So I was like I walk in and then he put a thing is like that.
Speaker 1: now it's locked and it really was locked.
Speaker 1: So crap now my guy can't get in.
Speaker 1: You know stuff like that.
Speaker 1: We had this whole currency system where various pieces were worth more or less money or value depending how rare they were.
Speaker 0: Story of the space shuttle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can tell the story of the space shuttle But you know like there were the little gold pieces from the pirate set.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I had one tiny set of the gold between us.
Speaker 1: So those are like the rarest like a piece of gold was worth like a million normal pieces.
Speaker 0: Yeah The Pirates are some of the best ones.
Speaker 0: actually I had one pirate tower that was like this island with a tower on it And some guys with guns.
Speaker 0: they weren't actually pirates.
Speaker 0: They were the anti pirates and I planned to get pirates But I always just bought castles instead.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like the pirates.
Speaker 0: I'd go to the store and he said like a pirate ship and then I'd be like ooh a pirate ship But then I would see a giant castle.
Speaker 0: I'm like a giant castle.
Speaker 1: one thing I had though.
Speaker 1: I didn't have the pirate ship But there was a big red boat that was like a barge and you could.
Speaker 1: it was a Lego thing and you could put Legos In it and make various types of boats.
Speaker 1: It also actually floated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had a white Speed boat that was like six inches long and four inches tall.
Speaker 1: I always wanted that but I never had it.
Speaker 1: I had the giant red boat.
Speaker 0: There was like a foot and a half long Yeah and you could just put Build any kind of boat on top of it and then it actually had a little slot.
Speaker 0: if you got the motor.
Speaker 1: I got the motor that no one I knew ever had.
Speaker 0: I don't know how you got the motor.
Speaker 0: I didn't see it for sale anywhere But if you got it You could attach it to this boat and it would go around but as long as you didn't weigh this down with a piece of Metal it would float.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did it Once.
Speaker 1: I made a boat that had a big tower in it and then it tipped over and filled with water and sank.
Speaker 1: But I we used to play in the pool actually had an above-ground pool in our backyard.
Speaker 1: I'd take that thing out there and we'd have guys swimming around in the water and fighting with each other.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: yeah, we put it in the pool once but Didn't last very long.
Speaker 1: when I was real real little we used to take it to the bathtub with me constantly.
Speaker 0: It was one of my first Legos, oh man, I could talk forever about my bathtub toys and I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I'll stick with two words.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Bubble.
Speaker 1: Ah Mr.
Speaker 0: Bubbles overrated you suck.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna buy some.
Speaker 0: what are you gonna do about that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you go ahead and take a bath in our bathroom.
Speaker 1: You just do you do that.
Speaker 0: Maybe I will.
Speaker 1: okay That means you'll have to clean it.
Speaker 1: maybe All right, anyway, yeah, we're not gonna do a show on bathroom toys cuz that's not very geek specific every kid had that Sort of toy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah bathroom toys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay Well, I consider my DS a bathroom toy.
Speaker 1: I'll often play the DS while I'm sitting in there doing my various Leanings of my body.
Speaker 0: so Lego.
Speaker 0: Yeah Lego.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So this current like my brother like the gold pieces were rare and we had.
Speaker 1: you know There's a briefcase that came with one set that snapped open.
Speaker 1: You could fit some gold pieces in it.
Speaker 1: That was like the most powerful rare awesome thing because there was only one.
Speaker 1: We always figured that there were like the nuclear secrets in it or whatever.
Speaker 0: All right, I never saw that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what said.
Speaker 1: it came in.
Speaker 1: We had one.
Speaker 1: Okay and the best thing is you know the little jammie pieces like.
Speaker 1: there's the like the yellow ones and what the clear ones for headlights and Like the various different ones.
Speaker 1: you used them for various.
Speaker 1: yeah,
Speaker 0: cuz originally the yellow ones were used as gold and I would take a treasure chest and I would just dump a bunch of Those in there and then eventually when the pirate sets came out They actually had these little flat gold pieces with numbers on them, which is different.
Speaker 1: Yep All I remember is that we we'd assign various because the gems were also energy.
Speaker 1: Like if you want to make a laser gun, you had to have the jammie things on it Or if you wanted to have whatever I mean, but I had various laser security systems being a geeky little kid.
Speaker 1: But the orange ones from the ice planet set were the most powerful because they were the rarest because we had the fewest of them Mm-hmm, and I remember I took the freaking.
Speaker 1: you know, the ice planet had that giant orange shield thing over it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I used that.
Speaker 1: I put it around my base and oh man, that was just nuts Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I remember my brother had a space set with a giant blue shield.
Speaker 1: Oh, I never had that set.
Speaker 1: There was also a set with because there was.
Speaker 1: there were three space sets.
Speaker 1: the ice planet set came much later.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is like a research dome that had this thing had came with the two vehicles that would drive around Picking stuff up and it came with a ship like oh, yeah a separate set.
Speaker 0: There was a robot but its head would fly off as a ship.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never had that idea.
Speaker 0: and shuttle type of ship?
Speaker 1: See, I remember there were two different sets of space guys.
Speaker 1: There were the guys who were like all.
Speaker 1: they were all like blackish and they had the yellow shields And oh, this wasn't it.
Speaker 1: and there were the other guys that had the bluish jammies and the bluish shields.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is the bluish guys with.
Speaker 1: I think those were the good.
Speaker 0: they were all white ships with blue translucent stuff.
Speaker 0: That was those I think were the main space guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I forget what they actually called this stuff.
Speaker 0: They actually had names for it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I never knew it even as a kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we just kind of mish-mashed everything together.
Speaker 1: I mean when our guys would fight, you know They'd run into each other and my brother and I would do a battle.
Speaker 1: some guys have sword some guys have musket Some guys have laser guns Whatever.
Speaker 0: What's up Lego?
Speaker 0: all of the different Lego sets seem to have this plot in this universe, you know Sort of like a campaign setting but they never explain any of it to you and there's no way to find out about it.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: That's good because there's just enough there kids.
Speaker 1: as kids We were cognizant of the fact that there were these different clans of Lego guys and that there was some sort of conflict between them And our fertile minds created the rest of it.
Speaker 0: even today They have what like the bionicle or whatever and there's something to it, but I have no idea what the hell it is.
Speaker 0: You know, what's the story of bionicle?
Speaker 0: does these guys?
Speaker 0: they're bionicles?
Speaker 1: See I remember I had the story of the ice planet was a harsh and unforgiving place and my Lego men were trying to survive in the face of adversity.
Speaker 1: The reactor would break and then they always let.
Speaker 0: the story of the ice planet was that Normal space guys wanted to do some research there and but it was very harsh.
Speaker 0: So they had to you know build bases and do terrible things like sort of like Antarctica.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I played different things all the time and the story of the castles was that the Robin Hood guys were fighting against the evil monarchy which is all dark and evil had wizards and witches and things and the Robin Hood guys were all Valiant and such.
Speaker 1: I remember the glow-in-the-dark ghost.
Speaker 0: Oh my god the glow-in-the-dark ghost.
Speaker 0: I had like two or three glow-in-the-dark ghosts because I got the Tiny $5 glow-in-the-dark ghost set.
Speaker 0: then I got a big castle with a glow-in-the-dark ghost in it And I got something else at the ghost but he was awesome.
Speaker 1: now It seems that Lego was very defined like things click in in very rigid ways but I seem to recall that almost every kid came upon a number of Innovations or discoveries regarding Lego pieces and it seems that these discoveries are universal among children who are geeks.
Speaker 1: The first I remember is that if men were fighting with swords or Spears or whatnot you could always kind of crack the guy's Abdomen open a little bit and stick the sword in him and then leave him there dead with the sword sticking out of his back.
Speaker 1: Yep, every kid did that or you know, you'd have the guy laying there dead.
Speaker 1: You'd pull his hand out still clutching the sword and put it in front of him.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: the one thing I remember really big was I captured one of my little brother's guys once and He wouldn't pay the ransom.
Speaker 1: so what I did is I executed him, you know the whip the green whip Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I used that as a hangman's noose and I made a gallows and I put it around the guy's neck and I hung him From my battlements.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: He I usually use those whips not as whips but The forest men the Robin Hood type of guys.
Speaker 0: They always had this green greenery in all their Buildings to make it look like trees and stuff And I would put these as vines hang from the trees and guys would do sort of a Tarzan thing with them.
Speaker 0: Ah get around.
Speaker 1: I really only used him as hangman's nooses, though I remember when I was young my mother yelling at me for doing something so horrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah My mom didn't really pay attention.
Speaker 1: Well, she did cuz my.
Speaker 1: we were real young and I remember my brother crying that I killed one of his guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah So Legos today really aren't the same as they were when we were Playing with them.
Speaker 1: No, there seem to be so many specialized pieces.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like back in the day when I made these castles and things.
Speaker 0: I made a mostly like 90% out of just Lego bricks.
Speaker 0: Occasionally, there'd be a weird piece like the things that a little window in them.
Speaker 0: But you get a whole bunch of those that became like a standard piece for castles.
Speaker 0: It was like a castle piece.
Speaker 1: Like I remember getting airplanes and they were just.
Speaker 1: it was all just normal pieces.
Speaker 1: There was nothing special to him at all.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Eventually all the sets I'd bought became cannibalized into this giant mishmash of pieces.
Speaker 0: Yeah nowadays and you buy a set it's like it's all there's like.
Speaker 0: there's like barely any normal Lego bricks in there And it's all like specialized pieces that are used to make specifically that thing.
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of the problem is that Legos last forever.
Speaker 1: You can't freaking destroy the things.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think maybe of all the Lego pieces I've ever had one got destroyed because our dog ate it And then when he pooped it out, no one wanted to touch it.
Speaker 1: I think we definitely destroyed one Lego piece Or two Like some of the little things like a sword would break or a spear.
Speaker 0: Sometimes in some piece got stuck somewhere and you couldn't separate it.
Speaker 0: We would like hammer at it or something.
Speaker 1: Oh, didn't you have the separate II thing?
Speaker 1: We got the separate II thing, but I never was unable to separate two pieces.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you're unable to separate something from like the baseboard if there's some.
Speaker 0: if there was some hot and cold involved Baseboard that was cake.
Speaker 1: I never had I never ruined a baseboard.
Speaker 0: No, we didn't ruin the base.
Speaker 0: We're in the piece attached to it.
Speaker 1: But even so 99% of Lego pieces last forever.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's for sure.
Speaker 0: I still got all mine.
Speaker 0: I should bring them here for fun.
Speaker 1: I want mine here.
Speaker 1: as soon as I go to Arizona I'm have.
Speaker 1: I'm shipping them all back to my son.
Speaker 0: next time I go to my house and put them on my car.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know you realize we get Lego.
Speaker 1: That's the end of the podcast cuz that's the end of video games.
Speaker 1: That's the end of everything.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be at least a week of us.
Speaker 1: Just playing with Legos.
Speaker 0: I'll have to get the instructions how to build on my castle sets again.
Speaker 1: I'm totally gonna build the most gigantic empire of death you could imagine.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll go buy a new Lego.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: I can't buy a castle real castle Legos anymore.
Speaker 1: But because they're so enduring it seems like in order to maintain the market of selling more Lego because parents can just keep passing their Legos on to their kids forever They keep coming out with these new sets with more and more specialized pieces that you can't get any other way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do like.
Speaker 0: some of the new sets though like the Star Wars ones are always good.
Speaker 1: yeah, they're alright.
Speaker 1: They still have a lot of pieces that just really only work in those one specific guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't like that at all.
Speaker 0: like You know what to call like the front of a spaceship will be like this pointy bit.
Speaker 0: It's like come on that point even it's not useful for anything.
Speaker 0: It's only useful there for the fronts of spaceships.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all that is I mean even because in the war between me and my brother.
Speaker 1: it finally ended when one day I put together $70 and bought the US Space Shuttle set.
Speaker 0: Was it the Columbia or the?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: What was it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: all I know is it was huge and Like it had it wasn't.
Speaker 1: it was the Space Shuttle and all the pieces like all the part bits of it the solid rocket boosters and the liquid tank Mm-hmm, and it was a baseboard.
Speaker 1: and it was the entire like Tower and the thing that held it up and all these little Wiry rope.
Speaker 0: things damn rules up to it the the launch pad that drives around like a tank.
Speaker 1: That's the only thing it didn't have.
Speaker 1: it had everything else.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: There was not a single specialized piece in that whole thing.
Speaker 1: The entire Space Shuttle and everything was created entirely with normal Lego bricks.
Speaker 0: It didn't have like just you know, a solid rocket booster.
Speaker 0: That was one piece.
Speaker 1: No The solid rocket booster was made with you know, this the fort the four by one the two by two by one Lego pieces that were cylinders.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, that's awesome.
Speaker 1: It was made with just a whole ton of them Yeah, and then at the top there was one of the coney ones that goes into a one at the top and then you stuck a normal.
Speaker 1: I Don't know what to call it.
Speaker 1: They're little cone things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know not the cylinders, but it was a cylinder, but it combed out.
Speaker 0: I know what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those went in the top great.
Speaker 1: The whole thing was just normal pieces.
Speaker 0: So the what about the middle liquid fuel tank thing?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure if I recall correctly was just a bigger cylinder thing that you still had to put together.
Speaker 0: Oh, I never seen a cylinder that big.
Speaker 0: that'd be interesting.
Speaker 1: I forget exactly how it was made.
Speaker 1: I've got the pieces.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd like to see those pieces.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean the only close thing is that's in the big red tower that held it up There were a few like, you know, the castle pieces with the window in them.
Speaker 1: you know, there are some pieces that were.
Speaker 1: there were of that type, but they were more like buttressing or like just Fortification type stuff.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But other than that, it was just regular pieces.
Speaker 0: Wow See nowadays you would get a solid rocket booster piece and a fuel tank piece and like shuttle door pieces You know what?
Speaker 1: If I got something like that, why don't I just buy a model of a space shuttle?
Speaker 1: It's not Legos.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know I mean friggin.
Speaker 1: the doors on the shuttle were normal Lego pieces that you could even find in other sets with the little hinges and everything.
Speaker 0: Like my brother has a Lego x-wing right.
Speaker 0: the four wings are like these wing pieces.
Speaker 0: Ah, it's just like these big triangular flat Legos And it's like that's so terrible.
Speaker 0: Couldn't they make some sort of?
Speaker 0: you know something if they?
Speaker 0: I think the problem is that if you don't make a piece like that You have to make it bigger and thus more expensive with more plastic Yeah, which I was fine with.
Speaker 1: I remember Lego caused more than Nintendo games most of the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the giant.
Speaker 0: I never had the biggest castle of them all even though I wanted it cuz there's a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wanted the monorail more than anything when I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: No one ever got the monorail.
Speaker 0: Little Lego catalog Lego catalog.
Speaker 0: whenever you bought Legos you got it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you'd always stare at that monorail like oh my god I'd be the coolest kid ever.
Speaker 1: This would be the most awesome thing in the world.
Speaker 0: You'd always look through there, and you'd be like all.
Speaker 0: look at set number 6 4 2 1 that's the greatest ever.
Speaker 0: oh look you can buy a set of guys And they come with all those extra items that I don't have.
Speaker 1: I remember on Christmas time time I'd always take the catalog and circle all the things I wanted and give it to my parents.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember my circle almost everything I remember doing that, but I remember not getting really anything from the catalog ever.
Speaker 0: yeah Once I wrote a letter to Lego, and I told them to they should make a set that was army guys like tanks and stuff And they said yeah, it's great.
Speaker 0: They sent me a letter back and that that was it.
Speaker 0: But I'm surprised they don't make army guys Lego You know what.
Speaker 1: definitely let's get our Lego and play with them, and then put pictures online of what we've done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we definitely got to make cool cthulus with them.
Speaker 1: cuz just imagining it.
Speaker 1: now I really have this urge to play with some Lego.
Speaker 1: yeah me too like badly I. I have an urge to play with Lego.
Speaker 1: that's stronger than my urge to play with any piece of entertainment or video game or anything that I currently own.
Speaker 0: I Really hope that all that we've.
Speaker 0: I think this podcast will be considered successful If all our listeners have the same.
Speaker 0: I want to play with Lego urge and have no Legos available.
Speaker 1: So you know what?
Speaker 1: once we get our Lego shipped out here if any of you live nearby We'll totally hang out and play with Lego Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I got dibs on all the horses horses whatever.
Speaker 1: They don't need no stinking horses.
Speaker 1: I'll shoot them with my laser guns and my lightsabers.
Speaker 0: ah Good thing my horses are made of plastic.
Speaker 0: They won't die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah, so that's probably enough about Lego.
Speaker 1: if I talk about him anymore I'm just gonna go nuts because I don't have any to play with.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 0: so in Podcast news yeah some meta bits.
Speaker 0: yet the the podcast reviewer.
Speaker 0: Who's this guy who I guess has a podcast of reviewing podcasts?
Speaker 0: I've listened to him a couple times.
Speaker 0: He's all right.
Speaker 0: I found out about him, and I asked him to review us and To my surprise he actually reviewed us which was kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: yeah, he didn't really say that much about us.
Speaker 0: I think he was a little sick and a little tired.
Speaker 0: You know recently in his life, so I can't really blame him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've been tired for the last couple weeks, so I've been a little off and your banter hasn't been the greatest lately But we're just tired.
Speaker 0: Yeah, our lives are busy very busy, but he reviewed us.
Speaker 0: He said what I considered be mostly compliments But one thing he wanted was there to be separate feeds for separate days.
Speaker 0: You know people were only interested in anime only want to listen on Wednesday and people only interested in games want to listen on Tuesday only.
Speaker 0: so Little did he know that WordPress, which is what our site runs on already has this set up.
Speaker 0: But I just didn't make nice easy links for everyone to use because I was gonna wait until we had the new theme ready.
Speaker 1: Yep, because we're working on that yeah, and we'd actually come up with the idea way back.
Speaker 1: We were gonna just do it for the anime one.
Speaker 1: when we realized that I mean we do four podcasts a week Which the more we're learning is that that's insane.
Speaker 0: it is very bad people.
Speaker 1: That's fucking insane and no one does that.
Speaker 1: like once a week is even a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah Most people record much much less podcasts than we do so our one day a week of anime is more anime Podcasting than most anime podcasts out there.
Speaker 1: So we were thinking we were gonna make a separate feed burner feed and everything for a geek nights anime and market it Separately even though we haven't done any marketing at all.
Speaker 1: yet everyone listens is just all word-of-mouth, which is cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so anyway.
Speaker 0: I made a post on you know front row crew calm You can see it right up there at the top.
Speaker 0: well I guess now it'll if once he posts this podcast they'll be the second one down and it has links to the raw Not so clean, but fully functional.
Speaker 0: Monday Tuesday Wednesday and Thursday Separate podcast feeds.
Speaker 1: I'd hold off on subscribing to him since sometime soon We're gonna set up real feed burner nice feeds for him.
Speaker 0: well They'll work, and they'll work forever.
Speaker 0: just fine, but they won't have all the meta information properly like The name of the episode the name of the show what track?
Speaker 0: well I love the track numbers some of it some of it will be there and some of it won't be.
Speaker 0: I just I can't tell You what will be there and what won't be but it won't be clean.
Speaker 1: use these at your own peril.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'll work.
Speaker 0: I guarantee it'll work.
Speaker 0: Just fine.
Speaker 0: You'll download the mp3s and listen to them.
Speaker 1: You just won't have all the correct information surrounding them though the thing is I think all the people who currently listen Probably just I mean if they're not interested in anime.
Speaker 1: they probably listen to the first half of anime day And then they tune out when we start talking about the anime mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean we really we strive to have some sort of common geekery every day.
Speaker 1: That's why we do the news and things of the day And then we delve into the specifics so people who aren't interested in one topic can just tune out whenever they want.
Speaker 1: yeah But it seems like everyone is listening really wants to listen to every one of them.
Speaker 0: Some people have expressed a desire to only listen one day, so I'll let those people they can do as they wish.
Speaker 1: and plus the nice If I set up the feed burners, that's why I want to do that I'll get nice statistics on how many people and who are listening to what so we'll know what bits are popular.
Speaker 1: It'll give us a lot of good data to figure out how we can make the show better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is a one important thing.
Speaker 0: But for now if you really really just want to listen to one of the days of the week or a couple of them There are separate feeds.
Speaker 0: I made links.
Speaker 1: you can use those until later when we have them more official now of course if you listen to most or all Of them or anything.
Speaker 1: just subscribe to the main one.
Speaker 1: don't bother subscribing to all of these.
Speaker 0: it won't help you silly.
Speaker 1: This is really only for someone who really only wants to listen to our Monday podcast Tuesday or Wednesday or Friday.
Speaker 0: we don't do Friday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah if we did Friday if we did full five days a week We probably die.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be here right now.
Speaker 0: I'd be dead.
Speaker 0: They'd be like this tombstone and a picture of it, and that's all that would be on the website.
Speaker 1: Though I gotta say we're getting a lot better at this.
Speaker 1: I mean we've pretty much gotten down all our ways of interviewing people online or over the phone whatever though We're trying out some more software.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could use a little more interviewing experience.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: but yeah well Someone's recommended to us because Skype doesn't let you record automatically is this gizmo voice over IP which apparently is awesome.
Speaker 0: We'll try it.
Speaker 0: I think Google Talk might be a good thing to try out also.
Speaker 0: yes, it's gonna be in the next version of g-aim and The really the best way ever is to use an asterisk PBX But we don't have a well the best way ever to do it in person.
Speaker 0: Oh of course of course, but the best telephone wars the best telephone ways to use an asterisk PBX But we don't have one.
Speaker 1: so yeah, though.
Speaker 1: I gotta say I am pleased with the fact that we're getting better at this.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean when we first started doing the show.
Speaker 1: well when we first first did the show the beta out like episodes that are Unaired not on the internet unless you know where to look for them.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll release them someday as a yeah We used to sound like this But they were recorded with a crap microphone in the middle of the room and us yelling on either side of it like literally They're terrible.
Speaker 0: those are the days.
Speaker 1: half of it is us arguing with each other about what to say.
Speaker 1: Awesome, but once we really I like once we actually started doing episodes after we got the mixer and the microphones and everything It took about an hour and a half to do post-production on a given episode.
Speaker 1: now It takes about a half hour and most of that time is waiting for my crap ass slow computer to finish processing my filters.
Speaker 0: That's crap a slow computer.
Speaker 0: the video card broke today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh my god I didn't even mention it.
Speaker 1: my met in my meta bits or my leader bits, but I came home from work today And you know what.
Speaker 1: I'll save this for tomorrow All right, so if you want to hear what happened to my computer because it's kind of hilarious Tune in tomorrow or oh wait It's Thursday.
Speaker 1: tune in on Monday.
Speaker 0: tune in Monday for the tale of the screwed up video card.
Speaker 1: Hopefully by then I'll have a new video card and the tale of ubercon.
Speaker 1: Yeah ubercon.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: We definitely got to mention that it'll be on the site, but Saturday We're going to be at ubercon in New Jersey.
Speaker 1: if you want to see us and play games show up We're not hard to spot.
Speaker 1: I'm not kidding.
Speaker 1: Just look for us.
Speaker 1: We're kind of obvious.
Speaker 0: I Think so.
Speaker 1: Well, we're loud annoying geeks who stand at the center of attention shouting about board games and yelling at each other.
Speaker 1: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at Www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206. three three three one five three seven.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.