Speaker 1: It's Monday August 28th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about the miraculous bit.
Speaker 1: tauren.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Well independently of one another.
Speaker 0: all three of us went out of town last weekend.
Speaker 1: Yep, yep, yep.
Speaker 0: I went to Albany to help our friend our friends Kate and Adam move into their new townhouse.
Speaker 1: I would have done that if I didn't go home to my parents house.
Speaker 0: Yep, and Alex also went out to his parents house.
Speaker 0: Holy crap It was a lot of heavy lifting on my part and it took until about two in the morning.
Speaker 1: I did a lot of heavy lifting at like IKEA, but I forgot an important piece to my bookshelf.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean the piece that the instructions say you have to buy the piece that is pictured and everything that you purchase the piece.
Speaker 0: That was obviously necessary.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, I didn't know how to shop at IKEA.
Speaker 1: So what do you want from me?
Speaker 0: Could I ask someone?
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 1: they weren't very helpful.
Speaker 0: What did you ask them?
Speaker 1: I asked them where little metal bits were that held the shelves on.
Speaker 0: I Didn't realize and he answered didn't?
Speaker 0: he told you where to buy the wall mounts.
Speaker 0: Yeah You didn't ask him where the cross braces were.
Speaker 1: I didn't know I needed a cross race.
Speaker 0: Nor did you ask him if you had everything you needed?
Speaker 1: No, no No, so the blame falls squarely on Scott Lloyd Rubin also making IKEA not the easiest place to shop.
Speaker 0: I thought it was perfectly easy.
Speaker 0: You look in the instructions and it says pretty much if you bake this kind of shelf You need a cross brace and then in the picture of the shelf you're making it shows the cross brace.
Speaker 1: I didn't really read the direction so well.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh Yeah Good game Scott.
Speaker 0: But to not bore you with all the details of our mostly unexciting weekends other than the fact that we just got a new board Game that we've been playing a lot and it's a lot of fun, but we're not sure if we like it or not yet.
Speaker 1: Well, I think I like it in terms of it's fun to play.
Speaker 1: the question is how long will it be fun to play?
Speaker 1: and The strategy but that's for a Tuesday.
Speaker 0: It is though I will note that I just creamed in fact between me Alex and Scott.
Speaker 0: Scott only got three points higher game.
Speaker 1: Well, I won the first time we played the second time we played.
Speaker 1: I had a good showing.
Speaker 0: the latest time we played I got hosed See in the three times we play I was in dead.
Speaker 0: last by a lot.
Speaker 0: I was in the middle of the road pretty much right in the middle and then I won by a lot.
Speaker 1: So my performance was inversely proportional to yours.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: and then Alex just did really well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, generally.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway in the news.
Speaker 0: This is a little bit old, but it's something that really bothered me.
Speaker 0: I mean everyone who knows me in the real world nor in meatspace Knows that there are certain issues that even if I don't say anything or if I just let it got by You know There's that glimmer of.
Speaker 0: if I felt like it there would be a torrent of me talking about the topic ad nauseum.
Speaker 0: Maybe a bit of frustration.
Speaker 0: Usually these things are pseudoscientific things.
Speaker 1: We just can't stop yelling about those.
Speaker 0: I mean someone says the word chiropractic and I just think And it really it really takes effort to not say anything.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And another one of those issues is Ecoterrorism.
Speaker 0: now not the fact that it exists or when people talk about it But when it affects the world or when it happens.
Speaker 0: and recently the world has lost a great scientist due to eco terrorism What did they kill him?
Speaker 0: Well, basically Dario Renok I don't know if I'm pronouncing his name, right but he is a well-respected Neuroscientist from UCLA and from what I read on slashdot and articles about him I don't remember exactly what he did and I don't feel like doing any fact-checking tonight.
Speaker 0: But I read that he has done all sorts of fantastic things and he has put forth a lot of Somewhat significant advancements in the various fields surrounding neuroscience new neuroscience.
Speaker 0: Yeah I can't go into more detail than that because I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about neuroscience either.
Speaker 0: See, I looked it up at work But then I got distracted by you know work and then I never bothered to finish looking it up.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: But anyway, he and his family had been harassed or much of his career by eco terrorists and Why would they be harassing a neuro sign?
Speaker 0: Well, because he's a neuroscientist who among other things occasionally experimented on monkeys.
Speaker 1: Well, you need to.
Speaker 1: you're gonna test on human brains.
Speaker 0: see, I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna worry about the issues of you know, why eco terrorists do what they do or Why people care other than the fact that to all the people out there who are staunchly against animal testing in any form I'll know that animal testing has come a long way and it's really not as bad as groups like PETA really want to portray it as.
Speaker 1: and I say no matter how bad it is one Person greater than animal see I disagree.
Speaker 0: I've met a lot of people where I would put a puppy's life ahead of them.
Speaker 0: No, there were pretty bad people are pretty annoying people.
Speaker 0: You would have to.
Speaker 0: Alright, here's a question for you Who would you rather have living in our house right now?
Speaker 0: a puppy that was quiet and well-behaved that I had trained Didn't even poop in the house.
Speaker 0: I've did everything outside.
Speaker 0: or He who shall not be named he who lived with Pete.
Speaker 1: It would be more interesting to have he who shall not be named Because unlike some other people who would allow their lives to be ruined by he who shall not be named I would ruin the life of he who shall not be named.
Speaker 1: I don't think you could and achieve great entertainment from it.
Speaker 0: That's like saying I'm gonna hurt that masochist.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna hurt him real bad.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 0: Alright, how about a nice well-behaved clean puppy or an amalgam of stinky Rob's body Dwayne's brain pre giving up marijuana and Hitler's mustache?
Speaker 1: Hey Hitler's mustache?
Speaker 1: interesting that would definitely Be more interesting.
Speaker 0: Well anyway Nothing I mean, I mean I am against.
Speaker 0: you know there I mean there is some gratuitous animal research out there.
Speaker 0: Luckily that is diminished over the years and a lot of places like cosmetics a lot of cosmetics aren't tested anymore because they're using Really well-known chemicals that have been tested in the past and there's really no reason to test these things further Mmm, so if someone was still testing, you know, like I'm gonna keep injecting this deodorant into this rate.
Speaker 0: These are cats eyes for a hundred years.
Speaker 0: Let's just stupid.
Speaker 0: Mmm or a guy who's like I'm gonna boil a monkey just to see what happens that that's not cool Point.
Speaker 0: other than I'm sure pen would have a lot to say about that.
Speaker 0: I'm sure he would laugh hysterically.
Speaker 0: I don't think that it is worth either the monkeys pain or the possible entertainment pen would get.
Speaker 1: yeah I I'll agree that you know, okay if I have a choice between saving a person and saving a monkey I'm probably gonna say it's time for the monkey to go.
Speaker 1: But if you're just gonna kill a monkey for no reason, I'm gonna say what the hell don't kill that monkey.
Speaker 1: for no reason We might be able to use that monkey's life to save a human life or possibly Another monkey's life.
Speaker 0: I mean there are cats that get insulin shots because they have diabetes.
Speaker 0: Wow, yeah, so it.
Speaker 0: animal testing also helps animals.
Speaker 0: to all you dirty hippies out there.
Speaker 1: Did the cats hurt when they pee?
Speaker 0: Take it out of my wife and dog.
Speaker 1: How's the cat?
Speaker 1: take it out of the dog?
Speaker 1: That's interesting.
Speaker 0: I You know what I've noticed.
Speaker 0: we can't with diabetes While we're losing it today, it's over.
Speaker 1: it's a cat with diabetes.
Speaker 0: I Tell you now out there seriously that we don't find diabetes funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my grandpa had diabetes.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm not kidding But a cat with diabetes is hilarious anyway.
Speaker 0: There's the thing is I trust the scientific community and the people who do this research because I know people personally who do Research like this or who facilitate this research that the scientists do it because they feel that what they are doing will benefit the world or benefit mankind and It is they.
Speaker 0: they put a lot of thought into it.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of ethics involved and a lot of scientists will refuse to do research.
Speaker 0: That is just obviously stupid or harmful without any reasonable benefit or gratuitous or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's not like back in the day when you had like crazy Russian and you know Nazi scientists who would just do whatever the hell they want to do.
Speaker 1: mad science, you know, it doesn't happen anymore.
Speaker 1: Scientists actually know what they're doing and they won't do bad things.
Speaker 1: I mean someone who's sitting around going.
Speaker 1: I need to cure AIDS trying to figure out how to cure AIDS.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be like let me totally mutilate some monkeys.
Speaker 0: Boil a monkey.
Speaker 0: see if that kills the AIDS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not doing that shit because they're smart now.
Speaker 0: Despite this this this man who apparently had tested on monkeys was a well-respected well-known Neuroscientist who'd contributed volumes of work and data and experience and knowledge to the scientific community and it advanced mankind.
Speaker 0: he'd been harassed and his family had been harassed for years by various activists and Just recently.
Speaker 0: He decided that he's going to retire.
Speaker 0: He's given in to these effectively terrorist demands or feared not so much for fear of his life and not even so much for Family's life but for fear for the lives of people around him.
Speaker 0: because just recently these eco terrorists tried to firebomb Something it was either his house or facility he worked at and they accidentally left one of their Molotov cocktails on just like a neighbor's porch and He said he's had enough.
Speaker 0: He's not going to risk people's lives for his research and he's given up.
Speaker 0: The world is lost to scientists because of what are effectively terrorists.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well number one How can you tell someone that they're bad?
Speaker 1: for even if he was killing monkeys just killing tons of monkeys How can you tell you him that he's bad when you're fire bombing people with Molotov cocktails?
Speaker 0: I guess their rationale is that if I kill this one man, I'll save a whole bunch of monkeys.
Speaker 1: Okay, number two if I was this guy, I would say I was quitting science and continue science in secret.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe he is.
Speaker 0: he's smart.
Speaker 0: He's smarter than us.
Speaker 1: number three If a guy was outside my window with Molotov cocktails, I would shoot him.
Speaker 0: now The thing that bothers me is not.
Speaker 0: I mean not only.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't want to use the word hippies because hippie is a really broad term and I don't now it's a broad term.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it used to be more specific.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I guess I want to use the phrase dirty hippies when I answer.
Speaker 0: When I say dirty hit the one I don't even really mean people who just happen to not bathe and happen to be very free Or happen to be very spiritual.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Those are plain hippies.
Speaker 0: When I say dirty hippie, I effectively mean eco terrorists pseudo scientists and all that tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they they do these things.
Speaker 0: Yet they're really not given the label terrorists despite the fact that they're terrorists.
Speaker 1: Well, some of them are given the label terrorists.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: There are organizations a lot of them in the u.s That pretty much promote all of these terrorist acts straight up and openly Mm-hmm, but yet they always say and the courts always hold up that they're not responsible when these things happen because they didn't Directly do it.
Speaker 0: They just happen to post this guy's address and they just happen to post molotov cocktail Instructions and someone just happened to follow these instructions.
Speaker 0: They didn't take direct action and very rarely.
Speaker 0: but then how come like how can we go after Hezbollah?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, how come?
Speaker 1: I say all sorts of things, you know, sometimes like oh what if I did this?
Speaker 1: and you always say But then you're telling someone to do that.
Speaker 1: You can't tell someone to do bad things.
Speaker 0: See, there's a real fine line and a couple of these people have gone down before.
Speaker 0: no, but the sad fact remains that you know Hezbollah maybe might not do anything directly But then someone does something in their name and then oh we can't blame Hezbollah.
Speaker 0: or the thing is we do blame Hezbollah but then someone does something in the name of the animal liberation front and Oh, well, that wasn't us.
Speaker 0: That wasn't them.
Speaker 0: That was just some crazy.
Speaker 1: What bothers me more right is of course the people doing Terrorist acts like bombing stuff are way out of control and you know, that's a separate thing.
Speaker 1: forget them.
Speaker 1: It's the people right under them the people who sort of agree with what those Terrorists are fighting for but aren't evil and doing terrorism.
Speaker 1: The problem I have is that those hippies that aren't actually terrorists but agree that you know You shouldn't test on monkeys or whatever Those are generally good people with good intentions, you know, like they want good Yeah, I don't want evil but they're just.
Speaker 1: they don't understand They're ignorant or they're dumb or they're doing used or they're being used like someone is just you know Feeding them false information.
Speaker 0: petta petta Michael Moore Even though Michael Moore is not nearly so bad cuz at least he's entertaining.
Speaker 0: There's nothing funny about PETA.
Speaker 0: That's true But you know and oh as an aside don't forget the head of PETA is diabetic.
Speaker 0: She uses insulin.
Speaker 0: Oh, but we tested insulin on animals.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the point is is that these people if you know anyone else had, you know Given them the correct information would be on the good road.
Speaker 0: They'd all be cool or in the very least they might say be rational about it.
Speaker 0: Like I still disagree with the animal testing because I am against science and whatever But I'm not going to kill people because my belief the thing is is you know, someone could be evil.
Speaker 1: someone could be Rationally or irrationally evil and it doesn't matter either way because the result is the same.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but someone can be rationally or irrationally good and it's the irrationally good people that it's like.
Speaker 1: What do I do with you?
Speaker 1: You won't listen to me because you're not Rational, but you're not doing good like you want to.
Speaker 1: you're doing bad because you don't know any better.
Speaker 0: I mean, there are a lot of environmentalists that really care about the environment.
Speaker 0: they get active, you know They work on recycling programs and they do good things.
Speaker 0: Then there are a lot of environmentalists who they don't know much about it.
Speaker 0: So like they'll campaign against nuclear power because they think it's dangerous.
Speaker 0: They think they're doing a good thing when really nuclear power is probably the cleanest form of energy.
Speaker 1: We have yep It's like oh, I just don't know what to do with those people.
Speaker 1: The worst part is it's like I'd rather have the rational evil guy Cuz.
Speaker 1: at least I can talk to him and he'll talk back in a way that makes sense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if he's saying the wrong thing, I mean if you went up to Emperor Palpatine You know after you know in the fourth fifth sixth movies of Star Wars and you say you know, you said hey You're an evil fuck.
Speaker 1: He would say Yep, and then he'd zap you with his lightning and you'd say yeah, that's about what I expect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you might say at least you know what you're getting, you know, the irrationally good people.
Speaker 1: It's like oh They hurt so much.
Speaker 0: now that the worst part is.
Speaker 0: I mean at least I can almost Understand what went through these guys tiny little brains because you know, he's testing on monkeys.
Speaker 0: So we'll kill him Apparently in 2001. the ELF.
Speaker 0: I don't know what that stands for.
Speaker 0: It's one of those groups.
Speaker 0: It stands for elf, you know, like Rivendell they bombed a facility at the University of Washington for kind of the same reasons.
Speaker 0: now You might think oh was it the facility of monkey testing or the facility of crushing cats?
Speaker 1: It was like a planetarium or something wasn't it?
Speaker 0: It was the University of Washington Center for Urban horticulture Plants nothing but plants.
Speaker 0: they were studying how to grow plants in cities, basically But they happened to have done a little bit of genetic engineering on these plants.
Speaker 0: That is why these dirty hippies bombed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think I need to go in anymore because I don't want to turn this into the episode of rim bitches about eco Terrorists dirty hippies and pseudoscience, but suffice to say I really don't like eco terrorists dirty hippies pseudoscience and I was gonna say someone's name just to be funny, but never mind.
Speaker 1: Well get ready for fun cuz we're gonna bitch and moan about DRM now.
Speaker 0: God damn it.
Speaker 1: So Windows Microsoft Windows and Windows Media format have a DRM Schema, I guess you would call it known as plays for sure plays the number four and then sure as opposed to Apple's fair play.
Speaker 0: All right, that's somewhat painful because it's not even lead speak.
Speaker 0: It's just like cutesy aim speed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you buy you know an mp3 player that supports plays for sure.
Speaker 1: or you have Windows Media Player or You know anything like that.
Speaker 1: you can get plays for sure DRM files and play them.
Speaker 0: do those files even exist?
Speaker 1: Yes, you can get plays for sure DRM files.
Speaker 1: I think if you sign up to Napster or a couple other of the you know, those pay services.
Speaker 1: I think they provide you with plays for sure files.
Speaker 1: now the way some of those services work is you basically pay monthly to like maintain your account and Then you get so many songs, but you can also buy more songs.
Speaker 1: I'm not exactly sure if they specific.
Speaker 0: is this one of those?
Speaker 0: when you stop paying you lose access.
Speaker 1: Exactly when you stop paying you lose your songs.
Speaker 0: That's such a bad idea for so many reasons no matter how you feel about DRM.
Speaker 0: That's a bad idea.
Speaker 0: Yep now can't okay.
Speaker 1: anyway some guy came up with this program called fair use the number four and then the WM.
Speaker 1: so fair use for Windows Media.
Speaker 1: It removes the encryption and the DRM from plays for sure files.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: This guy is probably one of the closest men or women to being given the title of a geek night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like DVD yawn.
Speaker 1: and then this guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm real happy with this guy.
Speaker 0: In fact, I think he I'm going to nominate him as the first possible candidate for this year's geek night possibly possibly Anyway.
Speaker 1: So like one guy was writing an article like please Microsoft don't patch The DRM.
Speaker 1: to fix this we want to be able to use this program.
Speaker 1: Please don't patch it.
Speaker 0: Wait, please Microsoft.
Speaker 0: Don't fix this obviously glaring hole in your failing DRM scheme Exactly.
Speaker 1: Well as we know it is Technologically impossible to create a DRM scheme that is foolproof because you are essentially giving someone something but you're giving it to them inside of a safe and then you're giving them the key and You just have you know some sort of mechanism on the safe where the key only works at certain times.
Speaker 1: But they have the key and they have the safe.
Speaker 1: So eventually they're going to figure out how to open the safe and keep it open and even then you can always figure it out Because of the analog hole.
Speaker 0: I think I need an analog hole.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a hole.
Speaker 1: There's a hole in the back of the safe that they can peek into and eventually they'll figure out how to suck Whatever's in there out that hole.
Speaker 0: if anyone feels like it try to make us an audio.
Speaker 0: That is some sort of booming Analog hole thing.
Speaker 1: we should just turn on the echo effect and say analog hole analog hole.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright, I think that's what we'll do.
Speaker 0: We'll get someone who can sing.
Speaker 1: Yep, the point is now is that maybe if Microsoft doesn't patch this is it now smart to sign up for like the new?
Speaker 1: Napster and get a crap ton of music that is not DRM.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Most of the music I like isn't on Napster anyway.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: But for other people who are into the current music, you know,
Speaker 0: maybe I mean I guess my opinion is that I mean early on I hated the RIA and you know Bastards and I'd always fight it and I fired everything and I realized that the vast majority of the music I was pirating had almost nothing to do with any of this because most of the music I like is either foreign old or Obscure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean all the old music that was RAA I got in the Napster days and the win Mx days and now there really isn't.
Speaker 0: you know, you can't make what we've got Every little we've got every Rolling Stones.
Speaker 1: No one's making more old music.
Speaker 1: It's already existing.
Speaker 1: That's why it's old.
Speaker 1: I've already got all of it that I want.
Speaker 1: if I want more I can go and get like.
Speaker 1: I can go buy UCDs rip them and get them back to the UCD store or I can go to my dad's, you know Take a you know, his turndable and a vinyl record and take them off with the analog hole.
Speaker 1: but You know the new music I don't care about but some people do.
Speaker 0: and thus well, I care about new music.
Speaker 0: I don't care about top 40s new music.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I mean by new.
Speaker 1: I mean, I gotta say music in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Total aside, but I have fallen in love with the cat Empire All right.
Speaker 1: I don't care so much for the cat Empire.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't like ska Kinda you don't even like any of the sky I've played except for like that one song from snatch.
Speaker 1: There's a few skies.
Speaker 0: this town is looking like a ghost town Whatever.
Speaker 1: Okay So that's that's the news.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of an old news.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: It's like from a while ago, but from that long ago.
Speaker 1: It's like August 25th.
Speaker 0: Oh Whatever.
Speaker 0: What day is today sky?
Speaker 1: It was three days ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: When was the last time we did a show?
Speaker 0: Uh Yeah, we pretty much broke this news as soon as we could without doing a geek nights on the scheduled news bulletin Which we've never had cause to do yet.
Speaker 0: Yep, rest assured though if something crazy ever happens There's gonna be a geek nights about it right away unless we're dead or we're there or we caused it.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: All right This one's a bit old but I don't think a lot of people out there have seen it and I think it's pretty cool partly Because I did something similar though on a much lower scale than this, dude Now I'm sure.
Speaker 0: well, I hope because I realized that a lot of our listeners are younger than us.
Speaker 0: There was this golden age of nerf when we were kids because when I was young the nerf bow and arrow debuted.
Speaker 0: It was a one-of-a-kind toy.
Speaker 0: It was the first toy like that and It was amazing.
Speaker 0: It sold out immediately.
Speaker 0: There was crazy runs on it like there were for Cabbage Patch Dolls back in the day and I don't know tickle me elbows and all that crap.
Speaker 0: In fact, it was so bad that on Christmas.
Speaker 0: My brother got one, but there weren't anymore.
Speaker 0: So I didn't get one.
Speaker 0: I got this knockoff Robin Hood bow and arrow with terrible foam arrows that barely worked.
Speaker 1: See we had very little nerve stuff, you know, because at first my parents were like apprehensive.
Speaker 1: They were like, I don't know if we're gonna get you nerve what but then you know Eventually, we got some.
Speaker 1: we just didn't get a giant arsenal.
Speaker 1: nerf was no one I knew actually had an entire.
Speaker 1: Most people just had like a bow and arrow and a ball Zuka and that was it where I grew up.
Speaker 0: Everyone had an arsenal of nerf.
Speaker 0: nerf was such a pivotal part of my childhood.
Speaker 0: In fact, I would say nerf Nintendo slash Atari, uh old like Hitchcock Vincent Price movies and Damn Dungeons & Dragons pretty much define my childhood.
Speaker 0: And I had like every good nerf thing because nerf started out great and all the original nerfs were awesome awesome awesome.
Speaker 0: and Then they fell to super soaker syndrome because the I'd say that the some of the original super super soakers Much like the original nerf were far superior to the products that came out later and they kept discontinuing good products and then releasing Crappy breakable big pieces of plastic products.
Speaker 1: Yeah nerf did over time decrease in quality.
Speaker 1: The early nerf stuff was light on the plastic and was very functional.
Speaker 1: later There was a lot of flair Like.
Speaker 1: I remember that we had a nerf gun with like a LED sight that would kind of work like a laser But it was.
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: The nerf bow and arrow was a fantastic toy and I never understood why they discontinued it and why they made just crap.
Speaker 0: nerf.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're disappeared nowadays.
Speaker 1: They still have nerf but barely Yeah.
Speaker 0: and when I was a kid like we would have wars where Everyone was art like I have a nerf bow and arrow on my back and I'd have to like single shot pistols.
Speaker 1: It was all about the at six shooter of arrows.
Speaker 1: It had six big arrows.
Speaker 1: anyone doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 0: Yes, that was in fact the best nerf gun and that was like the m16 of nerf.
Speaker 1: It fired six arrows and all you did was pull the trigger six times.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, no No That one is crap compared to the original incarnation of that where it was a pump.
Speaker 0: you basically pulled it back and then it fired And then you pushed it forward and it rotated the Gatling gun mechanism.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the what the Gatling good.
Speaker 0: It didn't have a trigger I thought you.
Speaker 1: you pumped it and then you pulled it.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: No, you didn't pull the trigger.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I know my nerf.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't have it.
Speaker 0: So it was called the nerf arrow store.
Speaker 1: That was the one.
Speaker 0: it was the best nerf gun ever made.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the one now.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I Somewhat modified my arrow storm because later this thing I think was called a razorback came out and it was actually.
Speaker 0: That was the beginning of the end of nerf because that was the first bad nerf product.
Speaker 0: It was a Gatling gun.
Speaker 0: that well, it wasn't really a Gatling gun.
Speaker 0: It was a chain fed machine gun How's that?
Speaker 0: and it had this plastic chain?
Speaker 0: you loaded it with these orange suction darts and you cranked it and it just spat out arrows like bit a bit a bit a bit a bit a bit a bit a bit a bit a bit a Problem.
Speaker 0: was it jammed like a motherfucker.
Speaker 0: It barely worked.
Speaker 0: It didn't shoot very hard or very far and the chain would just break.
Speaker 0: but the arrows I noticed fit inside of the Launchers for the arrow storm because normally you would put a big yellow arrow over the arrow storm.
Speaker 0: Instead I'd shove these tiny little orange arrows into the launcher.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it used to be an arrow with a hole in it and you would stick a little.
Speaker 1: you know A blower of air would blow air into the arrow.
Speaker 1: Now you're stuffing that blower with an arrow in it.
Speaker 0: I also opened the thing and put a bigger spring in it Now when I would shoot it at people because the people come into my basement and I'd be like check out my nerf gun and they'd always say that doesn't look like and then I'd shoot him with it.
Speaker 0: and As far as I can gather because I was never personally shot with my own gun, but apparently it hurt a lot And it was fantastic Awesome.
Speaker 0: Now this guy did something times a million to get back on track.
Speaker 0: He made a bonafide nerf sniper rifle.
Speaker 1: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: You have to see this thing.
Speaker 0: This is a sniper rifle.
Speaker 1: It's quite large and quite high quality.
Speaker 1: Like usually you see someone make a mod and it's slightly shoddy.
Speaker 1: This thing is polished.
Speaker 0: It looks really good.
Speaker 0: The guy doesn't look like a super nerd and the thing looks like it really really hurts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you can tell by the way he loads the arrow bolt into it how quality it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so check this video out.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: Okay, so this isn't really the greatest thing of the day but it's it's a good example of Linux Discrimination if you will.
Speaker 0: Ah, you're doing my classic.
Speaker 0: I don't have a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'll take a news and just kind of jam it into the thing of the day spot sort of.
Speaker 1: it's not really a news so much Yeah, anyway at New York Times com the website of the New York Times.
Speaker 1: they have some videos and Some of these videos are in different sections on the site.
Speaker 1: Now these videos play with the flash player.
Speaker 1: It's it's sort of like YouTube, you know.
Speaker 1: It's it's flash video with a slightly different piece of you know, not the same as YouTube, but it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: anyway If you want to watch a video on the front page It just shows up and you click play and you watch it.
Speaker 1: It works fine in every web browser and every operating system as long as you have a New enough version of flash that supports flash video and it doesn't matter if you're using Firefox or IE or whatever.
Speaker 1: however For some reason on Linux if you decide to go to the video section of the New York Times website it It won't work.
Speaker 1: It won't actually let you go there even if you know You have.
Speaker 1: you know, obviously your computer can play the video because it's playing the video on the front page.
Speaker 1: But if you go to the video page where there are more videos, it won't let you go there now, uh, it gets better.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you realize it only looks at the user agent string and if you change that it works just fine in Linux?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: So there's absolutely no reason for it to not work in Linux except that all they do is they check to see if you're using Linux and if you are they make it break on purpose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well it's it's not if you're using Linux.
Speaker 1: it doesn't say if Linux don't work.
Speaker 1: It says if you're not using Internet Explorer if you don't have a new enough flash And if you're you know, not using Netscape 6.2 or higher then don't let them view this page.
Speaker 1: show them this error message instead.
Speaker 1: now For me, I just tried it.
Speaker 1: It just worked.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they change something or if my user agent is lying or well This is all you with the new with this thing.
Speaker 0: If you got some bad reporting and it's not true it's not it.
Speaker 1: If it's not true anymore, then it's changed very recently.
Speaker 1: The point is Rob limo an old slashdot guy made a video on his computer of him You know falling into this trap on Linux and you can watch this video Which is the thing of the day the video itself where he shows the blatant discrimination by the New York Times against Linux.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, it's bad enough that a lot of people don't make things for Linux, you know, or whatever.
Speaker 1: But someone to make a website that Linux would normally work just fine on but they purposefully filter you out.
Speaker 1: It's like uh, all I got to say is that no website Anywhere ever any more Ellie in the past.
Speaker 1: It was okay to do this, but not anymore.
Speaker 1: You should never check to see what you know operating system and browser Your visitors are using and then decide not to let them see your content.
Speaker 0: You should just you could warn them.
Speaker 0: Hey, I suck and the site might not work with you.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: You can also, you know Change the content differently like let's say, you know If someone has IE then you want to use this CSS and if they're using Firefox you want to use this CSS because it'll make the page look correct because the browsers do CSS differently.
Speaker 1: That's fine But you should never block anyone From seeing your site based on the browser or else you're an ass because that's not necessary anymore.
Speaker 1: they might have a browser that will be able to render your content just fine and You're gonna prevent them from seeing it because you're not sure if it will work or because you don't know about their obscure browser.
Speaker 1: Screw you screw you with a hose.
Speaker 1: so this video demonstrates Exactly this principle in action.
Speaker 0: and so on.
Speaker 0: to the actual main bit today something we kind of spoke.
Speaker 0: Scott said we talked about it.
Speaker 0: I didn't say anything, but it's something we could do.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's easy and it's informative and a lot of people seem to not quite grasp this concept that I thought was common knowledge.
Speaker 0: Yes Now we're going to talk today about bit torrents
Speaker 1: something you should already have known about
Speaker 0: Partly because there are a lot of misconceptions as to what bit torrent is and who it benefits
Speaker 1: and what it's for and how it Even though all of this is widely publicized and talked about.
Speaker 0: so first I guess a bit of history Okay.
Speaker 1: Well back in the day occasionally, there would be a very popular file that people would want to download like perhaps the latest update to counter-strike or a large ISO to a new version of a Linux distribution or a Final Fantasy 5 translated ROM That's a personal story.
Speaker 1: I got boned Anyway, or a new anime fan sub.
Speaker 1: Now the solutions.
Speaker 1: in the past this would cause a problem because if a lot of people all wanted the same file at the same Time you needed a gigantic computer to be able to serve it to all of those people Gigantic.
Speaker 1: now sometimes you could set up some mirrors and people would you know disperse themselves among the mirrors?
Speaker 1: However, they wanted.
Speaker 1: but this is bad, too Because now everyone has to go to all these mirrors and some people hit all the mirrors because you can't stop them from doing that You know.
Speaker 0: So that didn't work out either and there was also the issue that it's not like these files would be Downloaded like this all the time and you needed this horsepower all the time.
Speaker 0: It would be a swarm You know.
Speaker 0: a million people try to download the file over the course of a week and then five people try to download it a Month later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like you buy a gigantic computer to serve one file and then nothing.
Speaker 1: I mean sure someone could start a business where they have giant computers that they rent out, but that's not ideal either.
Speaker 1: You know, there are other people set up systems of cues.
Speaker 1: read wait in line and then get the file.
Speaker 0: That's just piss people off.
Speaker 0: Yeah with things like hotline or different IRC f-serve File planet pretty much only exists because of this problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they came up with file planet which used to be.
Speaker 1: you just go to file planet and get video game files.
Speaker 1: That's how it used to be.
Speaker 1: Now if you want to go to file planet and you don't want to pay money You have to wait in line to get a file.
Speaker 1: if you want to pay money You can just get the file right away because barely anyone pays money.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: don't go to file planet never go to file planet.
Speaker 1: unless there's absolutely nowhere else you can get the file you want.
Speaker 1: and if you Really really really need it and can't get it anywhere else.
Speaker 0: So what to do?
Speaker 1: Yes what to do about this problem?
Speaker 1: if only there was some way that you know, we could all get a file at the same time and Without having anyone need a gigantic server and a gigantic bandwidth bill.
Speaker 0: now this is where BitTorrent comes in because essentially in a very high level what it does is if One person wants to download a file.
Speaker 0: They get it from the server.
Speaker 0: If two people want to download the file, they both get different parts from the server, then they share those parts.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: If a hundred people want to get a file from a server a hundred people are all getting different parts and sharing them with each Other.
Speaker 0: so the server is effectively in this high-level somewhat optimal theoretical situation Only giving the file out once and then it's being shared by everyone else in a swarm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, more people download the faster it gets and the server no matter how many people are downloading it sees almost no traffic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's be a little more specific.
Speaker 1: Let's say you have a file.
Speaker 1: That's a hundred megabytes right now.
Speaker 1: You need to give it to a whole mess of people.
Speaker 1: What you do is you break it into smaller bits, let's say each of them is one megabyte and there's a hundred of them.
Speaker 1: I'm just making up numbers.
Speaker 1: They're probably much smaller and You need to give this to a thousand people.
Speaker 1: Well first you give one packet, you know one megabyte to one guy.
Speaker 1: Then you give a different piece to a different guy and a different piece to a different guy.
Speaker 1: Then they share the bits among themselves.
Speaker 1: So everyone is out there saying I need this bit and then someone gives them that bit.
Speaker 0: So I have one in three.
Speaker 0: Scott has two and four.
Speaker 0: I give him the ones he needs and he gives me the ones I need and eventually everyone has all the ones they need.
Speaker 1: but they don't all get them from the server.
Speaker 1: They don't all get them from one person.
Speaker 1: They all get them from different people over time.
Speaker 1: So, of course the actual download speed is going to be slower because you're losing time Trying to figure out who to get the next bit from.
Speaker 1: you're getting different bits from different people who transfer the bits at different speeds.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not good at the same time.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: one You're downloading all these different bits at the same time up to the cap of your bandwidth and their bandwidth.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And two there's no waiting.
Speaker 1: Yes, you know, that was the biggest problem was the waiting?
Speaker 1: I mean sure back in the day downloading a counter-strike update as soon as you actually started downloading.
Speaker 1: it would be as fast as you and that server could go and it Would go to done because it would just send you the whole file in a straight shot.
Speaker 1: But you had to wait so long and you had to keep clicking on different mirrors until you found a link that worked and it Was just a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: with bit torrent you click once and you wait and you leave, you know You don't have to sit there doing things You just get up and leave you come back and it will eventually be there and it's all happy.
Speaker 1: Okay, let's talk a little bit about Where bit torrent came from?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, you're the one who looked all that up.
Speaker 0: Yes, I didn't remember who made bit torrent.
Speaker 1: I used to know his name because it used to Bram Cohen like I thought yeah there's a guy named Bram Cohen and he worked for a company called mojo nation.
Speaker 1: that was Basically, they were making a system that allowed people to break up files into little bits and encrypt them and then Distribute those encrypted bits over computers running them, you know mojo nation software.
Speaker 1: So it was sort of like this security thing where files got broken into bits and then sent in bits.
Speaker 1: You know like, you know different chunks That were encrypted for security.
Speaker 1: So that way no one could spy on your file because they only had a small portion of it Which is useless, you know.
Speaker 1: and those small portions would all go to different places on the internet and eventually You know end up where they were supposed to be.
Speaker 1: He left that company and made bit torrent which does you know breaks things into bits to share them instead of you know encrypting them all secret like.
Speaker 1: And we have bit torrent today.
Speaker 1: now today bit torrent is like an actual company that does things Instead of just.
Speaker 1: it used to be one guy asking for donations and getting a lot of publicity.
Speaker 1: Now it's a whole company with businessmen and all sorts of fanciness and that's a good thing.
Speaker 1: I say it's I mean the guy Bram Cohen's still the CEO.
Speaker 1: So The key invented it pretty much all on his own.
Speaker 0: Now I've noticed a lot of people lately partly in our forums and partly on the internet.
Speaker 0: They'll complain about bit torrent in that they'll say things like oh, I want to download this anime.
Speaker 0: That was on anime Sookie a month ago, but there's no seeds and it's downloading really slowly.
Speaker 0: I thought bit torrent was supposed to make this fast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, bit torrent wasn't supposed to make it fast.
Speaker 0: It was supposed to make the files available And basically it's faster the more people are downloading it.
Speaker 0: so if something's not popular anymore it's going to be at best as fast as that server could have served it on his own and probably broken because For various reasons mostly involving copyright law torrents tend to be very ephemeral.
Speaker 0: They come and go and then they're gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something you have to understand about bit torrent is The cedars and leechers and back in the day leecher meant you know someone who downloaded a whole bunch and never uploaded anything on a network like Napster or something.
Speaker 1: and You know leecher and bit torrent doesn't mean exactly the same thing, but it's pretty close in in its meaning except It's not really a bad thing because it's just how it works.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of people can't really serve so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, leecher used to be a bad saying like hey, you're downloading a whole bunch of stuff off Napster But you're not sharing anything.
Speaker 1: you've got, you know, and that wasn't cool.
Speaker 1: But nowadays leecher me in bit torrent when you're downloading something.
Speaker 1: You're also uploading at the same time.
Speaker 1: So a leecher isn't a total leecher.
Speaker 1: There's also a cedar.
Speaker 1: a cedar is Someone who's already downloaded the entire file.
Speaker 1: but they are continuing to send chunks out to people who need those chunks and that More cedars that you can find on a torrent the faster it will go.
Speaker 1: So leechers help a bit because you know They're uploading and downloading.
Speaker 1: but cedars help a whole lot because you can ask a cedar and you know, he'll have whatever chunk you need.
Speaker 1: So the more cedars and the more leechers out there the faster the torrents gonna be.
Speaker 1: but that's not the only factor.
Speaker 1: a lot of People still complain, you know that a torrent isn't working.
Speaker 1: Well Even when there are a whole bunch of cedars and leechers.
Speaker 1: Well, it could.
Speaker 1: a torrent could work really well when there's only one cedar in leecher if that cedar is your next-door neighbor Because you're gonna be able to get all the chunks from him right away and you won't need to worry about anyone else in the Whole world, you know.
Speaker 1: But you know, there could be a hundred cedars on the other side of the world Which means it's gonna be slow because no matter who you're getting the chunks from they're on the other side of the world.
Speaker 0: or there Could be one cedar who's well, he's seeding for you and he's really really fast, but he only has half the file.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the rest of the file is all coming.
Speaker 0: Everyone is getting the file from the.
Speaker 1: well He's only got half the file.
Speaker 1: He's not a cedar.
Speaker 1: He's still leecher.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but he's all.
Speaker 1: you can also be serving Yep, and you know and the thing is is when someone makes a new bit torrent what they do is they take a file That's already completed.
Speaker 1: They then create a torrent file.
Speaker 1: Then that torrent file is a small tiny file that anyone could download in like a second from a website.
Speaker 1: if they're so small and insignificant I think if you're on dial-up, it would take you less than a minute to download a torrent file and You give that torrent file to your torrent client and that tells the torrent client how to start how to find the tracker and how?
Speaker 1: To get those chunks of the file and you know who's seeding it and who's leeching it and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: We could go into more detail, but you probably don't care.
Speaker 0: if you guys really care.
Speaker 0: Let us know.
Speaker 0: We'll do another episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much what it is is the tracker tells you where the other bit torrent are.
Speaker 1: Torrent errors are for the file and then you know, the torrent file tells you what the file looks like.
Speaker 1: That's why when you start a new bit torrent the file appears right away because the bit torrent file tells you how big the file is and what its name is and all that good stuff and Then it just fills the file with data as it does its torrent thing.
Speaker 0: now There are also ways to do like trackerless torrents, which basically it doesn't mean trackerless Actually, it means that everyone is a tracker basically.
Speaker 0: Yep Yep and the the only thing you need to know is that there are two ways to go about this the Normal way that every bit torrent client in the world except one uses and then the azure is way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the way that every other bit torrent client in the world uses is the one that is recommended.
Speaker 0: What DH?
Speaker 1: DHT is developed by the bit torrent company.
Speaker 1: So it's the official way and that's the way you probably want to do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because if you do it the azure is way.
Speaker 0: you can only take advantage of this with other.
Speaker 0: azure is users.
Speaker 1: Yep Now a lot of people get confused and they think a tracker is the same thing as like a listing.
Speaker 1: a listing is not the same Thing as a tracker.
Speaker 1: all the tracker does is it tells you where the other people are torrenting?
Speaker 1: You never look at a tracker only the bit torrent client talks to the tracker.
Speaker 1: it's not something you see with your eyeballs.
Speaker 1: generally a Listing is a place where you get torrent files and torrent files are listed and those are like, you know websites like, you know mini Nova and torrent spy and torrent box torrent reactor torrent reactor and The the ill-fated Loki torrents.
Speaker 0: I remember Loki torrents.
Speaker 1: Yep, then they got hosed by course.
Speaker 0: Luckily.
Speaker 0: We have the Pirates Bay.
Speaker 0: The Pirates Bay will never die.
Speaker 1: the king of torrent tracker not torrent listings.
Speaker 1: Yes, not track the pirate listing.
Speaker 0: Yes exactly.
Speaker 0: Anyway now in terms of actually using bit torrent I assume all of you out there can do it.
Speaker 0: you download a bit torrent client now and get the Bit torrent client if you want, there are also a million other bit torrent clients.
Speaker 1: I prefer the bit torrent client.
Speaker 1: However, you can also get a serious which is a big Java thing.
Speaker 0: Yep, a serious is really really simple to use.
Speaker 1: you can get.
Speaker 1: a very popular one is micro torrent Which is not actually micro torrent.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know mu the little micro Greek letter and that's the word torrent that you with the long thingy coming off the left Side.
Speaker 0: Yeah Scott why did the cat fall off the slanted roof?
Speaker 1: Why did the cat fall off?
Speaker 0: because it lost its mu?
Speaker 1: Don't do.
Speaker 0: mu is the coefficient of friction.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is.
Speaker 0: I made a physics joke.
Speaker 1: Oh, no Yeah, that's a very popular one.
Speaker 1: that is a very popular joke a Very popular, but I'm torrent client.
Speaker 0: I should be all Groucho Marx.
Speaker 1: There are other bit torrent clients out there and you can use any one of them, you know And they'll probably all work just fine.
Speaker 0: Now one last bit about using bit torrent clients is that and where we're gonna do a whole show on this because no one Out there seems to understand it unless you know They're technologists.
Speaker 0: and yet it's something that you all should really know about because almost everyone accesses the internet through a net now a router That basically gives you different IP addresses.
Speaker 0: if you don't know what that means don't worry about it, but you probably have it anyway.
Speaker 0: The thing is there's something called port forwarding.
Speaker 0: To not go into any technical detail, even though I will someday I will go into excruciatingly boring technical detail if you want.
Speaker 0: but you need to forward ports TCP ports on your router to whatever computer or computers you want to use bit torrent with and Different bit torrent clients can use different numbers of ports The ray if you're using the normal bit torrent client and you have only one computer that wants to download torrents forward ports six eight eight one through six nine nine nine to the computer that is running bit torrent.
Speaker 0: Assuming that that computer is somewhat secure.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm bit torrent will run just fine If you don't use any of this port forwarding But it'll be a lot faster and better if you do.
Speaker 0: If you use a serious the easiest way to know if you've got this set up or not is if you've ever seen a green Smiley face, you're okay.
Speaker 0: If you've only ever seen yellow, you probably don't have port forwarding set up.
Speaker 1: Another thing to note is that if you have universal plug-and-play UP and P enabled on your router and your OS supports it then most bit torrent clients Especially the default one take advantage of that and will be able to get you the green smiley faces by telling the router to open the ports, however You P&P is not the most secure thing in the world so turn it on with much hesitation.
Speaker 1: Yes Usually you P&P will cause you problems if someone gets access to your network and then opens up ports to the outside world and then Comes in through those ports.
Speaker 1: That's that's what you got to worry about.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And of course one nice advantage of a serious if you don't want to really bother with this so much is that you can tell It.
Speaker 0: use this one port for all that crap and then just open that one port.
Speaker 0: And in a lot of ways that is probably how the bit torrent client should be.
Speaker 0: But I guess because the bit torrent client is written by someone who's technical and because this solution works just fine for technical people There is no reason to make a single port solution.
Speaker 0: Yeah I am an advocate of single port solutions in most applications as an IT major.
Speaker 1: I Think it's just the way the software is written.
Speaker 1: It's faster and more efficient this way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you can make arguments both ways.
Speaker 0: He chose to do it this way.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna argue I think it's mostly because you don't know about coding.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time to look at the software You don't know about networking so much.
Speaker 1: I know about network coding.
Speaker 1: I know how to code network applications.
Speaker 0: I took classes on coding network applications.
Speaker 1: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, that is all you need to know about bit torrent unless you want to know more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you don't know how to like specifically use bit torrent, I mean, it's so dead simple.
Speaker 1: You can find it on the internet at the bit torrent website.
Speaker 0: And if you guys really want to hear a more technical discussion like specifically You know why these ports need to be open or how a tracker works or what like what protocols are used or how does it?
Speaker 0: Know that the pieces you're getting from other people aren't broken.
Speaker 0: We could do a show about that But we found in the past that the shows we did that were overly technical did not go over so well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people seem to go like hey you talked over my head and I'm like, well, it's tech day.
Speaker 0: I figure people who listen on tech day want to talk about you know I think the people who listen on tech day want to learn about tech stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they got to understand the over-the-head talk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right Bit torrent is awesome.
Speaker 1: You should use it, but it does not replace napster.
Speaker 1: It is not a napster replacement It does.
Speaker 1: it is not a Kazaa replacement It's all.
Speaker 1: it serves a different purpose and solves a different problem and it is awesome.
Speaker 0: In fact, it solves a problem that many of you young kids probably never saw because it was a problem that came and went on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's why a lot of people don't understand it because they never experienced the problems.
Speaker 0: They never experienced the Golden Age of peer-to-peer.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: I mean we lived through the dawn birth Rennet of rise Renaissance death Renaissance death Renaissance and death of Napster.
Speaker 1: that is correct.
Speaker 0: there was a time when I would go on to my computer start Napster and Every song in the world that I could ever dream of was available Immediately at insane speed and as far as the world was concerned.
Speaker 0: It wasn't illegal.
Speaker 0: the recording industry barely even knew this existed.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It was just this crazy thing.
Speaker 0: No one was getting sued.
Speaker 0: No one even thought of the possibility that you might be sued.
Speaker 0: Most people just assumed it was legal if they even knew anything about copyright law.
Speaker 1: It was good times.
Speaker 0: It was crazy time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh and one more thing that you know, a lot of people I know complain about bit torrent again thinking it's Napster Cuz.
Speaker 1: they say I can't get individual songs.
Speaker 1: I can only get albums.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like.
Speaker 1: first of all, why don't you want the album instead of the original song?
Speaker 1: If you're not if you're gonna steal it, why not steal the whole thing?
Speaker 1: steal as much as you can Yeah, the old pack right?
Speaker 0: Where's mentality?
Speaker 0: if I can download it, but damn it.
Speaker 0: It's worth archiving on my raid Yeah,
Speaker 1: and if you just want one song Well if bit torrents the easiest way to get it download the whole album and delete everything but the one song Yeah,
Speaker 0: or if you just want the one song you could use the iTunes store for a dollar
Speaker 1: and of course deal with DRM's And whatnot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then you hack the DRM Can't hack the iTunes here.
Speaker 1: I'm right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't analog hole But the way to do it now is to burn a CD and then rip it off the CD.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the pseudo Danna log costs one CD and then a dollar.
Speaker 1: But anyway no, but The reason that is is because putting incredibly small files on bit torrent is kind of pointless unless it's an incredibly popular file.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, if you have a three megabyte mp3 You can.
Speaker 1: nowadays that everyone has Broadband because realistically bit torrent doesn't work if you don't have broadband with dial-up.
Speaker 1: It's basically used.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: If you have dial-up one, you're probably not listening to geek.
Speaker 0: not though I know we have a few listeners.
Speaker 0: use dialogue.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 1: I can't expect anyone to even download mp3s at all.
Speaker 1: I'm dial-up granted.
Speaker 0: I downloaded mp3s over time.
Speaker 1: That's like someone driving on the highway where the speed limit is 65, but their car can't get over 40.
Speaker 1: It's like you shouldn't be on this highway.
Speaker 1: get off.
Speaker 1: You're gonna.
Speaker 1: you're being dangerous.
Speaker 0: I remember when downloading and successfully getting a three megabyte mp3 Was this crazy deal.
Speaker 0: and then you would break it up onto a floppy disk and give it to your friend.
Speaker 1: I downloaded open office over 56 K and brown three or four CDs or something.
Speaker 0: I lived in the promised land.
Speaker 0: I had a cable modem pretty much.
Speaker 1: I don't remember it was just one CD.
Speaker 1: It was big hundreds of megabytes.
Speaker 0: I had a cable modem pretty much forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the point is If you have broadband sending a three megabyte mp3 to like a whole mess of people takes like five seconds each.
Speaker 1: So you don't really need bit torrent for that.
Speaker 1: You could just have a FTP server and it wouldn't have a problem doing it even if a thousand people showed up.
Speaker 1: The problem is if you want to have a 500 megabyte or two gigabyte game demo that you have to distribute to people Then it takes so long to do it that bit torrent actually makes things go faster and not slower.
Speaker 1: So that is why people only distribute entire albums and movies and TV shows on bit torrent and not Individual songs because it's pointless.
Speaker 0: Well, hopefully we've dispelled some of the Myths rumors and misunderstandings about bit torrent.
Speaker 0: as always if you want to argue with us or anything You can hit the forums the four.
Speaker 1: Oh also one note.
Speaker 1: I keep forgetting to say this if you apply for membership to the forum and you do not receive an email that says Congratulations.
Speaker 1: You are a member of the forum Come back to the forum and try to sign in with the name and password you chose.
Speaker 1: there is a hundred percent chance that you were approved and you just didn't get the email because you use hotmail or something stupid like That and the spam filter is overly aggressive.
Speaker 0: Not only have we never denied entry to anyone but we've only ever Banned one person and good God was that kid annoying?
Speaker 1: Yes, and if you would like to apply for membership to the forum if you wait, maybe I don't know.
Speaker 1: There's a hundred percent guarantee that within 12 hours you are going to get approved if anything by the next episode of geek nights.
Speaker 1: if there is an episode of geek nights that was not pre-recorded and You hear it and you applied for the forums before that episode airs.
Speaker 1: You are now a member of the forums.
Speaker 0: Congratulations, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: you can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.