Speaker 1: It's Monday May 15th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about the worst technologies ever.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: another successful geek end.
Speaker 0: Indeed we had a bunch of friends over.
Speaker 0: we climbed that mountain and we played fury of Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: Well, I didn't climb that mountain.
Speaker 1: I went home and then came back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the rest of us call of food, but we did play fury of Dracula.
Speaker 1: We played free of Dracula.
Speaker 0: the game takes fucking five hours to play.
Speaker 1: It would have taken three and a half hours if there wasn't a rules ambiguity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though not to you know make fun of Scott because apparently according to people out in the forums I make fun of Scott too much.
Speaker 1: Oh, so now they know which one of us is which.
Speaker 0: again, I guess Uh-huh I just found that really hilarious because honestly in the real world most people would say the exact opposite because Scott's the one who calls Everyone stupid.
Speaker 1: I make fun of everybody he does.
Speaker 0: It's like we make fun of Cartman because he's fat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we make fun of Cartman because he's stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah And they make fun of Cartman because he's ass.
Speaker 0: damn he already did me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway we we all decided like everyone but Scott was like, all right, it's obvious.
Speaker 0: the rule is this let's just play.
Speaker 0: But Scott let us on an hour and a half goose chase to try to find the actual rule.
Speaker 0: in the end He found out we were all right.
Speaker 1: But that point is is that you saw where the rule was in the rule book.
Speaker 1: You saw that didn't you?
Speaker 1: Where was the rule in the rule book?
Speaker 0: I'm not pretending that the rules were not shit Lee written.
Speaker 0: Okay, however I was okay with us.
Speaker 0: Just making up a rule and continuing.
Speaker 1: I'm not okay with making up rules.
Speaker 1: I got to find out the real rule.
Speaker 1: But now actually I think there aren't so many ambiguities left in that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like there could be a few situations that arise due to a combination of event cards and encounters and things but not many.
Speaker 1: I think we pretty much got the game down 100%.
Speaker 0: Yep, of course.
Speaker 0: I specifically avoided one possible conflict with a car just because I didn't want to deal with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but other than that, I mean the game is fun.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I'll probably play it a few more times at least see what happens.
Speaker 0: Yep, though in another quick metabit as you all know, I quit IBM and this is my last week.
Speaker 0: In fact tomorrow, I'm doing my last duty for IBM.
Speaker 0: I am going on a business trip to like bumblefuck Connecticut to install a server at this location all day.
Speaker 1: So what are you doing Wednesday Thursday Friday?
Speaker 0: Probably answering questions about all the things I've built for IBM for the last three years that no one knows how to maintain Or even knows what they do.
Speaker 1: Didn't you write documentation?
Speaker 0: Oh, I wrote documentation that no one ever read and I didn't document everything because let me put it this way.
Speaker 0: I Documented the things I did that needed documentation.
Speaker 0: I did not document how Linux works.
Speaker 0: That is the problem.
Speaker 1: So, you know what you do is you go on your way to work tomorrow You stop at the bookstore and you get Linux for dummies and you give it to them and then you write and then you fill An expense report so you get your money back.
Speaker 0: I actually refused to do one project right now.
Speaker 0: They wanted in wine to make printing work.
Speaker 0: There are two ways to make printing work and because of stuff I don't want to get into I had to make it work the hard way where you get a Postscript driver that is built into wine to work inside of wine.
Speaker 1: Fuck that It's hard enough to get a post your cover to work in Linux for Linux.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now I know how to do it and it's not trivial, but I could have done it in a couple hours.
Speaker 0: But I basically told them that I'm not gonna do it and that they should really do it on their own because then they'll learn A lot about wine and Linux and then they won't be totally screwed when I leave.
Speaker 0: That's good tough love.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I started the new job Monday and my benefits are crazy.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute tough love.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's any love.
Speaker 1: It's just tough.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's just tough shit, this is what it is.
Speaker 0: Yep, but they all want to take me out drinking and all this crap.
Speaker 0: But whatever the thing is my new company has crazy awesome benefits.
Speaker 0: Like I I pity the people who stayed at IBM now that I've seen what the rest of the IT world gives for benefits.
Speaker 0: I'm getting a lawyer.
Speaker 0: My company is giving me a lawyer.
Speaker 0: Well, they don't giving you a lawyer They're giving you access to a pool of lawyers Yes, which is going to cost me a grand total of like six dollars a month.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good benefit.
Speaker 1: But um Generally, I don't want so many benefits.
Speaker 1: I'd rather have more money because most of the benefits I'll never ever use.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the thing is I there's all these benefits I could take that I'm opting out of and getting money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see that's the way to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm taking some sort of medical at least catastrophic medical in case I get hit by a car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the only health insurance that I need is if I break my leg.
Speaker 1: I need a free fucking cast.
Speaker 1: That's what I need.
Speaker 0: Yep, and you know basic dental.
Speaker 0: because oh, yeah dental cleanings are like a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is my uncle's a dentist so that's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah But dental coverage is like eight bucks a month.
Speaker 1: but he is a lot more happier if I have insurance because then he gets some Money as opposed to just nothing.
Speaker 0: Ah Actually, I don't have to deal with this but apparently a lot of HMOs and DMOs won't pay if the dentist or doctor you Go to is a blood relative Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course fuck HMOs.
Speaker 0: I'm not dealing with any of that crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't have an HMO.
Speaker 1: I have PP whatever PPD whatever.
Speaker 1: I have to look at the card, but I'm too lazy to take out my wallet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I barely understand it because most of that stuff doesn't involve me.
Speaker 0: I don't have any medical problems.
Speaker 0: I go to a doctor.
Speaker 0: like I got allergies.
Speaker 0: Give me a prescription for allergy medicine.
Speaker 1: I hardly ever go to a doctor unless I really really need to.
Speaker 0: yeah like that time when we told the story about With the leg right exactly.
Speaker 0: We're in that fight club.
Speaker 1: It's usually physical injury.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's when I go to a doctor extreme physical injury that might require stitches or casts.
Speaker 1: or You know.
Speaker 1: if anything's worse than a cast like if I need screws, I'll probably just kill myself.
Speaker 1: so That's not gonna happen either.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I actually want good dental because I have good teeth.
Speaker 1: I've got teeth that better teeth than anyone almost.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is not anyone in the world, but I have damn good teeth.
Speaker 0: I have good teeth now because I had braces when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I had braces when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: someday I'll tell the story of the the Debacle that was my braces.
Speaker 0: suffice to say I had them for almost nine years.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had braces.
Speaker 0: I got him off.
Speaker 0: then I got different braces from a different orthodontist.
Speaker 1: Yep Me too And it said it wasn't nine years.
Speaker 0: it when I finally.
Speaker 0: well It was like eight years and a little bit more.
Speaker 0: when I finally got him off and I chewed gum for the first time it Was like whoa.
Speaker 0: gum is awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah gum sure is awesome.
Speaker 0: I love gum, but the braces kind of screwed up some of my teeth.
Speaker 0: So I got a bunch of fillings as a result.
Speaker 1: See, I only have two fillings and the first filling I ever got was when I was 21.
Speaker 0: Wow I have like six fillings Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see it.
Speaker 1: My teeth are awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I took the old mercury ones because just to inject a little Randy here.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with amalgam fillings.
Speaker 0: They don't poison you.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Stop spreading that urban legend you freaks.
Speaker 1: All right next Thursday.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about teeth.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad idea.
Speaker 1: It's not bad at all.
Speaker 0: Okay, well Scott's got a lot of biting stories, oh I sure do okay.
Speaker 1: So anyway, today's episode is gonna be about worst Technologies because it's a worst week.
Speaker 1: every episode this week will be about the worst video games the worst anime manga comics and The worst I think we decided.
Speaker 1: the worst people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that either the worst people in history or the worst people we know currently We're not sure yet or both depending on how long it goes.
Speaker 1: I think worst people in history could be like three episodes and it might be more entertaining Especially since worst people we know should be saved for geek fables.
Speaker 1: Then we get more episodes out of true Plus.
Speaker 0: we have to decide how much information to give it worse people and how many which names to name and which names to?
Speaker 1: Just say so this guy and I want to remind everyone that there's a poll.
Speaker 0: if you go to front row crew calm Which is our website Currently, I just want to point out that geek night socks is winning great.
Speaker 1: There's a poll on the right side of the page and I update it every now and then and I'll probably just you know Say something on the podcast whenever I change the poll so I can make sure everyone goes to answer it
Speaker 0: Even though almost no one answers it so far.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Like maybe maybe a fifth of our listeners answered the first one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go to front row crew calm and on the right side of the page is a poll.
Speaker 1: Answer it.
Speaker 0: I'm just curious because I know there's a lot of people out there who listen and don't go to the website.
Speaker 0: I know you're there.
Speaker 0: I see you connecting.
Speaker 0: It's fine If you don't ever want to go but I'll note that we link to everything we talk about in case you ever get confused.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the things of the day the links are at front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: the news stories.
Speaker 1: the links are front row crew.
Speaker 1: calm You should go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah What else is there?
Speaker 1: Oh that logo contest.
Speaker 1: we should decide on one soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've got a lot of submissions We're?
Speaker 0: we like many of them.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 1: there's a couple that I really like and if I could get the creators to slightly modify them, they would be perfect Meaning we'll probably be contacting a few people in the next in the coming weeks and talking.
Speaker 1: Yes So if you still want to submit a geek night's logo to win the $50 in cash for creating the best geek nights logo
Speaker 0: not to mention the fame on the website and the fact that you can put geek nights on Your resume
Speaker 1: and we'll credit you in every episode and all that You should send in your logo submissions to geek nights at front row crew calm or post them in the forums at front row crew Calm forum.
Speaker 0: be aware that ones posted to the forums are subject to mockery by all the other forum denizens.
Speaker 1: Yes We will not comment on the logos until after the contest because that would be unfair for the contest because there's $50 involved.
Speaker 0: and bear in mind if you're not an artist if you just come up with the concept We know people who can turn it into a real logo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we just need the concept the idea.
Speaker 1: Like if you just draw it like in pencil, that's cool.
Speaker 1: And then we just you know After that's enough to win the contest and then later We'll turn it into a real fully photoshop shiny thing that we're actually is usable for printing on t-shirts and all that jazz Yep, and then we'll come the merch.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So the requirements for the logo contest again is it should be a square because we need a square To turn it into an iTunes album cover.
Speaker 0: Yes I mean we are.
Speaker 0: we are looking for art for the top banner and all that but that comes later.
Speaker 1: Well, no is that?
Speaker 1: that's also it should look good when it if you go to front row crew comm and you'll see the top Of the page is this blue bar?
Speaker 1: That's sort of a gradient.
Speaker 1: It should look good against that gradient.
Speaker 1: And if it doesn't then if you win, I'll ask you to modify it.
Speaker 1: So it looks good against that grade.
Speaker 0: So don't make your logo a blue gradient.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I want us because we're gonna stick it right at the top of that page in the blue area.
Speaker 1: So it should look good up there And It should.
Speaker 1: I'd like it to incorporate geek and night Summit somehow in some fashion.
Speaker 0: Yes, if we knew what fashion we wouldn't be having this contest exactly.
Speaker 0: So anyway, it's worst week.
Speaker 0: We're going to try to be objective here, which that chance?
Speaker 1: But yeah, this isn't most hated because if it was most hated we'd be like, oh man, do we ever hate that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that sucks.
Speaker 1: But the problem is is we might hate it, but it might still be really good.
Speaker 1: We just don't like it.
Speaker 1: So this is worst week things that are objectively Terrible either.
Speaker 0: and because it's Monday science and tech We really had to narrow it down because if we were just talking about science and tech we'd have things like nuclear weapons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you have a really broad definite definition of technology like rim wanted to have yeah I was like, let's talk about razors and nukes and war.
Speaker 1: I'm like those things are technically technology If you use a very broad definition, but I'm going to limit it to things that appear on slash dot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically consumer technology gadgets computers that sort of thing home electronics software Consumer software.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the list we've got so far that we're gonna talk about basically seems to cover Failed technologies and bad technologies which usually go hand-in-hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not always though.
Speaker 1: So for example Oracle would not make the list because while we hate Oracle and it's it's pretty bad It's not you know Can widely considered to be this terrible thing and it also has its uses.
Speaker 0: my only real complaint is the price.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if Oracle is free, it'd be pretty good.
Speaker 1: So, you know, that's not going to be something you see on worst week.
Speaker 1: Something you will see on worst week is something like tomorrow.
Speaker 1: We'll probably talk about the virtual boy Or the engage.
Speaker 1: exactly that's it.
Speaker 1: so Let's talk about worst technologies.
Speaker 1: What's the first?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, we're not.
Speaker 1: we got the news.
Speaker 0: news See.
Speaker 0: now for anyone who doubts the geek nights is recorded live.
Speaker 0: I could have cut that out, but we don't cut anything out of the show anymore at all.
Speaker 0: Yep, like I just wanted to mention that.
Speaker 1: Okay, so the news.
Speaker 1: oh, oh my news.
Speaker 1: So Skype the thing that lets you you know Talk to other people on the internet and also you can pay money To call other people on the real telephone and receive calls on the real telephone.
Speaker 1: It's called Skype out Skype out and Skype in.
Speaker 1: well You're getting free Skype out to anywhere in the US and Canada Until the end of the year.
Speaker 0: free no strings.
Speaker 0: No nothing.
Speaker 0: You don't have to do anything.
Speaker 0: It's just it's already working.
Speaker 1: It's completely non bullshit.
Speaker 1: So starting today and ending at no sooner than January 1st, 2007 you can install Skype for free get an account for free and Call on the telephone any phone number in the entire United States and Canada For absolutely free.
Speaker 1: So if it's long distance to call your grandma and floor in Florida or your friend who moved to California And you know your cell phone you don't want to use minutes and your regular phone.
Speaker 1: You don't want to pay extra.
Speaker 1: just freakin.
Speaker 1: Install Skype plug a microphone and a little headset into the computer or whatever.
Speaker 1: Type in their number into Skype.
Speaker 1: their phone will ring and BAM free phone call.
Speaker 0: Now because of this we're probably going to really open up to interviews until this ends.
Speaker 0: Yeah interviews with people who don't live nearby.
Speaker 0: So in addition to us talking to some guests that we wanted to have on but we haven't really had the means to interview them.
Speaker 0: we're also.
Speaker 0: if anyone wants to call in about a topic and Talk to us in the forums or in the email and we'll set something up.
Speaker 0: I think we should pay for one of those Skype voicemail things I think we should do even though I don't know when he sent us voice feedback via that phone number we have now.
Speaker 1: Well that phone number we have now sucks while it sucks.
Speaker 0: No one's used it.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't matter if it sucks.
Speaker 0: Alright, everyone just record yourself on your computer with like Windows recorder Yeah, or just talk to us and then we'll have a little live interview.
Speaker 0: we thing yeah All right, you know we can probably do it better than pen can on his radio show.
Speaker 1: Oh god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this thing doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Okay, so that's so.
Speaker 1: if you don't have Skype already, you know I was a little against Skype earlier because it was made by the same people who made Kazaa, which is all spyware evil.
Speaker 1: But now eBay bought it.
Speaker 1: So Skype is really legitimate.
Speaker 0: now It's not evil spyware and even if they ever became spyware There are a lot of geeks watching it constantly and you'll know immediately if they do anything shady.
Speaker 1: Yes, Skype is pretty trustworthy.
Speaker 1: It works pretty well for what it needs to work as and it's good Using it.
Speaker 1: No fear.
Speaker 1: It's now you can make free calls.
Speaker 1: It's obviously this free call thing.
Speaker 1: They're obviously just trying to get a whole bunch of people to use it who aren't using it already because now it's so amazing.
Speaker 1: And then you know, they'll get them all hooked and then at the end of the year They'll get them all paying next year.
Speaker 1: And I think it's a plan that's gonna work.
Speaker 0: that kind of plan works all the time Yeah, get people hooked on something and then now for just five dollars a month.
Speaker 0: You can continue to use it.
Speaker 1: I mean flicker works in the same way.
Speaker 1: You can store a bunch of pictures.
Speaker 1: Oh, but only so many.
Speaker 1: now You got a if you want it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like flicker too much now.
Speaker 0: I gotta pay Yeah, but also with a reasonable price.
Speaker 1: Yep, very reasonable price.
Speaker 0: So so for a long time.
Speaker 0: Well, basically every time a new technology has appeared on the internet that used bandwidth the ISPs have all gotten in a tuft and said oh This technology is going to choke the internet with traffic and crash it and we're gonna need money and we're gonna need all these Things to make the internet not suck if this technology takes off
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: and it's always been bullshit.
Speaker 0: They said this about when real media started having like streaming audio.
Speaker 0: They said this is the end of the internet when mp3s appeared.
Speaker 0: This is the end of the internet.
Speaker 0: They've been doing this since the dawn of time and Just today Reuters is carrying a story that the ISPs are saying that if HD content You know video and high-definition video becomes popular on the internet and is watched by many people The internet will collapse under its own weight because of too much traffic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people are already bit torrenting HD videos that are encoded in h.264 and xvid and the internet isn't choking.
Speaker 0: Yes, just fine, I mean I see the story and it's not really news to us.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to talk about it because for anyone out there who sees this or reads about what's going on with the ISPs right Now it is complete horseshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're just lying.
Speaker 0: They're lying because they want more money and now Now it's even this separate thing because you know the whole net neutrality thing how they want to like charge Google to use So their customers can get to Google and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: This is just an excuse to lobby for that more strongly.
Speaker 0: they can go to Congress and say see we're gonna collapse under our own Weight unless Google pays for their share of using Google video.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: and because Congress doesn't know shit about technology They believe pretty much whatever companies tell them.
Speaker 1: so Usually what happens is a Google guy goes to Congress in some committee and ISP guy goes to Congress and they both say and Congress Doesn't know what to think.
Speaker 1: so they think whatever they want to think and then bad things happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't want to sound cynical, but they probably just think whatever.
Speaker 0: the guy who gave them the most money says Yep, and if you don't believe me open secrets org.
Speaker 0: in places like that You can see exactly which companies have paid which senators and then you can look at their voting records And there's some interesting trends in there.
Speaker 1: Oh really?
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh Anyone who frequents our forums knows what that song was And anyone who is at our house recently knows what that song is.
Speaker 0: now first I'm going to talk about that thing and then I'm going to talk about what happened over the weekend.
Speaker 0: My thing of the day is long great.
Speaker 1: Am I thinking they will be short if I can get my point across, but that's alright Alright.
Speaker 0: so someone posted in our forum this little animated gif thing that apparently had music to it.
Speaker 1: It was a flash.
Speaker 0: I think actually yeah, but the thing is I was at work and I didn't have sound so I clicked on it And it was this just animation of a girl spinning a leak.
Speaker 0: a leak for anyone who doesn't know is appliance.
Speaker 1: It's some sort of vegetable that people eat.
Speaker 1: You'll find it in Asian foods and such.
Speaker 0: you see it in anime a lot.
Speaker 1: It's just like a long white plant with a green tuft at the end kind of like a celery but different.
Speaker 0: Anyway this vid this thing I saw it.
Speaker 0: I thought whatever I didn't know that there was sound to it.
Speaker 0: Then I came home and the link was broken and I thought oh well, whatever.
Speaker 0: Fast forward to where someone in fact one of our listeners ugly Fred messaged me and yelled something about spinning leak lady And I didn't really care.
Speaker 0: and she expressed Oh, you didn't hear it and I got a link from her to an updated link where I could actually listen to it.
Speaker 0: Go watch it.
Speaker 0: It's the most addicting like Creepy.
Speaker 0: just it's in my head and it won't go away.
Speaker 0: Why won't you stop spinning that leak?
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: And the thing is it took off on the internet like it exploded.
Speaker 0: It's everywhere now and it got to the point where Wikipedia has an article about it.
Speaker 0: This is like that There's an article in Wikipedia about everything and now there's an article about it and they even have a link to the forum.
Speaker 0: I think the forum is in Finland where this was created and posted the first time.
Speaker 0: We're at the point in the world where a meme that appears can be traced back to its exact origin via Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Yes, it was it's fantastic.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: I like this thing.
Speaker 0: It's really cute.
Speaker 0: People are making more.
Speaker 0: I think this is gonna be the next, you know big meme on the internet after the haha guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like it a lot more than I like YTM n DS in general.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is kind of like a YTM n D only it seems higher quality like higher production values.
Speaker 0: more thought was put into it.
Speaker 0: I mean someone sat down was watching bleach saw this scene and thought huh Found this silly song stuck him together and made a thing.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: That's what the Internet's all about.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Now as a result of this a lot of people have been looking for this band The band that did the song.
Speaker 0: they're a Finnish folk band and their music's really cute cool.
Speaker 0: I can't find torrents of it yet, but I'm really thinking of ordering the albums.
Speaker 1: You're nuts.
Speaker 0: I like Finnish folk music.
Speaker 0: now great.
Speaker 0: Now the funny thing is I should.
Speaker 0: we showed it to everyone when they came over for the geek end because they hadn't seen it.
Speaker 0: they didn't really pay attention to it in the forums and we put it on the TV and For about two minutes.
Speaker 0: We just sat there watching it and no one said a word.
Speaker 0: No one wanted to admit.
Speaker 0: Wow, I don't want to stop watching this.
Speaker 0: So everyone was just quiet and no one said anything and we watched it like it was a TV show Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: We eventually just someone turned it off and saved us.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And then while I was upstairs the next morning I turned it on and then I went and took a shower and I left it on and then we all decided Let's just leave it on all day.
Speaker 0: You could barely hear it in the background downstairs.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: I mean at first I was hearing it like in the morning I heard it a whole bunch But then eventually it faded out and then occasionally faded in because and then it faded out
Speaker 0: But it was like this low-level slowly driving you insane song playing in the background that you could almost hear.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Then we forgot about it.
Speaker 0: Then our friend Scott Johnson comes over and We hang out we go out and get food We start playing this game and for hours and hours and hours every now and then he'd look up like, huh?
Speaker 0: No, whatever.
Speaker 0: and then finally he looks at all of us.
Speaker 0: He's like guys.
Speaker 0: What's that song?
Speaker 0: That's playing and We all look at him and we almost explode with laughter Almost like we all have.
Speaker 1: we held it in.
Speaker 0: somehow we all held it in.
Speaker 0: So we're all sitting there like what song?
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: and he's looking around like I hear this thing.
Speaker 0: I can't describe it.
Speaker 0: It's like this girl and she's singing but it doesn't it.
Speaker 0: and I'm like what is there?
Speaker 1: sounds like it's going in a loop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like, is there a radio going on outside?
Speaker 0: and then Scott's like, yeah, maybe something, you know radio driving by Maybe the lady downstairs.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: no I hear it.
Speaker 0: It's it's looping.
Speaker 0: It's been looping for the past hour.
Speaker 0: It's the same song.
Speaker 0: Ah, don't you guys hear it?
Speaker 0: and we stifled the laughter.
Speaker 0: We're like, no, we don't know what you're talking about And after a few minutes that he's like I gotta find it.
Speaker 0: He stands up and starts walking around the house and he's like looking out that he walks out goes out the front door.
Speaker 0: Now while he's standing outside we bust out really And he walks back in really hip.
Speaker 0: Did you hear anything?
Speaker 0: and he's like no, I think it's in the house and we're like you're crazy.
Speaker 0: We don't hear anything.
Speaker 0: and then finally he gets this look on his face and he's like, uh, he runs upstairs.
Speaker 0: It's on your goddamn computer room.
Speaker 0: what the hell.
Speaker 0: and then we exploded.
Speaker 1: I'm just falling all over myself on the stairs.
Speaker 0: We just we were laughing so hard it hurt.
Speaker 1: It was great.
Speaker 0: So the spinning leak to all of you who have not seen it go watch it and I Guarantee the song will be stuck in your head for at least a year.
Speaker 0: Mmm, so Scott do you have a thing of the day?
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: It's a useful piece of software.
Speaker 0: It's actually really cool.
Speaker 0: Don't let my long thing of the day detract from this because this thing is awesome
Speaker 1: now if you use Windows, which I think a Lot of you do because not enough of you are smarter cool enough to use Linux and a lot of you are so rich And arty that use apples.
Speaker 1: so you Windows users out there Are you the type of Windows user that has I don't know a bajillion icons on your desktop or maybe a giant start menu?
Speaker 0: I believe the post pictures of your desktop thread answered that question.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, you know some programs in your start menu.
Speaker 1: you use them all the time So you usually make little quick launch buttons down in the taskbar, you know, the things you click once and it runs the program.
Speaker 1: You know you put Firefox down there and stuff.
Speaker 1: well, I Got tired of my work laptop always having to dig through the start menu for the rarely used application or have a whole billion icons everywhere for the applications that I launched frequently.
Speaker 1: and there were some applications where I You know, you don't want them to start up all the time On startup, but you wanted to start up.
Speaker 1: sometimes, you know, like if I turn my computer on at work I always want outlook to start up, but if I turn it out at home, I don't want outlook to turn on at all.
Speaker 0: Yep, and sometimes I want notes to start, you know Lotus Notes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, shoot me now But sometimes I need to actually do work on my computer and I can't deal with Lotus Notes spending its 10 minutes shitting itself Before it actually opens.
Speaker 1: So what I needed was an easy way to Launch and Start any Windows application that was installed on the computer without digging through the start menu and without having a billion icons Cluttering up my screen because I need my screen to be clean or else I go insane.
Speaker 1: So there's this program called launchy la you and CH.
Speaker 1: why?
Speaker 0: Lunchie lunchy lunch.
Speaker 1: Yes, it launches launches programs.
Speaker 1: Now what you do is first you install launchy and Then you run launchy and launchy runs at startup and you want launchy to always run and start up or else is useless.
Speaker 1: What launchy does?
Speaker 1: is you type in a keyboard?
Speaker 1: shortcut?
Speaker 1: the default keyboard shortcut for launchy is alt space and you would type alt space and launchy will appear.
Speaker 1: once launchy appears you can right-click on it and change the skin and Change the hotkey.
Speaker 1: So if you don't like alt space you can use control space Which is what I use control alt f7 meta.
Speaker 1: Well, no, you can combine.
Speaker 1: you can mine two keys.
Speaker 1: So it's like you have control alt shift and Windows key combined with any other key.
Speaker 1: So you could be like window L for you know, but even though that locks the screen, but you get the point.
Speaker 1: and what launchy does is it opens up this little window and The window looks like whatever skin you pick and most of the skins are really cool-looking and there's transparent also and you can move it around the screen to wherever you want.
Speaker 1: also and In this box you type you could type anything in this box And what it will do is as you type it will search the start menu For the program that most matches what you're typing.
Speaker 1: So if I want to start audacity, I type a You and already it knows I want audacity.
Speaker 1: So I press enter and audacity starts up and launchy disappears.
Speaker 1: if I want to start Firefox I open up launchy.
Speaker 1: I type F. There it is because I use Firefox more than anything else.
Speaker 1: I Go in and I type M. Oh, that's Mozilla Firefox, of course.
Speaker 1: I Microsoft Office Outlook It just it looks in your start menu and indexes all the icons and shit that are in there.
Speaker 1: So you don't sue let your start menu become a huge mess.
Speaker 1: You're never gonna go in there again if you have launchy and What you can do is your run launchy and you can get to any thing in your start menu just by typing the name of it and It'll launch between that and the XP eyes test switcher.
Speaker 0: I don't even have a test bar or anything.
Speaker 0: My desktop is just completely empty now at work.
Speaker 1: Yep, just use a little launchy guy and you can run any.
Speaker 1: you can start any Windows application just by opening launchy With a quick keyboard shortcut and typing in the name of it.
Speaker 1: Now this is even better because a lot of the you know Let's say you're a big on the keyboard and you alt tab between running programs and all your programs.
Speaker 1: you use you know the keyboard shortcuts for but in Windows you always needed to go and Go down to the start menu or stop.
Speaker 1: take your hands off the keyboard to click on something to start a new program.
Speaker 1: Sure, you could do window R to get the little run dialog box But even then you need to type the whole path of the executable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not fun Unless you put everything in your path, which is bad.
Speaker 1: That's really bad.
Speaker 1: You don't want to do that either.
Speaker 1: So launchy is what the run is what start run really should be.
Speaker 1: Here's where you type in the name of any program, you know the English make sense name of any program in Windows that's installed on your computer and it's in your start menu and It will start it for you.
Speaker 1: So a lot less mouse use a lot more keyboard use a lot more efficiency a lot more coolness.
Speaker 1: It makes windows suck a lot less.
Speaker 1: So you should install launchy and the link is at front row crew comm.
Speaker 1: So now you have to go there.
Speaker 0: All right, so worst week worst week.
Speaker 0: now once again We're gonna try to be objective here and talk about things from a reasonable non opinionated standpoint.
Speaker 1: All right, so you got the list so you.
Speaker 0: So we'd like to start with now.
Speaker 0: this one's a really complicated one, but we'll qualify it digital television and high-definition television in the United States.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well HDTV is pretty much the same everywhere in the world.
Speaker 1: The only difference is that the rest of the world doesn't have it at all at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but well digital television.
Speaker 0: other countries have digital television some of them.
Speaker 1: a lot of them just have satellite television.
Speaker 0: Yep, but we're not talking about the idea of high-definition.
Speaker 0: I think high-definition is great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's nothing better than HD sports.
Speaker 1: they kick the shit out of normal sports Yep, and while eight most video games may not need HD You can do awesome things with HD like split screens that you know where everyone can see what the hell's going on.
Speaker 0: So don't get us wrong.
Speaker 0: We're not against HD.
Speaker 0: HD and Advancing display technology is an awesome thing.
Speaker 0: but have you noticed how in America with the HD standards and all that basically every time they bring up an HD thing they With DRM and then they make it obsolete because someone broke it and then they make a new standard and then they cripple it and Then they break it and then nothing works.
Speaker 0: and it's so complicated.
Speaker 0: We barely understand it.
Speaker 0: The average Joe has no idea what's going on.
Speaker 1: They got 720p 720i 1080i 1080p.
Speaker 1: They got different numbers.
Speaker 1: They got different cables TVI HDMI DisplayPort.
Speaker 1: they got TVs that are HD ready and they have TVs that are actual HD TVs and they have TVs with digital Receivers without digital receivers.
Speaker 1: they have TVs that only support one format support all the formats.
Speaker 0: It's just insane TVs that upsample TVs that can't display content because they don't have the copyright stuff built into them anymore.
Speaker 1: Cuz they're old with the HD CP.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's just the company.
Speaker 0: It's such a mess that I think the technology is going to fail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think what's gonna happen?
Speaker 1: My prediction is in a few years HD will eventually coalesce into just one standard.
Speaker 1: It'll be like 1080p.
Speaker 1: This is the cable This is the format and all the other HD stuff will either be Sort of half working or not working anymore and they'll be one standard.
Speaker 1: and then once they say this is HD This is the end.
Speaker 1: then everyone will go out and buy HD stuff when they buy new TVs.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the same goes for HD DVD and blu-ray.
Speaker 1: Yeah, both of those are even worse.
Speaker 1: I mean when you add those into the equation We're not just ragging on Sony HD DVD and blu-ray.
Speaker 0: both have serious problems And there's gonna be a huge war between them both and I don't think consumers care about either one.
Speaker 1: When you read today the some guy got a one of those Toshiba HD DVD players.
Speaker 1: Oh, and you know what it is.
Speaker 1: It's just a computer.
Speaker 1: It's like a $600 Pentium for computer with a with a HD TV with an HD DVD drive in it.
Speaker 0: great We have enough problems with our crap.
Speaker 1: Oh DVD players overheating and it takes forever for the disc to load.
Speaker 1: So basically you put the movie in it and you wait and it's a whole computer and you wait for it.
Speaker 1: It takes forever to boot the thing.
Speaker 1: it takes forever for it to load the movie But once the movies loaded it plays an HD movie.
Speaker 1: That's what it does.
Speaker 0: That really can't compete with DVD at all Yep, and we could go on and on about how DVD was a big a much bigger leap for consumers than HD DVD is.
Speaker 0: But we don't need to get into that.
Speaker 0: The point is that the company's screwed this up by making it complex obtuse and by you know fighting too much.
Speaker 1: You know Sometimes you need competition and sometimes you need a standard.
Speaker 1: competing over the standard doesn't work when all the standards are essentially equal But different.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean this is worse than beta versus VHS.
Speaker 0: This is just crap.
Speaker 1: This is ass Alright.
Speaker 0: so digital audio mp3 took off right?
Speaker 0: What about all the formats that socked or failed?
Speaker 1: Like a track or vqf.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to know how old I am.
Speaker 0: Does anyone out there know what a vqf file is?
Speaker 0: Because when mp3 came out like once mp3 had mainstream.
Speaker 0: vqf appeared like right after and it was higher quality Per bitrate, but it took significantly more processing power to play Mm-hmm as a result because computers were slow.
Speaker 0: I have one vqf file to this day that I can still play an XMMS.
Speaker 0: I've never seen another one.
Speaker 0: I think it's completely dead.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell It just it didn't serve the market at the time it came out and thus it was terrible and worthless.
Speaker 1: Yep, even though if it came out more recently, it might have been able to compete with the likes of AAC and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now here's a good one.
Speaker 0: This is something that is still useful in the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: to a point and it's a thing that was awesome Except for the fact that it was crippled arbitrarily.
Speaker 0: Minidisc.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: I know we have a lot of foreign listeners.
Speaker 0: So I know Minidisc is used a lot in the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: in Japan It's big.
Speaker 0: in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Minidisc died.
Speaker 0: Minidisc was a silver.
Speaker 1: Minidisc they pushed it and then when I thought it was dead They pushed it a little more.
Speaker 1: and now it's dead.
Speaker 1: And the only time you really see Minidisc is in personal audio recorders.
Speaker 0: But it's horribly crippled with DRM and you have to pay a lot of money to get non crippled Minidisc.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, they have crippled Minidisc, which is kind of it's not the greatest.
Speaker 1: and then they have non crippled Minidisc Which is incredibly expensive.
Speaker 0: I mean Minidisc was great.
Speaker 0: I knew someone who had a Minidisc player and this was I mean Minidisc came out before it was Widely available.
Speaker 0: the ability to burn CDs for yourself Yep.
Speaker 1: And that was the advantage of Minidisc was that unlike CDs which at the time you could not record Minidiscs could record.
Speaker 1: So it's like aha.
Speaker 1: Minidisc sound as good as CDs.
Speaker 1: They hold almost as much music and you can record to them.
Speaker 1: They're great.
Speaker 1: They're perfect.
Speaker 1: They're most so much better than the CDs.
Speaker 1: CDs gonna die.
Speaker 1: They're gonna start selling Minidiscs in the store.
Speaker 0: This will be great Yeah, but then Sony decided wait a minute.
Speaker 0: people might pirate our music with this.
Speaker 0: We'd better fuck this format and destroy it.
Speaker 1: Well Sony made Minidisc so all they wanted was for it to succeed.
Speaker 1: But they also didn't want it to become a super piracy land.
Speaker 1: and that's where you get formats like the 8-track.
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about 8-track as in the number 8-track.
Speaker 1: That's an old, you know, it came between cassette tapes Yes vinyl records, which we wouldn't call a failure because it was actually widely used.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm talking about 8-track ATRAC Which is Sony's proprietary Competitor with.
Speaker 1: so basically if Sony had made iTunes instead of Apple making iTunes you wouldn't be using AACs you would be using ATRACs 8-track, which is what you would be all of Sony's Early digital audio players and the digital Minidisc players would only play music in the 8-track format.
Speaker 1: So you needed to use Sony's Windows software to convert music to the 8-track format and you could only buy Music from Sony in the 8-track format to play on those things.
Speaker 1: and that's why iPod won because it played mp3 and the Sony stuff some of which was.
Speaker 1: some of the devices were actually good devices But they failed because they forced you to convert everything to ATRAC which sucks.
Speaker 0: and this is Sony's real main problem.
Speaker 0: Is that Sony is a whole bunch of different companies?
Speaker 1: Effectively that have different markets and different products jammed together into one big umbrella company and they mess with each other and what's best for one Company might be bad for another company.
Speaker 1: So they don't do it sometimes.
Speaker 1: and they do do it sometimes.
Speaker 1: So if they do it, they end up hurting another part of the company.
Speaker 1: But if they don't do it, they hurt that part of the company that doesn't do it.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean, it's basically just the intellectual property wing of Sony at this point.
Speaker 0: Yes ones that cripple everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah So Sony Records doesn't want you know Sony electronics to make something that allows free recording of sharing of music Sony can make an awesome music sharing recording device.
Speaker 1: That's great.
Speaker 1: But if they did that the Sony music part would fail.
Speaker 1: But if they don't do it the Sony electronics part fails.
Speaker 0: Sony electronics probably didn't want any DRM to be in blu-ray But the rest of Sony wanted the DRM because otherwise that's the end of them.
Speaker 1: Yep So that's that's that.
Speaker 0: All right, and along the lines of replacements like that.
Speaker 0: The floppy disk was ubiquitous.
Speaker 0: The floppy disk was I mean, it's obsolete now and it was actually fairly unreliable and terrible.
Speaker 0: But it was basically the standard of storage for a long time It was the standard for removable storage.
Speaker 1: It was really, you know, there was the five and a quarter inch floppy Which was replaced pretty quickly by the three and a half inch floppy, which is much much better.
Speaker 1: But for a long time it was the only media that every computer could handle Which you could read and write to and remove from your computer easily and ship move it around.
Speaker 1: You know between take it with you.
Speaker 0: Now a bunch of companies tried to make the successor to the floppy disk.
Speaker 1: There's the zip disk which actually almost worked.
Speaker 1: The problem was Not enough.
Speaker 1: computers had zip disk by default Yeah, so it wasn't ubiquitous.
Speaker 0: a lot of people think they saw zip disks a lot because they saw him in universities.
Speaker 0: They weren't really used so much outside of universities.
Speaker 1: Well, there are people like who had lots of digital files people who did photoshopping a lot and such Zip disks, but most people just didn't have a need, you know for zip disks and they were really expensive Which is what hurt them.
Speaker 1: you could you would go to the store and you'd buy a friggin box of floppies for 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: One zip disk was like 10 bucks and that's why you didn't see people using them like crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But then there was like LS 120 and all these other great formats that were like a hundred megabytes on a basically three and a quarter Inch floppy disk.
Speaker 1: Yeah that there were drives which could take there.
Speaker 1: They looked like floppy disks three and a half inch floppies, but they weren't.
Speaker 1: they had something different inside of them.
Speaker 1: they could store a hundred and twenty megabytes instead of one point four four megabytes and The drives that took those things could also take normal floppies.
Speaker 1: So that's a good idea.
Speaker 1: if you want people to you know, carry on, you know here.
Speaker 1: take this drive.
Speaker 1: You can still use floppies But you can also use our new things and they hope that people would use the new things and they almost did if floppy didn't Die soon after.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: These are just more cases of companies or technologies that come out that are good technology But they cost too much for what they give you at that time.
Speaker 0: or they're not good They're not better or the timing is off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or they're just not better enough from what's out there now to justify it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, because people don't like to upgrade constantly geeks do we like to upgrade the kernel, you know a thousand times a day, but Normal people don't really seem to want to upgrade things constantly.
Speaker 0: They want to buy something and then ten years from now buy a better thing.
Speaker 1: they don't want to upgrade unless there is an obvious benefit that you know, they just can't avoid and The price is right.
Speaker 1: So it's very easy to upgrade, you know, if there's a huge benefit like look Firefox It's free and there's an a tremendous obvious benefit.
Speaker 1: yet It's still just so much effort to get someone to do it because they resist change so much.
Speaker 1: Yep, so imagine, you know trying to get someone to change To something that costs money and the benefit is less obvious Or they don't understand the benefit a lot of times the benefit is tremendous.
Speaker 1: But because people don't understand how it will benefit them directly and obviously or because no one tells them how it will benefit them Then they don't care tabs.
Speaker 0: I don't need tabs pop-up pop-up blockers.
Speaker 0: I can just close them.
Speaker 0: Yeah Exactly of course following the lines of technology We're not gonna say Windows or Microsoft because Windows has done a lot of good and it has its purposes.
Speaker 0: And while we may feel it's a certain way about it.
Speaker 0: It's definitely not a worse Windows.
Speaker 1: me however is the worst.
Speaker 0: that is probably the worst thing Microsoft has ever done.
Speaker 1: so after Windows 98 came out they came out with Windows XP and 2000. now the thing was well, no, they can't win Windows 2000 Yep, and that Windows 2000 was supposed to be for business users.
Speaker 1: It ran on the NT kernel not on the win 32 whatever.
Speaker 1: So it was like Under the hood.
Speaker 1: It was very different from Windows 98 and Windows 2000 wouldn't run a lot.
Speaker 1: You know It could run a lot of programs that were built for Windows 95. early on there were a lot of things that just didn't work in Windows 2000 Yeah thing and You know, it was a quite a big transition, you know Microsoft with their long backwards compatibility thing Where Windows 3.1 programs still run in Windows XP, but from 98 to 2000?
Speaker 0: It was you're really switching platforms completely there and to me I mean it was a great thing to this day.
Speaker 0: I consider Windows 2000 to be Microsoft's greatest server offering.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they wanted Windows 2000 to be for business people and Windows 98 as the second edition to be for Normal people in their homes because it really kind of made sense when you understood how the software worked.
Speaker 1: The problem was is Windows 98 was still kind of unstable and slow and Windows 2000 wasn't and all the games worked on Windows 2000. so all the people switched to Windows 2000. now When they were upgrading Windows 2000 they still really had the idea that home users were on a different track.
Speaker 1: They weren't supposed to be using Windows 2000.
Speaker 1: So they came up with Windows me which was the next line in.
Speaker 1: you know Windows for the home user.
Speaker 1: The problem was Windows me was just Windows 98 with a bunch of shit on it and the shit made it crash all the time.
Speaker 1: It made it useless.
Speaker 1: It made it slow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it wasn't useful.
Speaker 1: It was No one was gonna pay for.
Speaker 1: it was security holes like more so than you would expect It was worse than Windows 98 second edition.
Speaker 0: They basically said it was worse than Windows 95.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they said here upgrade your Windows 98 to something even worse.
Speaker 1: when Windows 2000 was sitting there.
Speaker 1: That was better than everything that had already come.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because honestly I never used Windows 98.
Speaker 1: I used Windows 98.
Speaker 0: I had Windows 95 a I had Windows 95 B and then I had USB didn't you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't have any USB 95 B and then I had Windows 98 SE because those are the OEM CDs my dad stole from work.
Speaker 1: I Still have them.
Speaker 0: I waited in line the day Windows 2000 was released and bought it in the store for two hundred and seventy-nine.
Speaker 1: Now I didn't do that.
Speaker 1: I used Windows 98 SE for a while in tandem with Linux also.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I bought Windows 2000 to this day.
Speaker 0: I have a legitimate CD key.
Speaker 1: Wow awesome.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: now along the lines of computers.
Speaker 0: We'd like to say a bit about electronic voting and how.
Speaker 0: While it could have been done Well, it has turned into probably one of the most horrible things that could have happened to democracy in the United States.
Speaker 1: So you've got these voting machines.
Speaker 1: we go up in this touchscreen and you touch the name of the guy you want to vote for or a girl you want to Vote for and it.
Speaker 1: if I was gonna make an electronic voting machine.
Speaker 1: There are two components.
Speaker 1: Number one it has to count votes correctly.
Speaker 0: That's Increment a number.
Speaker 1: making a voting machine that works and counts votes is Incredibly trivial.
Speaker 1: you can make it in Visual Basic with the beginners book on Visual Basic if you knew nothing about programming whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It's so brain-dead stupid to write that software now.
Speaker 1: So the only thing it to really worry about when writing a voting machine is in the software because it's very simple.
Speaker 1: It's the security.
Speaker 1: so you need the software to be secure so that someone coming up and using the machine Can't force the machine to change the votes in any way.
Speaker 1: then you need the physical security.
Speaker 1: So the machine.
Speaker 1: no one can bust into it and mess around with the insides and change all the votes.
Speaker 1: The company that was hired to make digital electronic voting machines was devolved.
Speaker 0: They failed on all counts.
Speaker 0: The machines are blatantly obviously open and broken.
Speaker 1: Yep Well devolved is a company that is expert in making boxes mostly, you know safes Things you can't break into they may like.
Speaker 1: if you go into an office building You'll see like the circuit breakers are in a devolved box or a lot of ATM machines or devolved.
Speaker 1: You can't break into them.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of ATM machines.
Speaker 1: run windows and crash But that's of course, but the point is is it physically devolved makes things?
Speaker 1: Boxes physical boxes that are tough to bust into you need like dynamite and you know They can make it as tough as you want or as weak as you want it, you know, that's their specialty.
Speaker 1: Their software on the other hand is that like they just hire some schmucks to write some stupid software and they screw it up royally.
Speaker 1: so You they train.
Speaker 1: they actually did.
Speaker 1: this is a video on the internet.
Speaker 1: They trained a monkey to go up to a devolved voting machine and enter the debug mode and screw up all the votes.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the black box voting is showed over the past several months just more like countless holes that either back doors They're either intentional or just insane that let you do anything you want to the machine.
Speaker 0: There's also no physical verification of the votes.
Speaker 1: Yep, so It's not printed out.
Speaker 1: It's just written to memory.
Speaker 1: So if I go in and I change all the votes There's no way to know that the votes are changed or even if the machine if you say devolved was crooked.
Speaker 0: They could write the machine where I click on Joe Smith and it says you voted for Joe Smith But it counts a vote for Bob Shider.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have no idea what it's doing.
Speaker 1: It's all secret.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not hard to come up with a voting machine that works.
Speaker 0: I mean aside from the specific hardware Scott and I and I mean He could write the software in a few days.
Speaker 1: I got the software in one day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I'm talking, you know also testing and and getting vetting it by X.
Speaker 1: Okay, we in a week I could have perfect voting machine software and hardware.
Speaker 0: wise how hard is it to come up with this concept?
Speaker 0: All right, you got a touchscreen.
Speaker 0: you click on who you want to vote.
Speaker 0: It shows their name.
Speaker 0: It asks are you sure if you hit yes?
Speaker 0: It prints out a receipt behind glass showing your vote in ink your actual vote.
Speaker 0: Then it asks you is the vote on the piece of paper.
Speaker 0: You're correct.
Speaker 0: You say yes.
Speaker 0: It then puts that piece of paper internally into a box that is sealed.
Speaker 0: That way you have a perfect paper trail in case the machine breaks to verify.
Speaker 0: Yep, what what's?
Speaker 0: how could they not do that?
Speaker 0: How could for all the millions of dollars?
Speaker 0: They didn't do that unless they either have a reason not to do that or they're just so incompetent They couldn't.
Speaker 0: there's no alternative.
Speaker 0: They're either evil or incompetent and I really don't know both.
Speaker 1: They're both evil and incompetent because if they were just evil and not incompetent Then the machines would look perfect as far as we know and we wouldn't be able to figure out that they were evil.
Speaker 1: yet They would be evil, you know, it's they were incompetent Justin cut.
Speaker 1: Well, they could just be just incompetent.
Speaker 1: But yeah, they're either evil and incompetent or just incompetent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you'd think that evil and incompetent would count.
Speaker 0: cancel each other out.
Speaker 0: But for some reason they seem to amplify.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright, let's move away from computers a bit and all that.
Speaker 0: There's a something that I saw in the mid 90s and it's been around for a long time and the news is finally Realizing and reporting that this is crap.
Speaker 0: now You know people have been on a kick about like home air filtration and that sort of thing for a long time.
Speaker 0: places like sharper image have sold these ionizing air filters and What they do is they ionize the air.
Speaker 0: Well, they that they basically pull dust particles out of the air with electricity.
Speaker 0: Now you think oh that'll keep my house clean.
Speaker 0: and a lot of places sold these especially to elders people in houses and they sold Them and you know, Brooke stone type stores.
Speaker 0: and as a kid I thought wouldn't I just make a bunch of ozone and you know what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it makes a bunch of ozone which for those of you who aren't aware is toxic.
Speaker 1: Yep, so these ozone is all cool and it's in the ozone layer because it you know Makes the Sun go away and not give you cancer.
Speaker 0: and it's cool in small quantities because it smells good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it smells like thunderstorm and Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Yep That's a good smell.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is.
Speaker 1: But in large quantities, like I fill the room with ozone you're gonna die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and especially susceptible are the elderly who are the primary market for those sharper image bullshit fests.
Speaker 1: So ionizing air filters one of the worst technologies ever technology that just harms people and guys no benefit It's a poison killer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean this is worse than some of the things like magnet bracelets.
Speaker 1: sure magnet rate bracelets don't actually heal you They don't do anything.
Speaker 1: They're just bullshit, but they don't hurt you.
Speaker 0: Well, they might hurt you psychologically They might hurt you psychologically and they'll hurt you financially.
Speaker 1: They will not hurt you physically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the best are you me can make that they hurt you physically.
Speaker 0: is that because you have them?
Speaker 0: you don't seek other treatment?
Speaker 0: But that's very indirect.
Speaker 1: Yes, the ionizing air filter will hurt you financially Psychologically and then physically it will kill you with ozone.
Speaker 0: Hey Scott, you want to buy a poison gas maker.
Speaker 1: really a That's great for parties, I'll just stick it in someone else's room.
Speaker 0: Great, all right.
Speaker 0: So back to computers.
Speaker 0: Does anyone remember Microsoft Bob?
Speaker 1: I remember Microsoft Bob.
Speaker 0: Bob was an attempt to make computers accessible to idiots.
Speaker 1: It was this.
Speaker 1: it wasn't even an operating system.
Speaker 1: It was this piece of software that was called Microsoft Bob and you would run it After you started Windows or maybe set it up to run on Windows startup.
Speaker 1: I think it's Windows 3.1, right?
Speaker 0: I believe so.
Speaker 1: and what it did is it showed you it like.
Speaker 1: it turned the desktop From a metaphor into a literal thing.
Speaker 1: It showed you this picture of a room with a desk and a bookshelf and all this stuff and this happy smiley face whose name was Microsoft Bob and you would click around the room to make your computer do stuff.
Speaker 1: and you could you know, You click on the Rolodex to store your phone numbers and you you know I don't really remember it all too clearly because I only used it in a CompUSA.
Speaker 0: There are lots of websites that will show you in detail.
Speaker 0: In fact, there there are Bob software's out there.
Speaker 0: That'll show you what Bob was like.
Speaker 0: Yeah search hard enough.
Speaker 0: The problem with Bob is one.
Speaker 0: it was done really poorly like really poorly.
Speaker 0: It didn't work and it crashed and took up all your machines RAM.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it didn't work.
Speaker 1: It crashed.
Speaker 1: computers couldn't really handle all the graphics.
Speaker 1: It wanted to do.
Speaker 1: it was really Even if you used it and made things brain-dead easy or at least it made things make sense for idiots.
Speaker 1: the problem was is it was horribly inefficient.
Speaker 1: if you Kind of knew what you wanted to do with your computer Bob just got in your way and made it harder for you to get your work done.
Speaker 0: Bob also prevented you from learning how your computer really worked so you wouldn't really understand how your computer worked because it put this metaphor in front of you instead.
Speaker 0: that was so Abstracted.
Speaker 0: and the problem is that the metaphor, you know, all right, I'm in my office, but now you get unintended Consequences of that because you think of how you would do something in your office and that's not how you do it on a computer.
Speaker 1: Nope, not at all.
Speaker 1: so Microsoft Bob failed miserably.
Speaker 1: no one bought it and it's a Computer's back in the day like in the in the 90s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was a similar Semi-bad thing called Packard Bell Navigator.
Speaker 1: Oh, there were.
Speaker 1: there were things for all kinds of computers.
Speaker 1: There was a tab works Yeah, which is I think on a lot of compact computers.
Speaker 1: and basically all these were Because Windows 3.1 the operating system had the program manager.
Speaker 1: and what these things were is they replaced the program manager with some other Interface that was supposedly more efficient, you know user interface wise tab works had all these tabs which made it somewhat easier to use than the program manager, which is Now.
Speaker 1: if you go over try to use program manager nowadays You just want to kill yourself God.
Speaker 1: But the problem was they were all slow or useless or they had.
Speaker 1: you know They weren't compatible with all the kinds of crazy stuff and they just caused problems.
Speaker 1: Though trivia manager did work, even though it was a pain in the ass to use before Windows 95.
Speaker 0: You all realize that there was no such thing as a taskbar, right?
Speaker 1: There was no taskbar.
Speaker 1: You had program manager.
Speaker 0: that was it.
Speaker 1: you had this one icon and you're the program manager and you could minimize things to the real Desktop including program manager.
Speaker 0: Yep, and they minimized as little icons.
Speaker 0: Yep and Program manager if you minimize that all you had was a blank desktop with one icon on it program manager.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm That was it.
Speaker 0: That was your computer.
Speaker 1: Even before that you had DOS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't you?
Speaker 1: actually if you exited Windows you went to DOS because Windows is wasn't an operating system.
Speaker 1: originally It was a program that ran in DOS.
Speaker 1: I basically would just type DOS commands for whatever you were doing and it loaded a bunch of like wrapper driver type of things and then other programs could run in Windows, which is running in DOS and DOS.
Speaker 1: DOS really wasn't much of an operating system Which is why you were able to run Windows on it because DOS was already so close to the hardware that Windows wasn't very far away from the hardware running on DOS.
Speaker 1: In fact Windows now, which isn't running on DOS is probably farther away from the hardware than Windows 3.1 was Alright.
Speaker 0: last and least It amazes me how few people I meet in the street know about this because it was big news As far as I can remember and I remember laughing at it failing.
Speaker 1: I remember my friend who worked at Circuit City trying to sell it to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I knew someone who bought one.
Speaker 0: Whoa, no, he bought it because after it failed as a DVD player.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, his DVD players back then were expensive.
Speaker 0: They were.
Speaker 0: we're talking about divics.
Speaker 1: Now you might.
Speaker 1: when someone says divics You might be thinking about the video file format that you download from the internet and watch anime with and such.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they named that codec.
Speaker 0: that because it screwed me up for the longest time.
Speaker 1: It screwed me up as long as time.
Speaker 1: I was like, why are they calling this divics?
Speaker 1: There's already something else called divics that Existed and died.
Speaker 1: you can't calling it.
Speaker 1: The same thing is only gonna mean bad things for you.
Speaker 0: It's like they didn't even know.
Speaker 1: they must have not known.
Speaker 0: I think they didn't know cuz I mean I meet people who are older than me who've never heard of divics yet.
Speaker 1: It made big news.
Speaker 1: It was very big news and Circuit City had a huge thing because they were like the number one company trying to sell it.
Speaker 0: Divics was a semi competitor to DVD.
Speaker 0: That had its gimmick was that you buy a divics player and you plug the divics player into a phone line.
Speaker 0: You buy.
Speaker 1: did you have to plug it into a phone line?
Speaker 0: I think you had.
Speaker 0: yeah, it had to be able to phone home.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't know that part.
Speaker 0: I think there were some that didn't but I know it had to be able to phone home at some point.
Speaker 0: like occasionally Like once a month you have to plug it into the phone line.
Speaker 0: Let it call back and figure out stuff.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that.
Speaker 0: all right But you get a divics disk and you buy it and it cost like a dollar or two and it's a movie DVD.
Speaker 1: they were like what people don't want to pay $20 for DVDs and they've been paying $10.
Speaker 1: or VHS is.
Speaker 1: we're gonna make a Divx player which is basically DVD movies But they cost a dollar and that way people will buy a shit ton of these $1 Videos and we'll make a killing off of them.
Speaker 0: So you put it in your divx player and you watch it.
Speaker 0: right now you've watched it once.
Speaker 0: you have to pay The divx company to watch it again like another 50 cents every time you want to watch it.
Speaker 1: So instead of going to Blockbuster or using Netflix you have to mail discs back and forth.
Speaker 1: you would go to the store Give put like a dollar in a vending machine or give a dollar to Circuit City get whatever movie you wanted and bring it home And you could keep that forever instead of renting it, but you only got to watch it once and if you wanted to watch it again You would have to pay more money.
Speaker 1: and that way you know like how many DVDs Do you have?
Speaker 1: where you paid 20 bucks and you watch it one time?
Speaker 0: How the initial D movie?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: And how many DVDs do you buy once and you watch them 30 times?
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: so their idea was that you buy more DVDs that you watch once then you buy DVDs that you watch 30 times and Therefore using Divx will save you money, and it'll make them a lot of money by giving you Divx.
Speaker 0: They had a huge marketing campaign about this, and it was a everywhere was a big deal.
Speaker 0: They were pushing it as this is going to be the future and the first thing I thought when I heard it was wow why don't I just hack it so I could buy movies for a dollar?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what.
Speaker 1: why don't I just hack it?
Speaker 1: so um?
Speaker 1: I buy the movie, and then I never need to give them money again and it lets me watch the movie forever and ever.
Speaker 0: every geek thought that and Luckily even beyond that the rest of the consumer world just balked at it, and it died almost immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they Circuit City really tried to sell these players to people because they were cheaper than DVD players.
Speaker 1: obviously because they had this you Know subscription plan thing going on, but they also.
Speaker 0: they also play DVDs.
Speaker 1: They also play DVDs, so Some people bought them and use them as DVD players.
Speaker 1: some people you know people didn't really understand the whole Divx thing no matter How much Circuit City employees tried to explain it to them.
Speaker 0: Circuit City took a bath like they.
Speaker 0: they they didn't.
Speaker 0: they got close to Bankruptcy.
Speaker 0: I believe.
Speaker 1: over that Circuit City is not doing as well as Best Buy these days even though It's pretty much the same store.
Speaker 1: It's a Best Buy.
Speaker 1: I think sells like home appliances and Circuit City does not.
Speaker 0: yeah But Circuit City dumped money into this knowing it was gonna succeed.
Speaker 0: the same way Nokia dumped money into the engage knowing it would succeed.
Speaker 1: I'm an engaged tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is it failed.
Speaker 0: It's one thing if a company takes a risk on something and and you know accepts that risk like we might lose this money.
Speaker 0: They must have assumed that this would succeed.
Speaker 0: so when they failed they couldn't really deal with that.
Speaker 0: the money was gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was really bad for Circuit City and the technology itself was really bad and everything about it was bad.
Speaker 1: It's one of the worst technology things ever.
Speaker 0: The scary thing is as time goes on I could see technology like that being more acceptable to the consumer public Because they're starting to accept DRM more and more.
Speaker 0: but if you tried to voice the DRM that is currently in like HDTV To people 10 years ago.
Speaker 0: They'd laugh at you spit on you, and then tell you to die in a fire.
Speaker 1: Well the thing is people are willing to accept DRM as long as it doesn't get in the way.
Speaker 1: So look at Apple.
Speaker 1: Apple has DRM and iTunes right.
Speaker 0: you don't even notice it.
Speaker 1: You don't notice it.
Speaker 1: It doesn't you never.
Speaker 1: you wouldn't know is there if no one told you or unless you tried to really do some crazy stuff The DRM in What has really bad DRM?
Speaker 0: the Sony recording bit?
Speaker 0: I'm holding right here in my hand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that really gets in the way because you buy a recording you know device And you want to take the audio from it and put it on your computer But you can't because you need to use Sony special software and Sony special software sucks And then you can't do it with Linux in meter It.
Speaker 1: it starts to get annoying that the DRM is preventing you from doing something you should be able to do.
Speaker 1: The Apple iTunes DRM really doesn't prevent you from doing that much that you should be able to do.
Speaker 1: You really have to kind of go way out of your way to make it say you can't do that.
Speaker 0: And that's basically it.
Speaker 0: I mean we could talk for hours Based on our thinking and trying to remember Technologies in recent years that have been just objectively terrible that weren't already related to anime or video games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this isn't gonna be.
Speaker 1: this is gonna probably be the worst Episode in worst week.
Speaker 1: not that it's gonna be bad that it was a bad episode But it it's not gonna be as good as the rest of the week.
Speaker 1: So because video game news like the end the game gear failing and the virtual boy The gizmondo power glove yeah, there are so many video game things we can talk a long time about.
Speaker 1: that are CDI.
Speaker 1: There you go Atari.
Speaker 1: Well, not all of Atari.
Speaker 1: Atari.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the the whole Atari leading into the crash of the gaming industry Yep, but we're just gonna talk about games and consoles and such.
Speaker 1: so yep, Neo Geo Saturn Yeah, so you know I'm sure there's a bunch of horrible technology We missed but that's obvious because we only prepared for like an hour before the episode.
Speaker 1: There's no way we could have found all or remembered all the old stuff.
Speaker 1: That was terrible.
Speaker 0: plus remember things like favorites week best week worst week our weeks.
Speaker 0: We can do again if we really get hard up for content because there's more to talk about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think that'll happen for a while though.
Speaker 0: No we got a lot of content.
Speaker 1: So if you've got a horrible technology That was just terrible and you remember it, and we didn't go to the forum with everyone else and we'll go oh, yeah Oh my god.
Speaker 1: We should have talked about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, holy crap, and if you don't remember Divx don't say anything.
Speaker 0: It'll just make me feel really old.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just go on the internet and search for Divx and or on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: that way you can yeah look on Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: If you just search for Divx you'll find nothing but codex you'll find nothing But the actual good Divx video format, but if you go on Wikipedia You'll find a story about the old crap Divx we're talking about and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.