Speaker 1: It's Tuesday September 12th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We continue origins week with detail of how we discovered video games.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, we're a bit by bit planning our trip to uber con in New Jersey this year where we will be doing a podcasting panel And probably some other fun things.
Speaker 1: The uber con it is an awesome convention of awesome.
Speaker 0: now We're not as some of you have asked going to do a pregame show for uber con.
Speaker 1: We've really only do pregame shows for Otakon and if we went to PAX we might do a pregame show.
Speaker 1: Or if we were going to e3 if it existed anymore Or if we're going to anime Expo or anything big like San Diego comic-con We would get a pregame show.
Speaker 0: much of the smallest con that I would even consider doing a pregame show for be katsu khan.
Speaker 0: And if then only because there's a chance we'll be doing a lot at katsu khan Yeah pretty much.
Speaker 0: the pregame show is for the conventions with at least 20,000 people and no other conventions or Conventions that are so awesome that you multiply the number of people there by some arbitrary number of like 1.6.
Speaker 1: So here's your uber con pregame show everyone.
Speaker 1: You're ready go to uber con.
Speaker 0: go on Friday Play awesome games play in Luke cranes game called burning wheel Inheritance playing that and also come see us.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Our panel will likely be from 11 to noon on Saturday.
Speaker 0: It'll be the typical podcasting panel though.
Speaker 0: We might be sharing it with two other podcasters though I think that would be interesting because I don't know if there are many Podcasters out there who would go to the kind of cons we go to Or not to sound conceited but as professional as we are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know who these podcasters are.
Speaker 1: Are they someone we know?
Speaker 1: are they someone we don't know?
Speaker 0: I don't really know who they are, but I didn't really look.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna look up who they are tonight sometime.
Speaker 1: Oh, did they tell you they are?
Speaker 0: they told me two people who might want to share the panel with us.
Speaker 0: They gave names and I didn't recognize the names off hand.
Speaker 1: if it's those dragons landing guys I listen to their show.
Speaker 1: They're cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know who else it could be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll find out.
Speaker 0: I just I get the.
Speaker 0: I get the expectation that the panel that if we ever shared a panel with anyone Would just be us talking and us correcting anyone else who said anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might be.
Speaker 1: we'll see what we do about panels at the sitcom.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, we'll talk more about sitcom tomorrow because it is more of an anime thing than a gaming thing.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: But anyway today is game day and we have a lot of well Video game related talk since we're doing origins week and many of you have been wondering how we got into video games.
Speaker 1: That is what we're gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: But first the news is.
Speaker 1: the news is and today was Apple Day.
Speaker 1: Everybody knows it yada yada yada now.
Speaker 0: I gotta say Apple Apple Apple.
Speaker 0: This was probably the least Anticipated Apple Day there has ever been for my perspective because I barely remembered it happened and I totally forgot about it And I thought all right.
Speaker 0: I have an iPod nano.
Speaker 0: It's pretty badass.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine them releasing anything other than possibly a larger nano Hard drive wise or a nano in a different color.
Speaker 1: Well nanos don't have hard drives.
Speaker 1: They have flash.
Speaker 0: But yeah a larger storage mechanism.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, what did Apple release today?
Speaker 1: I'll sum it up real quick.
Speaker 1: Number one.
Speaker 1: They got a new shuffle that doesn't suck It's smaller and better.
Speaker 1: They have new nanos.
Speaker 1: They're basically the same as the nanos We already have except they're like the mini with the with the metal instead of the scratched up plastic so they won't scratch up.
Speaker 0: They'll be twice as durable.
Speaker 1: Right and if you get the 2 gig one you have to get silver.
Speaker 1: if you get the 4 gig you can get green blue Or pink.
Speaker 1: and if you get the 8 gig nano the new 8 gig nano comes only in black.
Speaker 0: That is a lot like what I used to happen back in the realm the first MMO.
Speaker 0: I bring it up only because I remember this and it happened in puzzle pirates, too.
Speaker 0: By making the black item only available with the highest end item People now have more incentive to buy the highest end item who might not otherwise need the 8 gigabytes.
Speaker 1: Because now all of a sudden you're cool.
Speaker 1: You have the black one.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm cool because I have a black nano and you can all go to hell.
Speaker 1: personally I have a black nano.
Speaker 1: that's 4 gigs.
Speaker 1: and if I was buying a nano today, and I didn't have one right now I would buy that metal green one or that metal blue one because the metal is way better than the scratching plastic.
Speaker 0: The thing is my nanos not scratched up at all.
Speaker 1: No because you yours came with a protect II thing.
Speaker 0: It's not just a protect II thing.
Speaker 0: It's also a buffer.
Speaker 0: every time I put it in it cleans it and polishes it.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't have one of those things.
Speaker 1: how you saw cuz I bought my nano right away.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you know what?
Speaker 0: because I purchased my Apple product later.
Speaker 0: It is far superior.
Speaker 1: They also came out with new regular iPods black and white.
Speaker 1: they think there's a 30 gig and an 80.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure they're big.
Speaker 1: They're the regular iPods But they have higher resolution screens.
Speaker 1: So now the video is 640 by 480 and the screen is brighter but it's the same size screen as before.
Speaker 1: oh and Yeah, that's about.
Speaker 1: and iTunes 7 which I whatever I actually that's the most.
Speaker 1: that's if anything isn't cool.
Speaker 1: That's what's cool because iTunes 7 sucks way less than iTunes 6 really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I installed it on this computer and I upgraded the little Mac mini downstairs.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, see, I haven't looked because I put a whole bunch of podcast.
Speaker 0: I listen to so many podcasts now that I haven't had to update my nano in like a week So I haven't even touched the Mac downstairs.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I just I just did it when I got home I upgraded the one downstairs and I upgraded this as soon as possible and a lot of the Difficulties people have with iTunes will now no longer be a problem.
Speaker 1: It's now easier to use your iPod and like a bunch of different computers that all have iTunes You know It's easier to have multiple iPods on the same computer.
Speaker 1: a lot of the options that a lot of people Needed to use but didn't know how to use or hidden away in the options menu and now they're right up front.
Speaker 1: The software that updates your iPods firmware is now part of iTunes.
Speaker 1: You don't have to go downloading that separately all the time.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of good stuff in there now.
Speaker 1: It's way cool.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's still iTunes But it's better than the old iTunes significantly and it's free.
Speaker 0: I mean, I got to say it's sad to me that iTunes really isn't that great.
Speaker 0: all things considered it really isn't the only for like podcasting and everything except that While it's far from great.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much better than any other solution.
Speaker 1: That's in terms of synchronizing with the iPod or any mp3 player for that matter, you know The whole process of getting podcasts maintaining, you know Your podcast collection and then synchronizing it with an mp3 playing device.
Speaker 1: iTunes is the only program that does it all in one go in a smooth way, you know It's iTunes 6 or 7 7 is just slightly smoother, you know And no other program can do that.
Speaker 1: Even though iTunes is kind of crappy at like music management and all this other stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh, they added other stuff too like iTunes 7 will now just go out and get album covers for songs you have Really?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, even my pirated songs.
Speaker 1: Supposedly it says when you uh, you need to decide to enable that option.
Speaker 1: It says that we are going to send information, you know to get the album covers But Apple is not keeping any information about any songs you have.
Speaker 1: That's what it says.
Speaker 0: It's like out.
Speaker 0: I doubt that Apple would have album covers for the vast majority of my music collection.
Speaker 1: I also doubt that but Supposedly they're gonna get album covers somehow.
Speaker 0: So hey, I'm really curious about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Actually, I turned it on but I haven't.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try it out in a bit to see how it actually works.
Speaker 0: Well, we've got on the Mac right now some cat Empire and some Tom McRae and stuff so we could try that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it has to be something that's like in the iTunes music store for it to work.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I had to go and investigate.
Speaker 1: Another thing is there's talk of this ITV which is like it's.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's out but it's gonna be out.
Speaker 1: It's basically a little.
Speaker 1: it's like a flat Flatter wider Mac mini, but it's not a computer.
Speaker 1: You just plug it into your your TV You know your big screen real television.
Speaker 1: and then what you can do is from any iTunes, you know on the same network You can say hey see that video.
Speaker 1: I have play it out of that Television over there.
Speaker 1: and so that way you can download things off of iTunes like movies and play them out of your television Sort of like the Airport Express allows you to play music from your iTunes on your computer out of your stereo If you have you know with the audio out hole.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'd be a lot more impressed by that if it weren't for the fact that at least as a geek those problems are easily solved With cables that connect various devices together and a computer.
Speaker 1: Yes had a computer and okay The last two bits of news in the whole thing.
Speaker 1: or that you can buy games for your iPod for five bucks.
Speaker 1: Why fucking dollars you get?
Speaker 1: you can get Tetris you can get pac-man you can be jeweled $5.
Speaker 1: yeah, I was thinking about doing it just to try it out and to have five one dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a lot of money for a probably mediocre game.
Speaker 0: with that You couldn't control so easily because it's on your iPod.
Speaker 1: Well, the iPod is up down left right and a button.
Speaker 1: That's it's not so bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm real leery that plus five bucks.
Speaker 0: I could see it being a dollar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I thought about it for a minute just to see how it work.
Speaker 1: But hey, it's like I could understand.
Speaker 1: maybe on the normal iPod It might be a little better.
Speaker 0: on the note in terms of up down left right button My cell phone is the exact same loadout.
Speaker 1: Yeah cell phone games are five bucks, too.
Speaker 0: Well now the cell phone games on my phone are $2.
Speaker 0: the ones on my phone are $5 But the thing is they're all terrible and they're not worth any amount of money.
Speaker 1: There was gonna be a Phoenix Wright, but I haven't seen it yet.
Speaker 0: Whatever anything Phoenix Wright would also come out to the DS.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: There's no worries on that front.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the last thing is that all the iPods are cheaper now.
Speaker 1: The now the 8 gig iPod cost as my iPod nano cost the same amount as like the 30 gig iPod.
Speaker 0: god Damn it.
Speaker 1: It's the same price.
Speaker 0: I just bought an iPod nano.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I bought one as soon as it came out So I got the least screwed possible, but you know, the thing is that it's actually kind of good about this particular iPod upgrade season is that these aren't really sixth sixth generation iPods, you know these are more like the 5.5 generation iPods because I mean when our Fifth generation iPods came out the previous generation of iPods is basically useless like they couldn't do any of the new stuff.
Speaker 1: I have a fifth generation iPod and I can get in on all this new iTunes stuff.
Speaker 1: I can download the games I can pretty much everything except the video which I couldn't do anyway because I have a nano.
Speaker 1: You know for all intents and purposes other than the metal casing My 4 gig nano is just as good as the new 4 gig nano.
Speaker 1: So I'm not so upset and Probably some when my nano dies.
Speaker 1: I'll reconsider my portable media device options.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway, I'll be quick about my bit of news because we imagine we could talk a lot about our main bit today.
Speaker 0: We could indeed but Facebook has been impressed a lot lately.
Speaker 0: first because they added all this user tracking stuff.
Speaker 0: Well, it wasn't really adding anything.
Speaker 0: It just they added reporting where now there was a little feed where all your friends could see what you do on the site all the time which sparked Massive outrage among hundreds of thousands of Facebook users.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh
Speaker 1: I didn't realize that many people were still using it Like I used it and then I just kind of let it sit there and if it ever emails me which means like someone from my past is looking for me then I can get the emails and I'll go check it.
Speaker 1: but Otherwise, they just let it sit there.
Speaker 0: see a lot of people use Facebook a lot.
Speaker 0: basically everyone who wants that sort of thing and Doesn't want to use myspace for obvious reasons use Facebook Mm-hmm, but Facebook as everyone knows was fairly off-limits.
Speaker 0: You had to be in a school and they've opened it up bit by bit over the years But you had to be basically a student somewhere or like an employee of a company like Apple to get in on it.
Speaker 0: Now they've said they're opening it up to the world and once again Facebook users have protested in the many many many thousands.
Speaker 0: They're incredibly pissed off.
Speaker 1: My prediction is that at first Facebook will become infinitely more usable as more and more people get into it.
Speaker 1: Like how many people from my past, you know have might have been looking for me But they couldn't because they didn't go to school so they didn't get on Facebook.
Speaker 1: And well, do I really want to see those people is another story?
Speaker 0: Plus there's the fact that I kind of wanted to get in on Facebook way back But I had effectively left our IT and I there's really no way I could as an alumni thingy.
Speaker 1: That's how I'm in there.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point the other thing is I predict that very soon some random country will take over Facebook.
Speaker 0: pick a country I'd say Brazil, but they're so in trend up.
Speaker 1: Brazil's are.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be Peruvian Facebook.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you right now Who's gonna take it over.
Speaker 0: the thing is no one took over myspace except punk kids.
Speaker 1: Yep Punk kids are their own country now.
Speaker 0: Well, the worry is that now that it's open all the people in there are worried that it's just gonna descend into the depths That myspace is in.
Speaker 1: I don't think so because Facebook is a different thing from myspace.
Speaker 1: My space is you make a page where you basically advertise yourself and chat with friends.
Speaker 1: Facebook is more of a find.
Speaker 1: You know people you went to school with in high school in college and you know Arrange for parties and only.
Speaker 1: it really doesn't have the expanded functionality and freedom that myspace has.
Speaker 1: so you can't make a terrible web Page with Facebook all you can do.
Speaker 1: I mean it does less than Orkut does, you know, it's very single purpose.
Speaker 0: well the other thing I think it won't fall the to the faith that Orkut fell to at least because The main failing of Orkut was that it was very spammable.
Speaker 0: it trusted everyone to not be an asshole.
Speaker 0: Because if it's invite only nous, yeah, and it was fine until some guy Invited some Brazilian kids someday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do think though that Facebook might have to worry about spammers people making fake pages like hey I'm a girl at your college.
Speaker 1: come out with me, you know that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Why don't we make a whole bunch of pages that are I'm a girl.
Speaker 0: come out with me.
Speaker 1: Why would we do that?
Speaker 0: you sounded like me because then I don't know we could lure.
Speaker 1: You want to lure boys into your bed?
Speaker 1: Yes, we know we're in.
Speaker 1: Yes You want to lure all the college boys into your bed?
Speaker 0: I believe that that was more of a topic for tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, yeah, I might jump on just because Facebook might be slightly useful if anything for geek.
Speaker 1: Yes, I just keep my page up there in case people from my past That's a good place that they might know to look for me.
Speaker 0: My Orkut is still up there and I occasionally get email from Brazilian people trying to convince me to join whatever Spanish group they formed.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 0: thankfully Tonight I have very special and very sad thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So special
Speaker 0: this is see but I have a tiny glimmer of hope that this is a joke because 4chan has been known to pull jokes like this before where they make up the kind of person they don't like and Then they they basically make their own straw man and then beat that straw man at the Internet.
Speaker 0: I mean they've done it before at Otacon once they had a guy Pretend to be a perverted furry guy in a fursuit and then they had another guy attack him and like another year They put someone up to do something stupid as some other they just.
Speaker 0: they seem to do that sort of thing a lot But at the same time I've known people like this guy.
Speaker 0: I've seen people like this guy and I really am.
Speaker 0: I'm doubtful that this guy is not entirely sincere in his internet bravado.
Speaker 0: This is a video of a man a fat man a fat stuttering man.
Speaker 0: There's a nervous fat man who's emotionally problem Trying to put forth his manifesto to the internet that all of the 4chan people who invade his chat rooms And the YMNTD.
Speaker 0: Yes the YMNTD.
Speaker 0: He says that twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's YTMND.
Speaker 1: You the man now dawg.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: You ain't the man now.
Speaker 1: You were never the man.
Speaker 1: You're the loser.
Speaker 0: He basically says I'm this awesome guy.
Speaker 0: I Am going after this because I'm dressed up to the graduation of my sister or something from police academy Just a little aside there that he brings up.
Speaker 0: And he you know join me smart people in the fight against these 4chan idiots.
Speaker 0: I have gotten the police to go after all of you.
Speaker 0: They'll be knocking on your doors shortly.
Speaker 0: That's what you get burn fading my chat rooms and generally annoying people on the internet and being 4channers.
Speaker 1: Yes, you're not free to be a punk kid while there is a fat Christian idiot guy talking on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I don't think we're religion bashing at this point, which we do occasionally Somewhat often but in this case the guy very specifically at the end out of the blue for no just says You guys can't stop me from preaching Christianity.
Speaker 1: He's like I'll continue to preach Jesus the word of Jesus in my chat rooms.
Speaker 1: It's like Alright, but if you leave your chat room open You can't complain of.
Speaker 1: a bunch of 4chan kids come in there and harass you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like uh, you know Where's your God now?
Speaker 1: How come he's not, you know punishing these 4chan kids who were supposedly like?
Speaker 0: actually You know why?
Speaker 0: because if he were a Christian or you know I actually studied all that stuff.
Speaker 0: the New Testament has a lot of things about how Don't get revenge on people now because God will take care of that later.
Speaker 1: But isn't he trying to get revenge on people now, but oh supposedly.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe he's not the best kind of Christian.
Speaker 1: It's one of those people just you know says a bunch of Christian words and believe was what he wants to believe and is stupid and insane and is a person and is the kind of person who makes this world the worst place and he's fat.
Speaker 0: The sad thing is I've seen a lot of people like this before and there's things like YouTube have gotten more prevalent.
Speaker 0: It is a lot easier for people like this guy to put themselves in front of the veritable Steamroller that is popular internet culture.
Speaker 0: this guy Is going to be completely bowled over by everyone who thinks he's sad?
Speaker 1: yeah, it's sort of like if You know a Jewish woman walked into Syria or Iran like hey, what's up?
Speaker 1: Not wearing any you know the cover-ups you wear a bikini like hey no no she'd have to walk in and scream about how.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's basically what this guy's doing and You know.
Speaker 0: now you can see the armies of 4chan have already destroyed all the comments on this video.
Speaker 1: They have indeed.
Speaker 0: I mean this guy really reminds me of Things that I got to get off of my chest hurting this community more.
Speaker 0: so now Deep in other people all right.
Speaker 1: well you get real deep into that guy cuz he's so fat All right, so there was a thread in our forum about Mighty Max, which is an old cartoon and toy.
Speaker 1: I guess I'm not a hundred percent sure and Someone who is the someone up?
Speaker 1: I do our friend I do.
Speaker 1: She said she remembers the show and Apparently he looked on IMDb and the show Mighty Max had a storyline about Cthulhu.
Speaker 0: oh really yeah really.
Speaker 1: so I went to the IMDb and you know what I noticed there.
Speaker 1: it says Apparently there was another cartoon show a cartoon show that I actually watched which also had an episode about Cthulhu.
Speaker 0: now After I saw this episode I might have seen that but not known what Cthulhu was back then.
Speaker 1: I believe that might have also been.
Speaker 1: my Situation is that when I was a kid I might have seen this episode of this show and not Realized what I was seeing because I didn't know about Cthulhu mythos till like I got to college.
Speaker 0: so Scott What were you seeing I?
Speaker 1: Was well of course as soon as I realized that there was an episode of the show dealing with Cthulhu I've searched for it on YouTube.
Speaker 1: lo and behold there it was photography photography.
Speaker 1: there is an episode of the real Ghostbusters Written by what was the guy's name Michael Evans or something.
Speaker 0: well Scott just updated the Wikipedia article about him to add this Ghostbusters episode to his credit list.
Speaker 1: I did and it's in the Ghostbusters episode where the Ghostbusters Fight Cthulhu and there's an evil cult who summons him and there's an economic on and a Miskatonic University.
Speaker 0: the best part is that at the end one the crazy cultist is being dragged away And he starts quoting basically HP Lovecraft at them.
Speaker 1: They quote this HP Lovecraft all over this episode like you think it's just.
Speaker 1: oh they K They made a monster Cthulhu for them to fight.
Speaker 1: no they went all out.
Speaker 1: I mean the name of the episode is the collect call of Cthulhu.
Speaker 0: They spell it wrong But we're pretty sure that was just a copyright issue and to help kids read because it was you know phonetically correct.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I was a little kid, and I saw a word spelled like Cthulhu I don't think I know what to do with that.
Speaker 1: I would know to do it either.
Speaker 1: and you know watching the show I realized the real Ghostbusters wasn't a bad show.
Speaker 1: It's still tolerable to watch it today, and the voice acting was really good.
Speaker 1: I mean those guys did a pretty good job of impersonating the actors from the movie.
Speaker 1: it sounds just like him and There's good writing.
Speaker 0: and and the best part was at the end when the girl takes the Necronomicon back to Miskatonic Mm-hmm and the Ghostbusters like so we beat him and shit.
Speaker 0: They're like she's basically says something to the effect of oh heavens no he'll be back, but not right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah They're just like great.
Speaker 1: We're the Ghostbusters.
Speaker 1: whatever the thing is the link.
Speaker 1: I'm giving you guys is To the second half of the episode on YouTube.
Speaker 1: It's actually titled Kaza phantasmos verse Cthulhu - because Kaza.
Speaker 1: it's some Spanish guy posted it and Kaza phantasmos is Ghostbusters.
Speaker 1: but You can see if you look on the right side of the page you can see the first half of the episode.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: so a link to the first half of the episode.
Speaker 1: in case you want to see that the second half is really the only Is the good part so?
Speaker 1: It's all you.
Speaker 0: Well to continue Origins week.
Speaker 1: well actually I just checked the forum just now and we would you believe it in The poll to see what our episode tonight is.
Speaker 0: it is it tied should be about.
Speaker 1: it is a dead Heat.
Speaker 1: it is 20 votes for video games and 20 votes for board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: now I know that only 40 of you voted what.
Speaker 0: there are so many of you in there.
Speaker 1: I Guess a lot of you didn't care.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: I've noticed that aside from a contingent of about 60 people most people don't seem to check the forum every day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is probably good because the forum is getting to the point where we're going to have to hire more moderators.
Speaker 1: I think it might.
Speaker 1: mr..
Speaker 0: Perry can't keep up with you people anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Because video games is winning most of the day and board games just finally caught up.
Speaker 0: Yes, mad props to the board game rally, but I've already been thinking about what I'd say about video games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know I mean It would have been something if you were winning by one vote.
Speaker 1: now I would turn it over you know, but we already did the intro to the show.
Speaker 0: so so once again Democracy matters.
Speaker 0: one vote counts.
Speaker 0: you could have been the one if you thought you wanted to hear us talk about Role-playing games, and you didn't vote in that survey.
Speaker 1: This is your fault Yeah, so um you should join the forum, and you should watch out for when.
Speaker 1: we you know.
Speaker 1: Do that this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: yes, there will be another origins week because there are many origins topics We've gotten into a lot of.
Speaker 1: there's no way for me to close the pole while keeping it visible.
Speaker 1: I can remove the pole But I can't just like close it projects.
Speaker 0: kill the pole because people are gonna go vote now, and it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: yeah All right, I'll remove the pole.
Speaker 0: I would like to say that Scott and I have Quite a bit of video game credentials probably more so than we have computer credentials.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think my computer credentials might be slightly better, but I have mad video game.
Speaker 0: We at least have mad old-school video game credentials, that's for sure.
Speaker 0: I mean I Have been exposed to video games since the moment.
Speaker 0: I was conceived.
Speaker 1: my mom was playing breakout.
Speaker 0: My mom played the Atari 2600 our family had while she was pregnant with me, and I remember very specifically.
Speaker 0: she liked the 2600 because the Controls on it on the actual physical box were these big metal switches that stuck out and she could stick her foot over and reset Games without having to sit up while she was pregnant.
Speaker 1: Yeah My mom just liked to play breakout with the paddles.
Speaker 0: also my grandpa on my father's side had an Atari 2600.
Speaker 0: He played all the time.
Speaker 0: my dad played Atari all the time in addition to my mom and on my other Grandparents side they had an Intellivision 2 and an Intellivision that they played all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, wasn't your grandma the burger time?
Speaker 1: man?
Speaker 0: my grandma was better at burger time than I have ever been.
Speaker 0: Wow And my my dad was.
Speaker 0: I mean we'll talk about this game called kaboom in a minute.
Speaker 0: It was not until I was about 20 that I finally surpassed my father's skill at kaboom Mmm, but I've been playing video games my entire life.
Speaker 0: My family was playing video games many many many years before they even decided to have children.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, I came out with the breakout in the pac-man on the Atari 2600, but it broke eventually.
Speaker 1: and you know I continued to play mad video games, you know, I was playing Nintendo at every one of my friends houses.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think the first time I saw an NES was at my cousin's house.
Speaker 1: It must have been between kindergarten and first grade maybe even at very very early in life.
Speaker 1: I went to My cousin's house and he had Nintendo and he played Super Mario Brothers 1 and I didn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't even really understand.
Speaker 1: We were getting into there, you know Yeah Cuz at first I play.
Speaker 0: I remember I played Mario 1 at my friend Joe Ogilvy's house and I had at that point an Atari 7800 which I was convinced with the pinnacle of fucking gaming.
Speaker 0: that thing was fantastic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I I usually I still have my Atari and all my games and you know what to this day I enjoy my Atari and NES games more than I enjoy most other games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: But I remember I was went over and I watched him play Super Mario Brothers 1 and he beat world 1. right and you know There's that cutscene where Mario goes underground.
Speaker 0: I got pissed cuz he.
Speaker 0: every time I watched him play He'd always walk into the side pipe and I always said why don't you go in the top pipe?
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Is it different?
Speaker 0: and he would just look at me with his look of God.
Speaker 1: Yeah I used to think that kind of stuff too.
Speaker 0: Yep, or I actually cuz they got.
Speaker 0: we had the Nintendo.
Speaker 0: we eventually got it.
Speaker 0: I remember when I put the day my parents bought the Nintendo.
Speaker 0: we went to Pizza Hut and They had one of those Nintendo coin ops.
Speaker 0: It was basically an NES and you could play like Mario Brothers on it.
Speaker 0: and it was in the Pizza Hut and My dad was like dad.
Speaker 0: I want to play.
Speaker 0: give me a quarter.
Speaker 1: It's always seem to have those instead.
Speaker 1: of.
Speaker 1: you know Real arcade games.
Speaker 1: remember our Pizza Hut had like a Sega Genesis you would put a quarter in to play Altered Beast.
Speaker 0: My Pizza Hut also had operation wolf.
Speaker 1: Whoa, it was great.
Speaker 0: It was a good game, but then my dad looks at me and says no You can't play it now cuz we're gonna go buy one after this.
Speaker 0: my reaction was I Was I was dumbfounded that I would now be able to play that game Anytime I wanted.
Speaker 0: I only played.
Speaker 0: I didn't get another Nintendo game for like a month.
Speaker 0: I was happy playing Mario 1 and duck hunt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, but I had a lot of Nintendo experience at my friends houses my cousin's house.
Speaker 1: I remember these two guys.
Speaker 1: I forget who they were.
Speaker 1: They were just some friends that I guess we stopped talking to at some point.
Speaker 1: who what they had robbed the robot.
Speaker 1: they were so old-school and I would put like Donkey Kong and spy hunter at their house and Zelda 1. and I Played a whole lot of Nintendo at a whole lot of places except my house.
Speaker 1: until one day I did get a Nintendo like around like 87 and he I don't know Megaman 2 was out at the time so that that'll give you a good estimate.
Speaker 1: One of the first Nintendo and my Nintendo came with a red light gun.
Speaker 0: so did mine.
Speaker 0: Okay, but my friend Joe Ogilvy had the gray one, but it was broken.
Speaker 0: So then he bought a red one.
Speaker 1: our Nintendo had the red light gun and I got mega.
Speaker 1: basically was on my birthday I remember because I got the Nintendo the day before my birthday and I played Mario 1 and duck hunt and the next day I got Megaman 2.
Speaker 0: the first game I got for the Nintendo aside from the games It came with were the power pad and the two games that were out for it at the time.
Speaker 0: Well, two of the three games that were out.
Speaker 1: Oh, see I got a Nintendo way before the power pad came out.
Speaker 0: You know, I didn't get games for it for a long time because the Nintendo was expensive.
Speaker 0: So I had to contend myself with Mario 1 and duck hunt.
Speaker 1: I see we we didn't get a lot of games total But we got games at sort of a steady rate of like one or two every six months.
Speaker 1: See what we did is like birthdays.
Speaker 1: We got games and then the holidays you got rented a lot of games.
Speaker 0: Pretty much every week we would go and rent like two Nintendo games.
Speaker 1: Well, see we did some renting.
Speaker 1: I remember renting fix an ado and I remember renting a few other games.
Speaker 1: and we did a lot of borrowing and trading with the Friends, it's something a lot of people don't do nowadays because you know, there are other ways to do to do that.
Speaker 0: The front row crew does extensively.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Yeah, but I'm saying like in those days the trading was heavy and much more coveted.
Speaker 0: Remember the trade with.
Speaker 0: hide lied that I pulled off.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right, there's this kid.
Speaker 0: I think his name was Dave.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: He was basically chunk from the goonies.
Speaker 0: You know truffle shuffle Do the shuffle shuffle and Kid was annoying as all fuck, but we've hung out with him cuz we're kids.
Speaker 0: No, he's kind of hung out with all the kids in your neighborhood.
Speaker 0: I mean like.
Speaker 0: he would always come with like if we all had a squirt gun war he'd come with like the weird squirt gun.
Speaker 0: We'd have another war and he'd come with like the weird nerf gun that no one else owned but independent that he was just a weird annoying kid, but one day comes to my house and he's like, ah Trade you Mega Man 3 for your copy of hide lied and I said, yes.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes here Good fucking god hide lied.
Speaker 0: suck Mega Man 3 and I played the living hell out of that until two days later when this other kid Eric who was kind of a Bully in the area, but he came to my door and it's real polite, but he basically said Yeah, so Dave took my copy of Mega Man 3 and he said he traded it to you.
Speaker 0: I want it back.
Speaker 0: Here's your shitty ass.
Speaker 0: Hide lied.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I said I don't want to give it back But I can't do that to you.
Speaker 0: and I gave it back.
Speaker 0: And then I bought Mega Man 3 for $5 at garage sale.
Speaker 0: Not three days later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Mega Man 3 3 it was my favorite Mega Man.
Speaker 1: No Mega Man a lot of people argue between Mega Man 3 and 2.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll put it this way Mega Man 3 was my favorite Mega Man.
Speaker 0: Mega Man 2 was the best mega.
Speaker 1: Mega Man 3 was pretty much like the last Mega Man.
Speaker 1: That was still a good Mega Man.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I mean after that It's pretty much been downhill.
Speaker 1: I mean Mega Man x1 was okay, but you know, I like the rest of them there.
Speaker 1: I'll play them but I recognize that pretty much.
Speaker 1: Mega Man 2 Mega Man 3 and Mega Man x1 are the ones that are worth playing and everything else is Kind of now.
Speaker 0: the thing with my family was that my I mean my grandparents my parents my aunt and uncle.
Speaker 0: Everyone was really like.
Speaker 0: everyone played video games in my whole family.
Speaker 0: So Whenever we got a new video game system like when we had the Atari 7800 the Atari 2600 was plugged into another TV so two people could play at the same time and often times I would come home and the Nintendo was in one room and then Atari was another room and the other Atari's the Other room and I would often decide to play the Atari instead of the Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when we had the Sega Genesis, I was still break out the Nintendo for some good old-school action Even though it wasn't old-school at that point because I mean the Nintendo lived on well through the 16 era.
Speaker 0: the Nintendo lived on Pretty much until the end of the Super Nintendo era.
Speaker 1: Yeah pretty good.
Speaker 0: I mean it got the.
Speaker 0: the main Stint of gaming in my house well console gaming was that we had the Super Nintendo in my little brother's room and the Nintendo in my room and the Atari's in the living room and Often times I would be in my room trying to go to sleep but my brother would.
Speaker 0: it would be like 11 o'clock at night or midnight and he wanted to play Final Fantasy and he wouldn't stop.
Speaker 0: or Vice versa, I'd be in his room playing Final Fantasy 4 and wouldn't stop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just Nintendo just wouldn't die.
Speaker 1: I mean every kid had one.
Speaker 1: It was the one thing that everybody had.
Speaker 1: Everyone had Nintendo games.
Speaker 1: if you went to someone's house you played Nintendo Nintendo Nintendo Nintendo NES NES NES, I mean the Nintendo played such a prominent role in my early life.
Speaker 1: It was like the focus of my childhood.
Speaker 1: without it.
Speaker 1: My life would not be the same.
Speaker 0: I mean, I remember when I beat Oh God when I beat a game I would call my friends They would come over immediately to see the ending whatever game I just beat.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah beating a game was a big deal in those Days, I remember specifically beating Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: I was sitting there, you know with some friends In my bedroom and I had Zelda 1 going and I'd gotten to Ganon and like on the third try I beat him and everyone was like, whoa Yeah, my little brother my silver fucking arrows would.
Speaker 0: some Common thing we would do is we'd sit down and be like you want to beat guerrilla war you want to beat Contra?
Speaker 0: And we'd sit down and we beat the game and then we'd watch the end Because guerrilla war had a really funny end.
Speaker 1: I also remember beating Megaman 2 like in the living room I was sitting on the floor.
Speaker 1: It was like a Saturday morning and it was the cartoons weren't on yet And I think it was in those days when x-men the cartoon was on so I had to beat it before the x-men cartoon Cuz.
Speaker 1: I hadn't missed a single episode And I got to the crazy alien and I heard from my friend to use the bubble on him and I got it and I was Like yes, yes, and I did that without Passwords or anything.
Speaker 1: I freakin beat the whole game on my own.
Speaker 1: Like yeah straight through the day.
Speaker 0: as a little kid with no cheating or anything I remember very specifically the day I beat Final Fantasy 1 because I I was afraid of chaos because I had that Nintendo Power strategy guide.
Speaker 1: We got I was scared to the last level in Zelda, but I did it anyway.
Speaker 0: but I was so afraid of chaos that my brother and I were playing the game together and we had decided we had Tried a bunch of parties and we ended up on fighter fighter white mage black mage Which was probably the second best party you could have Other than fighter fighter red mage white mage, but I digress
Speaker 1: fighter black belt black mage white man.
Speaker 1: Yes The black belt puns you.
Speaker 0: there was a time in my life when quite literally you could say a chess Location in that game and I could tell you with reasonable accuracy.
Speaker 0: What was in it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the moat like with my brother and I were like I. always we tell each other like if you make it to chaos I don't care if you.
Speaker 0: if it's one hit point use every potion you've got before you fight him.
Speaker 0: and we were like psyched up and one day I was walking through and fighting and fighting and fighting and I got to chaos and I saw him there and I was like what and spoiler right now.
Speaker 0: It was garland What what what what.
Speaker 0: and I clicked on him.
Speaker 0: and you know when you beat Final Fantasy 1 you get three screens of text And then that's it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I remember reading those screens of text and not understanding what was going on anyway, and then I beat the game and I just started yelling and yelling and yelling.
Speaker 0: and my little brother comes home from school and he's and I'm still yelling.
Speaker 0: He's like, what are you yelling about?
Speaker 0: And like I beat Final Fantasy 1 and he's like what.
Speaker 0: no It was like the worst thing that ever happened to him Is a pretty terrible thing I Think.
Speaker 1: I remember the game.
Speaker 1: I actually remember playing a whole hell of a lot.
Speaker 1: was a Mario - oh god I love Mario.
Speaker 1: - I remember like I borrowed it from someone for a long period of time because it was the borrowed game.
Speaker 1: I played it so much because it was the borrowed game.
Speaker 0: Yep, like when I rented a game I played the ever-living fuck out of that game until I went back.
Speaker 1: Yes, I was basically coming home and playing Mario - every day immediately and I would you know Frickin bomb that mouse here and you couldn't save.
Speaker 1: so I was playing those early levels thousands of time.
Speaker 0: Yep In fact, I remember very distinctly and now that I'm talking about it I can feel it that sense of awe you would have when you're playing.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know if I can get that anymore from games but when I can't when I would play like like Mario - and Just the awe of wondering like I wonder if I can get on that ledge.
Speaker 0: I wonder if did anything over there.
Speaker 0: I wonder if there's anything behind that waterfall.
Speaker 0: I'm in a level.
Speaker 0: I've never been in before.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: That's a monster I've never seen before.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That was the good stuff in those days.
Speaker 0: I can't describe the feeling but like Zelda - when I took the raft for the first time to the other half of the game Yeah, it was like whoa.
Speaker 1: This is a weird place.
Speaker 1: I still get it a little bit, but it's not the same.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I know what's coming and even if I play new games now I don't get it.
Speaker 0: cuz.
Speaker 0: now I know a lot about games and games.
Speaker 1: See what I mostly get is the anticipation of the feeling but not the feeling itself.
Speaker 1: and then afterwards I get sort of this Disappointment like oh, it's over where to go.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean, I remember plus the patience I use I would literally burn Every bush on a screen in Zelda and it wouldn't bother me.
Speaker 1: I'd be like we burning bushes.
Speaker 0: Yep, because there was a chance I'd find somewhere Castlevania.
Speaker 0: I'd walk around throwing holy water in Castlevania 2 and every goddamn brick and I remember one.
Speaker 0: one day I discovered that if I had the claw equipped I could break through bricks and I found a scroll and the scroll said something Creepy about Dracula and it scared me.
Speaker 0: and I had a nightmare about Dracula that night Because Castlevania 2 scared me more than any game.
Speaker 0: I've ever played as a human being.
Speaker 1: All right, so so enough with Nintendo.
Speaker 1: we were mad Nintendo fiends.
Speaker 0: The thing is I was an equally mad Atari fiend and right up through see I was an Atari fiend playing pac-man Combat Scott and More Atari games that I've owned.
Speaker 0: I mean I we had like 70 Atari games like 40 Nintendo games about 20 Super Nintendo games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had maybe 30 to 40 Nintendo games and then We had like maybe 10 Atari games, but the Atari broke pretty early on so
Speaker 0: it was you never got to play these 7800 games like pole position -
Speaker 1: no, I played a lot of arcade games though I would go to arcades.
Speaker 1: often, you know, like all the time I'd be going to arcades.
Speaker 1: every family vacation we ever went on was basically go somewhere touristy and go to the arcades.
Speaker 0: Yep I remember Cedar Point used to have.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's still there cuz I mean we twice my family went to New Hampshire to Lake Winnipesaukee where there was fun spot the biggest Arcade in the country.
Speaker 1: and we just go to fun spot every night and get like a big fucking cup full of tokens And go Ching Ching Ching Ching.
Speaker 0: well Cedar Point and if they still have it I gotta find out had when I used to go this
Speaker 1: huge
Speaker 0: retro arcade filled with like arcade games going back to like barely electronic games Like the oldest of old pinball and the oldest of old like shooting gallery and the oldest of old Crapple like the Star Wars game.
Speaker 1: Yeah fun spots got that.
Speaker 1: Yeah another place We always went was I think we went there twice with Sesame Place in Pennsylvania Which is the Sesame Street amusement park, which not only has awesome cargo nets of awesome But it also has this giant arcade of awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess the moral of all this is just that.
Speaker 0: I mean we've been into anime.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much I mean I've been an anime since I was in fourth grade and I've been into Dungeons & Dragons since I was in about.
Speaker 0: you know, I don't know I think it was fifth grade maybe late fourth grade.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the video games since before I was sentience.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I don't spend a lot of time playing video games now and they're not like my main focus.
Speaker 1: I'm like, I'm not constantly looking at the video games But it's because they I've been in them so long like since I was zero I've been video gaming.
Speaker 1: You know that it's just constantly there looming over.
Speaker 0: I mean I would play break when I was like.
Speaker 0: I have memories.
Speaker 0: I must have been like three or four.
Speaker 0: I was so young because I remember when my brother was born and I remember times around that time when I would sit there playing kaboom with my dad.
Speaker 0: Mmm video games are such a big part of my life in terms of how it shaped me as a human being even though like Scott said I don't play him so much anymore.
Speaker 0: I just don't have time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it.
Speaker 1: you can kind of tell like it shows up in other areas Like I'll see like.
Speaker 1: right now I do spend quite a bit more time You know reading mangas and watching animes than playing video games.
Speaker 1: But if I'll go to a convention and there'll be a piece of Merchandise and like an anime I like I'd be like ooh, but then if I see a Mario it's like a Mario.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I mean when I was playing the Castlevania DS, right?
Speaker 0: there's one section where it plays like original Castlevania.
Speaker 0: music and the graphics are all original Castlevania.
Speaker 0: and The moment I walked into that area and I heard that music start I felt this fluttering in my chest of like the deepest nostalgia One can experience like it was on par with the nostalgia I feel like if I go back to Detroit and see my old house or Like when I meet a friend I knew in like elementary school.
Speaker 1: So basically We were crack babies.
Speaker 1: only the crack was Nintendo and Atari.
Speaker 0: and as my final bit I would like to say there is a game for the Atari 2600 called kaboom KABOOM.
Speaker 1: Now I like.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised you haven't said anything about bionic commando.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, oh bionic commando is probably my favorite game ever man - please.
Speaker 0: but kaboom is a game that has such importance to me because I You know Tommy, you know from the who yeah pinball wizard Yeah, when I sit down in front of a game of kaboom.
Speaker 0: I am Tommy at that game.
Speaker 0: I Can play that game to fucking death.
Speaker 0: It's it's scary.
Speaker 1: I don't even think about it because I've been playing this game since literally They really need to make a version of kaboom Where one guy's the mad bomber and one guy's the buckets since I mean before I was sentient.
Speaker 0: I played kaboom.
Speaker 0: I've been playing this game my entire life and When we were at our IT, I was telling everyone about this game and and they were all like, yeah Whatever you were right as a kid blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: game can't be that hard.
Speaker 0: So I pulled out the Atari and I plugged it in and I turned it on and I plugged in the.
Speaker 0: I have two sets Of the analog controllers because this game is analog.
Speaker 0: all the only control you have is one button and an analog twisty.
Speaker 0: It's a paddle and the first set of paddles.
Speaker 0: because of the room we were in there was too much electromagnetic interference.
Speaker 0: the thing would jump all over.
Speaker 0: the screen said to plug in the second set and Scott sat down and let him play it and he died almost immediately.
Speaker 0: Greg and Alex and everyone just died.
Speaker 0: and then I sat down in front of it having not played the game for almost three years and I racked up like 2,000 points in a game where a hundred points is a big deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's pretty good at kaboom.
Speaker 0: This game is probably the game.
Speaker 0: I'm better at than any game ever.
Speaker 0: I love it And if I ever meet any of you in a situation where I'll have my Atari and we can play kaboom I will give a cash prize to anyone who can beat me at that game.
Speaker 1: All right, just to summarize the rest of my video game career NES.
Speaker 1: then I had a Genesis and I played SNES at all my friends houses so it evened out, you know, everyone would get the system that the other people didn't have and get the games the other people didn't have.
Speaker 1: and then after that I Started doing the PC gaming thing while my brother had an N64, but I still played a bunch of N64 stuff.
Speaker 1: I didn't really play so much PlayStation 1 stuff and PlayStation 2 stuff and I got to college.
Speaker 1: I did PC gaming PC gaming PC gaming GameCube GameCube and You know We did Gameboy stuff also, but I didn't get the Gameboy until like the Gameboy color right now.
Speaker 1: My brother actually got the Gameboy pocket right now.
Speaker 0: It seems to be DS for us most.
Speaker 1: right now It's DS and soon it's gonna be we.
Speaker 1: the PC faded out when we started using Linux basically.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, I still do saw my PC gaming is pretty much steam steam steam steam.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll do the same little summary Scott did before we end this, you know Atari's and the Intellivisions and Nintendo and the Super Nintendo and I played the Nintendo and Super Nintendo All the way through until the very end of that era.
Speaker 0: I mean we got a Super Nintendo right when it came out and like every launch game and pretty much when the Super Nintendo died, I moved into PC gaming and I Completely abandoned console gaming from that point until the GameCube.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no PlayStation No in 64, I had no interest at all.
Speaker 0: I was a 100% PC gamer other than the fact that I continued to play my Nintendo and Super Nintendo and Continuously through that entire era until the GameCube.
Speaker 1: Yeah from the end of the 16-bit era to the GameCube I was strictly a PC gamer except the Gameboy and then the Gameboy Advance sort of lived on in the background.
Speaker 1: You know always, you know all the way up through now the DS, you know, it's like it's like a separate track almost.
Speaker 1: It's just always there.
Speaker 0: See actually in terms of portable gaming I wasn't really in on that boat too much until I got a Game Gear and My brother got a Game Boy and we traded him back and forth a lot and I really wasn't big on the Game Boy.
Speaker 0: I like the Game Gear a lot more except that it eventually died because there weren't enough games for it.
Speaker 1: They're all crap.
Speaker 0: And then I got a Game Boy Advance really late.
Speaker 0: My mom bought it for me at one point and then I got hooked on Advance Wars and now I have a DS and the DS is my primary gaming console.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I mean my basically like the Game Boy was something I would play at my one friend's house who had an old-school Game Boy and you know
Speaker 0: While
Speaker 1: it was cool I didn't really want one that badly because what you know the games I was playing were like Kirby's pinball which was only exciting because I played it rarely at this one kid's house.
Speaker 1: or What was the other game?
Speaker 1: Freaking Oh Solomon's Key, which is that puzzle game?
Speaker 1: That was impossibly hard and I knew that if I had it for myself, I would I would just kill myself Games like that.
Speaker 1: So I didn't really want a Game Boy, but I like playing at my friend's house.
Speaker 1: but then when Pokemon came out, my brother got a Game Boy Pocket and Pokemon and I was kind of like Whatever.
Speaker 1: That's a kitty looking Pokemon thing.
Speaker 1: And then I said, oh, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: That's worth playing.
Speaker 1: So I got the Game Boy Color and Pokemon.
Speaker 1: when the Game Boy Color came out I got it.
Speaker 1: then when the Game Boy Advance came out I got it right away.
Speaker 1: And then when the DS came out got it right away.
Speaker 0: Yep, Scott and I bought DS's the day they came out and and multiple games for them.
Speaker 1: So for the past three, you know game, you know, Nintendo portable systems.
Speaker 1: I've gotten them pretty much at launch.
Speaker 1: I never got the SP's or you know, the anything like that.
Speaker 1: I just got the Game Boy Color their original advance and the old original DS.
Speaker 0: I skipped all.
Speaker 0: I went from Game Boy and Game Gear to GBA and then DS never had a Game Boy Pocket, Game Boy Color.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got in the game late and stayed in the game.
Speaker 1: You know until today you got in the game early dropped out and came back in.
Speaker 1: Yep But other than that, I think that's it.
Speaker 0: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.