Speaker 0: It's Wednesday July 26th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We give you an overview of all that is slayers that classic fantasy comedy franchise.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: If I sound slightly weird today It's because the novocaine from when I went to the dentist earlier hasn't quite worn off and part of my mouth feels kind of weird.
Speaker 1: So who had zero cavities when they went to the dentist?
Speaker 0: actually Scott the thing is my cavity Grim.
Speaker 0: the funny thing is this this cavity.
Speaker 0: I basically for the last like six or seven years every dentist I've had has always said I want to keep an eye on this one tooth.
Speaker 0: it looks like it's gonna get a cavity soon, but they kept saying that and it never got a cavity.
Speaker 0: and Finally my latest dentist I went in and he said the same thing and I said you're sure it's not a cavity.
Speaker 0: He said it's real close.
Speaker 0: It's hard to tell.
Speaker 0: and I said, you know what just fill it in.
Speaker 0: So he filled it in.
Speaker 1: You see I've had two different.
Speaker 1: I've noticed two different ways that dentist can tell if it's a cavity or not.
Speaker 0: the first he did the x-ray because he couldn't tell From looking at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's the x-ray which is the easiest way.
Speaker 1: You just freakin look which is almost the same as looking at it.
Speaker 1: but yeah the the other way is they have this little sonar device that they can use and they hope they put it on your tooth and They push a button and a number shows up on this little LCD screen.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: I've never seen anything like that.
Speaker 1: They used it on me once and if it beeps and the number goes over a certain I guess I don't know what the limit is like 70 or 80.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: then it's a cavity that needs filling.
Speaker 0: I remember when I was a kid the way the dentist seemed to do it was he'd scrape metal over my teeth and anytime it Stuck somewhere.
Speaker 0: He'd examine that area more closely and look for a cavity.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, but the thing was I had my teeth sealed.
Speaker 0: we talked about this in the dentistry episode.
Speaker 0: I got sealants back there.
Speaker 0: The cavity is right at the edge of the sealant and it looks like because the sealant so old that it had retracted.
Speaker 0: So there was a hole there And there's no way you can brush a hole in your tooth.
Speaker 1: I see you have an excuse.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Brush.
Speaker 1: Yeah brush a lot.
Speaker 0: However, however, I don't have an excuse for like the other four cavities.
Speaker 0: I got like nine years ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I still have only had two and the first one was when I was 21.
Speaker 0: So I've got a grand total of Seven But two of those are technically sealants.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I have two other Leading bits that I would like to talk about because today wasn't a very interesting day.
Speaker 0: We made BLT's for dinner and they were awesome, but mmm inexplicably Somehow despite the fact that Scott and I probably eat more bread in our household than any other household near us You know, it's the bottom of the food pyramid.
Speaker 1: You're supposed to eat more bread than anything else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but what about Atkins?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's bullshit.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, so I now make lunches at work because there's a fridge and I wanted to save some money and also because the food near my work is A lot more expensive than the food near IBM used to be.
Speaker 0: so I took my loaf of bread from home to work.
Speaker 0: Scott also took his loaf of bread from home to work and when we went to make BLT's we had no Bread no B.
Speaker 1: It was just gonna be an LT.
Speaker 0: Well, the B stands for bacon.
Speaker 0: All right You know, you know what?
Speaker 0: I'd make plenty of bacon I'd make fun of you But I was about to say the exact same thing and the only reason I didn't say it?
Speaker 0: because you said it first and my brain Figured out what was wrong with that statement before?
Speaker 1: so so we were gonna make some BB LT's and Well, well a to be BLT.
Speaker 0: So I lost our to be.
Speaker 0: I made a bblc instead with some cucumber because we didn't have any tomato.
Speaker 1: Either I had one piece of tomato on each because you stole it from the salad.
Speaker 0: I made.
Speaker 1: that's right and the tomatoes on the plant on the back porch aren't ready yet.
Speaker 0: So I ran to the local key food to get some bread.
Speaker 0: now I don't want to rip on mom-and-pop chains or anything.
Speaker 1: So key food isn't a mom-and-pop chain.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I didn't realize that until I saw one in New York City.
Speaker 0: I didn't know it was a chain.
Speaker 0: But people who visited us asked us why we don't go to the local grocery store and why we drive You know 15 minutes away to bigger grocery stores.
Speaker 1: key food sucks.
Speaker 0: Every time we've gone there something horrible has happened.
Speaker 0: I mean the first time we ever went to this key food.
Speaker 0: They didn't have a price on something that I wanted to buy and then they didn't know what to do.
Speaker 0: So they were like, well, we can't sell it to you even though you know It was out in a display and it was a thing I needed to barbecue and I was only buying stuff to barbecue.
Speaker 0: So I basically said well if you can't sell me that I don't need any of this stuff.
Speaker 0: And they got really mad and they just they couldn't deal with this situation.
Speaker 0: They could have named a price.
Speaker 0: I probably just paid it.
Speaker 0: then we went a couple weeks later and Someone in the parking lot rammed a shopping cart into Scott's old car like straight up and they yeah, I remember no They backed up and they jammed a parking shopping cart into the back of your car.
Speaker 0: And then we talked about how much we hated the key food.
Speaker 1: I Remember that particular incident, but okay, you really don't remember that.
Speaker 0: No, it scratched the hell up out of your bag bumper and everything that remember.
Speaker 0: you bitched about it for like a day did?
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Yes, you did.
Speaker 1: I think you're making it up.
Speaker 0: No, I'm really not doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: That was an old shit guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: it was the old tempo Anyway, and food sucks every time.
Speaker 1: I didn't even have all the different like grocery products that we need.
Speaker 0: so today I go there to buy bread and I see oh I'll buy some Kaiser rolls and they're in these bags.
Speaker 0: and I look and the bag is buzzing and Look and there's a fly in it.
Speaker 0: and then I look closer and there's a million baby flies in it, too.
Speaker 0: And I know there's probably maggots in there as well.
Speaker 0: And I I just stared at it in disbelief Went and found some bread that there's no way the key food could have tainted Bought it and I'm never going back to that place.
Speaker 1: No matter what bread from a commercial bakery.
Speaker 0: Yes I am never going back to that grocery store.
Speaker 1: Good God Uh Key food.
Speaker 1: and in Queens, New York key food is like the grocery store.
Speaker 1: There isn't any other choice.
Speaker 0: Really, I drive past two key foods when I go between my office and Yonkers and one of the hospitals I work at in the Bronx.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like this supermarket, but it's not super.
Speaker 0: It's just a regular market Yeah, but it's not good.
Speaker 0: Like usually when I think of a market I think of like those small specialty markets that have higher prices But higher quality specialty goods.
Speaker 1: No, those are like the ultra small market.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's a small market.
Speaker 1: we go to a large market.
Speaker 1: this is just a market.
Speaker 0: but I got another quick story today.
Speaker 0: You know all these balloons.
Speaker 0: So as you all know I work in hospitals and today I had to go to a neurological intensive care unit which was one Exactly the way you see these sorts of things in movies.
Speaker 0: It was really kind of cool to be in there though.
Speaker 1: Hey weren't there?
Speaker 1: isn't that where they put brain-dead people and all sorts of things?
Speaker 0: It was people who had a lot like head injuries and all sorts of stuffs and final injuries.
Speaker 0: I felt bad because at one time I wanted to be professional because this is.
Speaker 0: I'm sent here to meet with these very well-known Very skilled doctors like this.
Speaker 0: nobody knows like these doctors are.
Speaker 0: I guess they're not famous But within the community of the specific things they do they're fairly well known for their research and they're really knowledgeable really smart dudes.
Speaker 0: They're also really a lot older than me and Even though I'm a technology Professional like this is my job and I do this sort of thing all the time.
Speaker 0: When I walked into this room and I was standing around there's all these Doctors who save lives every day and they all introduce themselves like hi.
Speaker 0: I am doctor blah blah blah blah PhD.
Speaker 0: Hi, I'm doctor blah blah blah specialist and blah and I'm like, hey, I'm the computer guy And you know what.
Speaker 1: you might not know anything about neurological whatnot, but I'm sure they don't know jack about computers.
Speaker 0: no, they don't but you know what I. It's weird, but I don't begrudge them not knowing about computers at all because they know that they're so smart.
Speaker 1: They should just be able to figure out the basics of compute.
Speaker 1: You know, like.
Speaker 1: they don't have to be experts like we are but they have to know more than the average person just by their Shear, you know Minimal level of intelligence.
Speaker 0: It seems that they from what I gather.
Speaker 0: I don't think they even have time to use computers.
Speaker 1: Wow, the how do they do doctoring?
Speaker 0: because they do the doctoring and other people take care of all the paperwork.
Speaker 0: But there they were really smart dudes and it was just weird to be in this in this place Which is a foreign and somewhat frightening sad place full of very injured people Talking to a bunch of extremely highly paid extremely well-educated intelligent men, and I'm just the computer, dude I'm dressed in like a silk black shirt and I got my little locus klein pin and they're all in Business suits with lab coats over them and it was fun
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: What did they say?
Speaker 0: a bunch of stuff that no one cares about?
Speaker 0: I'd have to tell you the details of my job, which is actually not that interesting and probably very tedious.
Speaker 1: Did they say anything doctory?
Speaker 0: Actually before they started the thing talking to me.
Speaker 0: They were in the middle of a conversation and I Barely unders like now I know how a lot of our friends who aren't so technological as us feel When they're sitting in the room.
Speaker 0: well like me and Scott and Alex and James are talking about this stuff because I was standing there politely waiting for them to be finished and I understood all of the individual words they said but combined they meant almost nothing to me.
Speaker 0: Haha.
Speaker 1: It's another.
Speaker 0: it's like Okay, yeah, I'm done with that.
Speaker 0: That story doesn't actually go anywhere.
Speaker 0: I just thought it was interesting.
Speaker 1: You know what I got today.
Speaker 1: I did more work today than I've done any day in the past many months.
Speaker 0: You know what going to that meeting was the only work.
Speaker 0: I really did today Because all the work I've got to do was canceled or delayed or something.
Speaker 0: I got nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just wow All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you got some anime news, I believe All right, the Fullmetal Alchemist movie which the verdict is sort of out on whether it's actually worth watching or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we haven't seen it yet So we can't make an opinion, but I have not heard anyone say anything positive about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you think like with some anime movies.
Speaker 1: Everyone's all excited about it.
Speaker 1: You know the heat talking about it and I was.
Speaker 1: I was really before the movie came out people were saying ooh a Fullmetal Alchemist movie but it was emphasis on the Fullmetal Alchemist like hooray Fullmetal Alchemist.
Speaker 1: we like that a lot and There wasn't so much, you know after the movie came out people going.
Speaker 1: Oh, you got to see this movie.
Speaker 1: It's so great It just kind of people stop talking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone who saw it basically told us The point is is that Funimation Films is putting it out in movie theaters in the US.
Speaker 1: We don't know what theaters but we do know that the show times are Friday August 25th at 930 at night Saturday August 26 at 2 p.m.
Speaker 1: And Saturday August 26 at 930 p.m There's gonna be basically three showings.
Speaker 1: Hopefully there's a theater near you.
Speaker 1: if you want to go see it.
Speaker 0: Well, hopefully it'll be in New York City cuz I'll probably head down there and see it.
Speaker 1: Maybe it depends how much it is.
Speaker 0: It's New York City.
Speaker 0: It'll be like 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: Like every movie is.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's worth 15 bucks.
Speaker 1: 15 bucks I could buy the damn DVD.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it is.
Speaker 0: I mean apple seed was really worth seeing in the theater.
Speaker 0: I mean that was really cool and ghost in the shell innocence was Absolutely worth seeing in the theater.
Speaker 0: That movie was just a spectacle of animation.
Speaker 0: I don't know about the FMA movie in terms.
Speaker 0: I mean it doesn't.
Speaker 0: it's not like FMA was particularly pretty or well drawn.
Speaker 0: It was actually very generic in the way it was drawn.
Speaker 1: Well, the the trailer for the movie makes it look a lot better.
Speaker 0: true It does.
Speaker 1: the movie was a much higher production value.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: The new Funimation trailer is kind of like Yeah, like trailers I'd seen before made me more excited and then that trailer made me less excited.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, once we see the movie we'll review it.
Speaker 0: we've had it on our computer for a long time But we never actually watched it.
Speaker 0: and then we finally said alright tonight's the night We're going to watch it and then we learned that the subtitle track was broken and then I fixed it But it was then and watched it since then.
Speaker 0: Yeah We like we the the spark of let's watch it came and then we failed at watching it and then the spark died and I don't Think it's coming back.
Speaker 0: But anyway instead of a second news now you'll all groan.
Speaker 0: I have a geek back and the verdict seems to be that most of you don't like the geek back so much.
Speaker 0: or you want him at the end of the Show or something or you want him if it doesn't.
Speaker 0: take away from the news, but one.
Speaker 0: There wasn't so much anime news that we would talk about.
Speaker 0: interestingly - there wasn't enough news in the real world that we're ready to talk about.
Speaker 0: yet today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are some big news is but I think they're gonna wait till tomorrow and next Monday.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz I guess I've gotten to the point where I kind of want to save news that are worthwhile and Especially until everyone out there who listens knows something about it or at least has heard of it.
Speaker 0: that way We don't have to spend so much time explaining what the news is and we can spend more time talking about the ramifications And or arguing with each other.
Speaker 0: But before I do this geek back, I'd like to say that we may have gotten our first hate mail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone did send us something that is kind of like a hate mail But it it's weird because one he accused us of being homosexuals awesome And - he makes some pretty.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't want to say valid but definitely Understandable criticisms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I I replied and started a little conversation.
Speaker 1: Just to you know, add some meat to the email and we'll get to it tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yes, we will but suffice to say It's gonna be fun Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's actually a hate mail or not.
Speaker 0: I'm still not absolutely sure if he's kidding or what but he did say that it was more of an Irritation mail.
Speaker 1: like a hate mail is usually when someone hates you this guy is sort of Irritated with us, but he still is a fan of our show.
Speaker 0: So yeah, well, he didn't actually sign his email either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he did what like an uppercase I or a lowercase L.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's his is like screen name or whatever.
Speaker 0: That's not a screen name.
Speaker 0: one character is not a screen name.
Speaker 1: Well, you can see it in his email address.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but still okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this is an old geek back We got a while ago and it's also kind of a news because anime Expo happened and we did weeks
Speaker 1: and weeks ago
Speaker 0: and we didn't really talk about it so much and we got a feedback from one of our listeners Colin who was actually there and He gave us pretty much his short rundown of what anime Expo was to him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, meanwhile comic-con just finished, you know, which is also on the west coast and we haven't talked about that really either.
Speaker 0: So we'll talk about that after Otakon.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like if a con is on the east coast we cover it the day after.
Speaker 1: if a con is on the west coast It gets delayed about like a month or two.
Speaker 1: Then we'll talk about it.
Speaker 1: those west coast conventions.
Speaker 1: They're crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I'm gonna skip over some of this but I'm really just gonna focus on the anime Expo stuff because we have a lot of opinions about anime Expo and This email is mostly a.
Speaker 1: we've never been to anime Expo.
Speaker 1: So we can't really yes say them.
Speaker 0: Our opinions are based mostly on hearsay.
Speaker 0: Yep, but this is a Very this is an email.
Speaker 0: that's right along our opinions.
Speaker 0: Hi Raymond Scott.
Speaker 0: I wanted to share my thoughts on anime Expo.
Speaker 0: Thanks for the heads up.
Speaker 0: as to the size of the con I've been to many sci-fi and comic-con starting in the late 70s.
Speaker 0: I must say that I concur with your comments as to the type of people who attend anime cons versus other cons.
Speaker 0: I Found the anime folks to be much more open and friendly.
Speaker 0: There are people playing ps2s and gameboys groups of people watching anime on portable DVD players.
Speaker 0: Others are playing card games and/or being much more outgoing than the average con goer in my genre.
Speaker 0: The people waiting in all the lines were very friendly and outgoing, too.
Speaker 0: Thanks Scott for telling me about the updated Japanese version of Gigantor Blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: skip a bit skip a bit.
Speaker 0: as for the con itself It was one of the worst run major cons I have ever been to comparable to the stories you told about comic-con in New York.
Speaker 0: I got there 30 minutes before opening and the entire parking lot parking area around Anaheim Convention Center was already full.
Speaker 0: They must have had many more people show up than they expected.
Speaker 0: They use chairs to mark the rows for ticket lines But they ran out of tape to roll off all the areas.
Speaker 0: There were no free goodie bags once you got your tickets.
Speaker 0: No program either.
Speaker 0: the freebie table wasn't even in a huge weight.
Speaker 1: There was no program.
Speaker 0: apparently He says there was no program either.
Speaker 0: They ran out or they didn't give anyone anything.
Speaker 1: Okay, I mean it's one thing cuz you know people have been saying that the goodie bags have been drying up But for no program.
Speaker 1: whoa?
Speaker 0: also the fact that it's anime Expo I mean kinetic on had a lot of really valid reasons for the anime Expo is supposedly the anime con of this hemisphere.
Speaker 0: Well, it's also well.
Speaker 0: I would say Otakon is but yeah.
Speaker 1: But well the thing is that anime expos more of a trade show and Otakon is more of a.
Speaker 0: but anime Expo has such Support from the industry.
Speaker 0: I can't believe that the industry would chaff them on that.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean can I got had good reasons.
Speaker 0: anime Expo is no excuse.
Speaker 1: Anime Expo is sort of like the e3 and Otakon is sort of like the packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I love packs.
Speaker 0: I want to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we love it.
Speaker 0: We haven't been to it right to keep going on this.
Speaker 0: the freebie table wasn't even in the huge hall where people checked in Out or bought their tickets.
Speaker 0: it was off in the corner somewhere And you actively had to search it out.
Speaker 0: the ACC is multiple stories high.
Speaker 0: Signs for the various events only said things like second floor third floor etc.
Speaker 1: They didn't.
Speaker 1: they didn't say what room quote.
Speaker 0: They didn't tell you the room number.
Speaker 0: you are you sure?
Speaker 0: you had to ask a staff member and some of them didn't know.
Speaker 0: There were other examples too, but you get the idea.
Speaker 0: He also made a whole bunch of copies of our flyer and spread them around.
Speaker 0: Thanks for that He.
Speaker 0: Everything else he says is just telling us cool stuff about us or other stuff that isn't related to the con.
Speaker 0: He was happy that we pronounce his name correctly, which mostly is because we had a friend named Colin.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, I know how to pronounce the name Colin.
Speaker 1: It's not howdy.
Speaker 1: How are you gonna pronounce it?
Speaker 0: He says here people pronounced it Colleen or Colin.
Speaker 1: Well, it could be Colin, but that's Colin Powell and and if it's Colin, it's a female and Colleen's usually Co le en Co le en.
Speaker 1: that could be a good one, too.
Speaker 1: See, that's another thing.
Speaker 1: I just remembered about Otacon.
Speaker 1: is they had that information desk?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the people there always know what's going on.
Speaker 1: They know everything at the information desk and I've used it at least once every year for some random thing Like even if it's just oh I shit.
Speaker 1: I forgot what room I'll just happen to be near the information desk.
Speaker 1: so I'll say hey what room is X in?
Speaker 1: and they'll be like room number number number number and It's a lot of conventions don't have an information desk like that, you know, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean, I'd like to go to anime Expo maybe once to confirm.
Speaker 0: but If any of you have been to anime Expo and had a positive experience Please let us know because I have never really heard good things about this convention at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like the good things you hear about the convention are always in the press releases.
Speaker 1: or yeah You never hear good stuff like people's you know excited about anime Expo that are fans.
Speaker 1: Like if you go to a fan forum, there isn't a lot of anime Expo excitement.
Speaker 0: In fact, the best I've seen is I've seen some people who would say they had a good time at it mostly in anime Expo forums.
Speaker 0: But mostly these are people who had never never been to Otacon and vice versa.
Speaker 1: So it's like we've never been to anime.
Speaker 0: So yes far away.
Speaker 0: It's possible that we just really underestimate that con and they just really underestimate our cons, but I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's a tough girl.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if everything he said in this email is true.
Speaker 0: That's really kind of sad because I mean I expect even small conventions to be better than that and they almost all are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Kinetic on even told you what rooms and they had a program.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean a program That's not perfect is better than no program.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just wondered did they run out of programs?
Speaker 0: Which means they didn't come make enough?
Speaker 0: or did they not have one which means they're having other problems?
Speaker 0: Or did they have them and screw up distributing them?
Speaker 0: So people who wanted them didn't get them.
Speaker 1: I have no idea But it's not good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if anyone has anything positive to say about anime Expo, please let us know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and maybe we'll go to it sometime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe you can use that audio link on the website to send us some audio.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got an owl of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah Did you say that specifically to bait me into saying?
Speaker 0: Maybe I see what you did there.
Speaker 1: So This is a. It seems like a Japanese TV show.
Speaker 1: Of course, it could be Korean.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I generally assume that anything like that is a Japanese TV show.
Speaker 1: It's got to be and there's an owl and he's sitting on a log and he's all like yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm an owl.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: what you gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: and this guy comes up with a little jack-in-the-box and the jack-in-the-box goes off and Then hilarity ensues and I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, watch this owl.
Speaker 0: I just I love watching birds react to things because they're smart and they react in Almost human-like ways in the way they look at.
Speaker 1: most birds are just kind of it but owls.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah something else.
Speaker 0: owls and parrots and smart bird.
Speaker 0: I mean, there are dumb birds starlings not so bright.
Speaker 1: It's all about the owls, baby.
Speaker 1: Yeah, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, really?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right now I this is something I found kind of randomly because I was actually looking for video of my old marching band because a couple of people had asked me about it and Actually all my friends in the van.
Speaker 0: I've been asked him around and no one has the videos anymore.
Speaker 0: So I'm trying to hunt down like some videos.
Speaker 0: But anyway, and I found this kind of randomly and it's basically a guy who plays a trumpet duet but it's just one guy and He does the old trick of hold two trumpets one in each hand on two parts of your lips and play a song on both Trumpets playing different notes on both of them.
Speaker 0: It's not that difficult to do but it's really difficult to do so.
Speaker 0: it sounds like anything other than crap And it's just really cool.
Speaker 0: Check it out.
Speaker 1: Oh You know, it's like those guys who play two guitars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like stuff like that.
Speaker 0: I really like watching people do cool things with instruments.
Speaker 1: you know, it really always bothers me like You know, how long has it been since someone's invented a new instrument, you know?
Speaker 0: Well, keep in mind that the vast majority of instruments that have been invented over the years have been ignored for good reason That that is absolutely true.
Speaker 1: But you know, you can't tell me or convince me that there isn't a useful instrument that hasn't yet been created.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well there I mean over the years have been a lot of things like trombones and trumpets and French horns have evolved considerably and Gotten better and better and better.
Speaker 0: Of course new instruments has appeared like the sousaphone Was a new instrument that Basically how new a Long time ago centuries John Philip Sousa days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hence sousaphone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so so it's not a new instrument.
Speaker 0: It's new.
Speaker 1: I think the newest instrument.
Speaker 1: That's Theremin is the theremin or perhaps the electronic keyboard the synthesizer.
Speaker 1: See, oh, you know, there's new synthesizers every day true Maybe that's why there's no new Instruments because people just make a new synthesizer to sound make a new sound if they come up with one and That we don't need an actual instrument for it anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there's already a million kinds of trumpets.
Speaker 0: I can't think of a different kind of trumpet.
Speaker 1: I would want to know a different mechanism like not a woodwind instrument not a brass instrument a new kind of instrument that works on A different principle.
Speaker 0: All right, so other than something vibrating at the end of a tube Yeah, okay How about hitting something?
Speaker 0: we got that covered?
Speaker 1: We've got the hitting we've got the string plucking We've got the the blowing into something.
Speaker 1: We need a. we need a fourth way to make music.
Speaker 0: Hmm, maybe we should read the fourth way.
Speaker 1: No because I'm gonna do with music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the moon might know.
Speaker 1: No, it's just gonna eat your soul Alright.
Speaker 0: now to the geek back.
Speaker 0: We got a while ago complaining about inside jokes.
Speaker 0: That was a fucking inside joke right there.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: Was that inside?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, uh, I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: today We're going to talk about Slayers.
Speaker 0: it kind of in general.
Speaker 1: we're not Slayer as in the band Not Slayer as in I'm going to slay you or don't forget people who ride sleighs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know arrow of slaying versus arrow of slaying right.
Speaker 1: so The Slayers that we're talking about are these slayers as in the anime mostly.
Speaker 1: the anime mostly but also the manga.
Speaker 0: We're not reviewing it so much because I've only seen the first layers and most of slayers.
Speaker 0: next God has only seen the first layers and a bunch of the OAVs and neither of us have read the manga at all.
Speaker 0: I bought a bunch of it, but I haven't even looked at it yet.
Speaker 1: I haven't read a single slayers manga.
Speaker 1: now Let's let's first talk about What slayers things exist.
Speaker 1: there are?
Speaker 1: two mangas, yep, there are.
Speaker 1: There is a prequel movie.
Speaker 1: there is another as a prequel OAV.
Speaker 1: There are one two three four sequel movies.
Speaker 1: There's the original slayers TV show 26 episodes is slayers next which is the second TV show also 26 and there is a third slayers TV show slayers try which is 24 episodes and then some crap.
Speaker 1: Yep, yep.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So slayers is about mostly this one girl Lena inverse.
Speaker 0: now She is a magic user.
Speaker 0: She is a high-level magic user in a world that is basically Dungeons & Dragons Made real this.
Speaker 1: this is exactly Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 1: I mean imagine who made slayers were D&D players and this was like one of their campaigns.
Speaker 0: like imagine a world where you're the world.
Speaker 0: it's just like D&D and people can just cast fireball and High level people just kick the living hell out of anyone who's lower level.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's big baddies and you fight them.
Speaker 1: Now there are two types of slayers shows and manga.
Speaker 1: They're the Lena inverse with Naga the serpent and there is Lena inverse with everyone else.
Speaker 0: now I greatly prefer the latter of the two.
Speaker 1: I greatly prefer the former.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see they're both good shows and they're both good.
Speaker 0: They're just there's a very different feeling.
Speaker 0: I mean the theoretically slayers with Naga Occurs way before she meets up with all these other people.
Speaker 1: Yes slayers with Naga is what you're gonna see in All the prequel movies and and like the OAVs most all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep, the actual TV shows you're not gonna see Naga the serpent.
Speaker 0: She's not there which is fine by me.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Naga the serpent let's talk about her first cuz it's simple to explain.
Speaker 1: All right now get the surface.
Speaker 1: That's Naga the serpent.
Speaker 1: she is Incredibly tall has gigantic boobs and black hair and she's a powerful sorceress.
Speaker 1: Yeah And see here's there's Lena inverse is short has small boobs and is an even more powerful Sorcer seems.
Speaker 0: the general differences between the Naga slayers and the everyone else layers is that the former tends to rely mostly on Boob jokes.
Speaker 0: My boobs are small OMG.
Speaker 0: And then they blow stuff up and make puns.
Speaker 0: Yep, the latter is more.
Speaker 0: We're hungry.
Speaker 0: Chaos ensues.
Speaker 1: we go to an inn we eat.
Speaker 1: the inn is blown up by a dragon.
Speaker 1: We go to another in to eat.
Speaker 1: It is blown up by a dragon.
Speaker 1: They cannot eat at an inn without it being blown up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, if you haven't figured it out, these shows are nothing but comedy.
Speaker 1: Slayers is perhaps the perennial Fantasy D&D adventuring comedy series of all anime and manga.
Speaker 0: I mean lotus war is looked to by many as the earliest really good fantasy Like high production value anime of the modern era.
Speaker 1: Yes slayers is hilarious lotus war.
Speaker 0: Yes It's fine.
Speaker 0: I find it funnier than lotus island and I really like lotus island.
Speaker 1: Oh, man Slayers just you know.
Speaker 1: lotus island is made to be cute.
Speaker 1: lotus war but slayers the whole thing.
Speaker 1: He's just meant to be as funny as possible.
Speaker 1: Even at the incredibly serious parts.
Speaker 0: Yes
Speaker 1: they make jokes that are just stupid like
Speaker 0: it gets to the point where the show like starts getting serious and then something stupid happens and They break the fourth wall all the time and they'll turn to you and be like, yeah There's no way they let the show get that serious.
Speaker 1: Haha Yeah, it'll be like they'll fighting the the super serious bad guy and this is a super serious awesome fight.
Speaker 1: music and you know They're gonna save the world or a bunch of people are gonna die.
Speaker 1: and then some guy would be like, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: Now the best part about slayers that they kind of mean every.
Speaker 0: a lot of things in slayers are very cliche but a lot of the cliches and slayers were not so cliched when they were done and they've become cliches more so since.
Speaker 0: and also there's one moment in the original season of slayers that to me just defines part of the awesome of the show where There's the big bad guy and he's about to do his big bad thing and the hero show up to stop him and he's like You cannot stop me and he sends a monster for them to fight.
Speaker 0: now in any typical fantasy Whatever the bad guy would stand there watching While the you know, the good guys fought his giant monster and then when they beat the giant monster There'd be some sort of epic final conflict.
Speaker 0: The bad guy as soon as he sticks the monster Immediately runs away locks the door does his evil ritual and completes it as fast as he can.
Speaker 0: Yep The show is just awesome.
Speaker 1: It's very awesome.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of other things that make it awesome.
Speaker 1: like rim is talking about some of the cliches You know how many animes have you seen where the cat the main care group of characters is always hungry and they you know?
Speaker 1: Once in a while they get money and food like samurai Champloo and kawaii boppin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all those slayers I think is the first show to have that I'm sure anime world order is gonna send us.
Speaker 0: Oh you forgot about Poland.
Speaker 1: Oh, we sure did damn Poland.
Speaker 0: Uh Yeah, I mean once again, we're not reviewing slayers because I think we're gonna review each season and each bit of slayers independent.
Speaker 1: Yeah this is an introduction to the world of slayers.
Speaker 1: for those of you who don't know of it cuz slayers is a really old show that was super popular and they licensed the hell out of it and they distributed all over the US and then After they sold it to everyone.
Speaker 1: It's been kind of forgotten in favor of newer shows and I think even some of the licenses lapsed and were Re-picked up and
Speaker 0: I mean it used to be back in the day when you went to a Suncoast or somewhere that actually sold Anime, they would have VHS's of Ranma and then a VHS's of slayers like those two were always there everywhere.
Speaker 1: And nowadays a lot of new fans don't even know slayers or they know of it, but they've never seen it.
Speaker 0: Yeah and honestly I I have to admit that I hadn't seen that much of the first season of slayers and it wasn't until Scott and I actually Watched it all the way through That it was actually weird to see the characters before they met each other because I'd seen so much of slayers where they're all already together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was deaf.
Speaker 1: It's always weird to watch.
Speaker 1: You know what happened before.
Speaker 1: if you if you already know what happened after Star Wars Oh God Yeah, let's talk about this one.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna watch any slayers the movie the movie is what you have to write now.
Speaker 0: when we say the slayers movie We mean the one that you'll see in the anime store on DVD the one that is right there everywhere It is everyone knows it as the slayers movie.
Speaker 1: It says on the DVD case slayers the motion picture now.
Speaker 0: It is a Lina and Naga and This is where many of our inside jokes come from.
Speaker 0: surprisingly.
Speaker 1: There is the main joke in this the bit.
Speaker 1: the plot of the movie is that this is island Mipros Island and Lena inverse is on this island and there's something bad going on there and She has to figure it out and stop it.
Speaker 1: and she's a super powerful sorceress.
Speaker 1: So that's not a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's mostly the figuring it out.
Speaker 0: That's the problem Yeah, plus she doesn't really care until they bribe her with a lot of money.
Speaker 1: exactly, you know.
Speaker 0: But keep in mind that this movie is a lot different from the slayers TV shows and that it's very surreal and weird Very at least at some parts of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but overall I mean compared to the TV show which is very straightforward.
Speaker 1: So early on in the movie some guy shows up and he's like he's fighting he's gonna fight with Lena and he says I'm the Fifth strongest man on Mipros Island now ha ha ha ha ha.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend you watch the dub because it's pretty well done.
Speaker 0: And I got to admit hearing someone yell in English, huh?
Speaker 0: I am the fifth strongest man on Mipros Island.
Speaker 0: Just I can't.
Speaker 0: I can't help but laugh at that.
Speaker 1: and then a little while later She runs into the fourth strongest man on Mipros Island and well, you can see where it goes from there.
Speaker 1: But when we talk about being the ex strongest something in something we're making fun of the first slayers.
Speaker 1: Well the slayers movie.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Now if you've never seen any slayers If nothing else pick up this movie because it is very funny.
Speaker 0: It'll introduce you to the world It'll introduce you to all the kinds of jokes and you don't have to invest in an entire TV show.
Speaker 1: Yeah This is a completely self-contained movie.
Speaker 1: someone who knows jack and shit about slayers will laugh their ass off at this thing if you like It.
Speaker 0: either Netflix or buy the first season of slayers because it's really easy to come by nowadays Mm-hmm, and it should be even easier to come by as time goes on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one's printing more of it But no one's buying it and the price is just gonna drop.
Speaker 0: now the TV show as opposed to the movies and OAVs and such the.
Speaker 0: I mean it gets very serious at times, but it always fades back to funny.
Speaker 0: and Then slayers next which is the sequel to slayers and it takes place pretty much right after.
Speaker 0: it just keeps going.
Speaker 0: It kind of widens the gap.
Speaker 0: There's more serious but even more funny.
Speaker 0: and then slayers try which I actually didn't like so much and I didn't even see all of it Takes it to the extreme and it has the crazy Stupid funny and the crazy serious and it the dichotomy almost gets too big.
Speaker 0: but luckily the show didn't progress beyond that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, another warning for anyone who's gonna watch slayers is that there's a lot of running gags and repetitive humor.
Speaker 1: You'll see the same you'll see a joke and then they'll keep going with that same joke and never change it ever.
Speaker 0: Though the thing is it's usually still funny.
Speaker 1: to me it is it's still a little bit funny every time.
Speaker 1: but if you're the kind of person who groans and moans when they've you know, Some character has a shtick like.
Speaker 1: what's a good example?
Speaker 0: Amelia falls on her face when she tries to jump into the heat of battle.
Speaker 1: exactly Amelia whenever she's about to enter a fight She climbs up somewhere very high and then she jumps into the fight and then she lands on her face every single goddamn time.
Speaker 1: So it's funny as hell.
Speaker 1: the first three times is you realize?
Speaker 1: aha she falls in her face all the time.
Speaker 1: But then in in future episodes, she just keeps falling on her face.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is that type of humor seems to be a mainstay of a lot of the early anime comedies.
Speaker 0: So if you can't deal with it in slayers You really shouldn't watch any of the early anime comedy shows because they're all like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah So many jokes like that in slayers.
Speaker 1: I mean every time they're eating food in and in it explodes Or sets on fire.
Speaker 0: Who knows what the hell things get blown up all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's also a lot.
Speaker 0: if you play Dungeons & Dragons or any kind of fantasy role-playing You will appreciate these shows on such a higher level than if you don't.
Speaker 0: I mean Lena needs money at one point.
Speaker 0: So she sits there like basically making magic items to sell in town.
Speaker 1: Yeah They actually animate that whole scene where like she gets some equipment and she goes out to like some shrine and she starts casting Metamorphosis spells to turn some dreck into some gems and then she sells them at a store in town.
Speaker 0: or she gets some magic items and they start selling them You know like to take magic.
Speaker 0: Ooh, this one's worth this much and tries to sell it to people.
Speaker 1: It's yeah, isn't there some episode later on where they go somewhere where there's no magic and they're ridiculously powerful.
Speaker 0: Yes in slayers try see it.
Speaker 0: They're ridiculously powerful.
Speaker 1: Anyway, these are slayers is a story about high-level characters.
Speaker 1: They're stupid powerful like saving the world from the most powerful demon god powerful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they are.
Speaker 0: I mean D&D terms their 9th to 12th level even more than that.
Speaker 0: Well Lena probably more but everyone else seems to be there.
Speaker 0: They're high level.
Speaker 0: They're definitely not epic level yet.
Speaker 1: No, they're not gods, but they can stave off gods through the use of incredibly powerful artifacts.
Speaker 0: Yes kill a couple of gods even yeah, but it Actually slayers try had something really good going for it.
Speaker 0: that part of the plot there is that They end up in a world where there is no magic like people don't like.
Speaker 0: magic is this crazy rare thing and I don't really want to ruin much but there's not much to ruin in slayers really and They still have all their powers because they know how to cast spells.
Speaker 0: So like there's a part where one of the characters at like goat like has one of the townspeople lead him to like this ancient ruin of the ancient masters like this Secret Forbidden Palace that has been sealed by something and hasn't been open for thousands of years And he's like is this a place?
Speaker 0: the guys like yes, and he just kicks the gate open walks in.
Speaker 0: he's like oh All right, he grabs some artifacts like this is pretty weak.
Speaker 0: Another character flies up on the top of building to look around and all the townsfolk think that she's gonna jump to her death And just funny stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: layers next has probably my favorite joke in all of slayers the the whole thing with trying to find the Claire Bible the Claire bevel the Claire bevel I don't even know.
Speaker 0: I've never actually seen the sub of slayer.
Speaker 1: One of my favorite jokes is the fish men.
Speaker 1: There there are these.
Speaker 1: this is race of creatures.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of different races of creatures as in any Fantasy universe and one of the races of creatures in slayers are the fish men and they're basically fish with cartoon arms and legs.
Speaker 0: They're ugly as hell and you get the sense that they smell bad and they're all evil.
Speaker 0: yet They're all silly also kind of stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're stupid evil and silly And they show up when you at least expect them.
Speaker 0: It's like like altros.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you're walking around and there's a fish man.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 0: Oh my god Remember the fish man that was flying around like a bullet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: What was his problem?
Speaker 0: I think the funniest part of that was you said why don't they just do this?
Speaker 0: and then they just did that and it killed the fish man immediately.
Speaker 0: That's one nice thing about the show.
Speaker 0: the characters always seem to act intelligently Like they were being played by real people in a D&D game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but sometimes they also act stupidly, you know, like.
Speaker 1: well stupid characters do like they get lost and then they can't find each other Again, you know it they'll get into trouble and then they won't be able to get out.
Speaker 1: But as long as they stick together, they can just keep acting smartly and do the right thing.
Speaker 1: There are other sort of annoying things like I think for a stretch of episodes in the original slayers It just every episode seemed like it was the same thing.
Speaker 1: They would be in a different place But they would fight the same bad guys and then those bad guys would run away and the next episode they'd be in a different Place and then to fight those same bad guys again.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, the thing is I really enjoy like I just like it.
Speaker 0: slayers The original series has a really good nice place in my heart and I really enjoy it.
Speaker 0: It's one of my favorite old shows, but I enjoyed slayers next a lot more.
Speaker 0: So I think Scott when you see slayers next you your love of slayers will come to a whole new level.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm still more a fan of the naga the serpent because that stuff is just all-out Hilarity and doesn't doesn't even bother with the serious.
Speaker 1: then hilarity then serious.
Speaker 0: It's just all funny jellyfish in the sea cucumbers Exactly or the giant golems.
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah if you want to see really silly stuff get all the slayers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, yeah God yeah slayers must be good because we just keep laughing as we remember scenes from it.
Speaker 1: yeah, so anyone out there who doesn't know of slayers or Maybe you know of it and you've never seen it.
Speaker 1: It is an anime that all should see an experience.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's definitely not.
Speaker 0: I don't think in my top 5 or top 10 No, no, no.
Speaker 0: But it is definitely on the list of.
Speaker 0: if you consider yourself an anime fan But not like as in you would define yourself as a fan or anime is your thing.
Speaker 0: You really have no excuse to have not seen slayers.
Speaker 0: you.
Speaker 0: that is like.
Speaker 0: I must see anime because so much comes from slayers that is in modern anime and it was such a good show when it came out and the fact that It's still a pretty good show all things considered even today.
Speaker 0: It would even stand up to a lot of modern shows.
Speaker 1: And the thing is even though some slayers OAVs and movies are better than others They're all at least at the bare minimum funny.
Speaker 1: You will laugh it no matter which one you watch and if you don't laugh, you're not gonna laugh any of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you don't laugh at them, there's a lot of anime you're not gonna like.
Speaker 1: There are also some slayers video games.
Speaker 1: I know there's an SNES game, but they're all Japanese and I don't think they've been translated.
Speaker 0: Yes, any s game has been but not officially there have been.
Speaker 1: it's not a fun game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, well, it's like Final Fantasy 6.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like Final Fantasy 6 in fact And I played through a little bit of it and then the translated ROM I was using.
Speaker 0: it turns out that whatever fucker Translated it translated the first bit and then just stopped.
Speaker 0: So fine one day I get to a village like I get somewhere and I talk to someone and it's just gibberish and not even Japanese characters are just gibberish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then everyone I talked to was gibberish and I couldn't forget through the game anymore Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wouldn't really recommend it as a game.
Speaker 0: You should play unless you're Japanese though I can't verify this cuz I didn't play through the game and I'm not gonna look it up or anything, but I heard There's some slayers trivia for you that you know.
Speaker 0: Naga and Lena adventure and then later Naga and Gauri and everyone else adventure and there's really no overlap at all.
Speaker 0: Like there's no Continuity directly between the two and Apparently in the video game Gauri and Naga meet one another.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: now That is nothing but hearsay.
Speaker 0: I will not back that statement up at all But more than one person has told me this and I've never bothered to look it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I said before, you know some slayers.
Speaker 1: things are Lena inverse and Naga the serpent and no one else except for the bad Guys, of course and the rest of slayers is Lena inverse and an entire party of adventurers, but not Naga the serpent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd go through all the characters because I could say a lot about him, but even describing it now He's a fighter there's well, it's saying the names of certain characters ruins things that oh that guy's not a villain.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm assuming that people who are gonna go out and watch the show because of us They haven't seen it and they won't know that that one guy is actually a really cool main character or that that other guy dies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's generally there's a fighter There's a guy who's a magician, but he's a different kind of magician like a druid type.
Speaker 0: Yeah They there's a lot of clarity in the magic like there's a rogue type of person kind is Dungeons & Dragons style magic.
Speaker 0: you say the spell it happens and the fireball.
Speaker 0: The spells follow the same kinds of rules that D&D spells would and in fact the characters explain this stuff all the time Like they explain it to each other.
Speaker 0: they'll explain what spells do just this for the benefit of the Watchers.
Speaker 1: They'll lose their spell powers during that time of the month.
Speaker 0: Yes, which It's a really freakin good show, I don't know how many times I need to say that.
Speaker 1: all right I think that covers it.
Speaker 0: Yeah under the few meta bits Don't forget that next week is the last week before we go to Otacon and the week after that We can't promise that there will be Episodes.
Speaker 0: Yes, most likely the week after Otacon they're going to be some short like five to ten minute geek night specials that we're going to record ahead of time and Set up to automatically upload because we're not going to be able to do the shows from the beach.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean we probably could but it'd be too much effort going to McDonald's and using the Wi-Fi and plus.
Speaker 0: I got to tell you once we get back the week after that We are going to have almost a month worth of content from all the interviews and the coverage of Otacon and the coverage of Wildwood and all the crazy things we're going to do.
Speaker 0: We're bringing all this equipment.
Speaker 0: We're gonna record almost everything we do throughout this entire two weeks of awesome.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be pretty freakin crazy.
Speaker 1: So don't be disappointed about.
Speaker 1: you know a week of not so good episodes.
Speaker 0: and also if you're planning on going to Otacon if you're a member of the forum say something in the forum.
Speaker 0: if you're not a member of the forums join the forums.
Speaker 0: if you really Don't want to join the forums email us because we want to see all of you.
Speaker 0: We know a lot of you are going to Otacon and we're doing where I'm doing two panels Scott's doing one We're gonna be all over the place causing trouble.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna be freakin everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: and if you want to see a good time at Otacon join the front row crew posse because we are always there causing whatever trouble you're About to run into.
Speaker 1: and the one place you can be guaranteed to see us as always is the Saturday night Horrible tasteless movie.
Speaker 0: Yes, Saturday night smoke probably sometime around midnight probably in like panel or video.
Speaker 1: for well who knows.
Speaker 1: but look in the con schedule and you'll see that there's one video room and That video room shows only live-action cinema.
Speaker 1: If you go to that video room late Saturday night to watch the final show or you know The late late show that's horrible and disgusting.
Speaker 1: We will be there.
Speaker 0: Oh, will we be there?
Speaker 0: We will be there with an entire crew.
Speaker 0: They'd be there n-force yelling and screaming All right, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.