Speaker 1: It's Thursday August 24th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight You will finally hear the tale of the front row crew.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Some at work today.
Speaker 1: and for those of you who do not know I work alone in an office in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: There are stories about that that Scott probably can't tell on the air.
Speaker 1: Yes, and People really don't seem to pay attention to what I'm doing or give me a lot of instructions on what to do.
Speaker 1: I mean, they didn't even do that when I was working next to them in the same office in New York City, but Nonetheless today I got an email that said hey How is X coming along?
Speaker 1: and I said X is about 90% done.
Speaker 1: and they were like awesome alright, and I was like, okay and For those of you who don't know of course said.
Speaker 1: for those of you who don't know I know I don't know why I said that again But let me tell you I haven't worked on X for an entire week.
Speaker 1: In fact in all of this week, I have done zero work at work.
Speaker 1: I have played Fire Emblem and browse the web at work.
Speaker 1: That's about it.
Speaker 0: Well, all I have to say is that if you keep this up for another two weeks uninterrupted You'll beat my IBM record if not doing work.
Speaker 1: I think actually though next week I am going to finish the final 10% of X.
Speaker 0: Well, see my rule when it comes to counting not doing work If you do work for less than one half hour per day, I consider it not working at all.
Speaker 1: No I think what I'm actually gonna do is work all day For like two or three days and just finish the whole thing and it'll be perfect and amazing.
Speaker 0: See, I wish I could do that but in my job most of my work involves just waiting for other people to do the piece of their crap so that I can then do all my Paperwork and finish everything up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see my work.
Speaker 1: as soon as someone gives me, you know tells me what they want made I could just make it and it's all me and I can do whatever and get it done.
Speaker 1: and I realize now that The people at my company are never going to give me instructions as detailed as I would like them to give me.
Speaker 1: so I pretty much have to take what they ask and then do my own thing and you know, do what I think is best and Apparently they'll be pleased with it no matter what I come up with.
Speaker 1: So that's what I'm doing from now on because I don't really care if I get fired.
Speaker 1: I'm bored sitting there.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna fire you.
Speaker 0: I've learned that people do this.
Speaker 0: Don't you have to be such a fuck-up to be fired?
Speaker 1: but here's the thing.
Speaker 1: when I first got to the company like they were firing people like People I thought were cool and doing work and I've seen some internal thing.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know but people talk about you know, like oh so-and-so isn't really good their work and all this kind of.
Speaker 1: you know what.
Speaker 0: as far as I'm concerned very few of the people I've ever worked with Really were good at the job.
Speaker 0: They were supposed to be doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's I'd say less than 10%.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, the point is is that they fire people where I work.
Speaker 0: and yeah Yeah, I've been having the opposite issue lately.
Speaker 0: other I mean not the op.
Speaker 0: I wish I had work to do.
Speaker 0: I have so little work to do and I do it all and then I kind of Look like I'm busy.
Speaker 0: or I wait for more work to come or I ask for work but I'm starting to meet more of my co-workers and starting like I'm talking to more people around the office and in the other sites and without fail every time I Like people eat.
Speaker 0: Oh, what did you before?
Speaker 0: What are you doing?
Speaker 0: I tell him, you know I was a Linux this admin and I did development for this and I worked IBM and blah blah blah and They stare at me and they always ask in the exact same tone.
Speaker 0: So why are you here?
Speaker 1: Because you're paying me more to do less.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except the thing is I probably still did last at IBM.
Speaker 0: I just did.
Speaker 0: I did more real work, but I did a lot less total work.
Speaker 0: I mean IBM.
Speaker 0: I'd basically do nothing But then they'd ask me for something like do X and I would do X Wonderfully and immediately and then there was nothing to do for another month.
Speaker 0: Hmm other than you know busy work that I could generally avoid.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll start a business and beacon.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's looking more and more attractive as time goes on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even if it's financially Terrible, it'll be a lot more interesting and I won't feel like shit.
Speaker 1: I'll feel like I'm doing something with my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz once my that's more important to me than money right now once my student loans are paid off I could live on very little money relative to what I need now to survive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I could live on.
Speaker 0: I could probably live pretty comfortably on $30,000 a year if I didn't have all my debt.
Speaker 0: Mmm now I think I could manage to run a business where I could make at least $30,000 a year or at least I could make enough money on the side to round out that much money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe it really depends, you know, we got to learn more about starting a business.
Speaker 1: But you know a lot of people out there run businesses that aren't really smart and we're pretty damn smart.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're like butchers.
Speaker 1: they run a butcher shop.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing.
Speaker 0: while I while a computer shop would be the optimum thing in terms of enjoyment I think the best business we could open in this area is a sub shop in the vein of de bella's.
Speaker 0: Yep, I agree I'm reasonably certain that if we got together the capital and did that we could make a shit ton of money.
Speaker 0: But for a number of years we would have to personally manage and work at a sub shop.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, tell you what you work at the sub shop, right and I'll sit at home I'll manage the sub shop and you can Work at it.
Speaker 1: You can bake the bread.
Speaker 1: I'll make the bread.
Speaker 1: set up the point-of-sale systems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right now you can see why we still have work at shitty jobs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though I have another completely unrelated Scott bit of news here.
Speaker 0: All right, because recently now we had though You know the week of awesome and everything and one advantage that was if we had to hang out with a lot of friends We don't get to see often like James and Lisa who are in Texas.
Speaker 0: But at one point it ended up being myself Scott and yuko driving together to the shore And Scott and I didn't have our voices so much.
Speaker 0: So it was mostly yuko talking and us listening and nodding and periodically saying things then going because our throats hurt.
Speaker 0: hmm and Ever since Otakon and the shore and all this time we hung out with all these people Scott has been pretty much talking like a tiny bastardized yuko.
Speaker 1: Well, you know whenever anyone there are people out there who have sayings like I have sayings Yeah, well, there are things I say often like like, you know Oh god.
Speaker 1: Oh god, the word penis the word penis There are many, you know people have.
Speaker 1: Every person who's a real person tends to have catchphrases and yuko like most people has some catchphrases.
Speaker 1: Oh, man Oh man's.
Speaker 1: by the by and by the by now Oh Man's was very apparent to me.
Speaker 1: I realized oh man's was a yuko catchphrase and recently I decided to steal it.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't actually consciously decide this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's more like.
Speaker 0: I noticed that he was saying it a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it just rubs off.
Speaker 1: You know, I remember in high school.
Speaker 1: There was a kid Brandon something and Not rim rims.
Speaker 1: real name is Brandon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well one of my names.
Speaker 1: Yeah your real name.
Speaker 1: So And he would always say like dos equis, I don't know why he said dos equis.
Speaker 1: If you don't know dos equis is that Mexican alcohol with the two X's on it though Because dos is two and equis is X. yes, and he would just be like dos equis and I'd be like Dos equis and like all of a sudden the whole group of people that like were closer to him.
Speaker 1: I just rubbed off than me in physics class But other people he talked to like it would rub off on them and they'd say dos equis a lot
Speaker 0: general it seems to be more a thing among geeks than other people lately is that these sorts of mannerisms and catchphrases are viral and they spread like wildfire among people who are susceptible to them and independent of that.
Speaker 0: it is generally known that people who are perceived as being Charismatic or having some sort of presence.
Speaker 0: This is stuff why we talked about in all those communications classes I took at RIT since I basically took the whole major.
Speaker 0: but one thing we learned about a lot was that people who appear charismatic something they do either consciously or a lot of times subconsciously is That they will mimic the body language mannerisms and sometimes accents of those around them.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and Scott and I seem to do that a lot.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: I do that a lot I noticed like sometimes like the way I talk will just change completely when I'm with different people.
Speaker 0: I have a funny story Yeah, where I was interviewing for a job and at one point one of the international business manager to the company I was interviewing with decided he wanted to talk to me and he's this British guy and he travels all over the call.
Speaker 1: They were just like right.
Speaker 0: I wasn't like that, but he starts talking to me and I started like I was talking normally and then I realized halfway through that I Was kind of doing a sort of fake British accent.
Speaker 0: Totally didn't realize it and I suddenly noticed it and I was really kind of.
Speaker 0: I wasn't embarrassed.
Speaker 0: It was more that I didn't know what to do.
Speaker 0: Do I suddenly stop doing it?
Speaker 0: Do I just pretend I've got this accent?
Speaker 0: What do I do?
Speaker 0: and I was kind of like deer in headlights for a minute?
Speaker 1: Yeah What did he look?
Speaker 1: does he do you look weird at you or anything?
Speaker 0: He seemed to really like me.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, that's.
Speaker 0: I don't think he ever heard me talk normally though And it wasn't like I was talking like get in the vase Or anything.
Speaker 0: it was just there was a little bit of and I was saying words that I'd often don't normally say and it was like Boot and schedule.
Speaker 0: I did say leisure a number of times But I do for fun and I was like well in my leisure time I Did The word.
Speaker 0: that was actually the moment I realized what I was doing because I said leisure in a not like.
Speaker 0: I say leisure sometimes funnily but I usually say leisure and I Realized when I said leisure that I said it because the guy was speaking British.
Speaker 0: Yep, so but it's not just the whole front row crew.
Speaker 0: Does it?
Speaker 0: it's a very big thing among us.
Speaker 0: Yes, anyway mimic each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so oh, man's I realized when I was saying oh, man's that it was.
Speaker 1: I was like.
Speaker 1: I said oh man's once and I was Saying I stole totally stole it.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I'll keep saying it cuz oh man's is cool and I've been saying oh man's recently.
Speaker 0: So today Scott comes up and he says to me so rim by the by and I didn't realize That by the by was a saying of anyone.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've heard it before in my life, but I didn't realize it was a yuko thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I stopped him and I was like, um Scott you're turning into yuko except you're not nearly as cute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd ever noticed that she said by the by at all and I guess I'm gonna stop saying that cuz it's not as I Would say that it's not as cool as oh, man's.
Speaker 0: I would say that a good two-thirds of the conversation She starts with me begin with hey rim Oh, man's by the by or some permutation thereof.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, man's oh man's by the by.
Speaker 0: you should know that a woman's That doesn't work.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we got some news I guess.
Speaker 0: Okay, even though it's funny you guys out there always seem to say that Oh, we want to hear the news.
Speaker 0: Don't get rid of the news, but we always get the most feedback from the throwaway crap We do before the news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so whatever All right.
Speaker 0: There was a thing called or cuts Orcutt might be before your time for some of you younger internet kids.
Speaker 1: Well his it was.
Speaker 1: um, I'll sum up the story of or cut ready first off I'll sum it up in the I won't.
Speaker 0: it was a flash in the pan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what it was.
Speaker 1: Let me sum up the story.
Speaker 1: There was a guy who developed some social You know computing technology social networking, yeah, he basically invented like myspace friendster, I don't even know and Like he worked for Google and then he didn't work for Google or he worked for someone else.
Speaker 1: make I think yeah That's it.
Speaker 1: He invented this shit at another company that was social website type stuff and he.
Speaker 1: then he went to Google and at Google He made Orca and the other company was like hey You just made that here and then you went to Google and made the same thing for them.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a really well executed social networking thing.
Speaker 0: that part of the gimmicks of it were that one you had to put your Real contact information in and the real information about yourself and you actually got in trouble if you lied in this thing Like they would get rid of you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it was invite only Invite only mostly like most Google things now that worked Really?
Speaker 0: Well because it kept the shit heads out because no one would give them invites for the longest time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it also made it Really interesting for the people running Orca to see how the network was expanding because you knew that Every expansion to the network was a branch off of you know, the guy who started it.
Speaker 1: So there's like this middle dot.
Speaker 1: and then you just saw you know Who sent out lots of invites who sent out only a few who didn't send any and
Speaker 0: like I
Speaker 1: make this big like chart Of all the
Speaker 0: people like I can I think it was Steve Pomeroy who actually gave our group the first invite.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because we knew about it and he's like, oh I didn't realize you guys were interested in that when we started talking about it and then he invited all of us.
Speaker 0: Yep And then we invited a crazy ton of people and we became huge proponents of it and we would all sit on it like every day Making communities and talking and setting things up Like I made the Otacon community which is still there and we have the RIT anime community, which apparently I still own.
Speaker 0: Awesome, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it took me forever to remember my password to this damn thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so or cut Was ruined or cut Eventually like the Muslim hordes that tried to overrun Europe like the sea peoples the Phil Stines that overran Greece Philistines Phil Stines whatever.
Speaker 0: anyway the Portuguese speaking Brazilians came one day and within the span of not exaggerating within the span of about two weeks Orcutt went from amazing and cool to utterly useless.
Speaker 1: It was just dominated Completely by Portuguese Brazilian.
Speaker 1: I got nothing against Brazil.
Speaker 0: Brazil's a cool place Yeah And it wasn't even that people who don't speak English were using this thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was set up so that any languages can work and it was really beautiful and unique.
Speaker 0: The Brazilians had no concept of internet etiquette.
Speaker 0: they had no concept of not spamming people and basically there was nothing but Brazilian spam of Brazilians trying to trick other people into joining their communities and being their friends so that their numbers would go up so that they can get more people.
Speaker 1: it was just craziness and utter chaos just basically like this flood of millions upon millions of Portuguese messages just flooding the system completely filling up every box and they took over every community.
Speaker 0: they destroyed Everything.
Speaker 0: they broke or cut for a while with the massive amounts of spam.
Speaker 1: Yeah Orcutt was real slow for a while and because they were just filling it up with so much shit It was basically vandalism.
Speaker 0: and the funny part is I saw a post by a Brazilian who wrote in English and he basically said To any of you who might be thinking that this is cool Don't be.
Speaker 0: I can read what these people are saying and this is the bottom of the internet.
Speaker 0: get out get out get out.
Speaker 0: And Orcutt.
Speaker 0: and just collapsed completely and we all fled.
Speaker 1: but Orcutt is still there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not only is it still there but apparently now it's a den of child pornography.
Speaker 0: Oh really in Brazil see I had forgotten about Orcutt.
Speaker 0: Orcutt was this wonderful short chapter in my life and I see on slashdot a news story about Orcutt.
Speaker 0: I didn't even read the story.
Speaker 0: I thought Orcutt and I went there and I posted the quick story of what happened to Orcutt because it seemed like the people Commenting on whatever the story was.
Speaker 0: I had no idea what Orcutt really was.
Speaker 0: They were talking about Google search and they had no idea.
Speaker 1: Imagine if myspace existed for about a month and then disappeared because it was just full of crap.
Speaker 1: That's what Orcutt is Yep.
Speaker 0: Now the story doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: I don't care about it.
Speaker 0: It was just an excuse to talk about Orcutt, but basically Brazilians were using Orcutt to share child pornography allegedly and the Brazilian government has demanded that Google and Orcutt hand over all of the information to track these people down.
Speaker 0: Google has said fuck you.
Speaker 0: We're in America.
Speaker 0: Send us some Legal documents and then we'll talk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's about right and I don't know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: I mean like of course if I was Google I would go through the system cleaning up all the child porn You know, but I wouldn't give information to the Brazilian government unless they had.
Speaker 0: I mean if I were Google I would comply with the legal request.
Speaker 0: if I got served the real papers I would cooperate 100%.
Speaker 1: not just that but even if there are no legal papers, I would go around my little Orcutt You know getting rid of all the child porn.
Speaker 0: Yeah the problem it I have with this is that the Brazilians seem to expect Google to cooperate in their investigation without any sort of You know legal process.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no matter what they were investigating I mean, I gotta say if a police officer bothers me and tries to get information out of me.
Speaker 0: I Warrant or I was seeing a crime happening at that exact moment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the only real time I would give up information to.
Speaker 1: well if I saw a guy with a knife Yelling and screaming and laughing maniacally covered in blood running away Well, I was just gonna say if I was a witness to something and then a cop came around and was like, hey Oh, you know you doing.
Speaker 0: there was a story on FARC recently.
Speaker 0: That might not always be the best idea Really?
Speaker 0: The story is a guy.
Speaker 0: I forget the exact story.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna pull the pendulate thing here and make up a story that has the same basic facts.
Speaker 0: Okay crime was committed.
Speaker 0: I think it was a murder or something.
Speaker 0: Guy witnesses it.
Speaker 0: Guy goes to court like, you know, he's gonna testify.
Speaker 0: Judge is afraid that this guy might not appear in court to actually testify for the real trial Orders.
Speaker 0: the guy arrested and keeps him in jail until the trial for months.
Speaker 0: then due to a clerical error After the trial they didn't let him out and he sat in jail for a long time.
Speaker 1: I heard that story.
Speaker 0: finally, he someone fought on his behalf and got him out of jail and I Get the impression that events like this will not have this magnitude happened somewhat regularly in the US for a judge or someone will Detain someone to testify an important case because they're afraid that they might not testify.
Speaker 1: Trick is don't go to court until it's testifying time because as soon as you walk into the courtroom they can contempt you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they could just put out a warrant and a subpoena and get you anyway, but what are they arresting me for?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, they put him under protective Custodianship or something.
Speaker 1: Alright, so all I really have to do is whenever I'm a witness to anything I'll call a lawyer immediately and I say you keep your eye on me.
Speaker 1: If anything happens to me, you got to come get my ass out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just really it's sad because I'm generally a very law-and-order person, but I don't trust the police at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty.
Speaker 1: if I was a witness though.
Speaker 1: I and I wasn't worried about being locked in jail.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, if it weren't for that I would just I would tell them whatever I saw sure.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, cuz I definitely believe that if someone does something bad you should you know mitigate the damages.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you got some news.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So Pluto is.
Speaker 1: Is it a planet or is it not a planet?
Speaker 0: Well, no, it is not a planet by the by.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it really all depends on the definition of planet and for a while on the internet I'd say about a couple years now.
Speaker 1: It's been a very large point of contention.
Speaker 1: What exactly constitute a planet?
Speaker 1: What should constitute a planet etcetera, etcetera?
Speaker 0: I never made the song but I have this little sample here that I may or may not have added into what I'm just saying right now in post-production, but Rim doesn't give one shit about whether or not Pluto is a planet because Pluto is still there regardless of what I call it
Speaker 1: Yeah, really I mean the.
Speaker 1: the way the solar system is constructed and what rocks are floating around in it and where they float is not affected by the names we choose to apply to those rocks.
Speaker 1: so anyway, some people seem to care about what's a planet and what's not and It seems that their largest concern is elementary school textbooks.
Speaker 0: Now that is the student.
Speaker 0: if a teacher can't deal with telling their students This book is somewhat out-of-date children and Pluto is not actually a planet because of blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: They can't handle that.
Speaker 0: They shouldn't be a teacher.
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think what it is is just that's you know, a whole nother show about how Adults, you know underestimate children and treat them like children.
Speaker 0: I think it's also that's why they're children.
Speaker 1: if you treated them like adults, then they would become adults much quicker.
Speaker 0: I think it's also a show about how when people To want to resist change, they'll just look for anything they can to complain about whenever change comes.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean that is an asinine complaint and I don't know what they think.
Speaker 0: They think the the committee is gonna say, you know what?
Speaker 0: All right for the elementary school students Pluto is a planet Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: What the hell anyway.
Speaker 1: here I'm gonna read this paragraph of stuff so that you can get the full facts of this debacle into your brain.
Speaker 1: a Planet is a celestial body.
Speaker 1: That is an orbit around the Sun.
Speaker 1: check as sufficient mass for its self-gravity to overcome rigid body forces so that it assumes a hydrostatic equilibrium Nearly round shape check I believe and has cleared the neighborhood around its orbit.
Speaker 0: Pluto hasn't done that.
Speaker 0: Pluto's too little.
Speaker 0: it didn't do that.
Speaker 1: a dwarf planet is a celestial body that is in orbit around the Sun check has sufficient mass for its self-gravity to overcome rigid body forces that it assumes a hydrostatic equilibrium nearly round shape.
Speaker 1: Oh man has not cleared the neighborhood around its orbit and is not a satellite.
Speaker 0: Alright, so the moon now is not going to be considered a planet like some people feared.
Speaker 1: No, the moon is a satellite.
Speaker 1: Therefore.
Speaker 1: It is not a planet nor dwarf planet.
Speaker 1: And you know, the real thing here is that You know, you had to clear.
Speaker 1: you can't just clear, you know, the neighborhood around where you are.
Speaker 1: You have to clear your orbit.
Speaker 1: So, you know you take the orbit of the earth and you draw this big circle on the star map or whatever and you say Hey, is there any shit floating around in the orbit of Earth?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, there's no shit floating around in the orbit of Earth.
Speaker 1: Well, then Earth has cleared its orbit.
Speaker 1: you look at Pluto and you look at Pluto's orbit and you say hey Wait a minute Neptune is in Pluto's orbit.
Speaker 1: Pluto has not cleared its orbit and the moon, you know Someone might say oh the moon is a planet because you know, the definition of planet doesn't discount satellites.
Speaker 1: But the moon has not cleared its orbit of I don't know the earth which is kind of in the way.
Speaker 1: So well the thing is.
Speaker 0: I'd also read that there's a chance The moon is going to eventually escape earth and kind of become a free-roaming body.
Speaker 1: That could happen and apparently I read in some places that certain astro scientists of various sorts believe the moon and the earth to actually be two planets sort of Switching places and orbiting each other in a duality, you know Well by the by.
Speaker 0: I'm sure Lara will if she listens to geek nights tonight will probably correct us on something we've said.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know that she's the only person we know that knows anything about Astro whatnots?
Speaker 0: Astro whatnots?
Speaker 1: that shows you how much we know.
Speaker 0: she can tell us about the kajigger.
Speaker 1: Yep The kajigger in the flying rocks in space.
Speaker 0: Oh Man, speaking of space.
Speaker 0: It's time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: I am the pusher hoe behind.
Speaker 1: I am the shover rim For tired to protect you from the terrible secret of space.
Speaker 0: do not trust the Scott robot.
Speaker 0: he is malfunctioning.
Speaker 0: I am here to protect you.
Speaker 0: I'm here to protect you from the terrible secret of space.
Speaker 1: Please stay hidden near the top of the stairs.
Speaker 1: I'm the pusher robot.
Speaker 1: stand near the top of the stairs, please All right, I'm pushing the bread into their mouths.
Speaker 0: no, no, no you shove the bread down the people's throats You push the people around the blind people whatever whatever.
Speaker 0: Space has a terrible power.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: This is the thing that this is a classic thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Yes, well, I can't believe we forgot to use it during classic week.
Speaker 0: Well classic two weeks, basically Yeah, this is just an old flash video from God like five years ago.
Speaker 1: It's really just a flash music video to this song.
Speaker 0: if you've ever seen the words peck chewy um, or Ever heard anything about the terrible secret of space and you wondered what the hell that was.
Speaker 0: Here's your answer.
Speaker 1: I'm not exactly sure if this is really the origin of pack chewy.
Speaker 0: Um, well, all I have to say is that this is where Most people would know it from if they know where it's from at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you search for peck chewy, um on Google guess where it takes you the terrible secret of space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what that's.
Speaker 0: well I mean space has a terrible power.
Speaker 1: It does indeed.
Speaker 0: Yeah by the by.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I saw this thing on the internet this morning.
Speaker 1: God, this is great and it just it's some guys watching the Pokemon movie now and Okay Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah pack pack chewy.
Speaker 1: Um, that's where a pack chewy.
Speaker 1: Um for originated at least according to the Urban Dictionary.
Speaker 1: It is the Urban Dictionary says pack chewy.
Speaker 1: Um question.
Speaker 1: Do you have stairs in your house?
Speaker 0: The thing is I've never heard pack chewy on other than in reference to that or from someone who didn't know what it was.
Speaker 1: I think I saw a t-shirt that should have packed chewy.
Speaker 1: Um fun it.
Speaker 0: I've seen that a lot.
Speaker 0: I assumed it was to the shover pusher robots.
Speaker 1: Oh anyway so Back to this Pokemon movie.
Speaker 1: There's a video here of two guys.
Speaker 1: They seem to be New York North New Jersey type guys, maybe Brooklyn guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I get the definite impression of Brooklyn Yeah, and they're watching a Pokemon movie.
Speaker 1: I think it might be the second or third one It looks like because it has.
Speaker 0: that was that the 48th one.
Speaker 0: There's so many freaking Pokemon movies.
Speaker 1: I don't know that much about Pokemon movies But I know quite a bit about the original the first two sets of Pokemon games because I played him.
Speaker 1: I played Pokemon red and Pokemon silver and I know about Pokemon adventures the excellent manga that everyone should read Which is the only Pokemon really worth reading.
Speaker 1: Anyway, these guys are watching a Pokemon movie and this one guy starts going off about how Snorlax is freaking awesome.
Speaker 1: I mean, he's like look at Snorlax.
Speaker 1: He's holding ten Pokemon without Snorlax.
Speaker 1: They'd be screwed.
Speaker 1: Snorlax owns you.
Speaker 0: Snorlax is fucking ripped.
Speaker 1: Look Snorlax is huge.
Speaker 1: He's more ripped than you.
Speaker 1: Hold ten Pokemon get out of here.
Speaker 1: You don't know nothing.
Speaker 1: It's not right.
Speaker 1: you speak at you.
Speaker 1: What do you know?
Speaker 0: While we generally don't speak that way.
Speaker 0: I mean we're like that but we're not that much like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is not a representation of what the front row crew is like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we are much more Articulate erudite erudite.
Speaker 1: That's the word that.
Speaker 1: however Listening to these guys, you know go off.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, those are my people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, honestly, I would say that in terms I mean because anime world order always talks about how different you know the geek community is and the anime community is down in like Florida and everything and RIT where we became full geeks when we ascended to.
Speaker 0: like alpha geekery We have.
Speaker 0: we realized now that it is one of the geekiest places in the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah Just about.
Speaker 0: and I would say that the average dorm room or the average Apartment in RIT that wasn't full of drunk frat guys who were the other half of RIT Was full of people exactly like that video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we used to go over and Play Mario Party with some friends quite a quite a few.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Once again, I'll reference but not speak of the bamboo story.
Speaker 1: Yes, but when we were there, you know We had schtick just like this like, you know, that's where my vision comes from.
Speaker 0: I have a vision.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have a vision of a row You know and we would let's think of some other stuff ahead of it.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 1: whenever DK showed up We'd be like DK and we had a little DK like figurine and stuff and we had a stick going on with that.
Speaker 1: And there was another stick where you know when you get in Mario Party when you're about to play a minigame It shows you like a few minigames, you know to choose from and obviously it picks randomly.
Speaker 1: but we would call out what game we wanted to play right and Very often it would land on the game.
Speaker 1: We called out and we were like is the microphone the magic microphone and it?
Speaker 1: because we didn't actually have the game cube microphone yet.
Speaker 1: This is Mario Party 4 and I think the microphone came out at Mario Party 6 or 7.
Speaker 0: Yep There was also the championship belts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had W to have championship belts to give to the winners and stuff.
Speaker 1: But you know we it was basically watching us play.
Speaker 1: Mario Party is exactly the same as those guys play watching the Pokemon movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got to say Mario Party we and Wario where we?
Speaker 0: I think we're gonna have to buy a front row crew geek nights world.
Speaker 1: Well, wwwf We WWE no, no notice.
Speaker 0: I said wwwf Geeks, that's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're gonna need some championship belts for that shit I got.
Speaker 1: why don't we just go to hot topic and get one of those belts that has an NES controller for the buckle?
Speaker 0: That would probably be perfect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's get one of those I think we're gonna have to.
Speaker 1: that way We don't give money to the stupid pro wrestling crap.
Speaker 0: and we've said it often and we'll say it again.
Speaker 0: There's a story about while wheel and whoa Competition the championship belts and most importantly the vision and bamboo.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I have a vision.
Speaker 0: I have a vision of us telling the story of bamboo, but not tonight.
Speaker 1: No, not tonight.
Speaker 1: You'll be kept in suspense for all eternity until you hear the story of the bamboo.
Speaker 0: Good God the bamboo.
Speaker 0: Good guy the bamboo is probably worse than being shot in the face with the clown pistol.
Speaker 1: You kidding I would take 30 clown pistols at point-blank before.
Speaker 0: I'll be very blunt.
Speaker 0: The bamboo was one of the worst things that has ever happened to me in my life.
Speaker 1: That's you know, that's a pretty good life at the bamboo I don't know.
Speaker 0: I still I would trade getting like shot just a little bit instead of having to ever deal with that bamboo again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: cuz I mean a little gun show just like a little gray, okay, okay Let's let this.
Speaker 1: enough of the bamboo the fucking bamboo.
Speaker 1: Let's protect ourselves with a terrible secret of space.
Speaker 1: Sorry, like so protective the terrible seat doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna go too long.
Speaker 0: You can tell tonight's episode is kind of out there.
Speaker 0: We're kind of jumping all over the place.
Speaker 1: That's what we try to do on Thursday.
Speaker 0: Give the people Yeah, you know, I mean they pen has his monkey Tuesday.
Speaker 0: We have our something Thursday.
Speaker 1: crazy ass Thursday.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think it's more the.
Speaker 0: we're tired of doing podcast all week Thursday.
Speaker 1: That's exactly what it is Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now a lot of people have wondered why Despite the fact that we are called geek nights.
Speaker 0: We are at www.frontrowcrew.com And in fact, we call ourselves the front row crew.
Speaker 1: Oh G and we get offered no explanation for this whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Well, we talked about it briefly way Way back in one of the earliest episodes of you.
Speaker 1: I think those episodes might actually dropped out of the feed.
Speaker 1: Well, that's so old.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, we can't have the feed be longer than that or feed burner will choke on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh and just so you know if Every episode of geek nights you can still find it at front row crew.
Speaker 0: calm Yes, all the way back to our inaugural episode on October 31st 2005.
Speaker 1: take note.
Speaker 0: In fact, that is generally when we change up seasons and geek nights.
Speaker 0: But we're gonna.
Speaker 1: we're gonna more on that in the future.
Speaker 1: We might.
Speaker 1: yeah I got some ideas about what we.
Speaker 0: there are also about 11 episodes from before.
Speaker 0: then That will eventually be released to people who aren't cool enough to find them on their own as bonus content.
Speaker 0: But the done even though you probably don't actually want to listen to them.
Speaker 1: No, you don't.
Speaker 1: Okay, so front row crew I was a dude and I went to high school in Connecticut and then after high school I went on this trip to Israel for 28 days and then I came back and then I went to the Rochester Institute of Technology.
Speaker 0: So I was a child and I grew was born in Detroit, Michigan.
Speaker 0: I went to school in Michigan.
Speaker 0: I lived my whole life in Michigan and then on a pretty much total whim I decided to go to RIT.
Speaker 0: and when I say total whim I mean I can do an episode about how I pretty much completely randomly chose to go to RIT.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I'm at RIT and I have some kind of roommate guy and he likes soccer a lot.
Speaker 1: You know, he's a normal cool guy.
Speaker 1: I got nothing against him.
Speaker 1: But you know, he's not a super geek.
Speaker 1: So we don't have too much in common other than you know things that every guy has in common.
Speaker 0: I have a roommate.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember his name because I'd never talked to him.
Speaker 0: He was completely uninteresting to me.
Speaker 0: We had nothing in common and we pretty much ignored each other.
Speaker 1: I only remember my roommates name because it was slightly strange.
Speaker 1: His real name was Robert, but everyone called him Tom, but he spelled his name.
Speaker 0: That's kind of common because my middle name is Tom ass, you know Thomas and Thomas is spelled th om a s. Okay, so that's why a lot of people spell Tom th om.
Speaker 1: All right, that's fun.
Speaker 1: But anyway And I'm at this college and I'm going to classes doing my thing and you know I'm looking for some friends and you know looking to get with the geeks.
Speaker 1: and the first place I go to get with the geeks is The two most obvious places to go the gaming club and the anime club.
Speaker 0: I Do the same though?
Speaker 0: I did not go to one of the early meetings of the anime club because I had Due to our it's random freshman scheduling a class that was four hours long during the anime club that I promptly dropped.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I went to the very.
Speaker 1: the first thing I went to was the very first anime club meeting at which I met Luke Yep, now all of us.
Speaker 1: he was greeting pretty much everyone who came in.
Speaker 0: now pretty much most of the front row crew at least the Core original front row crew were all at this particular meeting of the anime club, but we didn't know each other.
Speaker 1: I mean if you go back basically like I didn't really you know Make any friends at that first meeting even though I talked to a bunch of people, you know I went back to my dorm alone after the meeting.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I definitely had a good time watching some anime there.
Speaker 0: I went with my friend Ken who came to RIT with me from our high school And I mean if you would go back like, you know anime flashback and it shows like the room in Black and white like the past and all of us sitting in this big room and this huge sea of people.
Speaker 0: You can all the front row crew people have like those halos around them because destiny is about to bring them together.
Speaker 1: So it's Tuesday and it's time for the gaming club.
Speaker 1: And what do I do?
Speaker 1: I show up and I'm like, oh there's a gaming club.
Speaker 1: I bet someone there wants to play battle tech with me, which is a game I had and loved and did not get many chances to play.
Speaker 1: So I had my little battle tech box and I walk over the gaming club and I'm standing around Talking to some scary gamer types, you know, and there's this guy Katsu there and he's got this.
Speaker 1: You know, he's an Asian dude, and he's got the umbrella.
Speaker 1: He's got this Japanese style umbrella.
Speaker 1: it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: and he's talking about battle tech with me and I'm like, okay a dude, what's up?
Speaker 1: and Then you know, there's a whole bunch of other people there I'm not really talking to kind of talking to whatever and this guy comes out and he says I'm running a Dungeons & Dragons third edition campaign.
Speaker 1: And the first thing my brain says is third edition.
Speaker 1: I didn't know there was a third edition.
Speaker 0: Yeah now granted I've been playing third edition for a while already not a while But I've been playing it a little bit just because it came out pretty much right before I went to college.
Speaker 0: So I thought awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get to play D&D again.
Speaker 0: My life will not change in any significant way because D&D was a big part of my high school life.
Speaker 1: yep, and immediately I go over to this guy and I'm like I'm in and a whole bunch of other people come and say they're in a lot of people like 20 people now.
Speaker 0: of the 20 people One of them I ended up dating not the other nine baited into the background because they were worthless or at least uninteresting and Everyone else pretty much immediately became the group of friends.
Speaker 0: We didn't have a name We didn't even really recognize that we were a group of friends.
Speaker 0: yet It happened so kind of gradually and unnoticedly.
Speaker 1: Yep well I think what really Did?
Speaker 1: it is like I was sitting there and I didn't know how to make a third ed character or anything and the only ones had players handbooks.
Speaker 1: there were very few of them going around the table and We didn't have cars or anything so couldn't exactly go get more.
Speaker 1: and we didn't have money either.
Speaker 1: being freshmen.
Speaker 1: and you know There was Ken and rim and they had players handbooks.
Speaker 1: So I was you know mooching off of them and asking them questions because they knew what was going on.
Speaker 0: now Ken and I We met this this kid.
Speaker 0: we didn't know his name and he was kind of cool.
Speaker 0: He was a little uh little tactless little rude, but rude and in the you know Kind of way we like like the cool asshole kind of rude.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So so he was also noticeably Jewish Like it was kind of I mean it really came off strong.
Speaker 0: so for a while we called him that super Jew guy.
Speaker 1: I thought you got me the pimpin Jew.
Speaker 0: We called you the pimpin Jew as well.
Speaker 0: Okay, you were something Jew every time.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So we'd see it like I'd see him walking around cabs be like, hey, it's that guy yep,
Speaker 1: and then you know one day at Gracie's which is a place where freshmen eat at RIT I saw rim and Ken sitting at a table and I didn't even know they were rim and like what their names were.
Speaker 0: And yeah, none of us knew any of our names.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I just kind of walk up to them to their table with my tray after I was done eating and they were still eating.
Speaker 0: And I said, hey, and I was thinking all right.
Speaker 0: I think I have a friend in college now Yeah I think we're huh.
Speaker 0: and then over time like.
Speaker 1: and then I said hey and they were like hey.
Speaker 1: and then I just kind of Shrugged and walked away because I didn't have anything else to say to these.
Speaker 1: complete stranger.
Speaker 0: Yeah but over time like we kept.
Speaker 0: eventually it started to coalesce that bigger and bigger groups of us ended up bumping into each other at Gracie's and Eventually we started eating together kind of by chance because before I would either eat with Ken Or I'd eat alone or I ate with people from my floor.
Speaker 0: But I really didn't like any of the people from my.
Speaker 1: yeah, I think I ate with my roommate twice.
Speaker 0: They were all kind of drunken scary boring annoying people.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we had this group of people that we played D&D with you know, those of them that were freshmen that ate at Gracie's Yes and attended RIT and eating dinner together at this long table and in addition some new people who weren't playing in the game.
Speaker 0: But we met through an anime club and the gaming club started to join and it ended up being Not at any given time, but there were about 20 people who would come and go from these nightly six o'clock dinners.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: Now let's go to the anime club where the stuff really started to go down.
Speaker 1: It was like the gaming club was the starting bit.
Speaker 1: It was sort of like the starter in the car, but the anime club that was like the alternator.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the gaming club all it was great for gaming.
Speaker 0: There was very little unity and a lot of scary people.
Speaker 1: Yep, so at the anime club, it just so happened that a lot of the same people were chilling there, you know.
Speaker 1: So hey, what are you cool?
Speaker 1: So we sat near each other at the anime club and we sat near each other in the front row.
Speaker 0: For some reason we'd always sit in the front front front row and then we always made jokes about the back row people because Anyone who didn't get to the club early enough who was in our now growing friend group was forced to sit in the second row.
Speaker 1: So they were losers, obviously Yeah, we would get to club mad early and fill the front row and we would harass the eboard and he harassed the people around us.
Speaker 1: Yep, we'd yell out shit and be generally rude and hilarious.
Speaker 0: I mean it got to the point where what we'd all show up to club like clubs Club opened at 7 like that was when the room opened and club didn't start until 8.
Speaker 0: But as far as we were concerned club started at 7, that's right.
Speaker 0: So we'd show up kind of take over the room and make all sorts of mischief.
Speaker 0: The eboard was always like why are you guys always here so early?
Speaker 0: Don't you have anything better to do like homework?
Speaker 0: And we were like what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much none of us ever did schoolwork.
Speaker 1: No, we did not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look at us now highly paid technology professionals.
Speaker 0: I wonder how that happened.
Speaker 1: Take that homework All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I should go back and explain to all my professors that my no homework policy worked just fine for me.
Speaker 1: Yep Anyway, so, you know, I don't know where we actually decided to call ourselves the front row crew but long before we Self-identified as this.
Speaker 0: the executive board of the anime club called us those front row guys and eventually the front row crew.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they generally disliked us and they think that one point they wanted to get rid of us and kick us out of the club Or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah The problem with that was that we were a big part of the club at that point because us and our extended group of friends Comprised a good quarter of the people in that room.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Generally what happened is like early on in our in the life of the front row crew like at.
Speaker 1: we just go to anime club together and then we would just walk back to the dorms talking along the way in a group and Then we would just kind of stand in a group talking outside the dorms until there wasn't much more to say and then we go Back to our rooms.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the group would slowly whittle down and a lot of times ended up being me and Sometimes Katsu or Ken and this fuzzy haired guy who joined kind of later Like he didn't go to the same clubs as us, but we always saw him cuz he had this fuzzy curly hair.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we called him Trotsky.
Speaker 1: Yep But he was.
Speaker 1: that's Greg.
Speaker 0: Yeah They'd always ended up being like a few of us talking for like another hour after everyone else went upstairs or whatever their building was.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now one day I was walking back to my dorm.
Speaker 1: now the dorm I lived in was different than everyone else's and that it Was unrenovated.
Speaker 1: it was bigger.
Speaker 1: It had bigger rooms.
Speaker 1: It had nicer lounges, even though it was on renovate Bigger lounges.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: And most of all it was drugs and alcohol-free dorm, which means there weren't drunk guys vomiting in the hallways and shit.
Speaker 0: Yes as opposed to fish.
Speaker 0: be where I live where we.
Speaker 0: the slogan was we drink like fish if you if you can understand the Clever clever humor.
Speaker 1: Yep, and also the RA of my dorm DJ was the coolest dude in the RIT dorms.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, no my city of God reference my RA there is a quite a story about it was the student council president.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but not then.
Speaker 0: he was just the RA who hired strippers for the floor.
Speaker 1: Awesome, and then no wonder he became the student council president the year after.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's a whole other episode.
Speaker 1: He was an okay guy though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except he got power and then he squandered it.
Speaker 1: That's right I thought because I think he realized that he was in a position of meaningless power.
Speaker 1: He had power over things that didn't matter in the grand scope.
Speaker 1: So he had no problem using them for personal and pretty much just bought pizza for his friends.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the dorm that I walked back to that fuzzy haired guy Greg when I walked back to it He just he was walking with me the whole way and I was like, wait a minute You live in the same dorm on the same floor as me and just in a different room.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 1: How come?
Speaker 1: I had never seen you here before and he's like, huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah And that.
Speaker 1: and then I continued.
Speaker 1: I pretty much bothered him all year whenever I would just go down the hallway knock on his door And bother him a lot.
Speaker 0: Yep Now also two of the other really core core people of the crew were Pete and Alex.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were two guys who were in the D&D game and Alex is downstairs right now.
Speaker 0: And yeah, he's Calyx is currently living with us until he finds an apartment in Poughkeepsie or Beacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Pete is around somewhere and you know, they were both in the D&D game and you know We kind of we were making friends with them pretty well and we didn't realize it.
Speaker 1: Hey, they were roommates.
Speaker 1: Just by random chance Pete and Alex were roommates.
Speaker 1: two pretty similarly minded guys Just happened to be put together by RIT.
Speaker 1: What do you know?
Speaker 1: and so they were hanging out with us.
Speaker 1: and Eventually, what happened is instead of standing outside by the dorms then walking back to our rooms We'd all go back to my room have an orgy.
Speaker 1: No, we all went back to my Floor in my dorm and go to that lounge there because no one was ever in it.
Speaker 1: We'd go back to the Peterson 3 lounge and hang out there.
Speaker 0: now as time went on Now the crew got big bigger and bigger and bigger and it wasn't really called the crew It was just this huge group of like 30 people in all who we all knew and it was this kind of social group.
Speaker 0: but then as time continued there was definitely a sort of consolidation and The crew itself the front row crew formed and it was actually a small very close-knit group.
Speaker 0: And then we had the periphery which we knew and basically we never progressed beyond the stage of stand outside and talk with the periphery.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like there are people who were like friends of the crew.
Speaker 1: But then there was the core and the core didn't change much.
Speaker 0: It got to the point with the core where we would on a weekend end up in Peterson 3 pretty much Expectedly like we would all expect that everyone would be in Peterson 3 at some point on Friday and we'd stay there until 1158. then we'd run to the corner whore the corner store.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I forget that I can't use all those RIT isms.
Speaker 0: I know I know and then we'd you know buy Red Baron for cheese pizzas before they closed at midnight And we'd go back and eat him and then we'd hang out for like another couple hours.
Speaker 1: Generally what happened on an average day a week on the average weekday?
Speaker 1: if it was Monday Wednesday or Friday?
Speaker 1: Well Monday Wednesday, which are the non club days because gaming club was on Tuesday and anime club was on Thursday We would just you know, go about our daily business at dinner.
Speaker 1: Everyone would be dinner generally the same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah between 6 and 7 we'd all just kind of filter into Gracie's sitting at the same big table And then that whole table would finish eating and go to Peterson 3 and then go to bed.
Speaker 0: Yep Now the thing is staying like we'd hang out and it started out, you know around 11.
Speaker 0: We'd all go to bed and then midnight and then 1 and then 3.
Speaker 0: I got to the point where like it'd be like 4 In the morning and I'd be like I got class at 8.
Speaker 0: I should leave it within an hour or so.
Speaker 0: Yeah It got really bad.
Speaker 0: We didn't sleep at all
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then on Tuesdays we'd go to the gaming club, which was basically at you know right after the Gracie's we went to the gaming club and we would game and game and game and play D&D and then after D&D we'd go to Applebee's
Speaker 0: and Get the half-off appetizers at
Speaker 1: the half-off appetizers on Tuesday nights And then after that we would go to Peters and three and then we would go to bed.
Speaker 1: eventually Thursdays, it was a similar thing.
Speaker 1: We'd go to anime club.
Speaker 1: then we might or might not eat out at Jay's diner.
Speaker 1: We usually add out of Jay's as long as we had money Yep, and then we went back to Peters and three and hung out and this is all freshman year, by the way now weekends Consisted of utter chaos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I mean Friday night, it's like oh, it's Friday night.
Speaker 1: go to Peters and three.
Speaker 1: No, no, they wouldn't leave Peters and three until Sunday night.
Speaker 0: now notice that there is no time in here For homework or classes.
Speaker 0: nothing literally and I am I'm not exaggerating at all.
Speaker 0: Class time was between 10 o'clock and 4 o'clock Monday through Thursday and with few exceptions.
Speaker 0: No one ever did schoolwork or had classes outside of those times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, generally and none of us had jobs for the longest time except for the people who worked at Gracie's.
Speaker 1: Well now what were we doing in Peters and three all this time?
Speaker 1: Well here an example of some of our.
Speaker 1: here's an example some of our activities.
Speaker 1: Activity number one watching anime.
Speaker 1: We watched so much and we had no less than I think five anime marathons.
Speaker 1: he watched all of escaflowne all of Evangeline all of KO century KO century be such a short.
Speaker 1: you watched all of the El Hazzard OAV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we watched a whole ton of movies a whole ton of anime movies.
Speaker 1: Lots of Lupin Cuz.
Speaker 1: remember a lot of stuff that I fell asleep during.
Speaker 0: the RIT anime club has one of the largest anime libraries I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Yep, and we just took lots of anime out of it and watched as much as we could on Crappy as VCR and a tiny TV and we would play a lot of Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 1: We played a lot of D&D and we played a lot of other RPGs as well.
Speaker 1: We played kobalt ate my baby in Peterson 3.
Speaker 0: we played a lot of video games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, generally most of the time we played N64 stuff because that's the system we had.
Speaker 1: we didn't have a GameCube yet.
Speaker 1: That would come the next year and So we played Smash Brothers and Mario Party and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I think we even played some Atari action.
Speaker 0: We would also often just sit in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we sat in there and talked and hung out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly talking and hanging out.
Speaker 1: Oh and most of all we played fucking battle tech fucking goddamn.
Speaker 0: We used to break into other places to play battle tech because they had nicer tables or just because we were bored.
Speaker 0: like a lot of times if we Ran out of anything to do or if we were just talking we'd serve wandering around campus and we'd talk while we wander.
Speaker 0: but it was just like we were sitting in the dorms who's happened to be walking around and The moment we found an unsecured conference room.
Speaker 0: That was when the battle tech got broken up and whatever that room was.
Speaker 1: Yeah We played a battle tech for hours and hours and hours and always crazy stuff happened like the quad legged mech that wouldn't die Yeah, or the pristine mech that got hit in the head with the Gauss rifle and blew up.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yep, all that kind of crazy awesomeness that battle tech brings with it.
Speaker 0: So in addition to all that in Peterson 3 remember I said we did schoolwork between 10 and 4 Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: We did something else during that time and that was play Counter-strike.
Speaker 0: lots of counter-strike pretty much any moment and then tribes 2 and then when tribes 2 died Counter-strike again any moment where we were not in a class that we could not skip Hanging out with everyone or sleeping.
Speaker 0: We were playing counter-strike or tribes 2.
Speaker 1: Yep That was a good freshman year.
Speaker 1: That was just freshman year.
Speaker 1: Wait till you hear what happens the rest of the years of college.
Speaker 0: God, we'll have to do separate shows about all the head.
Speaker 1: Yep The point of it is the front row crew is a group of awesome people who met Freshman year at the Rochester Institute of Technology and Remained awesome and together until today.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's honestly to not we we all consider each other family at this point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much I mean I consider the crew to be no different than my blood relatives.
Speaker 1: Yep, and front row crew comm is a website that Will host the exploits of the entire front row crew not just geek nights.
Speaker 0: Hopefully, I mean eventually if if other people start making awesome things and not being shit talkers, huh?
Speaker 0: They're gonna be all sorts of something.
Speaker 0: dot front row crew comm.
Speaker 1: yeah, like if someone makes by the by.
Speaker 1: Yeah if someone were to make say another podcast or a webcomic in the front row crew or if we were to open front row crew Studios actually got to making some anime music videos those would be you know at like studios.
Speaker 1: dot front row crew comm.
Speaker 1: you know Geek nights is just the premier central deal right now But hopefully we will expand in the somewhat distant future as we get our shit together.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I mean in college though I mean, it wasn't just the fact that we became such close friends that we all had very very similar interests.
Speaker 0: I mean, we were all fans of HP Lovecraft.
Speaker 0: We were all fans of anime.
Speaker 0: We were all fans.
Speaker 1: I actually didn't know what HP Lovecraft was till everyone told me but then I became a fan of it.
Speaker 0: There was a point at which you read Call of Cthulhu to all the freshmen when we were seniors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, there were other people there too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't finish reading it either.
Speaker 1: Everyone fell asleep.
Speaker 0: But we were also a group of people that as our extended crew Pretty much put all of our effort into hanging out and having fun with friends.
Speaker 1: And what do we do today?
Speaker 0: We hang out and have fun with friends.
Speaker 1: We got them.
Speaker 0: it is not a lie to say that we put more effort into Hanging out.
Speaker 0: then we put into all of our schoolwork combined.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and We all we do today is we go to big-ass Conventions and hang out and we try to find new people to hang out with.
Speaker 1: and we hang out with the old people I mean.
Speaker 0: or geek nights, what do we do?
Speaker 0: We're basically doing the same thing we'd be doing if we were just hanging out without microphones and there was anyone to listen to us.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean if for anyone who stopped by our hotel room at Otacon and for anyone who heard about it You know, there were a lot of freaking people in there.
Speaker 1: That was front row crew all those people.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you know you were doing hanging out.
Speaker 0: our lives consists wholly of hanging out.
Speaker 0: Everything else is just pursuant to being able to hang out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if I don't eat I can't hang out cuz I'll be dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I want to eat I gotta buy food.
Speaker 0: She means I could have a job I gotta make money and a lot of times we will go places and do things.
Speaker 0: But we do these things mostly to give us a new context in which to hang out.
Speaker 0: Yep, cuz hanging out in the same context repeatedly as we know from doing it for five or six years I mean like some night we'd want we go to downtown Rochester and wander around at night hanging out.
Speaker 0: or We'd wander around the campus hanging out or we'd bust into the liberal arts building at night Hanging out and every Thursday we hung out in the front row.
Speaker 1: And that made us the front row crew.
Speaker 0: so that you now know the terrible secret of our origin We'll have to shove you down the stairs.
Speaker 0: There will be many episodes in the future.
Speaker 0: at some point We'd like to get each and every member of the front row crew on it interview them Separately as to what they think the front row crew is and what I think.
Speaker 1: we just get one show with Everyone and then we can just go around and you know introduce everyone.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of be like a cast of characters type of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like a who's who in the front row crew I mean, I'm a poet.
Speaker 1: No, I don't know it.
Speaker 0: The thing is the front row crew grows, but not quickly at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we have a lot of friends.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of people who know us.
Speaker 0: I mean if you go to Otacon, it's kind of scary how many people are like, hey Scott.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Hey Riff.
Speaker 0: Hey we we have a lot of friends but To actually be considered a member of the front row crew that is pretty much a level of total and unmitigated trust.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: I mean we people from the crew have an open invite to stay in our house at any time and we don't even think twice About it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like if someone just showed up, I'd be like, hey, what's up?
Speaker 1: You know, even if they live far away like Texas or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we know that if we what we suddenly appeared in, Texas James and Lisa would say hey come in and then we'd probably watch some anime or play a game and then sleep on their floor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if someone was like an acquaintance and they showed up at the door be like, hey What are you doing here?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, I might let him in but not just like.
Speaker 1: hey, what's up?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if your mom showed up at the door you open up and go.
Speaker 1: hi What's doing, you know, but if some if I showed up at the door, you'd be like, hey, who are you?
Speaker 1: It's that borderline that is crossed with the the front row crew.
Speaker 1: However, the front row crew does decrease rapidly if Stupid people are cut out right quick.
Speaker 1: And everything is is all the stupid people right now are already cut out.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is that when remember and I said that the group kind of coalesced and Concentrated and we kind of made the bear like we formed we spontaneously generated social life.
Speaker 0: there was the sea of people that were connected like this giant protein thing and eventually the front row crew came together and formed a cell membrane, yep, and With one exception.
Speaker 0: No one has ever left or no longer been considered a part of the front row crew Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It really can't happen.
Speaker 1: you Yeah, it's like peep, you know anyone who was cut off was basically not all the way in the crew yet They were outside the cell membrane and then we just kind of squirted some toxins at them.
Speaker 0: Yeah They were basically a person we hung out with who for whatever reason either wouldn't go away or we just didn't trust or like enough They actually be considered to the crew.
Speaker 0: You really have to be awesome in our eyes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I are I don't mean me and Scott I mean by everyone in the crew Mm-hmm, and I mean there are plenty of people who are like my friend But everyone else is just an acquaintance to them and you know, we don't see them so much.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean we we put a lot of thought into it.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess we really don't know.
Speaker 1: It's sort of just a common sense type of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now that I think about it It's just common sense and you know who your friends are.
Speaker 1: You don't like think about it logic.
Speaker 1: Well, a lot of people do really yeah, that's kind of freaky.
Speaker 0: I mean look at all the people who like friend and D friend people in my space and then bitch about each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't have that shit.
Speaker 1: if you're that kind of person you ain't in.
Speaker 0: yeah, there's no drama In the crew between crew members ever.
Speaker 1: it goes with my you know, theory of stupidity and drama.
Speaker 1: There can only be drama if there is stupidity.
Speaker 0: Yes, and we don't put up with drama.
Speaker 0: So over the years we've not put up as a crew with anyone who caused drama.
Speaker 0: So as a result, we'll have 20 people with us at Otacon and it works out great because no one fights with anyone.
Speaker 1: There's no drama because there's no one stupid.
Speaker 0: But then we see you know, all these other groups of people trying to have hotel rooms Otacon.
Speaker 0: There's all crazy drama.
Speaker 0: people don't pay people don't show up people break up with people and then have fights.
Speaker 1: We don't deal with that shit.
Speaker 0: All right, we're like Snorlax.
Speaker 1: We kicked your ass to the back row.
Speaker 1: Okay, I think that covers it.
Speaker 0: Wow, we really need some sort of way to end this because we just keep talking.
Speaker 1: Snorlax could beat up the whole front row crew.
Speaker 1: Look at that Snorlax IV fuck.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think Pete could beat up Snorlax.
Speaker 1: Do you know how big Snorlax is?
Speaker 1: You don't know shit about Pokemon, do you?
Speaker 0: Do you know how big Pete is?
Speaker 0: Pete is ripped.
Speaker 1: He's no more ripped than Snorlax.
Speaker 0: He might be.
Speaker 1: No, he couldn't hold ten Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Pete has the power of his Viking ancestors.
Speaker 1: Don't be shit in the face of some Pokemons.
Speaker 0: Alright, we're done And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: If you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.