Speaker 0: It's Monday June 26th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We cop out and just do a tech news roundup which means we didn't have a good topic for today.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So my car needs an oil change.
Speaker 1: well it needed an oil change.
Speaker 0: It's needed one for a while hasn't it?
Speaker 1: yeah I just whenever I need an oil change.
Speaker 1: I just I never get it when I need to.
Speaker 1: it's always way late.
Speaker 0: See I used to not have to worry because I commuted.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: eight miles every day
Speaker 1: That's one of the things I like about the car I got is that any oil change place will tell you 3,000 miles, but the car dealer when I went to Look test drive the car He said 7,000 miles, and then if you look in the actual book from the car It says something like the normal maintenance schedule is 7,000 in the like.
Speaker 1: the better maintenance schedule is 5,000.
Speaker 1: So I went 6,000.
Speaker 0: that's pretty good alright, so you did the one thing that wasn't listed anywhere.
Speaker 1: yep exactly but Yeah, usually I go get oil changes at valvoline And I had.
Speaker 1: you know the problem is the closest valvoline is a little out of the way And I didn't have time to go to it over the weekend, so I went after work today And they didn't have filters for my car air filters.
Speaker 0: You know I remember Ken used to run into that oil filter not air filter because he had an intrigue.
Speaker 0: Which take to take a bit at a big oil pan took a weird filter and all sorts of fun stuff.
Speaker 1: So I saw this other place on the road that said oil change car wash, and it looked pretty nice You know, but it was sort of generic.
Speaker 1: I went there anyway, and the people were nice and the place was nice, but they kind of sucked.
Speaker 0: yeah I probably I could have warned you.
Speaker 0: I've never been to that place But just looking at it gave me the vibe of no one goes there for an oil change.
Speaker 1: Actually, it was real crowded like there were a lot of people there.
Speaker 0: That's weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but It just took forever to change my goddamn oil and They didn't do Like.
Speaker 1: they didn't even show me the dipstick after they changed the oil.
Speaker 1: I had to ask Valvoline just comes and shows it to you whether you ask or not and most people go.
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: and So I was like you're gonna show me the dipstick.
Speaker 1: so I know that you put oil in my car before I give you money maybe.
Speaker 1: and Then they got like some sort of green you know oil on my windshield and shit.
Speaker 1: It just wasn't good.
Speaker 1: They sucked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, meanwhile I go to.
Speaker 0: I don't go to Valvoline anymore either but I found this place in the Bronx right near one of the hospitals I work at and Not only are they cheaper than Valvoline by like eight or nine bucks and not only are they fast and awesome and real quick and All that but I get a discount because I work at the hospital.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there really just isn't a place anywhere near me to go.
Speaker 1: do that like nowhere.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: You could drive up to the Valvoline.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the closest place, and I went there, and they didn't.
Speaker 0: you know there's a Valvoline right across the river in Newberg, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not on my way home.
Speaker 1: That's out of my way.
Speaker 0: It's a lot closer than driving up Route 9 in rush hour traffic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but it also costs an extra dollar to go over there.
Speaker 0: Oh, no a dolly whatever we like to do What are you said?
Speaker 0: if something costs less than five dollars?
Speaker 0: It's free.
Speaker 0: No you always talking Oh, it's less than if it's below certain amounts of money.
Speaker 0: You decide whatever it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It's effectively free not if it's nothing not if there's a Valvoline on this side of the river.
Speaker 1: than zero dollars.
Speaker 0: I submit that the gas you use driving up Route 9.
Speaker 1: It's not that far up Route 9 No, it's not that far distance wise but the traffic and the lights under there really wasn't traffic and lights today.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's kind of went whoosh.
Speaker 0: Usually there are especially at rush hour.
Speaker 0: I tried to drive up that road before back when I used to live in Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 1: not enough problem.
Speaker 0: It took me usually about an hour to drive to Poughkeepsie from where I work going up Route 9 Five minutes to get to the Valvoline On the exit.
Speaker 0: usually that roads just back backed up.
Speaker 1: No, no problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well usually Anyway, you got a news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's some news.
Speaker 1: is that dig upgraded today.
Speaker 1: Finally.
Speaker 0: All I got to say is whoopty shit.
Speaker 0: It looks the same it acts the same.
Speaker 0: I all I'd all.
Speaker 0: the only reason I noticed cuz my RSS broke Yeah, and I just deleted it.
Speaker 0: I didn't bother re-adding it.
Speaker 1: Well what they've done That's good that you might not notice.
Speaker 1: this is really two changes that are well three changes.
Speaker 1: The first change is kind of silly and meaningless.
Speaker 1: Is that if something gets dug a shit ton that it gets this little like green sort of star near it.
Speaker 1: So it's like this is a crazy story.
Speaker 1: That's big deal.
Speaker 1: Secondly the the big thing is that they've added more sections.
Speaker 1: dig used to be just tech news now It's tech science world and business videos entertainment and gaming and then there are subcategories as well.
Speaker 1: And if you log in you can change your preferences so that you get rid of certain categories.
Speaker 1: For example, I got rid of the science health category is 99% of that category is just Randy bullshit And I'm tired of looking at it.
Speaker 1: It's just people saying oh my god, this causes cancer when it doesn't.
Speaker 1: or oh my god.
Speaker 1: Here's an amazing panacea.
Speaker 1: No, it's not And I'm like get the hell out of my face.
Speaker 0: I guess I just I don't like dig that much and I only ever go there If I'm either really idle and I have nothing in the world to do which isn't really an occurrence anymore Or I'm desperate for news and I couldn't find anything on any of the other sites I go to.
Speaker 0: I go to dig is the last resort.
Speaker 0: I'll find something here.
Speaker 0: I just I don't like the comments.
Speaker 0: I don't like the community and the stories 99% of them that are worth reading appear on Fark and slash dot.
Speaker 1: anyway Yeah, you know Fark slash dot all that stuff appears everywhere.
Speaker 1: eventually, you know, it's just dig is like the.
Speaker 1: It goes there first there's greater quantity.
Speaker 0: I would submit that it probably goes to Fark right about the same time.
Speaker 0: It goes to dig.
Speaker 1: maybe You know, but the I don't read the comments on dig at all.
Speaker 0: So there's a thing I go to such for the comments.
Speaker 0: I go to slash dot for the comments now go to Fark for the comments And I just go to get links to the actual story, which I then read.
Speaker 0: I usually read the comments first and then I read the story.
Speaker 1: Yes very most of the comments on dig are becoming more and more Fark like or Or they're meta comments saying don't dig this dig this.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Something like that is definitely not becoming Fark like because surprisingly Many of the posts on Fark are very informative about the article in question Not quite so much as slash dot.
Speaker 0: but it's that it's sad.
Speaker 0: It's really weird to me that Fark intellectually definitely seems a step up from dig.
Speaker 1: Well dig has the comments.
Speaker 1: are you know now that this moderation, you know There are comments in there that are informative about the topic.
Speaker 1: The problem is there's also a lot of people who don't know what they're taught.
Speaker 1: This is generally the same problem with dig comments.
Speaker 1: The same problem with dig is that if there's an article but you know Even though if it's false of a if it's popular it gets dug up.
Speaker 1: So even if someone says something that's factually incorrect in the dig comments it goes up.
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 0: Remember when we were at a penguin and we met what's-his-name from slash dot?
Speaker 0: Yep, and Actually, we we had.
Speaker 0: we talked to him for a while because the panel was basically him and us and some quiet nerds who were real shy and they didn't really talk.
Speaker 0: so basically just us talking to the dude.
Speaker 0: and at one point we asked him how come there isn't a moderation tag for like?
Speaker 0: this is false or this is untrue or The information this post is bullshit and his reason was perhaps the the least expected reason he could have ever given for that.
Speaker 1: It's because he couldn't find a single word for it.
Speaker 0: I mean I said why don't you use factually hyphen incorrect?
Speaker 0: and he balked at it.
Speaker 1: Notice how all the moderation things on slash dot are insightful interesting in form.
Speaker 1: They're all I words except for troll and flame bait and flame bait and underrated overrated funny and funny.
Speaker 1: Other than almost half of all the good ones begin with.
Speaker 1: I all the ones you all the ones you want funny is good.
Speaker 1: No, not that good.
Speaker 0: I go for funny.
Speaker 1: I don't go for funny, but he wouldn't.
Speaker 0: he knows he needs that tag.
Speaker 0: He's wanted that tag for years.
Speaker 0: He can't come up with a one word that means that concept other than like now because anything else he would.
Speaker 1: there are words like false or incorrect or lying or anything like that, but the problem is all those words have other connotations and the Tag won't.
Speaker 1: the moderation won't be used properly.
Speaker 0: if he uses those words I say you should just bit the bullet and said factually - incorrect.
Speaker 1: That's what I say.
Speaker 1: But that's the one thing that's wrong with dig is that you know most the Chaff gets weeded out for the most part and the good stuff goes up for the most part and the duplicates get weeded out Almost a hundred percent, but there's stuff that's just wrong.
Speaker 0: and because the masses are not experts Shit, that's false goes up and actually the moderation system makes this worse even in the comments because I've noticed whenever there's a terribly Stupid Randy on dig like oh lol apple seeds cure cancer lol one.
Speaker 0: yeah exactly now in Articles like that I've seen that the people on dig who post and say this is crap.
Speaker 0: This is a stupid fake story.
Speaker 0: Those people get dug down because they're you know, they're they're raining on the parade on FARC.
Speaker 0: Nothing can get run down.
Speaker 0: So whenever an article is crap all the people who say it's crap and are right are right there in your face And you realize right away.
Speaker 0: You can just skip the article.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: You don't get that in dig.
Speaker 1: Nope, but see on dig if I'm smart, so first of all Before I had to deal with all those stories But I was smart enough to say this is obviously a fake story and it's lying.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna ignore it now.
Speaker 1: I don't see those stories cuz I got rid of that subcategory.
Speaker 0: I don't see it anymore, which is great Yeah, but you should have still gone in and railed against him and dug down all the people who said good things.
Speaker 1: It's not worth my time It's really not.
Speaker 0: honestly, I got the same thing going with slash dot now as much as I love it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've had God how five ten fifty twenty.
Speaker 0: I had almost 40 moderator points on slash dot in the past three weeks.
Speaker 1: There's the other thing they added to dig which is which is actually I think the best part is undig.
Speaker 1: before you can make Friends, but now it's actually useful.
Speaker 1: You make friends with people and people make friends with you and now on the left side of the screen It will give you your friends activity in the last 48 hours.
Speaker 1: It'll give you the number of stories dug by your friends the number of stories that your friends dug that you also dug The number of stories your friends dug that aren't yet on the front page that are upcoming stories The number of stories your friends commented on and the number of stories your friends submitted.
Speaker 1: Then you can click on any one of those things to see which stories your friends dug Which stories your friends and you agreed on etc, etc?
Speaker 1: Huh, so that way, you know If you make a network of friends who all use dig you can just completely ignore the stories on dig itself.
Speaker 1: And it's sort of like a delicious but with the popular element more powered up and easier to use and with only guys That's right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the statistics show that 94% of dig users are male.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta find me some dig ladies That 6% is out there.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: No, you know what?
Speaker 0: 94% are males 6% are males who lie about their gender.
Speaker 0: damn it Dig is really kind.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I won't get into that.
Speaker 0: We're this isn't a show about dig.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, so talk about another thing.
Speaker 0: I don't like live journal.
Speaker 0: I don't like life really Well, I like the idea of live journal because live journal was a blog before blogs really totally all real.
Speaker 1: All live journal really is is blogging software.
Speaker 0: It's no different than say WordPress or My space or other than the fact that it's old and it had a large active and very Inward looking community.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's it's simply a blog software But the way it's designed is that all the bloggers are sort of linked into this giant blob called live journal.
Speaker 0: You know as opposed to your nose blob, I learned something interesting, you know, live journal has live journal syndication, right?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's basically like RSS but only for in live journal.
Speaker 0: Yep, more people use that then use RSS Probably like I mean Otakon is in a live journal syndication and an RSS feed and I've heard numerous people note that it seems like Many more people use the live journal syndication.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Why do you just keep stepping on your chair?
Speaker 1: What you were like tapping your foot on your chair and make it squeak while you talked like that.
Speaker 0: Yes, it doesn't get picked up by the microphone and I always fiddle around with my feet.
Speaker 1: It's annoying cuz it was making the squeaking.
Speaker 0: you want to talk about annoying things Mr.
Speaker 0: Breathes into the microphone constantly.
Speaker 0: Anyway live journal that that den of iniquity that seething pit from which no traveler returns Has one more reason to be hated and despised.
Speaker 0: Now a little while ago They added a thing where there's an ad supported live journal thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know all the details but they ran ads in live journal.
Speaker 0: It just so happens that some of the ads they ran were put in by evil people.
Speaker 0: they were filled with Malware.
Speaker 0: if you were running Internet Explorer and Windows you got spyware Just by visiting live journal or using live journal.
Speaker 1: awesome It's.
Speaker 0: this specific one seemed to only attack Non United States live journal users in a in an attempt to get around some of the checking that live journal does.
Speaker 0: But there's really no technological reason why they couldn't have just attacked live journal users in the u.s..
Speaker 1: Wow That's kind of weird and crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually live journal does do a lot of testing on their ads But they obviously one didn't do enough.
Speaker 1: and two they must have accepted ads from shady people Because obviously they're needing some money because myspace and others are probably kicking their ass Now.
Speaker 0: slash shot even got hit by this once a long long time ago, but in this day and age There's no excuse.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm if you I mean you can't you're gonna Do ads.
Speaker 1: you do ads for a reputable source like Google or Yahoo or you know a real ad company?
Speaker 1: You don't do those shady ad companies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even like ad click isn't that shady?
Speaker 0: yep good God I?
Speaker 1: Mean some of them will make pop-ups or something.
Speaker 1: But you know or pop behinds or poker ads or porn ads but the spyware ones.
Speaker 1: That's the shadiest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm still not too up on this whole ad concept.
Speaker 0: I mean I haven't seen an ad on the internet in what like five years.
Speaker 1: This is big white area at the top of the new dig.
Speaker 1: I wonder what goes there.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They must have just left that white there some sort of artistic.
Speaker 1: I don't know why they did that.
Speaker 1: It's kind of strange.
Speaker 0: Yeah all of you out there right now one if you don't have Firefox to get Firefox then go get the Firefox ad block extension.
Speaker 0: then Either right click on every ad you see and make it go away or run the filter.
Speaker 1: G filter set G updater.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah One of them requires more effort however.
Speaker 0: one of them prevents you from playing Kingdom of Loathing in its full glory.
Speaker 1: Only accidentally you can fix that all right now.
Speaker 0: I like birds and This video is just amazing and hilarious.
Speaker 1: and birdie?
Speaker 0: now There's this flock of starlings in this video and a lot of starling.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of birds like they could blot out the Sun handily a hagilian birds.
Speaker 0: And there's this tiny tree Hitchcock's the birds this tiny little tree.
Speaker 0: and these birds are Circling and circling and circling and then they all try it again into this tiny tree to the point that it Bends over to the point where it's gonna break.
Speaker 0: then suddenly the tree snapped back and they all fly away.
Speaker 1: I think it's.
Speaker 1: they leave the tree, and then it snaps back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know exactly what prompts them to leave the tree But the thing is they circle they land on the tree it bends it snaps up They fly away, and they keep doing this over and over and ever.
Speaker 0: they just really want to get into this tree.
Speaker 1: I think they want to break the tree.
Speaker 0: Honestly my best guess is that the birds are really enjoying what's going on, and they're doing it for fun.
Speaker 1: Maybe or maybe they're just birds doing their mindless bird shit now.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of smart birds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're like owls.
Speaker 0: Oh really.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really But it's just.
Speaker 0: this is a really interesting video to watch because honestly when I used to live in New Baltimore We had there wasn't starlings.
Speaker 0: we had birds would do this our backyard instead of having we had a normal fence.
Speaker 0: But instead of having a privacy fence or anything we had huge hedges that surrounded the entire backyard.
Speaker 0: They were very tall.
Speaker 0: Every evening in the summer just millions of birds would descend upon them and then squawk around and fly around and fight and make a god-awful racket all evening long.
Speaker 0: It's like that times a million.
Speaker 1: I Just think it's cool that so there's so many little tiny birds that it causes a tree to bend over More than like I could pull it if I wanted.
Speaker 0: I just wonder if the birds realize like if they figured out What was going on in any dimness because starlings aren't the smartest of birds.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much just fire.
Speaker 1: What do they eat just like bugs and twigs?
Speaker 0: now the best part of this is while we were looking at this and then we learned something about demoic acid poisoning and We learned and Alex actually looked this up over the weekend.
Speaker 0: I don't remember all the details, but you know Alfred Hitchcock's the birds right mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's based on a true story Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that but apparently this flock of sea birds was Poisoned by this diatom poison that's in algae or something and they went nuts and they came to shore and just attacked people until they all died.
Speaker 0: Whoa, and it was this crazy thing.
Speaker 0: if any of you out there want to dig up the article again post it in the forums We'll have a good look, but yeah Alfred Hitchcock's the birds was based on a real-life event.
Speaker 1: Did not know that?
Speaker 0: yeah none of us did.
Speaker 0: and Watch the video cuz it's really cool.
Speaker 1: and watch the movie cuz it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: and actually the guy's blog I linked to this is his second video of birds flocking and someone suggested in his comments Why don't you make a separate blog just for bird flocking videos?
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, you'll be the most popular thing on the internets.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: No there's funny animal blog Meow meow.
Speaker 1: Okay, okay, so there's Always good things to see and laugh at on Japanese television.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: This is probably the best of them yet.
Speaker 0: So I laughed at this more than I laughed at hard gay.
Speaker 1: There's a guy.
Speaker 1: it was a crazy TV show.
Speaker 1: It's usual a typical crazy Japanese TV show crazy.
Speaker 1: And they have some porta-potties.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be comedy coming up with porta-potties.
Speaker 1: You know that and
Speaker 0: I this is what I love about non United States countries because I noticed in Japan and in Europe and In Brazil, I don't know why I said Brazil specifically, but in all these countries and all these places I see TV shows that are practical joke shows
Speaker 1: And they
Speaker 0: pull amazing crazy practical jokes that if you tried to pull that shit in the u.s.
Speaker 0: You just get sued.
Speaker 1: you get sued because the people you did it to it would be you know your heart.
Speaker 1: They're literally just harming people and ruining people.
Speaker 1: and yeah Like take it.
Speaker 1: if someone's like afraid of spiders, they'll dump them in a spider pit.
Speaker 1: It's like you can't can't do that shit in the u.s..
Speaker 0: What if that girl who's afraid of pickles?
Speaker 1: That's that's the worst you can do in the u.s.. And I'm surprised she didn't sue cuz that was obviously fake.
Speaker 1: That's why you know it's like.
Speaker 1: you can only do that in the u.s.
Speaker 1: If it's fake, and if you know it's designed to make you feel sympathetic towards the person in Japan.
Speaker 1: You know if you're afraid of pickles They'll dump you in a pickle vat and then they'll all the whole country will laugh at you.
Speaker 0: so uh Describe what happens.
Speaker 0: cuz I'll do the lead-off.
Speaker 0: you know guy walks up, and he has to pay.
Speaker 1: well first They actually see the reason that you had a better experience watching it.
Speaker 1: This is I fast-forwarded over the beginning part that explained what they were gonna do in Japanese.
Speaker 1: Yes, but they also had pictures.
Speaker 1: gets a video.
Speaker 0: See I didn't know what was going on so I know that's why it was funnier for you.
Speaker 1: I did that on purpose.
Speaker 0: all I saw was a dude and he has to pee and he goes to the porta potty and he opens It.
Speaker 0: he goes in he closes it and he squats down over the thing and then there starts a 10-second countdown and Once it hits like five seconds these lights start counting down next to him and It gets to.
Speaker 0: it's like red red red red And just as the green one turns on he looks at it And he has this look like I wonder what that light is and then suddenly the
Speaker 1: roof of the porta potty Opens up the sunlight shines in and a lift brings the toilet him The roll of toilet paper on a stand and anything else in the porta potty Straight out to the roof of the porta potty and he's standing up there Squatting on the squat toilet for all to see.
Speaker 0: he has no idea what to do.
Speaker 1: He's the most stunned human being I've ever seen and I'm not gonna spoil the rest of this video But it gets better than that.
Speaker 0: they do one.
Speaker 0: they do it to a lot of people.
Speaker 0: They do it to a lot of people in all these different places, but then they go one step further.
Speaker 1: They hurt people in the one in the one step further.
Speaker 0: yeah the one dude falls off.
Speaker 1: Watch this whole video.
Speaker 0: This is fantastic.
Speaker 1: I recommend also for added humor like Try to skip around that way that you don't see the explanations of what they're about to do before they do it.
Speaker 1: That way you get the effect of oh my god look what just happened in addition to the oh my god.
Speaker 1: They actually did what they said they were just gonna do.
Speaker 0: Hey All right, so we wanted to do it.
Speaker 0: he sucked today.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah We were gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: we were gonna do the next part three of how computers work which was flip-flops and neither one of us Really wanted to talk in excruciating detail about flip-flops.
Speaker 1: Blame that on the summer the weekend come on.
Speaker 1: It's a four day a week show.
Speaker 1: You can't you know?
Speaker 1: yell at us for anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus.
Speaker 0: We had a quite a mentally exhausting weekend.
Speaker 0: We played a pile of board games.
Speaker 1: good for tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I will say I got a gloat a little bit at the Mars meeting.
Speaker 0: We went to where we play the board games.
Speaker 0: I went undefeated in one every single game.
Speaker 0: We played all three of them.
Speaker 0: Yep, not just one, but one like other than anyone three games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Attica was close, but I I had more points than all of you combined in that stupid Timbuktu game guys.
Speaker 1: See if it's him like to be.
Speaker 0: yeah But that was honest.
Speaker 1: if I would have knew what I was doing in the first round it would have been close.
Speaker 1: Yep But I Did every other round just fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that'll be a story for tomorrow.
Speaker 0: That's quite hilarious Yep, anyway in addition to that.
Speaker 0: You know it's summer.
Speaker 0: It's hot as hell.
Speaker 0: It still hasn't really rained here Mm-hmm so we're going to do what we always do when we can't come up with a topic to do on a Monday Tech news roundup you can just call this twit nights.
Speaker 1: But before we do a tech news roundup I I wanted to talk about you know my new switch to Ubuntu Ubuntu and Some other things related to that and it really it can't give a whole show to that.
Speaker 1: cuz then rim is just gonna sit there Not talking.
Speaker 0: the only option we had was that I could talk about my Mac experience But I want to do a whole show on that like a month from now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when it's not so close to the Mac sucks experience show.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz I want to talk about the non Podcasting aspect of Mac which I really like.
Speaker 0: yeah, I just don't like the podcasting.
Speaker 1: okay, so I'm my Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: one thing.
Speaker 1: I just did the other day Ubuntu as I set up XGL.
Speaker 1: now if you don't know X X is the X windowing system.
Speaker 1: This is what makes the graphics and the gooeys and the clicking and the mouse and the windows on Linux.
Speaker 1: You don't need to know more than that unless you're not yeah You have Linux which is just the lowest part of the operating system And you know you get a command line on a black screen with white text.
Speaker 0: X is old as hell and Incredibly difficult to understand.
Speaker 1: yeah X is the thing that makes the gooeys appear and makes it look like a usable computer.
Speaker 1: It's so archaic, but now there's X org, and I'm not gonna explain anymore.
Speaker 1: But it's not as bad as it was and it's getting better and all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah What no nice little hint.
Speaker 0: if you ever make sure if you ever make a new Linux box or anything that you're using X org.
Speaker 0: If you're using Ubuntu You know that you're using X org, but if you're a red hat, dude.
Speaker 1: Well red hat.
Speaker 1: I think pretty much everything uses X org.
Speaker 1: now X for 86?
Speaker 1: honestly No except for old shit red hat.
Speaker 0: Enterprise 3 uses X free 86.
Speaker 0: Uh the most updated one because that's what I had to use when I worked at IBM.
Speaker 0: Uh unless Red Hat Enterprise 4 uses something else.
Speaker 0: I don't know it was painful.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway, so There's a thing called X GL.
Speaker 1: It's actually made by Novell.
Speaker 1: I think it's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't like Novell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well Novell's not so bad.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: I don't like Novell NetWare.
Speaker 1: No no Novell NetWare is bad.
Speaker 1: the company is a little different, but What it does is it takes X. it does the same thing X does.
Speaker 1: it's actually an add-on to X and it makes X go With OpenGL.
Speaker 1: so your video card is doing all the work of X instead of your CPU.
Speaker 1: That's good because you have this GPU in your computer might as well use it, and you know save some CPU cycles for other stuff.
Speaker 1: As a result there's mad eye candy mad eye candy I gotta say.
Speaker 0: Scott's XGL, which I looked at for like a second is At least as shiny as what my Mac can do.
Speaker 1: hell it kicks the shit out of that Mac in terms of eye candy Except for the front row.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the real pretty.
Speaker 0: not so useful, but real pretty.
Speaker 1: the front row.
Speaker 1: I think is more useful than it is pretty.
Speaker 0: We have some trouble with it though the only.
Speaker 1: we have a little bit of trouble, but not much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that might just be.
Speaker 1: a problem I have with the front row is that it's not responsive enough.
Speaker 1: like I push the button I have to wait for it to show up.
Speaker 1: If it showed up as soon as I push the button then it would be perfect.
Speaker 0: I also want to be able to customize it and add more stuff to it.
Speaker 1: That would also be cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe maybe we can and we just don't know how.
Speaker 0: yeah, we have.
Speaker 0: we're not saying you can we just haven't tried yet Yep, but anyway There we're talking I can't like.
Speaker 1: when you move windows around in XGL they wobble and you can modify the amount of wobbling.
Speaker 1: and if you resize windows they wobble and icons kind of Animate and when things fold up they kind of go whoosh.
Speaker 1: and when applications close they fade to the.
Speaker 1: they kind of go whoosh Into the background.
Speaker 0: important thing is the cube the cube.
Speaker 1: So when you normally on a Linux computer a bunch of desktops and they're virtual desktop.
Speaker 1: So you're looking at your screen and you got like two windows open.
Speaker 1: you go to virtual desktop number two There's no windows on virtual desktop - then you go back to virtual desktop one.
Speaker 1: There's your two windows.
Speaker 1: you go back to virtual desktop - empty now.
Speaker 0: I have often been a person I usually turn off a lot of eye candy because anything I like eye candy as long as it doesn't in any way delay what?
Speaker 0: I'm doing so when I switch desktops, I want it to be just an instantaneous switch.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Except I'd rather have the cube than that because even though it slows me down.
Speaker 0: It just looks too cool.
Speaker 1: so instead of having a You know just desktops that change there's a spinning cube.
Speaker 1: So when you change desktops this cube actually spins around and all the four sides of the cube have your four Desktops on them.
Speaker 0: if you have more desktops, it's just a different three-dimensional figure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it is.
Speaker 1: I haven't actually tried to make more desktops yet though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should try that.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try that after the show and on the top and bottom of the cube you can put a picture whatever picture you want and It does all sorts of crazy wicked cool shit.
Speaker 1: It holy crap and it's not even that hard to make it work in Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: I'll link to the guide that says how to make it work in Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: You just add some.
Speaker 1: Are we gonna do that?
Speaker 1: every time we say Ubuntu?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's I think a shtick that just kind of came about and neither one of us said anything about it until just now.
Speaker 0: Alright, it's like when our Gilbert Gottfried was on pen show.
Speaker 0: great anyway I'm gonna make a Gilbert Gottfried Joe.
Speaker 0: No, I think we're getting anything else to say about that.
Speaker 1: It's really cool and really easy to set up and you should switch to Ubuntu just to you just so you can use.
Speaker 0: it's weird because I'm 50/50 between going to Ubuntu or Going with Gentoo, I think one thing's for certain that whatever distro you choose it will end in two.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, I'm not going to Red Hat.
Speaker 1: In fact, it'll end in mmm - It'll be either J and - or Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: so since Scott did a quick semi personal tech bit My quick semi personal tech bit is that we are in fact keeping the Mac.
Speaker 0: We are not returning it.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess yeah today tomorrow's last day, isn't it?
Speaker 0: Yeah I would have to drive to white planes and return the Mac tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I'm not doing that We're keeping it.
Speaker 1: We're probably just gonna use it as plugged into the TV because it works.
Speaker 1: real nice is that function it does.
Speaker 0: it is also The.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna sync my iPod up to that because I don't want to deal with Banshee and all that.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's a. it's really nice for the downstairs computer and it's going to be our Podcasting on the road box once we find a program to replace garage bad or make boot camp work with Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: Yep, the thing is is that?
Speaker 1: You know downstairs we had a giant computer Well normal-sized computer and a DVD player and a VCR.
Speaker 1: this little tiny Mac mini replaced all those and it's quieter and quieter.
Speaker 0: It's silent.
Speaker 1: This Mac is quieter than our DVD player was and it's a better DVD player than our DVD player and It's a better.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's kind of a better living room PC than our living room PC at least power wise though
Speaker 0: I do have some fondness from the DVD player for the DVD player because our first DVD player was an apex That I bought for like $30 and then hacked the firmware to make it region-free Even though we only ever put one non region one disc in it ever and then about seven months later it started overheating and then it died and it.
Speaker 0: It was only through the goodness of our friend Yuko's heart that she came forth and bought us a DVD play.
Speaker 1: I think she found one out of like a tag sale for 20 bucks or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but still it was much nicer than the apex that we had to pull the case off of to make work And it lasted us until now.
Speaker 1: so and it still works.
Speaker 1: So if anyone if she wants it back she can have it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, otherwise, we'll use it as a prize.
Speaker 1: No You win a DVD player.
Speaker 0: It works real great unless you have Netflix.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't read scratch DVDs.
Speaker 0: so well, yeah granted I don't fault it too badly for that because some of those Netflix's were real shade.
Speaker 1: They were real shady.
Speaker 1: We'll see if the Mac has trouble.
Speaker 0: but yeah also in general we're techies and we're real up on Windows and we're real up on Linux.
Speaker 0: it's good to have a house Mac because that's the thing We really weren't so up on.
Speaker 0: and as you can tell we don't know a lot about him other than the BSD nous underneath.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm learning about him real quick.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We might.
Speaker 1: I'm learning that there's a lot of things You can't do without shitty ass shareware.
Speaker 1: Yeah, be the open source Mac shit.
Speaker 0: I got a big talk about the developer culture around OS X and how it's ten years behind the times.
Speaker 1: I mean like there are two nice emulators for NES and SNES games on the Mac.
Speaker 1: I don't have any illegal ROMs though, but Yeah, no illegal ROMs here.
Speaker 1: Okay, okay and In order to get joysticks to work with these emulators.
Speaker 1: I needed this shareware program called emulator enhancer.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: not one SNES goddamn one?
Speaker 0: Windows the evil Empire's operating system.
Speaker 0: since Windows 3 1 1. if you plug a joystick in there's a widget that just makes the Joystick work in any program.
Speaker 1: Yep, - that's a direct actually DirectX thing.
Speaker 1: But yeah go on but -.
Speaker 0: ms-dos every program that needed a joystick could just use the joystick on its own.
Speaker 0: Three share where has not existed in viable form in almost a decade?
Speaker 0: Yeah, in fact, it's been over a decade since share where was a viable method of distributing software?
Speaker 0: Shareware is dead.
Speaker 0: There's no such thing as shareware anymore.
Speaker 0: Why are Mac developers making shareware?
Speaker 1: Everything is either closed source freeware or open source.
Speaker 0: where or proprietary don't use or pirate way of you punk kids Shareware because there was a time when there was freeware.
Speaker 0: shareware pay where they're all these words?
Speaker 0: Shareware was a very specific class of software postcard way.
Speaker 0: Yep where you would make a program and either Cripple it after a certain amount of time Cripple it from the start or it would just be the full version.
Speaker 0: but it would nag you and it would nag you to Send 10 bucks to rim who wrote this program and then they'll send you the code to unlock it.
Speaker 1: and all Unlocking it would do is make it stop nagging you.
Speaker 1: I can't tell you how many how many years people used winzip without ever paying for it.
Speaker 1: But every time you had to unzip a file you would have to click.
Speaker 1: Yes I agree that you can keep nagging me and it would tell you how many times it nagged you.
Speaker 1: Now like a thousand times you've unzipped something.
Speaker 0: the open-source software movement made shareware Obsolete because now if people really like things they just donate money.
Speaker 0: I mean Scott and I both donated money to open SSH.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I use SSH every goddamn day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they deserve my money.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, well, we should do our tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's start with WinFS.
Speaker 1: Okay now win FS has a dumb idea.
Speaker 0: Well it From an overview it was a good idea.
Speaker 0: Let's make an awesome Metadata file system kind of thing for Windows.
Speaker 0: Let's make it awesome.
Speaker 0: Let's make it the be-all-end-all of file systems.
Speaker 1: How it riser for is to win.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now it wouldn't.
Speaker 0: Microsoft said we're gonna make win FS.
Speaker 0: Microsoft said that about Windows.
Speaker 0: what like 98?
Speaker 1: No, they said that.
Speaker 1: they said it about Vista.
Speaker 0: Well, they said even before they kept saying they were gonna make like.
Speaker 1: well, they they had the idea Brewing but for Vista they said we're gonna make win FS.
Speaker 1: and then they said alright, we're gonna make it but not in Vista.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know what?
Speaker 0: I was confused with.
Speaker 0: and there's NTFS and then there was the next iteration of NTFS.
Speaker 1: No, that's that's not.
Speaker 0: no there was slightly different.
Speaker 0: But originally they didn't call it win FS but Microsoft said when they were they were gonna change NTFS and make it add all these things to it and then one by one those features kind of disappeared and And I don't remember that there.
Speaker 0: I'll show you an article later about it because I remember I was pissed off Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Anyway, when FS was gonna be this awesome file system that Microsoft was touting as this is going to be the big thing This is going to be what you will buy Vista for pretty much.
Speaker 1: the idea of win FS is that you would have this database of meta information that would Make it real easy to find your documents Even though you you wouldn't have to know where stuff was stored on your drive anymore.
Speaker 1: So gone would be the days of where did I put that file?
Speaker 1: C colon backslash documents and settings backslash desktop backslash.
Speaker 0: No to to not to pop to people who know how to use computers.
Speaker 0: those days have never existed.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 1: But anyway, but it's all the idiots those days are pretty much constant.
Speaker 1: So the idea this is people would have to browse anymore.
Speaker 1: You would just type in like, you know, it would.
Speaker 1: it would be Google desktop, but built into the OS which means, you know No performance hit or anything.
Speaker 1: Well, there would be a performance it because it's a big heavy thing you're using but you know It wouldn't be Like a tacked on deal.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, they they kept reducing the scope of it and now it's completely dead.
Speaker 0: It just kind of dwindled away to nothing and now it might Kind of exist a little in a completely different form.
Speaker 0: that is useless and basically a different thing.
Speaker 1: It's like Microsoft said they were gonna do something and they tried and tried and tried.
Speaker 1: they couldn't cut it.
Speaker 1: So they pushed it.
Speaker 1: they couldn't cut it So they pushed it back and then now they can't cut it at all.
Speaker 1: It's completely useless and crap.
Speaker 0: So we'll see what Vista has to offer.
Speaker 1: See, I'm really of the camp that if you want to do something like this it should be actually the way Mac does.
Speaker 1: it is.
Speaker 1: they have that little Sherlock tool or A tool on Linux like s locate where if you want a database if you want meta information on your files You don't put that in the file system.
Speaker 1: the file system should just be a way to arrange data on your hard drive and So the operating system understands it.
Speaker 1: That's what the file system is is efficient and as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: if you put all that metadata in a file system That's great.
Speaker 0: Then if you take the file off of that computer onto a computer with a different file system, it's all gone.
Speaker 1: Well, no, you could say yeah, but the well a different file system.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that yeah, I'm definitely a fan of putting metadata in files or putting metadata in databases.
Speaker 1: You know if I want metadata on my music files, I should use iTunes or Banshee or so or Mmdb or whatever it's called and you know You make a database of all that has links to all your files and then has meta information on all your files in it.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what Microsoft.
Speaker 0: that's where you have to do now because there's no more WinFS.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: I want next That's a good question.
Speaker 0: All right, fine Bill Gates.
Speaker 1: Okay, Bill Gates is the richest guy in the world.
Speaker 0: Now who was the second richest guy in the world?
Speaker 1: I think it's Warren Buffett.
Speaker 1: I don't know what he does though, even though I know his name.
Speaker 0: Well, he's given most of his money to Bill Gates.
Speaker 1: See the thing is Bill Gates has a lot of money and you know not being a complete evil fuck.
Speaker 1: he wants to give most of it away and he decided that curing diseases and Getting rid of things like malaria is the best way he can spend his money And I wouldn't attribute much evil to him at all.
Speaker 0: It's mostly balmer.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but the point is is that that's hard to argue with that one.
Speaker 1: You know, it's sort of like, you know anything else that you could pick to spend money to fight against.
Speaker 1: Someone might disagree with you.
Speaker 1: You know, if you tried to spend money to fight against the evil Communist regimes then the commies would disagree with you.
Speaker 1: All right food.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: Invest in not letting people starve to death.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna disagree with that.
Speaker 1: there are people Fucking up because in a you're fucking up economic things.
Speaker 1: be People who are argue with your Franken food and Example for yours.
Speaker 1: There are people who are very much against the curing of diseases, but those are so few I submit that and none of them are large governments that are all Christian scientists.
Speaker 0: there are large governments that are very much opposed to research into AIDS because AIDS is God's punishment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well he's not actually doing AIDS at least not right.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen anything that specifically said he was doing AIDS.
Speaker 1: for most of what I seen He's doing the old-world diseases that are still hanging around.
Speaker 1: Oh, so, you know malaria typhus mostly African diseases is what he seems to be concentrating on.
Speaker 1: Of course AIDS is a big one there too.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: I wonder if any of this money is gonna go toward the reinstatement of DDT spray.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: but the point is is that you know, Bill Gates in a couple years is gonna quit Microsoft Almost completely and spend all his time giving away his money.
Speaker 1: And what he said is that you know He could just give away his money pretty easily But he would feel bad if he gave the money to someone who used it poorly, you know.
Speaker 1: Like if he gave his money to someone who then used it to buy mansions and yachts Then he would be upset.
Speaker 1: So he set up the get Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation.
Speaker 1: Linda's his wife to give the money away Responsibly.
Speaker 1: that way, you know, he can spend me.
Speaker 1: he doesn't give money away to fuck tires by accident.
Speaker 1: and Warren Buffett is another incredibly rich guy who also wants to give away his money responsibly.
Speaker 1: But it's too hard for him to do that on his own.
Speaker 1: So he's just gonna give most of his money to the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation that way that it's given away responsibly.
Speaker 0: Yep, I gotta say I very much like this whole thing because it really harkens back to the that You know the old robber barons and the super-rich people all through the history.
Speaker 0: and now they'd always do great philanthropic things too.
Speaker 0: You know, let's make Rockefeller Center or something like that.
Speaker 1: Yep It's they actually.
Speaker 1: some other podcast mentioned those guys all in the same breath, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just I'd like to see people who have that sort of wealth at least trying to do good with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I always said that you know if I had you know, let's see what if I had like a you know a house Ferrari all the computers I needed and enough money to live the rest of my life with interest and all that good stuff That every other penny I got I would either give I would give away either to family friends or charity.
Speaker 1: Because you know, there's only so much money that I need more money.
Speaker 1: I've already got everything, you know, if I've got a home theater a Ferrari not a mansion, but I don't need more Only a boat but that's it.
Speaker 1: That's the end any more than that.
Speaker 1: I could buy all that with a few million dollars Billion dollars, I wouldn't know what the fuck to do with it.
Speaker 0: Don't you buy a personal ball washer?
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: No, just one the Ferrari.
Speaker 1: it's all.
Speaker 1: you need one car Ferrari the end.
Speaker 1: But you know, I might buy things like an f1 team, but even that is only 200 million dollars.
Speaker 1: So what the fuck am I gonna do?
Speaker 1: the billion dollars?
Speaker 1: I buy a business.
Speaker 0: I would do you know what I would do?
Speaker 0: I'd go around the world looking for people who seem as cool as the front row And then get them all live together in a giant place.
Speaker 1: Not only that but even that is only a hundred million dollars at most.
Speaker 0: if you do it crazily I could live the life of hedonism bot until I died of a ripe old age.
Speaker 1: You couldn't spend a billion dollars if you were hedonism, but I bet I could spend a billion dollars.
Speaker 1: Hedonism bot could not spend a billion dollars on hedonism.
Speaker 1: I guarantee it Unless you got a billion.
Speaker 1: one dollar whores What?
Speaker 0: or one ten dollar hooker?
Speaker 1: about ten dollar ten cent or ten billion ten cent whores?
Speaker 1: If it weren't so late I'd pull up that bender quote, I know right Anyway, but yeah, I like you know, you got to realize that if you giving away a little bit of money It's real easy to give it away.
Speaker 1: You just toss the United Way bin give it to your favorite local charity.
Speaker 1: Even a church will probably do something.
Speaker 1: Okay with it.
Speaker 1: Most of the time except for a Catholic Church They'll just buy gold with it.
Speaker 0: But no, no, cuz they sell it to the gnomes of Zurich.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right, you know.
Speaker 1: But even the Salvation Army will probably do something good, but they give up not the Salvation Army.
Speaker 1: Well, they might know, you know, they will buy one Bible to give to you know, someone instead of giving them food.
Speaker 1: But they'll also buy a food.
Speaker 0: No, they buy like a hundred Bibles for every one food.
Speaker 0: I did if you'd said anything about the Salvation Army would let it slide.
Speaker 0: The Salvation Army is a terrible.
Speaker 1: Well, if you think about it if you give them a dollar and they buy ten Bibles for every one food It's like giving them ten cents.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you're not getting your money's worth, but at least you're getting something now cuz I have other reasons to dislike them.
Speaker 1: yeah, but there are worse places to give it like The revive Hitler fund exactly.
Speaker 0: It's always a bad place.
Speaker 1: revive Hitler fund is bad.
Speaker 1: What are those guys from that South Park episode?
Speaker 1: Oh NAMBLA don't give it to NAMBLA.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, there are worse places you could give it but there are also many better places you can give it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: I got a quick aside news and we're gonna talk about this much more on Wednesday But I figured since I was interrupted right now about this and we seem to have a streak of people Talking to us while we're doing the show so we get semi live updates here.
Speaker 0: Jim Vowles of Otacon would like to remind all of you who are thinking of attending Otacon that you should pre-register now.
Speaker 0: So you get the $10 discount that ends on the 4th of July.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you're going to Otacon get your pre-registration in it'll save you ten bucks.
Speaker 1: We should probably just say that on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I figured I'd say it right now, okay?
Speaker 0: It'll explain why Scott talked a whole bunch of time, and I didn't make fun of him or anything for a couple minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you have a shit ton of money to give away It's not as easy as just dumping it in a charity bin somewhere.
Speaker 1: You've got to make sure you don't give it to a fucktard.
Speaker 1: and at least Bill Gates is smart enough to realize that.
Speaker 1: yeah And so is Warren Buffett who is even cooler in my eyes because he realized it and he realized he didn't want to deal with It.
Speaker 1: so he does have someone else do all the work, and now he gets all the credit.
Speaker 0: All right, we got another quickie here Belgium the government of Belgium the country from which a good portion of my blood is from Originally like little tiny thing that's in between France and Germany in the north that Hitler ran through.
Speaker 1: yeah that thing.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: the country that has the French half and the Flemish half and The Flemish half don't like the French half, but they all speak English, so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I like Belgium.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the guys who fucked up Africa Yeah, I mean the.
Speaker 0: if you rank the colonial powers in terms of how horrible they were to the native people The French were probably the best in terms of treating them, and then you know under them It's like the British and and the Spanish were pretty much.
Speaker 0: most people think Spanish are at the bottom because they were Other than the Portuguese.
Speaker 0: the Portuguese and the Spanish were just horrible horrible conquistador type people.
Speaker 0: But they got nothing on the Belgians, but you read up on some of the things Belgium did to their colony people.
Speaker 0: yeah Anyway, Belgium has gone open source.
Speaker 1: Well, they're not going open source.
Speaker 1: It's for any of their document formats used in government.
Speaker 1: They're going to use an open document format.
Speaker 1: Yeah, specifically the open document format.
Speaker 0: It's a big step I Think in general.
Speaker 0: It's a big step toward.
Speaker 1: You know open source I think a lot of technology a lot of non tech.
Speaker 1: people don't really understand this problem.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem.
Speaker 1: Let's say the government decides.
Speaker 1: Let's say you have a government of a country and that government uses Microsoft Word documents for all government computer documents.
Speaker 1: now government things is supposed to be public things like laws things like Forms to fill out all these things that must be public.
Speaker 1: so anyone supposed to be able to get them for free.
Speaker 1: Cuz it's your government.
Speaker 1: your taxes paid for it already.
Speaker 1: It's free for you If it's in Microsoft Word document format.
Speaker 1: in order for you to do anything with it You need Microsoft Word which costs money.
Speaker 1: This is like if a government decides to use Microsoft Word.
Speaker 1: They're basically saying if you want access to your government.
Speaker 1: You have to pay this company money.
Speaker 1: I mean imagine if the government highways said only Ford cars can drive here.
Speaker 1: That's what it's like if the government uses Microsoft Word documents.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's the same as if they made highways were only Ford cars could drive.
Speaker 0: in fact I ran into this problem directly a little while ago my friend Katsu.
Speaker 0: I wanted to give his resume to my company and my company would only accept it in Microsoft doc format.
Speaker 0: none of us have Microsoft Office, so he made an open office which wasn't fully Compatible.
Speaker 0: I'd open it in Word at work and twiddle with it to make it look right.
Speaker 1: yeah I only have word on my work computer and I you know the only times I really use it are for work.
Speaker 1: shit because no one.
Speaker 1: they use stupid office.
Speaker 1: and Also if I need to convert something to a format for cousin it for an idiot who doesn't use another open format.
Speaker 1: now With an open format like open document format or some XML for which is an XML format But any other open format like text or anything open generally means XML.
Speaker 0: Yes, ml does not necessarily mean open.
Speaker 1: No, well open doesn't always mean XML.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but these days it seems to Concerning document formats.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they seem to be using XML mostly but That means that you know.
Speaker 1: sure open office is the program that is mostly associated with the open document format.
Speaker 1: But because it's an open format, which means everyone in the world knows how these files work Anyone can write a program that can read these files.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know if Microsoft Office reads them, but I think Abby word reads them and You can just read it with just about all kinds of different free software.
Speaker 0: So in fact it because it's so documented you could just write something to read them.
Speaker 1: So if the government uses open document format then you can drive any car you want on the road.
Speaker 1: You could drive an expensive car like my you know, Microsoft Office maybe with a plug-in.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't even know if that works cuz I don't use Microsoft Office.
Speaker 1: or you can use Open office, which is free.
Speaker 1: You can use Abby word, which is free.
Speaker 1: You can use all sorts of things and they're all free.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: One of the reasons Microsoft is so against this and it's something I've run into a lot just in the work I've done is that the main reason cut the primary reasons.
Speaker 0: companies can't just move all of their Menial computer users to a lockdown.
Speaker 0: Linux is that one they need to interface with other companies and the primary ways Small and medium-sized companies interface with other small medium-sized companies is through Microsoft Word.
Speaker 1: Yes They have to excel they use off access they have Microsoft Exchange servers with Microsoft Outlook and they email each other Microsoft documents.
Speaker 1: and because they've been doing this so long they have all these existing documents that they still need access to.
Speaker 1: and if Even if you start a new company Even if you decided to use open office and open document formats the other companies don't see you need office to communicate with them.
Speaker 1: So you would really need to get all the companies to switch.
Speaker 1: But if the government switched then everyone would need open office or something to commute to Interact with the government which every company has to do.
Speaker 1: also if people did that then they might be able to phase over to an open document format convert their word documents over time and eventually give Microsoft the boot because office is really their biggest moneymaker still right now and Open document format could kick its ass, especially if more governments adopted and mandated Which is what they should do being good open governments and not evil Tyrannical governments.
Speaker 1: So, I hope that people who didn't understand this issue now have a clear understanding of why any good open democratic Government and not a communist dictatorship needs to use open document formats to not be tyrannical.
Speaker 0: All right, and on that note, I think that should wrap up our tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: We went much longer than we expected to which is great because we were worried it would be a short episode.
Speaker 0: Hooray Tomorrow is gaming day, which should be yes.
Speaker 1: The rest of this week will be awesome.
Speaker 1: We had you know last Thursday that are little nothing and then Sunday We did a crap little episode and today, you know, it was okay, but they're starting tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Geek nice is gonna be super awesome again.
Speaker 1: And also if you haven't already this Thursday is going to be an episode of ask rim and Scott anything.
Speaker 1: So if you haven't asked us anything and you want to either send an email to geek nights at front row crew calm or Join our forum and visit the thread about asking us anything and ask any question you want and on Thursday We will answer all the questions unless there's too many in which case we will answer As many questions as we can.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except for one which we might possibly answer on someone else's podcast.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: Yes But we will let you know where to hear us answer all these questions that we do answer.
Speaker 1: so ask away.
Speaker 1: We need more questions email us.
Speaker 0: ask ask ask and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206 3 3 3 1 5 3 7.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.