Speaker 1: It's Tuesday May 23rd, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We go back to German games for a bit and review an old standby Alhambra.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I'm kind of bored at work with no work to do.
Speaker 1: as I've said many many times before I Don't have any work to do yet, but that's because I've been working at my new job a grand total of two days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at least you're not bored out of your gourd.
Speaker 1: No it's awesome.
Speaker 1: actually today I went to the data center like the main data center for my company.
Speaker 1: Now I have to say I mean I worked at IBM, and you'd think IBM would have like these crazy awesome data centers.
Speaker 0: No, I think they have mad old shit.
Speaker 1: the data center I was in for my company was probably the most well organized well documented well labeled Perfectly put together well staffed awesome data center.
Speaker 1: I've ever seen in my life Like I think I stumbled on a gold when I took this job.
Speaker 0: God damn you see you think it's gold, but here's the thing right?
Speaker 0: On the one hand you have IBM a company that's incompetent and all you do is bitch and moan about how they could be doing Things.
Speaker 0: the way the company you work for now is doing them.
Speaker 0: But then there's the other situation where if they were doing things the way that your company does them you have no work to do.
Speaker 1: Well actually no I have a lot of work to do because there's the big difference between where I'm working now Which is kind of a normal company in IBM at IBM.
Speaker 1: It was a factory environment.
Speaker 1: I wasn't doing the fancy client facing you know Igs blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I was doing the keep the factory running at all cost thing Which meant that my only job was retroactive.
Speaker 1: It was never proactive.
Speaker 1: I never made anything better.
Speaker 1: I just fixed things that were broken and maintain the status quo.
Speaker 1: The only goal was keep it working.
Speaker 1: here the goal is always make it better make it better make it better.
Speaker 1: if you think of Something cool make it better mm-hmm, but how can it be better if it's already so great because they're doing more?
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: All right, so anyway being bored at work I my new hobby is to turn on Skype and set it to Skype me mode.
Speaker 1: now It's funny because Emily did that by accident when she first got Skype.
Speaker 1: She had it set to.
Speaker 1: you know Skype me instead of just I'm online and I was talking to her over You know and she said these weird people keep trying to talk to me.
Speaker 1: I Think the same people were trying to talk to you.
Speaker 0: So first of all if you go on Skype and you search for users that have Skype me mode enabled There are very few like a handful.
Speaker 0: you can count them.
Speaker 0: There's so few yet Skype advertises in the bottom right corner that they're like six million people online With less than a hundred of them have Skype me mode enabled.
Speaker 0: so If you turn on Skype me mode the number one Category of people that will try to talk to you by the text or voice are Chinese people.
Speaker 1: It's insane Chinese people or Chinese people who only speak Chinese People from China.
Speaker 1: Do they speak English?
Speaker 0: I only talked to one of them and they barely spoke English.
Speaker 0: It seems like everyone who messages me even if they're from a foreign country Which most of them are like 90% of the people are from foreign countries.
Speaker 0: They want to speak English.
Speaker 0: So today the two best calls I got one of them wasn't a call it was a text just a chat with some truck driver from Ohio and He Seemed like he didn't like truck driving and he was bored and lonely and I was like, alright, whatever
Speaker 1: Did he want to make the hot online man love with you?
Speaker 0: You know, he didn't go that far, but he's like.
Speaker 0: You know, he started out with like a or hunk.
Speaker 0: I'm like, okay.
Speaker 0: Whoa, and then he was like.
Speaker 0: so he did I know.
Speaker 0: and then he was like, hey your roommates risk a cuz he he was you know He my link to my flicker was in there.
Speaker 1: Oh god, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: So because of you some guy was ogling me, I guess and it was like you about it.
Speaker 0: He was like a roommate who had his shirt off and I'm like whatever.
Speaker 0: and then he's like Where are the pictures of you with your shirt off?
Speaker 0: I'm like, alright, if you're if you want some porn You can just search for it on Google.
Speaker 0: You don't have to Skype me and waste my time Wow, so Then the best one was these two German guys Email.
Speaker 0: they come.
Speaker 0: they conferenced me in so I was talking to two German guys and one guy.
Speaker 1: you asked him about board games.
Speaker 1: Yes, did you ask them if you're saying bevagung odoric schlagen Z.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't.
Speaker 1: you should have.
Speaker 0: I already knew the answer to that one but you know They were like they.
Speaker 0: their English is really bad and they knew it and they kept talking to each other in German.
Speaker 0: a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: I was trying to figure out what they were saying, which I did a mediocre job of.
Speaker 0: yeah, and Then they would like ask me a question and I would answer it.
Speaker 0: and then I tried to ask them some questions and I was like Brett spiel.
Speaker 0: well Like they were like, uh, and I was like board game Brett spiel.
Speaker 0: Well And they're like, ah and the guy said Brett spiel up properly to the other guy.
Speaker 0: And then the guy was like, oh chess.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, all right great.
Speaker 1: And they were like you weren't like DC Dlerf on Catan?
Speaker 0: no, then they were like do you play World of Warcraft, I'm like no Counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh nice.
Speaker 0: Not every time I said something they liked they were like nice nice.
Speaker 1: You know, I've heard that like the f1 people seem to say that a lot of them He was.
Speaker 1: I say the word nice a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was like nice nice.
Speaker 0: and then I'm like, uh Do you watch?
Speaker 0: Formula one.
Speaker 0: and one guy was like I do.
Speaker 0: the other guy was like I don't he does.
Speaker 1: you should have told him to watch.
Speaker 1: Listen to geek nights.
Speaker 0: I don't think they barely understood me Like we could only use words that were the same in both languages Or it wouldn't work like names of video games.
Speaker 0: Like they were like 1.6 or source and I said both.
Speaker 0: That was how far it went and then eventually I got bored.
Speaker 0: I just hung up on him, you know You could probably get him to listen anyway.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll note that we seem to be once again more popular with foreigners than we are with Americans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we thought for all of you we just got and if you're listening It's awesome because I know you're trying hard.
Speaker 1: We got a listener in Bangkok who was complaining that he speaks English properly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he speaks English better than some of you fools in the forums now.
Speaker 0: No offense, but mr Period won't be hurting him anytime soon.
Speaker 1: but he was complaining because apparently Libsyn doesn't allow resume and all this stuff and He's in Bangkok.
Speaker 1: He doesn't have the best internet connection to the US Nope, but he's listening to geek nights anyway, and he's trying to download it.
Speaker 0: Keep going man.
Speaker 1: Yeah fight the good fight.
Speaker 1: get a better ISP and we'll hook up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll go visit Bangkok We had to get.
Speaker 0: we're gonna have to start doing the Akamai to get people so everyone in the whole world can listen All right.
Speaker 0: So some news is some news is it's video game day, right?
Speaker 0: Well, it's a day.
Speaker 0: It's some DS news in Europe, I think It's your news.
Speaker 1: So apparently the DS light is gonna come out here in June, I think yeah I'm really I want one, but I shouldn't waste the money especially because I'm not sure when my first paycheck's coming, but I want one.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, when are you getting paid real soon?
Speaker 1: It's bi-weekly.
Speaker 1: So at most it'll be three weeks All right.
Speaker 0: So I don't want you to be without money for too long.
Speaker 1: if I'm without money for too long you pay rent once and then I pay you back when I get my giant check.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Plus I'm getting a check from IBM Thursday.
Speaker 0: No, that's good.
Speaker 1: I might get one next Thursday, too.
Speaker 1: Ooh, all right.
Speaker 0: So Europe apparently is not only getting the DS light, you know, I think in July I didn't look but they're also getting a black DS light Huh?
Speaker 0: Why does Europe get the black DS light?
Speaker 0: How come we?
Speaker 1: don't my best guess?
Speaker 1: This is accomplices rims speculation time.
Speaker 1: I think that they've realized that the DS and Nintendo in general doesn't do so well in Europe But a lot of things don't do so well in Europe mainly because Europe is kind of the last place finish of video gaming.
Speaker 0: It seems like anywhere that's not Japan or the US is all PC gaming action.
Speaker 0: Mostly.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I mean look at the PlayStation 3 it's gonna be the equivalent of over $800 in Europe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean god damn All the games come there late.
Speaker 1: all the movies from the West and from Japan get there late.
Speaker 1: They really get the stick end of the stick.
Speaker 0: Europe should make more of its own stuff.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I think it is though.
Speaker 0: I think the problem is they get our stuff late and we get their stuff never.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean many Americans aren't interest interested in anything foreign.
Speaker 1: I know some punk kids where if you told them anime was Japanese.
Speaker 1: They'd probably freak out.
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: All your video games are Japanese - yeah Possibly Korean.
Speaker 1: Yep But I could see this is Nintendo trying to do like a a little olive branch to Europe saying hey Here's something just for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've also got this Weird European DS commercial.
Speaker 0: you can go watch.
Speaker 0: that looks like a clothing fashion commercial.
Speaker 0: only the people aren't wearing as many clothes.
Speaker 1: See it could also be part of the fact that they you know, you have to market to Europe differently.
Speaker 1: I mean they know how to market to the US and they know how to market to Japan.
Speaker 1: I mean look at the commercials here versus Japan and how different they are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's weird that they're actually trying in Europe.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: No other video game company tries So well, no console video game company.
Speaker 1: So in Nintendo's trying to you know, blue water strat blue ocean They're trying to open up to as many people as possible.
Speaker 1: If they even nothing else all the Americans in the Japanese will try to get this black DS Early and then the sales numbers will look like they were sold from Europe and then antenna will take the lead over there to.
Speaker 1: yeah You know also
Speaker 0: they're gonna put out a new Nintendo's in Europe with like a new dog and then it's sort of like the best hits where they took the most popular dogs from all the existing ones and Added like a Dalmatian and they put it out in Europe.
Speaker 0: They're gonna do that too.
Speaker 1: I think this is the beginning of a push by Nintendo to penetrate the European market.
Speaker 1: We'll see if it works and I did not mean any sexual metaphor there.
Speaker 1: I Don't know if it's gonna work You know, I mean look how they're doing now, I mean brain age and all these games for non gamers.
Speaker 1: I think those are the games they're really gonna push in Europe to try to make the DS sell more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't think people in Europe care about games at all.
Speaker 0: They have better things to do because they're in fucking Europe where there are things to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, they can live their lives They don't have to work.
Speaker 1: For all of you European listeners.
Speaker 1: I'll just let you know that Americans I don't think you realize how little vacation time and free time we get in this country.
Speaker 1: None I get a month as in four or twenty thirty days of vacation a year And that's really kind of crazy that I get that much right now.
Speaker 0: I get ten days at IBM.
Speaker 0: I got five next year.
Speaker 0: I'll have fifteen days five.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you got five days off a year, you know plus weekends and a few holidays.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus the holidays.
Speaker 1: we get off for the crap ones when everyone gets them off and you can't go anywhere because everyone's trying to go somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's hard we.
Speaker 1: it's hard for us to go on trips like.
Speaker 1: it's hard for us to say let's pop off to Europe and Backpack for a month.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if you're in Europe, you can just take trains to the other countries to see all the castles and shit.
Speaker 0: We can't see castles.
Speaker 0: No, there's no nice Over here.
Speaker 0: There is nothing nice here.
Speaker 1: We've got a castle.
Speaker 1: We've got banner.
Speaker 0: It's a shit castle.
Speaker 0: It's not a real medieval castle to shit post 1700 castle.
Speaker 0: Yeah 1800 castle.
Speaker 0: That sucks.
Speaker 0: I want to see some 1200 castle to its credit.
Speaker 0: It's an 800 castle to bannerman castles credit.
Speaker 1: It did explode and then burn down and now it is covered in poison ivy great and possibly wild animals.
Speaker 0: I want to go see the German castles and the Welsh castles.
Speaker 1: You know by night this time next year we have more money because we've kind of spent a lot of money lately.
Speaker 1: We should just go to Europe and meet all our listeners over there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there won't be Any podcast for like two weeks.
Speaker 0: They'll be one really long line.
Speaker 0: It's like here's what Rimmins got recorded while in Europe.
Speaker 1: Actually, I got a better idea.
Speaker 1: if things get bad enough in this country Can we stay with one of you guys out there in the free world?
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't think it's that free over there.
Speaker 0: It's just an illusion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could always go to Canada.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's so much better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it kind of is except for the weather.
Speaker 0: Yeah, great.
Speaker 0: Why can't Canada be on the bottom?
Speaker 1: Yeah Because then it would be Mexico.
Speaker 0: Let's go to Mexico then.
Speaker 1: All right Yeah, we'd probably make a lot of money in Mexico's IT guys.
Speaker 0: We got to find some internets in Mexico The there's internet and learn some Spanish is.
Speaker 1: I know French a little I know Spanish.
Speaker 0: I can read a Spanish newspaper kinda Yeah, but I can't speak it a lot because I don't like.
Speaker 0: if I see a word I can figure out what it means But I can't just come up with the word in my brain to say it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I'm a further step removed because I can kind of read a French newspaper.
Speaker 1: So then a Spanish newspaper is I can kind of read.
Speaker 1: I get almost nothing out of it.
Speaker 1: So you go to Canada and I'll go to Mexico All right, and then and then we'll wait for them to build that highway over the u.s.
Speaker 1: Between the two.
Speaker 1: good idea All right.
Speaker 1: I got a non video game news because there's no other video game news.
Speaker 1: I care about today.
Speaker 1: now Microsoft supposedly is going to take administrator rights away from most of their employees on their computers.
Speaker 0: Why would employees have administrator rights if they're not the network administrators?
Speaker 1: the vast majority of people who use Windows run it as administrator Always.
Speaker 1: you may not be called administrator.
Speaker 1: You might be called something else, but you're probably in the administrator group.
Speaker 0: You're basically root on your computer and that's bad for a zillion reasons.
Speaker 0: But because Windows sucks you need to do it that way or else it's incredibly frustrating and that's why Windows sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's not just Microsoft's fault.
Speaker 1: It's kind of complicated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's Microsoft made because Windows 3 1 and earlier had really no permission model at all.
Speaker 1: No You just you had a computer with NT early NT like NT 3 and such and even like early windows like Windows 95 You could futz with it to make a kind of log in as different users.
Speaker 0: Windows her work groups had it in the wussiest possible way.
Speaker 1: Yeah back with wins and all that Yeah, but even then it barely work barely worked.
Speaker 0: Remember when Windows 95 had that inbox on the desktop.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, no one had an email system where that would work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know to this day But When they as they added they started adding security stuff and permission stuff kind of like what?
Speaker 1: Unix and Linux have only kinda.
Speaker 1: it's actually fairly robust and well done in terms of the concept.
Speaker 1: It's just really counterintuitive and annoying and not easy or trivial to use at all.
Speaker 1: Like I it's not easy if you don't know about computers to deal with Linux file permissions the first few times.
Speaker 1: It's a thousand times harder to deal with the windows ones.
Speaker 0: Well, that's because you know They came over.
Speaker 0: the Unix file permissions is lean years ago and there was nothing wrong with them and they haven't changed And they're not complicated.
Speaker 1: They're well documented too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just a number.
Speaker 1: Windows.
Speaker 1: don't don't even get me started on Windows file permissions File permissions, what are the versions for other things?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have some stories about file permissions But they had the security model and it's gotten more and more robust over the years.
Speaker 1: but they've tried to make windows so that you don't have to run as administrator anymore or as root anymore, basically and One of the ways they've did this is they made a thing called run as where you can be a normal user But you can right-click on a program and say run this as administrator Because many programs need the access that administrator has usually
Speaker 0: when you're trying to install software.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but there's a lot of software that was won't run at all.
Speaker 1: Unless you're administrator.
Speaker 0: Well, it's terrible.
Speaker 0: That's really bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly I've seen stuff that won't install properly unless you're administrator.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but lots of proprietary applications some office II things Earlier versions of narrow.
Speaker 1: you had to be administrator to burn.
Speaker 1: Wow, yeah all sorts of stuff and One Microsoft permissions are kind of wonky.
Speaker 1: So this run as thing doesn't work like at all.
Speaker 1: It's really useless.
Speaker 1: You still have to log in as administrator and you might as well just stay administrator because otherwise half the things you have won't work.
Speaker 1: Yeah to people who write programs for Windows Often don't understand how the permissions work or don't understand how to you know, write code Selena writing a program that needs administrator access to work for no other reason than that.
Speaker 1: They're stupid and they don't know any better.
Speaker 1: Microsoft yells at him They don't know or care.
Speaker 1: But then Microsoft's thing is almost as broken and in the end You have to be administrator all the time or your Windows computer is almost useless and that leaves it Incredibly open to all sorts of security problems.
Speaker 0: because if anyone gets control of your computer run out there.
Speaker 0: the administrator and they have complete control Is if you were running as some other account and they got control of your computer.
Speaker 0: they couldn't do that much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the worst they could do is ruin your user space.
Speaker 0: Oh, they deleted my my documents folder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if your user space is the administrator space then they're gonna raise your hard drive.
Speaker 1: This is base includes everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah every day.
Speaker 0: See now the real reason for this that I see design wise is that in Linux ever in Unix and any Nix?
Speaker 0: Everything is a file.
Speaker 0: Absolutely, everything is a file.
Speaker 0: So you only need to set a permission structure that deals with files and that can deal with everything devices Users everything because it's all files.
Speaker 0: See all you need is to control the files and Windows.
Speaker 0: It's not just the files.
Speaker 0: There's all sorts of other things that aren't files and that makes it so that your permission structure has to be incredibly Complicated to deal with all sorts of different things
Speaker 1: Which also wouldn't be that bad Except that they don't document a lot of it because it's their proprietary secret internal closed source code
Speaker 0: and the implementation is really Crappy
Speaker 1: and kind of arbitrary kind of spotty.
Speaker 0: different things work in different ways for no reason Yeah, and the active directory and the domains don't help.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they work really well if you know what you're doing But if you know what you're doing.
Speaker 0: You probably hate them and if you try to do anything out of the ordinary it fucks up.
Speaker 0: and the worst is this is a?
Speaker 0: Problem I think my company has is that you know you have let's say you set up an active directory and a bunch of Windows 2000 clients by the book right.
Speaker 0: it's perfect glorious.
Speaker 0: Then you start to add something.
Speaker 0: well you add Let's say a printer a network printer.
Speaker 0: you add it by the book and everything's still cool.
Speaker 0: Then add maybe a file server still cool, then you go out and you get this proprietary device that your company needs say a Fancy machine and the machine needs to get on your active directory.
Speaker 0: well now you need to modify your active directory somehow to accommodate This machine.
Speaker 0: then you get another proprietary software.
Speaker 0: We have to modify your active directory to accommodate that.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: Then you start getting conflicts between the different accommodations.
Speaker 0: now other things stop working.
Speaker 1: so you got User needs Oracle database.
Speaker 1: I defy you to install Oracle database properly without being administrator.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, or even use it.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is if it was written properly then I would as if I was a sales working at a company right and I had a User account that was not administrator, and I had a properly written Oracle database.
Speaker 0: as soon It doesn't exist, but let's say it did.
Speaker 0: I should be able to install it into my my documents folder into my user space With no one else on the computer having access to it.
Speaker 0: That's what you're allowed to do in Unix.
Speaker 0: you can install any software you want to your home folder.
Speaker 0: No one can stop you unless they decide that they don't want to let you write to your own home folder But that you know.
Speaker 0: you get the idea You can do anything you want in your little box.
Speaker 1: now despite this most corporations still don't give their users They're run-of-the-mill users administrative access you shouldn't?
Speaker 1: I have administrative access to my computer because I know what I'm doing.
Speaker 0: yeah They should.
Speaker 0: you can give them administrative access to the local machine But you should not not.
Speaker 1: even then most companies most companies give you nothing to your local machine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah Well it really depends a lot of the time.
Speaker 0: I mean remember.
Speaker 1: We're tech workers We see it from the entirely different side, and they usually accommodate us.
Speaker 0: well Yeah, but you know that's.
Speaker 0: that's besides the point now.
Speaker 1: I think this whole you know the actual news here is great because now Microsoft and Microsoft employees are gonna have to deal with all the brokenness of the windows Permission scheme which might drive them to try and fix it.
Speaker 0: It's if they got it.
Speaker 0: if they don't fix this in Vista.
Speaker 0: It's the end.
Speaker 1: It's the end for Vista anyway.
Speaker 1: I'm can I'm done?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know, but it's the super end.
Speaker 1: I mean corporations aren't even gonna go to Vista.
Speaker 0: No no one is.
Speaker 1: They're probably gonna stay on XP.
Speaker 1: they might even hire people.
Speaker 0: You know who's going to Vista.
Speaker 0: the crazy Too much money buy a new computer every week from Alienware gamers because it's gonna provide some fancy words.
Speaker 0: You know what I'll keep playing Half-life 1 & 2 and the yuppies who you know gotta have all fancy gadgets that they don't use.
Speaker 1: you know we're kind of yuppies.
Speaker 0: We're not yuppie like those guys yeah, but we're young.
Speaker 1: we're upwardly mobile for professionals.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so so But we're not like those guys who are just like buying boats and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well that's because we're not upper middle class.
Speaker 1: We're just middle class.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm if you combine us, but we're there's only if we combine our salaries But there's just one of us.
Speaker 1: then yeah, we're upper middle class.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah anyway Microsoft is probably gonna have some trouble with this new policy, and I can't wait for the hilarity Microsoft employees will be pissed.
Speaker 1: I'm waiting.
Speaker 0: you know what though?
Speaker 0: what it's gonna happen is the Microsoft employees.
Speaker 0: They know how to hack windows because they get all the reports.
Speaker 0: if he has the new Vulnerability and then they're just gonna start hacking their own machines it might And they're not gonna want to fix those vulnerabilities because then their own hacks won't work anymore, and it'll be funny.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be great all right.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day is pretty old.
Speaker 1: in fact It's real old.
Speaker 1: we saw it way back at RIT in like 2003 2004.
Speaker 0: So this is like a thing of the day of ancient times.
Speaker 1: It's more than I realized.
Speaker 1: it's so old.
Speaker 1: it was before we started doing geek nights And I don't know how many of you have seen it because it's kind of faded from The limelight.
Speaker 0: should we start doing archaeological things of the day we could do a thing of the day Dinosaurs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right all right.
Speaker 1: This is a series of movies.
Speaker 1: I don't think it'll ever be completed, but there's four of them.
Speaker 1: the second one is in my opinion by far the greatest of them.
Speaker 1: They are Mario the story done in a super overdramatic Really really dark and serious way, but with the original sprites Like the Mario one and doki-doki panic sprites.
Speaker 1: The only doki-doki panic sprites are the toads which they needed to use because there was no sideways facing toad in Mario 1.
Speaker 0: No There was only the front facing toad at the end of the level.
Speaker 0: who said the princess is another castle bitch?
Speaker 1: in the very least.
Speaker 1: Watch the second of these videos.
Speaker 1: the first one first works, but the second video is the best one.
Speaker 0: It's really really cool Yep, and if you already know as you've seen is already Yeah, it did show.
Speaker 1: I mean it shows the army of Koopa attacking the Mushroom Kingdom in an awesome way.
Speaker 1: It feels very much like the second Lord of the Rings movie hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah with the epicness Yeah, maybe giant army all right.
Speaker 0: so everyone knows about YouTube and We have a lot of things of the day that are specific videos from YouTube and/or Google video.
Speaker 0: But today I found a crazy thing on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Apparently on YouTube you can make playlists of videos and Some user on YouTube named dig user as in dig.
Speaker 0: the website Has created a bunch of playlists and these playlists consist of numerous complete episodes of popular cartoon shows.
Speaker 0: And we got some item maniacs Aquitaine Batman whoo Beavis the butthead Bobby's world
Speaker 1: like Bobby's world
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna read them all but we got some inspector gadgets Voltron
Speaker 1: captain and the game master
Speaker 0: captain and Mario Super Show pink in the brain muppet babies x-men Mickey Mouse real ghostbusters etc.
Speaker 0: etc.
Speaker 0: It's a there's a lot of good stuff, and you can watch it all on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Hurry up and watch it before they take it down.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know what I'm doing tonight.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, we got to get one of those Firefox extensions and lets us download videos from YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: It is pretty slow But what it's worth it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see to watch some of these old shows that aren't on DVD or won't be on DVD.
Speaker 1: the Super Mario Brothers show is Yeah, it's actually in the Netflix queue.
Speaker 0: I think it's actually in this giant box set you can get for like 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like eight discs all of the Mario Super Show 20 bucks 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't remember.
Speaker 1: So we haven't talked about board games in a while mostly because there's been you know e3 and all this video game news lately.
Speaker 0: Yep, and recently the let's look at Mark Johnson who has the cool board games to go podcast.
Speaker 0: He meant she found discovered us and mentioned us in his podcast and so a lot of his listeners came over So we will entertain them with some board game talk that they have been no doubt awaiting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now one of our favorite game.
Speaker 1: I mean we have we have a huge pile of games.
Speaker 1: We have more games than most people we know just piled up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course compared to super board game guys We got nothing.
Speaker 1: Well, partly because we don't really if a game sucks.
Speaker 1: We just get rid of it or we don't buy it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the only bad game we really have is Hellas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: Yep, and Hellas is really small.
Speaker 1: Yeah, physically speaking I don't really like Ticket to Ride Europe, but it wasn't that bad.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll sell it someday.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 1: I don't like it.
Speaker 0: All right, whatever.
Speaker 1: I like railroad tycoon a lot more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a different kind of game though.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we realized that a lot of these games are so good.
Speaker 1: We play them so often.
Speaker 1: We never even thought to really talk about him on the show.
Speaker 0: I thought to talk about him.
Speaker 0: the problem is he kept talking about the new games We were acquiring and we never went into the backlog of games that we've had forever.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean, we haven't really talked about Puerto Rico Tigers and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: No, none of those games that we've had for years that we played a zillion times.
Speaker 1: So we just we decided one game that I actually didn't play it this weekend, but all the rest of these fools did Alhambra.
Speaker 0: Alhambra is a game that we played a whole bunch and we got it and then we stopped playing it just because we didn't have An opportunity even though we tried to play a bunch of times and then finally this weekend.
Speaker 0: We finally got a game out.
Speaker 1: It's a real handy game because the man it's two to six players.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only thing with more players than that is something like Citadel.
Speaker 1: Citadel's.
Speaker 0: I think Scotland Yard is also two to six, right?
Speaker 0: I think so three to six.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so six players is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Of course, I don't recommend the two-player of Alhambra because it It added it gave us an inside joke Matt Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's start with that.
Speaker 0: Alhambra is a Yeah, Alhambra is a game where it's better to have more players.
Speaker 0: six players is best two players is worst.
Speaker 0: But if you play with two players, the way it works is you're actually playing a three-player game But the third player is an imaginary player.
Speaker 1: He's just some guy named Matt Yeah, the book actually names him as Matt.
Speaker 0: Yes, and Matt has a set.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like black check where the dealer just follows some rules and doesn't actually play.
Speaker 0: Matt is like the dealer in black check.
Speaker 0: He just follows the rules of Matt and makes the decisions that Matt makes.
Speaker 1: I don't think it really.
Speaker 1: it makes many.
Speaker 1: I think he just starts with a bunch of tiles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he just starts with a bunch of tiles sits there.
Speaker 1: Yep He generally just makes the game crappy to play with Matt Mostly because I have to dig through the tile deck pull out X number of tiles do all this other stuff to the game before I can play it.
Speaker 0: yeah, so Basically you don't want even though Alhambra says two to six.
Speaker 0: don't mistake it for a two-player game.
Speaker 0: The two-player game is a hack and it's not fun more unless you're in an emergency and you really have this insane Raging urge to play Alhambra.
Speaker 1: We've had that before.
Speaker 0: so yeah, we did play it with Matt once or twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was terrible.
Speaker 0: Very terrible.
Speaker 1: All right, Alhambra is a very in terms of what you need to do and know an incredibly simple game.
Speaker 1: It has.
Speaker 1: there's money.
Speaker 1: there are four colors of money orange blue green and yellow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're like dinars ducats Somethings and somethings.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I heard it doesn't matter four colors of money.
Speaker 1: and there's what?
Speaker 1: five or six colors of tiles.
Speaker 0: I think the six and You.
Speaker 1: the tiles are square and they have a color on them They have a price on them and they have one two, three four or zero wall segments on them.
Speaker 0: They have zero one.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, they can't have four walls.
Speaker 0: No, they can't Have zero one two or three walls on them.
Speaker 1: and all you do on your turn is you either take some money from a money pool or Buy a piece and put it in your Alhambra.
Speaker 0: Now the gimmick of this game is that You don't have money like monopoly where you make change all over the place.
Speaker 0: You have cards with numbers and colors on them.
Speaker 1: You don't make change.
Speaker 0: So, let's say the only.
Speaker 0: let's say I have a card that says nine orange.
Speaker 0: It's a has a number nine and it's orange and I want to buy a tile that costs five orange.
Speaker 0: I Can't put the nine in and take four back.
Speaker 0: I have to pay with the nine and then take the tile.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is if you pay with exact change Let's say I have a nine orange and the tile cost nine orange I buy it and then I get a free action.
Speaker 0: so I could buy something and then take money on the same turn or Buy two things and take money where.
Speaker 0: normally if you don't get any free actions Your turn is either buy something or take money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you get one action per turn.
Speaker 1: This is very much a game of when it's not your turn.
Speaker 1: There is nothing you can do.
Speaker 1: Don't try to think about your strategy because all it'll do is piss you off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really in Alhambra you have no decisions and no actions that you may take when it's not your turn.
Speaker 1: Absolutely nothing.
Speaker 0: pestering people of course pestering which is key and you know paying a ten counting other people's Alhambra's and how many colors Are and then to see if you're ahead or behind and what moves you should make in the future.
Speaker 0: But other than that, there's nothing you can do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the way the game works is every round you either draw money or buy an Alhambra tile or rearrange your Alhambra.
Speaker 1: But that basically means wow, I suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah This game is all managing actions.
Speaker 0: you get only one.
Speaker 0: you get this pretty much the same number of actions as everyone else.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get more or less and less.
Speaker 0: by some miracle the game ends on a certain players turn.
Speaker 0: You know and oh my god, you get maybe one extra turn of actions by.
Speaker 0: you know Some stroke of luck.
Speaker 0: you can't count on that shit.
Speaker 1: Yep Scoring rounds are semi random as in they occur at semi predetermined.
Speaker 0: Yes about one-third of the way through the game There's a scoring round and about two-thirds of the way through the game of the scoring There's a mechanic of putting the scoring rounds triggering cards in the deck at certain places and then the deck of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the deck of money.
Speaker 0: So the more people take money the faster the scoring grounds come.
Speaker 1: now you take one action per turn.
Speaker 1: You can either take money because there are four money lying face-up and you can take any one money or any Number of money that are no more than five money's worth.
Speaker 0: So if there's a nine a six a two and a one out there you could take just the nine Just the six or you could take just the two or just the one.
Speaker 0: but you can also take the two and the one together.
Speaker 1: If there's all threes out there.
Speaker 1: just cry yourself to sleep.
Speaker 1: Yes, the same as if there's all like fours Yeah, or you can buy an alambra piece.
Speaker 1: now the way to win is To have more than other people of the various colors of alambra pieces in your thing.
Speaker 1: So there were.
Speaker 1: there are different numbers of the colors in the bag because they're secret and they're different Point values for each color.
Speaker 1: purple is worth the most red is worth at least but there's more purple tiles and less red tile.
Speaker 1: Also purple tiles tend to be more aren't the blue tiles at least?
Speaker 1: the blue tiles at least blue Yeah, but the the better tiles the ones that there are more of and that are worth more points also tend to cost more Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So if you want there are like 11 towers in the game, but they all cost at least nine money.
Speaker 0: They're expensive.
Speaker 1: Also, we mentioned there's walls.
Speaker 1: There's also a game of placing your Alhambra together because you start with one open piece and you put a little color thing that says Who you are on it.
Speaker 1: when you buy a tile you stick it on your Alhambra and the rule of that is that walls?
Speaker 1: cannot touch non walls.
Speaker 1: You cannot have holes in your Alhambra.
Speaker 0: Well, you can have a hole but you can't surround an empty space.
Speaker 1: Yes You can't have a full hole Yes, and you can't have a piece that a little dude couldn't walk to from any other part of your Alhambra.
Speaker 0: So if there was a purse an imaginary human being in your Alhambra and it was a real place He has to be able to walk from every place in your Alhambra to every other place in your Alhambra without Jumping over the table or jumping over a wall.
Speaker 1: and you can not rotate pieces.
Speaker 0: No, you can't.
Speaker 1: Unlike Carcassonne and The walls the other than making difficulty for you They are worth points.
Speaker 1: every time there's a scoring round in addition to all the points people get for tiles Everyone gets one point for each wall segment in their longest exterior wall.
Speaker 1: Yep, so there are many games in one but the games don't interfere with each other too much as long as you plan ahead.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alhambra is really a game about planning.
Speaker 0: some people will try to make a giant wall and the thing about making a giant wall Is that you lock yourself in your Alhambra becomes has a giant wall surrounding it?
Speaker 0: And it becomes very difficult to add new tiles to it.
Speaker 0: So even if you have the money to buy tiles You have nowhere to put them in the Alhambra where they will fit.
Speaker 1: You'll see the people who fall for this trap.
Speaker 1: at the end of the game they're buying pieces and putting them in their sideboard and then spending action after action trying to get these pieces into the Alhambra by Moving things around
Speaker 0: and in the meantime They're not buying any new tiles or getting any new money and everyone else is and they lose.
Speaker 1: Anytime you waste an action in this game, you just drop down a peg.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you ever have to rearrange your Alhambra or use the reserve board you're pretty much gonna lose unless by some.
Speaker 0: the only time I can see using the reserve board is if you have such a Extra mounds of money and you have it A tile that you can buy on this turn that someone else who's right up on your ass on the scoring track really needs to Win.
Speaker 0: you can buy that tile to prevent them from getting it and then let's say it's a tile That's going to ruin your Alhambra or it won't get you any points by adding it to your Alhambra.
Speaker 0: Just stick it in your sideboard and you it won't matter.
Speaker 0: That's the only real time I can see the reserve pile being useful.
Speaker 0: Other than that if you have to use that reserve board you better be scoring a zillion points with that action or else.
Speaker 1: Now we said there were four colors of money and there are all these colors of tiles.
Speaker 1: The way you buy a tile is like we said you don't get change back you whenever.
Speaker 1: if you pay too much You don't get it back.
Speaker 1: If you pay exact change you get a bonus by having another action.
Speaker 1: there are four colors of money and there's a little board that has four spots with the colors on them.
Speaker 1: if A tile is sitting in the yellow spot.
Speaker 1: You can only use yellow money on it.
Speaker 0: This is what really messes with the game is because there's no way you could.
Speaker 0: you can know what tile you need But you have no idea what color of money you will need to buy it.
Speaker 0: So you have to either concentrate on a few colors of money and hope the good tiles show up there or Just keep taking all colors of money and have a nice wide spread.
Speaker 0: So no matter what tile shows up you might be able to buy it.
Speaker 0: Of course then you won't.
Speaker 0: you might not have enough to buy really expensive tiles.
Speaker 1: So now there there is.
Speaker 1: definitely is some luck involved in the game and you know Which tiles and which money come up when and in what order?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's significant luck, but it's not out of control It's it's much.
Speaker 1: it's less luck than even poker because as long as you're making good decisions The luck can't screw you so much and you'll do well in the end anyway.
Speaker 1: And if you're a better player than your friends in aggregate, you'll win more often Significantly more often.
Speaker 0: Yep, like people who don't know what they're doing in Alhambra will often take money when they don't need to or They will refuse to buy a tile for any exact change.
Speaker 0: Even when it gives them a huge advantage and score wise.
Speaker 0: or Maybe they'll hoard money hoping to buy a whole bunch of tiles, you know in the future But then they won't score in the first and second scoring rounds.
Speaker 1: Actually, I've done that to great effect by ignoring the first scoring round.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the first scoring round you can ignore but you can't ignore completely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can ignore it a little bit, but the second scoring round you can't ignore anymore because there's too many points.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean the game is really fun.
Speaker 1: I really enjoy it.
Speaker 1: It starts to break down if everyone who's playing is very very very good at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if everyone is very very good at Alhambra and you're all playing together What ends up happening is the winner is determined by what money comes up Who draws what money at the beginning and what tiles show up when on which squares.
Speaker 0: because you can't do anything to anyone else.
Speaker 0: All you can do is do the best with what you get on your turn.
Speaker 1: but luckily it has the Carcassonne effect of even though you have very few actual decisions to make during the game and The game is very much, you know You're affected a lot by what happens and what comes up on the board and what money or what pieces appear.
Speaker 1: certain people still tend to win the game a lot more often than other people and The luck is really mitigated by the skill and the decision-making in the strategy.
Speaker 0: Yep You're not gonna find a whole bunch of people who all have such a similar Strategy and thinking that they'll cancel each other out and the whole thing will come down to luck, but it could.
Speaker 1: it could happen Yep, and the game is definitely I mean Carcassonne is pretty much almost pure tactics.
Speaker 1: There's very little strategy involved.
Speaker 1: Alhambra is there's definitely a tactical element But it's much more strategic in that because there's so many turns and so many tiles even though you can't have a strategy turn to turn you can have a broad strategy and You'll be able to do it because the tiles will come up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you come up with a really specific strategy, like I'm going to buy all the green tiles That's not gonna do it.
Speaker 0: a good strategy for Alhambra is I'm going to concentrate on the colors that other people don't concentrate on at least one of which will be one of the top Three colors of working points.
Speaker 1: Yep, or things like I'm gonna go after towers and such early in the game And then I'm gonna ignore them later in the game when everyone else is fighting over them and I'm gonna go.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go after walls for the first two rounds ignore them in the third round stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Or I'm gonna take a whole bunch of money early on and only buy a couple tiles in the first scoring round So that when the second score ground comes around and I have a better idea of what people have I will buy the tiles that other people don't have to Maximize my points versus them.
Speaker 0: So no one will be competing with me on the same colors.
Speaker 1: There's also the strategy of taking money and using money in such a way that you get the most number of exact change purchases Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: that is key and a lot of people really forget that.
Speaker 1: or they'll see a piece and they want it so much They'll spend their money and buy it or they'll always take the big money when it comes up and they'll negotiate Like the little money.
Speaker 1: that's really useful to make exact change.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing about big money and little money is that in general?
Speaker 0: But if you take the big money You can buy the big tiles and the people who take the big money all the time will get more big tiles and more points.
Speaker 0: But if you get enough exact changes you can beat that and that's really the way to win.
Speaker 0: is the exact change?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I found that the people who take the big money every time no matter what when it's there or when they need money They never have exact change.
Speaker 1: They never win either.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, you don't take the big money every time but let's you know Let's see if it you get.
Speaker 0: a look at what's in your hand when you take money is what it really is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you've got say a four in your hand and you have a choice between Eight and a nine Well, you're gonna take the eight instead of the nine because there are there tiles out there that cost twelve and not really so Many.
Speaker 0: the cost thirteen.
Speaker 1: also if you see a situation like three one one are out there or two one one one It seems like whenever there's a situation like that people scoop it up.
Speaker 1: Of course cuz getting all those little cards is real great to fill in the cracks between your exact change making machine Yep.
Speaker 0: However, here's a good example from the game I just played.
Speaker 0: I started the game with two yellow ones, right and I didn't spend them ever.
Speaker 0: No the opportunity never came up to spend those cards.
Speaker 1: the other problem with that is if you take a bunch of money cards that now puts a bunch of new money cards out which either may trigger a scoring round or May allow someone else to take the money you actually wanted because now they have a choice.
Speaker 0: That's one aspect of the strategy of a lambda that I just ignore.
Speaker 0: I pay attention to the colors of the tiles the walls and The money and making sure I don't screw up my Alhambra and what other.
Speaker 0: I may pay attention to what other people have in their Alhambra, so I make sure mine isn't going to be competing with anyone who's too strong.
Speaker 1: See I count cards.
Speaker 1: I pay attention to who's spending what colors money.
Speaker 1: so I know who has money what color and who doesn't.
Speaker 0: I pay attention.
Speaker 1: It's too much effort to pay attention that for me I don't keep it like specifically like I have no idea how much money someone has.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I know I know trends like Pete's taking a lot of green money.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I noticed that Scott's spending a lot of green money.
Speaker 0: I noticed when someone takes a specific color of money a lot or I can look and see when someone is very there's a tile That's sitting out on the board and I can tell when someone really wants it and just scoop it out from under him.
Speaker 0: Or I can tell when a money comes up that someone really wants that particular money and I'll take it.
Speaker 0: They don't get it.
Speaker 1: I really pay attention to when the scoring rounds are coming.
Speaker 0: I kind of pay attention when the scoring rounds are coming, but you know, it is sort of random.
Speaker 0: But I will look at the size of the deck and be like, okay the first scoring rounds coming up I often will take a bunch of money early on to try and blitz the first scoring round.
Speaker 0: That can work depending on what tiles show up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it once again That's a tactical decision more so than a strategic one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just kind of play it as it goes.
Speaker 0: every turn I look I see the four tiles I see the four money and I do the best I can Pretty much.
Speaker 0: if I can buy something for exact change I'll almost always do it unless it's going to screw up my Alhambra origins to useless piece.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there isn't like sometimes someone else will have.
Speaker 1: If everyone else has four three three and two towers respectively, you're not gonna buy that tower for exact change.
Speaker 0: I think that's all the towers in the game actually four five six seven eight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's eleven towers.
Speaker 0: I think so on three three three three.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know buying the one tower won't help you unless it's got some really nice walls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think what happens is that the tiles that have more walls are cheaper than the ones that have less walls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they restrict you a lot.
Speaker 0: So the tile that has three walls on it the pink the tower with three walls is cheaper than the tile would note the tower With no walls, but they both count equally as towers.
Speaker 0: So if you build your Alhambra really slick like You can fit the three walled pieces in without limiting your options and also make a nice.
Speaker 0: You know don't go for the longest wall because you don't get special bonus points for longest wall.
Speaker 0: You get points for having a wall.
Speaker 0: So you just need to have your wall sufficiently long.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know increases the gap between you and the other players because you're gonna get more points from the scoring rounds than you'll ever get From the walls ever though.
Speaker 1: I've seen people do very well with a wall heavy but not wall centric strategy.
Speaker 1: Yes, I mean there are people who they don't have so much in this car grounds.
Speaker 1: They just have this massive wall because it keeps getting points.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Yep, the wall will score points.
Speaker 1: No one can take those going around.
Speaker 1: basically if you can get a big wall in the first scoring round That's fantastic because that doesn't go away and in the first scoring round the wall is worth more than the scoring round is.
Speaker 1: I mean basically in the first round the first scoring round Every wall you have counts it.
Speaker 1: consider it three points because it's gonna be scored two more times Yeah, and then the wall becomes less and less valuable as the game goes on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's one good thing Especially because the wall tile the heavy wall tiles are cheaper and early in the game You have less money because you've been taking it for less time.
Speaker 0: you can buy the tiles that are wall heavy make a big wall without limiting yourself too much and Get a bunch of points and then the rest of the game buy the more expensive tiles to get the colors.
Speaker 1: But the bigger wall you make the harder it is to expand later when you're buying a lot of tiles later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I said later twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, if you make a stupid wall that you know cuts off like the top of your Alhambra and the left of your Alhambra Well now any tiles that were that need to be attached to the top or left You're not gonna be able to put him in.
Speaker 1: was it?
Speaker 1: you repeat who made the?
Speaker 1: Alhambra that basically had three of the three wall pieces and then there's a hole in the top and they were screwed.
Speaker 1: I think it was paid.
Speaker 0: I think I did it once or Pete did it once I don't know.
Speaker 1: I did something similar where I Didn't have any open spaces to the top or left of my Alhambra and all the pieces that were coming out only had holes For a top or left placement.
Speaker 1: No, I couldn't put anything in my Alhambra.
Speaker 0: I think a good way to make an Alhambra is to just kind of stretch it out You know make it really long as you can and then sort of make branches.
Speaker 0: that way you can add any tile you want Onto the branches without needing to you know cut off.
Speaker 0: if you have a square Alhambra or you know Generally a blob then you can cut it off too easily.
Speaker 0: So if you make one that sort of branches out like a like a fractal You know just like a branch here to branch there.
Speaker 0: Then you can attach wall pieces to those without limiting your options.
Speaker 1: Yep, plus I mean my general strategy there is to always have at least one hole in every cardinal direction.
Speaker 0: Yep, I try to keep one hole in every cardinal direction and you know Sometimes I can't and I'm willing to sacrifice one if the tile is really important.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially near the end of the game when I won't be getting many more tiles But early on I really try to keep it open.
Speaker 1: Yep, because it's sticking on one of those wall this tiles into a hole will just suddenly open your board up like crazy.
Speaker 1: Yep Now in terms of rearranging your Alhambra We have yet to see an instance where doing it meant anything other than you fucked up earlier in the game And now you're losing.
Speaker 1: I've never seen someone win after rearranging the Alhambra ever because rearranging the Alhambra is the game Obviously is doing it as sort of a punishment, but you can still keep playing the game.
Speaker 1: You're not totally done, but you still can't win.
Speaker 1: it punishes you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can either take a piece from your sideboard and put it on your Alhambra.
Speaker 1: Now if you put it in the sideboard, that means it didn't fit in your Alhambra Which means it's probably not gonna fit now either.
Speaker 1: unless you built a whole bunch of stuff You can swap it.
Speaker 0: if you you know, there might be some really ever tile.
Speaker 1: But I point out swapping a piece that just you still waste an action.
Speaker 0: because no waste an action.
Speaker 1: now You've spent an action and you still have a piece in your sideboard.
Speaker 0: Yep It's only worth it if the piece is worth so many points.
Speaker 0: It's like this incredibly rare instance that you know It would be useful and they allow you to do it in that incredibly rare instance.
Speaker 0: that way You know in case the game gets super crazy, you don't just lose because you can't do something Yep, or you can take a piece out of your Alhambra.
Speaker 1: Those are the only three options.
Speaker 1: So it usually to do anything useful with the sideboard.
Speaker 1: You have to spend at least two actions.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Sideboard and that's one action and then the next turn you have to put the tiles.
Speaker 0: so either swap the tile Which is the best situation?
Speaker 0: Well, no, the best situation is not doing anything at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not using the sideboard.
Speaker 0: But you know the next best option is you swap it and then insert the tile on the next turn.
Speaker 0: One good strategy I've noticed is you buy something and you put it in the sideboard and you let it sit there.
Speaker 0: Then you just keep playing the game as usual and eventually at some point you buy something for exact change And then take the tile from the sideboard and bring it in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good strategy.
Speaker 0: with the free action You know, it's like I don't have a place for this now, but I need it and I'll have a place for it later.
Speaker 0: You know you make a place with buying something for exact change bring it in on the free action and you didn't really lose an Action for that and it's it works pretty well.
Speaker 1: Now there's also a fun mechanic.
Speaker 1: at the end of the game the game ends.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are two scoring rounds about 1/3 and about 2/3 of the way through the game.
Speaker 1: Then there's the final scoring round which happens when the bag of tiles runs out.
Speaker 1: the rule there and I just thought this was needs.
Speaker 1: at the end of the game when there are no more tiles left the fall the tiles that are left are put in the little buying box the little board and Whoever has the most money in their hand at the end of the game of each color Gets whatever tile.
Speaker 1: it was in the case of a tie.
Speaker 1: No one gets it.
Speaker 0: so if you have the most green money and there's one tile left in the green spot at the end of the game you get That and the same for yellow orange blue, whatever It just.
Speaker 1: it makes the end game even if there's no more tiles.
Speaker 1: you need or you can't.
Speaker 1: you don't have enough money and the game Is gonna end soon.
Speaker 1: You can still go for that and there's still some decisions to make.
Speaker 0: Yeah, generally what I do is because new tiles are put into the number one spot first Which I think is I don't know what color it is.
Speaker 0: I don't have the board right here.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah The tiles.
Speaker 0: when the new tiles come out they're placed in the top left spot on the little board first Which is a particular color of money.
Speaker 0: So towards the end of the game if you pretty much aren't buying too much any more stuff Start collecting that color of money and the second color of money because those are the spots most likely to contain a tile up For auction at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the last space is least likely because there's a bunch of mechanics to keep people from cheating or putting tiles.
Speaker 1: You know where they'd be useful to them on your turn.
Speaker 1: You know You buy your action.
Speaker 1: you either buy a tile or you take a card.
Speaker 1: when your turn is over you replenish whatever is there.
Speaker 1: So if you took two money cards, you draw two more money cards.
Speaker 1: If you bought four tiles you put out four new tiles.
Speaker 1: You have to place the tiles on the board in the order that you draw them in the order on the board.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you draw a tile you look at it and you say ooh I really need this.
Speaker 0: and then you say I have a lot of orange money.
Speaker 0: You just put it on the orange spot.
Speaker 0: Well, that's no good.
Speaker 0: You have yet to put it in the top leftmost spot and then the top right and then the bottom left in the bottom, right?
Speaker 0: Depending on which ones are open and available.
Speaker 1: Now all in all a lumber is a solid game.
Speaker 1: I love it Very solid.
Speaker 0: so I won this field this yard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's also.
Speaker 1: it was 2003.
Speaker 1: I think that it won it.
Speaker 1: It's also a very fun game.
Speaker 1: It's it's actually pretty quick.
Speaker 1: It's very very easy to teach to people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a game where you don't have to be a crazy strategy gamer guy to play it.
Speaker 0: You know families can play this game pretty easily You know, you just got to get them to do it.
Speaker 1: and while the strategies can be fairly complex in terms of actual thinking power The game is very light.
Speaker 1: You can play the game and have a conversation.
Speaker 1: You can play the game while people are watching a movie on TV.
Speaker 1: You can play the game while friends are over.
Speaker 1: you can play the game while you're drunk.
Speaker 0: Yep, and While someone who's big on strategy and will win more often People who don't have a lot of strategy or thinking can still play and have fun Yep, even though they'll get their asses handed to them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the way the game works You never really.
Speaker 1: even if you're losing you never really feel like you're wasting your time.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because even if you're really terrible at the game you still collect money at generally the same rate as everyone else and you still buy Tiles because no one can interfere with you.
Speaker 0: You just do whatever you do on your turn.
Speaker 0: You'll just be doing less on your turn than other people, but you'll still be buying tiles and making a happy Alhambra, which is fun.
Speaker 1: It's one of those rare games.
Speaker 1: That's very beginner friendly, but also very hardcore gamer friendly Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Now there's some expansions which I've never played.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they seem to be trying to pull with this what they pulled with Carcassonne.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where they have two billion expansions, but I don't know about them.
Speaker 0: I haven't played them yet.
Speaker 1: Maybe if we ever get them, it's all you because I bought all those Carcassonne expansions.
Speaker 0: That's because you own Carcassonne.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I own a longer - that's right bastard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're not getting any.
Speaker 0: I don't buy games that require expansions.
Speaker 1: They're not for you.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: But he said yeah any game that requires expansions or has expansions is definitely a bad road to go down.
Speaker 1: Well, it's I mean Carcassonne.
Speaker 1: We talked about it a while ago the inns and cathedrals.
Speaker 1: expansion takes a good game and makes it great Like it fixes everything with the.
Speaker 0: you know, if that's the thing then that should be the game and the other expansion shouldn't exist.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well it came out later.
Speaker 1: I mean look the river was an expansion.
Speaker 1: then they just threw it in the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and of course that's a bad expansion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a beginner's expansion.
Speaker 0: I say well settlers has expansions.
Speaker 0: It's also a game you have.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but settlers is broken.
Speaker 1: like settlers was real fun until I got good at games and realized that settlers is broken.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh Well, I think that the point was really driven home.
Speaker 1: when I played in a sanctioned settlers tournament at ubercon a while ago Came down to the dice rolls.
Speaker 1: Yep, like the first two rounds I won but it was.
Speaker 1: I mean there was a wide range of skills and Decisions would end the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you make a decision you win you lose The fight the semi-finals where I got knocked out.
Speaker 1: I will always say that every single person in my game of four was equally good and we were all just sitting there.
Speaker 1: No one would trade with anyone.
Speaker 1: yeah, like there were maybe four or five trades in the whole game and the points were like three three three three three four three three three three three four And it was like nine nine nine nine and then someone got ten.
Speaker 1: Yeah Everyone made the exact optimal decision at every point and it just came down to the dice.
Speaker 0: Mmm Yeah, Alhambra doesn't have that problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it seems random what tiles come up, but all the decisions are made by you and by the other players Mm-hmm, so there's not so much there's no game driven randomness so much, but there's a lot of player driven not randomness But unpredictability.
Speaker 0: Yeah, another thing about Alhambra is that the game itself is really nice.
Speaker 0: It has nice Cardboard boards has nice wooden pieces.
Speaker 0: The tiles are really nice.
Speaker 0: the cards, you know, I usually hate You know, I like the cart little cardboard token money or chip money mostly and Card money is like, you know second best to that.
Speaker 1: The worst is paper money.
Speaker 0: paper money is absolute crap, but the Cardboard money and Alhambra isn't bad.
Speaker 0: It's like great because it's like your hand of cards.
Speaker 1: Yes It doesn't even feel like money.
Speaker 1: It feels like a card game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it feels like I got a hand of cards in my you know Which is really cool Easy to manage everything works out nice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a cheap high production value good game for anyone of any level of board gaming skill.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: Yep Alhambra.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and We thought about talking about another game today.
Speaker 1: We've already gone almost an hour.
Speaker 0: But have we really?
Speaker 1: yeah, okay Which is good because that means you know a year from now We'll still have Tuesday episodes because we won't just do all of our games and run out.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: We'll just have to buy more games.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling next week.
Speaker 1: We'll either talk about the new Mario DS game that we both beaten.
Speaker 0: I think that's what we're gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: and we'd like to talk about Stratego at some point.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, we'll do that.
Speaker 1: It's you know, I mean, it's all crap.
Speaker 1: Milton Bradley game, but we bought it for like four bucks.
Speaker 0: It was ten bucks Oh us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's still worth it.
Speaker 0: And we pretty much any Milton Bradley or Parker Brothers game is $15 or less depending on the number of pieces and we played the hell out of it.
Speaker 1: And now that we're older and wiser and know about German games We actually have insightful things to say about Stratego.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right, we can maybe do in two weeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll do that at some point cool.
Speaker 1: So once again, welcome all the new listeners from all the other podcasts who have mentioned us.
Speaker 1: Hooray Where.
Speaker 1: I hope the guy in Bangkok keeps listening.
Speaker 1: Yay Bangkok Yeah, he actually made a comment in the email he sent us about How the inside it's not.
Speaker 1: it's hard to tell if our inside jokes are just American isms or if it's just us being weird.
Speaker 0: No, our inside jokes are very inside.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most Americans have no idea what we're talking about.
Speaker 0: Just geeks Yeah, but apparently even people have no idea what we're talking about.
Speaker 0: Think we're hysterical, you know We're not trying to be hysterical like comedians.
Speaker 0: This is what we're always like.
Speaker 1: Yeah when we're trying to be hysterical.
Speaker 1: It's usually Kind of scary.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, tell all your friends to listen to geek nights Yeah, and go to our forums and go to our website.
Speaker 0: front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: and that was geek nights with rim and Scott Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 1 5 3 7.
Speaker 1: geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.