Speaker 0: It's Tuesday April 4th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We bring you our coverage of gaming for hope at Marist College.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: We've pretty much been playing Metroid and Tetris non-stop since we got them But you're not gonna hear about those today.
Speaker 0: No not for a couple weeks at least dumb dumb dumb.
Speaker 0: Now today you're gonna hear about some other things good things though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well we can start with some news.
Speaker 0: I beat Calus.
Speaker 0: Well I beat Scott at Calus.
Speaker 1: I Also beat you at Calus.
Speaker 0: I beat him in three rounds.
Speaker 0: I think I set a record.
Speaker 1: That's only cuz I forfeited Because I neglected to look at an important piece of information in the game.
Speaker 0: Yes, the piece of information was rim is going to win.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the thing is it's like I had this move.
Speaker 1: I could have done this move real easily, and I would have been just fine if I had done this move.
Speaker 1: But I said you know what I can do this move next round.
Speaker 1: Why should I do with this round?
Speaker 1: I didn't even look at the board and realize that this was the round.
Speaker 1: I had to do it, and I said oh oops well there that goes.
Speaker 0: yep Well at least I can say I have won sixty six point six.
Speaker 0: repeating percent of all games of Calus I've ever played.
Speaker 1: I have one thirty three point three three three percent of all games of gala side just three three three three three three three three three three three three five is right out.
Speaker 0: Also is for unless it's anyway to it then immediately proceed to three.
Speaker 0: Anyway in the actual news I'm sure you're all aware that Michigan among other states had recently tried to pass a law.
Speaker 0: in fact They did pass a law restricting the sale of certain mature video games to minors.
Speaker 1: Just what we need?
Speaker 1: more Politicians you know trying to get votes by pandering to the family types.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean honestly I'm generally a big fan of Hillary Clinton as controversial of a Politician as that may be but I really dislike the fact that she always seems to jump on this anti-video game bandwagon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't really care.
Speaker 1: You know by their way about Hillary.
Speaker 1: I'm not you know whatever But it really pisses me off when there's all these people who are like otherwise okay, and then they're like video games are evil Lieberman.
Speaker 1: yeah Lieberman is.
Speaker 1: he's not a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Okay, but now he's not.
Speaker 1: he's like 75%.
Speaker 0: Okay, of course.
Speaker 0: There's always a the right honorable Jack Thompson Jack down Jack Thompson.
Speaker 1: Zero percent okay in fact.
Speaker 0: He's negative a hundred percent, okay You know I think we've made fun of Jack Thompson in the past 86 episodes of geek nights more than we've made fun of anyone else.
Speaker 0: well No, this is the first time we've mentioned him in a long time Yeah, but we mentioned him almost every day for like two weeks.
Speaker 1: Cuz our podcast started amid Thompson gate.
Speaker 1: yeah, in fact it did like Thompson gates one two and three.
Speaker 1: Wow at the sometime We're gonna have to do a retrospective When Jack Thompson dies which I don't imagine will be too too long from now.
Speaker 1: We'll do a look back on the life of Jack Thompson.
Speaker 0: You know thinking back I just think that the word retrospective is probably a little highbrow for what we do.
Speaker 1: We'll give him a lifetime achievement award for Worst person ever most humor provided.
Speaker 1: No, no, there's some other things that are provided.
Speaker 1: slightly more humor.
Speaker 1: Yeah like that freaking Dana Carvey show that was on HBO every day for like a Year you were just looking for a way to bring that up cuz we were talking about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz it's in my head just chopping broccoli.
Speaker 1: You know what I was saying before when you weren't even in the room.
Speaker 1: What were you saying make it to make it time make it teeny make it to each time I click it's not To you all right.
Speaker 0: That was off topic.
Speaker 0: And if you don't know what we were talking about, well, we're gonna talk about that some Thursday.
Speaker 0: I think oh, no, I think we could do a whole show on that probably.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this Michigan law basically, because I mean this law was passed and it restricted the sale of games that were possibly violent or obscene or whatever to minors and a state judge first ruled that there was going to be an injunction against this law being enforced while he ruled on the Trial that I think the ESA had put against the law.
Speaker 1: for anyone who doesn't know Injunction means the law doesn't count until the judge says so yeah, it's like if I made a law that said rim has to stand on his head and Then a judge said wait, I'm gonna put an injunction.
Speaker 1: That means rim doesn't have to stand on his head yet He had to wait.
Speaker 0: Yeah now injunctions are used usually if the judge thinks that there's going to be some Undo harm that would come about as a result of a situation or a ruling or a law that is in place and he.
Speaker 0: Generally if a judge puts forth an injunction, there's a decent chance He's gonna overturn whatever he put the injunction against in the first place.
Speaker 0: That's basically what it is because if he doesn't think he's gonna overturn it he wouldn't bother.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: but anyway, he put the injunction some months ago and Just now he ruled on the law and it was basically can found flagrantly Unconstitutional.
Speaker 1: so he pretty much spent those months writing and not thinking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think he thought right away with that injunction action.
Speaker 0: I mean basically it came down to the fact that in addition to the fact that the law was just Right out of the First Amendment and there are all sorts of constitutional problems with it The the lowest test of whether or not a law is constitutional.
Speaker 0: Is that will.
Speaker 0: does the law perform a stated purpose?
Speaker 0: you know, that's like the lowest lowest thing and It's usually trivial.
Speaker 0: I mean if you make a law you can assume that it'll carry out its stated purpose.
Speaker 1: I mean like the purpose of the law is to give rim a headache Rim must stand on his head.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there I go.
Speaker 0: I did it.
Speaker 0: Now the law is bad may be bad for other reasons but that's like the lowest bottom rung.
Speaker 0: if you can't make that the Supreme Court's just gonna laugh at you and You won't even make it to the Supreme Court.
Speaker 0: now this law.
Speaker 0: the purpose of the law was to stop Violence caused by video games among children and they had all sorts of studies to try and back this up.
Speaker 1: the studies They paid for that are to have no science in them.
Speaker 0: Now the judge had this to say Dr.
Speaker 0: Anderson studies have not provided any evidence that the relationship between violent video games and aggressive behavior exists.
Speaker 1: You know what that tells me?
Speaker 1: The judge fucking read the study unlike some other people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I bet you the Congress people don't read the study.
Speaker 1: It gets better.
Speaker 0: the research not only fails to provide concrete evidence that there is a connection between violent media and aggressive behavior It also fails to distinguish between video games and other forms of media.
Speaker 0: Yep, the law was just crazy.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: Some people have said that why should this be bad?
Speaker 0: I mean there are laws against letting kids see R-rated movies and all that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, no, they're all right.
Speaker 0: That's completely untrue.
Speaker 1: There is no law that says a kid can't see an R-rated movie.
Speaker 0: There are laws against corrupting minors But those laws are fairly difficult to invoke and they vary state to state and county to county
Speaker 1: to corrupt a minor You pretty much have to like prostitute them out on the street
Speaker 0: or show them hardcore snuff pornography
Speaker 1: Yeah Or something like that.
Speaker 0: now as when it comes to movies like R-rated movies or even quote MC 17 or x-rated movies There's no law.
Speaker 0: the theaters that don't let kids in or check ID and all that are Really only doing that because they're afraid that the government might pass a law Mm-hmm, but there's absolutely no legal precedent.
Speaker 0: and in fact where I grew up There was one theater that just didn't enforce that at all and they'd show R-rated movies to anyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah I can't tell you how many times like we go to a theater and they didn't ask for ID.
Speaker 1: and now when they ask for ID like your parent comes says let him in and let him in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and no one cares the theater wants to.
Speaker 1: they want to sell tickets to 17 year old kids.
Speaker 1: They know it's not gonna.
Speaker 1: you know, screw you over, you know MPA does one thing good.
Speaker 1: But something else about this law is that most of the comments I saw about it on the internet were Lambasting the state congresspeople for trying to push it and the reason they were doing this is they were saying Look at this.
Speaker 1: This guy knows this law is unconstitutional.
Speaker 1: The congressman even said the law was probably unconstitutional and that he was gonna try to get it passed anyway, and that means that he is Spending state tax money on the stupid court system.
Speaker 1: He's making a law where he knows everyone is gonna have to spend money to get it thrown out.
Speaker 0: That's like when South Carolina recently tried to ban abortion Straight up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know Supreme Court Roe vs.
Speaker 0: Wade precedent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I'm gonna make a law and waste a whole bunch of know what I got it.
Speaker 0: I got a great idea for a law.
Speaker 0: Let's pass a law that says that whenever troops from overseas come home They'll be quartered in people's houses.
Speaker 1: Awesome that'd be fantastic.
Speaker 1: I got a better idea, huh?
Speaker 1: If there's ever a war in this country like someone invades us Everyone's house becomes a military base.
Speaker 0: All right Great.
Speaker 0: And while we're at it Let's uh add a clause to the police charter saying that they can always engage in unreasonable search and seizure.
Speaker 0: Dude, I want to see a lot more cruel and unusual punishment out there.
Speaker 1: Wait, here's another one.
Speaker 1: No one can possess ethanol Didn't they try that?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah It worked just as well.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Here's a quick trivia.
Speaker 0: the first person to post in the forums the name of the federal law that was passed that actually enacted prohibition will win nothing other than me giving you a shout out at some point
Speaker 1: and We'll know if you use Wikipedia or the Google or something because that's totally cheating.
Speaker 0: You know what though that's fine because in this case if you don't know you'll have to find out and it yeah Yeah, it doesn't matter if we're ever actually gonna give a real valuable prize.
Speaker 0: It'll be some something you can wick.
Speaker 1: It won't be something you can just look up.
Speaker 1: It'll be something you have to figure out or some shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: Now anyway now the ESA they're the ones who actually put forth the lawsuit to get rid of this law.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you don't know the ESA is just like the MPAA and RIA only instead of being about video game Instead of being about movies and music.
Speaker 1: They're about video games.
Speaker 0: Well, the other thing is they actually seem to care about the video game industry and do anything they can to protect it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but because the video game industry isn't dying in a gutter And it's making a hajillion dollars by selling awesome video games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know and you don't see them.
Speaker 1: I mean they say bad things about piracy, but you don't see them going around all kinds of hoo-ha Like the MPAA is trying to make all kinds of laws and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, they just found technological solutions.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's actually oh, yeah great like Star Force.
Speaker 0: Well, no, that's terrible.
Speaker 0: But look at consoles.
Speaker 0: It's almost impossible to pirate games of a current generation console.
Speaker 0: No, you know like the current one that's around you're not gonna be able to pirate Xbox 360 games for a while.
Speaker 0: No, not really, but previous generations get easier and easier to pirate over time.
Speaker 0: But they seem to care less and less about that because that's almost lost revenue.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I think Nintendo's got it really going on.
Speaker 1: see what they realized is.
Speaker 1: Okay, firstly is cartridges.
Speaker 1: You can't pirate those.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Now we can't use cartridges anymore.
Speaker 1: Okay, people are even pirating GBA games at this point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people are pirating Diaz games at this point.
Speaker 0: Hey, let's compete with the pirates and sell the old games.
Speaker 0: Everyone wants for almost nothing.
Speaker 1: I know here's an even better idea.
Speaker 1: Let's make it fine.
Speaker 1: You can pirate the games.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: You got a revolution controller to work with your computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what are you gonna do now?
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah, or it's like yeah, you can pirate DDR all you want.
Speaker 1: You got to buy a pad from us bitches.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: What do you do, huh?
Speaker 1: Alright, okay.
Speaker 1: So a guy from Microsoft today this Microsoft security guy or whatever.
Speaker 1: He comes out and He says something that everyone's known or at least that I've known for a long time.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now it used to not be a hundred percent true in that You used to always be possible to do what he says can't be done.
Speaker 0: It was just usually not worth the effort.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Let's just not say what it is All right.
Speaker 0: Then it now has gotten to the point where it's absolutely in many cases impossible to do what he said can't be done.
Speaker 0: So he is now, right?
Speaker 1: Everyone have enough suspense.
Speaker 1: Oh All right, so the guy says if you get malware adware spyware Whatever.
Speaker 1: It's becoming really impossible to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: Once you've got it.
Speaker 1: You're done You got to reformat your hard drive and reinstall windows and you know what.
Speaker 0: that's pretty much true.
Speaker 0: now There's really no way to get rid of a lot of this stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean back in the day You could get like a little spyware maybe like, you know a toolbar or something.
Speaker 1: That was no good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, bonsai, buddy.
Speaker 1: You could have it cursor Yeah, you could use adware or you could use spybot and you could clean it out and you'd be alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah, adware used to be this tiny little thing that ran in like 30 seconds and it only searched for like 20 things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's all there was.
Speaker 1: Those are good days.
Speaker 0: Ah good days.
Speaker 1: Nowadays, if you get spywares or malwares or whatever your computer is pretty much done like.
Speaker 1: You're just gonna have to back up all your data Reformat your hard drive reinstall windows put all your data back make sure your data doesn't have spyware still in it.
Speaker 0: And in fact, I remember we were roped into helping an old lady Fix her laptop that wasn't working so well and we found it just a completely infested with I don't know how much Goddamn malware and viruses and just horrible stuff.
Speaker 0: It had even disabled the antivirus stuff that she already had.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the malware had got she probably the Norton probably wasn't updated and probably wasn't scanning.
Speaker 1: So the malware ran and then disabled the Norton.
Speaker 1: so the Norton couldn't be used to remove the malware that had snuck in.
Speaker 1: And she's mainly she was using IE.
Speaker 1: So let this be a lesson to everyone.
Speaker 1: It's really easy to prevent getting spyware.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: So don't get it in the first place.
Speaker 1: now Scott's easy tips.
Speaker 1: I'm not getting it in the first place.
Speaker 1: one use Firefox - don't use windows.
Speaker 0: three Don't go to shady websites.
Speaker 1: for before you download a piece of free software Make sure that you know, it's either open source legitimate free software or that it's like not spyware.
Speaker 0: Basically, if you can't find it on SourceForge or it's not something well known like I don't know Skype.
Speaker 1: And if it's not unlike download calm you can trust download calm yeah, because they check stuff.
Speaker 1: but like if you're looking on the internet for like I need a Free program that does X Y & Z.
Speaker 0: a lot of them seem to be like.
Speaker 1: I need a program that'll make icons for windows or I need a program that will edit this weird type of file or Something that will Oh God do something with DVDs.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: had a flashback to the mid 90s when I don't know how many of you out there were young enough to remember the like Golden Age of wares when pirated software was plentiful and everywhere you just went to where your sites and downloaded it like nice Categorized where sites and you just download like I don't know whatever programs I use.
Speaker 0: back then Macromedia flash like - I don't know all the studios and everywhere's file would come with a dot NFO file and The dot NFO was just a text file that told you you know who cracked the program who pirated it when they did it and Usually some sort of funny quote or something and maybe how to install it how to run the key generator or whatever.
Speaker 0: now There were a lot of NFO viewers out there Because people didn't realize at least stupid people didn't realize that dot NFO files were just text files with a different extension.
Speaker 0: so they download these NFO viewers that would show them the contents of the NFO and Fill their computer with horrible Trojan horses and viruses.
Speaker 1: awesome.
Speaker 0: That was I remember those days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it says right here Dan seglio.
Speaker 1: I don't know Dan seglio is that's his last name I guess said the success of social engineering attacks is a sign of the weakest link in malware defense is human stupidity.
Speaker 1: Social engineering is a very very effective technique.
Speaker 1: We have statistics that shows significant infection rates for the social engineering.
Speaker 1: malware Fishing is a major problem because there really is no patch for human stupidity now.
Speaker 0: We can solve this pretty handily I mean especially in terms of weak passwords.
Speaker 0: if you have a weak password or you're not you're not sure if your password is strong.
Speaker 0: Just email it to us at geek nights, and we'll analyze it and let you know if it's a good password or not.
Speaker 1: Hmm very good advice.
Speaker 1: We'll definitely Set up our free.
Speaker 1: I was ready to get some passwords.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone would.
Speaker 0: I don't think our listeners are that stupid.
Speaker 1: frankly Yeah, yeah, anyone who was that stupid listen to the show would rather get pissed off.
Speaker 1: or who knows yeah?
Speaker 0: Frankly I wonder how much we've actually pissed anyone off because even the the most Horrible things we've said about some of our listeners in the early episodes.
Speaker 0: You're all still listening.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what if we piss you off because that's what we're trying to do sometimes.
Speaker 0: Let us know me.
Speaker 1: send an email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright, you're a pimple on society's ass.
Speaker 1: Most most you are.
Speaker 1: I'm not even joking.
Speaker 0: there is no God and your idiotic human ideals are laughable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but seriously it says here that 250,000 unique machines got this like Fishing like worm that you can only get by doing something stupid.
Speaker 1: God Yeah, so to anyone listening Don't be stupid with your computer.
Speaker 0: my thing is they will Email from someone who says they're from your credit card company And you got to put in your password to like fix something horribly wrong with your account.
Speaker 0: step back and think wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't my credit card company call me if there was something bad or wouldn't they send me a letter or something?
Speaker 0: Would my credit card maybe stop working?
Speaker 1: is the next time before you send money to the Nigerian princess Who's gonna help you out and find out if she's a real princess?
Speaker 1: Yeah And whether she's in another castle or not.
Speaker 1: I Think we're done So.
Speaker 0: things of the day now.
Speaker 0: this apparently I was told Recently is a little bit older than I realized, but this is the first I've seen of it.
Speaker 0: so Basically some dude or girl or someone who played World of Warcraft World of Warcraft again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, World of Warcraft as much as we hate.
Speaker 0: It is a great source of amusement.
Speaker 1: it's like this festering cesspool of crap and Occasionally these really funny things come out of the crap.
Speaker 1: It's like poop.
Speaker 1: No poops poop.
Speaker 1: you want to flush poop down the toilet, but poop jokes are hilarious.
Speaker 0: That was a wonderful metaphor.
Speaker 1: It was great.
Speaker 0: Yeah now first of all before I do my thing of the day I got a beef with the World of Warcraft community.
Speaker 0: How come there are a million million million videos on the internet that say there's something awesome about World of Warcraft But they're just this screen with a guy running and a million buttons everywhere and like some death metal playing over it.
Speaker 1: What the hell that's what World of Warcraft is.
Speaker 0: they're like eight minutes long.
Speaker 0: What are you filming?
Speaker 1: That is what World of Warcraft is and what software are using to make these videos?
Speaker 1: Is there something in World of Warcraft that does this?
Speaker 0: or using some external program or maybe some horrible malware?
Speaker 1: That's what I was about to say when I used to look back in the day for Windows programs that did that.
Speaker 1: They were all either pay money or horrible malware.
Speaker 1: There's one program for Linux that does it.
Speaker 1: It's not malware It's not very good.
Speaker 1: No, so what are you using anyway?
Speaker 0: So this person who played World of Warcraft was in a guild and had a lot of friends died in the real world.
Speaker 1: Oh for real?
Speaker 1: What'd he die of?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: It was actually a girl.
Speaker 0: That's why I clarified because I wasn't too sure but someone corrected someone on dig.
Speaker 1: Okay, so a person died for real.
Speaker 0: so and they apparently all their guild mates contacted the family or something and logged into the account and Set up basically a funeral slash wake slash ceremony in game.
Speaker 1: How did they get the password?
Speaker 0: They like I said, they talked to the family or something.
Speaker 1: the family knew it.
Speaker 0: They set something up.
Speaker 0: All right, and they had this huge elaborate funeral and hundreds hundreds of people lined up to pay their respects to the person they were friends with and They had like a priest in the game who did something and speeches and everyone.
Speaker 1: Wow Wait, I gotta say it sucks that someone dies.
Speaker 1: But if you're doing like if you're serious about a funeral in an MMO, you got a problem.
Speaker 0: Now I honestly I could see this being a somewhat good thing and that I mean if you have friends that you don't Can't meet in the real world and one of them dies I mean, this is probably the only way you can all get together and talk about it.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: You're against real funerals?
Speaker 1: Now you're gonna argue that you're for World of Warcraft funerals.
Speaker 0: I understand that other people view death a lot differently from the way I view it and I can empathize with how other people treat Death.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about this on another show, but I absolutely don't care at all about death.
Speaker 0: Really don't care when people died it happens.
Speaker 0: I don't worry about it me either.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I understand that other people do and I think this would be a cool thing.
Speaker 0: But I'll point out that the world of World of Warcraft That was really kind of awkward to say is a violent horrible dangerous place in game.
Speaker 0: If you're gonna have a funeral event like that of that magnitude You should probably have some guards standing by or something.
Speaker 1: Don't they have a church somewhere or something?
Speaker 0: They did it out in the woods in this nice serene lake or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, great.
Speaker 0: So they're doing this and basically a bunch of guys in an opposing guild got together an army you mean the heroes and This army marched out to where this funeral was hit over a hill.
Speaker 0: One guy like walks out and walks over to like the the priest or whoever.
Speaker 0: the focal point of all this is It's a Google video so I couldn't really see Attacks him and apparently that was the signal because then the army comes over the ridge and they kill Absolutely everyone at the funeral screaming poon poon poon the whole time.
Speaker 1: I Seen it and I knew what this was before we did the podcast.
Speaker 1: It's so funny now.
Speaker 0: the video is great because it starts with actual quotes from various forums of people who were attacked by this.
Speaker 0: after the Fact and the quotes I'm not even gonna read them on the air.
Speaker 0: They're just they're priceless people like I hope your dad dies of a heart attack.
Speaker 0: And then when you're at the funeral a naked guy runs in pushes over the coffin and runs around yelling poon Dude, if someone did that in real life, they would be my hero also.
Speaker 0: But they kill everyone in.
Speaker 0: the video shows like the stately funeral and everyone lining up to pay their respects.
Speaker 0: Then it cuts to this army running through the woods and it keeps cutting back and forth and then it shows the chaos.
Speaker 0: Awesome It was fantastic.
Speaker 1: We should recreate that in real life.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: You know, that could be a project for a mega 64.
Speaker 1: They could be oh my god.
Speaker 1: What would make a 64 do with World of Warcraft?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Oh my god All right, so then you have some thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not that exciting.
Speaker 1: It's it's a simple little web page with some text on it.
Speaker 0: It's not even game related.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you're thinking.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I couldn't find any game related ones that I thought were worthy.
Speaker 1: So whatever it says here on the top of the page computers and the Internet according to normal users and then they're a sequence of sentences that are humorous such as Things that these are these are basically things that normal users think such as there's no such thing as a word processor or spreadsheet.
Speaker 1: There is Word and Excel respectively.
Speaker 1: It's inconceivable that there would never be a computer without them.
Speaker 0: I like the one that was.
Speaker 0: the Internet is Internet Explorer.
Speaker 1: Internet Explorer is more commonly known as the Internet.
Speaker 1: when you say open the Internet you mean opening IE.
Speaker 1: You have no idea what a browser is or there are alternatives to IE.
Speaker 0: I have one thing to say.
Speaker 0: if you read this website and you think these are at all far-fetched You have no idea how absolutely ignorant the vast majority of people are when it comes to computers.
Speaker 1: And if you are this ignorant like any one of these if any one of these describes you I'm inviting you over to my house.
Speaker 0: If you invite just because you if you invite him over you're not allowed to kill him.
Speaker 0: get out of here Flanders okie-dokie I Wow we're just fully inside jokes today.
Speaker 1: I don't think that one was too inside.
Speaker 1: anyone who's seen that.
Speaker 0: that's like a huge Simpsons episode it is But you realize how long ago that was.
Speaker 1: it's the one where Wiggum loses a job or something?
Speaker 1: no It's the one where it's not to do with Wiggum.
Speaker 0: no Wiggum's in the room because he's talking to Homer about what to do if an intruder comes back.
Speaker 0: It's the one where shot sideshow Bob is coming back to kill Bob.
Speaker 1: sideshow Bob number two.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: so yeah cuz Wiggum is like you know if a man comes in your house uninvited You can do whatever you want to him, and he's like Homer's like come over here Flanders.
Speaker 1: He's like hi Lee ho and then Wiggum says it doesn't work if you invite him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he's like get out of here Flanders Ugly-dugly.
Speaker 0: Thank You Ted.
Speaker 0: that was the joke.
Speaker 1: yes, that was the joke we described one inside joke.
Speaker 1: We're not giving you the rest.
Speaker 1: no more freebies.
Speaker 1: Haha If you receive an email from a long-lost relative in Nigeria, it's probably legit.
Speaker 1: after all he's got the same last name as you.
Speaker 0: Actually one Fairly well thought out phishing scam I've seen lately.
Speaker 0: that seems to affect these people.
Speaker 0: since you're thinking the day and your news seem to Really fit together.
Speaker 0: well They'll put something about your credit card blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And then they'll show like the last four digits of your credit card number and people think oh that must be legit They know my credit card number.
Speaker 0: I just want to tell all of you out there that there's a finite number of last four digits in credit cards And they're not very unique in fact.
Speaker 0: They're identical across many types of cards Indeed.
Speaker 1: so they all they do is pick four digits send them out to everyone and they'll get like a 25% hit rate in fact.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like the scam that the bad guy in the in math net.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 0: I hope you've all seen that movie.
Speaker 0: if not I feel really really really old.
Speaker 1: you know we have an Episode that you could go back in the archives and listen to.
Speaker 1: it was a Thursday.
Speaker 1: That will inform you someone.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna see if that movies in frickin Netflix go for it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, check the IMDb first.
Speaker 0: well to move on to our main bit as we mentioned yesterday over the weekend We went up to Marist College where they had their annual gaming for hope.
Speaker 1: now the first thing Let's start at the beginning.
Speaker 0: all right now game.
Speaker 0: It won't.
Speaker 0: we can explain what game.
Speaker 0: No, let's start.
Speaker 1: even more earlier than that I find out about gaming for hope on the internet He sends me a message with the link to it, which I promptly ignore.
Speaker 0: I said it again I click on it And then I never actually look at the page because it opened in another tab.
Speaker 0: And then I went home from work.
Speaker 0: I say something about it to you, and I say what are you talking about?
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right once we got past that part we and it was not such good weather We decided to go.
Speaker 1: we had nothing better to do.
Speaker 0: yep on the way We bought Metroid Prime hunters and Tetris DS, which we'll talk about in a future episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can say however that purchasing those two items was key key key key to our enjoyment of gaming for hope Absolutely key.
Speaker 0: now first off I'd like to say Marist College is a really pretty campus.
Speaker 0: that is probably the most poorly designed campus I've ever set foot on.
Speaker 1: the roads are just horrible.
Speaker 1: there were two different entrances.
Speaker 1: I went in one entrance And I couldn't get to the other entrance from the one I went in.
Speaker 0: plus we drive in and every parking lot has a sign That says if you don't have a parking permit you will be towed and there's a sign that says go to the X building Security desk to get a whatever.
Speaker 0: There's no sign saying where that building is not one at all.
Speaker 1: There's just no way to get around this campus if you haven't been there granted the campus isn't so large So you're you're okay in that department.
Speaker 0: Basically just drove up and down every road until we found the sign that pointed toward gaming for hope.
Speaker 1: yeah But we found it was all good.
Speaker 0: Yeah now it was in the gym and We were a little worried because there was also a lot of sports going on at the same time And it was hard to tell walking in is alright.
Speaker 0: Is this gonna be a good event or is this just gonna be some podunk crap thing?
Speaker 0: and these people are all here for sport?
Speaker 1: There's actually pretty sizable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the first thing we see is a giant beautiful Dell flat-screen display that was up for auction.
Speaker 0: well up for a Contest a raffle a raffle.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: They actually had two of them for raffle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I bought some tickets.
Speaker 0: I didn't win.
Speaker 1: damn it.
Speaker 0: some guy put like 70 bucks in because he figured the odds were he'd get it.
Speaker 1: The odds were he'd get it.
Speaker 1: there weren't so many people there.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he actually got it.
Speaker 1: I don't know either.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this is your typical gaming event.
Speaker 1: I mean on one side the head look command center tables.
Speaker 1: They were selling soda and whatnot.
Speaker 1: they had many many rows of tables set up for land partying But only about two of the rows worth had computers.
Speaker 1: the other a lot of them were empty.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I have a lot to say about that later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then around the edges of the main area of the room They had tables with TVs and consoles set up with all kinds of games.
Speaker 0: I mean they had consoles ranging from like the newest newest consoles coming out now to old Nintendo's and at one point they announced over the loudspeaker system that they needed someone with an old-ass TV Because they had pong and they were gonna hook it up.
Speaker 1: They had a pong Pro-am not a pong super Pro-am, but a pong Pro-am that they were ready to hook up.
Speaker 1: I saw the guy holding it, but they didn't.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they got an old TV to actually play it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they also had a bunch of game tournaments.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there were prizes or not.
Speaker 1: yeah I don't know what the prizes were either.
Speaker 1: It seemed like they had a bunch of little doohickeys in behind the command center like little Death Star toys and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Nothing particularly interesting now.
Speaker 0: We basically only went knowing because we have that club we run with maws.
Speaker 0: these are gamers.
Speaker 0: we actually run the website on the same hosting that we run geek nights and We figured we were gonna meet them there to play the new game.
Speaker 1: We got Calus, but you'll talk about in another episode.
Speaker 0: yep, so we figured no matter how bad this event might be we're covered.
Speaker 0: We'll play a game at Calus and go home.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It was from 1 p.m.. To 1 a.m..
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: We get there and - yeah - ish cuz.
Speaker 1: we had to stop and eat and then stop and buy the video games and the MOS guys are there.
Speaker 0: They're playing some other game.
Speaker 0: They'll probably finish up within an hour, so we decided to sit down and play some DS.
Speaker 0: Not two seconds after we open our DS's a bunch of guys walk over and say hey you guys have DS's Cool guys, and we immediately proceeded to play Metroid Prime hunters with cool guy, and then all sorts of other games.
Speaker 0: yep And I got to say over the course of this night one I saw 2p2 PSP's at all and I saw at least 20 DS's.
Speaker 1: at least three or four times.
Speaker 1: there were large Gatherings of like four to eight people in the middle of the room sitting in a circle of DS's.
Speaker 0: like at one point They announced people are trying to get a full game of Mario Kart in this up the games full nevermind Yep, that's how it goes now.
Speaker 0: I was very pleased that I walked over to this circle of people playing Mario Kart at one point And I asked them if anyone was any good and they gave me this look like are you trying to start something?
Speaker 0: and then?
Speaker 0: Over the course of the night I raced many various people and I kicked all of their asses into the ground handily.
Speaker 0: I was very pleased.
Speaker 1: apparently I did the same thing with Tetris even though I had just bought it.
Speaker 1: apparently I'm better at Tetris than most people is.
Speaker 0: I mean he kicks my ass.
Speaker 1: I played online though and then some people I come across kicked my ass, so it's all good.
Speaker 0: Yep
Speaker 1: I'm not the god of Tetris I'm just better than most
Speaker 0: but Metroid Prime hunters is one hell of a game Especially when you're playing with a bunch of people who haven't played it before either And you're all of the same skill, and you're sitting five feet from the person so you can punch them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll talk more about the game later, but the only thing I can say negative about it Is that it's very controllable, but if you play too long your hand will hurt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my left thumb is actually a little sore right now.
Speaker 1: It's mostly in the lower palm.
Speaker 0: We'll see you play with the stick.
Speaker 0: I play with the thumb nub.
Speaker 0: I don't play with the thumb nub But yeah, we played much DS throughout the night and Everyone had DS.
Speaker 0: I mean there's an old guy who had a DS.
Speaker 0: all these awesome College punk gamer kids who are a lot like we were when we were in college.
Speaker 0: They were also penny arcade fans Which we could tell from the highbrow penny arcade shirt.
Speaker 0: one of them was wearing.
Speaker 1: well gaming for hope.
Speaker 1: let's go back The.
Speaker 1: the gaming club at Marist I think was called 4g something.
Speaker 0: yeah for 4gh.
Speaker 0: They also apparently have an anime club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, they They were putting on this event.
Speaker 1: apparently they do it annually.
Speaker 1: you can go to gaming for hope calm and read all about it Where it's basically free LAN party free consoles free tournaments free pizza.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they fed us twice like free pizza showed up around like four.
Speaker 0: ish now.
Speaker 0: You should have seen this.
Speaker 0: I wish we'd had a video camera.
Speaker 0: Imagine there's like maybe a total of about 90 100 people all in various corners or like outside the door playing games talking whatever.
Speaker 0: Suddenly someone yells pizza and You blink and then your eyes open again, and everyone's gone, and you turn and there's a sea of geeks like violently scrounging pizza out of boxes.
Speaker 0: like a box would open it would disappear and then another box would open.
Speaker 1: and what was great is Everyone was sated.
Speaker 1: it was there was no one standing around like I didn't get any.
Speaker 0: yeah They had pretty much exactly the right amount of pizza and then to our surprise later in the night pizza showed up again Right when we were thinking hey, we should go get some food before we die.
Speaker 1: yeah, it was like.
Speaker 1: How cool is that?
Speaker 1: not only they give it away for free they give it away for free twice.
Speaker 1: The best part was when it came.
Speaker 1: the second time I went over to get some a box was opened in front of me And two seconds later the box is empty, and I had to open another box.
Speaker 1: I took out two slices, and then the box is empty and the next guy opened another box.
Speaker 0: I freaking love gamers.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Now they had some kind of deal going with balls which apparently is an energy drink.
Speaker 1: They had to seem to have deals going on with a lot of people who it didn't seem like they had big sponsorships like the mega land parties do but they had like you know Like sponsorship packets that must have come from corporations And they had a bunch of free stickers and goodies and all kinds of shit.
Speaker 0: Yep, there was one guy who was trying to cover himself entirely in stickers.
Speaker 1: Well those are the stickers for the gaming club, but yeah, so oh yeah back to what gaming for hope is is they?
Speaker 1: They don't collect money because it's free to get in but all the raffle tickets and all the other money They collect they give the child's play and they have one of those giant checks and all that good stuff.
Speaker 0: And they said they were selling stuff like t-shirts And they were just taking donations, and they were selling soda.
Speaker 0: ended up buying some balls Which I'm sure the money went to the charity though.
Speaker 0: I bought it only because they didn't have change for the bills I had.
Speaker 0: Gamers must be poor.
Speaker 0: I mean I had a friggin $10 bill, and they couldn't make change.
Speaker 0: Wow, so I just bought enough pop and balls until they didn't have to give me change.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's gamers It's.
Speaker 1: it's not the fact that the gamers and where it's college.
Speaker 1: No money in college.
Speaker 0: They're gamers, and they're in college.
Speaker 0: That's like a double whammy.
Speaker 1: yeah It was really weird because it's like we're people with loads and loads of money sitting in the middle of a room.
Speaker 0: People with no money yeah, but we used to be those people with no money.
Speaker 0: We did and you know what those were good days.
Speaker 1: It's actually surprising a lot of people that we met there were not from Marist.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like every time we thought all right like we met with this one group the guys who played DS with and we kept running a Foul of them all night.
Speaker 0: They were awesome.
Speaker 0: They were just like we were in college and We were thinking you know all right.
Speaker 0: There's some geeks around here now They all live from other freaking all over the place.
Speaker 0: one guy was from Jersey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a matter.
Speaker 1: They were cool anyway didn't matter.
Speaker 1: yeah, and The Moz guys you ended up playing a lot of cool games with them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Kayla's is fantastic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll do a whole show about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're going to play it some more though I'm sure we'll play it some more before we do an episode on it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and also everyone was cool.
Speaker 0: I mean we had a bunch of little kid like not little kids But young punk kids and other people just walking up over playing because they'd obviously never seen German board games before.
Speaker 0: So we were kind of like hey stick around We'll play a game with you after we finish this and we got all these people who really hadn't played games before to play Games with us, and I think we got a few people a little bit hooked on the German style games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Moz finally listen to my suggestions.
Speaker 1: They had some flyers and stuff and they talked to people.
Speaker 1: so I some people took the flyer.
Speaker 1: So they'll probably come to Moz at some point.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah, that'd be cool.
Speaker 1: Get some more people there instead of just old scary old guys.
Speaker 0: What was the name of that really quick game?
Speaker 0: We played the the chicken game where you put the cards around and you put tokens on them.
Speaker 0: I forget whatever.
Speaker 0: It was a fun game.
Speaker 0: We played with this little punk kid.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That is if I played it once before I think I told you about it, too.
Speaker 1: It's it's.
Speaker 1: it's a nice little easy card game, you know, and it really sucks because you remove those nine cards from the deck.
Speaker 0: Yeah now I guess the best testament we can give to how well done this event was is that one we have a really high standard for Events in general.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll walk out of an event at the drop of a hat
Speaker 1: like we can tell when something is poorly organized and it really like grinds the gears
Speaker 0: mostly because at RIT I mean RIT has a massive gaming club and a massive massive anime club And we kind of ran and helped run the anime club for a long time.
Speaker 0: So we saw like the big events where you know hundreds of people would show up and all the planning and coordination and we saw events that went without a hitch.
Speaker 0: often and Whenever a club did something poorly We just we couldn't stand it and it would bother us because how could they do something so shittily?
Speaker 1: What's worse is when a convention does something for us?
Speaker 1: That's like we did it only once people are paying for it and you fucked it up aka the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: New York Comic Con Ohio Con was Ohio Con - Ohio Con - Yeah, yeah, every other kind I've gone to as well went off pretty well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven't really been to anything else that messed up.
Speaker 0: But these guys put up pulled off a fairly high-class event.
Speaker 0: There were no incidents other than one guy opened a door.
Speaker 0: He shouldn't have opened and set off an alarm at one point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we didn't have to evacuate or anything.
Speaker 1: It was cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the only things that went wrong at all was the one tournament we wanted to enter the doubles Mario Tennis tournament.
Speaker 0: No one ran it and it was canceled.
Speaker 0: Oh And there was this one dude playing DDR who smelled like the inside of a horse's asshole.
Speaker 1: I couldn't tell which dude it was but we were sitting playing DS in closer proximity to the does real smart of them.
Speaker 0: They hit the DDR on the far side of the room DDR in the one corner guitar heroes way off in the other corner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there were four to empty tables meant for extra land people between Everyone and the DDR and the DDR pretty much had constant use by at least two people at a time.
Speaker 0: So we were sitting about I don't know 20 feet away from the DDR just playing DS game
Speaker 1: and all of a sudden I can't Breathe
Speaker 0: like we all look at each other and the one older guy we were playing with says something to the effect of Did someone step in something or did a pipe break?
Speaker 0: and we recognize the smell because we played a lot of DDR.
Speaker 0: That's the smell of unwashed fanboy.
Speaker 1: That is indeed the smell.
Speaker 0: I mean we and we couldn't get away from it and we like ran to the other side of the room And we're trying to figure out because there were two guys playing DDR which one of them was the smell.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it was a guy and a girl playing.
Speaker 0: well There were two guys.
Speaker 0: the guy left and a girl came over and she was playing.
Speaker 0: and then we noticed that halfway through she pulled Off like the scarf thing.
Speaker 0: She was wearing and held it across her face.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and she booked when the song ended.
Speaker 0: So we're pretty sure it was that one guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then he came over to our side of the room.
Speaker 0: It didn't bring his odor with him yeah, so I guess either someone was dead and rotting behind the DDR screen or Maybe the guy's smell is all held in by his clothes.
Speaker 1: now that it wasn't moving I have no idea what it was.
Speaker 1: All I can say is there's a rancid smell and DDR was the source.
Speaker 0: And yeah, I mean really we decided we were gonna show up at two and leave.
Speaker 0: I don't know whenever we finished playing kalis, you know, four or five and let something awesome.
Speaker 1: We ended up staying until pretty much midnight I think but see the thing is though is we would have left maybe at ten if we knew that the Mario tennis was scheduled For nine.
Speaker 1: we didn't look at the schedule because you're idiots And the Mario tennis is scheduled for nine and if we came around to ten and it hadn't happened we probably would have left Yeah, but instead we ended up talking to some more gamers.
Speaker 1: Yeah planes and DS That's all I really did between 10 and midnight was talk to gamers and play DS.
Speaker 0: Yep, didn't get another board game in because that board game guy didn't return Yeah, which was fine because I gotta say kalis hurt my brain and I wasn't really in a state to be able to play another.
Speaker 1: German is a rough game, but it's an awesome game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I love it a lot.
Speaker 1: man We're just like totally tease in the next two weeks.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Maybe people listen.
Speaker 1: If they're listening now, they're already gonna listen next week.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz I will say that of now that we have feeds for all the four days of geek nights.
Speaker 0: Gaming day is by far the most popular one.
Speaker 0: It has about 40 more listeners than everything else.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: That's kind of weird because there's a whole lot of competition when it comes to gaming news.
Speaker 1: I mean you can go anywhere to get gaming stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean hell.
Speaker 1: if you want to listen to two guys talking about video games Gamers with jobs radio kicks our ass.
Speaker 1: I listen to it.
Speaker 0: Yep And I mean basically the sci-tech one is the next and anime is almost right under that Even though I don't want to sound conceited.
Speaker 0: but other than anime world order I can't think of any other anime podcast that even comes close to us.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean I've listened to a lot of anime podcast because I tried to get a podcast for each geekery and anime world order.
Speaker 1: they mostly talk about older stuff because they're older than we are and they you know has a slightly different perspective but Also, they know a whole lot.
Speaker 1: So that's what makes their podcast really interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we're the ones who talk like oh this anime sucks blah and we tend to.
Speaker 0: we tend to be more humorous than Informative.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but all the other anime podcasts seem to be like really annoying fan boys Because Naruto is the best anime and I think he could beat up Goku.
Speaker 0: and and my favorite thing is the PSP Because I can play Metal Gear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't take those yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's just weird that like in the most maybe that's why there's so many gaming Podcasts is so many gamers.
Speaker 1: So many people want to listen to one.
Speaker 1: I don't know Whatever.
Speaker 1: listen to whichever day you want.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just noted that this is our most popular day.
Speaker 0: At least it has been for the last three weeks.
Speaker 1: Go All right, we're gonna close the show out with little meta bits.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We got a very some praise for you people out there.
Speaker 0: You've all finally started to join the forums and it's gotten to the point where I can't keep up with the forums on a regular Basis anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it used to be I would have to go say girl people say stuff and now people are saying stuff.
Speaker 1: In fact, you're saying too much stuff, which is great Yeah, so if you didn't join the forums before because they seem too quiet and lonely and empty.
Speaker 1: Well now, you know the What are you called the catch-22 of no one joins because no one joined.
Speaker 1: Well, that's over.
Speaker 1: people have joined.
Speaker 1: It's now you can join also.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I'm very I had like.
Speaker 0: I love all you being in there I'm gonna start a flame war again.
Speaker 0: We had that awesome religion argument flame war a while ago.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to think of a new topic that'll get everyone all pissed off.
Speaker 1: Secondly in the forum.
Speaker 1: There's a thread about that has pictures of what front row crew comm is going to look like The newest screenshot.
Speaker 1: I think people seem to really like a lot.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean I think that with maybe Tiny changes based on what people in the forum say is probably gonna be what geek nights is gonna look like in the coming weeks.
Speaker 1: However, we still need a geek night's logo and a front row crew logo would also be good Yep.
Speaker 1: So if you want to make one Like I could go to this website where they have professional graphic designers and pay a hundred bucks and they would give me something That's you know, that would do the job.
Speaker 0: or we have I mean literally like 15 friends who are amazing artists Who all said at some point?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll make you a logo and they've never actually done it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't fault him because they're all busy with school and such but still we don't have anything yet.
Speaker 1: So here I'm gonna say right now if you have some ideas for a geek night's logo do like a two-second sketch.
Speaker 1: I don't want you to do like a whole bunch of work in Photoshop for hours just to say I don't like it.
Speaker 1: so do like a two-second sketch of what you think it's gonna look like and Then scan it and email it to geek nights at front row crew comm or put it in the forum or something.
Speaker 1: And if we like what you came up with and then I'll give you 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: Not only that but obviously if you I mean if you're if we use what you give us you'll get you know You'll be on that credits page.
Speaker 0: The only other person on that page is DJ pretzel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and your name will be in the fight of every podcast and all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well probably interview you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that too.
Speaker 0: So plus think about it geek nights is actually starting to grow at a fairly.
Speaker 0: It's growing at a pace to where if we hadn't switched to Libsyn when we did we would have started having bandwidth trouble in Short order.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you could be you know in the future the person who made the geek night's logo And if it's a really good logo.
Speaker 1: Maybe other people looking for logos will come to you and you can start a little logo making business.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean for now the only person who's really given us anything is our friend cad who actually made a fairly awesome little 8-bit style Geek nights thing that I'm thinking of putting on a business card.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'd be alright but we still need one that'll look good and go to the forum and look in that thread and Actually look at the forum and you notice the top of the form is this blue gradient sort of thing.
Speaker 1: It has to make a logo that will look good on that gradient and you'll be all set.
Speaker 0: Scott's not kidding.
Speaker 0: We'll give you 50 bucks plus all the other stuff.
Speaker 0: We yeah Cuz it's either give you 50 bucks or give some professionals a hundred bucks and we'd always rather get the amateurs or the friends Or the people or the listeners that we know.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm pretty much always and save 50 bucks to buy a video game.
Speaker 0: Yeah that too.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So that way, you know when the DS game comes out you can take the 50 bucks I gave you and buy it and I'll take the 50 bucks that I saved and buy one to copy for me and then we'll Play some Wi-Fi action and hopefully I'll kick your ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and while we're at it since it's gaming day final final bit if you got DS games put your friend codes up.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, we're looking for them.
Speaker 1: Tetris and Metroid friend codes big time now.
Speaker 0: I know we've all been posting them, but we haven't used them a lot lately.
Speaker 0: Once we have more free time We're gonna start saying like alright on Sunday from this time this time Eastern everyone in the forums light up and we'll play games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really hard to get a four-player Metroid.
Speaker 1: But if we use the friend codes, I think we can get it on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and even I mean Mario Kart Tetris anything.
Speaker 0: if we all put our friend codes together and we all just try to connect at The same time we'll all randomly connect to each other.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: All right, we out appear and That was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.