Speaker 2: It's Tuesday July 11th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 2: We talk about age of steam.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Well for all of our new listeners.
Speaker 1: This is Tuesday meaning we talk about gaming.
Speaker 1: so if you're here looking for our kinetic on Wrap-up show that will be tomorrow on anime day.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but we will still talk about the gaming that went down at Kinetic on today.
Speaker 1: Yep, partly because we did play a game.
Speaker 1: We had never played before.
Speaker 2: we have quite a bit to say about it And I played some of the games there too without rim and whatnot.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, I was you know fraternizing and wondering about the con.
Speaker 2: yeah, and we don't only talk about board games and such.
Speaker 2: on Tuesday we talk about video games and role-playing games and Any kind of gaming if it's if as the word game in it we talk about it Tuesday.
Speaker 1: in fact We should do a show on punch for punch and a red rover 52 pick up something like that.
Speaker 1: But that goose, but anyway, we've been.
Speaker 1: we're gonna do this all week probably for all the new listeners.
Speaker 1: So if you're new to geek nights listen to the following if you're not new to geek nights Just bear with it or fast-forward.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now.
Speaker 1: We've got a frapper map on the website www.front row crew.com Along with show notes links to everything we talk about RSS feeds for all the different days.
Speaker 2: We have a forum front row crew.com slash forum where you talk about stuff.
Speaker 1: It's real happening.
Speaker 1: in fact right now There's a huge flame war going on about libertarianism and jury nullification.
Speaker 2: awesome and Yeah, that frapper map is like a. you just add little push pins to it so we know where the listeners are and Email us if you want to tell us something or have us say something on the show or anything at all.
Speaker 2: It's geek nights at front row crew.com.
Speaker 1: Yep, and actually in relation to that we got some feedback from The news story I covered yesterday on open DNS, and I'm not really gonna go over it.
Speaker 1: We're gonna save this for probably next Monday, but the guy the open DNS guy Who was all over slash shot was all over geek nights, and he posted in our forums.
Speaker 1: They emailed us like three times.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I don't know how he found us from Wherever he was.
Speaker 2: I mean what did we link to slash that right?
Speaker 1: I linked to the slash dot article unless slash dot told him or he happened already be a listener geek nights Which I guess we'll find out because I'm talking about it today.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I guess if he's a listener geek nights, or maybe he just started listening because you know, but we'll find out.
Speaker 1: yep That was a nice add-on to that.
Speaker 1: we got all the equipment finally to integrate Skype into our daily podcasting.
Speaker 1: So we might try to get this guy on the show as a test and just to hear what he has to say Or we might get do a whole Thursday of prank calls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that is gonna be great.
Speaker 1: But I mean we go four nights a week Monday and every day every night is a different topic or set of topics And there's a different RSS feed both in iTunes and on the website for each one of the days.
Speaker 1: So if you don't like anime But you like video games and technology you can just listen to Monday Tuesday and Thursday or just Monday or whatever you want.
Speaker 2: Yep, or you of course there is the mega feed which gives you all of the geek nights Which is the most popular feed scarily enough yep, and that also includes the unscheduled special geek night specials of which there has been One special geek night special special.
Speaker 2: Yeah, there's not gonna be too many of those.
Speaker 1: No, those are when we cop out or out of town or something weird.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right, so then without further ado I'll jump right into the news because There's been a lot of ongoing debate in our forums and with our listeners as to the relative merits of the Nintendo DS and the Sony PSP.
Speaker 1: Now one the observation I would like to make that I'll talk about a lot more tomorrow.
Speaker 1: But because this is gaming day and we were at Kinetic on over the weekend.
Speaker 1: I can say that the DS was Crazy at Kinetic on Larry crazy or so than any convention I've been to yet during the big uber web comics panel Which is one of the big like well-known draw events of this con.
Speaker 1: channel a on DS picto chat was completely full and it was like there was a simulcast of The entire panel in picto chat while it was going on.
Speaker 2: Was there any overflow to channel B?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I was in channel a Awesome where all the cool people were.
Speaker 1: Ah, yeah channel B people can go to doesn't it?
Speaker 2: Like, you know kind of hang up and you can't send so many messages.
Speaker 1: No, it worked perfectly.
Speaker 2: really I think.
Speaker 1: what it is is that every time we've had trouble it's because there's someone's Misconfigured or annoying Wi-Fi in the area.
Speaker 2: It could be we need to do some experiment.
Speaker 1: I remember it.
Speaker 1: Otakon channel D worked real well, but channel a just.
Speaker 2: but the Nintendo store remember it was sucking.
Speaker 1: bad Yeah, but that might also be like there was a perfect number of DS's and the big thing was they were all in the same Room, except for one guy who was doing security on the other side of a flimsy wall.
Speaker 1: The picto chat only seems to break down if you've got like one or two people who are real far away or breaking up Or if it starts relaying or anything bad starts going on.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But yeah, in fact, I did not see a single PSP, but I saw at least 50 DS's.
Speaker 2: no exaggeration Alright, so what's the news?
Speaker 2: Well, this isn't news.
Speaker 2: This is common sense
Speaker 1: Yeah but the news here is that a lot of our listeners had been arguing earlier that that while the DS is Farring away the winner in Japan and while the DS is the winner in the United States by a significant margin that is growing every day In Europe the DS wasn't doing so well and the PSP was winning.
Speaker 1: and the actual numbers which are not too easy to verify because Nintendo says how many units they sell and Sony shows.
Speaker 1: that says how many units they ship to retailers.
Speaker 1: big difference there.
Speaker 1: But the actual numbers show that the DS and the PSP were pretty much neck-and-neck.
Speaker 1: the DS lite which was released I think 10 days ago in Europe in the EU has sold I think 200,000 already and the DS is now far and away the winner in the European market.
Speaker 1: Also, the the nice interesting bit about this release was that the new black DS light was released there and currently only there.
Speaker 2: Aha, so, of course the people are thinking hey Maybe the only reason so many DS lights sold in Europe is because people from America and Japan are buying black DS lights and having them imported back to US and Japan.
Speaker 1: now, it sounds like a real intriguing idea and Scott and I were talking about this before the show.
Speaker 1: Well, we were actually cooking dinner and one it.
Speaker 1: while that may be true The number of people who do that sort of thing is very small compared to the number of gamers.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I mean, you know whenever I go to a con or some event like waiting in line at the Nintendo Store There's always maybe two guys at most five would be like a crazy Over-estimation of how many people have crazy imported stuff.
Speaker 2: most people just have what's available in their country and a very very few people actually pay a Tajillion dollars for crazy imports like that.
Speaker 1: Yep, so it really couldn't have been a big impact You know, what was more it's definitely not anywhere near 200,000 maybe a thousand.
Speaker 1: there was a case with this whole release of 12,000 DS's that were stolen.
Speaker 1: They were in such high demand that these were stolen and may or may not have been sold on the black market.
Speaker 2: Additionally, yeah, they stole like a whole boatload, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like 12,500 I believe is the number or a truckload or it's crazy.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of DS lights.
Speaker 2: That is.
Speaker 1: How did anyone stealing any PSP's?
Speaker 2: In fact, there's a. there's a picture of a PSP being used in a Japanese convenience store as a little Advertising display and it's just showing a rotating ad to buy some insoles for shoes.
Speaker 2: now pretty Creative use of the BSB.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now the news is simply that the the DS is now winning in every global market.
Speaker 1: I mean Sony.
Speaker 2: well Japan US and Europe.
Speaker 2: It's not winning in Africa.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: South America is the thing Russia Sony the the only number they were released is they claim that they have shipped six million PSP's to Everywhere in the world other than Japan and the United States of America.
Speaker 1: So that includes South America, Canada all of Europe all of Africa Australia everywhere except Japan in Mexico the Caribbean.
Speaker 1: and Yet the number of units Nintendo has sold as in consumers purchased Five million four hundred thousand something DS is just in Europe.
Speaker 2: Oh Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah now couple this with the news It's old news that the UMD format is basically being discontinued for absolute lack of sales.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and the fact that Really?
Speaker 1: No, almost no games have come out for the PSP in a while.
Speaker 2: now that I think games are coming out for it.
Speaker 2: The thing is is that none.
Speaker 2: it's like.
Speaker 2: the DS has a shit ton of games, right?
Speaker 2: But people only talk about the big games.
Speaker 2: They're mountains and mountains of crap games that no one talks about.
Speaker 2: But if you go to GameStop you see him on the shelf.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but no one Has a whole bunch of games.
Speaker 2: There's some mega There's like two Megaman games and all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 2: But people only talk about like three or four of them and I haven't seen any talk about any newer games at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean new games come out.
Speaker 1: just no one talks about them at all.
Speaker 2: I should go look at a PSP blog and see if there's any good stuff on it.
Speaker 2: Someone send me a link to a good PSP blog.
Speaker 1: Yeah, honestly, I'd consider buying a PSP just so I could talk about it more Erudite Lee, but I would consider buying it if the price is much much less maybe under 100 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look at this way.
Speaker 1: We just bought a Mac Mini and we still think the PSP is overpriced for what it does.
Speaker 1: Yeah The Mac Mini was a little overpriced Yeah, but I get the fact that it also replaced our broken DVD player as venerable and awesome as it was in its day.
Speaker 1: Fastest Prime.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it actually you know, while it's an expensive DVD player.
Speaker 1: It is a pretty good DVD player Yeah, and it does a lot of other things we needed and it's quiet.
Speaker 2: Yeah, very quiet and very small.
Speaker 1: I mean I could have made a Micro ATX.
Speaker 2: maybe we should get a new like better stand for the TV.
Speaker 2: that'll look better with such little small amounts of equipment Like a shiny black or brushed steel or something.
Speaker 2: Yeah, something like that only with like thin shelves or something, you know or less shells You know what?
Speaker 1: The only reason I haven't done that yet is that the TV stand we have is free.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it is and it's perfectly serviceable.
Speaker 2: I know I Have a. really everything we've ever bought seems to be something new or something broke and we're replacing it.
Speaker 2: We've never replaced something that was working and functioning perfectly.
Speaker 2: There was one something better.
Speaker 1: There is one case.
Speaker 1: Alright We had an RIT.
Speaker 1: My dad before I went to college for my apartment gave me a couch and a loveseat.
Speaker 1: with a couch and loveseat were white.
Speaker 1: They were put into our apartment at RIT when we moved out several years later.
Speaker 1: They were no longer white They were far from it.
Speaker 1: They were this dark shade of gray and I didn't realize how bad it had gotten until we brought them somewhere with better lighting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then I flipped over a cushion and it was all this white and it was whoa.
Speaker 1: So we threw away the couch, but we only threw it away because Emily and her family and their infinite generosity gave us a better couch for free Which is good because this couch has a bed in it.
Speaker 1: Yes, the couch also has many fond memories.
Speaker 2: It is also called the fucker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if we told that story on the show or not.
Speaker 2: We'll hold it off.
Speaker 1: We'll save that.
Speaker 1: Let's just someone put that in the thread.
Speaker 2: Yeah, remind Rem and Scott to talk about the couch named the fucker.
Speaker 1: now, I will say the the story there.
Speaker 1: I won't tell the story but the couch almost killed us almost.
Speaker 1: In fact, if our friend Pete had not been there Scott and I would probably have died probably have died Under the weight of the evil couch, but I gotta say I mean our TV.
Speaker 1: I mean we're such geeks used to have.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know the old penny arcade comic about the guy who died behind the TV Cuz.
Speaker 1: there's so many wires.
Speaker 1: our TV was like that.
Speaker 1: I mean we had an intent the NES.
Speaker 1: we had the Atari.
Speaker 1: we had a VCR that barely worked.
Speaker 1: We didn't have a remote to it.
Speaker 1: We had the original DVD player which was an overheating region-free cracked apex with a case open so it wouldn't overheat.
Speaker 1: It was 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah We had the GameCube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had.
Speaker 1: we didn't have a computer hooked up to it at that time.
Speaker 1: No, we had the busted old TV.
Speaker 1: We had all those wires.
Speaker 1: We're really sure what they did.
Speaker 1: Yep, and we've.
Speaker 1: and we had the PlayStation one that didn't do anything or some play DDR.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now all we've got connected to our TV is a Mac Mini a Mac Mini and a GameCube and the GameCube We don't even really use so much right now.
Speaker 2: You know, we get a Wii that GameCube.
Speaker 2: We don't need it anymore.
Speaker 1: No, we don't the game.
Speaker 1: I'll probably keep it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, are we gonna sell it?
Speaker 2: - I don't know.
Speaker 2: But it'll go in the closet or something and then in like 30 years.
Speaker 2: I'll whip it out and people be like, holy shit.
Speaker 1: The hell is that I'd say oh we'll just bring it to conventions But we're bringing the frickin we to conventions.
Speaker 1: if we bring anything you damn, right?
Speaker 2: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you got a news.
Speaker 2: I do.
Speaker 1: is it video game related?
Speaker 2: It sure is outstanding.
Speaker 2: When did the Atari die?
Speaker 1: See, I know the answer to the hypothetical question or the rhetorical question because we already did pre-production But I'm gonna say in the 80s.
Speaker 2: Yeah sometime in the 80s.
Speaker 2: They just stopped making games to the Atari 2600.
Speaker 1: Here's what you say.
Speaker 2: Ah, but but just today Someone released a new game for the Atari 2600.
Speaker 1: this game compared to the vast majority of Atari games looks bad Freaking ass now though.
Speaker 2: The thing is an Atari 2600.
Speaker 2: The games themselves could only be have so much memory like 4k or something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now the NES were the same way and they got around it by a lot of trickery in the cartridge.
Speaker 2: Mm-hmm, but someone made a What's it called?
Speaker 2: they made this cartridge have two 4k Memory chips in it and it switches between the two.
Speaker 2: so in bank in the second chip You have the intro to the game the intro screen and all the sound and in the first chip You have the actual game.
Speaker 2: So they put a game on one chip and they put fancy graphics for the intro and the music on The second chip.
Speaker 1: this game is real fancy.
Speaker 2: Yeah for an Atari game It's real fancy.
Speaker 2: now the way the game works is first does the fancy intro screen.
Speaker 2: then it's sort of like What's the game?
Speaker 2: a night driver night driver?
Speaker 2: I was thinking Knight Rider night driver.
Speaker 1: I was really good at night driver.
Speaker 2: Yep, and you're this running Aztec guy trying to get up to the pyramid and you're in the desert.
Speaker 2: So you run towards the pyramid while dodging Spears and stuff.
Speaker 2: basically night driver with a running Aztec.
Speaker 2: Then when you get to the pyramid it switches to game number two where you have to climb the stairs of the pyramid without Getting pinned by various things like the evil priests dropping rocks on your head Sounds like a great game.
Speaker 2: And then when you when you get to the top of the pyramid you beat it and when you beat all the pyramids you get Some sort of ending.
Speaker 1: see now.
Speaker 1: It's really got nothing on kaboom, which is in my opinion one of the greatest games ever created.
Speaker 2: It's got nothing on pole position.
Speaker 2: forget kaboom.
Speaker 1: pole position was okay pole position - was much donkey Kong for the Atari.
Speaker 2: Actually was damn good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: I've got it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 2: What else was there?
Speaker 1: Oh combat Yeah, which you suck at you suck.
Speaker 2: I'm a great at God.
Speaker 2: what I kicked your ass the last time Last time sure, but ten times before that I'm going all of them.
Speaker 1: You've ever beaten me a combat.
Speaker 2: I've been you a combat many times.
Speaker 2: in fact I made a combat game for as a project in a class.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that has nothing to do with the argument in hand which is that you suck at combat and that the last time we played I wrote the program on combat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what I think after the show We're gonna whip that Atari out that Atari 7800 because I'm so leap.
Speaker 1: we're gonna have to play ourselves some combat.
Speaker 2: How are you gonna look it into the TV?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna plug it in through the little RF doohickey that I got all right.
Speaker 2: We'll see how that works.
Speaker 1: I got some ideas.
Speaker 2: We'll see.
Speaker 2: anyway, there's a new game for the Atari 2600 called a VCS tech challenge torrent, please All right, anyway that is the news.
Speaker 1: things of the day.
Speaker 2: Yes new listeners.
Speaker 2: We have a segment on this show.
Speaker 1: every show called things of the day comes right after that music which Ironically, well not ironically but just interestingly is the only music we play during the episode.
Speaker 1: Due to the fact that I never bothered to finish writing any of it Awesome.
Speaker 2: Anyway, anyway the things of the day is.
Speaker 2: we talked about cool things We might have seen on the internet or other places and if you want to visit these things you can go to front row.
Speaker 2: Crew calm and in the show notes, there are links to the things of the day.
Speaker 1: They're usually worth visiting.
Speaker 1: They're often videos.
Speaker 2: Yes, if there is anything worth looking at on the internet today it is the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It's been suggested that we make an RSS feed of the things of the day, which we just haven't bothered doing.
Speaker 2: Oh someone thought about see that might cause some Manual labor or a wordpress plug-in.
Speaker 1: Yeah something we'd have to do either some screen scraping or make the things of the day Special fields.
Speaker 1: instead you just type in them.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we'd have to make it a special field and then I'd have to write a little program to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're just.
Speaker 1: I mean we might do it in the future.
Speaker 1: But to those of you who suggested it be no let it be known that we've gotten your idea and we were considering it.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I never heard it.
Speaker 2: Who's who suggested that?
Speaker 1: I'd ever seen that before, you know I don't even remember but it was suggested months ago, and I just never thought about it.
Speaker 2: You never told me.
Speaker 1: I figured it was an obvious suggestion.
Speaker 2: Yeah, was it?
Speaker 2: obviously it wasn't Even to someone like me.
Speaker 1: All right, so my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I was gonna do something else, but then Scott got his thing of the day and I couldn't pass up the thing of the day that he was passing up.
Speaker 1: So I'm taking it to save it from the obscurity.
Speaker 2: Yeah, basically I had a thing of the day.
Speaker 2: I found a better one, but the one I had was already good.
Speaker 1: So rim saved it Yep, and my thing of the day was alright.
Speaker 1: I'll just use it some Tuesday years from now when I got nothing.
Speaker 2: I've got another thing of the day just waiting in line that I don't know if I can hold on to all right now.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you all are familiar with crusty the clowns show on the Simpsons, you know a show within a show And I'm sure you are familiar with bozo the clown.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that kind of show, you know funny man kids in the audience kids get involved a little bit show a cartoon.
Speaker 2: yeah, a lot of you kids don't realize.
Speaker 2: but Back in the day before everyone had cable there were TV shows that were only on the air in certain areas.
Speaker 2: like there would be a local TV studio where they would make A show and everyone within a certain distance of that TV studio could pick it up on the air Kind of like a radio station occasionally.
Speaker 1: really big shows would be syndicated and they'd appear in like three or four cities.
Speaker 2: Yeah, what they would do is they would send the show to all the different, you know They would tape it send it to everyone and then they would all play it.
Speaker 1: now actually interesting trip our tidbit.
Speaker 1: They did that with unencrypted satellite transmissions back then because they never even expected that geeks would just buy Satellite dishes intercept it and get free.
Speaker 1: pay everything television.
Speaker 2: and back in the day people had Rich people had satellite dishes and they watched all kinds of crazy TV.
Speaker 2: and even today with a satellite dish You can watch all sorts of crazy things.
Speaker 2: that with your satellite dish without paying dish.
Speaker 2: network.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all sorts of fun international TV, but if you can portion of it is non English.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's a world out there.
Speaker 2: The thing is is that there's plenty of TV that you is encrypted on satellite.
Speaker 2: so you need dish network or Direct TV to actually or or you need to be some kind of a hacker elite hacker.
Speaker 2: Yeah, the kid who figured it out got in big trouble serious trouble.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we're not gonna talk about that.
Speaker 2: No, that's not we're gonna talk about.
Speaker 2: we're talking.
Speaker 1: one of these shows Was rediscovered by some people and put on the internet and it's a relevant thing of the day because it is King Koopas show King Koopas cartoon King Koopas cool cartoons all with K's.
Speaker 1: Yeah the KKKK That's just great.
Speaker 2: Well, it is King Koopas cool cartoons.
Speaker 1: now to me if this show had been out over in the baddest ass thing ever because I mean It's cool I mean, I like the Super Mario Brothers Super Show and I was a big fan of Mario and the heroes and not Koopa whatever but I Always had more of a respect for Koopa than I did for Mario.
Speaker 1: There's one Koopa was kind of like a dragon.
Speaker 2: listen kid Koopa.
Speaker 1: your favorite dude kid Koopa is the man Nobody talks smack about kid Koopa.
Speaker 2: kid Koopa suck.
Speaker 1: You know what you know what you're getting some lava All right now.
Speaker 1: Imagine if King Koopa were there and he had a show and you could become one of his Koopa Troopas and wear a Koopa Troopa Hat.
Speaker 2: and he's got an audience full of little kids going Koopa and some of them have Goomba hats and some of them have Koopa hats.
Speaker 2: it's kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: And he's making fun of Mario and all sorts of fun stuff.
Speaker 2: I didn't actually see any making fun of Mario going on.
Speaker 1: I saw just because there were pictures from the screenshots of Pictures of the Mario Brothers behind him and the text he was like.
Speaker 1: they talk about Mario the princess.
Speaker 2: Oh, okay like that.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this telephone looks like it moved or something like there's an alligator.
Speaker 1: I don't know Koopa Koopa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, we're not gonna make an inside joke that inside.
Speaker 2: He's the king of the afternoon Koopa Koopa.
Speaker 1: I Just think this is cool.
Speaker 1: I hope someone has archival footage and puts it all on the internet for everyone to see.
Speaker 2: Yeah, cuz right now we basically got the intro.
Speaker 2: I Have a theory about King Koopa though.
Speaker 2: Oh, I think I know who's in that King Koopa costume Mr.
Speaker 1: Belvedere.
Speaker 2: No, but that's a good guess captain Lou Albano.
Speaker 2: No, that's a bad guess.
Speaker 2: judging by the way this Koopa axe and The me the meager amount of footage I have of him.
Speaker 2: the only person that I know that would fit the That King Koopa would be Steve Ballmer Cuz.
Speaker 2: when he's going he's going like Koopa Koopa trying to get all the kids excited.
Speaker 2: It's it matches it so well.
Speaker 2: I almost forget.
Speaker 1: You can't forget.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I think we'll just we'll play.
Speaker 1: I remember We'll play a clip from Scott's thing of the day and then Scott will explain what that clip was.
Speaker 2: Okay, they're not to $600.
Speaker 1: I let that say I'm a Sony fan.
Speaker 1: I let that slide Okay, and then they keep on pounding you and pounding with bad news.
Speaker 1: That's a bad news.
Speaker 0: It's a bad news.
Speaker 0: bad news Okay.
Speaker 1: Oh You're not buying a game system.
Speaker 2: You're buying raw potential.
Speaker 1: I don't give a I don't give a damn.
Speaker 1: Okay Okay All right.
Speaker 2: So game spot has this hotspot podcast, which I listened to a few times, but whatever That was a Sony a fan of Sony who sent in an audio feedback to their little podcast radio show.
Speaker 1: the kid is definitely a fanboy, but One the fact that Sony's even pissed off the Sony fanboys is a bad sign.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I mean think about it.
Speaker 2: This is a kid who loves Sony.
Speaker 2: he loves the PlayStation.
Speaker 2: He loves Sony stuff, you know If you were on a message board with him and you said Sony sucks He'd be like no Sony is to awesome.
Speaker 2: Nintendo and Microsoft are to poop But because Microsoft are number 10.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but look Sony if you look in the news of video game websites and magazines other than of course the official Sony stuff All you will see is bad news.
Speaker 2: He I mean he's crazy You know in his in his mannerisms.
Speaker 2: But what he's saying isn't far from the truth.
Speaker 2: all the news about the ps3 and the PSP is bad news.
Speaker 1: I mean, let's let's go chronologically through all the news that came out for the ps3.
Speaker 1: It the only good news was the first news which was there is going to be a ps3.
Speaker 2: There was also the news that it's going to be a region free.
Speaker 2: true true and it's gonna have Linux maybe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know those were good days and those days fell into utter chaos and ruin.
Speaker 2: everything else about the ps3 has been I mean, let's see.
Speaker 2: Oh and it's gonna be cheaper than a blu-ray player But that's that's bad news for blu-ray players, which is also Sony.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: It was delayed.
Speaker 1: It was gonna be real expensive.
Speaker 1: The blu-ray was real expensive and not going so well.
Speaker 1: Then they have e3.
Speaker 2: Oh No one clapped at their press release Even though that I think that's PSP news, but whatever doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: That was the that was the highlight of Sony's e3 appearance.
Speaker 1: In addition to all that, you know PSP not doing well UMD discontinued, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: And then all those other tidbits start coming out.
Speaker 1: The games are gonna be expensive.
Speaker 2: the games are gonna be are hard to make.
Speaker 1: Now the worst part about the games being expensive is that the news was Yeah, our PlayStation 3 games are going to be more expensive than the industry average and I thought all right It's not a big deal.
Speaker 1: And then the numbers were thrown out and the number the high range of the number was a hundred dollars.
Speaker 2: Now what game is gonna be $100?
Speaker 2: that has to be the best game ever made to be $100.
Speaker 1: Remember the Neo Geo?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah that didn't do so.
Speaker 2: well no didn't?
Speaker 1: you can't sell games for that much money especially if your system is 600 goddamn snakes on a plane dollars.
Speaker 2: The point is is that Sony is just putting out bad news and bad news and bad news and they expect you know Sony people to just Be so attached to the brand somehow that you know, and some people are that it's true.
Speaker 2: But it's such bad news that yes Even Sony fanboys will be broken and will go out and buy an Xbox or a Wii.
Speaker 1: I mean that would be like if we got pissed off enough at Nintendo to say something like that.
Speaker 2: Like imagine if the news about Nintendo is that we's gonna be a thousand dollars.
Speaker 2: the Wii controller doesn't really work.
Speaker 2: Mario's not gonna be on.
Speaker 2: the Wii.
Speaker 1: Mario's just continued.
Speaker 2: the weed isn't backward kavada with the GameCube anymore.
Speaker 2: No Wii games are gonna be a hundred bucks.
Speaker 2: We were just the Zelda game isn't gonna come out.
Speaker 2: It's like That's good.
Speaker 2: It's that bad.
Speaker 1: You'd get audio kind of like what that kid said only obviously much more a highbrow.
Speaker 2: Oh, of course Pokemon kids are so highbrow At least from us.
Speaker 1: No, maybe now see there's a visual gag in my head that I can't express in radio Where I cut to a penny arcade of Gabe just yelling the word fuck repeatedly.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I in about this fanboy though.
Speaker 2: I just love the reaction of the game spot guy.
Speaker 1: He's like he's like They can't stop laughing.
Speaker 1: they're stifling it.
Speaker 1: you could hear him in the background like.
Speaker 2: It's absolutely fantastic.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to play the whole clip because obviously we jacked it from their podcast.
Speaker 1: So Listen to this.
Speaker 1: It's linked everywhere.
Speaker 2: We linked to it in the thing of the day.
Speaker 2: There's a YTM ND for it.
Speaker 2: It's Sony fanboy dot YTM ND comm.
Speaker 2: You know what?
Speaker 2: This kid is definitely the man now dawg Alright.
Speaker 1: so we were at Kinetic on and we're going to cover Kinetic on in detail tomorrow.
Speaker 1: But because it's gaming day, we're going to cover the gaming at Kinetic on.
Speaker 2: Surprisingly the gaming at Kinetic on was high quality.
Speaker 1: Yes the board gaming euro gaming live-action gaming miniature gaming was Above average for conventions in general let alone a webcomic slash anime convention.
Speaker 2: I mean if I compared it to ubercon, which is a gaming con Period you know, I could actually say it was a slight step up if not You know because they had about as many games in their library as ubercon.
Speaker 2: Well the freeplay library Yeah, the freeplay library, but the room in which games are being played was much larger Dedicated only to gaming and gaming tables Had a lot of tables and a lot of air didn't smell bad and there were a lot of cool people in it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and we played a bunch of German.
Speaker 1: Well, I played one German board game and I played two German.
Speaker 2: well, I don't think age of steam is German but I Played two games.
Speaker 1: Yep But honestly while those are all good things as we'll talk about tomorrow the fact that they had so much space for the game room is Actually one of the indirect reasons why Connecticut leaves a little bit to be desired overall.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll get into that tomorrow.
Speaker 1: So but it regardless of that the gaming was tight.
Speaker 1: I mean they had a video game room that looked very typical of every gaming con I've ever gone to.
Speaker 1: it had the same type of tournaments.
Speaker 1: It looked really popular.
Speaker 1: It looked well run.
Speaker 1: I haven't heard any complaints from anyone about it.
Speaker 0: They had a miniatures room which I assume was running well because they saw a bunch of people in there playing miniatures games all day.
Speaker 0: Miniatures games go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact that it reminded me that as much as I love miniatures That is a part of my life that is dead to me now and I seek never to return to those days.
Speaker 1: Yeah Battle tech is as far as we go Because I remember we walked past the miniatures room on our way to the board gaming room in the morning and there was a set of people in there playing miniatures games.
Speaker 1: I Walked back toward the gaming room much later that day like in way afternoon way possibly evening.
Speaker 1: Yes, like I think we I think we had just gotten back from dinner Yeah, and the same people were in the same chairs.
Speaker 1: The only things that had moved were the miniatures in the same game.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's miniatures take a while.
Speaker 0: But in the gaming room, they actually they had some.
Speaker 0: it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: The way it worked is you could go up to the library the free game library Of course trading your badge and get any game
Speaker 2: you wanted
Speaker 0: and play it with your friends
Speaker 1: Yep, and they had to a couple of guys running the Booth where you could get the games who were definitely Euro gamers and they knew their stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah there was one guy who was in charge like he was staff in charge of the game room and he seemed to be cool and he knew what he was doing.
Speaker 0: he was going around teaching people games and Being friendly and recommending games to people and helping people set games up and all kinds of good stuff.
Speaker 0: he was definitely on top of things and what he would also do is he would go around to games that were being played and Give out prizes.
Speaker 0: now the way it seemed to work is He had they had this kinetic on money Which is just printed out money with a stamp on the back.
Speaker 1: they were bunny bucks because the mascot of kinetic on is an anthropomorphic rabbit.
Speaker 1: great and He would get wrong with anthropomorphic rivets, right?
Speaker 2: so he would give the winners.
Speaker 2: you go to a game being played put a 10 bunny buck bill on the table a 5 and then some ones for all the other players, I think he gave out more ones of games were longer and That would.
Speaker 2: the winner would get the big 10 and the second place guy would get five and everyone else would get a few ones Even if you lost.
Speaker 1: so you could use these bucks to buy prizes in the dealers.
Speaker 2: Yeah in the dealers room There was a prize Table and there are many things and they all cost a certain number of bunny bucks and I think it came out to our bunny Buck was worth around 50 cents.
Speaker 1: Now the really interesting thing is that systems like that are nothing new.
Speaker 1: They really only appear in Gaming cons and I was really surprised to see such a well executed system at a con that had gaming But it was definitely not a gaming con.
Speaker 1: It was a webcomic con.
Speaker 1: It is it is an anime con turned webcomic or vice versa.
Speaker 1: It is like an amalgamation of webcomics and anime.
Speaker 1: It is not a gaming con yet.
Speaker 1: The gaming was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think really if you look at the con It's I have to say that it was definitely an anime webcomic gaming con.
Speaker 2: like a whole half of the building Was gaming.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so well at least the whole hallway, you know was gaming.
Speaker 0: anyway We went to the gaming room and most of the games being played.
Speaker 2: I think there was an apples to apples.
Speaker 2: It just didn't stop.
Speaker 1: Oh god, the people just coming in and out.
Speaker 1: It was there the whole day.
Speaker 2: Yeah, munchkin was being played very much in all its varieties munchkin foo super blender munchkin Regular munchkin super munchkin.
Speaker 1: we could tell that we've become a different kind of gamer Over the years in that because actually we hung out with the staff guys and the game We're gonna talk about today age of steam the main gist of today.
Speaker 1: We played with the like the two staff kind of guys at the staff table.
Speaker 1: so he had to keep stopping to you know deal with all the stuff.
Speaker 1: and Half the people who walked up were like, you know, give me that German game.
Speaker 1: But a lot of people were like, you know, I play trivial pursuit or munchkin.
Speaker 1: You don't have monopoly or check.
Speaker 2: they had monopoly but they didn't have chess and a lot of people asked for chess.
Speaker 2: The German games were played just not as much as the other games, you know It seemed to be.
Speaker 2: people kept coming back for munchkin.
Speaker 2: They kept coming back.
Speaker 2: They wanted chess.
Speaker 2: They didn't have it.
Speaker 2: They played apples to apples constantly, you know those sorts of games.
Speaker 2: There's a lot of magic being played in the room.
Speaker 2: There was a lot of other CCG's being played in the room.
Speaker 2: I think I think they had a closed-deck magic tournament at one point.
Speaker 1: But all those people really stood out because the to us at least the German gamers the people who wanted the euro games We just walk up get the game walk away and sit down and play that fucker.
Speaker 2: Yep, and the
Speaker 0: It was funny because the second time
Speaker 2: we went to the gaming room the two I think I think these
Speaker 0: guys were volunteers
Speaker 2: actually the two guys sitting at the staff table Yep, they
Speaker 0: we went up and
Speaker 2: they were playing two-player carcass own and we were like, ah, no expansions weird
Speaker 0: and obviously Immediately, they knew that we
Speaker 2: were real gamers and they were real gamers.
Speaker 2: So they're like we can stop playing this and play something real and we want to.
Speaker 2: and I was like, yes, let's do that.
Speaker 1: Yep, and while I wanted to play Kayla's a lot.
Speaker 1: We I also wanted to play a game.
Speaker 1: I never played before.
Speaker 2: I really I most of all I wanted to play a game I never played before because a I paid a lot to get into the convention and that's how I'm gonna get my money's worth And be.
Speaker 2: I need something to talk about today.
Speaker 1: Also.
Speaker 1: I'm glad we picked a game that Absolutely insane because I wouldn't have wanted to have to play that game the first time on my own.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we'll get to age esteem.
Speaker 2: But first I want to talk a little about the game.
Speaker 2: I played Puerto Rico Early in the day with some other guys.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: This is when I slipped out to go to the uber webcomics panel.
Speaker 2: Yeah now early in the day I went in there and I was like in some guys like hey you wanna play Puerto Rico?
Speaker 2: So I'm like, yeah sure I'll play Puerto Rico with some people I never played with before and Originally, it was gonna be like me the head staff guy of the game room and three other people.
Speaker 2: but then some other You know con goers came around and I played with them and I taught.
Speaker 2: I think one of them knew how to play.
Speaker 2: one of them kind of knew how to play and the other ones are noobs.
Speaker 2: but I taught them how to play and Surprisingly enough.
Speaker 2: I don't know who it was.
Speaker 2: I forget everyone's name, even though I asked One of the noobs like when I explained to him the rules He Absorbed every rule like a super sponge.
Speaker 2: He didn't ask really any questions, you know.
Speaker 2: And after I had completed, you know all the rules and when he played he played better than all the other people there.
Speaker 1: Now things like that are very impressive to us.
Speaker 1: I mean are a lot of our friends are like that but that's because we're all very deeply mirrored in the board game culture When we run into a person who isn't a member of the front row crew who just picks a game up like that.
Speaker 2: That's amazing, especially a game like Puerto Rico where not only did he learn all the rules 100% from me telling him the rules once But he played the game better than some other guy who had played the game before.
Speaker 1: Of course Scott still won this game hand over fist.
Speaker 1: Of course I still win this game hand over fist and in fact Being that I played Puerto Rico a jillion times if we had stayed for the whole weekend We had a racket planned where we would both play together in every game We could win.
Speaker 1: most of them get feel like first and second place all the time King make each other in order to put ourselves in first and second place You know, like kind of like drafting
Speaker 0: and get a mountain of bunny bucks
Speaker 2: and then buy a board game with them Does getting our money back for the con?
Speaker 1: basically, yeah, but we're lazy.
Speaker 2: We were lazy and we had other things to do with the con.
Speaker 1: also stage esteem took over three hours.
Speaker 2: Yeah age of steam took a while, you know would have taken less time if the guys weren't busy doing their job But it's still.
Speaker 2: it would have taken a long time anyway.
Speaker 1: But I mean before we get on to age of steam Kinetic on if any of the staff or anyone are listening you guys did a fantastic job with your gaming and whoever was in charge Of that deserves some sort of commendation.
Speaker 2: They should be the con chair.
Speaker 2: All right, so later in the day we came back to the gaming room and we played age of steam.
Speaker 1: now before We talk about age of steam.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about another game that we used to.
Speaker 1: we played a couple times
Speaker 2: I think we talked
Speaker 0: about on the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah called Java.
Speaker 0: Oh Java.
Speaker 2: I think it's my railroad tycoon.
Speaker 1: No, I want to talk about Java.
Speaker 1: Okay, because I think explaining the Java story which is a complete Java is the same as any other German action point game.
Speaker 1: Yeah but the thing is Java was the first game we played where the game seemed to be set up in a way to Action points with which to do actions on the board putting pieces of land down and The way every played the game once and tensions ran high.
Speaker 1: we came up with the following Fable as to we completely made up, you know, we made this up.
Speaker 1: It is a fable this is not what actually happened.
Speaker 1: as To how they determined the number of action points that you get on your turn.
Speaker 0: Obviously the real way that did it is it's some sort of math.
Speaker 1: Yes, though, honestly I wouldn't put it completely out of the realm that they did it our way.
Speaker 2: It's a hypothetical Possibility.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So they get five Drunk German board gamers and they put them in a bar with the game and they give them 50 action points and tell them to Play the game.
Speaker 1: Then they tell them to play it again and they give them 49 and again and they give them 48 and they keep going down Until a fistfight breaks out.
Speaker 1: and the moment a fistfight breaks out
Speaker 2: you subtract one more action
Speaker 0: point And then you put the game
Speaker 2: out like that
Speaker 1: because the game was every round.
Speaker 1: I would do all my stuff and then I would just if I only had one more action point I could do it Every single round.
Speaker 1: it was the same thing and everyone was feeling it and the game just hurt.
Speaker 1: I love the game but that was our first experience with a game that did something like that a game where you didn't feel like you were progressing where Every time you did something good something bad happened to you.
Speaker 0: The age of steam is worse than that.
Speaker 1: age of steam is the most unforgiving Relentless kick your ass game I've ever laid eyes upon.
Speaker 0: now I'd known about age of steam because there are some guys at the local gaming group and Whenever we talked about railroad tycoon, they would say have you played age of steam.
Speaker 2: Are you playing age of steam?
Speaker 2: You know if you played age of steam.
Speaker 0: yet Do you want to play age of steam?
Speaker 0: and I was like they?
Speaker 0: Kind of gave me the impression that age of steam was the real man's railroad tycoon.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: They'd say things like it's Unforgiving.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is no quarter.
Speaker 0: so in If you want to know about railroad tycoon, I think we did an episode on it, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, we did.
Speaker 1: In fact, we did two episodes on it one of which we never uploaded.
Speaker 0: Yeah So if you want to know about railroad tycoon Just go listen to our episode on it and it might give you a little insight as to age of steam.
Speaker 1: I will link to that episode at some point.
Speaker 1: Maybe not tonight, but tomorrow while I'm at work with no work to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'll add it in now, you know how I feel.
Speaker 0: Anyway,
Speaker 2: of course, I'm doing work now But
Speaker 0: age of steam is basically actually railroad tycoon is very similar to age of steam because age of steam came first yes, but the point of it is that age of steam
Speaker 2: has a much smaller
Speaker 0: map than railroad
Speaker 2: tycoon and
Speaker 0: there's much higher competition for the cubes as well as for the terrain and putting tracks down and It's also a fucker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the mechanics are basically the same.
Speaker 1: You're shipping cubes around to get victory points.
Speaker 1: adding getting victory points also gets you more income.
Speaker 1: But the more income you get you start losing income in the long run.
Speaker 1: You don't start with anything.
Speaker 1: you have to take out shares which you have to pay forever for the rest of the game and lose points for at the end in order to get all your money.
Speaker 1: and Other than I mean, it's the same game just really small really compact much more arbitrary and with far fewer Catch-up mechanisms.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's the real thing about age of steam that bothered me.
Speaker 0: Is that in in railroad tycoon?
Speaker 0: You're trying to get victory points and victory points you get when you ship cubes and you pretty much get victory points in railroad tycoon.
Speaker 0: the same way you get income points in age of steam you ship a cube and If you ship a cube over three of your tracks you get three points.
Speaker 0: if someone else chips a cube over your track you get a point etc, etc.
Speaker 0: and In railroad tycoon you just keep getting points forever and ever and the more points you get your income goes up and up and up and then After a point you keep getting more points and your income goes down and down and down but you can still get more points in age of steam.
Speaker 0: your points your most of your points.
Speaker 0: there are ways to get points besides income but every point of income you get at the end of the game is three points of score and As your income goes up it goes down.
Speaker 1: Yep, so like once you get past a certain point every round that you're past that point you lose two income permanently.
Speaker 1: If you get further on the victory point track, it's four then six.
Speaker 0: So if I have less than ten points of income, that's cool.
Speaker 0: I just get my income every turn.
Speaker 0: I think it was ten.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ten was the line at least for the two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then like if I have let's say I have fifteen income points I get fifteen dollars and then my income is immediately put down to thirteen.
Speaker 1: So if you've been shipping a bunch of cubes and the cubes have dried up and you're up there It's gonna pull you all the way back down to ten over the course of turns.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you basically have to keep shipping cubes.
Speaker 0: You have to keep the machine moving Enough to push you ahead and then it pulls you back.
Speaker 0: So you had to do it again.
Speaker 0: You can't just like get a whole bunch of points then not do anything for a while while you set stuff up and relax And then get a bunch of points again.
Speaker 0: You have to make the game set up so that you're constantly getting more and more and more and more points Turn after turn after turn without slowing down like a giant snowball.
Speaker 0: if there's any pause in your snowball You're done because the game just pushes you back down the shitter.
Speaker 1: Yep Basically, this is a game where if you fuck up ever at all I mean not like in some games like Puerto Rico where if you screw up a little bit You still have a chance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you lose a few points, but other people can still fuck up.
Speaker 1: if you fuck up in this game You you're done.
Speaker 1: You're out of the game.
Speaker 1: You might as well give up unless Everyone else fucks up worse because the earlier you fuck up the worse it fucks you.
Speaker 1: Take that FCC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: If you take a share That's you know the way to.
Speaker 0: in railroad tycoon you can take a few shares at the beginning and not take any more ever.
Speaker 0: It's not hard to do that because you ship cubes you get your income up it stays up.
Speaker 0: You can sit around and collect income and then spend it and move on without taking more shares.
Speaker 0: But in age of steam you can't do that.
Speaker 0: You need to keep moving.
Speaker 0: So if on a turn you didn't get a lot of income you had you know You had to upgrade your train to ship a cube You had to.
Speaker 0: you know, you can't afford any tracks.
Speaker 0: You have to take another share now that you've taken another share.
Speaker 0: It's even harder because the more shares you have the less income you actually receive.
Speaker 0: and The thing is if you take a share and then you don't capitalize on each and every single share you take and Get that money and spend it in such a way that makes your income much much
Speaker 2: larger
Speaker 0: You're basically screwed because you can't get rid of the share.
Speaker 0: It's there until the end of the game and now you have to take another one.
Speaker 1: Yep, now not only is the game set up to where once you fuck up you're basically done.
Speaker 1: if You screw up enough.
Speaker 1: Not only can you will not win but you are eliminated from the goddamn game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if your income can go below zero if you know you you get a bunch of shares you move up and then You know your income doesn't ever catch up to the number the cost of your training your shares.
Speaker 0: Well, you can't get rid of the shares or shrink your train.
Speaker 0: So you're losing money.
Speaker 0: every single turn your income goes down down down down down and if it goes below zero You're out.
Speaker 1: You're just done because for any money that you owe at the end of your turn for your expenses that you can't pay you lose One victory point which is one income.
Speaker 0: Well, it's actually three victory points.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, three one income unit Mm-hmm, and it just kicks you out of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can be killed in this game and it really sucks Really sucks.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the worst part of the game is that.
Speaker 1: well I guess the worst part in terms of how it beats the hell out of you is that You'd never feel like you're getting anywhere.
Speaker 1: You always feel like everything you do is just in vain no matter what you build.
Speaker 1: It feels like crap no matter what you do.
Speaker 1: It won't work.
Speaker 1: No matter what you want to do.
Speaker 1: Someone else out bids you.
Speaker 0: it's just imagine if you're playing a game against some other people right and You're trying to attack the other people and you know get ahead in the game yourself.
Speaker 0: the problem is is that the game is like another player and he's constantly raping everyone in the ass and until Until you get the game out of your ass.
Speaker 0: You can't really do anything to anyone else.
Speaker 0: so if someone else might have gotten the game out of their ass already because they know how this game works and If the game is still on you you basically give up because you can't go do anything to that guy And now that he doesn't have the game bothering him He can just get away and there's not a goddamn thing you can do about it.
Speaker 0: so the winners keep winning and the losers keep losing.
Speaker 0: because
Speaker 1: at least a lot of games like Puerto Rico or railroad tycoon, even if you're losing if you're in last place and there's nothing you can do to win There's a lot to do on your turn and it gets to the point where you may not be able to win.
Speaker 1: But it's still fun to build railroad tracks and ship cubes and you're still.
Speaker 1: you're keeping.
Speaker 1: you're not falling further behind.
Speaker 0: You're still constantly accomplishing things and moving forward and moving forward at an increasing pace.
Speaker 0: Someone else might be doing it better than you But you're not falling back into the point where you can't do anything.
Speaker 0: You're constantly going up and rarer tight in age of steam.
Speaker 0: You're constantly going down and only the winners are going up.
Speaker 0: and as the winners go up It becomes easier for them to move up even more.
Speaker 0: and if you don't move up as fast as them It just becomes harder and harder to move up
Speaker 1: which in and of itself is fine except that most really good games are set up so that The point at which a clear winner is determined is pretty much the point at which the game ends.
Speaker 0: I think that's why age of steam has a defined number of turns.
Speaker 0: The game is X turns long the end Yep, as opposed to rarer tycoon, which goes until enough cubes have been shipped.
Speaker 1: The problem is that I mean honestly in the game we played the game was determined at the beginning of the third turn Yep, and the game was what five turns?
Speaker 1: Yep, in fact at the beginning of my round in the second term I made a mistake a very small mistake of a few monies and It was over.
Speaker 1: from that point on there was nothing I could do to win.
Speaker 1: not only that but there was nothing I could do To get cubes to ship to even do anything in the game other than take a bunch of shares The pay to do something which then just put me even further down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the game does have a saving grace in that.
Speaker 0: Theoretically if someone is getting real way far ahead They still have the difficult task of keeping that machine rolling.
Speaker 0: Like I talked about the snowball before.
Speaker 0: but the thing is is That you know sure there they might screw up while they're far ahead and you know If they stop their snowball at any point, they'll fall way back and everyone can catch up.
Speaker 0: But the reality is is If you get ahead of the game and you're actually getting money every turn fistfuls of money without taking shares You're pretty much You know.
Speaker 0: You can breathe a sigh of relief and just make moves to ship cubes without worrying and upgrade your train and do all kinds of stuff without war.
Speaker 0: I mean There was all kinds of times in the game where I just couldn't do things because they didn't have the money and it took me Until the fifth turn to really, you know, actually be getting a decent amount of income, but the game was over.
Speaker 1: now Here's my beef with the game.
Speaker 1: my main beef because I enjoyed the game.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'd spend much money on it.
Speaker 1: I don't know of many of my friends who would ever want to play this game with me.
Speaker 0: No, I don't really know anyone either.
Speaker 0: They just get pissed off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but because we didn't talk a lot about all the mechanics of the game that make it different.
Speaker 1: because honestly Unless you know railroad tycoon and you're really into board gaming You probably don't care.
Speaker 1: and if you do care you probably already know all about this game.
Speaker 0: and if you don't well email us Or go to board game geek this rules there.
Speaker 0: Yeah this game It's just not.
Speaker 0: you know Some games.
Speaker 0: you want to explain how they work because it's interesting.
Speaker 0: the way this game works is basically on your turn.
Speaker 0: You buy some cubes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my beef and I'll explain the game in a very abstract high-level way.
Speaker 1: The game is a giant collection of extant information.
Speaker 1: There is so much information you have so many arbitrary decisions and The game starts as a clean slate.
Speaker 1: the game is primarily Understand the math behind the game.
Speaker 1: Understand while you're playing that one victory one income point is worth X dollars in this round but worth Y dollars in this turn and because of the statistics of dice rolling the odds are that this will happen and It's just a whole bunch of math.
Speaker 1: It's a game that you could Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: Yeah now Scott Johnson a good friend of ours is the almighty god master of a game called acquire.
Speaker 1: Because that is a game where if you sit there and calculate the odds of everything on the board and look at all the information Take it into account.
Speaker 1: You can calculate fairly trivially the optimal move.
Speaker 1: He was just really good at calculating that optimal move before anyone even though it took him forever.
Speaker 0: He would just sit there for like five minutes figuring out the best possible move and then he would take it.
Speaker 1: Of course if he played with us we just hit him.
Speaker 1: Yep, the thing is this game is a lot like that is that once you know the equations behind the game It's just a matter of who executes the optimal strategy for the current board the fastest and while.
Speaker 1: that is a valid game And a good game.
Speaker 1: It's not a very fun game.
Speaker 0: No, the other thing is that you were used to playing games of tactics where you know in a game of Puerto Rico You can't sit down at the beginning of the game and say aha.
Speaker 0: I see how this game is set up.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be all captain-y this time or I'm gonna be all this this time You know, you just kind of play it as it goes and you know, same thing with Tigris and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: Sure, you can look at your starting six tiles and figure out your opening moves But you can't plan way out ahead in the game.
Speaker 0: What's what you're gonna do?
Speaker 0: because you don't know.
Speaker 0: there's so much information yet to be revealed.
Speaker 1: Yep, and while in a game like Tigris and Euphrates you can have a long-term strategy I do often like I'll think like I'm gonna build here and here.
Speaker 1: Well, my long-term goal is to put a monument over there somewhere or a monument attached to that Kingdom, you know Things like that, but if you make a strategy and then you have to deviate from it because of tactical considerations That's fine.
Speaker 1: The game doesn't really punish you for that in age of steam if you Misstep at all at any point you were fucked if your strategy was wrong on the first turn.
Speaker 1: you're done.
Speaker 0: It's over an age of steam.
Speaker 0: 90% of the information in the game that is gonna be known is visible right away where the cubes start What cubes are going to show up in what cities and in fact nothing goes in what order.
Speaker 1: nothing another player does is secret.
Speaker 1: Tigers and Euphrates has the thing that you don't know what other people have.
Speaker 1: You don't know what their assets are in this game.
Speaker 1: You know what everyone's assets are no matter what.
Speaker 1: no one can hide anything.
Speaker 0: Yep, so, you know everything and you know most of it right at the beginning of the game Even though everyone's an equal footing, you know all the cubes and all their positions and that's what really matters.
Speaker 0: And what you have to do is you have to make a long-term strategy for the game Based on the starting positions of cubes so that you know, those are the cubes.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna ship on turn one.
Speaker 0: Those are the cubes.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna ship on turn two.
Speaker 0: Those are the cubes are gonna ship on turn three.
Speaker 0: I know I'll have this much money because you can figure all that stuff out.
Speaker 0: I'll take this many shares on this turn and then I'll have this much money and I'll ship those cubes and I'll get you know that much money from that.
Speaker 0: and You could just plan out your whole game on turn one and then whoever plans out the best game on turn one and then happens To execute that to the fullest is gonna be the winner.
Speaker 0: you plan most of your game right away.
Speaker 0: the only thing that can screw with you is If other players do things to interrupt your long-term plan of which cubes you're gonna ship on which turns.
Speaker 0: The thing is it's pretty obvious when someone can stop you and if someone spends Resources to stop you that doesn't also benefit them.
Speaker 0: They're basically taking you and them out of the game together.
Speaker 0: So you don't really expect something that crazy to happen.
Speaker 1: Now I mentioned about the equations and the.
Speaker 1: you know figuring out how everything works in the game what the value of things are like in Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: a good example is that Early in the game money is worth more than victory points and later in the game victory points are worth more than money.
Speaker 1: But that's a very vague thing and you don't need to know.
Speaker 1: One money is worth two point nine six victory points on turn two.
Speaker 1: Information like that is useless in a game of Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: The generalities are far more useful Especially because the game is very cloudy in that situation.
Speaker 1: in this game You have to calculate down to the individual gold piece.
Speaker 1: So anyone who's played the game before The more times you've played the game the more advantage you ever.
Speaker 1: people who haven't.
Speaker 1: now you have an advantage over people.
Speaker 1: It's like say Tigers and Euphrates.
Speaker 1: if I played the game a million times you played it once.
Speaker 1: I have an advantage over you because I played the game a lot but it's because I've learned strategies and techniques and I'm just I've become a better gamer.
Speaker 1: and After they play the game a few times, they'll catch up.
Speaker 1: But in this game the information itself not the tactics or the strategy But the information of how the game is constructed is the knowledge that makes you a better player Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Once you know the equation the game is much simpler.
Speaker 1: and once everyone knows the equation the game goes much more smoothly.
Speaker 1: But at the same point, why are you playing it?
Speaker 0: it's like this really really hard math problem and you can solve it at the beginning.
Speaker 0: and if you know, you can't never get you know, the exact answer, but you can get real close and Sure, some other people trying to solve it might mess up your problem But for the most part, you know, wherever however far along you are on determining the answer You stay that far along the more you play.
Speaker 0: So once you're real close to figuring out exactly everything you're basically real close to winning every damn time you play.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean playing the game with a different with one group of people and playing with the other group of people is in many ways Part of the same game because the information doesn't change.
Speaker 0: Yep, but in the game like Puerto Rico At the start of the game everyone starts at zero and it's sort of like a race to see who can get the most.
Speaker 0: Just go go go go go.
Speaker 1: Yep, and also, you know, I mean both games have randomization but it's just the math and the Scott Johnson factor of this game are There.
Speaker 1: I mean I consider myself an extremely hardcore gamer.
Speaker 1: I Can't express to you the countless hours of my life I've spent playing German board games and Dungeons and Dragons and all the everything gaming gaming gaming.
Speaker 1: This game is Too hardcore for me.
Speaker 1: I don't like it.
Speaker 0: I Like how the game goes.
Speaker 0: I just don't like.
Speaker 0: it's not enjoyable unless It's like.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like go, you know, you play go and it's you enjoy how the game works.
Speaker 0: at least I do.
Speaker 0: but the first like hundred or so times you play go you just lose horribly and You kind of have to beat the game before you can beat someone else.
Speaker 0: and You know, it's like even though you're making progress in terms of getting somewhere in your mind You're not actually making any progress in the game itself.
Speaker 1: I guess because I actually wanted to talk about this, but I forgot.
Speaker 1: we mentioned chess earlier.
Speaker 1: now people kept wanting chess.
Speaker 1: I Really don't like chess and I was okay at it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I had a friend who was actually in high school who was actually a recognized master of chess.
Speaker 1: He was very good.
Speaker 1: Obviously, I'd never ever beat him at chess ever never even got close.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but I played a lot of chess and chess and this game have a lot in common to me in that You're playing against other people but not really you're playing against the game and a memorized series of strategies because chess is It.
Speaker 1: it's a tactical game if you don't understand the game.
Speaker 1: but once you know the game and the more you learn it the more.
Speaker 1: you memorize patterns of action and You just you know well if he does this and this and this then I do this and this and this but then he'll do this and this and This and it's just a game of figuring out the equation that leads to a checkmate.
Speaker 1: This is just a game of figuring out an equation that leads to me having the most victory points at the end of the seventh Round.
Speaker 2: Mm-hmm that one could say the same thing about all the other games though.
Speaker 1: Well now because the not so much because there's so little everything is so deterministic in this game and so open.
Speaker 1: and The fact that the game well when the game ends after seven rounds So the everything is very regimented.
Speaker 1: the randomness is already right up front there and there's no way to Secret it away or avoid it.
Speaker 1: and the fact that I think there's a very limited set of strategies.
Speaker 2: Yeah, there definitely seems to be a very limited set of strategies.
Speaker 2: It's like figure out where to build the tracks and in what order and on what turns in which cubes to ship when and how?
Speaker 2: Far and when on what turn to upgrade the train?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's very difficult to say in Tigris and Euphrates if he starts with a kingdom in that area.
Speaker 1: He's probably going to win.
Speaker 1: But in a game like this or chess is very easy to say if he enacts this series of things Then he will probably win.
Speaker 2: You know days in a game like Tigris and Euphrates the starting board is always the same and you're competing against The hidden information of what tiles the other players have and the how the other players play the tiles.
Speaker 2: in Age of steam the board is set up differently every time but it's set up with a series of cubes and you could sit down All alone and figure out the best pot.
Speaker 2: assuming there you were the only player you could figure out the best possible way and order of turns to lay track to get the most money and the most points and You're really playing against the game.
Speaker 2: Well, everyone else is playing against the game.
Speaker 2: It just happens to be that you're all on the same board So some.
Speaker 2: so sometimes you you know, you get in each other's way, but really not.
Speaker 1: So that was our experience.
Speaker 1: I mean he played Puerto Rico and age of steam at Connecticut Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I didn't even actually play my DS other than pick to chat.
Speaker 1: Yeah me either.
Speaker 2: I would have played a lot more games.
Speaker 2: if I had been there for a day other than Saturday I'll probably would have played some Medici which is a bidding game.
Speaker 2: I really want to play Yeah, and some other stuff too, but oh well.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, perhaps we'll go to Connecticut again someday, maybe Yeah, we'll talk about all that tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I think we're out for today because once again, we've got longer than we expected and that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 2: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 2: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 2: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.