Speaker 1: It's Monday October 9th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight being science and technology night We're going to talk about codex for audio video and images.
Speaker 1: if you're one of our new listeners from sitcom Remember that Tuesday's are gaming days Wednesdays or anime and Thursdays are awesome.
Speaker 1: the actual coverage of the convention will of course be on Wednesday nights.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, we're back from a weekend at sitcom.
Speaker 1: Hey It was a good time.
Speaker 1: I gotta say seeing the video game pianist and entertainment system live was pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were indeed pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: And the only other place you can really see the video game pianist is like video games live which I think is gonna be in Brazil next.
Speaker 0: so yeah, it was a rare opportunity to you know.
Speaker 0: see him play for a relatively low price Close up in the u.s..
Speaker 1: Plus.
Speaker 1: We had to hang out with him afterward And he's a really cool guy.
Speaker 0: yeah, he's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: He's way too modest man that dead I mean modesty is all noble and all.
Speaker 0: but he's really gotta Be more a little confident and at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean people like us think we're a lot more awesome than we are.
Speaker 1: this kid doesn't realize just how awesome.
Speaker 0: He's pretty much more awesome than everybody But he thinks he's like whatever plus.
Speaker 1: the best part is you know we're all hanging around We're all in our mid-20s if not greater at this table, and then someone asked me how old are you?
Speaker 1: he's like 19 We're all like.
Speaker 0: And then he's like you're not so old you're not so old we're like oh, yeah, okay, mr.. Mod is saying We're not so old.
Speaker 0: don't be modest.
Speaker 1: for us We're old Yeah, but of course to all of our new listeners.
Speaker 1: We may have picked up at sitacon.
Speaker 1: We will be covering sitacon on Wednesday because that is anime manga comics day.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's when we're gonna cover it though.
Speaker 1: at first I would like to explain to any new listeners partly because we've been way overusing this joke.
Speaker 1: But a while ago.
Speaker 1: We had this thing of the day Which was these guys with a Brooklyn accent kind of watching Pokemon and yelling at it and at some point during the video You think the guy says like you can't lift ten Pokemon can't hold ten Pokemon.
Speaker 0: So now whenever we begin a sentence with you can't?
Speaker 0: it just turns into you can't ten something something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were doing this panel on.
Speaker 1: you know your anime socks or anime you like socks and every few minutes We're just like you can't make fun of ten anime.
Speaker 0: You can't verb ten nouns.
Speaker 1: It's a bad thing.
Speaker 1: So I thought I'd explain it to all of you who were a little confused by that.
Speaker 0: yeah Maybe I'll look up what day that Thing of the day was.
Speaker 0: but when you just go look search your Pokemon on front row crew calm And you'll find it, and then you'll get the inside joke of you can't verb ten nouns.
Speaker 1: So anyway, there's really only one news today, so Scott has a little news to get out of the way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay little news is that there was some 100% carrot juice, and I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I don't have the article in front of me right now.
Speaker 0: I read it a few minutes ago and Some people in Toronto two people were paralyzed because there was botulism in the carrot juice.
Speaker 0: now The interesting part is that it was organic.
Speaker 0: Late you know is organic carrot juice.
Speaker 1: so it went.
Speaker 1: it didn't go through the process that would have prevented botulism from happening.
Speaker 0: Exactly you know a lot of people.
Speaker 0: they've done a really good job of marketing all these organic mostly fruits and vegetables You know but also dairy and meat products You know as organic and I guess there's some organic grains, but those really don't have as much of a problem?
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm not an expert.
Speaker 0: This is secondhand knowledge here You know.
Speaker 0: but anyway the thing is when someone says organic that means they do less Science to it, and if you're a hippie that kind of thing sounds great.
Speaker 0: you'd be like oh, it's more healthy.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have pesticides or hormones or all these sorts of evil things that other hippies come up with.
Speaker 0: that sound really bad because they're Chemicals and they're unnatural.
Speaker 1: remember at the same time.
Speaker 1: It's not all bad.
Speaker 1: I mean some organic food is really good.
Speaker 1: I mean if you get an unpasteurized orange juice.
Speaker 1: It's the bomb.
Speaker 0: yeah It's a. it's the bomb for about two days before it turns into the poison.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: and I yeah picking an apple off the tree is always gonna taste better.
Speaker 0: But that's not because it's organically grown That's because you are very close to the place It is growing.
Speaker 0: the reason fruits and vegetables in places like the Northeast where we live the Northeast us Suck is because those things are taken off the tree You know frozen or something shipped a very long distance and then eaten.
Speaker 0: if you go to Florida to get oranges They're all awesome because they're freaking traveled.
Speaker 0: You know they're one day ago.
Speaker 0: They were picked off the tree.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean there's some hippies here who make their own locally grown salsa, and it's really freaking good.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz it was grown right here.
Speaker 0: not because it's organic and organic stuff isn't any healthier.
Speaker 0: all that shit about Franken food where they genetically engineer it to be bigger or seedless or anything like that.
Speaker 0: That's all a bunch of hokey bringing any.
Speaker 0: any fruit or vegetable is awesome.
Speaker 0: You know if you eat a giant strawberry or a square watermelon.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna hurt you.
Speaker 0: It's not any different from a regular watermelon.
Speaker 1: But the thing is what about those poison watermelons in Iraq?
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: You don't want to poison Iraqi watermelon.
Speaker 0: however If something says organic on it that means that it went through less Science and our friend it went through less science.
Speaker 0: and our friend who's tests food Who was on the show a long time ago for a living?
Speaker 0: He says that he would not choose to eat organic foods because while many of them probably won't hurt you the quantity of Bacteria and other things like that that are in them are higher than in the foods that went through more scientific Processes.
Speaker 1: I remember he's talking more about processed food.
Speaker 1: I mean like if you take fruit and make a juice out of it.
Speaker 1: organically I mean organic fruits and vegetables aren't really any different and just have less pesticide on them usually and usually.
Speaker 0: But you know and they also more expensive.
Speaker 0: the even even if you know the regular Unprocessed fruits and vegetables, you know are organic and that doesn't necessarily mean they're gonna be poison or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Spinach was They.
Speaker 0: They're too expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever you can rant about organic foods as much as you want.
Speaker 0: and yeah Those people with their organic foods they bother me.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I'm just you rant about it all the time and it's annoying.
Speaker 0: Hey, they're they're worse more annoying things to rant about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, would you often do?
Speaker 0: What do you want from me?
Speaker 1: so what's your big news?
Speaker 1: the one that you wanted to have?
Speaker 1: only one news for today?
Speaker 0: Oh the 101. why I have both news is your news.
Speaker 0: My news is the organic carrot juice.
Speaker 1: Alright fine.
Speaker 1: Then my news is that Google bought YouTube for one point.
Speaker 1: six five billion dollars in stock the biggest news on the internet in a long time, holy crap.
Speaker 0: It's insane.
Speaker 1: Google the biggest people on the internet bought the biggest video on the internet for a lot of freaking money right after a whole bunch Analysts basically said that YouTube is worthless.
Speaker 0: I mean, holy shit.
Speaker 0: What were those guys at YouTube?
Speaker 0: They're finally they're probably all nervous every single day of their lives.
Speaker 0: Like god damn it.
Speaker 0: We made this big monster.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be ruined.
Speaker 0: What do we do?
Speaker 0: Today they probably freaking that sire a leaf just wave like I felt it over here.
Speaker 0: It was so big.
Speaker 0: No, but I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: Most of what we do on the internet nowadays is looking at videos and shit.
Speaker 0: Now for both places that we get it from or combined into one.
Speaker 1: I mean really the only places that had good videos on the internet were YouTube and Google video and now they're gonna be one in the same presumably eventually maybe.
Speaker 0: and they said YouTube will retain its distinct brand identity and They're keeping you know, the employees and everything else.
Speaker 1: But if anything I'll bet Google video will just index everything on YouTube and vice versa.
Speaker 0: That would be cool.
Speaker 0: They were like both the same site, but you could choose the interface.
Speaker 0: I really hope this is just one Flash application for displaying the video.
Speaker 0: that's on both sites because I really like the Google video one a lot more than the YouTube one.
Speaker 0: Yeah No But apparently the these accompanying news is all the deals that they had with legitimate entertainment companies.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean Google had video or had deals with Sony BMG music and Warner music over music videos where some sort of Profit-sharing royalties thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they did that today and before that YouTube made a deal with Warner in September and YouTube also made a deal with Sony and Universal today and whatever.
Speaker 0: They're just deals going around with all the media companies.
Speaker 0: But the big one is the one with CBS where basically now CBS is gonna give content to YouTube.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: and As If people post something on YouTube CBS is gonna look at it.
Speaker 0: and if it was something that was recorded off of CBS CBS is gonna be basically either get the final say as in yes, they can go on YouTube or no it can't.
Speaker 0: and if they Say yes Then CBS is gonna get a cut of the advertising money from that page.
Speaker 0: So if CBS let something go online from its network Then they're gonna get money whenever people look at it.
Speaker 1: now on one hand It's a smart move by Google because this puts the onus of copyright enforcement on someone else.
Speaker 1: if CBS lets something go through Google can't be blamed because they let CBS decide if it goes through or not.
Speaker 0: On the other hand, we got CBS looking at all our stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll have to see exact I hope.
Speaker 1: I mean I hope the EULA's or the various licenses around all this stuff don't change in terms of like.
Speaker 1: if you put a video on YouTube Then rights get transferred or yeah,
Speaker 0: this could be a real problem if people start feeling like you know I mean people use YouTube because a lot like the flicker of video, you know It's people putting their stuff up for other people to see.
Speaker 0: if the combination of Google video YouTube and all these media companies turns it into more of a Corporate kind of video thing and not you know, the people's video thing You're gonna see a lot of competitors show up and possibly kick its ass, you know, and it's on the internet We've seen.
Speaker 0: you know, you might think oh, no one could beat such a monster.
Speaker 0: It's so big.
Speaker 0: There's no way to win.
Speaker 0: It's happened on the internet a lot of freakin times.
Speaker 0: I mean the the friendster dead.
Speaker 0: myspace is the win or cut dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, myspace is the win.
Speaker 0: lots of things go down.
Speaker 0: I mean Alta Vista and Yahoo down Google up.
Speaker 1: It happens every day and it's not always like the best thing wins because no offense to people out there But myspace is the bottom of the internet.
Speaker 0: It's shite.
Speaker 1: You said shite purely because I said shite all week, that's right I don't know why for some reason all weekend.
Speaker 1: I just said shite instead of shit.
Speaker 0: That's what you do.
Speaker 1: I guess it just sounded funnier.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this is.
Speaker 0: this is gonna be mean big news for the future of awesome internet geekeries.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one company for your internet video needs one ring to rule them all and in the darkness of the style project bind them.
Speaker 0: Oh, no Oh god.
Speaker 0: Hopefully this will bring more good than bad But I feel an even dose of both coming this way.
Speaker 1: if anything I look at it this way Google is smart.
Speaker 1: the people who make decisions at Google know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're way smarter than us.
Speaker 1: if Google bought YouTube Google's got something planned.
Speaker 0: They know exactly what they're up against all the problem Obviously done the math on some way to combine adsense and YouTube and Google video to actually make some monies.
Speaker 1: this will probably put the nail in the coffin of you know Cuz I don't.
Speaker 1: Microsoft kind of wanted to have a video thing and Yahoo wanted to have a video thing.
Speaker 1: Those things have no chance now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think they're really how Google's doing it?
Speaker 0: I if you see if you look at a lot of the other newses about Google It's like they're fighting for a new standard of power supplies that are just 12 volts.
Speaker 0: They're fighting to have these like Mainframe server farms in a box things that they can put all over the country, you know These are the kind of things they're going for.
Speaker 0: they're trying to find a way to make it cheaper to do things that require Insane amounts of processing and insane amounts of bandwidth all over the world and by cutting those costs They're able to do things like YouTube for less money.
Speaker 0: Then people like YouTube can do it for the old-fashioned way of having a billion fiber optic cables in a giant server farm somewhere.
Speaker 1: And don't forget.
Speaker 1: I mean Google has all that dark fiber.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Google.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's another thing.
Speaker 0: They're doing the dark fiber and their own Wi-Fi, you know.
Speaker 0: They're cutting the cost on the back end to make insane internet applications more feasible when supported merely by Google adsense ads.
Speaker 1: I mean Google is like a spider now and they're going out in every direction and trying to take over like Everything.
Speaker 1: but I mean eat for some reason unlike, you know when Microsoft and AOL have always tried to do things like that in the past.
Speaker 1: They're really not being evil as far as anyone can tell and everyone seems to be backing them.
Speaker 0: I mean if Microsoft did the same thing if Microsoft bought YouTube the news would have been Microsoft ruins YouTube, you know That wouldn't have been actually so bad if you think about it because they could have combined it.
Speaker 0: if if they would have handled it If they would have combined it with the Zune and the Xbox 360 then it would have been hot.
Speaker 0: I might even go for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I could subscribe no better yet.
Speaker 0: You have the Zune right which is this portable thing and it has Wi-Fi and you can watch YouTube on it anywhere.
Speaker 0: That would have been so hot.
Speaker 0: Like imagine if the iPod with video could watch YouTube.
Speaker 0: that would be wicked.
Speaker 1: not even that saying my Xbox I could subscribe to like the YouTube top 100 channel and watch him in HD And just watch.
Speaker 1: well HD wouldn't really matter with YouTube haha.
Speaker 0: but I'm saying they could make it hotter for the Xbox 360 folk because they know that they're not gonna be able to pirate the Content through their Xbox granite.
Speaker 1: We can't speculate about that because that didn't happen.
Speaker 1: Oh, we know what happened and it's probably better.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I mean it is interesting that any other big company really geeks and people in the know generally don't trust them at all.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people keep saying they don't trust Google.
Speaker 0: No, they don't.
Speaker 0: they haven't done anything yet.
Speaker 1: people who don't trust Google are old people and a very very vocal minority.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they did do that China stuff though Yeah, but look at what Yahoo did in China.
Speaker 1: Google's policy is we're not going to harm the Chinese citizens.
Speaker 1: It's not their fault.
Speaker 1: So what we're gonna do is censor what they want.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll put a big thing saying we censored something because of your government.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm They turn the dude in and he got arrested.
Speaker 1: yeah Google is probably doing the best.
Speaker 1: I mean the only choices here are to Either screw the Chinese people and hope that they get mad at their government or do whatever you can to help the Chinese people out.
Speaker 0: Of course, you can't yell at Yahoo too much.
Speaker 0: They do provide flicker and delicious, which I use freaking every damn day All the time.
Speaker 1: I mean there was a time when Yahoo is my preferred search engine.
Speaker 1: Yeah in 1996 give or take 1998 after 97 or 98 Alta Vista digital started getting me bad results and every other search engine just sucked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, remember back in the day when search engines would link you to dead sites that were 404s.
Speaker 1: Those are crazy times or when search engines all gave you completely different results and didn't index the same pages.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what.
Speaker 0: at the very least I think.
Speaker 0: now searching on YouTube just searching YouTube for videos We'll get better because it'll be a Google search and not a YouTube search whatever that works.
Speaker 1: Let's notice how Google paid in stock and not in cash.
Speaker 1: So say this is a bad move and Google stock tanks.
Speaker 1: The more Google stock goes down the less they paid for YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it says right here YouTube will retain its the secret.
Speaker 0: its backers will retain a shed load of Google shares which no doubt will be converted into readies as soon as possible.
Speaker 0: and There is no doubt they're selling all those shares right now.
Speaker 0: As soon as the market opens tomorrow Google stock price is gonna go down a bit and get cheap from those YouTube guys selling all those shares for cash and going to buy new Ferraris.
Speaker 0: and then you see the Google stock will be cheap.
Speaker 0: and Because they bought YouTube a whole bunch of stock guys are gonna buy it and it'll go back up.
Speaker 1: Yeah things of the day Which day?
Speaker 0: we've been gone for three days.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what the hell happened in this world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter because something happened back at RIT.
Speaker 1: Now the college we went to RIT the Rochester Institute of Technology Decided while we were there to build a monstrosity.
Speaker 1: Now a lot of campuses have a monstrosity, you know a big ugly statue was something RIT decided to get a statue of a knight.
Speaker 0: But the statue of the knight I mean a statue of a knight when if you tell me that I'm like, yes That's awesome.
Speaker 0: a knight a knigget.
Speaker 1: it's a knight made out of metal scrap garbage.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's a pile of scrap metal.
Speaker 0: It's a rust knigget.
Speaker 0: It got rust hurricane.
Speaker 1: Nothing is.
Speaker 1: it doesn't look that bad.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of people complained about it when it went in but that was mostly because it was RIT and the students There.
Speaker 1: if anything changes for the better or for the worse people will bitch about it.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I could kind of understand the fact that it was a lot of money.
Speaker 0: was like 14 million dollars Yeah, but it was.
Speaker 0: it was a lot of my nervous 14.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was millions.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe was the The cop the GCIS.
Speaker 0: that was 14 million.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: No, the Sentinel was millions and millions It was.
Speaker 0: it was a lot of freaking money for this giant.
Speaker 1: So the Golisano building cost a lot more than 14 million.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that's what Golisano gave and I don't remember exactly.
Speaker 0: I'm just remembering.
Speaker 0: 14 million is some number.
Speaker 1: students complain like first they were like Oh They waste our money on this.
Speaker 1: and then RIT was like.
Speaker 1: actually That money was all donated by people specifically to build that and we didn't take any of your money at all.
Speaker 1: yep, and then people like well, it's ugly and It's not that ugly.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I mean the others.
Speaker 0: the existing statues around RIT are better like the sundial and the infinity Which are wicked cool.
Speaker 1: See I think it actually fits into the campus pretty well, and it's yeah ugly Like all the buildings made of brick.
Speaker 0: It's hot.
Speaker 0: It's made of rusty.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think the buildings are ugly either.
Speaker 1: I think RIT's campus looks really good, especially in the summer.
Speaker 0: It does it does it looks okay despite if you like bricks and I kind of like bricks.
Speaker 1: But the thing is just that people at RIT complain no matter what and the only complaint I have with the Sentinel.
Speaker 1: Is that what they should have built is a 90-foot tiger?
Speaker 0: Now there's already a tiger which is the best damn tiger only because it's balls get spray-painted gold every year.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: No, they should have built a freakin.
Speaker 0: if they built an actual night It would have been much that wouldn't have fit in at all with RIT.
Speaker 1: Mmm, the thing is the Sentinel fits in.
Speaker 1: you got it looks pretty good.
Speaker 0: It kind of fits in a little bit.
Speaker 1: now the thing is the students regardless of how nice the Sentinel actually is bitched about it and bitched about it.
Speaker 1: and while we were at RIT we Inspired several times to prank it in some way.
Speaker 0: Well, of course.
Speaker 0: I said everyone was thinking all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were like should we TP it?
Speaker 1: Nah, should we run a pirate flag up on it?
Speaker 1: Should we thermite it?
Speaker 1: Nah, and we just never got around to pranking it because we were seniors and then we all laugh.
Speaker 1: So we didn't care anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Sentinel went from a thing everyone complained about to something everyone walked by on their way to class to a joke.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so finally now that we're gone some people actually pranked the Sentinel.
Speaker 1: hooray now They did it in a classically geeky way.
Speaker 1: They took a bunch of throw ease which take an LED and a battery tape them together And now you've got a little light.
Speaker 1: That's a throwing and you put the tape like double-sided tape on it and you throw it somewhere.
Speaker 1: and now you got this light stuck To something.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So you use the tape that you use to attach the LED to the battery.
Speaker 0: is also the tape that makes it Stick.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, you just wrap it a double-sided tape.
Speaker 1: Yep, and People they cover the Sentinel in this thing and then they ran a pirate flag up it Whoo-hoo, and then they put pictures on to internet.
Speaker 1: Of course the news is that RIT took all of them down almost immediately.
Speaker 1: Oh Well, the guy who did it is awesome.
Speaker 1: And that's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, RIT just doesn't understand.
Speaker 0: They should really capitalize on that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: I mean if RIT left it up and even like praise the students who did it You know that would send a message to the whole world like hey come to RIT.
Speaker 0: It's an awesome place to go.
Speaker 1: You know what sends the message to the world?
Speaker 1: The fact that they have two OC threes connected to the internet, oh It's true.
Speaker 1: That's the only reason I went to RIT.
Speaker 0: That was one of that got him in this one Who they have major and I didn't even know.
Speaker 1: I thought they had a t3 and I was impressed by that.
Speaker 1: I get there like we don't have a t3 and before I could say what fuckers lied to me They said we have two OC threes and a t3.
Speaker 0: even no one knows either.
Speaker 0: He was where I went to ri3 and RIT and that's why I knew that's where I wanted to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what do you got?
Speaker 0: So this dude is this kind of technology right here.
Speaker 0: He you know how if you know if it's opened up a hard drive.
Speaker 0: first of all in any hard drive There's a wicked powerful motor that's small but spins discs really fast.
Speaker 0: There's also a bunch of discs usually three and they're nice heavy metal thick magnetic discs.
Speaker 0: they're just basically like CDs only solid metal and fat and magnetic.
Speaker 0: and This guy takes a whole bunch of floppy drive platters Which are the discs in the floppy drives puts them on one motor?
Speaker 0: Spins them up real fast and lets them go.
Speaker 0: and then if you think about the physics You'll know what happens to them.
Speaker 0: and then you watch and you go.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah That's what would totally happen if you did that and then he throws in a curveball at the end of the video and it's awesome.
Speaker 1: The video is funny and short and worth watching very worth what else can I say?
Speaker 0: very short That's all there is to it.
Speaker 1: So on to the main bit which is kind of a cop-out.
Speaker 0: It's not really a cop-out.
Speaker 1: today's is a cop-out because it is the overview of what we're gonna do.
Speaker 0: Yeah so this week and the following three weeks we're going to talk about something a lot of people don't understand and have problems with and That is dealing with many different sorts of file formats mostly video ones, but also audio and image ones Specifically the compressed formats that involve words like codec and Container and such.
Speaker 1: now a lot of people have trouble trouble with this and us included sometimes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is normally when it comes to computer stuff We always make fun of people like ah, you don't know about blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: You must be stupid.
Speaker 1: but when it comes to codecs It changes so fast and so often and it's not like there's a central repository or a website.
Speaker 1: That's like here's a list of all the codecs out there and all the containers how to use it
Speaker 0: And it's not like it's very easy to tell unless you're using Linux Exactly, which codec in which format a specific file is using and whether you have the right thing or not.
Speaker 1: yeah, plus a lot of people will download a player for a codec not knowing that they could just get the codec.
Speaker 1: or Some codecs cost money.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it's sometimes you can play a file, but you can't make a file.
Speaker 0: Sometimes there's different places to get the codec from like you can get the official real player or you can get some other thing That also does it and you always get the bad ones and you get stuff that doesn't work it with each other.
Speaker 0: So then you end up being able to play certain files and not others and different players.
Speaker 1: Yes, a lot of programs don't like you have to install codecs in them for them to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a crazy mixed-up world But hopefully we will tell you the under workings and also how you can get stuff to work.
Speaker 1: In the very least we'll learn a lot as we do a bunch of research for all this.
Speaker 0: All right Well, the first thing I think we have to explain is what is the point of all these formats?
Speaker 0: Why do they exist?
Speaker 1: I mean the word is codec.
Speaker 1: now codec is is kind of like modem.
Speaker 1: modem is it's the same kind of word.
Speaker 1: modem is not a word so much as modulator Demodulator.
Speaker 1: and then they shorten that to modem because you don't want to say hey, I bought a new 336k modulator demodulator today.
Speaker 0: Yep codec means compressor Decompressor or coder decoder or compression decompression or encoding decoding or whatever?
Speaker 1: This is digital compression not analog compression.
Speaker 1: We use analog compression and digital compression to make geek nights.
Speaker 1: digital compression is like making an mp3 Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: In fact, that's exactly what it is.
Speaker 0: You see there are two steps in this process.
Speaker 0: really is what we're talking about is images Audio and video.
Speaker 0: Those are all analog things.
Speaker 0: they involve waves slash particles of light and waves of sound and You have to convert those in order to use them in a computing environment into a zeros and ones.
Speaker 0: So you have an electrical signal that varies in voltage wildly and you have to turn that into an electrical signal That is either zero or five volts.
Speaker 1: now take the uh, maybe without losing information I'll take images just because this is the best easiest one to explain.
Speaker 1: Is this the simplest?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm?
Speaker 1: So what do you do?
Speaker 1: The first early one simply would say I've got X pixels.
Speaker 1: I'll figure out what color each pixel would be to look as close to that thing as I can and then I'll save a file.
Speaker 1: That's just a line of numbers that tell what every pixels color has to be.
Speaker 0: So like.
Speaker 0: let's say you have a Image file on your computer and there are two possible colors black and white.
Speaker 0: So the first pixel is the first bit.
Speaker 0: it's either a zero or a one.
Speaker 0: So it's just a bunch of zeros and ones and you go through one pixel at a time.
Speaker 0: It goes zero black one white zero black one white.
Speaker 0: and that's how it's done convert analog to digital.
Speaker 0: The second thing you need to do is realize that hey if you get a really big picture, that's gonna be a really big file.
Speaker 1: Thus we have compression where they use tricks and algorithms and various things which we'll talk about in much more detail to Compress it to make it smaller.
Speaker 1: So instead of having to say like say you have you know this picture and you can figure out looking at it mathematically that Hey, the whole second half of this thing is just ones
Speaker 0: It'd be easier to say yeah put a hundred ones here instead of actually having a hundred ones Because the number a hundred takes up less memory than a hundred actual ones do.
Speaker 0: That's.
Speaker 0: that's just a very simple example of the kind of things that you do to compress digital files.
Speaker 0: This gets even worse if you try to do.
Speaker 0: video is now you don't have just one picture.
Speaker 0: You've got a jillion pictures like 30 pictures a second and you've got an audio track also Yep, and maybe a subtitle track.
Speaker 0: Yeah, God God knows what else you've got in there.
Speaker 1: You might have like 5.1 surround sound mixed in with all this.
Speaker 0: Yeah You might want to have like three different languages and five different subtitle tracks.
Speaker 0: You might have alternate angles on the video file.
Speaker 0: when you get this kind of stuff You need to take up a whole DVD with it and DVDs like 4.3 gigs.
Speaker 0: It's crazy.
Speaker 1: Plus at this point there's another step up and we talk about codex But a lot of people get confused between codex and what would actually be called containers.
Speaker 1: Yes, very briefly the easiest way to explain this with AVI is it used to be that AVI Was a container and a file format because it was just raw Basically pictures in a row.
Speaker 0: Well, it kind of is sort of well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean AVI you could tell someone.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is an AVI file and all AVI files were the same.
Speaker 0: AVI file is basically the default video file.
Speaker 0: It is a completely uncompressed normal video file.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about the container, but the codex AVI is nothing.
Speaker 0: It's just a bunch of bitmaps.
Speaker 1: But the thing is now, I mean a lot of divixes are dot AVI But the codex was divix.
Speaker 1: So how come it's still AVI?
Speaker 1: How come my old player can't play these new AVI files?
Speaker 1: They have the same extension.
Speaker 1: Well, it turns out that the container can hold all different kinds of video streams in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't have to put an AVI Codex which is basically nothing because it's not compressed or decompressed at all.
Speaker 0: It's completely uncompressed video in an AVI container.
Speaker 0: You can put other videos in an AVI container And that are compressed in different ways.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean the first big one.
Speaker 1: Well, there's also MPEG and all that.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that in the video day.
Speaker 1: Yeah Divx was the one that really got this sort of thing big and that was the first one.
Speaker 1: That was really the first time where people actually had to do something to play a video file.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean before divx the only codex you really had in containers were.
Speaker 0: There was the AVI which was for micro.
Speaker 0: was it all?
Speaker 0: Microsoft stuff was AVI and it was completely uncompressed video MOV which was QuickTime and it was all the Apple stuff which barely worked If at all on PCs for a long time.
Speaker 0: There was the real stuff which is a real container which contained compressed real video and real audio.
Speaker 0: and There was MPEG - which is what's on DVDs.
Speaker 1: Well, there was also MPEG.
Speaker 1: There's also the MPEG is complicated.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that in great detail because there are a bunch of different layers of MPEG and different types of MPEG and different.
Speaker 1: We can't get into it today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're gonna do that.
Speaker 0: The third show is video but The fourth show I guess is the first show MPEG.
Speaker 0: Yes So these are all the containers that there were.
Speaker 0: and then all of a sudden someone said hey We're gonna make this new way to compress video that actually can make a really high quality video one That would normally take up gigs fit inside a hue a few hundred megs without losing significant quality.
Speaker 0: That was crazy.
Speaker 0: It was crazy.
Speaker 0: Absolutely insane.
Speaker 1: I mean the same with music.
Speaker 1: I mean I used to collect MIDI files and then like I had a couple of wave files of music and they were huge and my I was tiny.
Speaker 1: and then the day when I found mp3s and I downloaded Half of this live recording of Hotel, California and I started playing it and it was.
Speaker 1: it was real music But it was like three megabytes.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's insane.
Speaker 1: an equivalent wave file would have been like 30 megabytes.
Speaker 0: Yep, I guess we should now talk about the difference between lossy and lossless because it's something a lot of people understand But not everyone.
Speaker 1: it also applies to all three of the topics.
Speaker 0: Yes, now when someone says lossy and lossless compression They mean that you can make it smaller without losing data.
Speaker 0: You see an AVI file is not missing any data.
Speaker 0: If I take a video of rim with a video camera and I take the AVI file out of that camera It is pretty much in that AVI file exactly what I saw in the eye hole.
Speaker 0: It's it's the best quality that the camera could record.
Speaker 0: every single bit of information is in there, you know If I compress it to make it smaller with say Divx, it will get much smaller.
Speaker 0: However, if you watch both videos side-by-side you would say hey that Divx one is doesn't look as good It's missing some information.
Speaker 1: It still looks good maybe but then again you might not because even if something is lossy It doesn't mean you can tell the difference because a lot of times what a lossy compression will do is remove Redundant data or data that your eye couldn't pick up anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like an mp3 is lossy You are losing audio information when you turn a wave into an mp3 But you might not be able to detect that information with your ear.
Speaker 1: the stuff that it took out in fact the math behind MP3 originally was simply that there are obviously sounds that are in music that the human ear cannot detect.
Speaker 1: Therefore let's try to figure out a way to remove all the things that you can't hear and only leave in the things you can Hear.
Speaker 1: that way it doesn't take as much data to describe the sound.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So when someone says something is a lossy, that means that when you are compressing it you're removing Information.
Speaker 0: there is less information in the compressed file than there is in the non compressed file.
Speaker 1: Yep, the information may or may not actually matter But if you compress things over and over or change from one lossy to another you keep losing more data every time you do.
Speaker 0: If you make something into an mp3 then an AAC then you turn that into.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you can turn it into after that some other crazy audio file then back into an mp3 again.
Speaker 0: You're losing more information each time.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like recording from one VCR to another.
Speaker 0: it just gets crappier and crappier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, granted it tends to level off.
Speaker 1: I mean don't worry about this.
Speaker 1: mostly because the way the algorithms work is pretty smart and they realize hey I can't take any more data out of this.
Speaker 1: But even then you'll get some artifacting and trouble depending on exactly what you're doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if something is lossless it is possible to make something smaller without losing any data.
Speaker 1: now lossless Applies mostly to non media files because I mean say I've got a program that I've written, you know It's a bunch of instructions for the computer in a lane like assembler.
Speaker 0: if one of those instructions is lost.
Speaker 0: It's game over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if anything has changed at all, then it won't work.
Speaker 1: So I can only use lossless compression where nothing is actually lost.
Speaker 1: It just uses algorithms to figure out how to express what it was smaller.
Speaker 0: Like if I sent an email to rim, you know, I could.
Speaker 0: maybe it's a big long email.
Speaker 0: It's 100 megabytes.
Speaker 0: I need to shrink it to 500 megabytes.
Speaker 0: I can do.
Speaker 0: I know I'm making it up.
Speaker 0: It's crazy numbers for an email.
Speaker 1: No Check your math there.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, I need to drink it to 50 megabytes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a crazy email.
Speaker 0: I need to cut it in half, right so I will do.
Speaker 0: if I did a lossy compression I would shrink it to 50 megabytes.
Speaker 0: rim would get it.
Speaker 0: He'd open it up and half the email will be missing.
Speaker 0: So that wouldn't really work out.
Speaker 0: You have to do a lossless compression like a zip file.
Speaker 0: a zip file will shrink another file inside of a zip and It won't lose anything when you unzip it and uncompress it.
Speaker 0: the whole files there just like before.
Speaker 0: Yep But it takes up less space and there are a lot of lossless formats.
Speaker 1: I mean flack is probably the most commonly known lossless audio format.
Speaker 1: It's not used that widely but we use it on geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if you take a wave you take a CD and you rip the audio off the CD to a wave.
Speaker 0: you haven't lost Anything.
Speaker 0: this perfect PCM audio.
Speaker 0: that wave is the same as the CD.
Speaker 0: turn it into a flack.
Speaker 0: You're gonna cut the size by quite a bit, but you're not gonna lose a single sound.
Speaker 0: It'll sound just the same as CD.
Speaker 0: Turn it into an mp3.
Speaker 0: However, and it's not gonna sound the same as the CD But you might not be able to detect that with your ear.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean if you can encode mp3s, you know with like 320 kbps where it's used It has so much data of stream available That really no human can actually tell the difference at that point and people who say they can't are lying to you.
Speaker 0: But if you encode the mp3 to say 96 kbps You can clearly tell the difference that something is missing and it will not sound as good as the CD.
Speaker 1: yeah, you want to see a really good example of it.
Speaker 1: quick open a program like the GIMP or Photoshop and take an image and Then try to save it as a JPEG and usually you can pick the quality level you want.
Speaker 1: on the JPEG It'll show you the file size.
Speaker 1: It'll show you a preview of what the picture will look like and As you drag it to smaller file sizes, you can see the artifacts start appearing and the image looks worse and worse and worse.
Speaker 0: Yes, JPEG GIF pang all of those are Lossy image compression format.
Speaker 1: Scott GIF is lossless.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not.
Speaker 0: if you turn like a big bitmap into a gif gif has a limited palette So it can only give as a format is lossless.
Speaker 1: If you put something in the gift format.
Speaker 1: It is a perfect.
Speaker 0: If you take another if you take an image that the get a gif file format cannot handle Yeah, gif is only lossly lossy.
Speaker 1: If you try to put something into it that couldn't fit into it already Yeah, it only handles like 256 colors or whatever like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well think of it this way.
Speaker 1: if you have a file that has 3,000 colors in it and you want to compress it one way to compress it is to reduce the number of colors.
Speaker 1: That way you need less information to describe that picture.
Speaker 1: So if you turn it into a gif with only 255 colors It's not gonna look the same, but it'll be smaller.
Speaker 0: Yes much much much smaller.
Speaker 0: But if you turn into a JPEG you can keep all the colors you want But you're gonna lose Pixels here and there.
Speaker 0: it combines pixels together and mushes them into colors and it all and I'll describe more how it works next Monday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all this cool stuff with mathematical equations and you might have heard the term wavelets before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it gets pretty cool that.
Speaker 0: that's all the stuff for the next three episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz.
Speaker 1: then there's the frontiers of all this which is fractal compression.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how this compression actually happens is really freaking interesting.
Speaker 0: like you try to figure it out on your own like go home and try to like make a way to Write some words and then try to figure out a way to put the same information that is in those words to write the same sentence with fewer letters without you know Losing any of the information so that someone else can undo it and get the same thing back.
Speaker 0: You know make up like a secret code that shrinks things down and works for any sentence.
Speaker 0: You can come up with it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is it's a lot easier to do that than to do it for a computer because if another human is reading It humans are smart and can figure things out.
Speaker 1: computers can't actually figure things out.
Speaker 1: They have to follow a process.
Speaker 0: You have to be able to do it so that there's no actual figuring out involved.
Speaker 0: It has to be a process where you know, you perform these steps in this order exactly to you know.
Speaker 0: Take some information shrink it and make it big again without losing anything.
Speaker 1: So in the very least for the next three or four weeks We're going to be going into great detail about video audio and image codex decoders coders containers players Etc compressing decompressing playing watching listening.
Speaker 1: if you have any specific questions about this Are there any things you want us to cover directly post in the forums?
Speaker 1: Let us know.
Speaker 1: we'll probably be able to talk about it because we'll actually have some time to think about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and just to head off, you know the how do I get all these videos to play?
Speaker 0: There is a most.
Speaker 0: you are probably using Windows.
Speaker 0: There is a thing called the combined community codec pack aka the USSR.
Speaker 0: Yes, the cccp and if you go to cccp - project net Supposedly, I haven't tried it because I run Linux.
Speaker 0: this will help you play all your videos Specifically your anime fan subs that you downloaded legally or semi legally Animas key and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at two.
Speaker 0: Oh six three three three one five three seven.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.