Speaker 1: It's Thursday October 12th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We bring you a very special geek nights probably the worst fucking episode.
Speaker 1: We've ever done.
Speaker 0: It's a bit shit.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: so we played some more Atari games today.
Speaker 0: and Who is the master of the Donkey Kong's white rim?
Speaker 0: Alright, yeah, who is the master of outlaw rim?
Speaker 1: No?
Speaker 0: What was the other one?
Speaker 1: You beat me at something if you can remember what it was.
Speaker 1: You beat me at Qbert, that's right.
Speaker 0: I beat your ass at Qbert.
Speaker 0: There's something else to beat your ass at.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: What did you beat me at?
Speaker 1: I'm curious.
Speaker 0: I'm curious I'll remember.
Speaker 1: okay That'll be the the quiz question today on the show.
Speaker 1: if Scott can remember by the end of the episode What he beat me at at the Atari which?
Speaker 1: Just now we're talking to Emily.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I was talking to Emily and here's a bit of errata a bit of Something that I didn't realize and Emily pointed out to me and made me feel dumb kind of like when Scott noticed one day that Beatles wasn't spelled like the bug.
Speaker 1: yeah, so I Said I was playing Atari games and Emily says Atari means to win in Japanese yeah, and I was like That's why when you play go and you're gonna win.
Speaker 0: it's Atari.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway today, we're gonna talk about food.
Speaker 1: Maybe I think we're channeling the goats of Dave and Joel fast karate for the gentleman.
Speaker 0: I think we're channeling the ghosts of didn't get enough sleep started recording the episode too late ate a lot of food and Then had a busy day.
Speaker 1: see the thing is other than tonight when I didn't do anything And I just wasted my day.
Speaker 1: I had a really good day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I woke up.
Speaker 1: It was alright, and the weather was a bit shit.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry movies.
Speaker 1: You should see I can't stop making.
Speaker 0: ram is just becoming a pile of podcast references.
Speaker 0: I am me.
Speaker 0: why does it just be the meta podcast.
Speaker 0: We'll just mention every other podcast in the world.
Speaker 1: That's really a podcast reference.
Speaker 1: I think that's more of a British podcast pointer.
Speaker 0: alright alright.
Speaker 1: It's a bit shit.
Speaker 1: So you know I wait weather's crappy and you find this tree.
Speaker 1: Yeah our way to ruin my story I know right alright, so I'm at work, and I'm wandering around.
Speaker 1: I'm at the bottom tip of the Bronx like Manhattan is right there, and I'm working on some stuff.
Speaker 1: And I'm dressed up really nice cuz I was meeting with a client.
Speaker 1: so you know I'm wearing really nice like business professional.
Speaker 1: I got a little messenger bag, and I got all my paperwork And I am a stuffy looking white-collar businessman, and I walk out of the place I was working and I'm walking toward my car.
Speaker 1: I parked a couple blocks away on like 227th Street.
Speaker 1: As I'm walking I pass a park And there's a perfect climbing tree the same kind of tree that I had in my front yard when I was in high school But pretty much the best climbing tree.
Speaker 1: I'd seen in a long time, and I look around and There's a no one watching me.
Speaker 1: the streets empty because it's like one o'clock.
Speaker 1: So I drop all my stuff.
Speaker 1: I unbuttoned the top top couple buttons in my shirt I untuck it.
Speaker 1: I jump up, and I climb that goddamn tree.
Speaker 1: I climbed like 20 feet of the air now one.
Speaker 1: I would like to point out that I am a little bit older than I was the last time I climbed a tree and I don't feel really slower, or you know starting to wear down in any real way But I can tell you that my body felt a lot heavier and a lot more fragile Than it used to when I was climbing that tree.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I noticed that too when I was a kid I used to be like jump down a jillion stairs And I do all kinds of crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: Nowadays, I'll like a jump that when I was a kid would have been no problem.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: I look at it like Yeah, I got to the top, and I remember thinking you know if I fall.
Speaker 1: I'll probably die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so then you know I climb back down, and I I'd like jump off the last the second to last branch.
Speaker 1: I catch the last branch I swing back and forth a bunch of times And then I land and I think all right I can get on with my businessman life.
Speaker 1: Then I hear the clapping The clapping.
Speaker 0: you say so I turn around screw you and give you the clap.
Speaker 1: that was the dumbest joke I've ever heard anyone.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of joke that's gonna come out when I'm tired on a Thursday.
Speaker 1: I see I'm not that tired.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty tired all right.
Speaker 1: So there's this dude in a wheelchair this old man, and he's clapping And he wheels over to me, and he puts his hand up And he says man you just made my day, and he rolls his wheelchair away.
Speaker 1: Just laughing as hard as he can.
Speaker 0: So I that's an awesome dude.
Speaker 1: So I rebuttened up my you know Businessman shirt and I pick up my businessman briefcase and I walk back to my car and drive back to my office in Yonkers.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, today.
Speaker 0: I actually I have worked.
Speaker 0: I got work to do.
Speaker 0: They're launching this site on Saturday and I have to.
Speaker 0: I had an application that I wrote that I have to integrate into the site.
Speaker 0: And you know what I learned from working today.
Speaker 0: See I was worried that from not working for so long.
Speaker 0: You know just sitting at work not doing anything and that You know I lost my skills of working.
Speaker 1: and then you know I worry that occasionally I'll be at work, and I'll be like then.
Speaker 0: today I worked for maybe an hour And I got so much crazy shit done.
Speaker 0: if I actually worked eight hours a day of actually working Do you know how much shit I would do?
Speaker 0: I'd probably die from doing that, but yeah, I would do so much crap.
Speaker 0: It would be insane, so I don't know am I?
Speaker 0: I'm feeling in the mood of working yet I think I might start producing work soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe you won't though.
Speaker 1: I have this feeling you won't no.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna at least tomorrow I am for sure.
Speaker 0: another thing is I started As I was looking around on dig and there was some website that said to take a picture every day And I have a digital camera that I don't use enough, so I said why the hell not?
Speaker 0: So if you pay attention to my flicker, I'm gonna take one photo every day from now on all right yep We'll see.
Speaker 1: cuz I had a vision as to what kind of pictures Scott was gonna be taking.
Speaker 0: well The idea is to try to take a picture that sort of sums up your day So you can look at the picture and then remember that day.
Speaker 1: I imagine 365.25 pictures of a phallus.
Speaker 0: No, no the first picture is actually picture of the phone on my desk at work because I had a conference call today.
Speaker 0: That was pretty much the height of my day.
Speaker 0: Wow it was the last time I ever used that phone at work.
Speaker 0: never That never used the phone.
Speaker 1: that was the height of your.
Speaker 1: I climbed a tree.
Speaker 0: never use the phone at work So it's like a strange thing to use it.
Speaker 1: I climbed a tree, and you took a picture of a telephone.
Speaker 1: yep Right so in the news.
Speaker 1: I don't know much to say about this, but there's been a lot of talk.
Speaker 1: I mean we've been bashing blu-ray and HD DVD and a lot of people have been saying it'll do poorly.
Speaker 1: and a lot of people Have been saying that we're just really pessimistic, and I'd like to note that as of the most recent sales figures The sale of blu-ray and HD DVD devices has fallen a bit short of the projected sales And by a bit I mean more than 60%.
Speaker 0: That's not unexpected.
Speaker 0: who the hell has an HDTV and who the hell's gonna shell out a hajillion dollars to one of these players?
Speaker 1: Practically no one has bought HD equipment for blu-ray or HD.
Speaker 0: you know who's buying most of the equipment?
Speaker 0: no one.
Speaker 0: Gadget review websites like in gadget and gizmodo and even better.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna read magazines.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna read into this very much because there's really.
Speaker 1: I mean I'm not sure exactly how they got these numbers But they say that they expect game consoles that are equipped to play blu-ray or HD DVD To make up 1 million of the 1.7 million devices that will be sold before the end of the year.
Speaker 1: now Didn't Sony say they're gonna have 2 million PlayStation threes?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe not?
Speaker 1: so yeah They did so.
Speaker 1: how come the industry here is saying that they expect 1 million to be sold?
Speaker 0: I don't know either.
Speaker 0: They don't.
Speaker 0: is also supposedly gonna be some HD DVD thing on the 360?
Speaker 0: who knows it's up in the air.
Speaker 1: That was pretty much a rumor so far.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're gonna see what comes of that.
Speaker 0: It's craziness.
Speaker 0: probably nothing.
Speaker 0: probably I have.
Speaker 0: there might be a chance that they'll sell Xbox 360 the HD DVD players or they'll sell like a replacement disk drive for it and I don't know if they're gonna put games exclusively on HD DVD though.
Speaker 0: That's that's a long shot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I was gonna do the news about the correlation between being fat and being dumb.
Speaker 0: What happened to that news?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use that Monday, so you can all stew about it over the weekend all right.
Speaker 0: So my news isn't really in news, but it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: the guy who made bit torrent Bram Cohen Right he was talking about Share ratios.
Speaker 0: you see there are a lot of bit torrent trackers And what those track and these are basically run by people who have the same logic as the olden day IRC f-serves which I guess still exist in a lot of places.
Speaker 0: and the logic was you know This is a or the hotline servers also remember those you ran one of the most popular anime hotline servers out there.
Speaker 0: I did and then I got rid of it cuz hotline died, but Basically the way those servers worked was you would download files from the server But in order to get files you had to upload new files.
Speaker 0: So if you ran a server that would had a lot of files to begin with you were going to get a lot of more New files and it was basically saying hey if you were the kind of person who uploads to me Then you can get from me.
Speaker 1: you want to know how.
Speaker 0: I make sure there was a fair shake Especially back in the days of rename the same file upload it.
Speaker 1: no no no much simpler than that in the days of FTP file servers mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I made a file that was 1.8 gigabytes And I would just set that to upload for a while and then I download everything I wanted.
Speaker 1: then I never connected that site again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, no, but a lot of bit torrent trackers have are setting share ratio monitors.
Speaker 0: What they do is they say hey if you're only downloading and then closing right away instead of sticking around and uploading Then we're gonna kick you off of our you know torrent trackers.
Speaker 0: You can't get our stuff anymore.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: Whatever?
Speaker 0: well Those people are complaining because now people are you getting bit torrent clients that?
Speaker 0: Falsely report how much they are uploading and downloading so that they don't get banned by trackers Even if they do things the right way.
Speaker 1: oh fine, whatever it was a self-correcting situation right?
Speaker 0: so Bram Cohen you know what they'd happened.
Speaker 0: is the people running those trackers right?
Speaker 0: we're complaining that They need to change the bit torrent protocol so people can't lie about how much they're uploading and downloading.
Speaker 1: Let me guess.
Speaker 1: my guess here is that mr.. Bit torrent gave them the double-deuce.
Speaker 0: Oh he gave him the triple-deuce.
Speaker 0: He's like you know what if you weren't banning people?
Speaker 0: they wouldn't need to be lying in the first place.
Speaker 0: and also You're banning based on share ratio is completely stupid.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with bit torrent the way it is.
Speaker 0: You don't need to force people to seed you know.
Speaker 0: and then he goes on to talk about how You know when someone if there's a new torrent.
Speaker 0: That's hot right There's gonna be a lot of whoever's uploading it.
Speaker 0: at that point the few uploaders are gonna Have a lot of upload activity and then in the middle of the torrent You know there's gonna be you know really hot activity on both ends and then towards the end if Someone comes in to download at that point They're gonna get the file really quick because there'll be a bunch of cedars and no one else downloading because it's it's already done.
Speaker 0: So people coming in late to a torrent we get shafted by these idiots who don't know how to run their trackers.
Speaker 0: and those are the people who get banned just because they came late to a torrent.
Speaker 0: and You know people wouldn't get to upload so much by that point.
Speaker 0: And he's like you shouldn't ban people from your tracker based on share ratios.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: He's right.
Speaker 0: well
Speaker 1: I gotta say back in the days of winmx if I was at my computer I'd periodically look cuz I let a lot of people download from me And I had a lot of stuff And I just watch and anyone who was downloading slowly I would just kick them off so other people could get my stuff.
Speaker 0: That's what I would do.
Speaker 0: also You know if you someone was downloading too much stuff, or they were too much was fine.
Speaker 1: Well, no too much at once like I like that exclusion of other people trying to get in there You could set up filters that prevented that automatically and queued people up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I try, but it was always kind of tricky.
Speaker 0: Ah, it didn't always work.
Speaker 0: for some reason I can always inevitably get one guy downloading a thousand things at once or like queuing up a thousand things.
Speaker 0: And it was annoying especially when I wanted to close winmx and play a game.
Speaker 1: see I would just close winmx.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but you know the point is is people try to you know deal with these digital.
Speaker 0: You know p2p sharing as if it's a trade.
Speaker 0: They're like.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: they try to force people you know like to know and take equally You know like they keep trying to force people to give and take equally to force Fair sharing.
Speaker 0: all bit torrent is designed to share fairly by default.
Speaker 0: You don't need to do anything.
Speaker 1: This has always been around.
Speaker 1: This is the same people who beg and beg and beg and whine at IRC to be given up And then they lord it over people.
Speaker 1: the same people who care how many MP3 files they have.
Speaker 1: The same people who care if they got the zero day wares Because it makes them cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see I'm glad that the Bram Cohen bit torrent guy has given them the shaft But on the other hand you know it does show.
Speaker 0: the one weakness of open source is that idiots are inevitably going.
Speaker 0: You know bit torrents open source.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of bit torrent clients and tracker softwares out there that it that allow them to do things this asshat way.
Speaker 1: Well what I mean?
Speaker 1: a lying about your share ratio, whatever.
Speaker 1: that doesn't mean any.
Speaker 1: no no no also You know banning people based on Sherry that that really only has to do with the tracker and not the client.
Speaker 0: yeah Well, it's.
Speaker 0: it's both of those things combined and neither one of them should really exist.
Speaker 1: so your point was because Open-source exists people might use open source code to do things that you don't agree with personally.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay that could end up harming me.
Speaker 0: You know I want to get a file, but it's the server's run by assets.
Speaker 1: so now I can't get it, but you just get it anyway you deal with the assets, and then you take their stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't deal with assets, okay, then how you gonna get stuff that assets have?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna kick their ass.
Speaker 1: I mean if you ever actually well kick their hat.
Speaker 1: I don't think you've ever actually run into this problem.
Speaker 1: No, you've never run into a file.
Speaker 1: You couldn't get because someone was being an asshat.
Speaker 1: It's a fake problem.
Speaker 0: You made a straw man problems.
Speaker 0: It could happen It didn't.
Speaker 0: that's cuz I don't hang around those sleazy places getting sleazy files.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's mostly like porno, but torrent trackers I Imagine where's bit torrent trackers?
Speaker 0: no one else actually cares about that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so where do you get your porn anyway?
Speaker 0: No, and then thinking about it getting it from a new place so where he been getting it?
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm looking for new places.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: You don't know?
Speaker 1: How can you not know where your porn comes from unless you don't want to say the name of it because it's something.
Speaker 0: No, it's not really that weird that weird All right, so wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I gotta go back to this.
Speaker 0: Why don't we change the episode?
Speaker 1: Maybe instead of food?
Speaker 1: We'll talk about where Scott gets his porn.
Speaker 0: I don't know because there's a new website you porn calm which is like the YouTube of porn.
Speaker 0: I might go there, but it didn't work the last time I tried it.
Speaker 0: It was all crashing and freezing mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: We'll have to see if it's any better now.
Speaker 0: Oh, I got a good thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I was laughing pretty hysterically when I found out about it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, so do you know about lemon?
Speaker 1: That 24-hour race that's really really really really boring.
Speaker 0: well lemon.
Speaker 0: I think it's a type of racing I don't know enough about it because I don't care about it But it's endurance racing where they race cars for a long time and they stop and switch drivers And it's all about going fast, but also not having your car break down.
Speaker 1: It's exactly as boring as it sounds.
Speaker 0: yeah It's not the most exciting race in the world, but whatever.
Speaker 0: but here these guys in California have a race that they run called 24 hours of lemons as in lemons as in lemon cars that are crappy.
Speaker 0: and Basically, it's a 24-hour endurance race for cars costing $500 or less.
Speaker 0: and this picture is just hilarious looking to these jalopies driving around his track.
Speaker 1: And then if you go to this site and read the fact it's even funnier I like how the purses they pay out at the end are paid entirely in nickels.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like everything about this whole race is a complete joke like any Any place.
Speaker 0: they could possibly make something funny.
Speaker 0: They did like.
Speaker 0: halfway through the race Everyone in the grandstands votes on a car that gets just they're gonna crush it.
Speaker 0: they crush it right there.
Speaker 0: It's like no you suck you get crushed.
Speaker 0: And it's great.
Speaker 0: like on the instructions here, they're like the fact says will I die?
Speaker 0: Maybe safety equipment isn't included in the $500 car purchase price.
Speaker 0: You'll have kind of a fighting chance, but this isn't a brilliant thing to be doing.
Speaker 0: get used to it.
Speaker 0: It's like will my car die?
Speaker 0: oh almost definitely Yeah.
Speaker 0: And even if it survives on the track Halfway through the race one entry will be chosen by popular ballot for immediate crushing.
Speaker 0: could be yours heck it probably will be yours.
Speaker 0: be.
Speaker 0: The whole rules of this race read like a silly RPG book like it's paranoia or something.
Speaker 0: But it's a car race in California.
Speaker 0: man if I lived in California I would totally go this thing and probably race.
Speaker 0: that's so worth 500 bucks.
Speaker 0: I spent $500 on worse things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, almost definitely As you know drive around a track in a crappy car everyone else is driving a crappy car.
Speaker 0: You want to see how long you can go.
Speaker 0: you want to see how fast you can go?
Speaker 0: It's good stuff, right?
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day I stumbled upon this being you know bored at the end of the day at work.
Speaker 1: Someone now you might remember the old Mary Worth comic and newspapers.
Speaker 0: god.
Speaker 0: I hate all those comics.
Speaker 1: It's really a shitty comic and whoever does it is not a cool person at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you ever if you read the newspaper comics There's the the generic really popular ones then there's some of the more Targeted ones and then there's the boring want to be serious ones Like soap operas of the old school.
Speaker 1: they're not really very serious because there's only three panels a day and No one can actually follow that plot.
Speaker 1: and if you do the plot is shite It's.
Speaker 0: it's no different than watching a soap opera on TV only watching such a small part of it.
Speaker 1: The worst part was mean the art was bad and everything.
Speaker 1: so a bunch of people got together and they filmed Mary Worth using the dialogue and the framing and the camera angles from the comic.
Speaker 1: and I got to say this is a little disturbing to watch.
Speaker 1: you might not want to watch this if you're alone at night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they did it all in black and white and they had the people stand in the poses that they were in the comic frames But not moving.
Speaker 0: it is and they put this eerie music on it, and it was kind of freaky.
Speaker 1: If you don't good God is Mary Worth terrible now.
Speaker 1: I would put out a bounty.
Speaker 0: What are those other ones like apartment 3g?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I will put out a bounty Thor.
Speaker 1: I will put out a bounty right now.
Speaker 1: Anyone who can find someone who earnestly enjoys Mary Worth?
Speaker 1: Get them in my contact get them on this show.
Speaker 1: We will interview them.
Speaker 1: I guarantee it.
Speaker 0: Why don't we get the person who does it?
Speaker 0: I'm sure they're not busy.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they're even alive.
Speaker 1: It's probably just like a couple of syndicated dudes who were hired to keep it going or something.
Speaker 0: All right I'm gonna read the Wikipedia on it.
Speaker 1: Well, we're not gonna do that now.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not doing it right now, but I meant in the future because I don't care about the person who writes it.
Speaker 1: They do it for money.
Speaker 1: I want to hear from someone who reads it who reads that outer drivel.
Speaker 0: That's a very good question.
Speaker 1: I mean I can understand reading underwear pervert comics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do understand the underwear forever comics more than I understand Mary Worth.
Speaker 1: Plus I've liked a few underwear perverts.
Speaker 1: I mean Batman and you know Batman.
Speaker 0: It's a spider-man.
Speaker 1: No, I don't like spider-man.
Speaker 0: Well, it's spider-man.
Speaker 1: I like the spider-man movies.
Speaker 1: I hated every spider-man comic I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: It's most of them are suck, but there's some good ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, give me one that's good and I'll try to read it All right.
Speaker 0: It's usually the ones where it's not actually like the main spider-man book.
Speaker 0: It's always like here's spider-man and he's just hanging around town doing something funny cuz he's spider-man.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Those are the ones that I like.
Speaker 0: anyway All right.
Speaker 0: So today we're gonna talk about I guess we're gonna argue about food because rim Doesn't like yogurt or milk because he's a heathen and Scott doesn't like anything.
Speaker 0: That's good All right, all right.
Speaker 1: So let's start with cream of wheat.
Speaker 1: cuz Scott for some reason will eat cream of wheat.
Speaker 0: cream of wheat is awesome If it's cold in the winter, you know, you don't want to have a bowl of dry cereal with some cold milk.
Speaker 0: You don't want to eat some cold fruit.
Speaker 0: you want to get some nice hot mushy cream of wheat And you don't need oatmeal.
Speaker 0: oatmeal is all clumpy and nasty and you know, you want like Quaker oats.
Speaker 0: That's even nastier.
Speaker 0: You gotta have cream of wheat.
Speaker 0: It's creamy and weedy and not only that.
Speaker 0: but you freakin put some milk and some sugar and some raisins in there.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff man, but cream of wheat doesn't taste like anything.
Speaker 1: It's the second blandest thing in the world.
Speaker 0: That's why you put the sugar and the raisins and the milk in it.
Speaker 1: Why not just eat sugar raisins and milk because then it wouldn't be a hot cereal and heat it up?
Speaker 0: If I tend to not you need the highest.
Speaker 0: it's mostly the hot mushy part and it does taste like something.
Speaker 0: It tastes like wheat.
Speaker 0: It's like eating five you're talking about.
Speaker 0: like hearty bread doesn't get any hardier than cream of wheat.
Speaker 0: It's like eating five pieces of bread.
Speaker 1: It gets much harder than cream of wheat because cream of wheat is the most processed white bread.
Speaker 0: crap It's not.
Speaker 0: you got to get the kind with all the yellow bits in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it still doesn't taste any different.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: cream of wheat is just the player is it you haven't had there?
Speaker 0: you gotta eat the free.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've had all sorts of cream of wheat.
Speaker 1: when I was in the Cub Scouts They made us eat it every morning because it was the only thing they had at camp.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and no matter who made it or what they made it always tasted like nothing.
Speaker 0: I'll make you a cream of wheat that doesn't taste like nothing.
Speaker 1: I don't think you can I can.
Speaker 0: the trick is some people They put too much water or they don't get rid of enough water and then it's not thick enough and it's all watery and it Tastes like you want something hot and mushy and sweet on a cold day.
Speaker 1: have some chocolate, you know cocoa or something Hot cocoa filled with marshmallows.
Speaker 0: It's no good.
Speaker 0: It's all sugar.
Speaker 0: It's not a breakfast.
Speaker 0: That's freaking dessert.
Speaker 1: That's a breakfast.
Speaker 1: You realize in the I usually eat pumpkin pie for breakfast pretty much from it's also dessert.
Speaker 0: But I don't eat pumpkin from September until December not for eating there for decorating.
Speaker 1: All right, so let's get on this one.
Speaker 1: Scott doesn't like pumpkin pie, which is probably the best pie ever conceived on to man.
Speaker 0: I've cut open pumpkins.
Speaker 0: I smelled pumpkins.
Speaker 0: I've eaten pumpkin.
Speaker 0: pumpkin does not taste good.
Speaker 0: It's only use is as an entertainment.
Speaker 1: gourd See one or squat.
Speaker 0: I just a gourd or squash.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure gourds and squashes are very similar.
Speaker 0: if not, they are similar, but I wonder which one a pumpkin is.
Speaker 1: It's a squash.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I just I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You're just deciding.
Speaker 1: but here's the thing one cider one pumpkin bread is awesome to pumpkin seeds when roasted are awesome.
Speaker 1: and three Pumpkin pie especially when it's got a lot of nutmeg in.
Speaker 1: it is the most wonderful dessert pie in the world.
Speaker 0: I get it.
Speaker 0: It's all about the nutmeg and the hallucinating.
Speaker 0: That's why you like it Alrighty.
Speaker 0: so you don't really like pumpkin pie.
Speaker 0: you like nutmeg pie.
Speaker 1: Actually one thing I'll notice that the best pumpkin of I ever had and I'm not kidding here was one that Emily's mom made Over a Thanksgiving because she used a different amount of nutmeg and there were some other spices in it And it was just a really freaking good pumpkin pie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not a fan of eating pumpkin, but you won't eat strawberry rhubarb the second greatest pie ever made either.
Speaker 0: I'll eat strawberry.
Speaker 0: strawberries are awesome and I'm eating rhubarb.
Speaker 1: But you see you can't have a strawberry pie without rhubarb because rhubarb adds the bite.
Speaker 0: You can just not eat rhubarb.
Speaker 0: you can have a strawberry apple pie what?
Speaker 1: that's not.
Speaker 1: that's nothing compared to strawberry.
Speaker 0: We have a strawberry banana pie.
Speaker 1: That would be terrible be awesome.
Speaker 1: Can't make a banana pie Why not?
Speaker 1: Have you ever seen a banana pie?
Speaker 0: No, but we should make.
Speaker 1: there's a reason why bananas don't bake.
Speaker 1: Well, I think banana bread banana bread is not banana.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: Of course?
Speaker 1: Alright you take a banana and try to bake it and see what happens to it.
Speaker 0: I can freakin bake a banana pie.
Speaker 1: I'll take you up on that.
Speaker 1: I don't think you could I could do it.
Speaker 0: I'll get a little.
Speaker 0: get a generic pie.
Speaker 1: I think you can make a banana cream pie, but you couldn't just make a banana pie with slices.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know you strawberry cream pie.
Speaker 1: Mmm strawberry cream pie is very good, but it's got nothing on strawberry rhubarb.
Speaker 0: Rhubarb is ass.
Speaker 0: it is not meant to be eaten.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: What is not just have to cook it properly So it's not poisonous anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not meant to be eaten.
Speaker 0: It doesn't taste good.
Speaker 0: It's just like brown hard nastiness.
Speaker 1: It's not brown.
Speaker 1: It's red.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: It's reddish brown.
Speaker 0: It's not good.
Speaker 1: See a strawberry pie would be okay, but the rhubarb adds this kick to it that really pushes it beyond the realm of mortal food.
Speaker 0: Um Yeah, because you die when you eat the poison rhubarb, that's why it's not mortal food.
Speaker 1: Okay, except the fact that you don't die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you do Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Mr.
Speaker 0: Rhubarb is ass.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Hotshot bring up a food.
Speaker 0: Yeah, freakin what it's the hell with you not drinking milk the most necessary thing to drink.
Speaker 1: All right I'm a mammal and once mammals reach the age of majority, they don't need milk anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, okay.
Speaker 0: But then why don't you stop eating?
Speaker 0: I don't know other things that you only ate when you were a kid.
Speaker 1: I stopped eating a lot of the things I ate when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I almost never eat candy anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't eat candy so much either.
Speaker 0: but you know, you look at animals in the wild.
Speaker 0: They generally eat the same shit when they're you know throughout all their ages.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except change their diets based on age.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do.
Speaker 1: They all stop drinking milk.
Speaker 1: All mammals stop drinking milk except humans who have cows.
Speaker 1: and we drink cows milk Yeah, but they all.
Speaker 0: everything else stays exactly the same.
Speaker 0: What does it matter if you stick with milk or not?
Speaker 0: Just because because it does other animals don't have ways of producing other things.
Speaker 1: my body tricks me every now then because sometimes I'll have A whole bunch of candy.
Speaker 0: if you want to make that argument, maybe you should just you know only eat.
Speaker 0: But you know that you would get if you were like a caveman.
Speaker 1: see the thing is I'm an omnivore so I could eat anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if you're a caveman and oh, you know and you're a natural living in the wild human You would only eat nuts berries and raw meat.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I would really like to eat almost nothing but raw meat fine.
Speaker 0: No more strawberry rhubarb pies.
Speaker 1: Just strawberry nuts and Rami Strawberry rhubarb pie out in the wilderness.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, not if you're a caveman or a dumb animal who doesn't know how to get milk after you know But their mom is.
Speaker 1: I'm not a caveman anymore.
Speaker 0: I'm a human being and that's why you can fucking drink milk.
Speaker 1: Well, I could.
Speaker 1: milk tastes like crap.
Speaker 0: milk tastes great.
Speaker 1: It's filling and fatty.
Speaker 0: That's exactly why it's great.
Speaker 0: fat tastes good.
Speaker 1: Milk doesn't taste good though milk tastes great.
Speaker 0: Milk is like the most refreshing thing.
Speaker 1: I mean you eat like a cake or a chocolate chip cookie or anything I've noticed because every now and then I'll eat a whole bunch of chocolate cake or something I'll be like.
Speaker 1: I have a person girl cookies.
Speaker 1: cookies are nasty.
Speaker 0: Some of them are so all of them.
Speaker 1: I can't stand them anymore.
Speaker 0: No, it's all about the regular.
Speaker 0: the trefoils are good Now when I've been mince are okay.
Speaker 1: when I was a little kid I like Girl Scout cookies, but now I've grown up and I try to eat him and All of them except for the shortbread ones.
Speaker 0: That's the trefoil.
Speaker 1: I know tastes like.
Speaker 1: tastes like processed crap.
Speaker 1: It's like corn syrup and fat and lard.
Speaker 0: Well, the thin mint ones are okay, but the trefoil ones are by far the best.
Speaker 1: They're actually pretty crappy compared to real shortbread cookies And whatever you ever had.
Speaker 0: real shortbread cookies like fresh ones don't really care a cookie is a cookie.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: a cookie is a cookie.
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 1: So the only way a cookie can get better is by being hotter or squishier Alright, so if a cookie is a cookie then if I go to the store and get myself a cajun cookie It'll be exactly the same as a fresh-baked mama rose cookie.
Speaker 0: No, it's not the same.
Speaker 1: but you just said it cookies a cookie different kind of cookie.
Speaker 1: No, they're the same cookie a cajun cookie or a mama rose cookie.
Speaker 0: Those are two different cookies.
Speaker 1: No, they're not a Cajun cookie is just a mama rose cookie.
Speaker 1: That's been left out a while.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: What is up with you and these weird ass kind of cookie?
Speaker 0: It's like you like any food.
Speaker 0: that's weird.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: if it's a it's a weird food that something out of the norm rims like.
Speaker 0: ooh I like weird food just cuz it's weird.
Speaker 1: I don't like cajun cookies.
Speaker 1: cajun cookies the worst thing ever.
Speaker 0: I don't care I'm just saying you just like weird things for the sake of the weirdness.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: All right, I'll bite like what?
Speaker 1: What do I like?
Speaker 1: that's weird that I like for the sake of liking it pretty much everything you eat You.
Speaker 0: also whenever you cook something you will add like a bajillion spices just for the sake of adding a bajillion spices.
Speaker 1: Alright, like what?
Speaker 1: I mean if I make a grilled cheese Nothing makes a grilled cheese better than having some dill sprinkled in with the butter on the outside.
Speaker 0: No, that's generally not a good.
Speaker 0: where have you ever seen anyone do that, but you restaurants?
Speaker 0: What restaurant puts dill in the butter on a grilled cheese sandwich?
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of donners put dill on the grilled cheese.
Speaker 0: I never heard of such a thing and never seen such a thing ever or what else.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean what things do I add spices to that?
Speaker 1: You don't like me adding spices to.
Speaker 0: pretty much any time you cook a tomato sauce You take every spice that we have in the cabinet and dump it in there and then the tomato sauce is basically just a spice Mush.
Speaker 1: actually, all I put in is paprika usually and I don't even put in that much.
Speaker 0: Well, you're not putting in enough because you do got to put something in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I put paprika in there?
Speaker 0: No, it's usually not the net thing.
Speaker 0: You need to put in so much of.
Speaker 0: you generally need more garlic powder in there.
Speaker 0: That's what you need.
Speaker 1: All right, but I thought I wasn't supposed to put stuff in.
Speaker 0: you are but you put way too much stuff You know like throw spices and all kinds of crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: I think you might as well just eat the spice because the way you put spice on all the other flavors are destroyed.
Speaker 1: I think this argument comes out of the fact that Scott makes effectively McDonald's eggs make McDonald's eggs.
Speaker 1: That's idea of cooking eggs is?
Speaker 1: he'll beat him up, right?
Speaker 1: He'll just beat him up straight.
Speaker 1: doesn't add milk or water or anything.
Speaker 0: I thought you didn't like milk.
Speaker 1: I don't like drinking milk, but milk is useful for cooking.
Speaker 0: Well, but you're a mammal.
Speaker 0: you you're.
Speaker 0: you're done.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't ingest milk.
Speaker 1: No, that wasn't my argument wasn't that I shouldn't because that my argument was that that is a funny argument.
Speaker 1: The actual argument is that drinking milk is not a fun thing and it doesn't taste good.
Speaker 1: It refreshes the palate after a dessert, you know, what refreshes the palate much more after dessert some wine or a cold beer?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you just you're like those people who like drinking wine because you know, you like being all wine and froofy.
Speaker 1: I really like wine.
Speaker 0: You like being all froofy.
Speaker 1: I don't think I like being all wine.
Speaker 0: It just tastes like bad grape juice.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, you've never actually had good wine though.
Speaker 1: The only wine you've ever had is Meinischewitz and Hobo wine.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I drank some other crazy wine once.
Speaker 0: It just tasted worse.
Speaker 1: You drank that mead, but that mead was bad.
Speaker 1: That mead was.
Speaker 0: you gave me something once like way back at RIT.
Speaker 1: Yeah at RIT I bought this bottle of mead and we all opened it up and we all tried it and it tasted like an open asshole.
Speaker 0: I think there's another time.
Speaker 0: I drank like some white wine and it tasted bad.
Speaker 1: Mead was whitish.
Speaker 0: Whatever the point is White wine, especially white wine, but also fancy red wine is bad.
Speaker 0: I mean white grape juice is bad enough and I can read I can eat a green grape.
Speaker 0: a green grape is All right, not as good as a red grape, but good enough.
Speaker 0: and a grape juice That's you know, red grape juice.
Speaker 0: that tastes good, too But white wine is just bad.
Speaker 0: It doesn't taste like grapes.
Speaker 0: It tastes just like bad water.
Speaker 1: See, I don't know where you're coming from because white wine is fantastic.
Speaker 1: I really like a good German ice wine.
Speaker 0: It tastes like bad fruit water.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it tastes like ice wine and those kinds of things.
Speaker 1: tastes like really sweet like Rieslings.
Speaker 1: Whatever you just like knowing all those fancy names I need to know the names so I know what to buy.
Speaker 1: like if I try a wine and I like it I remember you just know you you like.
Speaker 0: just you know to know them and to say them so that other people go.
Speaker 0: Oh, he knows the names of the fancy, you know, it's that whole wine culture of except it's not because that wine culture is bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you're you're all into it.
Speaker 0: Even then you say it's bullshit.
Speaker 0: It's easy.
Speaker 0: being it being in something and saying it's bullshit is called Good job.
Speaker 1: It's like if I go.
Speaker 0: oh man all this psychic shit is bullshit, let me read your mind man.
Speaker 1: see.
Speaker 1: now the problem here Scott is that that was a straw man and more importantly in terms of straw man He has no brain.
Speaker 1: It seems to me that your argument with food with me Oh with everyone cuz you've made the same argument to other people before is that if anyone in the world like something that you don't Like.
Speaker 1: then you assume that they like it for some stupid reason that they don't actually know.
Speaker 0: not everything It's only things that are you know weird.
Speaker 1: what wine is not weird?
Speaker 1: wine was the staple of drink for thousands of years of human existence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not just not weird It's weird to have all these different strange, you know varieties of water.
Speaker 1: not strange.
Speaker 1: They only sound strange to you because they're in other languages because they come from those countries.
Speaker 1: It's called ice wine because it's German Bet.
Speaker 0: if all those?
Speaker 0: if they didn't have if the wines didn't have fancy names if they actually named them like why number one?
Speaker 0: Why number two?
Speaker 0: why number three or something?
Speaker 0: You know like that it.
Speaker 0: I'm saying the marketing of the wine and the labeling of the wine is a huge effect on you and your Psychology.
Speaker 1: no, it doesn't.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what has a huge effect on me the way a wine tastes?
Speaker 1: No, I don't think so because you realize the names of wines.
Speaker 1: It's not like marketers came up with them.
Speaker 1: We're gonna call this wine a Merlot and we're gonna call this wine a Chianti and we're gonna call this wine.
Speaker 1: I want you to call it a Hebrew.
Speaker 0: You know I should do is you take wines and like take them out of the bottles and switch them into different bottles and see if you Can tell.
Speaker 0: I don't think you good.
Speaker 1: I can tell the difference.
Speaker 1: I mean here's the thing I've had.
Speaker 0: so like if you went to the store and you bought a Merlot and there was actually Something else in that bottle and it wasn't a Merlot you wouldn't freakin know.
Speaker 0: I just like oh, this is an excellent Merlot.
Speaker 1: See actually probably not because my Merlots taste a pretty general way.
Speaker 1: And if it didn't taste like that, it probably tastes pretty bad and I'd go Yeah, this isn't good and I just pour the bottle out.
Speaker 0: Well, it wouldn't be something bad.
Speaker 0: It would be some other wine.
Speaker 0: It just that was good.
Speaker 0: It just wouldn't be a Merlot would be some other wine.
Speaker 0: I can't I don't know any names but you get the point.
Speaker 1: See I can tell the difference between the wines I like like but I can't tell the difference between most wines because I don't know enough about it.
Speaker 1: But like Merlot's I've had a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: so I can kind of tell.
Speaker 1: and if I drink like Alsatian wines I drink a lot of those because I like them.
Speaker 1: so I could tell if you gave me just some crap.
Speaker 1: Oh white wine when I expected another one, but if you gave me Watch your blah blah blah or versus a blah blah blah blah And I don't drink those much if at all then I couldn't tell I probably wouldn't know.
Speaker 0: And it's a whole culture.
Speaker 0: wine is no good.
Speaker 0: It's all I'm saying.
Speaker 1: but you realize the names come from, you know, ancient practice.
Speaker 0: It's not about the names.
Speaker 1: So what's it about?
Speaker 1: What's wrong with wine?
Speaker 0: It's about the fight that you had.
Speaker 0: just like it because it's good.
Speaker 1: I like it purely because it tastes good.
Speaker 0: It doesn't taste good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 0: It doesn't see that.
Speaker 0: I think you I think You know, it starts out where you like it because you want to like it.
Speaker 0: So you get into it and then I decide that it tastes good.
Speaker 0: you change your own mind To make you so that you like what you want to like and then you actually like it afterwards.
Speaker 0: You don't like it.
Speaker 1: to begin with you make this argument to almost everyone who likes things that you don't like.
Speaker 0: No, it's not just when you like things that I don't like.
Speaker 0: there are things you like that I also like or things that I we both don't like And it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: see don't freak.
Speaker 1: when I first had communion because I went to a Catholic school They made us do all that stuff and we had to eat the little Jesus cookie.
Speaker 1: And then we got to drink some red wine out of this giant gold chalice and everyone drank out of the same chalice Which is kind of horrible now that I'm older.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is kind of hard.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I didn't get tuberculosis or something.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: But the thing is it tasted really really good and I got in trouble because whenever communion came I'd tip the thing up in the priest's hand and drink as much as I could and I've always liked wine from the first time I ever had it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, same with soda.
Speaker 1: I remember the day my mom gave me a small glass of dr Pepper with ice cubes in it and it was like ambrosia.
Speaker 1: and from that day forth.
Speaker 1: I drank dr Pepper almost every day and in fact in high school, I would drink five or six cans a day.
Speaker 0: every day I drank a can of soda when I was a kid and it hurt my mouth and it was poisonous.
Speaker 0: It tasted like acid.
Speaker 0: that was just all right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So here's something you don't like soda.
Speaker 0: So it is poison.
Speaker 0: I don't drink it.
Speaker 1: How is it poison?
Speaker 0: Number one?
Speaker 0: The carbonation hurts.
Speaker 1: number two I gotta back that up here.
Speaker 1: the Carbonation hurts.
Speaker 0: it does so.
Speaker 1: you're saying that carbonated beverages in some way harm you.
Speaker 0: They don't.
Speaker 0: they make it my mouth feel pain.
Speaker 1: That's not normal.
Speaker 0: It's not normal about it.
Speaker 1: Um Do you do you think that everyone else feels pain when they drink soda, I think they just I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe they like it.
Speaker 1: There's no pain when you drink soda.
Speaker 1: It doesn't hurt.
Speaker 0: It stings.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: No, it does.
Speaker 1: I just had some tonic water.
Speaker 1: It doesn't sting.
Speaker 1: You know, what stings the quinine?
Speaker 0: whatever It stings.
Speaker 0: never drink carbonated beverage, even a lightly carbonated one.
Speaker 0: it goes And then it goes away.
Speaker 1: see to me carbonation is very refreshing.
Speaker 0: no, it's no good.
Speaker 0: All right, it's annoying.
Speaker 0: I want to taste the beverage.
Speaker 0: I don't want to have all these poisonous bubbles in my mouth.
Speaker 1: So why don't you drink some flat soda?
Speaker 0: Because it tastes like ass.
Speaker 1: what kinds of soda have you had flat?
Speaker 0: I think I had flat ginger ale and had diarrhea ones.
Speaker 1: flat ginger ale is great.
Speaker 0: It tasted like bad water.
Speaker 1: Okay, so apparently wine and pop taste the same.
Speaker 1: They taste like bad water to you or bad grape juice?
Speaker 0: and Well, it was bad in a different way okay, and the Soda tasted like freakin acid.
Speaker 0: He was uh, I don't know how anyone drinks that shit cuz it tastes great.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: it tastes bad.
Speaker 1: In fact, as soon as we stop recording this I'm gonna go drink some Tom Collins mixer with some ice over it while I do the post-production.
Speaker 0: Yeah, drunky.
Speaker 1: Uh, there's no alcohol in Tom Collins.
Speaker 1: It's just odd.
Speaker 1: It tastes kind of like squirt.
Speaker 0: What the hell is squirt?
Speaker 1: squirt is a soda I haven't seen for sale in a long time.
Speaker 1: the closest thing I found to it Is Tom Collins, so I drink that instead.
Speaker 0: Here's the point.
Speaker 0: You're just drinking weird stuff.
Speaker 0: because you like drinking I like squirt.
Speaker 1: It's a citrus.
Speaker 1: It's just citrus.
Speaker 0: It's a citrus drink, but you're like, oh, I'm drinking a Tom Collins something fancy.
Speaker 1: It's not fancy.
Speaker 1: It was 99 cents.
Speaker 1: I bought like 10 of them.
Speaker 0: The point is it's something out of the ordinary.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's a common drink.
Speaker 1: Squirt was just this brand.
Speaker 0: When was the last time you heard anyone say I'm gonna drink me some Tom Collins mixer?
Speaker 1: Actually when we were at the concert someone ordered a gin and Tom Collins AKA a gin Collins.
Speaker 0: I'd never even heard of Tom Collins before in my life.
Speaker 1: Actually, I looked up on Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: That's how I found out what it was and then I bought a bunch Because someone I heard it.
Speaker 1: so then you I go and I look at Wikipedia and it's the same as squirt and I really liked Squirt, but I haven't seen it for sale in a long time.
Speaker 1: So I bought it and it tastes like squirt.
Speaker 1: So now I got one of my favorite sodas back.
Speaker 1: Now if only I could get myself a big pile of some Faygo red pop, I'd be good to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, just great all these poisonous as a rocket Didn't you just eat normal food mainstream normal run-of-the-mill food.
Speaker 1: Are you saying that soda pop is not mainstream?
Speaker 1: I think most Americans drink it.
Speaker 0: I'm saying is that why don't you just drink, you know Coke and Pepsi and dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper in the normal ones?
Speaker 0: Why do you do a weird soda?
Speaker 1: Um, dr.
Speaker 1: My favorite sodas are pretty much any cream soda Any real root beer dr.
Speaker 1: Pepper, which is like my favorite soda ever.
Speaker 1: I've drunk it my whole life and I still drink it.
Speaker 1: and then like things like squirt I used to like seven up, but I don't anymore.
Speaker 0: I drink water juice and milk.
Speaker 1: That's it, but you don't even drink a lot of juices.
Speaker 0: I drink a lot of juices.
Speaker 0: I drink more juices than anything else.
Speaker 1: You don't seem to want to drink my pomegranate juice.
Speaker 0: It's cuz I'm gonna eat a pomegranate and I'm gonna drink pomegranate juice.
Speaker 1: When was the last time you ate a pomegranate?
Speaker 0: Six years ago.
Speaker 0: It's hard to get a pomegranate.
Speaker 0: They sell them in the store.
Speaker 0: They're not good the ones in the store.
Speaker 0: Okay, you got to get them right off the frickin tree.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I'll go find a pomegranate tree.
Speaker 1: See you can get the juice and it'll be fresh.
Speaker 1: because the juice was science.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the juice it doesn't taste the same because eating the pomegranate is all about the brainy bits in the middle of it That are all warbly.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, all right.
Speaker 1: Here's the food.
Speaker 1: Scott eats brain and I'm really I don't like it so much.
Speaker 0: What am I eating?
Speaker 0: the brain?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's just an inside joke from our IT.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's your brain eating habit?
Speaker 1: You gotta stop the monkey brain eater.
Speaker 0: you did it.
Speaker 1: That wasn't funny.
Speaker 1: That wasn't funny at all.
Speaker 0: You're not funny.
Speaker 1: Your mom's not funny If you can't tell we had nothing for the show today.
Speaker 0: We had nothing at all.
Speaker 0: We decided this is the worst show ever.
Speaker 1: we decided before the show that we were gonna pick a stupid topic and Argue about it as seriously as we could and get as mean as we could but we're tired.
Speaker 1: So we couldn't actually get that mean.
Speaker 0: yet today is just one of those days.
Speaker 0: We're sitting around like what are we gonna do the show on?
Speaker 0: I don't even want to do a show.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the hell we're gonna do a show on at all.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Let's just talk about nothing for some time and then give up.
Speaker 1: Yep And we're too tired even be funny about it.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I just want to go to bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so the thing is we didn't want to pick a real argument topic because that doesn't work when we're tired.
Speaker 1: I mean if we were trying to argue about philosophy or something, it would have just evolved into well the same thing.
Speaker 1: This one devolved into your mom.
Speaker 0: See the thing.
Speaker 0: it'd be so much easier right if we were like Gabe and Tyco.
Speaker 0: They just have to make like a three panel comic three times a week.
Speaker 0: So they have you know time to like prepare for it and it's there, you know, even when it wasn't their job.
Speaker 0: You know, you can edit the comic put it up later in the day.
Speaker 0: earlier in the day We get home from work and we have to eat dinner Do shit around the house
Speaker 1: watch anime play video games play board games
Speaker 0: have fun Cook dinner, right and Then we have to sit down for an hour and do the show And then we got to sit down for an hour and put the show
Speaker 1: up which would be fine.
Speaker 1: I said that we both have two hours of commute every day and Every single goddamn weekend we go out of town or something crazy happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we don't have a topic for a show.
Speaker 0: We're gonna lose a lot of time just thinking to the topic.
Speaker 0: and if we have to actually prepare for the show Oh forget that we're in trouble.
Speaker 1: instead of preparing for tonight's show Or doing anything constructive.
Speaker 1: We played every single level of outlaw.
Speaker 0: sorry Yeah, outlaw.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott beat me two out of 17 times.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't 17 times.
Speaker 1: That was 17.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was 17.
Speaker 1: You want me to list him off?
Speaker 1: It was unlimited ammo cactus.
Speaker 1: That's invincible.
Speaker 1: unlimited ammo cactus is not invincible.
Speaker 1: Limited ammo cactus that's invincible.
Speaker 1: limited ammo cactus is not invincible.
Speaker 1: stagecoach Unlimited ammo invincible non invincible.
Speaker 1: unlimited ammo stagecoach.
Speaker 1: I could keep going.
Speaker 0: I was gonna see how long you would go before you gave up.
Speaker 1: I could keep going all the stagecoaches.
Speaker 1: then Then there's all the walls.
Speaker 1: then there's all the moving walls.
Speaker 1: All right, plus we played one of them twice.
Speaker 0: I think you forgot the moving stagecoaches.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the invincible moving stagecoaches Invincible moving stagecoach is not invincible.
Speaker 0: moving stagecoaches.
Speaker 0: Yeah, both of those with ammo At least it's easier to describe than combat tanks.
Speaker 1: tanks with barriers tanks with more barriers tanks with bouncy shots Tanks with bouncy shots and more barriers.
Speaker 0: Tanks where you have to use a bouncy shot.
Speaker 0: You can't kill them directly.
Speaker 1: Tanks that are invisible yet somehow rim still find scott and jutes them every goddamn time anyway.
Speaker 1: Big plane versus three little planes.
Speaker 1: two little planes.
Speaker 1: It's two little planes plane versus plane helicopter boat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right we could play more air.
Speaker 1: see battle.
Speaker 0: oh god this episode.
Speaker 0: why are we still talking?
Speaker 0: let's quit this now.
Speaker 1: All right starting next week.
Speaker 1: We'll be back on track with our Monday.
Speaker 1: We're gonna continue that series on codex and everyone.
Speaker 0: we need Thursday episode ideas that do not require Preparation or research.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anytime you've suggested a good one like an actual Good Thursday.
Speaker 0: We're on that.
Speaker 0: we already did it.
Speaker 0: Now we're out of Good Thursdays, and we can't think of any.
Speaker 1: we've got about 15 Thursdays But they all require a modicum of effort which was not ready to be put forth today.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be ready to put forth ever.
Speaker 0: we need episodes that require no effort.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be upfront about it I think next week.
Speaker 1: It will be pretty easy.
Speaker 0: What are we gonna do next week?
Speaker 1: zombie apocalypse part 2 no How to not suck it not sucking.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: come up with how to not sucks cuz those are really easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what do you want us to tell you?
Speaker 1: how to not suck it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that sounds good, and we'll do it next week or the week after plus We'll probably get some sleep because honestly this weekend We're mostly just gonna be hanging out in someone else's house meaning.
Speaker 1: There's no messes to clean up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hooray hooray hooray.
Speaker 0: and Finally this goddamn episode is over.
Speaker 0: if this is your first geek nights.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry go listen to another episode.
Speaker 1: So don't judge us on this episode, so I'd like to conclude this by reading selections from the Great Gatsby.
Speaker 1: all right And I'll pay attention this might take a while Actually, I read the entire Wikipedia on Andy Kaufman today all right Cool, yeah, what did it say?
Speaker 0: did it talked about the part where he believed in Randy, and then he died.
Speaker 0: Transcendental meditation yeah, and he believed in lots of Randy.
Speaker 0: he went to get some alternative medicine far away And they basically just like ripped his guts out and he died.
Speaker 0: Or they did like the.
Speaker 0: you know the thing where the guy pretends to rip your guts out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, psychic surgery.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and You know instead of going to get real medicine, and then he died.
Speaker 1: yeah, of course all the other stuff was fake So it's hard to tell with him what he really did and what he was just making up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like he faked other people, but then he got faked himself.
Speaker 1: But did he really what?
Speaker 1: if that was all an elaborate thing - I don't know.
Speaker 0: the man was crazy.
Speaker 1: Watch the man's probably still alive.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: He's not if he's alive.
Speaker 0: He's chillin with Elvis.
Speaker 1: Yeah on the moon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure.
Speaker 0: ah This episode is done now.
Speaker 1: Oh is it?
Speaker 1: it keeps going.
Speaker 1: he's can't stop it.
Speaker 0: This is a bad train wreck.
Speaker 0: Just another is another round track coming down the rail.
Speaker 1: I'll say this at least This episode was better than a couple of podcasts out there that I've tried to listen to.
Speaker 1: oh Yeah next week, we'll be back on track tonight.
Speaker 1: We're going to bed And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: If you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.