Speaker 1: It's Wednesday June 7th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We bring you our coverage of Philly wizard world.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So anyone who breathes knows just how much I hate Sony.
Speaker 1: But I really have to reiterate today after the craft they put me through there are people who don't know you and they breathe.
Speaker 1: Oh, they know.
Speaker 1: kids born today their first words are Wow rim hates Sony.
Speaker 1: It's like those worms in that Family Guy episode.
Speaker 1: all right all right, so I go to conventions And I've got my little Sony ICD p320.
Speaker 0: now if you hate them so much Why did you buy one of their products?
Speaker 1: You know why?
Speaker 1: because there really aren't any good products in this area and Hardware wise Sony makes the best one.
Speaker 1: Now hardware wise I want I can't stress this enough this little piece of hardware that Sony made is awesome.
Speaker 1: It's very good at recording.
Speaker 1: I can plug my big external mic into it.
Speaker 1: it works.
Speaker 1: Just fine.
Speaker 1: it records tons of audio.
Speaker 1: It's a really good little thing and I love it.
Speaker 1: Now it has a little USB bit on the side and the USB bit Theoretically allows me to get the wave files.
Speaker 1: I've recorded off of it, so I can use them to make geek nights In order to get the wave files off.
Speaker 1: there is one and only one way I have to run the software for Windows only on The CD that Sony gave me and The sheer amount of DRM that they have put into this little CD is staggering.
Speaker 0: So they give you a huge pile of DRM to protect things that you recorded.
Speaker 1: Well if you're recording apparently I might record something unauthorized and then try to put it on my computer or Put a song on here in the crap quality that it records and then give it to someone else.
Speaker 0: And how this DRM?
Speaker 0: though?
Speaker 0: even if you use the Sony software There's nothing to stop you from doing that.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, there is you can't.
Speaker 1: if you put a file on to this recorder from a computer You cannot get it back off.
Speaker 1: It's flagged as un gettable.
Speaker 1: that way you can't share anything.
Speaker 1: it also flags things based on what computer and user ID recorded them and If you're not the same user ID you can't get it back off of the device.
Speaker 1: You can only put things on the device.
Speaker 0: But what if you go to a concert record something on the device take the device home take the wave file off make an mp3 And send it around the net?
Speaker 1: that I can do just fine.
Speaker 0: That's the only thing they should be worried about.
Speaker 0: no one else is gonna pirate.
Speaker 0: I think in another way.
Speaker 1: it only lets me get the file back off in a lower quality than the thing can actually do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and further it.
Speaker 1: it's really I don't know what they're trying to protect because I got all my stuff off of here.
Speaker 1: Just fine.
Speaker 1: It just took me a lot of wrangling and cheating and uninstalling and reinstalling the software And it's just also I can't get it to work in wine.
Speaker 1: There's no Linux version and even though it's a USB device It's not just a USB flash hard drive.
Speaker 1: It's a special proprietary thing that Linux just can't deal with and Windows can't even deal with.
Speaker 1: Only the software you get from Sony that is also difficult to uninstall and I think does bad things can get the stuff off.
Speaker 0: Why don't?
Speaker 0: you might have gotten root-kitted.
Speaker 1: you know what?
Speaker 1: that's fine, I actually expect that I got root-kitted.
Speaker 1: I don't use that Windows for anything anything in the world other than the stupid Sony recording.
Speaker 0: But why don't we make a recording bit that doesn't have DRM and sell it?
Speaker 1: you know what?
Speaker 1: that's not a bad idea It's not at all though.
Speaker 1: I think Eventually, I'll just buy a good SSR from a reputable company.
Speaker 1: the problem is I have to get a professional one that cost hundreds of Dollars more than this thing.
Speaker 0: yep, those are pretty expensive, but also pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: They even have those super microphone inputs and all that jazz, so if you needed one more reason to hate Sony Damn it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Alright yeah, anything happened to you today while I was at work.
Speaker 0: I said at work all day Reading comics so not working.
Speaker 0: No not working.
Speaker 0: then I came home.
Speaker 1: Surprisingly you came home not too long before I did.
Speaker 0: I had to stop.
Speaker 0: it was raining.
Speaker 0: I left.
Speaker 1: yes, it was raining.
Speaker 0: I left work a little late cuz I had to finish reading the comic.
Speaker 1: Oh, you tell me about rain.
Speaker 1: I woke up, and it wasn't sunny, but it was nice out here I didn't.
Speaker 1: it didn't look like it was gonna rain hard if at all when I woke up.
Speaker 1: So I drove to work.
Speaker 1: You know 50 miles to the south into a fucking rainstorm.
Speaker 1: Rim does not own an umbrella and rim did not bring a coat and rim has to park far away from his job and walk Around in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: I lost my umbrella.
Speaker 0: I need to buy a new one.
Speaker 0: I had a broken umbrella, and then I left another umbrella on the trains And I need to buy my third umbrella.
Speaker 1: Emily found an umbrella that she thought was mine But wasn't.
Speaker 1: but I took it anyway, and then it broke.
Speaker 0: It was just a crap By the newsstand city umbrella.
Speaker 1: it served me well for about four rainstorms.
Speaker 0: That's about how long those things last.
Speaker 1: it fell apart.
Speaker 1: I think Katsu or someone was swinging around like a sword, and it just went whoop.
Speaker 1: Well, it wasn't the best thing.
Speaker 0: no not at all.
Speaker 1: We're just fine.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of against umbrellas.
Speaker 0: I Pro umbrella.
Speaker 1: I prefer wearing a big long coat and a hat as opposed to having an umbrella.
Speaker 0: No, no one's making you use an umbrella.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: damn straight, but I'll take an umbrella if I have the chance, and it's raining.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna use one any non rain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a bit silly unless it's a parasol Or a Sunbrella.
Speaker 0: Not gonna use those Sunbrella.
Speaker 1: yeah, what if you are an albino?
Speaker 1: I'm not an albino, but what if you were say you were an albino now at that point?
Speaker 1: Would you be okay with using a Sunbrella?
Speaker 0: If I was an albino I'd probably just stay inside Not even if you had magic powers like powder Who?
Speaker 1: Wow okay never mind?
Speaker 1: I've never seen that movie.
Speaker 0: What movie is that powder?
Speaker 1: Okay, it's about an albino guy with magic power.
Speaker 1: I figured that out And in the end society doesn't understand him, and then he disappears.
Speaker 0: really yeah That sucks.
Speaker 0: in the end you should use his magic powers to fuck society.
Speaker 1: No uses magic powers to save the one person who wasn't totally afraid of him, and then he runs away And no one really learns a lesson.
Speaker 1: stupid albinos Alright, so you couldn't get some trouble finding some news, so what'd you dig up?
Speaker 0: I think we'll just Instead of saving it for next Tuesday will and say it's anime day.
Speaker 0: I want to do anime news, but there's also a big video game news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I don't know.
Speaker 0: they're both kind of quick.
Speaker 0: The big video game news is that there's new Smash Brothers Character roster announcements going down.
Speaker 1: I am jumping up and down in my seat right now because one of them was a Scott prediction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not only a Scott prediction, but a right up rims-alley prediction, that's right a Yeah, so let's see first who are they taking out of Smash Brothers?
Speaker 1: well They're taking out young link which I'm fine with because no one cared about young link.
Speaker 0: He's like who's little link.
Speaker 1: the same people use Pichu.
Speaker 1: yeah Pichu exists solely for the penis combination exactly.
Speaker 0: They also took out ice climbers.
Speaker 1: You see I'm kind of sad about that.
Speaker 1: I thought ice climbers was a neat character.
Speaker 0: I thought ice climbers could you know the character?
Speaker 0: fine?
Speaker 0: But the problem with them was that there was the duality of having two ice climbers But they didn't actually have any innovative way to use that.
Speaker 0: like you couldn't have one ice climber Somewhere beating up one guy with the other one beating up another guy.
Speaker 0: You're pretty much one ice climber with this Ball and chain other ice climber hanging on to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though I've seen videos of people doing crazy stuff with those eyes.
Speaker 0: People do crazy stuff with anyone, but I just it wasn't really fun or exciting.
Speaker 1: I found it fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I couldn't use the characters for shit, but I thought they were cool.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and Mr.. Game & Watch got cut.
Speaker 0: I like mr.. Game & Watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though he's a lot like Mewtwo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was.
Speaker 0: he's not like Mewtwo at all.
Speaker 1: He feels that way like he jumps.
Speaker 1: He falls a little slowly, and he's kind of woo.
Speaker 0: Not really yeah, but mr.. Game & Watch like the character again was cool But I thought his moves were pretty much Completely standard in every way.
Speaker 0: and there's already Mario who has completely standard moves and dr.
Speaker 0: Mario and Luigi.
Speaker 1: How standard is flipping flapjacks at someone?
Speaker 0: It's a pretty.
Speaker 0: It's just a standard kind of projectile.
Speaker 0: It's not right.
Speaker 1: wait a minute.
Speaker 1: So apparently all the characters is standard cuz either have a sword a projectile a jump fist kind of thing.
Speaker 0: He didn't have anything to differentiate him fighting wise from a lot of the other characters.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 1: Then what's the difference between say Roy and?
Speaker 0: Link nothing.
Speaker 0: they're both sword guys.
Speaker 0: That's my.
Speaker 0: that's what I'm saying is that in Smash Brothers They should really cut out the characters who fight similarly.
Speaker 1: all right, so get rid of Luigi.
Speaker 0: Well, you know you can keep them in there, but why bother making a whole separate character Which is moves that are crooks slightly different have like different fighting styles like sword guy generic guy gun guy?
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 0: and then just you can pick a model so you'd go to sword guy And there'd be like 50 sword guys to choose from it.
Speaker 0: It changes the way the model you use, but it's still.
Speaker 0: they fight like a sword guy.
Speaker 0: People seem to like the fact that they're all crooks slightly I know, but the thing is this way you could really please a lot of people by having a zillion characters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think you take a lot of people off too.
Speaker 0: But then you could also say there was sword guy link and then sword guy Meta Knight, but you know they would be.
Speaker 0: you know while their basic moves would be very similar They would all you could crook each one a little tiny bit like You know.
Speaker 0: maybe ones faster one slower kind of like different carts in Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: You know you just move the meters around for each one.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know it.
Speaker 0: just I felt that a lot of the characters and melee were redundant.
Speaker 0: so getting rid of these characters Removes a little bit of that, but now for the added characters.
Speaker 0: Scott's prediction kid Koopa.
Speaker 1: Oh my god if anyone out there knows me I play kid Koopa Exclusively in any game.
Speaker 1: I play where it's an option, and I defy you to pick it before me.
Speaker 0: well I'm smash brothers is okay, cuz they're gonna be for kid Koopas at once.
Speaker 1: ha ha Koopa.
Speaker 1: I just really like kid Koopa I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe it's cuz.
Speaker 1: I like dragons And he's kind of like a little dragon maybe because I'm a big fan of Bowser, and he's like the cool punk Bowser kid.
Speaker 1: I like his little face mask with the painted thing.
Speaker 1: I just I like him.
Speaker 1: I like him a lot.
Speaker 0: they got rid of kid link and they added in Wind Waker link.
Speaker 0: We I guess that'll be fun cuz he has some cool sword moves that the other links don't have and he also has some cool items that the other links don't have and In.
Speaker 0: it'll be pretty weird to see like this cel shaded guy fighting these ultra realistic guys Any more than seeing a two-dimensional game and watch fighting everyone.
Speaker 0: no it'll be similar.
Speaker 0: so that kind of.
Speaker 0: So it replaces the kid link and the game and watch.
Speaker 0: you know you just put a get Wind Waker link in there, and you're all good.
Speaker 0: and the last one that they've added in is Oh Ridley, I think that's gonna be cool because there weren't enough non humanoid things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really want to see non like weird things like.
Speaker 1: I'd like to see the vehicle from blaster master.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean In Smash Brothers so far they're pretty much been three types of things.
Speaker 0: you can be humanoids Bowser and Donkey Kong which are kind of big creatures and little creatures like Kirby Pikachu and Jigglypuff etc.
Speaker 0: So throwing in Ridley is a new kind of creature and that I think will really stir things up.
Speaker 0: They should put in all kinds of other weird Creatures that don't fit the usual.
Speaker 0: You know Things that are in Smash Brothers like the blaster master vehicle like the boys or the bionic commando.
Speaker 0: bionic commandos humanoid He while he's humanoid.
Speaker 1: He's a man who cannot lift his legs enough to jump yet He can fly around on a mechanical arm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the problem with him is that you pretty much have to jump in bionic commandos.
Speaker 0: So what if there's a flat map?
Speaker 0: What's he gonna?
Speaker 1: Do you know what?
Speaker 1: I don't care?
Speaker 1: I want him anyway, okay, and I want Megaman.
Speaker 0: no Megaman would be good.
Speaker 0: But again, he yeah, similar to Samus and he's a Capcom character.
Speaker 1: So good luck though They could make a Megaman.
Speaker 1: Well, if all of his attacks were turned into a classic Megaman bad guy with all their powers Yeah You could pull it off.
Speaker 0: Yeah Whatever.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway in my news there is someone is formed and I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna talk about the details because I'm not really These people.
Speaker 1: now there is the pirates Bay.
Speaker 1: There was also the pirate party political party over there.
Speaker 1: Yeah here in the US a bunch of people have gotten together and decided to officially legally form the pirate party in the US.
Speaker 0: Normally, I'd be all for that.
Speaker 1: now one their website is crap.
Speaker 1: They don't know what they're doing.
Speaker 1: They're very unprofessional about it and their only platform or plank as it were is this whole piracy thing.
Speaker 1: That's not the way to do this.
Speaker 1: that's not the way to win the hearts and minds.
Speaker 0: Nope, if you're gonna make a political party and you expect me to get behind it.
Speaker 0: You better be Professional and serious and have your shit together and stop playing with a knife while we're trying to make a podcast.
Speaker 1: Why doesn't affect you?
Speaker 0: You're obviously not paying attention.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I am you're sitting there paying attention to play with a knife.
Speaker 1: I'm very much paying attention.
Speaker 0: Anyway, if you're a pirate then you could play with a knife.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not joining the pirate party because they're lame and maybe one day if they actually are more professional and not a bunch of losers then we'll Get behind them.
Speaker 1: I mean I just I want to vote for third parties But at the same time I want to vote for the lesser of two evils.
Speaker 1: But at the same time almost every third party does something I don't like and there's really no candidate out there in the world Who represents me other than well me?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to vote for me.
Speaker 1: I think I'm gonna write myself in and the next election I can write in on.
Speaker 0: I got it everyone on.
Speaker 0: the next time There's an election.
Speaker 0: We're just all gonna write in like Ford Prefect or something like that Or Cthulhu or something Johnny.
Speaker 0: Yeah There we go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're just feel very disenfranchised more and more as time goes on.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, we should do a long show sometime on our specific political beliefs Since I think they kind of come out in the show they do.
Speaker 1: but I get the impression that freedom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've just noticed that the way them we tend to gloss over the details because we bring it up like oh girl Bush is dumber.
Speaker 1: Oh girl back is evil.
Speaker 1: Oh girl.
Speaker 1: The Democrats are wishy-washy but We don't I mean are.
Speaker 1: we actually have very complex political views that really don't come out in our quick arbitrary Gripping at one another.
Speaker 0: that's fine dirty hippies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we heard liberals.
Speaker 1: we are not leftists and it's right.
Speaker 1: things of the day.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: we've talked about Sega satana sashiro before.
Speaker 1: he's not being a thing of the day But we have periodically brought him up because we is one of our minor heroes.
Speaker 1: I've linked to my thing of the day today.
Speaker 1: Someone has made a actually someone.
Speaker 1: this looks like it's an old music video.
Speaker 1: I think it's legitimate from overseas but anyway, it is a compilation set to music of almost all of Sagatons videos.
Speaker 1: it is quite epic and awesome and I suggest you watch it.
Speaker 1: if You've never seen him before other than the video.
Speaker 1: I just linked to I Strongly suggest you seek out all of his commercials and watch them all in order.
Speaker 0: Yeah Just everyone knows.
Speaker 0: when the Sega satan came out in Japan It was actually a lot more popular over there than it is over here with good reason.
Speaker 0: It had many many good games over there that it didn't have over here and there was a series of commercials with this guy.
Speaker 0: And if they're awesome and famous and you should know about them Are we sure we're saying it right though?
Speaker 0: I think it's Sega satan Shiro.
Speaker 1: the side I linked to said Sega satan sashiro.
Speaker 1: Maybe they say it different ways in different parts of the song and the Google video link spells it differently from the image.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, actually long sounds like Sega satan Shiro, you know, so I don't know.
Speaker 1: it's it's different everywhere.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I don't care either.
Speaker 0: But all you have to know is it's Sega Saturn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'll find it.
Speaker 0: Yes my thing today It keeping you with my Smash Brothers theme.
Speaker 0: I feel really bad for doing two video games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mr Hey and the same video game.
Speaker 0: there's been a significant drought of things of the day lately on anime day but it's a video of Smash Brothers that shows jigglypuff getting smashed against the screen and And What appears to be a penis?
Speaker 1: Thank You Scott.
Speaker 0: Who can resist the the hot coffee of Smash Brothers?
Speaker 0: The the penis on the jigglypuff?
Speaker 1: P. Yes.
Speaker 1: Hey, yes Alright just in case no one Listen to that episode from a while back.
Speaker 1: There is a minor 12 year old ish Easter egg in Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: Now there's a character named Pichu.
Speaker 1: there's a character named Ness.
Speaker 1: When you click on a character to select him the game says his name.
Speaker 1: Therefore if you and a friend select Pichu and Ness with the proper timing.
Speaker 1: Well, try it yourself and see what happens.
Speaker 0: Pichu Ness Alright, so this weekend we went to yet another convention and you know what we're going this weekend to The Museum of comic and cartoon art.
Speaker 0: on Saturday There's some sort of art exhibition and the weekend after that is anime next and then I think we're probably gonna go to Kinetic Con Yeah, which is July the second weekend in July.
Speaker 1: We're going to that other comic convention over the 4th of July weekend.
Speaker 0: Possibly are we really possibly very tiny convention in Wildwood, I think it counts.
Speaker 1: All right to continue our string of con going and Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, it's convention season.
Speaker 1: What can I say?
Speaker 0: and last weekend?
Speaker 0: We went to for a few hours and Saturday wizard world, Philadelphia.
Speaker 1: Now this is unique in the cons we go to in that it is a comic convention as opposed to an anime or gaming Convention.
Speaker 0: is this the first I've been to comic conventions before?
Speaker 0: but mostly the small kind like in a mall Never this big before.
Speaker 1: this is like a real comic convention All right.
Speaker 0: Shall we talk about the events in chronological order?
Speaker 1: Alright, so it was pouring rain and it sucked driving there.
Speaker 0: it sure sucked driving there.
Speaker 1: In fact, it had rained continuously from when we left our house until we got to Philly And then the next morning when we drove to the con it was still raining.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't have too much time finding the place or driving around Philly was a lot more pleasant than driving around say, New York Yeah, or Chicago.
Speaker 0: It was like driving around Albany, but with roads a little bit more crowded.
Speaker 1: I caused an accident the last time I drove in Chicago.
Speaker 0: Oh, I've never driven in Chicago You know what?
Speaker 1: It really sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we found parking pretty easily But since it was raining we we did have to walk through some water to get to the con.
Speaker 0: But it was good that we waited for the line to get a bit shorter before he went over there.
Speaker 0: We sat in the car for maybe 10 minutes, you know playing DS and whatnot.
Speaker 0: And when we got over there the line only took about 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: then we paid what 25 bucks for a one-day pass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would like to note right now that I want my 25 bucks back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay 25 bucks for a con isn't a really bad deal except when the con You know doesn't provide the Oda cons.
Speaker 0: what 50 bucks?
Speaker 1: I think they raised it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there was a time when it was 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: All right, Oda cons about 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna bother to look it might even be 40 for all.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: That means this con would have to be half as good as Oda con not even close for one day.
Speaker 1: Keep in mind Yeah, one day one day.
Speaker 0: so Already the entry price is a rip.
Speaker 0: I say ten bucks would have been fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, more like five, you know, we didn't go in any official capacity So we didn't get in free like her kind of used to.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, now they gave us these to register into the con one.
Speaker 1: their badges were totally counterfeitable.
Speaker 0: Okay, not only the badges were counterfeitable But I'd like to point out when you go to an anime con or a lot every con I've been to you get to either they print your name on the badge or you put your name on the badge.
Speaker 0: these badges were just Stock.
Speaker 1: you got a barcode.
Speaker 1: Yeah didn't do anything because they didn't scan it or look at it or anything.
Speaker 1: They just stuck it in there.
Speaker 0: Yep, and seemed like everyone.
Speaker 0: no one really had customized badges except maybe guests and such.
Speaker 1: now They gave us a survey to fill out while we were in line.
Speaker 1: That was also a registration form.
Speaker 1: Now aside from the fact that it asked a lot of personal questions I really didn't feel comfortable answering to a freaking comic convention.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it had a wonderful bit where at one section and I did a little checkbox area You know a square and next to it.
Speaker 1: It said yes, please sign me up for Affiliated blah blah blah blah blah blah blah, please send me newsletters from the convention.
Speaker 0: people wizard because it's a wizard world convention.
Speaker 0: So it said yes wizard Please send me all your newsletters to my email address.
Speaker 1: now the yes was already checked off when we got it and there was no Option.
Speaker 0: so basically what it meant was if you enter your email address, you're going to get newsletters.
Speaker 0: So obviously we didn't enter our email addresses and sadly no one cared because he really wanted to fight with them on that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because they also wanted like my home address and phone number and all this information.
Speaker 1: that really wasn't cool.
Speaker 1: They want to know how much money we make.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean a survey is fine and I answered some of the questions But I left a lot out that I wasn't gonna tell them that they shouldn't ask.
Speaker 1: There was one funny question where it asked how many people did you tell you were going to Philly wizard world?
Speaker 1: And we were like hundreds and hundreds lots.
Speaker 0: The options were like one two, three, four five six other other a lot seven plus All right, so we got our badges.
Speaker 0: you went in the con.
Speaker 0: the con Was one big room.
Speaker 1: Well, there were other rooms outside.
Speaker 1: That's true panels, but The most of the con was just one big room.
Speaker 0: None of the panels are really interesting to us and some of the panels Required tickets that you had to pay for if you wanted to see Kevin Smith.
Speaker 0: You would have had to buy a ticket on Friday separate from your con ticket.
Speaker 1: now I don't like that.
Speaker 1: at least at anime cons The policy is if you pay for a con you get everything that con has to offer for no more money.
Speaker 1: Your admission is it?
Speaker 1: Gaming cons Go halfway and all the old-style gaming con seems to be dying but old-style gaming cons You would pay some pittance to get in and then you paid four or five dollars for every game you wanted to participate in.
Speaker 1: New gaming cons tend to just pay, you know, you pay like an anime con.
Speaker 0: I think what it is is that at an anime con?
Speaker 0: pretty much everyone there that you want to see and the panels you want to go to are Guests of the con which means the con Itself got those people to come and thus your membership fee pays for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of the things at the con were guests so you didn't pay for those panels separately.
Speaker 0: However, I think that certain people who are charging for autographs or people charging to go to panels Those aren't con guests.
Speaker 0: Those are con exhibitors holding events and charging them for them separately.
Speaker 0: So that's why that happens now.
Speaker 1: That's one thing I really want to talk about.
Speaker 1: that at any con I've ever been to if there's a guest and they're signing autographs They just sign autographs.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a line Maybe there's a limit but they just sign autographs and hang out and I think the people who are guests of the con were doing That.
Speaker 1: but there were so many people here who were charging money for autographs and those people are here with some autograph company.
Speaker 0: Yeah But still, you know the fact that you're coming there with an autograph company to sign autographs and you're not a con guest.
Speaker 0: It's like what the heck, you know, you're just.
Speaker 1: it's like it's all just a big scheme to get money out of us.
Speaker 1: gert gerts I was gonna say nerd and geek and it all kind of went together.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, don't start a new word I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've noticed people said in the forums but for all of you overseas listeners here in the u.s Nerd and geek seem to mean the opposite or have the opposite connotations that they do.
Speaker 0: It seems like different people have Decided.
Speaker 0: they mean different things.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Nerd is bad and geek is good At least where we live.
Speaker 1: geek is like what we are and nerd is like the comic book guy.
Speaker 1: Yep, worst word ever.
Speaker 0: a guy at a sci-fi convention dressed as a Star Trek dude is a nerd.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends.
Speaker 1: he could be a cool guy.
Speaker 1: He's also talking about the relative merits of Star Trek technology versus Star Wars technology And he doesn't shut up when you're given the body language of dude, please go away.
Speaker 1: The stench is overpowering me.
Speaker 1: That is a nerd.
Speaker 1: That is correct, that's what that is.
Speaker 0: Okay, so we got in the con now used to anime conventions which take up entire hotels or entire convention center our entire cities.
Speaker 0: this one had panel rooms out in the hallway, which are actually pretty good and The con itself was one giant room I'd say Equal in size to the Otacon dealers room, but with a slightly higher ceiling
Speaker 1: Yep, but also it only held is I think four or five thousand people.
Speaker 1: was the fire capacity of that room was it?
Speaker 0: Because I ran by the sign and I saw it there I didn't look that you sure that wasn't for just half because it looked like they combined two rooms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it looked like that was for the whole exhibit hall.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: Anyway, one half of the entire exhibit hall was dealers.
Speaker 0: Now the dealer half was split into yet again two halves.
Speaker 0: half of it was actual con dealers and half of it was the Publishers who had dealing booths which weren't used exclusively for dealing.
Speaker 0: So like the Marvel in the DC booth and such we're down in the publisher area Next to the spike TV booth and the guys from comic book stores selling comic books were in the other half.
Speaker 0: now the other half of the Convention Center was artists alley a gaming area and A food area.
Speaker 1: Well, there's also the autograph area which was cordoned off.
Speaker 1: Well, the autograph area was just this row of Little desks with people sitting at them giving autographs and then in front of those very long scary-looking lines Yep, where no one in those lines would interview with me, but I'll talk about that later.
Speaker 0: All right So we started just by walking around, you know scoping out the lid of the land and then we made our way through artists alley Yep.
Speaker 1: Now it was very different from an anime con artists alley.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it was people literally hawking their wares and I just I don't want to say that they were desperate But a lot of people were really trying to oversell themselves or wouldn't let me just walk by?
Speaker 0: Yeah that I agree.
Speaker 0: it seems like independent comic makers are You know?
Speaker 0: because in an anime convention The artists alley is gonna have just some people making cute fan art or some people with a webcomic and they're usually just hanging out.
Speaker 0: Yeah This artists alley most of the people there were people who were artists and writers mostly artists of independent comic books which means they're trying to make their living or a portion of their living or They already spent a bunch of money in printing comic books that they need to sell to make a profit.
Speaker 0: so they were really desperate to get your attention and Not so skilled at doing it in a way that wasn't off-putting.
Speaker 1: after about three times I just stopped being polite which is very difficult for me to do and I just started brushing them off because they wouldn't leave me Alone, I'd want to look through their sketchbook and they just wouldn't stop bothering me.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're gonna buy a comic.
Speaker 1: Oh if you buy this, I'll give you this for free.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like I go over to a guy's stuff, you know, cuz maybe I saw a cute drawing.
Speaker 0: I'd go look at it and he'd be like, oh hey You wanna you wanna this here?
Speaker 0: take some of this.
Speaker 0: Oh you want this is only one and I'm like All right, dude.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't everyone though.
Speaker 0: Some of the guys are just you know, cool The thing was some of the people were extra quiet and wouldn't be sociable.
Speaker 0: Like I'd be like, hey and they'd be like, oh, hey Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: it was two extremes.
Speaker 0: There wasn't anyone.
Speaker 0: there are very few people who were normally sociable in the artists alley.
Speaker 0: There were a couple.
Speaker 0: I ran in but the most were not.
Speaker 1: I would say there were three groups of people that were Normally sociable that I ran into.
Speaker 1: one was at the studio and I interviewed him But the interview didn't come out so well cuz a lot of noise around.
Speaker 1: the second one His comic is sitting right in front of me.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about him in a minute.
Speaker 1: and the third one was the comic geek speak people who seemed kind of cool.
Speaker 1: yeah,
Speaker 0: the comic geek speak people, you know, I listen to their podcast which is pretty cool and It's weird that when you met them in person because I already I already knew who they work as they put their pictures online And their logo is actually little characters of themselves so you can figure out who's who and all that.
Speaker 0: But the people who you know, like the cool comics in their group were less sociable than the people who are Ultra super trivia nerdy.
Speaker 0: It was kind of backwards which I think is part of what makes their podcast so good.
Speaker 1: Now the second guy I talked about.
Speaker 1: he was sitting there dressed Exactly the way the character in his comic looks.
Speaker 0: I think he said he was the character from his comic.
Speaker 0: He didn't give his real name.
Speaker 1: No, he didn't and I was looking at the comic and I don't see his real name anywhere prominent.
Speaker 0: I think he wrote a comic about himself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least his alter ego, which is common in comic books.
Speaker 1: Now he really had the art of the sail mastered.
Speaker 1: He's sitting there and I walk over and I see what his comic is and I hold out my little microphone.
Speaker 1: I'm like, can I interview you?
Speaker 1: and he stopped?
Speaker 1: He doesn't say a word.
Speaker 1: he stands up and he puts on his coat and Then in full character, give me the following About a hero acts and dresses like a pimp.
Speaker 0: You got a website or anything.
Speaker 0: we can find our listeners that definitely it's called Black bastard.
Speaker 0: calm don't forget baby Black bastard.
Speaker 1: he stayed in character.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell the whole con Yep, it's pretty much the best cosplay there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it was of a character.
Speaker 0: He created that's like if Who can I think of?
Speaker 0: the utenna guy came to the con Dressed as toga.
Speaker 1: All right, that would be really scared.
Speaker 0: It would be really scary and just stood in an artist alley booth Selling you tenor DVDs and playing toga in character acting as if he was toga and he didn't eco her.
Speaker 0: Who's that now?
Speaker 1: Not only was this guy awesome, but he didn't bother me because I was looking.
Speaker 1: I was like, I'm gonna come back and buy a comic or I'll be back later and Every other freaking artist.
Speaker 1: if I said I'll come back around or I don't buy anything in my first pass They obviously thought I was lying and they tried to like.
Speaker 1: they tried to bother me more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz rim really doesn't buy anything on the first pass.
Speaker 0: He hates carrying shit around the con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he'll go and figure out everything he's gonna buy.
Speaker 0: then at the last minute He'll run around throwing money at everyone and then leave anime cons.
Speaker 1: that works here.
Speaker 1: No one believe me They're all bastards.
Speaker 1: So I actually didn't go back cuz I was kind of pissed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're a bastard even if a comic looks, okay We're not gonna go for it unless you're a black bastard.
Speaker 1: cuz that guy was like, hey, that's cool.
Speaker 1: And then I came back.
Speaker 1: he's like.
Speaker 1: I knew you'd be back and I gave my three dollars and I got my signed copy of black bastard number one Black bastard.
Speaker 0: we gotta read that comics.
Speaker 1: I'll review it next week.
Speaker 0: All right I got some other.
Speaker 0: I can read some other comics to review next week - all right We'll have a little comic week for once.
Speaker 1: Now at this point the two Scots because we went with our good friend Scott Johnson who is the master of finding deals at conventions.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: He likes.
Speaker 1: I like crap.
Speaker 0: That's why he doesn't have to spend a lot of money.
Speaker 1: The back story there is that we were winding down We were about to leave for the beach and I ran up behind him and cornered him and started just interviewing him even though we're friends with a little recording bit.
Speaker 1: and he said that in the middle of talking about how he gets all the good deals and Then he said ah crap now you're gonna play that on your show like every day for the next 20 years and you know That's right.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: I Like crap No, but basically after I we had perused artists alley The only thing left for us to do at the con since he weren't interested in any of the panels That were at least none of the ones that were running while we were there Was to walk around the dealers room and make sure there wasn't anything insanely cheap and worth buying.
Speaker 1: now The two Scots did that while I went off for other erstwhile pursuits.
Speaker 1: So I like doing in such Yeah, so I'll let him talk about his dealing experience first.
Speaker 0: Well, it seems to me like most of the people running around buying stuff were They had a list of comics that they wanted because they were collectors and they were looking, you know they had the list that they in their hand and they would look through bins for anything on that list and pull it out and Make a pile and then once they had a pile big enough from one dealer They would pay for it and go to the next dealer trying to fill up their whole list Starting with the cheapest stuff and going to the expensive stuff.
Speaker 1: I saw dudes walking around with like a couple hundred comics in a big old sack.
Speaker 0: Yep Of course, there was a lack of bags.
Speaker 0: Someone should have called up bandai who always has the good Otacon bags.
Speaker 0: I mean they had Sony bags, but they disappeared right away and They weren't even really that big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've still got my bandai bag.
Speaker 1: That thing is really high quality Yeah, and the con bag was really crappy and mine broke.
Speaker 0: Yeah Someone needs some some better bags like the nice vis bags.
Speaker 0: vis always has awesome bags With the canvas and everything.
Speaker 0: I have two vis bags.
Speaker 0: anyway, I Was looking for one comic.
Speaker 1: what that?
Speaker 1: spider-man 2099?
Speaker 0: spider-man 2099 number 36 but I bought that.
Speaker 0: I bought spider-man 2099 when I was a kid and I got one through 34 or 35 something like that.
Speaker 0: and that yeah one through 35 I got when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: then Recently because I started buying comics again I found an eBay auction and I acquired 37 through the end.
Speaker 0: that leaves out number 36.
Speaker 1: Apparently it's impossible to find on eBay.
Speaker 0: It's five bucks.
Speaker 0: I could get it for like a lot of money But it's not worth paying because if I found it at a con it would cost me 25 cents or 10 cents or 10 cents, which I'll talk about too.
Speaker 0: So the good part of the con there are three things I was looking at 25 cent comic books.
Speaker 0: 50 cent comic books Occasionally $1 comic books, but only you know super rarely and Half off trades.
Speaker 0: half off trades are awesome.
Speaker 0: That's what Scott Johnson loaded up.
Speaker 0: He bought a pile ant-man Essential ant-man 50% off.
Speaker 1: as he buys it Now funnily enough ant-man came up in conversation like 15 times that weekend.
Speaker 0: He just because he read the ant-man was the first comic he read.
Speaker 0: You know what are when he had read a different comic in the car when that would have come up.
Speaker 1: when all you Have is a trade of ant-man Every problem looks like an ant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing was is that You know there weren't for all the the fact that the only thing for me to do with the con was look at cheap-ass comics.
Speaker 0: only maybe Five or six of the dealers had cheap-ass comics.
Speaker 1: Most of them had a million expensive Silver Age comics like on a wall.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most like there were three or four dealers Exclusively selling old expensive comics Which I wanted nothing to do with because they're terrible and only really collectors care about them because reading them is painful.
Speaker 0: And if you there are good ones to read they've been reprinted in trade paperback since and I can go get them for half off.
Speaker 0: Also, there were guys selling scary collector stuff like comics sealed in hard plastic things with like Grade numbers on them telling you how mint they are.
Speaker 1: there was that auction service that was selling collectible auction services.
Speaker 1: Wow, there was those.
Speaker 1: there were the group of people selling a collectible comic insurance.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So if you have a large comic collection They would sell you insurance in case your comic collection was destroyed in a flood or something.
Speaker 1: I didn't really talk to them.
Speaker 1: But based on what I saw in my brief watching of them talk to people I'm pretty sure it was some sort of scam or they.
Speaker 0: it was such a scam.
Speaker 0: These people didn't even look like comic people.
Speaker 0: They were two insurance salesman ladies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were People selling t-shirts nerdy t-shirts.
Speaker 0: That was cool.
Speaker 0: One guy had every nerdy t-shirt in existence.
Speaker 0: I wasn't about to buy anything from him because he was hideously overpriced.
Speaker 0: how much worse.
Speaker 0: hoodies.
Speaker 1: Oh God, they were $45 $45 hoodie.
Speaker 0: forget it, but he did have a lot of wide selections.
Speaker 1: However, you can get all that stuff at an anime con or you know on the internet internet Yeah for much cheaper.
Speaker 0: and there was plenty of guys selling overpriced toys.
Speaker 0: However, there were some gems such as the bin of $5 GI Joe's.
Speaker 0: That was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah The guy basically had old GI Joe toys with all the accessories and little plastic bags and you could root through the bin Pick out any plastic bag you wanted and it was a set price of a few bucks.
Speaker 1: One guy had in the middle of all this crack He had like this pile of crap laying somewhere and one item was the awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna die.
Speaker 1: Oh box set awesome.
Speaker 1: And I was like, how much is this?
Speaker 1: and he didn't know like.
Speaker 1: he was like, ah, there was no price on it.
Speaker 1: So I offered him 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: He said no and then I walked away.
Speaker 0: Yeah Wow 40 bucks He get for less than that online 30.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably 30 is a good price for that.
Speaker 0: That's that's about the right price I'd say at least for the box of the little DVDs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the little DVD, but yeah the new.
Speaker 0: yeah That's a $30 box set right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he wouldn't give it to me for 40s to screw that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all the good stuff to be found at this con were in the boxes under the tables.
Speaker 0: you get on your hands and knees And you dig through boxes and you dig through messes to find shit.
Speaker 0: The thing is I'm running out of patience.
Speaker 0: I went over and there were plenty of guys at 25 cent bins and plenty of people looking through them.
Speaker 0: Some people had their 25 cent bins in alphabetical order.
Speaker 0: for those I could just go straight to the parts I cared about and the rest whatever.
Speaker 0: Some of the guys had things completely unsorted, you know, what I looked through Cursor early, but it wasn't worth my time to look through every single goddamn comic in there.
Speaker 0: the comic I wanted might have been in there.
Speaker 0: It wasn't worth my time.
Speaker 0: I could have made more money working a minimum wage job than spending an hour to buy a 25 cent comic.
Speaker 0: But yeah other than that the dealing and the artists Ally and talking to a couple people There was nothing else to do.
Speaker 1: So we went to the beach Yep, and the beach was much more enjoyable.
Speaker 1: Yeah I can safely say that I am never returning to any comic convention that cost money to get into.
Speaker 0: Yeah the way I see it is that if a comic an anime convention or gaming convention is a big party with lots of Activities that will occupy you throughout a weekend.
Speaker 0: And so you want to go to those no matter what they cost.
Speaker 0: And as long as you know, well not no matter what they cost as long as the cost is proportional to the party.
Speaker 1: Well considering that I would pay about a hundred and fifty dollars just off the top of my head go to Otacon I think that's a good deal.
Speaker 0: Yep, a comic-con at least one like this seems to be less of a party and more of a temporary ultra giant comic book store.
Speaker 0: which means if you're gonna pay the entry fee and you're not interested in a lot of the panels like us because well, most of the panels are Regardless of whether we found them interesting or not.
Speaker 0: They were genuinely Uninteresting industry panels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or they don't go to those types of panels at anime con Or they cost a lot of extra money and you had to stand in line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure going to see Kevin Smith would have been interesting But you know what?
Speaker 0: It wasn't worth spending an entire weekend of rushing around Philadelphia at the crack-ass of dawn getting in lines paying extra money for tickets.
Speaker 0: It's just not worth it.
Speaker 0: If it was just walk in and see Kevin Smith.
Speaker 0: I would have been like, yeah, sure fine cool.
Speaker 0: He'd probably entertain me for a good hour or so Yeah, but it wasn't worth the effort required.
Speaker 0: only super nerds would go to that effort.
Speaker 0: So let them have their fun be my guest now.
Speaker 1: while the two Scots were doing all this I was doing what I do at every convention I go to.
Speaker 1: I was walking around trying to interview people about their con experience and something happened that has never happened to me before.
Speaker 1: and The more I tried to talk to people and interview people the more I realized that I was in a strange and foreign land.
Speaker 1: Now for the first thing the first person I asked like hey you want to be interviewed for a blah blah blah podcast Which yeah the same shtick I do at every time I interview someone and the guy backed off and he's like, uh and he seemed really surprised that I talked to him like he wasn't sure I was talking to him and Then he got really uncomfortable and told me no, he didn't want to talk to me.
Speaker 1: All right I figured I just picked some fanboy.
Speaker 1: the next three people I tried to interview reacted in almost the same way.
Speaker 1: Everyone refused an interview like they didn't want to have anything to do with me They didn't want to talk to me.
Speaker 1: They wanted me to leave them alone so they could continue about whatever business they had.
Speaker 1: hmm, I finally found two cool guys who look like they're having a good time and I interviewed them and I'll play a little segment from that at the end of this because it's not really relevant now.
Speaker 1: But I just asked him, you know why they're here.
Speaker 1: They really like Silver Age comics.
Speaker 1: They don't like anime They don't like video games.
Speaker 1: They only like Silver Age comics.
Speaker 0: Well one day there are only so many Silver Age comics, aren't you gonna run out of those one day?
Speaker 1: You know, I didn't think to ask him that I wish I would have.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean it's like I only like beer from 1970 through 1975.
Speaker 0: Well, eventually it's gonna all get drunk, isn't it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, then you'll have nothing left to like.
Speaker 1: kill yourself.
Speaker 0: It's like I. my only hobby is collecting model trains made in the 80s.
Speaker 0: There are only so many model trains made in the 80s.
Speaker 0: Eventually you'll have them all.
Speaker 1: Now some people would interview with me But either they didn't want me to record it like they were afraid of my little microphone.
Speaker 1: So I got to talk to him a little bit and they all basically said the same thing that these Comic guys I actually did interview said, you know Oh, I'm here for the deals.
Speaker 1: or oh I can get comics for cheap.
Speaker 1: or oh I can see the famous people I like and get him to sign my blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Those are really the only answers people gave me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as far as signing things goes I'm really kind of indifferent.
Speaker 0: the guy who made who writes and draws Mouse Guard was there which is awesome.
Speaker 1: He's which.
Speaker 0: Mouse Guard is an awesome freaking comic.
Speaker 0: If you don't know go to this comic store near you and buy Mouse Guard.
Speaker 0: It doesn't look.
Speaker 0: it's not the same size and shape as a normal comic But it's worth every penny if you like.
Speaker 0: I don't know red wall or anything involving funny because I don't like red wall anything involving anthropomorphic animals living out cool things or any sort of medieval questing intrigue stories.
Speaker 1: The fact that they are mice is irrelevant to the story, but it's directly relevant to the atmosphere.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 1: It's just really cool.
Speaker 0: We'll review it where the enemy because the enemies aren't dragons like they are in a human story.
Speaker 0: They're snakes and crabs Yeah, and other mice, of course.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the guy was there who I didn't expect and I was like, whoa, dude, you're awesome.
Speaker 0: And then I bought his.
Speaker 0: you know, I already had number one at home.
Speaker 0: So I bought two and three which are the only ones out so far.
Speaker 0: I asked him if there was gonna be a trade and he said yes.
Speaker 0: So all of you who like to save money just wait around for the mouse guard trade to come out and get all over that.
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna be a bunch of separate miniseries.
Speaker 0: So there might be a trade for each miniseries.
Speaker 0: so I'll probably just finish off the first miniseries and get the trades for the rest of them, but You know, I bought two and three off of them, you know, and I was complimenting how awesome he was and everything.
Speaker 0: He seemed like he wasn't talking so much But I found out later if when the CGS guys interviewed him for real that is because he lost his voice from talking so much.
Speaker 1: All right, that's cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, then he's like signing the issues and I'm like I don't really care if you sign it or not.
Speaker 0: I just want to read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but other comic nerds are like Oh, holy collectible increasing value.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they stood in line for like 45 minutes to get someone to sign something and to pay for the Privilege of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, the guy who does black bastard.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna assume his name is black bastard.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that's what he would like you to call him.
Speaker 1: He just signed it without even saying a word other than oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Now Finally, I ran into some people who were cool and they were excited to interview with me and one of them was dressed up as a Jedi and Then later later another one walked up and she was dressed as Sailor V from Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: Now you might wonder transformation noise, but I can't.
Speaker 1: you might wonder why.
Speaker 1: you know, someone would be dressed up as an anime character and It turns out that these people are anime con fans and they'd never been to a comic convention before.
Speaker 1: and this is their first one.
Speaker 1: and well Why do you guys go to conventions?
Speaker 1: Like what is the appeal?
Speaker 1: Mostly to dress up and be a celebrity and have everybody want to take their picture with you outstanding.
Speaker 1: If you stand still long enough some guy will come up and ask to interview you for a radio show.
Speaker 1: And while I'm here it appears that Sailor V has arrived.
Speaker 1: I have seen all 200 episodes of Sailor Moon including Amichandarotsukor So you're obviously anime fan.
Speaker 1: in addition to So what anime con do you go to?
Speaker 1: What conventions in general do you go to every year?
Speaker 0: I go to Otakon and Kasakon every year and sometimes Anime USA All right.
Speaker 1: So here's a nice broad-based question real broad you cosplay?
Speaker 1: obviously.
Speaker 1: Why very very open-ended?
Speaker 1: Why do you cosplay?
Speaker 1: I love sewing and I really like attention.
Speaker 1: All right, there's another broad question.
Speaker 1: obviously this is a comic convention which is often very different from an anime convention.
Speaker 1: Do you like one more than the other?
Speaker 1: like?
Speaker 1: what's the difference between the two?
Speaker 0: Actually my first comic convention ever.
Speaker 0: so I'm still forming my opinion.
Speaker 1: I Dragged her to it.
Speaker 1: That would be my boyfriend.
Speaker 1: Um, it's a lot less people cosplay here.
Speaker 1: It's very interesting.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of still getting used to it Now after I turn the mic off.
Speaker 1: they talked a little bit more and their basic impression of comic conventions Is that everyone's kind of scary and they're kind of boring and there's nothing to do and no one cosplays.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do think that the general comic-con atmosphere is one of Isolation, I mean it comes down to a few things.
Speaker 0: I talked already about how the name tags.
Speaker 0: You don't even put your name on them.
Speaker 0: So they're not expecting you to be social - there really aren't any group activities at the con other than the small gaming area Everything to do.
Speaker 1: there is an individual thing and the gaming area wasn't just free gaming like go set up a game and play it Or here's some games to play.
Speaker 1: It was definitely a. we're plugging this set of games.
Speaker 1: Come here and play them with us.
Speaker 0: It was watsy Lots.
Speaker 0: he was all over it, you know, you know an anime concept.
Speaker 0: plenty of solitary things to do But they also have plenty of group things to do, you know.
Speaker 0: cosplay is a group activity.
Speaker 0: There's always role-playing at an anime con.
Speaker 0: That's a group activity.
Speaker 0: You know There's all sorts of group things going down at anime cons and there just weren't any group things at the comic-con whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Also, I'd like to point out is that anime is a group activity.
Speaker 0: You sit together with people and enjoy Watching animated shows in a group.
Speaker 0: You don't do it all alone.
Speaker 0: Well, some people do it all in your room, but it's mostly you do it together.
Speaker 0: Reading comics is a personal thing.
Speaker 0: You sit down alone.
Speaker 0: You comic-booking you.
Speaker 0: you don't sit around with a group of people reading comics.
Speaker 1: now you I mean you can but it's not the same like if you're watching an anime with ten people, you know, like that host mojo and Something crazy happens.
Speaker 1: Everyone goes who yells and screams and laughs.
Speaker 1: That's a group thing.
Speaker 1: If you're all reading comics together, you're not going to all have the same experience together and yell and scream together.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think it's it's not just.
Speaker 0: I think that the resulting attitudes of the people in the particular geekeries are Mostly a result of the nature of the geekeries themselves and it's not something people think about a lot.
Speaker 1: Also that just the it's probably related but just the culture.
Speaker 1: it seems that anime and gaming conventions are wider nets.
Speaker 1: I mean everyone who goes to an anime con for the most part likes anime.
Speaker 1: Everyone who goes to a gaming con for the most part likes gaming and everyone goes to a comic-con for the most part likes comics.
Speaker 1: Most of the people who went to the comic-con Didn't like anime or just didn't watch anime or had no interest in anime or gaming for that matter.
Speaker 1: But most of the people who went to the gaming con like anime and most of the people went to the anime cons like gaming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or at least there's a lot more Crossover at the gaming and anime cons into other geekeries.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the crossover doesn't exist like a gaming con.
Speaker 0: there is significant sci-fi and fantasy novel type stuff.
Speaker 0: crossover in anime.
Speaker 0: video gaming heavy crossover ring at a board gaming con and Anime is slightly less crossover ring, but still plenty.
Speaker 1: Yeah But it's like the Venn diagram.
Speaker 1: of all the geekeries comics are really kind of mostly not overlapping with anything.
Speaker 0: Scott's Hypothesis for why this is so is that while all geekeries are expensive, you know board games are cheap.
Speaker 1: Hypothesis.
Speaker 0: if you it's a good hypothesis.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to say that anime is not a cheap hobby But comics with their collector mentality.
Speaker 0: I by far the most expensive men Geekery there is.
Speaker 0: yet if you're a comic nerd you're spending money Every single week on Wednesday when new comics come out anime fans buy DVD now and then board game guys Buy a bunch of games every few months.
Speaker 0: comic guys are consistently spending money and time week after week on their geekery thus to the exclusion of other geekeries and That is why there is less crossover with the comic geeks.
Speaker 1: That's why Scott thinks there is less crossover with the comic geeks now very relevant to this in the spirit of anime world order Which I'm more and more a fan of ever since I met them way back at Katsu khan.
Speaker 1: I Did my own search for the truth?
Speaker 1: Oh, I Tried to find out the truth behind the difference in anime convention goers Versus comic convention goers and I went around an amazement way back and I didn't.
Speaker 1: I got all these interviews.
Speaker 1: I asked people one simple question Why do you go to conventions?
Speaker 1: What is the appeal?
Speaker 1: What is the draw?
Speaker 1: Why are you here now?
Speaker 1: Here's what they answered.
Speaker 1: Let's see all the cosplayers mostly And I love everyone such a door to be with my people All the above Hot guys in costumes and I fit in All the above.
Speaker 1: It's a gathering of geeks.
Speaker 1: It's where we all come and we're with our own kind.
Speaker 1: It's like salmon go upstream Geeks come to cons And there's other geeks and the geekness, you know, reaches some new levels Now very typical very broad-based.
Speaker 1: They seem very Very thoughtful answers.
Speaker 1: They seem like they really enjoy what they do.
Speaker 1: They have a lot of very well other than hot guys.
Speaker 1: They have many varied reasons for being there hot guys.
Speaker 1: It's definitely a social thing.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Consider this.
Speaker 1: this was recorded at Philly wizard world.
Speaker 1: This is the only interview I got with someone that was intelligible Because almost everyone who actually would interview with me was shy or a low talker or mumbled or something and the interview is just worthless.
Speaker 1: This is a real broad question.
Speaker 1: But why do you go to these conventions?
Speaker 0: What's the appeal?
Speaker 0: What's the draw?
Speaker 0: The joys?
Speaker 0: you can get books cheaper and what you can do are if you buy them at the stand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, big dealers room.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I think my final assessment is that if Scott were to go to comic cons in the future.
Speaker 0: They would have to either be a Scott is a guest and thus it's everything's free.
Speaker 0: and why not go be Everything's?
Speaker 0: it doesn't cost anything to get in and I'm not I don't have to travel out of my way to get there.
Speaker 0: And thus why not go?
Speaker 0: and you know, maybe there's a chance of finding a good deal.
Speaker 0: Or see it's some point a couple years from now.
Speaker 0: I'm going well.
Speaker 0: starting now I'm going to start making a list of any old comic I want that I can't get or that should be in a 25-cent bin and if that list ever gets super long perhaps a couple years from now I will go to a car.
Speaker 0: I got an idea and get all the time.
Speaker 1: we could either provide this as a service and make money or Find people to do it.
Speaker 1: for us.
Speaker 1: have people who will stand outside comic conventions.
Speaker 1: You give them a list of all the things you want.
Speaker 1: Once they have a bunch of lists they go in search the bargain bins buy it all bring it back for a small markup.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's already a 25 cent bin.
Speaker 0: any kind of markup?
Speaker 1: Well, the markup is you pay him five bucks for all of their time.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: That's what it.
Speaker 0: you know, it's how long I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: you hire the fanboys.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be in there anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah I think wouldn't be.
Speaker 0: a much better idea is if all the dealers sorted their shit.
Speaker 0: You could just give the dealer a list.
Speaker 0: that would.
Speaker 0: that would have been nice because the main problem I had was in The big bins full of comics.
Speaker 0: I had to look through them manually.
Speaker 0: I would have much rather given the guy a list of what I wanted.
Speaker 0: He would have gone through his bins and he knows everything is in his bins Collected it all for me and then give it to me in charge.
Speaker 1: now I'm not.
Speaker 1: I don't want to sound like a conspiracy theorist But I have a sneaking feeling that some of that is intentional.
Speaker 1: if you force them to look through they might see other stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, get up something might enter their eyes is 25 cents, you know and stuff did catch my eye when I was looking for spider-man I got speedball.
Speaker 0: That's just for hilarity sake.
Speaker 1: but then again I mean, we're pretty discerning because actually while we were at the shore the bookstore on the boardwalk We're selling all of their old manga which was mostly some pretty bad stuff 25 cent.
Speaker 0: they were selling the comics.
Speaker 0: one manga and now comics one.
Speaker 0: It's not manga.
Speaker 0: It's mostly Chinese stuff.
Speaker 0: and Comics one was a company that brought over a bunch of pretty good Chinese comics.
Speaker 1: Well, they also had like first president Japan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, no, that was the Raijin.
Speaker 0: I think yeah, but I don't think that was comics one.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I'm just saying that they also had the bookstore.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's correct.
Speaker 1: Now they were all 25 cents each and there was a pile of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, ma.
Speaker 0: We're not talking comics for 25 cents Trait, you know Digest mangas for 25 cents.
Speaker 1: I only bought like four.
Speaker 1: they weren't even worth a quarter to me.
Speaker 0: I bought zero.
Speaker 0: now I would if there were certain things there.
Speaker 0: I would have paid the quarter without a second thought.
Speaker 0: like Comics one put out this great series Kazan and they put out a couple other great series, but I think one called one.
Speaker 0: I'm not I don't remember but I would recognize it if I saw it and they didn't have those.
Speaker 0: if they would have I would Have scooped him up instead.
Speaker 0: They had basically complete crap that I wouldn't want to read it all.
Speaker 0: so I didn't buy it Not even for 25 cents.
Speaker 0: Now one good one thing about the comic-con was you were not there on Sunday.
Speaker 0: on Sunday One of the dealers changed his 25 cent bins into 10 cent.
Speaker 0: Whoa now If I had been there when there were 10 cent bins I would have loaded up on stuff that I even had the slightest interest in.
Speaker 0: because well $0.10 for comic book.
Speaker 0: man.
Speaker 1: now, we're resistant.
Speaker 1: However, I have a feeling that the comic types who would buy the 10 cent comic Then decide that they have to read the rest of it and then the cycle continues.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well like for example, I went in and I saw Doom 2099 and now that's a comic.
Speaker 0: that's kind of normal ish, you know I mean, I read spider-man 2099 when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: So doom 2099 kind of goes with that and you know It's pretty cool-looking and all that.
Speaker 0: and I found in a bin number one, two, three four.
Speaker 0: So I kept going and going and then eventually it was like 12 24 36.
Speaker 0: I don't think those are the exact numbers, but I was like, oh Well screw that I didn't buy any of it.
Speaker 0: You know a comic guy would have gotten all of them and then gone elsewhere to try and fill in all the holes.
Speaker 0: I'm saying if you don't got it all I ain't getting any of it.
Speaker 1: I like how you went in twelves.
Speaker 1: Yep, I just I found that interesting.
Speaker 0: Well year by year.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know because comics come out whatever It's just what came to mind.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that was our experience at Philly Wizard World.
Speaker 1: I was very underwhelmed.
Speaker 1: It was really weird to have people not want to be interviewed.
Speaker 1: I mean that's never happened to me before.
Speaker 0: I mean because you've been interviewing in so many places.
Speaker 1: Yeah But all the anime cars have interviewed.
Speaker 1: I just started with the Katsu khan where I started doing it and no one ever turned me Down.
Speaker 1: I interviewed freaking parents Cops who were standing nearby watching the khan Random people walking by the hotel who were like what the hell is all this?
Speaker 1: No one ever turned me down.
Speaker 1: and even if they didn't even if I didn't get a good interview I talked to people here.
Speaker 1: It wasn't even that people didn't want to be interviewed It's that they didn't want to talk to me.
Speaker 1: They didn't want to be bothered.
Speaker 1: the fact that I talked to them like broke them out of this haze that they wanted to retreat Back into as quickly as possible.
Speaker 0: Yep, you know and I didn't even really see people talking to each other other than People who came with each other Discussing things they had bought and and stuff like that except all the people who go to anime cons Ended up.
Speaker 1: they seem to be all together like congregated in this open area And they were all hanging out having a ball and running around hitting each other with lightsabers.
Speaker 0: Oh great.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so for a second.
Speaker 1: I was like I got to break this up.
Speaker 1: There's like.
Speaker 1: no I don't.
Speaker 1: I paid to be in here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah Yeah, another thing was.
Speaker 0: you know I already think I mentioned it But there was a big giant booth for Spike TV and another booth for Sony.
Speaker 0: You know with the PlayStation shit mostly PSPs and ps2s anime cons don't have that crap Anime expo.
Speaker 0: they don't have this here.
Speaker 0: You know this is a corporate con.
Speaker 0: They had stuff like that.
Speaker 0: you know anime expo has that because that's also a corporate con, but you'll never see that shit at Anime or gaming cons that we go to that are largely geek run and not corporate run.
Speaker 1: Yep When you have volunteers doing everything and it's just people who want other people to have a good time Things always seem to work out better.
Speaker 0: Then if you're paying people to provide a service to other people at a profit you all sorts remember This is Wizard World Wizard magazine as in the you know the magazine about comics and superheroes and shit.
Speaker 0: They're running this con.
Speaker 0: so the con is going to be exactly what you expect.
Speaker 0: It's like going to a wizard magazine full of Superheroes and collectors and price guides and all that wizard magazine crap, and that's what it was corporate comic book whatnot?
Speaker 1: so in closing And That was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com, and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.