Speaker 0: It's Tuesday May 20th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about board games for a change with railroad tycoos.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I found the perfect job today.
Speaker 1: really yep the EFF is looking for a technology Person to basically do everything that Scott does awesomely.
Speaker 0: Alright, then take the job.
Speaker 0: quit your current one.
Speaker 1: I would I would jump all over this job in full force But I'd have to move to San Francisco.
Speaker 0: all right move.
Speaker 0: You're the one who always says that pick up and leave go over.
Speaker 0: the money are where the money is, but the jobs are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but San Francisco kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: Why do you say that you've never been there?
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 0: What do you know about San Francisco?
Speaker 1: I know it doesn't have me in it.
Speaker 1: That's why it sucks.
Speaker 0: But by that a logical point.
Speaker 0: then wouldn't you moving there?
Speaker 0: make it not suck?
Speaker 0: Nope, why not?
Speaker 1: Uh Because I said so yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we noticed that very recently we've gained a whole bunch of new listeners.
Speaker 0: So for all of you who've been listening for a long time We're sorry, but we're gonna go over a lot of the basics about the show pretty much every day this week.
Speaker 1: Yep This is a show called geek nights.
Speaker 1: There are two guys who talk about geeky shit.
Speaker 1: one of them is me named Scott And I'm rim.
Speaker 0: people have confused us before you spell his name.
Speaker 1: are why I'm not our?
Speaker 0: I am not our.
Speaker 0: H Why am though?
Speaker 1: I kind of like that one, but you do pronounce it as our.
Speaker 1: I am as in the job Yeah, or the basketball.
Speaker 0: You know no one's ever ever made a joke about a rim job to me.
Speaker 1: You know what no one's ever ever done that thing where they say no one's ever ever made that joke before.
Speaker 0: no I'm the first one.
Speaker 1: no you're not.
Speaker 1: you directly stole that from someone else.
Speaker 0: cuz no one's ever done it.
Speaker 0: so I'm so.
Speaker 1: You're gonna get a lot of shit like this as we talk about various geeky things and on Monday We talk about science and technology and all that, but it's Tuesday today.
Speaker 1: So we talk about games now.
Speaker 0: often we do video games because that's what a lot of our listeners are into.
Speaker 0: But we also cover well aside from video games board games card games role-playing games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mostly board games and video games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those have been a distinct drought of board games lately mostly due to the fact that we haven't had much time to play them Since it's con season, but this weekend is crazy board gaming weekend.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're having a bunch of friends out.
Speaker 0: We're going to meet a bunch of other people we know to play a big pile of board games all weekend And maybe buy a new one.
Speaker 1: who knows?
Speaker 0: yeah, there's really no board game.
Speaker 0: That's new that's excited me in a while.
Speaker 1: I know me either, but I might just buy something kind of mediocre or average or slightly above.
Speaker 0: You just can't top tigers and Euphrates in Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: No, okay, so Thursdays we talk about anime manga.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays Wednesdays.
Speaker 1: We talk about anime manga in comics and Thursday We talk about crazy shit.
Speaker 1: anything we want
Speaker 0: Yeah Including our very popular series on how to not suck
Speaker 1: where we tell you how to not suck at various things Which
Speaker 0: might sound I don't know not fun to listen to but Everyone really likes it and we get more feedback about that than about just about anything.
Speaker 0: We do.
Speaker 1: Yep, and If you are new to this podcasting thing, you can just you know, go to our website front row crew calm you can throw a Www in there if you want and over there, there's some links to our forums or you can talk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also show notes that we link to everything we talk about.
Speaker 1: Yep In the bottom right hand corner.
Speaker 1: There's a little PayPal dilly.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: Someone gave us PayPal.
Speaker 1: I forgot to tell everyone.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's the guy's name?
Speaker 0: Hold on Hold on I can't edit anything out because we're using garage band.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you just keep talking while I find this guy's name about frapper.
Speaker 0: All right Well, we got a frapper map which is basically this cool little integrated with Google Maps thing where anyone who wants to can join the front row crew geek nights pepper map and Put a little dot on the map so you can see where all our listeners are.
Speaker 0: and you might be surprised You know being meant that many of you are probably Americans that we have a lot of overseas and foreign listeners Which I think is awesome.
Speaker 0: We seem to be particularly popular in Australia and the UK.
Speaker 1: kind of yep.
Speaker 1: What else is there?
Speaker 1: Oh if you send us feedback in the form of audio meaning you attach an mp3 to an email or something or If you just send us an email to geek nights at front row crew calm Then we will most likely talk about it in the show or something.
Speaker 0: now We often talk about non audio feedback we get but we really don't attribute it or anything because it wasn't audio.
Speaker 0: So what do you want us to do?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, the forums are also good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, our forums are pretty rockin actually surprisingly.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and that's what this show is all about.
Speaker 1: Right pretty much everything we covered.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay the PayPal guy some awesome person Seems to be a Chinese person.
Speaker 1: I'm just guessing by the name.
Speaker 1: So if I'm wrong, oh, I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: Named Bey way Chang.
Speaker 1: I think I got that right.
Speaker 1: sent us.
Speaker 1: You're awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though we distinctly asked everyone not to send us money.
Speaker 0: We're not going to turn away money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is we.
Speaker 1: I put a PayPal on the site because you know It's more expensive for us to do the podcast now.
Speaker 1: Well and because that one listener asked us to Yeah, and the thing is is I don't want to ask for money.
Speaker 1: I don't need money.
Speaker 1: I don't want money.
Speaker 1: if no one sent me money.
Speaker 1: I'd be perfectly happy.
Speaker 1: but People out there want they're like trying to put money into my pocket and you know I really you know, you've only.
Speaker 1: you have to say no three times and then you have to let them put it there.
Speaker 1: That's that's the rule.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of like that rule of how many times a boy is allowed to break a promise.
Speaker 1: Yep So there's a PayPal hidden in the bottom right corner of our main site hidden down there and you know People can give us money if they are incredibly compelled, but we will not ask for it.
Speaker 0: In fact, if someone said yeah, we won't ask for it yet.
Speaker 0: You keep bringing it up.
Speaker 1: If someone came to me and said I want to give you PayPal money I'd say don't give it to me now.
Speaker 0: I will tell you right now that if you're thinking about giving us PayPal money hold off and wait because now that our logo contest and everything is mostly finalized if If you want to give us money, you'd be better off giving the company We're gonna contract to make awesome geek night swag giving them the money.
Speaker 0: We won't see any of it.
Speaker 0: Then you get swag swag.
Speaker 0: We'd rather you head of nothing.
Speaker 0: We'd rather you have swag than us have money.
Speaker 0: Yep, so stay tuned for the t-shirts.
Speaker 1: We've actually got a really good really relevant to today's show t-shirt but if you do want to get mad props on the show then giving us money is a good way to do that as Bayway Chang has evidenced.
Speaker 0: Yeah Great.
Speaker 0: So you've just told everyone we can be bought.
Speaker 1: No We're gonna say your name we're not gonna pimp your company or your website or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah Though I do have to give an awesome shout out to James and Lisa good friends of ours who recently well not recently was actually a while ago moved to Texas and I've got this new Mac Mini and tomorrow we're going to be interviewing the con chair of Otacon.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Jim Vowles.
Speaker 0: He was an awesome man And his cousin Jim consonants.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, I'll bet no one's ever made that joke to him.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should make it to him.
Speaker 0: But we decided to do the interview over iChat because it as apparently this nice GarageBand interface even though I hate GarageBand But I won't get into that today because it's not that day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can listen to yesterday's podcast for all that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I had to test it because I can't really test it without opening an actual conversation.
Speaker 0: So I looked and you know, not many of the people we know have Macs and far fewer of them use iChat.
Speaker 0: So James and Lisa were gracious enough to turn on their Macs and their iChats and talk to me and I recorded it.
Speaker 0: Thus I was able to prove that it works and now I learned everything about it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah news time.
Speaker 0: I think it's news time.
Speaker 0: We'll go with yours first since yours is actually video game news and mine is just piss you off news.
Speaker 1: Great piss me off news girl.
Speaker 0: I'm real good at piss you off news.
Speaker 1: Well, here you go ready.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read it straight from the website.
Speaker 1: In a bid to steal Sony's thunder Microsoft is rumored to be slashing the 360s price tag by almost a hundred dollars whoa sometime around autumn of 2006.
Speaker 1: Microsoft.
Speaker 1: maybe they'll redesign the system or you know with better cheaper hardware or something and They'll bring the core system down to Currently $300 and will be cheaper than the Wii and the pros super complete Xbox 360 would be slightly more than the Wii.
Speaker 1: And this is this isn't for sure.
Speaker 1: This is an industry.
Speaker 1: It's not even like a rumor.
Speaker 1: It says rumor, but it's like it's like a good guess.
Speaker 0: now I'll point out one that we won't talk about.
Speaker 0: Let's not take Nintendo right away.
Speaker 0: Let's just compare this to what's going on with Sony.
Speaker 0: I'd say that that's another nail in Sony's coffin because there are a lot of nails hanging around lately, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: You can't go beyond the maximum.
Speaker 1: It's oh when the nail is driven all the way into the wood hitting it more.
Speaker 1: It doesn't do anything.
Speaker 0: I guess what I want to say is that if this is true There is just a giant nail buried in the ground.
Speaker 0: There's no coffin.
Speaker 0: I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: the Xbox 360 which in as far as the I mean forget what you know about the Technology.
Speaker 0: the vast majority of people don't.
Speaker 0: they know that Xbox is hardcore gaming and PlayStation is hardcore gaming.
Speaker 0: I think the vast majority of people equate the two in terms of power and performance and everything.
Speaker 0: now if some mom wants to buy a video game system for Johnny for Christmas and The two hardcore gaming systems that are as far as she's concerned identical One of them is $600 and one of them is Hmm, huh?
Speaker 0: Cuz
Speaker 1: I mean right now it's like okay the Wii was 250 the super Xbox Which pretty much it seems to be the opinion of most people that the core Xbox the cheap one is basically worthless and you need the good one that cost more
Speaker 0: kind of like the Mac mini solo
Speaker 1: Kind of like the Mac mini course.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes So it's right now.
Speaker 1: It's Wii 250 Xbox 400 PlayStation 3 600.
Speaker 1: What if it was Wii 250?
Speaker 1: Xbox 360 300 so only $50 more than the incredibly cheap Wii.
Speaker 1: So it's a Wii plus a game and PlayStation 3 600. now the gap between the 360 and a PlayStation 2. a PlayStation 3 will be two Xboxes in price or Slightly less than two Xboxes in price.
Speaker 0: that's Ridiculous, I don't even know what to say.
Speaker 1: I mean back in the day when you had to choose between an SNES and a Genesis.
Speaker 1: a Genesis was cheaper by me at 50 bucks usually, you know and It didn't really matter.
Speaker 1: But if the Genesis was half the price of the Super Nintendo, that would have been insane.
Speaker 0: Now it's like huh.
Speaker 0: in terms of Nintendo there are two ways to look at it.
Speaker 0: either you could say that now that the Xbox is so cheap and Especially considering that normal people really equate the Xbox brand with hardcore gaming.
Speaker 0: It might put a dent in Wii sales But at the same time it might just make people more inclined to buy both.
Speaker 0: because you only need one of the Xbox 360 in the PlayStation 3 There are very few games that you can't play on one.
Speaker 1: there were many many surveys that were like, what are you going to get?
Speaker 1: and When you looked at the numbers, it seemed like even though very, you know people getting just a Wii wasn't super many.
Speaker 1: Of course only super gamers are voting, of course Yeah except slash dot.
Speaker 1: when you took into account the number of people who are buying something else and a Wii and you Combined it all it ended up where more than half the gamers had.
Speaker 1: we wanted wheeze You know, they just more than half of those guys also wanted something else in addition.
Speaker 0: so stay tuned.
Speaker 0: if this is true We'll talk about it again because there are far-reaching ramifications.
Speaker 1: Possibly buying an Xbox 360.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's so cheap.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say no man.
Speaker 0: What's going on with us?
Speaker 0: I bought a Mac.
Speaker 0: now we're thinking of buying an Xbox.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's like remember way back.
Speaker 0: I switched from gen 2 to Ubuntu Ubuntu When the Xbox came out the first Xbox and everyone made fun of it.
Speaker 0: In fact penny arcade Ruthlessly made fun of it.
Speaker 1: Giant controllers.
Speaker 1: Hey did like eight comics about how terrible the Xbox was all the while game was becoming the master of mecha salt.
Speaker 0: Fast forward to today.
Speaker 0: They're freaking Xbox gamers.
Speaker 0: They love it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they complain about it.
Speaker 0: But every gamer complains about every game they play They do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what they do.
Speaker 0: And that's what this is.
Speaker 1: That's what this is All.
Speaker 0: right now to the piss you off news.
Speaker 0: Now I was going to talk about Scientologists because I really don't like Scientologists, but there's another Pseudo-religious group that has the word science in it.
Speaker 0: that in many ways bothers me more Mainly because Scientology for the most part harms adults.
Speaker 0: it harms adults and families But it harms people who while I feel sorry for them and I think we should help them They kind of bring it on themselves by joining this crazy group.
Speaker 0: Christian scientists harm children and that's not cool.
Speaker 0: now to gloss over a lot of the details many Christian scientists don't believe in such things as Immunization or going to the doctor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just remember Christian scientists.
Speaker 1: when someone says Christian scientists They don't mean a person who is a scientist who also happens to be a Christian which would be an awesome thing and they don't Scientologists which is something very different than a Christian scientist.
Speaker 0: Christian scientists are Generally a God will save you if you're sick And there have been so many court cases where a family will have a child and the child gets sick and they won't take the Child to the doctor because it's against their faith and then the child dies or sometimes the state will sue and take the child away from them to give the child treatment and then the parents will kidnap the Child run to Mexico and then the child will die.
Speaker 0: that happened recently.
Speaker 0: now Science, I guess has won a round in that.
Speaker 0: in Boston just now there is a minor measles outbreak in a Christian science group.
Speaker 0: Measles measles is the disease that does not really exist in the civilized world anymore.
Speaker 0: We eradicated it.
Speaker 0: we through science technology and a concerted effort of mankind Practically eliminated a horrible disease similar to what we did with polio or typhus or What we almost did to malaria before Greenpeace got involved, but I won't talk about that today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pet.
Speaker 1: that reminds me.
Speaker 1: on Penn show today He was talking about genetic engineering But there was a relevant bit at the end where he talked about a t-shirt his friend has that says God wants you dead or God wants to kill you.
Speaker 1: He goes without science or any medicine or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Half of babies just die and half of mothers who make babies will die and Everyone else will die before the age of 30 most likely.
Speaker 1: I think the average life expectancy of a non science human is like 27 28. yeah, so Science is what lets you live.
Speaker 1: God will kill you.
Speaker 1: Don't be a Christian scientist.
Speaker 1: Christian science doesn't work.
Speaker 1: only real science will let you live now.
Speaker 0: Don't get confused.
Speaker 0: I'm not attacking faith religion Christianity not today.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: I'm attacking Christian science today.
Speaker 0: I want to bring this up mainly because the issue here was vaccinations.
Speaker 0: These parents decide did not want to vaccinate their child with the MMR the measles mumps rubella Vaccine which every child in this country gets now.
Speaker 0: there are a lot of reason.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of people who object to this vaccine for non religious reasons, which is just as stupid and just as dangerous.
Speaker 0: It so happens that many vaccines use a compound that has mercury in it to stabilize them or to preserve them.
Speaker 1: Now if you tell some idiot on the street They know that mercury is poisonous and you tell them that vaccine has mercury in it So they put two and two together and they say it's poison.
Speaker 0: even worse a couple of crackpots a while ago Brought forth some evidence that has mostly been discredited saying that Autism looks like it is caused in many cases by Vaccines and the mercury in vaccines, which is just not true.
Speaker 1: not true at all.
Speaker 0: It's it's definitely a genetic type of thing and or I mean there could be environmental.
Speaker 0: We really don't know.
Speaker 0: We know there are genetic factors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there is no substantial evidence that vaccines have anything to do with it.
Speaker 0: and Furthermore I would argue that even if they did the net benefit to mankind of vaccinating every child is You know good of the many.
Speaker 0: it's a greater good.
Speaker 0: You'll save far more people from far worse fates by vaccinating everyone if 0.01 percent of the people vaccinated develop Autism, even though that doesn't actually happen.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I just wanted to make the intellectual argument here in case anyone, you know decided to argue against it.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know my argument against vaccines is they hurt.
Speaker 0: No, they don't.
Speaker 0: you're a little baby.
Speaker 0: You don't know it hurts.
Speaker 0: Actually, I've gotten many interesting vaccines in my adult life.
Speaker 1: It doesn't hurt.
Speaker 1: Let me give you all kinds of shots then.
Speaker 0: Uh, Scott you realize that while I was young I had allergy shots for over eight years where twice a week.
Speaker 0: I would go in and get two shots in each arm.
Speaker 0: Shots don't hurt.
Speaker 0: I just they don't even bother me at all.
Speaker 0: All right, then I'll give you some Only if they do something useful for me.
Speaker 0: I mean I while ago I got the hepatitis vaccine and the meningitis vaccine cuz I work in hospital.
Speaker 1: All right, I'll put something in the shots.
Speaker 1: I'll put in.
Speaker 1: Um, yeah Heroin heroin will work.
Speaker 1: You Like everyone right?
Speaker 0: Yeah heroines just great perfect.
Speaker 1: We'll go we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: I just I saw this news.
Speaker 0: I was gonna talk about something stupid thing and then I saw this news about a measles outbreak in the United States And I just couldn't let that stand.
Speaker 0: I had to say something about it.
Speaker 0: But happily that music means that it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: Yes, if you're a new listener every episode we do the things of the day Which is where we pick a thing from the internet that we think is humorous interesting, etc.
Speaker 1: And the link to it is on the website in the show notes.
Speaker 0: Yep, or many people apparently just look at my delicious because I usually put in there what I'm gonna link to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mine is in my delicious.
Speaker 0: Anyway what I discovered on a much lighter note from what we were just talking about Hulk Hogan is selling his mansion.
Speaker 1: Now I'll note right now that I do a Hulk Hogan impression, but I almost did a macho man ready savages by accident.
Speaker 0: I can only do macho man Randy Savage and quagmire All right now.
Speaker 0: the interesting thing I noted is one he's selling the mansion for 25 million dollars and the mansion has a lot of Weird rich guy things in it like special hardwood floors from only the hearts of Oaks and woven in a pattern Whoa and weird stuff.
Speaker 0: But the very interesting thing I noticed and Scott noticed it too when I read it to him was that this house has five bedrooms and eight Bathrooms, okay.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So wait there is a bathroom for each bedroom.
Speaker 1: That's five.
Speaker 1: there's one downstairs six I Don't know.
Speaker 0: there's another.
Speaker 1: maybe there's like three stories of non bedroom.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's how many stories is it?
Speaker 0: You know, I didn't even read the whole article.
Speaker 0: I suggest I'll read it.
Speaker 1: Okay, maybe there's like one for the maid quarters.
Speaker 0: No just in the house.
Speaker 0: There are more bathrooms in the maids quarters.
Speaker 0: Uh The only thing I can think of is a quote from an old webcomic that I read where I Want a bathroom so big it has a bathroom in it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh That's all I got.
Speaker 1: Hulk Hogan selling his house, yeah, it seems to me like is he selling the house?
Speaker 1: I don't think he's selling it cuz he's poor.
Speaker 0: No, he's selling it because he moved to Miami Beach.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems like he's selling this mansion cuz it's a crazy mansion.
Speaker 1: It's not really the greatest most practical thing to live in.
Speaker 0: He's not like MC Hammer selling his mansion because his manager stole all his money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think MC Hammer had problems besides his manager ceiling is true He did but his manager was probably the final nail in that nail.
Speaker 1: Yep The manager just jumped off the sinking ship in the last lifeboat.
Speaker 1: The ship was already sinking with all the money.
Speaker 0: it was a ship made of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was the lifeboat made of money.
Speaker 1: He folded up the little dollar bills to make a boat.
Speaker 1: so gaming day excite bike.
Speaker 0: do Now first off.
Speaker 0: You all know excite bike.
Speaker 0: I would like to mention right now even though this isn't Scott's thing of the day That if you've ever thought you were good at excite bike No, you're wrong and there's a Google video to prove it.
Speaker 1: but anyway Oops, I started the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So what's your thing?
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's this flash game That's excite bike, but it's not the excite bike you're used to.
Speaker 1: What did?
Speaker 1: what you do?
Speaker 1: is the excite bike guy starts going and you can't really change lanes or anything like that.
Speaker 1: it's just you're on the bottom row and First is a meter that goes back and forth.
Speaker 1: need to push the spacebar when the meter is full to get a good start.
Speaker 0: All right, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: then the guy goes and he hits a jump and Using the ASD keys and the arrow and the W key and the arrow keys You do tricks while you're in the air like flipping over the bike, you know, all kinds of crazy motocross east All right,
Speaker 0: so it's just excite bike style and it's not really excite bike.
Speaker 1: No, it's not really excite bike.
Speaker 1: and the more tricks you do the faster you go the more airtime you get the more tricks You do the faster you go.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh now Even more fun than that for me at least was this other mode Where you choose a number of trucks to jump over one through ten?
Speaker 1: And you jump in.
Speaker 1: the way you build up speed in that mode is by going ASASASASAS hitting the A and S keys in rapid succession.
Speaker 0: I got a mad Nintendo finger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this is the Nintendo finger test for everyone out there.
Speaker 1: I was able to jump over all ten trucks.
Speaker 1: Whoa, you jump over all ten trucks.
Speaker 1: That is the question.
Speaker 1: If you can't don't play Mario Party with me, you'll just lose.
Speaker 0: I Remember that time you and me were on a team in Mario Party and I forget who we were playing against and it was the Game where it was teams and it was who can it a the most?
Speaker 0: and we won by like 400 button presses or something sick.
Speaker 1: It was something really sick.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright anyway, it's gaming day and we haven't talked about board games in a while.
Speaker 0: So we decided we pull out a game that we we like.
Speaker 0: we've played it a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: I bought it completely on a whim.
Speaker 1: It's a real impressive looking game and it's also a computer game that go.
Speaker 1: that's almost the same.
Speaker 0: Yep It is railroad tycoon.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now it's not true while the game is railroad themed and it plays like a railroad game.
Speaker 0: It is not a Railroad game not with a capital R. Anyway, yeah, it's like I'm a libertarian but not with a capital L. railroad game with a capital R or capital L is Kranz and wax paper.
Speaker 0: if you've ever seen a game with a bunch of scary dudes sitting around a table with a bunch of wax paper And maps and they're drawing colored lines on it and they're yelling at each other.
Speaker 0: That is a railroad game.
Speaker 0: I find them scary and frightening Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: This is just a fun happy game to play with your friends and move little cubes around.
Speaker 1: Oh the cubes.
Speaker 0: It's not the most Intellectually demanding game.
Speaker 0: It's not the most hardcore German game, but it's a solid game.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of fun and it's very tactical and strategic.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's also Pretty free.
Speaker 1: like you can do all sorts of different stuff in this game.
Speaker 1: It's not like other games that there's just a few decisions to make.
Speaker 1: you're you're free to do all kinds of crazy stuff Yep, and many of them are profitable.
Speaker 0: The game is very well balanced in that regard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems like no matter what you do.
Speaker 1: You'll always profit.
Speaker 0: The key is to just profit faster and more Yep, and the game will come down to a lot of little decisions you made throughout the game.
Speaker 0: Yep Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the game works.
Speaker 0: All right, the game is very simple.
Speaker 0: You have a very large board.
Speaker 0: That is the eastern United States.
Speaker 1: You know it the eastern half of the United States.
Speaker 0: it goes all the way out to the middle of the country where Kansas is Yep, and then it has two links that represent the West but you don't need to worry about them There's.
Speaker 0: no.
Speaker 0: I've seen people who made expansions, but it's just not worth it.
Speaker 0: Yeah and Basically, here's the thing you have money and you use money to buy railroad tracks between cities.
Speaker 0: you also use money to buy other things like upgrading trains and buying equipment and Buying the right to go first on a turn and your main goal is to ship cubes from one sit from cities to other cities Thereby generating profit thereby using that profit to ship more cubes and in the course of all this getting victory points Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So let's say there's a city.
Speaker 1: every city has cubes in it.
Speaker 1: at the beginning a random assortment a random assortment.
Speaker 1: and you know Different cities have different numbers of cubes based on how much industry is in that city.
Speaker 0: Yep, and each cube represents an industry.
Speaker 0: It's a very abstract thing very abstract.
Speaker 1: So let's say there's a red cube in Florida somewhere and I guess it'd be some city in Florida Tampa, I guess.
Speaker 1: Is that on the map?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Tampa's on the map all right, and the nearest red city because you can only send red cubes to red cities you see is I don't know somewhere in Carolina or something some other city.
Speaker 1: Yes So now you had to build railroad track from Florida to Carolina in order to send the cube from one city to the next One.
Speaker 0: now you can only lay certain amounts of track per round.
Speaker 0: So there are a lot of links that just can't be made.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you have to stop over in other cities.
Speaker 0: so you'll make a track from Chicago to Detroit and then Detroit to Toledo and then Toledo to whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then if you want to ship from Chicago to whatnot and it goes through to other cities You need an upgraded train to make that trip because it has too many stops.
Speaker 0: Now the one gimmick here is that when you build a track because you paid for it It's your track, but anyone can use any track on the board.
Speaker 0: The thing is you have to pay for the privilege.
Speaker 1: So if I send a cube from what my city Across my track then across my track again then across the rims track I get two points and he gets one point because I used one of his tracks and two of my tracks.
Speaker 0: So there's definitely a competitive thing going on.
Speaker 0: plus because of that say there's a city and two people have rail lines going out of it.
Speaker 0: They'll be fighting to ship those cubes out first and get rid of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah people will often ship cubes out over other people's tracks just to force cubes to be shipped.
Speaker 1: and Maybe you know Maybe it's a six player game and rim is lost and I'm in second place and I can ship a cube Over my track and then maybe five of rim tracks and I get one point for that.
Speaker 1: I might do it.
Speaker 1: it empties cubes.
Speaker 1: It does also, you know, there's all kinds of crazy stuff You can do.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: you have used money to do all these things.
Speaker 0: but gimmick number two You don't start with any money.
Speaker 1: you start with jack and shit for money actually, nothing.
Speaker 0: you start with all the lowest level train you can have and nothing.
Speaker 0: So, how do you do anything?
Speaker 0: and I really like this mechanic and I'd love to see more games that involve money.
Speaker 0: use a mechanic Like this.
Speaker 0: you can sell Stock in yourself.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: You can sell shares.
Speaker 0: Basically, you will sell say five shares.
Speaker 0: I think you get five thousand dollars for every share.
Speaker 0: you sell Every round.
Speaker 0: well every turn you then have to pay interest on all those forever Dividends dividends, you can never buy off or pay off a share, right?
Speaker 0: So you say in the beginning of the game you take two shares.
Speaker 0: So now you get ten grand every round.
Speaker 0: for the rest of the game you pay two grand back to the bank.
Speaker 1: Yep, so you want to take as few shares as possible, but at the same time.
Speaker 1: if you take more shares Maybe you can get a big start in the game with a big pile of money, you know, so it's all about Managing.
Speaker 1: if you take too few shares other people will jump ahead of you in the game But if you take too many you won't be able to make anything profitable early in the game and you'll end up just.
Speaker 1: You can screw yourself over by taking too many shares and end up with a very slow-moving Useless unprofitable railroad company.
Speaker 0: You can also screw yourself by not taking enough shares not expanding fast enough and being cut out of all The important markets.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's a very fine line that I have often crossed Often.
Speaker 1: the first time I played I took way too.
Speaker 1: I thought I was trying to limit shares.
Speaker 1: I took two way too many because what happened was you get in the ultimate.
Speaker 1: worst Situation is when you take a few shares.
Speaker 1: you took a couple more than you wanted to but okay, whatever You know, it's only a couple more shares, you know.
Speaker 1: And then you don't have enough money to pay those shares off and now you have to take a share to pay off the shares.
Speaker 0: That and for anyone who knows math and even if you don't you can figure out as a bad idea.
Speaker 1: You pretty much have no choice though.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's not good.
Speaker 1: So then you have no money to do any railroading to get more money to pay off these shares no money.
Speaker 1: So what do you do?
Speaker 1: you take some shares?
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: Now there's another gimmick involving the shares in that at the end of the game You lose one victory point and one victory point in this game is a big deal for every share that you have.
Speaker 1: So Shaking shares is not good, but necessary.
Speaker 1: It's like you must do something that hurts you in order to win, but everyone must do it.
Speaker 0: So it's who manages that must the best.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The game also has these cards.
Speaker 0: These are.
Speaker 0: these are a real nice.
Speaker 0: I don't want to call them a gimmick But they.
Speaker 0: without these the game would be very stagnant because aside from the randomization of the cubes on the cities The strategies would pretty much always be the same because the board static.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: so even though the cards add randomness they add flavor and they're not secret.
Speaker 1: So everyone can look at them and make a decision based on it.
Speaker 1: So it's not bad.
Speaker 1: And what they do is all their different kinds of cards but the interesting ones are the ones that say if you do this you get a pile of money or If you do this, then you get all these goodies.
Speaker 1: It's like first person to ship a cube here.
Speaker 1: So everyone will race to ship a cube there.
Speaker 0: a lot of more abilities to like.
Speaker 0: anyone who has this card can build extra tracks You know.
Speaker 1: or anyone who has this card can put more cubes in a city Yep, or just take an extra turn all sorts of fun stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: There are also character cards, which there's definitely another gimmick.
Speaker 0: Every person in the game has a secret card and they're doled out randomly
Speaker 1: at the beginning of the game
Speaker 0: and you look at it And it gives you a name a name of some famous old railroad tycoon and a relevant goal and you get bonus victory points at The end if you accomplish that goal,
Speaker 1: so for my favorite one is take the least shares.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're that guy and you take the least shares at the end of the game you get like 10 points.
Speaker 1: now There's nothing like that.
Speaker 0: There are two cards that say that Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So you might have two people who neither one of them knows it, but they're both competing for the least shares And Crazy cuz then one of them's gonna get points and one of them isn't don't don't Yep.
Speaker 0: But other than that, I mean the game is very simple.
Speaker 0: you build tracks.
Speaker 0: Well, basically we'll go over the road how the game actually works now that we've covered all the gimmicks.
Speaker 0: Okay, you you get your money with the shares and the game is could consist of turns and every turn Consist.
Speaker 0: well every round just call them rounds.
Speaker 0: go that way.
Speaker 0: there are rounds and within a round there are three sets of turns.
Speaker 0: So it goes around and everyone takes the turn.
Speaker 0: then it goes around and everyone takes the turn.
Speaker 0: Then it goes around a third time and everyone takes the turn.
Speaker 0: Then the whole thing is over.
Speaker 0: then you do the paying dividends out and taking new shares and all the stuff between.
Speaker 0: Now the other mechanic here is that when you build railroad tracks you can only build I think four Sections of track for each of your turns.
Speaker 1: so you can at most.
Speaker 0: you can build twelve Yep, and that's if you do nothing, but build the maximum every time it's your turn for an entire round.
Speaker 0: And if you build any tracks that don't connect to cities within the scope of your three turns Then they're wiped off the board and you just wasted all your money.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have to pay for each tile of track you put on the board.
Speaker 0: You also have to pay more if you go over like mountains or over rivers or through it to make a tunnel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it really it sucks to pay for building track.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much what it comes down to.
Speaker 0: it costs a lot.
Speaker 0: The thing is once the game's going especially towards the end of the game or the middle of the game Especially you'll have so much money and profit that you don't care and you're just blowing tracks through mountains everywhere left and right unless you suck And then you suck.
Speaker 1: Yep But there's also lots of strategy and placement of track because you can prevent other people from building tracks in efficient ways.
Speaker 1: They'll have to go and take an inefficient route that cost more money.
Speaker 0: also deciding where to build I mean say it's a four player game and three players are all fighting over the Northeast in New York.
Speaker 0: You just start building in the Midwest where no one's competing with you.
Speaker 1: Yep, even though you have to the cities there in the Northeast are closer together and have a lot of cubes.
Speaker 1: So early in the game, that's really good because it doesn't cost a lot to Set something up that can ship cubes, but later on in the game.
Speaker 1: There won't be any cubes left over there.
Speaker 1: But you it's harder to start out in the middle of nowhere early in the game Because you have to spend more money because the cities are farther away.
Speaker 1: you had to build more track Of course.
Speaker 0: our friend Pete showed us very very powerfully one game.
Speaker 0: We played.
Speaker 1: what happens when no one is watching what you're doing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're all fighting over the Northeast and the Southeast and a little bit over the Midwest.
Speaker 0: Pete just built tracks all over the West And we weren't paying attention and then we realized that he had built the Western link.
Speaker 0: So he connected to the West and then he built lines from there all the way to Chicago.
Speaker 0: Which is this crazy thing in the game?
Speaker 1: There's a card about it and everything and then all the way to New York.
Speaker 0: yeah, he got Yeah more points from that than all of us had gotten from our squabbling in New York combined.
Speaker 1: basically because what it does is the Western link to Chicago and this card makes a whole pile of red cubes and then if you connect Chicago to New York and You have a good enough train that can make that whole trip.
Speaker 1: All of those red cubes get you like five the zillion points each.
Speaker 1: so every turn he just shipped those red cubes and All we could do about it was maybe steal those red cubes and ship them somewhere else on our own Which is tough.
Speaker 0: one of the mechanics of shipping cubes, which we should probably talk about Is that you can ship cubes over any train lines?
Speaker 0: But the first line that any cube goes over that you're trying to ship has to go over one of your trains.
Speaker 1: so if you want to steal cubes from Chicago, you need to have a Connection with you.
Speaker 1: that is belongs to you.
Speaker 1: from Chicago to somewhere else.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah The way cubes work is that all the cities have cubes of different colors and you want to ship cubes to the city of their Color.
Speaker 0: if a red cube starts in a red city, you have to take it to a different red city.
Speaker 0: Simple as that.
Speaker 0: you can't ship cubes over a city of the relevant color to another city of the relevant color.
Speaker 1: yeah, so if it's like you have a purple cube in a blue city and then a train track goes to a red city then a Purple city then a yellow city and then a purple city.
Speaker 1: You can't ship it to the second purple city has to go to the closer Purple city because the first purple city will take the cube not the next one.
Speaker 0: Yep, which the reason that's important is that the way you get victory points.
Speaker 0: now on your rounds I said you can build four up to four sections of track.
Speaker 0: the other options you have are take one of those cards that may be leather to be laying face up or Ship a cube.
Speaker 0: So anytime you do something It's at the expense of shipping a cube or taking a card or doing one of the other things.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to decide sometimes on your turn because they'll be a really good piece of track You want to build and there'll be some cubes you want to ship and you can't do both.
Speaker 1: So it's always a fight should I ship the cubes or should I build the tracks, you know?
Speaker 1: It's like okay if I build the tracks then he'll get X points because he'll build the track first and then he'll ship that cube And all that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then he's thinking the same thing and the poison ends up going in both cups done.
Speaker 0: Now Say you get one point when you ship a cube for every section of track that it goes over.
Speaker 0: That is yours.
Speaker 0: And like we said any other sections of track that it goes over those people get the points.
Speaker 0: Now the interesting thing about this game is the way Scoring and income and all that work because we keep talking about money and dividends and selling shares in your stock But we didn't explain how to get actual money to pay all this off.
Speaker 0: Every victory point you get moves you up on this scale.
Speaker 1: There's a scale going up both sides of the board and everyone starts at zero, which means your income is like four thousand.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: It's really low.
Speaker 1: you basically barely get any money at the beginning.
Speaker 0: for every victory point that you get you move up the scale.
Speaker 0: and As you move up the scale the income you get for every round, you know set of three turns increases.
Speaker 0: So shipping a bunch of cubes Increases your income permanently.
Speaker 0: Thus you have more money to build more things to ship more cubes.
Speaker 1: The thing is the scale.
Speaker 1: Eventually when you get a ton of it now, of course over as the most victory points wins.
Speaker 1: Yes, more victory points is always better no matter what but if you get too many victory points I think around like 30 or 40 50 victory points.
Speaker 1: when you start getting up there your income starts Decreasing because your railroad is large and unwieldy and you're to pay to maintain it and all that.
Speaker 1: So someone who's getting way ahead in the game gets slowed down by decreased income.
Speaker 0: But at the same time you want to build up to that high income while you're profitable.
Speaker 0: Then during that time instead of shipping cubes and dropping out of that income area You just start building tracks everywhere or picking up all those cards.
Speaker 0: You're gonna need later in the game.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm There's a lot of strategy involved in that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's ship cubes ship cubes ship cubes.
Speaker 1: My income if I ship any more cubes will decrease.
Speaker 1: Let me build a bunch of tracks while my income is high.
Speaker 1: now That I've built a bunch of tracks I will ship cubes ship cubes to get a bunch of victory points not caring that my income will decrease Because I've already built all my tracks while my income was high.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile everyone else in the game is doing the exact same thing you're doing and there's crazy competition and you can't really predict What everyone is going to do and there's so many chaotic factors involved.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the way the game works really goes along with the theme of competing railroad tycoons.
Speaker 1: I must say it does.
Speaker 0: Now you ship the cubes get the victory points use the cards get victory points and in the end it comes down to victory points.
Speaker 0: Now the game ends when a number of cities have run out of goods.
Speaker 1: So there's a lot of strategy in that as well.
Speaker 1: You know, you'll.
Speaker 1: you'll see a city with one cube in it And if you want the game to end sooner Which is usually because you're winning you will try to to take the last cubes out of cities You know you and make those cities empty out because if a city has no cubes you put a brown thing in it.
Speaker 1: And what?
Speaker 1: how many brown things ends the game?
Speaker 0: It depends how many players you have.
Speaker 1: Yeah But you want to get a lot of brown things out there to end the game quickly if you're winning if you're losing the game You want to use cards?
Speaker 1: To put cubes in empty cities to bring them back to life and you want to ship cubes From cities that have a bunch of cubes in them.
Speaker 1: That way they won't empty out and you'll be safe and the game can go longer and you have a chance to dethrone the current Winner.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the game is really volatile.
Speaker 0: I mean if someone pulls ahead in the beginning There's a decent chance.
Speaker 0: someone who's smart can just blow them away by the midpoint of the game.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Now the game itself.
Speaker 0: the production values are very high except for a few tiny niggling little issues.
Speaker 0: The board is huge.
Speaker 1: The board is actually three boards and it's big.
Speaker 0: you lay them all next to each other And it's big and impressive looking.
Speaker 1: it takes up a whole table.
Speaker 1: This thing is giant.
Speaker 0: It comes with a whole bunch of colored little train pieces made out of plastic.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Those are pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except the their problems is like.
Speaker 1: the board is not a really fancy board.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a cheap board and make what it makes up for what it loot what it lacks in Thickness and sturdiness it makes up for in size.
Speaker 1: Yeah quantity and those little plastic trains are really cool But some of them little chimneys break off whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it comes.
Speaker 0: the only real drawback other than the fact that the boards a little cheap is that it comes with paper money.
Speaker 1: Oh paper money is the worst.
Speaker 0: paper money is annoying but it kind of works in this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the shares are nice.
Speaker 1: The cards are nice.
Speaker 1: the train Upgrade things are really thick cardboard like tiles.
Speaker 1: I don't know why they did that But it works, you know, everything is pretty good except for the paper money.
Speaker 0: Also the game is real expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the game is pretty expensive and the board is big and it's heavy.
Speaker 0: The thing is I mean, we're hardcore German gamers.
Speaker 0: We like the the brains banging against each other bevagon odor very schlagen see games.
Speaker 0: And this gives a really fun game.
Speaker 0: it's a good game to get six people together.
Speaker 0: I don't recommend playing it with fewer than two or three.
Speaker 0: Well, not fewer than two, but fewer than three or four people.
Speaker 0: It's just not as fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we played it with two and it was kind of a.
Speaker 0: yeah, we played it with three and it was okay.
Speaker 0: but if you play it with a full set of players it becomes.
Speaker 1: Thing is even though the game has ways to make up for the fact that there aren't enough players and that it takes a different number of empty cities to end the game if there aren't that many players what ends up happening is There isn't enough of that land-grabbing competition with a lot of players.
Speaker 1: You're really right into the game.
Speaker 1: You're fighting for.
Speaker 1: you know The cities and the connections and all that stuff because someone else will get it before you do.
Speaker 0: and that's the fun part of the game.
Speaker 0: I mean you can't directly screw people you can't directly make deals with people But there's just all this fierce competition and there's a long time between when you take your turn and everyone else takes theirs
Speaker 1: Yep, and in a two or three player game, you're everyone pretty much has all the room.
Speaker 1: They want to build whatever they want without anyone else getting in the way.
Speaker 1: It's like oh if he's gonna go over there I'll just go over here where he's not.
Speaker 0: the game causes a lot of yelling which is good.
Speaker 0: We like games that cause yelling.
Speaker 1: Yep, yelling is fun.
Speaker 1: How long is it?
Speaker 1: That's not bad.
Speaker 0: So I mean in some railroad tycoon is probably a good buy.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine any board gamer who would dislike this game significantly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you are a board gamer, you will probably like railroad tycoon and I was just a normal person.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I know I think normal people, you know Normies or muggles or people who aren't really into heavy German board games Would probably really enjoy this game as long as they played it with at least a few Gamers who knew how to play and were hardcore knew what was going on to kind of guide them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this game definitely is more accessible to normal folk than say a Tigris and Euphrates But it's not as accessible as say a battleship or an UNO.
Speaker 0: true true, but you get a lot out of it.
Speaker 0: I mean someone who doesn't know much about board gaming could really enjoy this game.
Speaker 0: And the thing is even if you're losing Even if you're just getting your ass kicked into the ground handed to you and beaten You're still building some tracks and putting some trains on them and it's real fun.
Speaker 0: moving moving some cubes around You always feel like you're accomplishing something.
Speaker 1: the first time I played I started out basically You know in the hole going deeper into the hole, but after a few turns, you know I I managed to just slowly crawl out of the hole and I was profiting and building stuff.
Speaker 1: You know, I never was able.
Speaker 1: everyone else, you know I was already way ahead of me on the curve and was building a lot more stuff and shipping a lot more cubes.
Speaker 1: But I you know, I did something and it felt pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yep That's the thing.
Speaker 0: The game is very fun in addition to the fact that it's very tactical and very strategic.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm But that's enough about railroad tycoon.
Speaker 0: I know we haven't talked about board games a lot.
Speaker 0: We're glad to bring it back.
Speaker 0: We'd like to get some feedback as always.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many of you out there have played this game.
Speaker 0: I recommend picking it up if you find it cheap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what did the game cost you?
Speaker 1: 60 80.
Speaker 0: I think it was like 60 but I got that discount.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: it's a big expensive game.
Speaker 1: You know in size and everything.
Speaker 0: it's real impressive looking.
Speaker 0: if you're at a convention where there's a lot of space It's a great game to set up somewhere, especially since you'll you're gonna need like two tables stuck together to play.
Speaker 1: Conventions are a great place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'll got.
Speaker 0: you'll gather a crowd real quick.
Speaker 1: Yeah people say what's this?
Speaker 1: it's huge and look at all those trains and whoa, it's big and They'll just hang around you and watch everything you're doing.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I'll find a little meta bit here because I know after yesterday's show I've gotten a lot of feedback and some people are giving me some really good advice on things I can do to make my Mac experience better.
Speaker 0: Most people seem to agree that garage band doesn't have a lot of deficiencies.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm but the only real point of contention I've seen now is that a lot of people are Saying that the PC itself the Intel core Little single core is not fast enough or that there's a performance problem with the hardware which I am 99% sure is not true because this is a screaming little machine for what it's worth.
Speaker 0: and This week at some point.
Speaker 0: We're going to boot camp and install Ubuntu Ubuntu on it and Then run resound and audacity and do the podcast the way we do in Linux in Linux just on this hardware Mm-hmm, and I'll have a full report on that.
Speaker 0: All right, because we do know that there is a lot of overhead in OS X. OS X is really pretty and great for day-to-day use But there's just there's a lot of overhead and we're going to be able to see exactly how much overhead.
Speaker 1: plus most of our complaints Aren't the fact that it's slow.
Speaker 1: I mean or that, you know, it ran out of RAM?
Speaker 1: Okay, the problem is not that it ran out of RAM.
Speaker 1: The problem is that it ran out of RAM.
Speaker 1: It didn't say anything though.
Speaker 0: If you look at the forums, it looks like that was just an even stupider bug About tempo and beats per minute.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, it's like I'm verifying it now, but it looks like GarageBand is limited severely in that it can only keep track of X number of events.
Speaker 0: so by default it has a beats per minute thing a tempo which because it was originally a Music program.
Speaker 1: Well, it still is a music program.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now they hype it for podcasting.
Speaker 0: They don't say much about the music aspect of it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It still has that in the podcasting.
Speaker 0: It has a feature that has no context in podcasting, but it's still there.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait.
Speaker 1: So there's beats per minute in our podcast.
Speaker 0: Yes Which get this?
Speaker 1: um, dumb dumb.
Speaker 0: when it maxes out the number that it can deal with It just stops recording.
Speaker 0: and the way to fix that as two people told me is to set the tempo to like 40 beats per Minute instead of the standard 120. that way it won't run out so quickly and you can record longer.
Speaker 0: Wow that that is a prime example of Context being used improperly.
Speaker 1: That is the kind of stuff that we're complaining about.
Speaker 1: It's the design of the software design of the interface of the software the code of the software.
Speaker 1: The reason we bought it was for the software and the software is bad But it was not free and I want to say right now.
Speaker 0: It's not OS X. I am absolutely enjoying OS X. It's running really well and other than GarageBand things are generally pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm mostly complaining about GarageBand Yep, and I'm complaining about Apple for hyping GarageBand saying it can do things that it doesn't do so well.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm But anyway, that's talk for next Monday and yesterday and yesterday.
Speaker 1: Well next Monday is gonna be I think how computers work some more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless we have a lot to say after we Ubuntu eyes Yeah, actually we could do it.
Speaker 1: We since we just did a show about Mac we could do a show about.
Speaker 1: I think we didn't Ubuntu show before.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: Actually, what I'd like to do is do a show on UI and context and all this stuff because I've noticed that I've had trouble explaining to people why I dislike GarageBand mostly because a lot of people don't seem to know all of the interface design or human computer interaction or Usability engineering terms or terminology like.
Speaker 1: they don't know what it means.
Speaker 1: and you say context.
Speaker 0: well I think people seem to not like I. the word context when referring to a design of Usability and interface thing is a very specific thing an extremely specific thing And I think people are taking that word very generally and thus misunderstanding me.
Speaker 1: Yep I think that I think a lot of people aren't exactly sure what you mean because I Mean when you say context menu people.
Speaker 1: 90% of people don't know what the hell that is.
Speaker 0: Yeah But plus I think that'd be a good show.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right, we maybe do that.
Speaker 0: I've taken a lot of classes on it.
Speaker 0: I mean majored in IT and that was one of the planks of IT.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the plank you didn't go for.
Speaker 0: no, I did four classes in it.
Speaker 0: I just didn't concentrate in it.
Speaker 0: So I didn't take classes beyond it.
Speaker 1: Yeah What's weren't those classes?
Speaker 1: mostly joke classes where you?
Speaker 1: Had other people do tiny chat crap projects and VB and stuff like that?
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, no, those classes were the classes on like technology transfer and God, what was the other stupid class I took?
Speaker 0: I Could do a whole show on stupid classes I took.
Speaker 0: All right, some of these classes were really good though They'll do that Thursday.
Speaker 1: stupid classes from college.
Speaker 0: That's a good one All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.