Speaker 0: It's Monday July 3rd, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: It's just me and I talked a little bit about podcast promotion.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Well while Scott and the rest of the crew are still at the beach.
Speaker 0: I am back in Beacon.
Speaker 0: I had to leave the beach a day and a half early to come back and go to work on Monday even though I get Tomorrow Tuesday off, but I guess no big deal.
Speaker 0: I'll just you know catch up on paperwork that I've been avoiding for the past.
Speaker 0: I don't know two years because I never have time to do anything.
Speaker 0: But I gotta say and we'll talk about this more on Tuesday We had one hell of a time at the beach and a big part of that was that the wild the boardwalk in Wildwood Which is you know south of Atlantic City near the bottom of New Jersey.
Speaker 0: It's always been for as long as I've been going there a bastion of DDR.
Speaker 0: I mean there are just tons and tons of DDR machines and all the whole DDR culture is down there.
Speaker 0: I mean there used to be a third mix Korean machine.
Speaker 0: It was 25 cents for five songs.
Speaker 0: fourth mix pluses everything and over time every machine was upgraded to an eighth mix machine and it got to the point where there was nothing but eight in the eighth mix.
Speaker 0: and As that happened and we kind of lost interest in DDR and if we didn't play it so much anymore.
Speaker 0: Now we went to the beach a few weeks ago And there were no new machines other than you know the in the groove.
Speaker 0: two machines Which whatever this time it's been have only been a few weeks.
Speaker 0: We come back to the beach and there are at least ten DDR ninth mix machines the newest newest DDR.
Speaker 0: This is the dance dance revolution from Japan.
Speaker 0: It was shipped freshly to the United States.
Speaker 0: These were brand new machines.
Speaker 0: I'd never played on a brand new DDR machine in my life And I gotta say all of us our interest in DDR has been fully rekindled and we played until our feet hurt.
Speaker 0: Now also in addition to that I've noticed that the boardwalk seems to very slowly be getting bits of geek into it.
Speaker 0: I mean there's all this DDR and all the good arcade games.
Speaker 0: I mean Wildwood has some of the best arcades I've been to since I was a little kid and They have put an internet cafe with kind of a Starbucks in it.
Speaker 0: recently and just now as we were walking down the boardwalk We noticed an empty abandoned Well not abandoned but empty and being remodeled storefront And there's a big sign on the door.
Speaker 0: two of them that said the word noob and it was crossed off like, you know No noobs allowed.
Speaker 0: So intrigued we run up and we appear in the window and it appears to be some sort of LAN gaming place.
Speaker 0: I guess I was just surprised to see something.
Speaker 0: So nerdy as a LAN gaming place in the middle of a Generally, I don't really want to say lowbrow But yeah, it's kind of lowbrow boardwalk.
Speaker 0: and also on a completely unrelated note My wonderful girlfriend Emily has informed me a little while ago that she arm wrestled a sumo wrestler in Japan and Beat him.
Speaker 0: now, there are more pertinent details of that story that might make it sound more feasible.
Speaker 0: But the story as I have stated it is technically 100% true and I'm sticking to it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I'm sure you all remember when Scott was stuck doing the show by himself and it came to critical acclaim Mostly critical especially in the forums and part of that was due to the fact that he didn't know how to use all of the equipment.
Speaker 0: So we ended up just using his computer in his room, but being me.
Speaker 0: I'm in my room with all the equipment We normally do the show on.
Speaker 0: all I did was turn off his mic and it's funny.
Speaker 0: But while it's more difficult to do the show, I don't have anyone to play off of.
Speaker 0: I don't have anyone to point the conversation or help me keep us on some sort of track and also, you know Reading body language while you're talking to someone really makes it easier to speak.
Speaker 0: I have absolutely no feedback and anything here except for all the little blinking lights and LEDs.
Speaker 0: But I don't have to deal with him breathing puck coughing and popping into the microphone.
Speaker 0: So editing is going to be a piece of cake this time around and thus without further ado.
Speaker 0: I do have some news.
Speaker 0: Ted Stevens the Republican senator from Alaska has voted against net neutrality.
Speaker 0: now We've talked about net neutrality many times.
Speaker 0: I don't really think I need to go over it in detail But very briefly it is the idea that internet service providers like Comcast have the right to charge entities like Google or Yahoo or Microsoft or YouTube Or the privilege of allowing their content to get to Comcast subscribers.
Speaker 0: They want to leverage the fact that we have X million subscribers so Google you have to pay us for access to these people and it is just this terrible idea and No one I mean no one who knows anything about technology is for it.
Speaker 0: the only people who are for this in any way shape or form are the people in charge of the ISPs who stand to make a lot of money and the Congressman that they have bribed and I say the word bribe because it's straight-up bribery.
Speaker 0: They've given substantial sums to a number of members of the House and Senate and all of these people have come out overwhelmingly against network neutrality.
Speaker 0: now one person in particular in particular Ted Stevens.
Speaker 0: he Made an analogy as he tried to explain why he voted against it and I could paraphrase.
Speaker 0: I was going to just read what he said to all of you because the actual words he said were bad enough.
Speaker 0: Then I found some audio of him actually speaking and it's a thousand times worse.
Speaker 0: So let's roll some of that footage here And I do not believe that net neutrality is.
Speaker 0: this is something that Well, I would say this.
Speaker 2: I don't think anyone here has to find what net neutrality is and We've heard that we're slipping behind.
Speaker 2: this bill is designed to let us go ahead To expand the whole concept of communication And here we have this one situation where an enormous entities Want to use the internet for their purpose to save money for doing what they're doing now.
Speaker 2: They use FedEx they use that delivery services.
Speaker 2: They use the mail.
Speaker 2: They they deliver in other ways, but they want to deliver vast amounts of information over the internet.
Speaker 2: And again, the internet is not something that you just dump something on.
Speaker 2: it's not a big truck.
Speaker 2: It's a series of tubes And if you don't understand those tubes can be filled.
Speaker 2: and if they're filled when you put your message in it gets in line.
Speaker 2: It's going to be delayed by anyone that puts into that tube an enormous amounts of material Enormous amounts of material now.
Speaker 2: We have a separate Department of Defense.
Speaker 2: You know that.
Speaker 2: you know why?
Speaker 2: Because they have to have theirs delivered immediately.
Speaker 2: they can't afford getting delayed by other people.
Speaker 2: The security United States requires a separate net for defense.
Speaker 2: Now, I think these people are arguing whether they should be able to dump all that stuff on the internet ought to consider whether they Ought to build a system themselves.
Speaker 2: Maybe there is a place for a commercial net but it's not using what the consumers use every day.
Speaker 2: It's not using the messaging service that is essential.
Speaker 2: I think that this this small business It's essential to our operation of Families.
Speaker 0: the whole now.
Speaker 0: obviously that is just an excerpt and he did speak for about 10 minutes in total And one I don't begrudge his speech impediment because he is an 83 year old man.
Speaker 0: What bothers me is that he has no idea what he's talking about?
Speaker 0: Which I mean wouldn't be a big deal in and of itself.
Speaker 0: people are allowed to not know about things.
Speaker 0: They just have to deal with the consequences.
Speaker 0: I mean if you have a VCR and you don't know how to program the time you can't use the time shifting features of the VCR but that doesn't affect anyone else who does know how to use that technology.
Speaker 0: when a member of the Senate who is voting on and deciding Policy about technology doesn't know anything about the technology.
Speaker 0: He's legislating.
Speaker 0: I just find this to be a travesty and I'm really.
Speaker 0: I have almost no recourse.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is a senator from Alaska.
Speaker 0: from what I can gather from some cursory research I did he is one of the big old boy Badasses of the Senate and almost anything he wants he gets.
Speaker 0: but he comes out very strongly against network neutrality and yet he doesn't seem to even understand what an email is or What the internet is or how it works or why his analogy is almost entirely broken.
Speaker 0: and even if it even if you follow his analogy and Even if it were right, it's still wrong because the underlying technological problems that the analogy brings light brings to light are completely fabricated.
Speaker 0: There is absolutely no shortage of bandwidth in the world.
Speaker 0: The only people who say there is are the people who have a vested interest in making bandwidth a limited commodities that they can sell It for higher prices.
Speaker 0: Well, we all know what that music means.
Speaker 0: It means rim wanted to cop out and not talk too long about any given news.
Speaker 0: So that again the show early and go to bed thus with things of the day.
Speaker 0: now I was poking around on Google video looking for something weird and I found a really cute video of a kitten Falling to sleep and it was just one of the most adorable things I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: There was going to be my thing of the day until I discovered this.
Speaker 0: someone has made a video.
Speaker 0: It is basically 4chan the movie and the best way I can describe this is if Well many times in the past.
Speaker 0: We've tried to explain what 4chan is.
Speaker 0: 4chan is a site on the internet.
Speaker 0: I would consider it a couple steps below FARC.
Speaker 0: in terms of Mainstream ness it is definitely a little bit above the style project because there are non horrible things on it.
Speaker 0: If you watch this video all the way through I think you will have as good of an understanding of what 4chan is as Any human being could possibly have.
Speaker 0: it's definitely worth a watch though.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you now that it is not good.
Speaker 0: It is just informative.
Speaker 0: Now while I was driving back from the beach I thought long and hard about what I was going to do today's Scottless show on and I thought I had a brilliant idea.
Speaker 0: I was going to talk about philosophy and in very very detailed terms now my personal philosophy my feelings very specifically on solipsism and Basically all the things that I can't talk about easily on the show with Scott mostly because he disagrees Exactly 100%.
Speaker 0: for me.
Speaker 0: I mean you see you've listened to the show and we seem to agree on Most issues of technology and science and all that but when it comes to philosophy We are exactly diametrically opposed in every possible way.
Speaker 0: So I thought that would have been an interesting show, but then I realized that it's late.
Speaker 0: I'm lazy I'm also somewhat tired and my foot hurts.
Speaker 0: You can't really argue about philosophy Especially when you're alone when your foot hurts.
Speaker 0: so instead I'm gonna cop out.
Speaker 0: and actually I have another relevant topic that I thought of just now as I Was poking around on our side and looking at the people who've linked to geek nights in the past few days Podcasting in terms of PR and promotions, you know promos getting your podcast out there all that sort of thing now.
Speaker 0: This is especially relevant because for any of you who read the forums any regular basis or subscribe to the non Podcast feeds like the blog feed you can see that we've finally after how many months made promos.
Speaker 0: we actually recorded them almost two weeks ago, and I never had a chance to get around actually editing them together.
Speaker 0: and Today since I was home alone and I had nothing better to do I put together all of our podcast or all of our promos.
Speaker 0: now We had a bunch of funny ideas and we made a whole bunch of different Remixes.
Speaker 0: now you can just go and listen to.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna play them on the air or anything like that But I will say we have the basic promo.
Speaker 0: the basic promo blues brothers edition.
Speaker 0: the basic promo Spanish Inquisition edition.
Speaker 0: the basic promo blues brothers Spanish Inquisition mega mix and a completely unrelated promo where we talk about how doing promo sucks and I gotta say I mean geek nights has grown very large and we if you look at we have a graph that we've been generating over time of The average number of listeners based on the hits we get to the feed from unique IP addresses and all that.
Speaker 0: it's something that lips it or feed burner does for us and The growth rate has gone from being a linear relationship to an exponential one recently and we have a huge influx of new listeners.
Speaker 0: Despite this I mean it's even now we haven't really advertised much.
Speaker 0: We've put some flyers at some cons.
Speaker 0: We've started appearing on other podcasts.
Speaker 0: This is a very recent phenomenon and may world order in their upcoming episode or maybe the one after that is going to have a long Segment that Scott and I recorded and then they're going to argue with us.
Speaker 0: and also we appeared recently on geek speak Which is a fun awesome podcast and he pseudo interviewed us and basically Scott and I are on his entire show.
Speaker 0: It's really fun.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna link to it in the show notes.
Speaker 0: Definitely worth a listen Especially if you want to hear a whole bunch more about what we have to say about Anime cons and anime conventions and also his podcast is worth listening to even if we're not on it.
Speaker 0: But now we're going all out on the advertising.
Speaker 0: I mean we've got these promos.
Speaker 0: We're starting to get other people to play the promos.
Speaker 0: You may start hearing other promos from the podcast We listen to being played on geek nights.
Speaker 0: We're not sure exactly where we're going to fit that into the whole lineup of bits on the show.
Speaker 0: But I got to say recording a promo was a thousand times harder than anything.
Speaker 0: I've done for geek nights And in fact everything I've done for geek nights combined was easier than trying to record a promo because doing the show is easy.
Speaker 0: We just sit down and we do what we would have done even if there weren't any microphones here.
Speaker 0: I mean after the first 20 or 30 episodes We got it down to an art and we can just sit down Crank out an episode and then it takes me about two or three minutes worth of editing and post-production to throw it up Not counting up and code times obviously because my computer is very slow.
Speaker 0: the actual time I spend editing the podcast and Actually doing things to it as opposed to waiting for my computer to finish doing.
Speaker 0: it is less than five minutes at Absolute most unless we do a crazy episode with a whole bunch of whole bunch of audio feedback or anything funny like that.
Speaker 0: But the promo was different because we tried to.
Speaker 0: actually I think our best promo was the one where we didn't actually do anything.
Speaker 0: We just started recording and started complaining about promos And then I just cut out a section in the middle there and made it a promo.
Speaker 0: But as for the rest of them, we actually wrote them up script them out practice them a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: at some point I'm going to compile all of the takes we did and Put them in the forums for all of you who want to see the creative process of rim and Scott on geek nights.
Speaker 0: Now some people have suggested that we do that for shows as well And I'd love to do it except that we very often do very little in terms of pre-production and most of the recording would literally be silence followed by Scott saying I'm doing this news and then a five minutes later me saying Well, I'm doing this news.
Speaker 0: I don't have a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's one.
Speaker 0: Never mind like we don't other than picking what news we want to do and Picking what things the day we want.
Speaker 0: we do absolutely no planning anymore for the show.
Speaker 0: it's just live off the cuff, but we actually sat down and we wrote up the promo and we practiced it and we did it and It took like 10 takes to get it down and even then I think that it sounds kind of cheesy.
Speaker 0: Actually, the only part I like is the Spanish Inquisition part and the Blues Brothers part.
Speaker 0: I think those parts are good, but all the parts where we're actually just talking about our show I feel a little skeevy like a shill.
Speaker 0: I'm very used to I guess selling myself or promoting myself on an individual basis, you know applying for a job.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to sell myself to the company or going to a new convention.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to sell myself to the staffers as hey, I'm the kind of person you want on your staff.
Speaker 0: I'm the kind of person you want to be a guest or a panelist or in my professional life as selling myself as I'm the Person you want to come to.
Speaker 0: I'm the expert you want to give money to in order to get services.
Speaker 0: And if I could just walk around and sell geek nights on a one-to-one basis to every person in the world.
Speaker 0: I think I could do it pretty easily, but well not not in terms of getting them on listen But in terms of me doing it, I know what I'd say.
Speaker 0: I know how I'd approach people.
Speaker 0: when it comes to making a mass market advertisement like a podcast promo It's a whole different ballgame.
Speaker 0: The one thing that really got to me was that I at first we were trying to make an actual generic Promo like the kind of thing that would be a radio spot And I realized that this doesn't work so well in podcasting because it's a very inward-looking community.
Speaker 0: Podcasting isn't growing very quickly among people who don't already listen to podcasts.
Speaker 0: So when we make promos now But by and large the only people are going to play them are other podcasts with overlapping interests.
Speaker 0: So as a result the best we can do is poach listeners from other podcasts or get people to listen to more Podcasts.
Speaker 0: none of these promos are going to get people who don't listen to podcasts to listen to podcasts now.
Speaker 0: We've got a whole strategy on a way to get a whole bunch of new people into podcasting and that's going to involve.
Speaker 0: our show at Otacon will actually probably be talking to a lot of the Podcasters we know who will be attending Otacon to set up some sort of press packet or something.
Speaker 0: We're going to make sure that all the podcasts that are worth listening to that are present at Otacon are Well not on the panel, I mean no no not to be evil, but it's our panel and we're running it.
Speaker 0: But we're gonna make sure.
Speaker 0: we want to get the word out to all of these people at Otacon that they're anime Podcasts and there are geek podcasts and that by and large many of them are awesome.
Speaker 0: Not as awesome as geek nights possibly, but very awesome nonetheless.
Speaker 0: but the whole idea of promoting podcasts to non podcast listeners is something that I realized outside of events like that or Paying for press outside of the podcasting world.
Speaker 0: the podosphere I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's no word for it yet And anyone who actually says podosphere in a non-ironic way deserves to be shot.
Speaker 0: It's really a topic that I just can't bother with.
Speaker 0: I have no way to do it short of spending a bunch of money.
Speaker 0: So we copped out and we made our promos very much aiming toward people who already listen to podcasts.
Speaker 0: We're already geeks.
Speaker 0: We don't explain how RSS feeds work or how to get to our podcast other than you know URL and maybe a word about iTunes or a podcast directory.
Speaker 0: now Of course, I would love to get some feedback from all of you out there as to what are how good the promos are.
Speaker 0: Do you like them?
Speaker 0: are they?
Speaker 0: are they painful to listen to?
Speaker 0: are they too corny?
Speaker 0: Do they work?
Speaker 0: which ones are good?
Speaker 0: which ones are bad?
Speaker 0: I mean, we really don't know.
Speaker 0: I listen to all of them and I really I can't judge them objectively and I can't really judge them too subjectively either because I Have the bias one.
Speaker 0: I have the bias of anything I do is awesome But I also have the self-critical bias of everything I do sucks Which is great when I'm trying to write a paper and I go over it a thousand times, but I digress.
Speaker 0: Let me know what you think.
Speaker 0: are these promos good?
Speaker 0: would you play them?
Speaker 0: and we also have to figure out how we're going to deal with playing promos on our own show because I've noticed that most of the Podcast promo people out there who set up, you know promo exchanges.
Speaker 0: there's very much this idea that if you play a promo for someone it's understood that they will then play a promo for you and I don't like the idea of that.
Speaker 0: I would honestly only ever play a promo of podcast that I or Scott listened to or at least if we didn't listen to it If we would vouch for it being good.
Speaker 0: I really wouldn't feel comfortable playing a promo or in any way promoting something Just because that group or that person felt fit to promote me.
Speaker 0: now I'm wondering if as time goes on and we may be paying far fewer promos than people are playing of ours if there will be any negative Consequences of that or if anyone's going to get angry with us.
Speaker 0: But I don't really care other than an idle curiosity.
Speaker 0: honestly now of course would have been wonderful if we had somehow gotten a a writer or Someone who could just write ad copy for us to read.
Speaker 0: I mean that would have been fantastic.
Speaker 0: We're not very good at writing ad copy our.
Speaker 0: I mean You should see the extensive notes we took and all the trial and error we tried to come up with even a rudimentary promo and we actually recorded it once and it was just terrible.
Speaker 0: and I still have That original recording of our first attempt at a promo which may or may not see the light of day.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll make some sort of special geek nights outtake CD or episode someday in the future when we're really hurting for content.
Speaker 0: Now, of course another fun promotional activity.
Speaker 0: We're going to try to be doing soon will involve swag and merchandise since whenever classic bribe finishes all of the you know, finishing design work from his Site design and the logo contest and all that.
Speaker 0: we're going to start in short order making a pile of various t-shirts and posters and all that fun stuff and I have a feeling that we're going to give a lot of it away for free and in the very least we've said this before.
Speaker 0: But I can't stress enough that we're not going to sell any swag We make at least any time in the next several years at any sort of profit.
Speaker 0: Because the idea of someone wearing a shirt that has something on it That was something I did is so awesome to me that I don't need to make money off of the idea.
Speaker 0: seeing someone wearing a geek Night shirt would be just amazing enough on its own and like on Penn Penn Gillette.
Speaker 0: So show where he's talking about how he's got his new phone number for the podcast or the radio show and it spells out Penn And he's won't shut up about that.
Speaker 0: but anyway I'll cut this episode short mostly because I'm just kind of lazy and I want to go play some DS games and Hit them and go to bed.
Speaker 0: Also the fact that it's a billion degrees here and my air conditioner still can't keep up.
Speaker 0: if you hear any odd noise in the background That's because usually we I make the room really cold before we do a show and then we turn the air conditioner off and I open All of the doors in the back of my room to prevent the echoes from coming into the microphones.
Speaker 0: and today I wasn't gonna bother with that because then my room would have become an inferno in short order.
Speaker 0: Thus the air conditioners on full blast in the background the fans going in the background.
Speaker 0: Everything's were in a buzzin, but be sure to check us out on geek speak.
Speaker 0: Be sure to check us out on anime world order At some point.
Speaker 0: I'm going to appear on Friday night party line since Scott did at one point and while I've really wanted to be on the show and they've asked me to be on the show.
Speaker 0: I Haven't had time.
Speaker 0: I haven't been home and free Until just now.
Speaker 0: tomorrow is gonna be my first free day in a long long time And I'm still not quite sure what I'm going to do with it.
Speaker 0: I'd originally planned to climb the mountain or go on a crazy hike or something But all that DDR on the boardwalk kind of killed those aspirations.
Speaker 0: I I've either torn or pulled a tendon or something on my left foot and it's really smart right now.
Speaker 0: So be sure to join us tomorrow when we resume our normal broadcast schedule with Tuesday gaming day.
Speaker 0: I imagine we're gonna talk a lot about DDR and Dance Dance Revolution on the boardwalk and at home and all that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Also some house of the dead for some time crisis for.
Speaker 0: and of course one final note I would love it if there was some feedback into the forums as to which show was better the Scott show or the rim show.
Speaker 0: Because I got to say I know I've said this a bunch of times already But it really is odd to have just me talking into a microphone like this And I don't know if I'll ever get used to it.
Speaker 0: I mean I could read copy I could read a book or I could do something like that But speaking extemporaneously to no audience yet at the same time as being recorded is just something that I don't know If I could ever get used to doing on any regular basis.
Speaker 0: It's very difficult to keep myself on topic or more importantly it's very difficult to resist the urge to just edit out any stumbling I make or Like say every bit every paragraph every sentence three or four times pick the best one and then hobble together over the course of several Hours.
Speaker 0: an absolutely amazing podcast.
Speaker 0: luckily laziness very much Trump's will and thus I will see you or at least you'll hear me tomorrow.
Speaker 0: and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.