Speaker 0: It's Wednesday March 29th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about V for Vendetta the comic.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well happily.
Speaker 0: It's warm here again Hooray For a long run about long some abandoned train tracks near us.
Speaker 0: I changed my blanket last night Less warm blanket, and I finally didn't wear my coat to work.
Speaker 1: I brought my coat to work didn't wear it so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: I installed the beta of ie7 yesterday and And it's ie great.
Speaker 1: It has it has issues.
Speaker 1: It's like ie trying to catch up with Firefox.
Speaker 1: It's all I can say about it because I haven't used it that much except one thing is it renders pages still Incorrectly.
Speaker 1: it renders them differently from ie 5 and 6 But it doesn't render them as good as Firefox or correctly.
Speaker 1: so whatever.
Speaker 0: of course it still has that vulnerability.
Speaker 1: It sure does, but there are actually I think two Unofficial fixes for those some vulnerabilities today, so yeah put out by other companies.
Speaker 1: Yep, Microsoft sure isn't gonna put them out right away.
Speaker 1: anyway Microsoft is currently telling people they've known this for a while that ie7 is gonna render pages different.
Speaker 1: We know it does, but there was also that eolos patent.
Speaker 1: now if you weren't paying attention to this eolos patent Basically what it means is that ie?
Speaker 1: Is not allowed to do certain things because someone else has a patent on them.
Speaker 0: So this is a bad patent in general.
Speaker 1: It's a very bad patent.
Speaker 1: I disagree with it.
Speaker 0: I'm actually on Microsoft's side, but not only that but they're probably gonna go after Firefox and opera next after they finish with Microsoft.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, so this is far from over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the point of it is is that they got Microsoft and it means that ie7 is going to have to handle active X type Multimedia in the web page in a different way making you click one more time to see it.
Speaker 0: Yep, the patent is basically I mean the patent is fairly broad But the one bit of it that I know is that if you use active X or anything like that to use I believe it's applet embed and object those three things.
Speaker 0: It can't happen automatically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's stupidest patent in the world.
Speaker 1: It's really really dumb.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the point is that ie7 is going to not do what this patent says and whatever and Microsoft is pretty much telling everyone you only have X days to change all your web pages So they're not gonna work when we switch everyone to ie7.
Speaker 0: Oh my god And all the people out there who have web pages that'll be affected have no idea what the hell's going on.
Speaker 0: They don't understand this.
Speaker 1: Yeah only like, you know people really close to Microsoft are gonna, you know be told by Microsoft.
Speaker 1: They're gonna have to change Everyone else like even big companies, you know, all their customers are gonna get automatic windows updates.
Speaker 1: they're gonna have ie7 and they're gonna go to web pages with it and The web pages aren't gonna work, right?
Speaker 0: this is really gonna hurt a lot of small businesses who paid like some kid to make them a web presence a long time ago and They don't know how to fix it or change it.
Speaker 1: It's gonna hurt a lot of companies with a lot of video on their sites Like maybe even like CNN and stuff, you know, who knows.
Speaker 0: it'll also possibly hurt a lot of online stores That make heavy use of active X Anyone who uses Java applets a lot on their pages.
Speaker 0: Yep, which is really gonna affect the people I work for currently People who are selling a Java applet application.
Speaker 1: I know there's like an online office suite.
Speaker 1: That's basically a Java applet, you know, and they're not gonna do too well because whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess all you can really come away from this with if you don't already know what's going on or aren't very in-depth on The tech?
Speaker 0: is that one?
Speaker 0: the?
Speaker 0: the way the internet works in a small way is going to change which is going to be very Obvious and apparent to most people because it affects things that they use directly and often You know, there's nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 1: It's just weird that in Firefox I use an extension so that I make it so I have to click one more time To activate.
Speaker 0: that only came up because people use flash and that more for ads than for anything.
Speaker 1: That's what a lot of people are saying.
Speaker 1: is a lot of the people who are gonna be affected by this are people who make Ads and you know ads aren't gonna work.
Speaker 0: I disagree with the patent, but I'm fine with anything that hurts the advertisers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's gonna hurt the advertisers.
Speaker 1: The thing is the advertisers are the ones who are gonna lose a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Oh wait That's great.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh terrific.
Speaker 0: I mean people keep saying that content doesn't exist in a void that no one will make anything on the internet unless they can make money off of it and The fact that Scott and I are here right now With a pile of professional equipment doing a podcast on the air and paying for everything out of our pockets really kind of shoots That shit down.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I have to say it's true.
Speaker 1: As long as you're talking about people who were born.
Speaker 1: I don't know around 1957 Oh 58.
Speaker 1: Anyone born recently at least in the Western world Isn't an ass and will do shit for free because they like doing it?
Speaker 0: Submit that many people in the Western world are asses.
Speaker 1: they are but mostly the young people are not asses.
Speaker 0: I would disagree with that too.
Speaker 0: I'd say mostly the young geeks.
Speaker 0: We really got to narrow this down cuz.
Speaker 0: uh I would submit that most of the people I grew up with who went to high school with me Would not do anything like this ever.
Speaker 1: Well, they must like doing something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they would do what they like for free.
Speaker 0: You know what they're gonna do.
Speaker 0: They're all.
Speaker 0: they're all getting married and having kids and settling down and having terrible jobs and they're eventually go free baby factories.
Speaker 1: All right, let's move on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, uh, you're all.
Speaker 0: you all know that Apple has been sued by a bunch of people over hearing loss and the iPods.
Speaker 0: great.
Speaker 0: now I think this is bollocks absolute bollocks.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's fairly obvious that listening to music 24/7 on tiny little headphones really really loud can damage your ears.
Speaker 1: Well, the real damage doesn't come from listening to the music.
Speaker 1: It comes from too high decibels for too long a period of time.
Speaker 0: Well way comes from listening to it too loud.
Speaker 0: the problem is people often listen too loud because they don't realize it's too loud because they've turned it up to drown out all the Ambient noise around them.
Speaker 1: exactly the earbud headphones that come with the iPod.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with the iPod itself It's the headphones don't block out external noise.
Speaker 1: So if I wear them and a plane flies over I'll still hear the plane, but now I can't hear the music.
Speaker 1: So what I do?
Speaker 1: I make the music louder and now I can hear the music just fine.
Speaker 1: And I don't hear the plane, but I don't realize it's too loud You know.
Speaker 1: and that over time or very rapidly will destroy your hearing completely.
Speaker 0: so I guess in one way it is a matter of education, but While people should know about this and while I think a slight education campaign would probably solve this problem Straight up people decided instead to sue Apple.
Speaker 0: Yep, because it's obviously Apple's fault for making a product.
Speaker 0: Everyone loves.
Speaker 1: Yeah Man, you can't have an amplifier in the iPod that can be turned up pot.
Speaker 1: It can't possibly be turned up to a point at which it will hurt someone ears.
Speaker 1: Well, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: What if I plug it into a different speaker a different headphone and now it's not enough amplification because there's more resistance in that?
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus everyone's ears are different.
Speaker 1: Everyone's ears are different.
Speaker 0: Music is different.
Speaker 0: music might be quieter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well iTunes actually normalizes all.
Speaker 0: yeah iTunes.
Speaker 0: A lot of people don't use iTunes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know it's all crazy.
Speaker 1: So but anyway, you don't have to install it if you don't want to.
Speaker 0: Apple has responded to all this by adding an update to the new firmware and Basically what it does is it allows you to one set a maximum volume that it won't let you go past.
Speaker 0: So basically if you want to make it louder after you do this You have to go through one extra click and then you can make it louder.
Speaker 0: Okay, which I guess I'll remind you and to Parents or anyone really can lock the volume at a maximum And then the only way to make it go above that is to enter a pin Which is just ludicrous, that's just silly.
Speaker 0: I mean, honestly, the only real way to go about this is either to get isolation headphones, which are big and cost money Isolation earbuds which are little and cost even more money or active sound cancellation, which is little and cost even more money.
Speaker 1: Well, there's some noise cancelling headphones you can get that aren't so expensive.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get any of those things for 20 bucks or 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: You'll spend at least 80 bucks to get a decent pair of headphones that will let you listen to music for long periods of time Without damaging your hearing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I bought a hundred and like $20 Isolation 6i earbuds from Etymotic and they're fantastic.
Speaker 1: Like you put them in and you can't hear shit.
Speaker 1: All you can hear is what comes out of those headphones.
Speaker 1: It's fantastic and they're small.
Speaker 1: They come with a little case thing Well worth the money.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Am I?
Speaker 1: hearing is save Things of the day?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: This is a thing of the day in Spanish, but there aren't so many Spanish words.
Speaker 1: I think you'll be alright.
Speaker 1: It's las on the matapias.
Speaker 1: if you don't know what an onomatopoeia is It's one of those words that sounds like the sound wack.
Speaker 1: Yeah Specifically, these are the onomatopoeias from the old Batman TV show.
Speaker 0: You know the terrible one the Adam West live-action.
Speaker 1: terrible god-awful Corny.
Speaker 0: Honestly, I consider Adam West to be the second best Batman.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess so right after Michael Keaton.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean those are the Batman's weren't up to par and that man's Batman.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: I heard that the Batman Begins is pretty good.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen it yet though.
Speaker 0: Everyone keeps saying that maybe we should.
Speaker 1: maybe that's that'll become the second best Batman And Adam West will go down to number three.
Speaker 1: Anyway This website here has a picture of every single one of those BAM clank it crash plop slosh Etc.
Speaker 1: That was ever in the TV show?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: Not only that it also tells you which ones were used in which episodes including the movie and how many times Each one was used.
Speaker 0: So there are interesting Correlations down there.
Speaker 1: Yeah The number one most used one was kapow.
Speaker 1: It was used 50 times.
Speaker 1: How it comes in number two at 49 times and after that you get mostly Biff and BAM and Boff Never understood Biff.
Speaker 0: I mean that was in our River City Ransom - yeah, I don't know who came up with that.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's like a 70s thing or an 80s thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyone old listen to geek nights.
Speaker 0: word Biff come from.
Speaker 1: Yeah What thing?
Speaker 1: as far as I know Biff is some guy's name?
Speaker 0: Yeah some guy from Back to the Future.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I'm talking about All right.
Speaker 0: So I've had in the past two different things.
Speaker 0: the day that involved some form of marching band or drum corps or whatnot.
Speaker 0: Now my thing of the day today is the same kind of deal However, it's special and I think it warrants a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: mentioned now the video I linked to and from that site you can get a link to the whole documentary of which this is only a small part of it and Basically, it's as far as I'm concerned some of the most advanced field and dance or not really dancing but field drill work I've ever seen coupled with the most advanced Stadium full of people holding up cards in a synchronized way work.
Speaker 0: I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: it's absolutely amazing.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's so amazing.
Speaker 0: It's scary.
Speaker 1: It's very scary.
Speaker 0: you see this is from North Korea and this is a rally in North Korea and Watching this video and just seeing the absolute level of dedication precision If anyone has any doubts as to how absolutely a hundred percent mobilized and militarized North Korea is watch this video and watch this documentary.
Speaker 1: It just shows you what you know can happen when there aren't any fuckers and everyone goes along with what you try to tell them To do.
Speaker 0: yeah yet at the same time.
Speaker 0: It shows you how easily you can completely dominate an entire Civilization.
Speaker 1: what really scares me the most is that there are a lot of people in this country who?
Speaker 1: Would think that that's good?
Speaker 1: Like, you know if all their if they got their whole like elementary school full of kids to do that They'd be like, oh look everyone is so well behaved.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's wonderful.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess most people seem to think that North Korea at least most people I talk to around here Not so much the geeks but normal people I run into at work North Korea is this backwater country.
Speaker 0: That's all warlike and we can just ignore it.
Speaker 0: and they don't seem to realize that North Korea is a very industrialized modern nation.
Speaker 0: It just happens to be completely cut off from the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: the people there have no idea what the rest of the world is like and They're just ready for war all the time.
Speaker 1: and we don't really know a lot about what North Korea is like except for the stuff In this documentary.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there's very little that's actually known about North Korean culture.
Speaker 1: if you watch this documentary You'll know more about North Korea than most people outside of North Korea.
Speaker 0: I mean the only other thing is I forget what it was called.
Speaker 0: left to ask But Emily a while ago told me about a book Someone who was in North Korea for a while wrote and it describes a lot more about their culture.
Speaker 0: And if I remember it, I'll say it on another show or I'll post it.
Speaker 0: I'll post it in the forums.
Speaker 0: what I remember because it's really interesting and North Korea I'm fascinated and scared of at the same time.
Speaker 1: the scariest thing I think about North Korea Is that it's really less than a hundred years old.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean North Korea didn't really come into being until the Korean War when for those of you who don't know American history So well, we lost and basically got our asses handed to us and had to give up and the war never ended.
Speaker 0: In fact, the North Korean War technically is still going on because South Korea never signed the armistice.
Speaker 1: Yeah armistice.
Speaker 0: So technically they're at war.
Speaker 1: Imagine this like Hitler, right?
Speaker 1: He took like a decade or so to come around and do all his stuff He wanted to do right and he lost in the end.
Speaker 1: imagine if Hitler didn't try to take over all of Europe in the world and he just stayed in Germany and no one bothered him and He didn't bother anyone.
Speaker 1: and he just militarized and militarized and militarized and he did it for not ten years like or which is about The same amount of time he did have in real life, but for almost 50 years.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: That's North Korea Not cool.
Speaker 0: Anyway, watch the video and be amazed and shocked.
Speaker 0: So in light of the fact that the movie came out recently both Scott and I a very also recently read V for Vendetta.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I actually bought it a long time Well months ago and I read it then and I read it again like last week and then for the first time in like a few Years, he went to the movie theater.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It was actually kind of a scary experience.
Speaker 0: There were ads and there were normal people there in the way.
Speaker 1: It was quite frightening.
Speaker 1: 650 I remember used to be like 450.
Speaker 0: yeah 650 that's freaking great.
Speaker 0: in the city It's like 15 bucks for 650 I can get.
Speaker 0: Wow, I can get like you can't get so much really Dude, I could totally buy even ride the roller coaster in Wildwood once You can't even buy a meal at the diner.
Speaker 1: I Could play DDR 13 times on a 50-cent machine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, six and a half times I can play air hockey 13 times.
Speaker 0: Alright, you know, I would least contend that seeing V for Vendetta in the theater was worth that money.
Speaker 0: It was actually a very good movie, but we're not here today to talk about the movie because It's also a comic.
Speaker 0: In fact, the comic came first and we realized that we could talk about the movie comic combined for more than two hours at least.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean it's real big so it's not hard to talk about a whole lot.
Speaker 0: So I guess we'll start today being you know Anime manga comic day.
Speaker 0: a lot of times people seem to forget that that third part is on there.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk just about V for Vendetta the comic by Alan Moore and David Lloyd Mmm, David Lloyd's the artist and Alan Moore is the writer.
Speaker 0: Yes, Alan Moore.
Speaker 0: You may remember from Watchmen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he wrote that too, but the artist was different.
Speaker 1: Yep They're both available at the bookstore.
Speaker 1: Obviously at the comic book store, you can buy the whole things in one book.
Speaker 1: You don't have to buy a bunch of little separate comic books or anything like that Alright.
Speaker 1: so Sometime dirt at the beginning of this episode.
Speaker 1: We're gonna just talk about general stuff and then you're gonna hit the spoiler line and we will warn you.
Speaker 1: We'll let you know when the spoiler line is and that's the part where we'll start saying like what happened at the end and all That stuff.
Speaker 1: so if you haven't read it yet Just save this episode on your hard drive or whatever and listen up to that point.
Speaker 1: and When you go and buy it and read it because that's what you're gonna do You can come back and listen to the part beyond the spoiler line or if you don't care just keep listening.
Speaker 0: But regardless, we'll give you fair warning when we start to spoil things.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, if you don't plan to read it ever, you know might as well keep listening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least watch the movie before you listen to the spoiler parts here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because they'll probably mention something about that.
Speaker 0: We'll probably talking about the movie tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well two episodes kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: so V for Vendetta is a story about a Theoretical future Alternate future kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a very 1984 ish kind of future.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's more.
Speaker 1: It's more like an alternate present because it was like written in the 80s.
Speaker 1: So it's like what it could be like now if it could gone differently back then.
Speaker 0: Now the basic premise.
Speaker 0: well, there are a lot of ways to talk about the basic premise but plot wise in terms of what happens the basic premise is that there is a 1984 ish world order at least in Britain and there is a man who for various reasons seeks to undermine this world order and Through
Speaker 1: very very clever means sort of Hannibal ish in nature.
Speaker 0: I would say transhumanist I believe could be a term for this Because he's very.
Speaker 1: you know Hannibal is so smart that they can't get him and he does things in such incredibly clever ways that no one can possibly Stop him.
Speaker 0: but also in the sense that Hannibal wasn't entirely human.
Speaker 0: he had transcended some of the aspects that make a human human and Thus these is motives methods and means were alien to the humans who were trying to stop it.
Speaker 0: And actually V for Vendetta very much follows the same kind of transhumanist ideas along with all of the actual plot going on.
Speaker 0: I think if that's it that might be in there somewhere if it's in there very strongly in a point that I don't want to Talk about until the spoiler section.
Speaker 1: Oh you think it's in there strongly because I didn't see it so blatantly.
Speaker 0: I think it's in there strongly.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I didn't really realize it until the end when I don't want to spoil it now But we'll talk about it in the second now because for me I only saw like a little tiny spot where it might fit in well.
Speaker 0: I'll point out a scene later.
Speaker 0: all right But anyway aside from that aspect of it It's also based very much on the idea of Guy Fawkes.
Speaker 1: now if you're not from Albion you might not know who Guy Fawkes is.
Speaker 0: yeah in fact when we saw the movie they actually Showed the legend.
Speaker 1: well not the legend really but the story of the first thing in the movie was the story of Guy Fawkes for People who didn't already know it aka Americans yes, but we already knew it.
Speaker 1: so we kind of noticed.
Speaker 0: remember remember the 5th of November Mm-hmm?
Speaker 1: what had the story of Guy Fawkes?
Speaker 1: is that on November 5th?
Speaker 1: a long time ago This guy named Guy Fawkes and a bunch of his followers and a bunch of his followers were all anarchists of some stripe.
Speaker 1: Yep, they took Literally barrels of gunpowder, and they snuck them under the Parliament building in London And they were going to blow it up.
Speaker 0: And they were at least as far as history shows.
Speaker 0: they were caught at pretty much the last minute and stopped Like literally.
Speaker 1: these guys had gunpowder in barrels under the building And then the police or equivalent came in and stopped them.
Speaker 1: you know like shot him or well No, I think he was hanged shot him.
Speaker 0: No they didn't shoot him.
Speaker 1: yeah They got him.
Speaker 1: they were they.
Speaker 1: you notice the Parliament building is still in London.
Speaker 0: It's still there now that if you don't know anything about Guy Fawkes read up a bit before you read this comic because Guy Fawkes plays prevalently in this.
Speaker 0: it basically the.
Speaker 0: the comic begins with the bombing of Parliament.
Speaker 1: That's like the.
Speaker 1: Guy Fawkes is like the number one of all the ideas in this whole comic.
Speaker 1: Guy Fawkes is number one.
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 0: it's about Guy Fawkes Very much Guy Fawkes and the ideas behind him at least behind him from a from an external kind of academic perspective Because the actual Guy Fawkes his motives might have or probably a lot less They were now, but yeah, that's not the point.
Speaker 0: I don't think that Guy Fawkes had the same ideas in mind that V does.
Speaker 1: it's not about Guy Fawkes in a Biographical way it is about Guy Fawkes in An idea sort of way yes, but at least read the Wikipedia on Guy Fawkes.
Speaker 1: So well let's talk about the different characters in this thing.
Speaker 1: the the main character Pretty main.
Speaker 1: the main character even though it might not be from their point of view is V and He's this guy who wears a Guy Fawkes mask.
Speaker 0: well even if he's not the main character He is the motive force in the plot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 1: He wears a Guy Fawkes mask so you can't see his face.
Speaker 1: He has like a cape.
Speaker 1: he's sort of like a superhero, but he doesn't have any superpowers.
Speaker 0: He's a superhero in the same way that Batman is a superhero.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's just.
Speaker 1: he's just a badass dude and He goes about you know doing terrorist things in this sort of 1984 scary Super Fascist Britain.
Speaker 0: yeah And if you think that me telling you that he blows up parliament is a spoiler that happens on like the sixth page.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean the story starts with V and The other character you meet right away is this girl Evie, and she is poor and destitute and needs money And has decided to prostitute herself.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm, so she wanders out into the street breaking curfew to do this horrible thing She's never done before.
Speaker 0: you know prostitute for money and to make a long story short she runs into some.
Speaker 0: they call them finger men, but basically police.
Speaker 0: yeah and Police in this 1984 fascist society are quite horrible.
Speaker 1: I guess they're very horrible.
Speaker 0: They decide they're going to rape her and then kill her because according to the law That's what they can do whatever they want to her.
Speaker 0: they caught her.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's fascism.
Speaker 1: imagine if you know you snuck out In Germany at night and rent some SS guys.
Speaker 1: It's like that
Speaker 0: yep, so then suddenly a crazy guy and a guy fox mask spouting prose appears and in the blink of an eye he kills all of them or just about all of them and saves the girl
Speaker 1: mm-hmm
Speaker 0: and Shortly after that he takes her to a rooftop where he shows her the Parliament building.
Speaker 1: And then it explodes and he did it and he admits to it, and he's like look what I did we.
Speaker 0: That's one thing I really love about this book is how direct V is throughout the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I mean someone asked him like did you blow up that building?
Speaker 0: He's like yeah?
Speaker 0: Are you going to kill this person?
Speaker 0: Yes?
Speaker 0: Are you going to kill me?
Speaker 1: That's one thing that really sets this apart from pretty much everything else I've ever seen is is a guy in the mask.
Speaker 1: We the only thing that's really secret about him is what he looks like under there.
Speaker 1: everything else about him.
Speaker 1: He just he's just wide open.
Speaker 1: It's not like in a Gundam where there's a guy with a mask and he's all secretive and whoo There's no mystery to be.
Speaker 1: he's just like yeah, I blew it up.
Speaker 1: Yes, what I'm gonna Do?
Speaker 1: yeah, what you can do about it?
Speaker 0: I can't think of a time where he lies in the entire comic.
Speaker 1: No, he doesn't lie.
Speaker 0: if someone I mean there's like me There's a scene where he's with a person and the person literally asks him are you going to kill me?
Speaker 0: Yeah, he says yes Yep, hey, you can't get more direct than that He's.
Speaker 1: it's the total opposite of what's normally going on because you know he has the appearance The physical appearance of being mysterious and secretive yet is the exact opposite.
Speaker 1: It's as you see.
Speaker 1: this gets not like you know.
Speaker 1: sometimes There'll be the mysterious guy who doesn't say anything and you see him in the corner like in Half-life.
Speaker 1: you see the g-man.
Speaker 1: you know it's like there.
Speaker 1: He is he barely appears.
Speaker 1: He says some cryptic things.
Speaker 1: right this guy says a lot of prose, and it's you know you have to read it But it's actually very relevant.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of times you'll see a comic where you know someone quotes a long Quotation from something and you kind of just glaze over it or maybe you figure out what they're quoting and then you ignore it.
Speaker 0: It all really fits in well, and it's worth it to read every word in this comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it takes a long time to read this comic.
Speaker 0: relative to others I mean I mean I kind of blew through it But that's because I read it in a go right before we went to see the movie.
Speaker 0: I finished the comic and then 10 minutes later.
Speaker 0: We were in the car driving to the theater.
Speaker 0: So Evie basically she's probably the other main character.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you want to put the point of view somewhere It's it's Evie.
Speaker 1: That's you know.
Speaker 1: It's that's.
Speaker 1: the story is mostly not 100% But mostly from what she sees and what she hears and that's yeah the story is driven by V.
Speaker 0: It is it affects Evie and the only other real perspective you get is there.
Speaker 0: you know policemen and investigators dealing with all this and One of those investigators you follow his perspective around a lot too.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He's the guy There's the nose the finger the eyes whatever you know there's different government departments for each part of the face.
Speaker 1: I think it's eyes nose ears mouth I think that and the finger and this is the guy who works for the nose because the nose of the detectives They find out the information.
Speaker 1: So that's the guy that's.
Speaker 1: you're kind of with a little bit more than the other guys who are just you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think they're all the departments in the 1984 government.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a guy who's the head of the finger.
Speaker 1: the head of those are the guys.
Speaker 0: They're the head of each department you're following and one of those guys I guess he's the closest thing to a good guy because I mean right away.
Speaker 0: They say he's the villain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course, but in terms of a classical story from the side of the fascist government There's really only.
Speaker 0: the only good guy is the one detective who's trying to stop V the terrorist mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the head of the nose.
Speaker 1: What's his name?
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 0: Oh, I forget.
Speaker 0: actually it's funny, but I forgot almost all the characters names Constantly while reading it.
Speaker 0: yet that didn't seem to affect in any way my understanding of that.
Speaker 1: Some of that has in the comic has to do with the art because the art is sort of this.
Speaker 1: it looks like watercolors Almost you know, I think was printed in newspapers or not?
Speaker 1: a super high-quality man.
Speaker 0: Yes I mean the people's hair color changes and things change all the time and it's really hard to follow what's going on.
Speaker 1: If you just look at the picture, that's another reason I think it takes so long, you know as opposed to reading like a crap Marvel comic, you know Where everyone looks exactly the same as they did in the previous panel.
Speaker 0: But yet at the same time it had an interesting effect at least for me I mean while I was reading.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, I definitely like it.
Speaker 1: I'm just so yeah But I mean
Speaker 0: the interesting effect I noticed was that as I read the art was there but it was in the background of the text and I'd read the text and Instead of like the Watchmen as I read it I puzzled over every image and I looked in the background and I looked
Speaker 1: at all this stuff in the background of the watch.
Speaker 0: in This I was picturing all the action in my head and I was barely looking at the art.
Speaker 0: The art was just like a backdrop for what I was thinking.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I mean it's important because sometimes they'll make like an important frame or two Where there's something like symbolic like.
Speaker 1: you'll see him because you know guy the guy Fox mask always looks the same no matter what It's like.
Speaker 1: they'll always zoom in on his face and you'll you know at the like the perfect time and he'll be smiling because the mask Is smiling even though that doesn't fit with what's going on?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like ooh, they'll just use that a lot And they'll use some other visual things here and there, you know, especially when stuff's blowing up Or when people are dying and such.
Speaker 0: now the basic conflict.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is the thing that everyone who reviews this seems to say but it seems to be mostly true that The basic conflict in V for Vendetta is between the forces of anarchy and the forces of fascism.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: This is to the two most extreme Ideas and put them in direct direct conflict.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: It's actually much more subtle and varied than that.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's more to it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but I mean to say I mean saying I was making a broad statement like that doesn't really do justice to the comic.
Speaker 1: No, well, I mean that's one of the things it's about being such a. you know A bit you can make one little comic that you know Like a normal-sized comic book about anarchy versus fascism and that's all you would need.
Speaker 1: but it's so big.
Speaker 1: So that's just one of the things in it.
Speaker 0: You know anarchy versus fascism was the way it seems to go.
Speaker 0: is that not anarchy in the sense of you know, chaotic No government crazy anarchy, but more in the sense of self-determination that people should make whatever drama they're gonna make on their own and not let a government or Authority make that drama for them and stifle their own lives?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not the anarchy that you know, people seem to think when you say anarchy Which means everyone run around doing whatever they want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably not the anarchy the actual guy Fox wanted.
Speaker 1: No, it's the anarchy that you know, people who call themselves Anarchists will say can actually exist.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of thing which I'm still.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it can exist or can't but that's That's a Thursday episode there But that's it.
Speaker 1: that's what they're talking about in the book.
Speaker 1: is the anarchy that people who call themselves anarchists talk about?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and basically just the idea that Authority and fascism or any sort of authority that has its power Not through the will of the people but through the will of but through force itself Really can never do good no matter how good the intent is.
Speaker 0: by stifling people's freedom You take away everything and nothing else matters.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It's a testament to one thing it's a testament to the idea that freedom is the most important thing that can ever be had the free or die and Never said live for your diet anywhere in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it makes a lot of other very quotable quotes.
Speaker 1: Oh, it sure does.
Speaker 0: This is quite a quotable comic.
Speaker 1: I also think it has to do with the fact it's it's British and it seems to Call upon like history of Europe and it doesn't travel over to America at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which we're fine with.
Speaker 0: but honestly if you don't know much about British history at all I suggest you brush up a little before you read this.
Speaker 1: Yeah and brush up on important buildings in London So you'll know which ones they're talking about.
Speaker 0: at least that's not too important because they I mean, you'll know Oh, that's obviously an important building or I'm sure everyone knows what Big Ben is.
Speaker 1: Well, but you know, you want to know what Big Ben sounds like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some people don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but as soon as you know as soon as you hear a wave of what Big Ben sounds like you'd be like Oh, I've heard that I get it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, like they'll show pictures in the comic of different buildings and things and it.
Speaker 1: they'll like go to them or you know You'll want to know like sort of how close they are to each other.
Speaker 1: that can sometimes help you out.
Speaker 0: Now there's one thing that kind of bothered me about it.
Speaker 0: Not about the story.
Speaker 0: This is a very meta observation.
Speaker 0: but in reading the comic there are a few characters who speak in either cockney or Like thick Welsh accents.
Speaker 1: Yeah, is that one gangster, dude?
Speaker 0: I had no idea what the hell that guy was saying.
Speaker 1: Either you're not alone.
Speaker 0: I mean the way they wrote.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna even dig through.
Speaker 1: I'm holding the comic in my hand Like the three-quarters of the way through that guy.
Speaker 0: but the way they write a cockney accent and I think it was on purpose you Really can't understand what he's saying.
Speaker 0: Even if you sit there and puzzle over it.
Speaker 0: It's just it's not.
Speaker 1: well No, if I read it slow enough, I can tell what.
Speaker 0: yes, if you read it that slowly though It's just not worth it at that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just get that I got the general idea of what he's saying because it's really not that important and there's only like one or two people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder if that was intentional.
Speaker 0: I mean, I wonder if Alan Moore realized that it's almost impossible to read that with any speed.
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: Maybe British people can read it.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what.
Speaker 0: we've got several Albion ish listeners out there.
Speaker 0: So if you've read V for Vendetta, we just have a simple question Can you understand easily what they were writing there?
Speaker 1: Maybe they can who knows?
Speaker 1: I mean think about this if someone writes a comic where people have a southern accent or or A Minnesota accent, can we tell what they're writing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean it depends on how it's written.
Speaker 1: I sometimes I can and sometimes I can.
Speaker 0: I've seen Cockney and Welsh and things like that Represented by other authors in other ways and I've usually been able to read it and it seems like just the way it was Done that the letters that were used in this representation of it.
Speaker 0: We're just very difficult to parse.
Speaker 0: You take a bunch of comics and you put them in spine.
Speaker 0: speech bubbles Get in.
Speaker 0: We be no offense to all the Welshman out there, but yeah whales is actually cool.
Speaker 1: They got a dragon on their flag.
Speaker 1: Yeah that haha, you know, I'll trade flags.
Speaker 1: Sorry Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: We're gonna put the spoiler line here.
Speaker 1: I think we put the spoiler line here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it's about time.
Speaker 0: So from this moment on in this current episode if you don't want V for V for Vendetta to be spoiled You should probably stop listening right now.
Speaker 1: All right, so let's summarize the whole comic.
Speaker 0: All right Obviously everyone who's still with us has read V for Vendetta or at least seen the movie or doesn't care and if you don't care You might be a little lost.
Speaker 1: All right, so starts out.
Speaker 1: He blows up Parliament and You have the book so I forget exactly what.
Speaker 1: next the second chapter starts with that music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then he starts murdering Everyone who worked at Larkhill, which was basically a concentration camp, right?
Speaker 1: So V is this guy who we don't know his past and he doesn't remember it either.
Speaker 1: But he remembers when he was at the concentration camp.
Speaker 1: Basically, they were doing medical experiments and he was a guy who during the medical experiments didn't die Like everyone else did if he was weird.
Speaker 1: He was a weird case and he was in cell number five.
Speaker 0: He was like whoa Roman numeral five V.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of V's in here a lot of V's.
Speaker 0: Yes, and it may you may not notice it in the comic itself but when you watch the movie they take some lines from the comic and put him in the movie and I don't think I've ever heard a man use that many words that start with the letter V in one cohen I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I wasn't sure when he was saying that I was like all that fits.
Speaker 1: But when he was saying that in the movie all those words with V's was that actually in the comic?
Speaker 0: I don't think it was in the comic word for word Notice it but very similar lines were all over the place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it also talked about that tomorrow Movie stuff anyway.
Speaker 1: so he begins killing all the people who worked at this concentration camp who are now all about society, you know.
Speaker 1: and Killing some of them has special effects Like the government has this computer called fate which is basically the thing that runs the government.
Speaker 1: It makes all the decisions and handles all the logistics of the fascists.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's also the only plot thing in the comic that I didn't like and I didn't really think needed to be there.
Speaker 1: Oh, I liked it anyway.
Speaker 1: And Of course the guy who is like the the king.
Speaker 1: what do they actually call him in the book?
Speaker 0: the leader?
Speaker 1: the leader, right?
Speaker 1: He is the one who uses the computer and he's actually sort of in love with it like Actually, yeah It's this whole side plot.
Speaker 1: like the leader of the country is a complete virgin and he's he actually says things like I don't I've never had any loins, but I don't need any because I got you my wonderful computer fate.
Speaker 1: So the first guy he kills is the voice of fate.
Speaker 1: He's basically this guy who goes on the radio like on every few hours a day and gives the news.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't think we need to summarize the whole comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm not everyone here because you I think you're.
Speaker 0: so far you're some.
Speaker 0: you've summarized almost nothing and if you go through it You're going.
Speaker 0: we're gonna summarize the whole comic over the next 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let me try to pick it up.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think we can just summarize the basic plot points.
Speaker 0: He kills all of these people who worked at the concentration camp
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: and then he continues to enact his terrorism and the people start to take notice and he basically Not directly, but indirectly leads the revolution that brings about the downfall of all authority
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm
Speaker 0: to put it very succinctly.
Speaker 1: Yeah now Evie the second character She starts out, you know almost getting raped by the finger men and then V saves her and brings him to her brings her To his hideout.
Speaker 0: now, she is definitely presented as a very weak character.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean physically emotionally mentally She is just weak and that over the course of the book.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's the point at which V Actually tortures her for a good while and this is the first transhumanist.
Speaker 0: Well other than the obvious V transhumanism bit that I noticed that basically, you know I mean, you know he tortured her and he put her through all that and then she comes out and she realized that it was him and Then she goes up onto the roof and I believe the word she uses is trend figures.
Speaker 0: she transcends the the fear and the pain and all those all those useless or dangerous emotions and Basically transcends an aspect of humanity the same way that V had.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Well and as a result of this transcendence, she basically becomes V's protege Follower disciple what-have-you and I mean she becomes the one who actually enacts his plan at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean at the end, you know after up V dies dun-dun-dun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a spoiler line.
Speaker 1: I can say that She actually becomes V after he's dead and then picks up a new person to be, you know her protege.
Speaker 0: It's like, ah Yep, and I thought it was really interesting Was really like.
Speaker 1: it's not what you I expected at all.
Speaker 0: like now the detective surprisingly enough the good detective the one who was actually trying to find the truth and Trying to stop V just because V was a killer.
Speaker 0: Yeah the nose guy he Transcends in a different way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he ends up going to the concentration camp after all his detective thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just like in in all the Hannibal movies when in order to catch Hannibal you have to think like Hannibal and become Hannibal.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because the only way to catch a trans humanist is to become a trans humanist.
Speaker 1: and he was like.
Speaker 1: he even said like I'm gonna Have to know this guy and it scares the hell out.
Speaker 0: I love how they did this.
Speaker 0: He actually I mean he actually went to the concentration camp.
Speaker 0: He did a bunch of LSD took LSD and he basically went insane and mentally went through everything that V went through and Then he realized what V was up to and he caught him fair and square.
Speaker 1: He went right back down.
Speaker 1: He's like, I know where the hell you are now.
Speaker 1: I got you and then he shot him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is V definitely definitely I don't think there's any argument that V could have stopped him and wanted him to shoot him.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah He definitely wanted him to wanted to get shot.
Speaker 1: He knew it was gonna happen.
Speaker 1: He like if you read it, it feels like V is expecting this guy to show up.
Speaker 1: He's like there you are.
Speaker 1: I was waiting for you.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: What I liked is I see two very real Effects of this.
Speaker 0: is that one?
Speaker 0: the guy who shoots him is very reliable as far as the government's concerned.
Speaker 0: So when he goes back and reports to his superiors, no hey, I shot the terrorist I shot V they all believe in and they report to the people that V is dead.
Speaker 0: and Then when Evie appears in V's outfit and continues what he was doing.
Speaker 0: That's just like the final blow to the government.
Speaker 1: Yep, definitely.
Speaker 0: I thought that was very well done.
Speaker 1: It seems like everything that V does is always like Planned and it seems at first like it has this side effect in the government, you know, and the government guys You know are now acting like in a. you know It's like V does something and then the government guys start acting in a different way.
Speaker 1: But really they're totally his like puppets like he's so far above them that he can just you know control everything they're doing.
Speaker 1: and actually he has a Computer link to the fake computer which is revealed towards the end.
Speaker 1: and so he actually is, you know Not only is he controlling all the government guys.
Speaker 1: He's really controlling everything, you know, it's like oh The guy who's actually been running everything for like 20 years is the guy who's against the government.
Speaker 1: It's like kind of weird.
Speaker 0: See it's a lot in a lot of ways and I actually thought this a little bit.
Speaker 0: the movie goes into it a lot more Because the movie just brings this up straight up and it's not mentioned in the comic but the Count of Monte Cristo Edmund Denn and how.
Speaker 0: it's the same type of.
Speaker 0: that's the same type of story in the sense of the guy comes back for revenge and various other things and He plans everything perfectly and everything goes off without a hitch from beginning to end like the whole thing was just Domino's ready to be knocked over.
Speaker 1: Yep, which they have a nice little domino metaphor.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the movie and in the comic.
Speaker 1: Oh the dominoes in the movie were so much cooler Much.
Speaker 0: we'll talk about that, especially when the dominoes come back later in one scene and you go.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh Now one thing I really liked was that they never they in this kind of book where there's a guy with a mask You always expect at the end.
Speaker 0: They rip the guy's mask off and you see who it really was Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: The fact that they never take these masks off.
Speaker 0: It's just fantastic.
Speaker 1: Well, no see here's the thing if you just made a story about a mask guy and you didn't take the mask off and you Said woohoo.
Speaker 1: I'm different.
Speaker 1: We didn't take the mask off in this one.
Speaker 1: Ooh, that's you know, it's like okay you tried to not take the mask off.
Speaker 1: The point is is that not taking the mask off actually meant something?
Speaker 0: Yeah In fact, I would submit that it didn't matter at all.
Speaker 0: And the fact that it wasn't taken off and the fact that by the time I got to the end I didn't care that the mask wasn't taken off I didn't care either because there really isn't much to know.
Speaker 1: It's like it's a disfigured face.
Speaker 1: Probably, you know Well, my
Speaker 0: my favorite scene of all that is after V's dead He's laying there and Evie's standing over his body and the comic shows her reach over and take the mask off And there's some guy's face there and then it backs up and you realize no that was just her imagining in her head.
Speaker 0: She didn't do it yet.
Speaker 1: And then it was not some guy.
Speaker 1: the face that she sees is the face of I think Gordon or Yeah, but I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying very generally it shows a face it shows a face and then it shows it again and it's a different face and Then finally it shows again that she realizes she pulls it off multiple times and keeps seeing different faces Because she hasn't actually pulled it off.
Speaker 0: and she doesn't pull it off and she realizes that it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Yep, it really doesn't it doesn't even matter to the reader.
Speaker 1: I mean It's like when I usually see like a Gundam when you watch a Gundam It's the mask guy.
Speaker 1: all you want is for the mass to come off because it's a mysterious guy and you want the mystery revealed.
Speaker 0: God got him seed did that to the point where at one scene he's got the mask off but his back is turned and he starts to turn around to look at you and then there's like a Conveniently placed thing and you don't see it and it's like ah, ah, don't do that.
Speaker 1: That's because there's something you know.
Speaker 1: The way that those things are designed is to.
Speaker 1: the reader wants to know more.
Speaker 1: They need to know more.
Speaker 1: it is actually important as to who that guy is and what he looks like is Important to the plot in the story here.
Speaker 1: It has nothing to do with it.
Speaker 1: It.
Speaker 0: you know the mask is his face for all intents and purposes and in fact They even go into that in the story itself in a very cool way.
Speaker 0: when detective catches him and they're standing there and he shoots V Over and over and over he shoots him dead and V ignores it and just walks over to him and he says right here Here's the line.
Speaker 0: Did you think you could kill me?
Speaker 0: There's no flesh or blood within this cloak to kill.
Speaker 0: There's only an idea and ideas are bulletproof.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he said that in the movie, too Yep, and then he walks away and then he dies later.
Speaker 0: But his idea lives on because Evie realizes what he was trying to do and assumes his mantle Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: now one aspect of the comic that I really liked was the kind of political message the very simple.
Speaker 0: I don't remember if this quotes in the book entirely, but it's definitely in the movie, but it was the quote that Governments or people should not be afraid of their governments.
Speaker 0: Governments should be afraid of their people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I don't think that was actually in the comic, but the comic did have what was it?
Speaker 1: Very veachy something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the five of you quote.
Speaker 1: Yeah the v-quote.
Speaker 1: Yeah one definitely There's this idea that self-determination and self-rule Yeah, that was one line that was in the comic a lot of times.
Speaker 1: That was not in the movie at all was do what thou wilt Aleister Crowley.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: I mean it's all about.
Speaker 1: you know you had this fascist government that doesn't let you do anything.
Speaker 0: And he's trying to say do what thou wilt shall be the law of the land blah blah blah Yeah, and he keeps referring to a fairy tale of the land of do whatever you want mm-hmm and various ideas about that.
Speaker 0: I mean he goes into a lot of the ideas of what anarchy really is.
Speaker 0: Transhumanism plays a very crucial role in this book.
Speaker 0: the political ideas of not letting your government control you unwillingly Obviously.
Speaker 0: the fascism is bad idea.
Speaker 0: The fact that unmitigated anarchy is just as bad because it's not actually anarchy, but chaos.
Speaker 0: I've in fact.
Speaker 0: I believe he says exactly that.
Speaker 0: I forget where.
Speaker 1: yeah, there was a point at which the people start rioting and going crazy and Evie is like is this the anarchy you wanted.
Speaker 1: He's like no this isn't anarchy.
Speaker 1: This is just chaos You know and he's like anarchy.
Speaker 1: is the world without government not a world without order?
Speaker 0: yep, and he basically says I did this so that the people would have the chance to either Create a new thing or destroy the last thing they have.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm all right all in all because once again.
Speaker 0: We've talked for a while, and I know it's been a little rambly But once again we could talk forever.
Speaker 0: This is a very good comic.
Speaker 0: if you haven't read the watchmen read it.
Speaker 0: if you haven't read V Read it like.
Speaker 1: even if you're not a person who reads comic books like I know some people are.
Speaker 0: I mean It's anime day.
Speaker 0: most of you who listen to this day listen for the anime.
Speaker 0: We don't have so many fans who actually like the comic books.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's plenty of comic book podcasts that are better than we are anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah But even if you don't read comic books you should read this.
Speaker 0: don't consider V or watchmen to be comic books.
Speaker 0: consider them to Be literature.
Speaker 0: well they are litters yes I mean, but like consider them that way think of them as something erudite that you will learn a lot from.
Speaker 1: Just like reading a classic novel only two happens to have pictures.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not for children like some illustrated You know c-spot run book.
Speaker 0: I just can't recommend these two comics enough Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean no matter how crazy this Alan Moore guy is I think we had a news about how crazy It was the other day or at least how crazy he looks.
Speaker 1: Oh, it looks crazy.
Speaker 1: He's got to be a little bit crazy Rasputin.
Speaker 1: anyone who makes good art is always crazy.
Speaker 0: He is the excellentist writer of comic books and actually you won't often hear me say that the movie Representation of a book is good.
Speaker 0: But also, and we'll talk about it tomorrow in fairly great detail probably in more in greater detail because now we'll be able to talk about comparisons between the two.
Speaker 0: Watch the movie.
Speaker 0: the movie in my opinion was very well done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as well done as it could be to have been released in America.
Speaker 1: It's not a maybe I mean yeah.
Speaker 0: the movie softened some of the edges of the comic But I can see why they did it mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I can see why it's just a lot of the wise You know.
Speaker 1: yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah, the one thing is that that fate computer subplot is completely missing from the movie Which I'm fine with because I thought it was kind of dumb to begin with.
Speaker 1: I guess The one thing I could definitely say the movie is worth watching and is definitely at least good in the book of Scott But I don't know if it's worth the 650.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's definitely worth seeing in the theater I think.
Speaker 0: keep in mind that in addition to this being just I mean the book and the movie are very good and very deep.
Speaker 0: However in the movie I mean in both of them There are various scenes where V is just killing people with knives.
Speaker 0: I like that in the movie, but it's done by the matrix guys.
Speaker 0: Yep the the knife fighting scenes are Very good knife fighting scenes.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah They're probably some of the best knife fighting scenes that have been in a movie in a long time.
Speaker 1: I say if you for the knife fighting scenes alone.
Speaker 1: I would pay $2.
Speaker 0: Alright, we're almost at the 650.
Speaker 1: Yeah, almost there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we're out.
Speaker 0: look tomorrow to hear us talk about the movie which we're gonna record in five minutes And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-15 37.
Speaker 0: geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.