Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Tuesday July 25th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about the Nintendo classic semi classic Advance Wars.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Not moments ago.
Speaker 0: I braved almost certain death to bravely fight a small tiny nest of paper wasps.
Speaker 1: You know I don't think you would have died even if they all stung you in the eye.
Speaker 0: You know what though that would have hurt a lot, and I really don't like it when things hurt.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, and how do you?
Speaker 1: how are you a hundred percent sure they were paper wasps?
Speaker 1: They could have been any kind of wasps actually.
Speaker 0: no I did a bunch of research at work because I really didn't have much to do today And I learned all the differences between wasps yellow jackets Hornets bees bumble bees and various other nefarious stinging bits and The main thing I learned is that the things that were living on our deck were almost certainly paper wasps.
Speaker 1: and what kind of?
Speaker 1: Characteristics of paper wasps makes you believe that that's what they were.
Speaker 0: one.
Speaker 0: They looked exactly like the pictures on the websites.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh - their nest looked exactly like the picture of the nest that a paper wasp makes which is very different from a hornet's nest Hornet's net.
Speaker 0: you see how to head out all those open exposed cells, and it was made out of that papery stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep, the hornet's nest have this whooshing kind of paper, and it looks completely different.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh and a lot of yellow jackets live in the ground.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hate it.
Speaker 1: in my yard at home my parents house a lot of bugs that live in holes in the ground.
Speaker 1: We'd have to fill them up or spray poison down there with the hose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there will be pictures in the form of this because I got one crappy picture.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: see I remember I'm about to go and Scott says I'm recording and then I fought the bees and then Scott says oh, I wasn't recording.
Speaker 1: That's what I get for using trying to use a digital photo camera.
Speaker 1: Try to use the video feature on it, which is not the greatest.
Speaker 1: And I didn't.
Speaker 1: it wasn't enabled even though I thought it was.
Speaker 1: it wasn't recording when I thought it was and it just wasn't good.
Speaker 0: But I did take one or two photographs so which were worth it because I wasn't afraid of Actually dying or being hurt because I'm pretty sure I'm not allergic to any of these sorts of stings.
Speaker 0: I just didn't want to feel any pain and Originally my plan was I'll buy the most dangerous poison I can buy without a license or any special permission or training and I was gonna follow the instructions and spray down this nest now.
Speaker 0: I didn't even want to get rid of the nest.
Speaker 0: I was fine with it there because they hadn't bothered us at all.
Speaker 0: but in my research I learned that wasps of that kind will as the summer goes on toward fall get more and more aggressive as they forage and Considering that they were on our deck in a place we frequent it would have been a bad idea to let that nest get any Bigger.
Speaker 1: well, it's dead now.
Speaker 0: Oh it is dead.
Speaker 0: I filled it so full of poison.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I destroyed it with the hose, but I didn't want to get stung and every single website I read said you will get stung If you try to take one of these down.
Speaker 1: so screw those websites.
Speaker 1: They're all written by idiots who got didn't get still.
Speaker 0: a bunch of them came at me and before they died Yeah, I felt at least one of them bounce off my trench coat.
Speaker 0: you see I put on armor I put on blue jeans and a shirt, and then I put my old trench coat on which unlike my new wonderful one that Emily and her family gave me the old one is filled with the Wax and decay of many many years of rim wearing it in all weather.
Speaker 0: It is basically armor, and I suit it up, and I put gloves on and over my head.
Speaker 0: I had a veil tucked into my neck made out of my.
Speaker 1: It was just a mesh laundry bag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what I it worked pretty well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least it didn't.
Speaker 0: I didn't die or anything better than nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I didn't want to risk one stabbing me in the eye.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right, so there are two things I just want to Pay note to real quick that it seems that no one in the else in the universe noticed including me.
Speaker 1: Yesterday was the one hundred and fiftieth episode of geek nights which hooray for arbitrary numbers Whatever.
Speaker 0: well the thing is it's hard to say because one.
Speaker 0: there was one slight Inconsistency in our numbering way back To.
Speaker 0: we started with episode one but then the next day we uploaded an episode from the previous day art which became our very first episode and I gave that the number zero.
Speaker 0: and There are a bunch of episodes.
Speaker 0: We made before we had a website.
Speaker 1: Well, here's how I counted you ready the Odeo which is what we were going to talk about.
Speaker 1: next is They have a thing that tells you how many episodes there are and in their list they had every single episode.
Speaker 1: that is on our Website.
Speaker 1: that is listed in the blog.
Speaker 1: so not counting the beta alpha episodes of geek nights.
Speaker 1: there were 150 of them as of yesterday.
Speaker 0: all right cuz Yahoo gives a different number and feed But no one.
Speaker 0: nothing gives the right number.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I checked Odeo had the right number.
Speaker 0: all right, okay?
Speaker 1: Also, people don't seem to notice that this past Saturday Was the 10th anniversary of the Daily Show.
Speaker 0: don't you feel old?
Speaker 0: don't you feel real old?
Speaker 1: Here's something to make you feel older that other guy Craig.
Speaker 0: What's-his-face Kilborn?
Speaker 1: He was only on the show for three years.
Speaker 1: Jon Stewart has been on the show for seven years now.
Speaker 0: the thing is not only do I remember the very First episode of the Daily Show because I watched it and I wasn't it on the same Night as the first episode of South Park.
Speaker 1: It was like right around the same time.
Speaker 0: all I know is that I was at band camp right and Someone we had said cuz someone was a senior in that a car, and they snuck out at night drove back home Which is like a two-hour drive?
Speaker 0: They went to their parents house who had taped both shows for them Drove back, and it was like this was like three days after it actually aired.
Speaker 0: We eventually got this tape and we watched South Park and a bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 0: whoa yeah But I remember when Craig Kilborn was gonna leave the show and I thought all right.
Speaker 0: That's the end of the show.
Speaker 0: Who's this?
Speaker 0: Jon Stewart guy?
Speaker 0: I didn't know he was actually famous from other stuff.
Speaker 0: I didn't know he did anything yep, and I thought the show was gonna be stupid.
Speaker 0: and after about five minutes I realized that Craig Kilborn was nothing to me, so everyone write it down.
Speaker 1: three years from now in 2009 on July 22nd, that's the 10th anniversary of the Daily Show with Jon Stewart.
Speaker 0: now I wonder how many of our younger listeners don't even know who Craig Kilborn is.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: We seem to be really detached from that sort of pop culture thing, so I'm sure that they know better than we do.
Speaker 0: I don't know because it seems like Comedy Central stuff seems to be a lot more Hip to the geeks because all the clips that are relevant are on YouTube anyway.
Speaker 1: Yep, okay, and last thing is the Odeo thing.
Speaker 1: for anyone doesn't know Odeo is a website that lets you handle podcast making and Listening and all sorts of audio.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's an okay website.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Point is is that if you go to frontrowcrew.com down in the bottom right side of the page way at the bottom on the right There is a link that says send me an Odeo.
Speaker 1: now There is also a link above that way above that that says like just Odeo That's not the one you want.
Speaker 1: you want the one in the bottom below the frapper link and oh yeah You should do the frapper map thing if you haven't already and if you click on that It will take you to a web page where you can send us an Odeo.
Speaker 1: this means you plug a microphone into your computer and this little flash program runs in your browser and it's dead simple to record a message and then click send and We will get that message in mp3 format to play on the show.
Speaker 1: So that's the easiest way now for to send us voicemail is to click on that.
Speaker 1: Send me an Odeo link in the bottom right hand corner of the page.
Speaker 0: now Here are rims fantastic hints for how to get us to actually play what you send us.
Speaker 0: one.
Speaker 0: Keep it less than like four or five minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, four or five minutes is pretty long.
Speaker 1: I mean other podcasts say keep it less than 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, keep it short.
Speaker 0: Keep it to the point.
Speaker 0: have something to say.
Speaker 1: Don't go Ramble ramble ramble rehearse it a few times.
Speaker 1: this thing lets you record, you know a race and then record again So you can keep doing it until you get it right unlike some phone calling things.
Speaker 0: now I mean, we've gotten a bunch of long long long audio feedbacks in the recent weeks and We're probably not going to play them anytime soon because stuff like that will probably save for gig night specials when we're you know out of town and we need filler.
Speaker 1: or if there's an episode Pertaining to that very thing or if you want to turn the long feedback into an episode itself.
Speaker 0: Yep, and also generally whenever we get a long feedback bear in mind that we're probably going to edit it to hell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just just a warning.
Speaker 1: So anyway now for those of you who had a hard time sending us audio feedback Like if we're saying something on the show and you go.
Speaker 1: Oh my god those guys go to the go to front crew comm click on the send me an audio link and Start recording whatever your rant is and then when you're done click send
Speaker 0: because I worry that We're gonna be in the situation that Penn Jillette is now on his radio show where?
Speaker 0: The best funny seemed to have is when people who hated him and disagreed with him and were angry at him would call In mm-hmm, but now the only people who listen to him are people who like him and generally agree with him.
Speaker 0: So I hope some of you disagree with us enough to yell at us.
Speaker 1: Yes, but now it's very easy to yell at us and We do have some news.
Speaker 0: We have two.
Speaker 0: news is today.
Speaker 0: now many of you will be happy that in the news we have in fact two news is.
Speaker 0: but first I Gotta say this again because it doesn't seem to be getting through to everyone when we said we're gonna you know cut down on the length of the show a bit and Possibly only do one news every now and then.
Speaker 0: I don't mean the show is gonna get short.
Speaker 0: the show is still gonna be 45 To 55 minutes like it always has been.
Speaker 0: yeah We're just not gonna do 90 minute shows unless we have a really good reason to but it seems like half the emails we get Have been saying please don't make the show really short Please don't oh my god.
Speaker 0: And actually even if we cut it down to the minimum we considered cutting it down to It's still longer than it was when geek night started by far.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so don't worry We're getting a lot of email about this, so I just wanted to say it again Okay Anyway in the actual news this was going to be a thing of the day But the forum discussion has prompted me to use it otherwise.
Speaker 0: Monopoly that terrible American board game is updating itself.
Speaker 0: They are now going to do what Scott and I did when we were little kids for the longest time.
Speaker 0: But now you know I guess the rest of the world's caught up.
Speaker 0: instead of using the paper money in the new sets You'll have a debit card and some sort of calculator like thing and all the money will be digital All right.
Speaker 0: now I say this is great except that I don't really care about Monopoly.
Speaker 0: the game is Generally a terrible game even though I played it a lot when I was a young kid only because I didn't know better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I also played it a lot as a young kid because what other board games that I have to choose from.
Speaker 0: well I had a risk and access now.
Speaker 1: I had risk and access and allies and Dinah bones.
Speaker 1: yep, I had a dampened fireball island.
Speaker 1: I had a lot of board games that you know other kids didn't have.
Speaker 1: that were pretty cool But like free parking that was great.
Speaker 1: the Monopoly spin-off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was a great game.
Speaker 0: now the thing is officer Jones Discussion.
Speaker 0: in our forums people seem to be arguing that but the paper money was important or whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna really go into why Monopoly is a broken terrible game Because that that is the purview of another another show entirely.
Speaker 0: I could do a whole show on Monopoly Like I could tell you exactly how to give yourself the best chance of winning.
Speaker 0: a simple thing could do it.
Speaker 1: I remember everyone knows that it's on the internet.
Speaker 0: a monkey could do it.
Speaker 0: You could train a monkey to play Monopoly and win as much as even the best Monopoly player mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: but some people were arguing that having the physical money can somehow change the game and That is outright not true other than possibly your own internal psychological things.
Speaker 0: Exactly now their arguments were one that openness.
Speaker 0: by having physical money you can see what everyone else has and Basically that comes down to the rules of the game.
Speaker 0: if the rules of the game say specifically that money is open Then money is open.
Speaker 0: meaning even if you're using a calculator or something if someone asks you how much money you have You have to tell them you are or you just have your calculator sitting wide open on the table.
Speaker 1: anyone can look at it In any time.
Speaker 0: yeah, it depends on what the rules say.
Speaker 1: you can make a special Monopoly calculator that shows the number Just in bright big LED LCD screen that everyone can see and to I mean the money can be a crutch for some kinds of People.
Speaker 0: the calculator can be a crutch for other kinds of people.
Speaker 0: It's really kind of arbitrary, and it doesn't actually affect the game.
Speaker 1: just affect affect the game.
Speaker 0: It only affects the psychology of people and how you think about the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is basically nothing.
Speaker 0: But in the end it just amazes me that every time Monopoly sales wane they can just make some other Monopoly set like Star Wars Monopoly or RIT-opoly and sell a bunch more even though it's the same goddamn game.
Speaker 1: yep Okay, my news is there was a Nintendo press release and It was a pretty funky press release.
Speaker 1: actually they talked about a lot of the games that are gonna be released Towards the end of this year, and I'm not gonna read the whole thing because you can do that yourself.
Speaker 1: But I'm just gonna go over the main points.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy 5 is coming to the Game Boy Advance on November 6.
Speaker 0: I'm very happy about that even though that is the hardest freaking Final Fantasy ever made.
Speaker 1: the touch generations stuff is gonna come out yeah, and Basically starting October 9th.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be a new game a DS game released every week the the touch generation the new nintendo dalmatians Magical star sign I don't know what that is Pokemon Ranger.
Speaker 1: Okay children of mana.
Speaker 1: We're gonna get that Elite beat agents isn't that the beat game?
Speaker 1: yeah I think it is Yoshi's Island 2 custom Robo arena and Kirby squeak squad.
Speaker 1: now the last Bit of this press release is the interesting part.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read this verbatim.
Speaker 1: everything I say from now until I say you know otherwise is directly from the Nintendo press release.
Speaker 1: all right including that no starting now and For Nintendo GameCube owners the Legend of Zelda Twilight Princess will be available for you this fall.
Speaker 1: an Enhanced version also will be a launch title for Wii.
Speaker 1: that will all happen on dot dot dot.
Speaker 1: Oh look.
Speaker 1: We're out of space God damn it.
Speaker 1: now I can't remember what website I saw it on but the guy deduced that Nintendo is hinting that the The release date for Wii and whatever was all coded into this press release.
Speaker 1: somehow
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and he said that you know his source at Nintendo kinda sorta wink-winked it and said yeah So his deduction was that the Wii release date is October 2nd because if you look at this release thing table there's a new game every week except for
Speaker 0: Except
Speaker 1: for the second two weeks in November, which is black.
Speaker 1: whatever Black Friday What do you keep saying?
Speaker 1: I just couldn't get past it anyway except for Black Friday and Another week which is past the release of the ps3.
Speaker 1: so it can't be that week.
Speaker 1: So he's deduced that the release date for Wii is October 2nd.
Speaker 0: Huh, we'll find out if that's true.
Speaker 1: Yes, we will.
Speaker 0: I give it a 50/50 shot.
Speaker 1: I think that's the best guess you've had yet looking at these release times.
Speaker 0: But well the thing is as time goes on the number of possible days decreases Pretty much on a day for day basis.
Speaker 1: Well, it has to be a week.
Speaker 1: It's not you know, so there are only.
Speaker 1: It's not like they have a choice of any day in the.
Speaker 0: well Yeah, but I mean the time frame is counting down because it's gonna come out before the end of the year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there what there's.
Speaker 1: there's four weeks.
Speaker 1: It's probably not gonna be in August or September, right?
Speaker 1: So if it isn't September so me I guess it could be so you got two weeks at the end of September.
Speaker 1: that are possible four weeks of October and like two weeks in November, so If you guessed you got pretty much a one in eight shot of getting it, right?
Speaker 0: I'd say we'd make a geek night's pool, but I don't really care enough.
Speaker 1: Hey, that's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Well, we could if you want to handle it.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about it.
Speaker 1: No, let's forget it great.
Speaker 0: If anyone in the forums wants to run a pool on when the Wii is coming out just put it up in the forums.
Speaker 1: Yeah We won't stop you Mm-hmm Even though you know someone else might some legal type person who doesn't know we won't Gamble.
Speaker 0: it's just a pool.
Speaker 0: the amounts of money We're claiming to send to each other's purely fake money where no one's actually going to send anyone any money.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: Yeah, obviously Okay, and I don't have it's gonna pay pal each other.
Speaker 1: bits zeros and ones.
Speaker 0: I don't have any illegal mp3s either.
Speaker 0: I don't have any ROMs.
Speaker 0: I've never pirated a movie.
Speaker 0: I don't even know what bit torrent is.
Speaker 0: Okay, but you just said bit torrent stuff Things of the day which are probably going to stay in the middle of the show due to popular demand.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So many of you are familiar with Daft Punk, which is one of my favorite bands consisting of two French dudes.
Speaker 1: They are two awesome.
Speaker 0: And if you don't know them check out interstellar five five five five.
Speaker 0: just google it.
Speaker 0: It's a DVD.
Speaker 0: buy it and watch it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'll pretty much give you everything you need to know about Daft Punk.
Speaker 0: Yeah Either that or find that old flash video more than ever hour after to River City ransom.
Speaker 1: just search for Daft Punk on YouTube or Google video or Google and you'll you'll you'll find everything that's good.
Speaker 0: now I use this as a thing of the day Mostly because we've been people have been talking about music bit in the forums and a lot of people have kind of asked what kind Of music we like which is not an easy question to answer at all.
Speaker 1: a lot a lot of music.
Speaker 0: Basically, you would have to ask us what music don't we like and even then it's hard for us to name anything.
Speaker 1: It would be easier to list the music.
Speaker 1: We don't like than to list the music we do Because there's a lot and there's also a lot of music we don't know about.
Speaker 0: so we can't say yeah, but like there aren't Genres of music that we really dislike.
Speaker 0: There are just a lot of very specific things We dislike like.
Speaker 0: I don't like most country music, but I like Western music Yeah, and there is some country music straight-up country that I like.
Speaker 0: not much but there's some yeah And it's like I really like Western music.
Speaker 0: Yeah and honky-tonk.
Speaker 1: Yeah God, yeah too much.
Speaker 0: We like everything.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we really like Daft Punk and This is just a really cool interview with them and Leiji Matsumoto's there.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much he talks in the interview because I didn't watch the whole thing.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much just an interview of Daft Punk.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It looks like it was done right after they finished.
Speaker 0: interstellar five five five five.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and see, you know in Daft Punk are two French guys who make all this great music and They never let you see their face in public as a few other bands do Because that way they can still go hang out at clubs and stuff and no one goes.
Speaker 1: Oh my god Daft Punk.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Now in this interview, it's a video interview.
Speaker 0: So the way they did it is they're wearing robot suits and you can't see their faces or their hands.
Speaker 1: yep, and It seems like their interview is recorded in a sound studio somewhere else and that they just videotaped them doing a bunch of robot stuff So that you can watch that while you listen to the interview.
Speaker 0: I wonder if they did the interview in any way where people could see their faces if they wore some sort of veil.
Speaker 1: I think they let you know, like their agent and you know interview people.
Speaker 1: I think they just don't put it anywhere super public or like during a concert or in a music video or an interview on TV.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Here's a bounty that I don't think any of our listeners will fulfill.
Speaker 0: If you can get me a picture of the two dudes from Daft Punk I saw a picture on Google Images.
Speaker 1: You don't want to bet that.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I wasn't gonna bet anything.
Speaker 0: I was gonna bet nothing.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure I saw one on Google Images.
Speaker 0: So, you know what those got.
Speaker 0: if no one knows what they look like just find a picture of some guy and say it's him Who's gonna know?
Speaker 1: I think the point is is that you know, even if you know what they look like It's their faces.
Speaker 1: don't become famous true?
Speaker 1: that way no one walking down the street will recognize.
Speaker 0: you know what it's like V.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kinda they're an idea.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter who they are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: They had to be these two awesome French guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever gonna make shit music It's not.
Speaker 0: at least they're not like the blue man group where if they made a group that because of the way they dress they're completely Interchangeable.
Speaker 0: so the band actually has a crazy number of people in it and they do shows all over the place with different groups.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day is The world's biggest hole.
Speaker 1: That's right the biggest hole.
Speaker 0: I was gonna make some sort of joke and I couldn't come up with anything good.
Speaker 0: The only thing I'd think of was the asshole song.
Speaker 0: All right, you ready?
Speaker 1: It's in Russia Odio Odio, the biggest hole in the world is in Russia the world's biggest hole Actually a diamond mine in eastern Siberia.
Speaker 0: Is it still a diamond mine?
Speaker 0: No, so it's just a hole now.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's 525 meters deep and 1.25 kilometers in diameter.
Speaker 0: Whoa I have a terrible urge to throw a rock into that.
Speaker 1: The hole is so big that it's caught the suction of the holes.
Speaker 1: existence has caused several helicopter crashes several.
Speaker 1: I Really want to throw a rock in this thing and now it is illegal to fly over the hole.
Speaker 0: Seriously this picture Scott just showed me is pretty freakin amazing.
Speaker 1: there's a picture here of a truck that is you that was used to.
Speaker 1: you know, go down and haul up stuff out of the hole and The trucks mighty big and when you look at like the spiraling road that goes down the hole it's Wow, it really puts it in perspective.
Speaker 0: Let me just say that Yeah, now I will say that because this was a diamond mine and the fact that Russian diamonds play a big part in what's happened I think it might still be a diamond mine.
Speaker 0: We should do a show about the diamond industry someday.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a good one.
Speaker 0: That's a big show we could do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, someone write that one down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah I think this actually might still have diamonds coming out of it.
Speaker 0: great You know if it's deep enough.
Speaker 0: I wonder if the amount of gas it takes to drive the diamonds up is worth less than the time it could take and just Make a diamond in Genesis or something.
Speaker 1: No, cuz I don't know diamonds aren't worth anything.
Speaker 1: So I know I know anyway.
Speaker 1: So today we're gonna talk about Advance Wars.
Speaker 0: Yes, we are.
Speaker 0: Advance Wars is a game that well We're not gonna talk about the Japanese releases or anything because we don't know much about the Japanese releases and it's hard to find reliable Information about.
Speaker 0: all I know is that it that the what we got as Advance Wars 1. when it was released in Japan Olaf looked like Santa Claus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was a game.
Speaker 1: there was a series of games in Japan for an in from Nintendo and I don't know what it was Called but it was basically.
Speaker 1: it's the Advance Wars that we have.
Speaker 0: Yes now the games are there a lot like those desert war type game for the old NES and SNES or Trying to think I don't remember what all these games were but games where you have military units that are described very simply.
Speaker 0: you know, they have a small number of stats and there's different types and You move them around and fight with another group who has similar units and you try to capture bases destroy units and you know General puzzling military stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know There's a lot of complicated war games out there with crazy maps and hexagons and all sorts of numbers.
Speaker 1: Advance Wars is the same kind of game, but it's way simpler.
Speaker 1: I mean, you've got a school a grid of squares.
Speaker 1: all the units are simple.
Speaker 1: It's infantry mech guy Tank mechanized infant.
Speaker 1: Yeah bigger tank biggest fighter jet even bigger tank bomber battleship Jeep, you know, yep, all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: And the thing is the way the game plays out is while it's a military kind of you know move units around and fight game.
Speaker 0: For the most part unless you're playing against other people or in certain special campaign missions The game is more a puzzle game than a military game.
Speaker 1: It really is a puzzle game.
Speaker 0: well at least in the first advance wars.
Speaker 1: Well, even in the it's sort of like a puzzle, but it's got like a lenient solution.
Speaker 1: You know how like some some puzzle games it's.
Speaker 1: there is one solution you either figure it out or you don't figure it out.
Speaker 1: Advance Wars is more of a puzzle game where there are a lot of slightly different solutions.
Speaker 1: You know one solution might be quicker one might take longer, you know one might.
Speaker 1: you know Done really quick, but have a bad score.
Speaker 0: I guess the point I was making is that advance Wars 1 compared to 2 and 2 and there's a progression.
Speaker 0: definitely that.
Speaker 0: The early advance Wars game was very very.
Speaker 0: there were a few options and the game was very unforgiving especially in the later stages or in the hard campaign where if you made one single mistake or Got to the got to the point where if you moved one unit to the wrong place You lost.
Speaker 0: you would lose the war.
Speaker 0: in advance Wars DS the third iteration the game involved to the point to where?
Speaker 0: Not only were there usually many multiple different strategies to win But the individual movements of a single troop alone would usually not screw you and you could always still win.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't get bowled over just because you put an infantry in the wrong square.
Speaker 0: You'd only get bowled over if you made poor tactical decisions on a broader scale.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the game became less of a puzzle game and more of a war game as the series went on But it is still definitely a puzzle oriented game.
Speaker 1: Let's do some informational stuff.
Speaker 1: There are three advance Wars games available in the United States of America.
Speaker 0: the first two came out for the Gameboy advanced and they're called advance Wars 1 or advance Wars and Advance Wars 2 black hole rising.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the third advance or his game is a DS game, which is advance Wars DS dual strike dual strike.
Speaker 1: Yes, they they they were very clever in their DS using.
Speaker 0: I know they're puzzle games slash military games and there is also a very Japanese element of instant.
Speaker 0: in addition to just having these units you have CEOs or commanding officers and Not only do they all have different powers like if you pick one CEO The all your tanks are stronger if you pick a different CEO or infantry or really badass.
Speaker 0: They all have personalities and they all interact with each other.
Speaker 0: and as you play through the campaigns you get to see this more and This is really really brought to the final the furthest extreme It has been yet in advance Wars DS where depending on what characters you use in certain battles You see different bits of plot and there's romance between the CEOs and all sorts of funny stuff that has nothing to do with the game.
Speaker 1: yep, and Not only that but every CEO has a special CEO power.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the way the mechanic works is kind of neat.
Speaker 0: I mean you're fighting, you know I've got my tanks and Scott's got his tanks and we're out.
Speaker 0: you're battling it out Anytime your units take damage your little CEO power meter goes up and anytime you deal out damage it goes up.
Speaker 0: Also, however, when you take damage it goes up more than twice as fast as you deal out damage.
Speaker 1: So if you're losing and you're taking a lot of damage You're gonna get your power more often to sort of help even out the game.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't really, you know, it's not really a handicap But it's there, you know, it sort of makes the game last a little bit longer and make it a little bit more interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean to me the function it serves and I'll preface this and we're not gonna talk about the strategy of the game because That would be another episode or two.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but I'm not kidding.
Speaker 0: when I say that I am freaking amazing at this game I mean you play too much.
Speaker 0: I did play too much.
Speaker 0: I advance Wars one and two.
Speaker 0: I beat every single single mission with an ass and I unlocked everything.
Speaker 0: Advance Wars DS.
Speaker 0: The only reason I didn't unlock everything and beat everything is because a lot of the maps are the same as the maps in advance Wars one and two.
Speaker 0: so I just didn't bother with them again Mm-hmm, but I really like I figured out almost everything about this game and it seems to me that the CEO power serve a very critical purpose in that they prevent people from winning by pure dumb luck and They force you to win by winning as opposed to just squeaking by someone and winning on a technicality.
Speaker 0: Say I'm beating Scott up a lot and I roll up and I destroy a bunch of his units But I don't have enough units in my supply line to follow through and finish him off Now because I failed to plan and I didn't actually destroy him.
Speaker 0: I just beat him back really bad.
Speaker 0: He gets his CEO power that I didn't get.
Speaker 0: he uses that to counter-attack my thinly supported units that are far off in his field Recapture everything and now we're back at square one.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The other thing is the The this different CEOs have different lengths in their CEO meter.
Speaker 1: So depending on some people have an incredibly powerful CEO power that like destroys everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some people have a power that's kind of weak, you know, none of them are weak like useless But some of them aren't as strong as others.
Speaker 1: So the CEOs that have less useful powers get them more often because their meter fills up faster because it's smaller.
Speaker 0: There's also a mechanic that for every time you use your CEO power It takes more damage to make it fill up the next time.
Speaker 0: So you can't keeper like if you keep getting your CEO power over and over and over and over again Because you're sucking but the other person is also kind of sucking so they can't finish you off They're just beating you back.
Speaker 0: Eventually.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna be getting your CEO power so much anymore.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: The game really isn't handicapped in any direction.
Speaker 1: Yep What else is there no about this game?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the game is very much.
Speaker 0: I mean all the units are very archtypical and very distinct, you know, you have infantry also cute.
Speaker 0: Yes, the game is very cute.
Speaker 0: But yet it's almost disturbing.
Speaker 0: I mean think of this.
Speaker 0: it's war.
Speaker 0: you were sending troops against each other to fight and kill and die for you.
Speaker 1: There are people taking over cities bombing each other shooting big guns at each other killing people and the CEOs are Oblivious to this because you even meet some.
Speaker 0: they're just happy anime characters like some of.
Speaker 0: there's a point Which some of the troops are talking to you and they're like and it's just.
Speaker 0: it's kind of sad because you're sending them to their Deaths.
Speaker 0: but the way the game is like one CEO is marching through a land right and this other CEO will come up and they'll talk and they'll be like I don't know if we can be friends Let's fight first and then they'll fight and kill a whole bunch of people and then they'll decide yeah We can be friends and then they'll march together.
Speaker 0: It's just really silly.
Speaker 0: It's real God yeah, but the game itself is not silly at all.
Speaker 0: The game is actually an incredibly well-done Tactical and strategic game that has many many levels of strategy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like how.
Speaker 1: it's a turn-based game, which you don't see a lot of these days but it's it really helps out because you know a lot of RTS is and Such the.
Speaker 1: the thing that matters most is knowing how to build things in the correct order for speed or clicking quickly And advance or as that's not the case.
Speaker 0: Yep, you can actually sit there and think and decide Alright, I need to send infantry to the north to capture those cities.
Speaker 0: Well, I have a few mechs to the south on the mountains to hold Scott at bay Long enough for me to save up the money to buy a mega tank and then roll it over and destroy him.
Speaker 0: Yep, stuff like that.
Speaker 0: now the game.
Speaker 0: I mean I said that we said the game is very puzzle oriented but also very tactical strategic and The key element there is that one part of the game is fog of war and I like how the game can be played both Ways.
Speaker 0: there are straight-up battles where the entire game is visible.
Speaker 0: You can see every unit you can see everyone's money You can see everything on the screen and when you're playing like that It's more of a puzzle game than anything, you know move my fighter So it's just out of range of his fighter.
Speaker 0: move my infantry so we can capture that city and I know that his recon will make it one turn too late.
Speaker 0: and In a lot of the campaigns, especially in the advanced campaigns, which I'll talk about a bit in a minute Which are basically these super difficult campaigns after you beat the game itself It'll get to the point where you have to move units to specific locations and it's just a puzzle game of How can I get this infantry through this maze of units to the end before he dies stuff like that?
Speaker 1: Yep Let's talk about the differences into the the three different games.
Speaker 1: the very first advance wars for the GBA was real simple.
Speaker 1: I mean the biggest tank you had was a medium tank.
Speaker 0: Well, it still had a lot of units.
Speaker 1: It did still have a lot.
Speaker 1: most of the units in the game were in the first one But there were.
Speaker 1: you know, the biggest tank was a medium tank.
Speaker 1: There weren't the boats?
Speaker 1: weren't that useful?
Speaker 1: they were you know, they didn't have the wide variety of boats and You know, it was Jen.
Speaker 1: It was a lot simpler game.
Speaker 1: The maps were a lot smaller and less complex.
Speaker 1: There were a lot less weird things on the maps like in the later advanced.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the game was very much a straight-up.
Speaker 0: introduce you to the game.
Speaker 0: In fact before you play the game, there's a tutorial that takes you through a bunch of lessons on how to play the game.
Speaker 0: That's actually very very well done.
Speaker 0: I give a lot of credit to the people who put that together.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the game is really doesn't have a lot of different modes.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's the campaign There's the war room and has the multiplayer which isn't the most exciting multiplayer in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the campaign itself is good.
Speaker 0: It's a great way to learn about advance wars and I've noticed a lot of the people I know who played advance wars DS And had never touched the previous two Didn't really do so well in the game and to this day don't do so well because I don't know.
Speaker 0: it's like you learn a Lot of fundamentals playing advance wars 1 also you can get it for like 8 bucks.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend picking it up now.
Speaker 1: advance wars 2 is is sort of like the game that just Improved leaps and bounds ahead of advance wars 1 and is it's pretty much the best you can do with advance wars on the GBA.
Speaker 0: Yes, I mean in advance wars 1 there was a limited number of CEOs and their powers were very generic.
Speaker 0: You know one guy hits really hard.
Speaker 0: one guys in one girl's infantry is really really good.
Speaker 0: One guy has really good long range.
Speaker 0: one guy is good in the snow and when it snows his weapons things are more powerful and he makes it snow.
Speaker 0: yep, and Advance wars 2 added a bunch more CEOs that even the game out quite a bit more.
Speaker 1: They there were a lot more subtle strategies a lot more interesting CEOs that were somewhat difficult to use sometimes and they I also added the extra units like the neo tank which is even better than the medium tank and They also added the superpower.
Speaker 1: so you know a CEO would have one power But if he wanted to wait even longer he could wait and fill up his meter even more to get an even better power.
Speaker 0: Yep, and advance wars 2 overall is an absolutely fantastic game Oh for sure, especially if you compare it to GBA games.
Speaker 0: It's probably one of the best GBA games Yes, and in fact I would say that the campaign all things considered in advance wars 2 was my favorite of all three games Mmm in terms of just the fun and the difficulty and the challenge.
Speaker 0: see Advance wars DS.
Speaker 0: the campaign was in my opinion Pathetically easy.
Speaker 1: it was pretty easy.
Speaker 1: there was one mission I had a little trouble on but then I got through it advance wars 2.
Speaker 1: There were some missions that I just couldn't do like the stupid battleships mission.
Speaker 0: I could I laugh to you so much because I beat it on my first try?
Speaker 1: yeah But you know it wasn't like a strategy thing.
Speaker 1: It's a puzzle thing, and I just can't solve that damn puzzle.
Speaker 0: Yep, now the thing is advance wars.
Speaker 0: all of them have a campaign and then an advanced campaign and once you beat the campaign Which is the single-player game which will take you a long time?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of missions even in the first advance wars.
Speaker 0: The advanced campaign is the same thing again only one.
Speaker 0: it's a lot harder, too.
Speaker 0: There's a lot less margin for error.
Speaker 0: three in a lot of cases some of the maps are completely different And there's different missions and everything and the AI is also more direct and better.
Speaker 1: also in advance wars.
Speaker 1: one It's a lot harder to unlock everything.
Speaker 1: you have to like use certain CEOs and certain missions and crazy stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm starting with two and three.
Speaker 0: you just buy them.
Speaker 0: you don't have to do anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know.
Speaker 1: and in all the advance horses as you beat things you get money and you can use that money to buy maps And unlock different things.
Speaker 1: Advance or is two and three you just use your money to unlock all the characters and shit.
Speaker 0: now in terms of difficulty I'll talk about the advance campaign because to give you an example Like the second or third mission in advance wars one the enemy has like a couple of tanks and you have to beat him.
Speaker 0: in The advance campaign is the exact same map and you start with the exact same units.
Speaker 0: But now they have like three medium tanks and a pile of tanks and it's like oh my god.
Speaker 0: How do I beat this?
Speaker 0: the advance campaign in advance Wars one was So difficult and so much of a precise puzzle that it got to the point that by the end of it You would literally have to move every single unit in the exact perfect direction every turn or you would die.
Speaker 0: Not that oh now it'll take a long time to win.
Speaker 0: you would die.
Speaker 0: It would be over.
Speaker 0: It was so difficult.
Speaker 0: I To this day.
Speaker 0: I can't believe I beat it and going back I probably couldn't beat it because I don't have that much patience anymore.
Speaker 1: Yep, now advance Wars DS was of course being on the DS leaps and bounds ahead of previous advance Wars.
Speaker 0: They added a million co's they address.
Speaker 0: one of the primary complaints people have had about the game Was that in advance Wars one and two?
Speaker 0: Naval units were all but useless and a Navy was never a viable strategy.
Speaker 0: They were just not worth it.
Speaker 1: it was too expensive and hard to use and Even if you you know built battleships and stuff like submarines just come and destroy them and it was very difficult.
Speaker 0: Yep, advance Wars DS added a bunch of extra new Navy unit like
Speaker 1: a black
Speaker 0: boat Yes or the aircraft carrier
Speaker 1: the aircraft carrier
Speaker 0: and it also changed some of the powers of older units to make it so that you could actually have a Navy and Send it out to sea and have naval battles.
Speaker 0: and it added a lot to the game in my opinion.
Speaker 1: Oh it added a whole lot.
Speaker 1: I mean just the addition.
Speaker 1: it used to be that the only reason to have a Navy was to have Battleships at sea that survived.
Speaker 1: if you could have Battleships at sea that lived you could use them to rain unholy death upon your opponent.
Speaker 0: Yep, especially if you were grit.
Speaker 1: every other naval unit was simply there to defend battleships or to destroy the enemy's battleship.
Speaker 0: Yep, other than the transport which served only to bring units across water.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's correct.
Speaker 1: So yeah also defending the transports.
Speaker 1: but now in advance or as DS they added the aircraft carrier Which not only can it airplanes land on it?
Speaker 1: But it can completely destroy any other aircraft within a huge radius.
Speaker 1: So the appeal of having battleships and aircraft carriers at sea Actually makes it worth it to build a Navy.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I mean especially in large maps and playing against actual humans instead of the AI.
Speaker 0: Very realistic military doctrine is important and very realistic military tactics in terms of you know I want air superiority I build fighters and such and I claim air superiority.
Speaker 0: now my bombers can fly around unmolested but to get air superiority I have to spend a lot of money which I could have spent on things like tanks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and with these new units you could shoot for naval superiority, which was just as powerful just like in the real world Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and naval superiority often also means air superiority because the aircraft carrier is just that dangerous.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's just also that hard and expensive to defend.
Speaker 1: No, we're talking about the strategy again.
Speaker 0: Yes Well, I want to get back to at least the way the game flows.
Speaker 0: that because before I was talking about the game is a puzzle game and advance Wars 1 was a super puzzle game advance Wars 2 which is a much better game and It's much more tactical especially the advanced campaign.
Speaker 0: It's a lot less of this move a unit in a specific direction X pieces per round ago lose and a lot more.
Speaker 0: Think of a strategy to overcome this enemy and you'll succeed.
Speaker 0: Advance Wars DS took this one step further and the game is much more tactical in a lot of degrees.
Speaker 0: and even if you completely screw up in the single-player game unless the advanced campaign you can probably still win, but I Said fog of war.
Speaker 0: the game usually is totally open and you can see all the units.
Speaker 0: but sometimes you can play in fog war mode where you can't see everything.
Speaker 0: and now visibility and All that plays a bigger role and that makes it played a role in the earlier advance horses But in advance.
Speaker 1: where is DS it really actually be?
Speaker 0: as something I mean, especially playing against humans It gets to the point where when you're playing with fog of war You can't see what the other person's doing.
Speaker 0: all the time.
Speaker 0: The game is so much more strategic and tactical and so much more of a realistic military game.
Speaker 0: It's no longer a puzzle because now you have a lot.
Speaker 0: I mean you can try things like Secretly constructing a Navy at your rear ports while you have a token defense at the front and then sneaking that Navy around and suddenly Launching a surprise attack on their southern shore.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Awesome stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yep The other thing advance or is DS they take a lot of.
Speaker 1: there's a lot more modes.
Speaker 1: There's the combat mode which is sort of like combat for the Atari.
Speaker 0: It's that it's silly and crap silly and crap, but they threw it in the game.
Speaker 0: It was fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a good way to get a lot of points to unlock stuff real quickly.
Speaker 1: Yes They also added these survival puzzle modes and things Those are actually like.
Speaker 1: not they're not even like advance or is one where it's a puzzle, but you don't know it.
Speaker 1: This is like here is an advance wars puzzle.
Speaker 1: solve it figure out how to do this And they'll give you like two units and put you up on like this crazy map Against a billion enemies and you'll have to figure out how to win in like x-turns.
Speaker 0: It's great fun It.
Speaker 1: the puzzle mode is fantastic the survival mode that whole thing.
Speaker 1: I love it.
Speaker 0: Now the one complaint we always had about advanced wars 1 & 2 was that they had a great wealth of multiplayer built into them.
Speaker 0: multiplayer advanced wars is a wonderful wonderful experience, but Playing multiplayer games on the GBA Was utter hell with those tiny ass little cables and you basically have pictures of us at the shore doing this.
Speaker 0: We're all hunched around in a circle.
Speaker 0: If anyone sneezes or bumps their cable the game crashes and it was just miserable.
Speaker 1: the DS has the wireless.
Speaker 0: Oh my god The day is saved.
Speaker 0: playing wireless advanced wars at the shore was one of the.
Speaker 0: that was the moment when the DS moved from a Wonderful gaming system to my primary gaming system.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, they also added the dual strike.
Speaker 1: so instead of having just one commanding officer you have two and you can swap them back and forth.
Speaker 0: which Kind of it has pros and cons.
Speaker 1: You can turn it off in the game You can you can just play with one CEO if you want.
Speaker 0: But again, it adds a lot more depth of strategy and depth of tactics to the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean you before.
Speaker 1: you could just choose the guy who's good with infantry and then that would be it.
Speaker 1: if you have two CEOs You can take the guy who's good with infantry and the guy who's good with tanks.
Speaker 1: So early game you bring out your infantry which are cheap and then you save up your money doing that and then you switch to Tanks and you're still good.
Speaker 1: You don't suck now.
Speaker 1: and There's also the dual strike powers.
Speaker 1: Or if you fill up the meters on both of your CEOs not only to both of them use their incredibly superpowers But you take two turns which is insane.
Speaker 1: It's actually it's super insane and it can turn the whole game around.
Speaker 0: Now I guess in conclusion I really I mean we've kind of reviewed the games.
Speaker 0: we're gonna do an episode someday now This will be way out in the future Because we're in no hurry to do this.
Speaker 0: we could do this any time about how to actually be good at advanced wars and all the strategies they're in.
Speaker 0: but For now if any of you have a DS or just bought one or a DS lite or even if you just have a GBA Yeah, and you need a game by any and all advanced wars games.
Speaker 0: You can get your hands on.
Speaker 0: they're Absolutely fantastic and they're well worth the money.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean advanced wars is sort of like this sleeper hit too.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it wasn't widely advertised.
Speaker 0: In fact, I poo-pooed it when I first heard about it.
Speaker 1: I didn't poo-poo it.
Speaker 0: I and Scott had it.
Speaker 0: cuz I didn't have a GBA and I saw it and him and Luke and all Them were really playing the effect.
Speaker 0: God.
Speaker 0: We have a story To make a long story short.
Speaker 0: one of our friends prac pretty much failed out of graduate school Because he was playing advanced wars trying to beat advanced Wars ones advanced campaign.
Speaker 1: Yep That's a true story.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yeah the was I saying I Don't know.
Speaker 1: Oh, all right.
Speaker 1: It was a sleeper hit.
Speaker 1: it wasn't advertised widely It wasn't very well known but it sold a shit ton of copies
Speaker 0: Yep, and I put kind of poo-pooed it and then I got a D or a GBA the platinum one for my parents for Christmas Which I was very happy with and I saw advanced Wars one for sale used for like eight bucks.
Speaker 0: So I bought it and the game was amazing and within a couple of weeks I'd beaten the whole thing and then within another couple weeks I'd beaten the advanced campaign and then it wasn't too long after that that advanced Wars two came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah so the reason I think I decided the I came up with the idea to an advance or his episode now is well a because Rim has been playing it again recently Yep, partly because I I just needed some stuff to kill time.
Speaker 0: now that I'm actually doing stuff at work I needed some downtime with my brain to work on something logical.
Speaker 1: Yep, and B. You know advanced Wars one came out and as soon as it started to fade advanced Wars two came out It started to fade.
Speaker 1: advanced or as DS came out started to fade and now, you know advanced swords is sort of disappeared from the public View.
Speaker 1: so I gave it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna give it a little boost until advanced or as ds2 comes out.
Speaker 1: Yeah or advanced or as we There is an advanced Wars kind of an advanced Wars game for the game.
Speaker 0: to what battalion war?
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't buy that now.
Speaker 0: Well, if you see it for like five bucks pick it up, I guess You know, there are very few GameCube games that aren't worth a couple bucks.
Speaker 0: That's true But it's as our friend Scott Johnson could tell you.
Speaker 0: he has every freaking game ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's.
Speaker 1: it's a bad game from what I hear.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have anything.
Speaker 1: I mean it kind of has something to do with advanced Wars, but not really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, so Yeah, don't that doesn't count.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying as a final challenge to all of you out there.
Speaker 0: I defy Anyone in our forums to consistently beat me at advanced wars.
Speaker 1: Too bad.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: That's I know that'll be in the next verse.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, if advanced war said Wi-Fi speaking of which we said way back We were gonna try to organize some sort of DS Wi-Fi gaming night.
Speaker 0: I think we should do that.
Speaker 1: sometimes Everyone forgot about it.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with?
Speaker 0: because I want to do it.
Speaker 1: It's all you all right.
Speaker 0: sometime probably after Otacon I'm going to try to organize some sort of night where we'll all play a DS game.
Speaker 0: Hopefully Mario Kart Tetris man Tetris.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Tetris is easier.
Speaker 0: But Mario Kart is awesome.
Speaker 0: All right, we'll do something.
Speaker 0: Okay, then and That was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.