Speaker 1: It's Tuesday April 18th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We're going to talk about the fury of Dracula.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I listen to quite a few podcasts while I sit at work and do nothing.
Speaker 0: you know and I got.
Speaker 0: I got an anime One and a technology one and you know all kinds of different stuff.
Speaker 0: And I got one gaming podcast that gamers with jobs radio.
Speaker 0: that goes with That gamers of jobs website of course.
Speaker 0: I don't read that website.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, we actually know one of the people there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 0: They were these two cool dudes, and they talked about video games And they did it better than like you know PC gamer or game spot or one up Or you know any of those people.
Speaker 0: so I listen to them.
Speaker 0: You know once a week whatever They come on episode get in the car this morning and They start going on about how this is the last episode and they weren't kidding.
Speaker 0: So now I'm without a gaming podcast.
Speaker 1: It's weird that someone could just stop doing a podcast.
Speaker 0: well they stopped doing it because one of the guys got a job with the escapist and They frown upon him doing something they pay him to do for free elsewhere at the same time.
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: That's a load of crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like you know.
Speaker 0: if you pay me to write software for you And I do it for someone else for free at the same time you might be upset I guess, but that's what most open-source developers Do I know.
Speaker 0: but apparently when it comes to writing about video games?
Speaker 0: They don't like that.
Speaker 0: so They can't continue doing this radio show if he works for them, and he's going to work for them, so that's that.
Speaker 1: That's really kind of sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz it was a really really good show.
Speaker 1: if anything the escapist should have used the show.
Speaker 0: Well, they can't because gamers of jobs is actually like a profit company kind of thing.
Speaker 1: I guess They could pull something off.
Speaker 1: Maybe better than what they did now.
Speaker 1: Just killing a good podcast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll have to go find a new gaming podcast that probably won't live up.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: There's always geek nights.
Speaker 0: I don't want to listen to myself And I don't talk.
Speaker 0: and they.
Speaker 0: the thing is I listen to them because they talk about all the video games I don't play.
Speaker 1: why do you want to hear about the video games you never play?
Speaker 0: Why would I want to hear about the ones I already played?
Speaker 1: But what I mean?
Speaker 1: the games you hear about that.
Speaker 1: you don't like you always bitch about.
Speaker 1: so why do you want to hear about?
Speaker 1: What they do or what they are?
Speaker 0: That way I know I'm in I'm informed.
Speaker 1: It's know thine enemy.
Speaker 0: so I can do some informed insulting instead of just That way.
Speaker 0: if someone comes up to me and is like you don't even know what that game is.
Speaker 0: you just know this is name Of a game that you're not supposed to like.
Speaker 0: I can be like.
Speaker 0: no I know about that game.
Speaker 0: that game sucks because of XY and Z.
Speaker 1: so there yeah I've just got the problem lately of World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: people who try to talk to me about the game And they'll say things like yeah hearth leek back 1f Bob Baker 9, whatever friggin jargon they have in that game I have no idea what they're saying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what happened is simple jargon.
Speaker 0: I mean game jargon is okay as long.
Speaker 1: All right all right.
Speaker 1: look zerg rush.
Speaker 1: We all know what a zerg rushes.
Speaker 0: I know I don't even play Starcraft.
Speaker 0: I suck at Starcraft.
Speaker 0: I know what a zerg rush is.
Speaker 1: Well, it's obvious because it's self descriptive.
Speaker 1: There's something called zerg and obviously they rush in some capacity.
Speaker 1: yep A fire sale usually involves Fire.
Speaker 1: say yeah, we should play that game again all right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's partly that World of Warcraft seems to be set up to create a complex environment And it's almost like people take pride in knowing the jargon of the complex environment.
Speaker 1: That's utterly alien to others.
Speaker 1: It's like they wear their being able to speak in tongues as kind of a badge to non gamers like oh You don't know what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you don't know what a hearth is what the hell, and I think yeah a hearth.
Speaker 1: That's where I put my fire.
Speaker 0: Fear my Linux hacks or podcast skills.
Speaker 0: what Exactly my point?
Speaker 1: okay So in actual news this is somewhat old news.
Speaker 1: We waited to report it mostly because it didn't seem Entirely possible or credible, but it's been picked up by every news source for a while.
Speaker 1: There's really no denying it.
Speaker 1: Lucent technologies is suing Microsoft and the end result may very well be the discontinuance of the Xbox 360.
Speaker 0: Wait so it is a lawsuit somewhere, and if the lawsuit ends up against Microsoft then Xbox 360 will just die.
Speaker 0: no more games no more systems no more nothing.
Speaker 1: Very it's possible.
Speaker 0: won't they just modify the Xbox 360 in some way and bring it back out?
Speaker 1: That's not easy because the games that are already out and that are coming out also rely on the technology at issue.
Speaker 1: Okay, basically to make a long long story short There's there MPEG-2 which is used in DVD and a number of other things is a way of encoding video to make it smaller.
Speaker 1: Compressing like mp3 is for.
Speaker 0: usually MPEG-2 is sort of well isn't it lossless, or it's really high quality?
Speaker 0: It's very not really so much compression.
Speaker 0: It's more like an encoding.
Speaker 1: Yes, though.
Speaker 1: It isn't far from lossless.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I guess.
Speaker 0: but yeah the point is it's usually not.
Speaker 0: it's not like MPEG-4 Where you're trying to fit it on a little tiny thing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it I mean it does do significant compression mostly because of the limitations of things like NTSC.
Speaker 0: Yeah it Basically, but you've used MPEG-2.
Speaker 0: you're getting a home movie to fit on one DVD as opposed to a whole movie to fit in Less than a gig.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's not very efficient has its issues But that's what DVDs use for the most part and there are a whole bunch of patents around it and almost all of them Are held by this consortium?
Speaker 1: I don't remember all the details the MPEG consortium.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically well I'm not no one cares except us.
Speaker 1: I want to get to the meat of this.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 1: But basically if you have a patent that covers MPEG-2 and you put it in this pool of patents then in return You get a share based on how valuable your patent is of the licensing fees to anyone else who doesn't have a patent who uses MPEG.
Speaker 1: So basically everyone who developed MPEG kind of works together and everyone wins.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea.
Speaker 1: Lucent has this patent that they've had for some time.
Speaker 1: They actually sued Microsoft back in 2003 about the same patent so Microsoft knew this was coming.
Speaker 1: they have a patent on quote adaptive coding and decoding of frames and fields of view and It basically covers the way the Xbox uses MPEG-2.
Speaker 0: How does the Xbox use MPEG-2 besides to play DVDs that you put in it?
Speaker 1: I don't know the details of the patent.
Speaker 0: I didn't read the patent and I mean of the using MPEG-2 for FMVs and games.
Speaker 1: I think they are all right.
Speaker 0: well That would be one.
Speaker 1: also the fact that the way it encodes it or the way it can Encode or decode it or the way the developers can encode it In the end result is that it infringes on the patent in a very obvious way.
Speaker 1: Like no one involved in the case denies that it infringes except Microsoft's lawyers.
Speaker 0: It's the brightest end with Microsoft giving someone another pile of money, and then whatever.
Speaker 1: here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Lucent has more money than Microsoft.
Speaker 1: They're not just gonna back down for some piddly-pittens.
Speaker 0: No, but it'll probably be a pile of money Percentage of the total Xbox 360 profits or revenues.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is Lucent is seeking an injunction to halt the sales of the Xbox and all sorts of nastiness.
Speaker 1: They're going for the throat.
Speaker 1: Wow No one's really sure exactly why they're handling the way they are But it might actually be a matter of pride or a matter of getting back.
Speaker 1: I mean Microsoft.
Speaker 1: this lawsuit came up a long time ago when the Xbox 360 was in development and Lucent sued Microsoft and it was eventually thrown out of court because there was a small typo in the patent.
Speaker 1: I thought Microsoft Okay, so the judge had to throw it out and the only reason the lawsuit reappeared is because they went through the process of fixing the one typo and now the patent is legitimate again and Resuing.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't know what Microsoft thought that it would go away that they give up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a guy who's a lawyer and his job his entire job since that first lawsuit has been Fixing that patent and ganking the new lawsuit.
Speaker 0: There's a guy whose job it is to come after you.
Speaker 0: What are you doing?
Speaker 0: not paying attention?
Speaker 0: Not hiring a hitman to kill him.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you now?
Speaker 1: I'm curious to see what the result of this will be.
Speaker 1: I mean Microsoft is pretty much said we're not going to pay you we're not going to change the Xbox.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they say shit all the time.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: I don't think Microsoft could afford to pay them off right now.
Speaker 1: I mean Vista.
Speaker 1: if unless Microsoft's lying and Vista is actually on time and awesome Vista is gonna be a failure or at least not going to do very well.
Speaker 1: the Xbox I mean.
Speaker 1: the news today was that the Xbox is plentiful.
Speaker 1: You can just go buy one if you want.
Speaker 1: There's no shortage anymore and no one's buying them.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I actually saw some in a store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Costco has them actually for a significant discount.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, you can go buy an Xbox premium with a pile of games.
Speaker 0: I think is anyone who wants one has one and now they're just buying games for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no one who doesn't have one that wants one.
Speaker 0: maybe in the holiday season coming up since you know It'll be a year old.
Speaker 0: Maybe they can drop the price a bit and people go.
Speaker 1: I think they're still selling it at a loss.
Speaker 1: We don't know the details of that though.
Speaker 1: Yeah but anyway there's lawsuit.
Speaker 1: depending on how it goes might be big trouble for Microsoft and Every analyst I've seen writing about it basically said that yeah the patent is valid.
Speaker 1: There's no way Microsoft can fight this.
Speaker 0: Now it's never happened before.
Speaker 0: we're like a very very popular product.
Speaker 0: It was just taken off the shelves and destroyed.
Speaker 0: It's never happened.
Speaker 0: I can't remember it.
Speaker 1: one IP lawyer said specifically, you know, the rim lawsuit over a blackberries.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was almost the first time it happened.
Speaker 1: Yes, they said that the egregiousness of the offense on Microsoft's part and the clarity of the patent is Far greater in this case than it was in that case and that case was pretty solid.
Speaker 0: Yeah that case.
Speaker 0: Well, even though NTP was just a company that held patents and nothing else loosens a real company.
Speaker 0: It does things.
Speaker 0: So this is complete.
Speaker 1: Whoa You know, yeah, so we'll we're reporting on it.
Speaker 1: a few people actually asked me about this.
Speaker 1: So don't bother us again.
Speaker 1: We'll report again if there's any developments.
Speaker 1: I don't think there will be for a while.
Speaker 1: This is one of those takes years to complete lawsuits.
Speaker 0: That's good for Microsoft.
Speaker 0: They can sell years of Xbox 360s and by then they'll sold all the consoles They're gonna sell.
Speaker 0: they can just keep making games and whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: My only question is I wonder why Microsoft Didn't do something back when they were sued the first time.
Speaker 0: maybe they thought that once they get the system out It won't matter anymore.
Speaker 0: if they could block the Xbox 360 from ever getting sold They'd be fucked.
Speaker 0: but as soon as they got it out there, it's out there where they win.
Speaker 1: But back in 2003 couldn't.
Speaker 1: they had just paid whatever licensing fee they would have had to pay unless loosen refused to take it.
Speaker 0: Well, see that's the thing is that there's no mandatory patent licensing.
Speaker 0: if you don't want to license your patent out You don't have to yep.
Speaker 0: So there really needs to be some sort of thing where you know People have to license the patent to you.
Speaker 0: if someone has a patent on something.
Speaker 0: I mean sure that's not the perfect solution to fixing the whole broken patent system But that's one aspect that needs to be fixed is if someone has a patent and I want to make something that would normally infringe There should be some basic rate that I pay and that's it.
Speaker 1: I mean we already have that for music.
Speaker 1: Yep And as much as that system is broken and corrupt and stupid as well.
Speaker 1: It's a step up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I want to play Someone's songs.
Speaker 0: They have to let me if I pay that's.
Speaker 1: yeah, there's even rules about how much they can charge.
Speaker 0: Yep, well this standard whatnots and everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we went long on that partly because it's our only non fluff news.
Speaker 0: Is the fluff news?
Speaker 0: Yeah So this guy he bought this shitty Xbox 360 game where you're a World War two pilot or something.
Speaker 0: That's not the point.
Speaker 0: The point is he bought this game And he it has a bug in it a bug that at some point in the game Forces you to fly in circles and die and you basically can't continue with the game because it's a huge bug and it sucks.
Speaker 0: so he went to the store to return the game as Someone should do yep, and he said give me a refund.
Speaker 0: They said we can't give you a refund.
Speaker 0: He's like, alright Give me store credit equal to the value of the game and I'll get a different game.
Speaker 0: Like we can't do that either.
Speaker 0: we have a store policy.
Speaker 1: who a store policy?
Speaker 0: So the store policy was that if he tried to return an open game.
Speaker 0: his only choices were either another copy of the same game or He could sell it back, you know, you sell it back to the store for like half price and then it kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: So he says, you know He argues with him a whole bunch and he gets the manager and he argues a whole bunch and he's like screw your store policy You bastards blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Finally he says fine I'll take a new copy of the same game and he takes it and then he goes over You know to hang with his kid who's looking at DS games, right?
Speaker 0: Then look a minute later.
Speaker 0: He goes back over to the counter.
Speaker 0: He says I have a game.
Speaker 0: It's in the package It's unopened and I have a receipt.
Speaker 0: I'm returning this for a refund.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: That guy's awesome.
Speaker 1: And they were basically like, oh That's very much like what I did when I needed to replace these sunglasses portion of my glasses.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had some glasses and law I think I might have told the story a long time ago, but someone stole the sunglasses that clip on to my glasses Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I go to the glasses place and I say yes, I lost my sunglasses part.
Speaker 1: Can I buy another one or something?
Speaker 1: I mean I was willing to just pay Because I mean I felt bad but someone stole it but it was my fault for leaving them on a table.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and They say I'm sorry you can you can't buy that separately.
Speaker 1: it comes with the whole frame set.
Speaker 1: and I said, oh well I have that warranty thing.
Speaker 1: So can I just get a new frame set?
Speaker 1: and they said no your glasses aren't broken.
Speaker 1: I said, okay and I left and then I broke my glasses in half and then I walked back in and I went through the Same deal and I got new glasses, you know It's like they could have.
Speaker 0: I mean you probably would have gladly traded in your perfectly Okay glasses for you know, the new ones with the same whatever's yeah, but instead now you gave them some broken ones.
Speaker 0: It's pretty stupid to them.
Speaker 0: Yep, they could have sold some used glasses for like half off or something.
Speaker 1: So did this guy's cunning plan work?
Speaker 0: Of course it did.
Speaker 0: I mean well, you know, they were real reluctant, but this line built up behind him and he made a scene.
Speaker 0: So the guy was like the guy at the store was like, yeah I'm gonna get in big trouble for this blood and he's like fuck you Give me my money in the game his money and then he left And his wife was waiting out in the car the whole time, but then she didn't care.
Speaker 0: She was all cool as she should be.
Speaker 1: so all right.
Speaker 0: So everyone out there you should know that if a game store refuses to take your return on a game But they have a policy allowing you to get a brand new unopened copy of the same game Do what this guy did and make a scene.
Speaker 0: don't be a wuss.
Speaker 1: in general whenever a company tries to screw you make a scene Because I mean, I don't want to.
Speaker 1: I don't want to suggest to you that you should always be that loud woman screaming and yelling.
Speaker 0: Well, because a lot of woman is yelling about something stupid.
Speaker 0: she's not in the right usually.
Speaker 0: Yeah Just a nut.
Speaker 1: or the crazy angry guy Standing off the outside the restaurant complaining that he saw a rat because he really just didn't have any money to pay.
Speaker 1: That's not cool.
Speaker 1: But if a company legitimately screwed you screw him right back.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, gotta be smart.
Speaker 0: Got a. you know when they have it's mostly stupid company policies.
Speaker 0: You got to beat the shit out of stupid company policies because companies make these things They don't think about them and you use them to get them just as much they use them to get you Yep.
Speaker 1: No, of course a lot of.
Speaker 1: sometimes they might just say ask you're the company policy, whatever go away We don't care.
Speaker 1: We don't want your business because you really have no recourse.
Speaker 0: at that point Call them BBB bees.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you realize how many complaints are lodged against companies?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh Jillian and no one really cares.
Speaker 1: It is so much to actually get a company without a lawyer.
Speaker 0: But it's um, it's like does a tiny bit.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so it's it's worth it.
Speaker 1: It's like bringing out those uh Whatever sorcerers and magic and tapping them every round.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Tim Tim Tim Tim some know me as Tim.
Speaker 1: So things of the day.
Speaker 1: I found this and I was sitting around bored waiting for something to finish at work And I thought it was rather amusing.
Speaker 1: It's basically a rundown of the differences between the North American release of Super Mario Brothers 2 AKA the weird screwy non-canon Mario - where it was all the dream and The Japanese game that it was based on called doki-doki panic.
Speaker 1: It basically goes down the list with screenshots and descriptions of every single thing.
Speaker 1: That's different between these two games.
Speaker 1: Doki-doki panic didn't look like it was that great of a game.
Speaker 0: Doki-doki panic is actually like you think I'll play the original real deal.
Speaker 0: No, it actually wasn't such a good game.
Speaker 1: And when they turned it into Mario - they made it a lot better Yep, and actually little-known fact that Super Mario 2 in the US was actually re-released and re-imported into Japan as Super Mario USA.
Speaker 0: that is correct.
Speaker 0: and Super Mario - Japan was brought over here inside the Super Mario all-stars cartridge and inside the Game Boy Color Super Mario Brothers cartridge as the Lost World Dun-dun-dun.
Speaker 0: Well lost levels lost levels lost worlds.
Speaker 0: Who cares?
Speaker 1: Yeah, all I got to say is that Super Mario 2 is one of my favorite games.
Speaker 0: I don't know actually not such a bad game when you when you get down to it Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not as good as no Mario 3, but it ain't bad.
Speaker 1: But you'd be surprised at some of the changes they made.
Speaker 1: I mean the game itself functions pretty much identically.
Speaker 1: But they changed some sprites and they're like one of them.
Speaker 1: they changed one of the vegetables so it looks different.
Speaker 1: I really can't figure that one out I don't know.
Speaker 0: one thing that weirded me out is that the the POW the POW bricks Which you know look just and work and look just like the POWs from plain old Mario Brothers were Unchanged except they changed the sound.
Speaker 0: but they didn't change the way they look which means doki-doki panic ripped off the pow-blip pow-brite.
Speaker 0: Yeah The POWs from the original Mario Brothers.
Speaker 1: The other interesting thing is that doki-doki panic You know in the Mario 2 a lot of the sprites are animated like the hearts do little wobbly-wobblies and everything's kind of animated.
Speaker 1: Nothing was animated in doki-doki panic.
Speaker 1: Everything was a static sprite.
Speaker 1: Just moving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really wasn't such a shiny game at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was largely forgotten until the internet brought it back.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, that's a good thing because I'm glad I know that.
Speaker 1: yeah And the site also has a nice comparison of Super Mario 3 in America versus in Japan.
Speaker 0: There really weren't too many differences with Mario 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Kuriboh shoe is red.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's not red It just it turns red when it gets hit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the main change is that in Mario 3 America if let's say you have you know The tanuki suit and you get hit you turn into just plain old Super Mario.
Speaker 0: But in the Japanese one if you're the tanuki suit and you get hit you turn into tiny Mario Which makes it a lot harder.
Speaker 0: So here's some other Mario.
Speaker 0: That's kind of Freaky like it freaked me out.
Speaker 1: I really don't know what to say to this.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what to say to it either.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna describe it and we'll move on save our sanity.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll say that while I was watching I kept thinking like there was this bearish memory of wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Do I know what this is?
Speaker 0: And no, I can't tell what the hell it is.
Speaker 0: It's it's definitely 80s.
Speaker 0: It reeks of 80s.
Speaker 1: It involves let's just say all the things it involves.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Belvedere ice Mario Koopa some 80s people a whole bunch of little kids Some toad girls who were kind of hot a computer virus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we're done.
Speaker 0: Yeah it starts out where it looks like some 80s teen show sort of like a Saved by the Bell but not and One guy's acting all 80s cool Like he's the video master and this hot chick that he's trying to hit on by telling her, you know He's so great at video games and they're trying to play Mario Super Mario Brothers the original Not playing Mario Brothers Super Mario Brothers.
Speaker 0: so and then it you know, he's watching it and as soon as she's about to play there's some virus that infects the Nintendo, I guess I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: and then all of a sudden mr Belvedere dressed as Koopa appears on the screen.
Speaker 0: and then you know, it zooms in on the TV and you see mr Belvedere dressed as Koopa and a bunch of bad guys dressed as Koopa Troopas and Whatever and it's Mario on Ice.
Speaker 1: you get like yes There's a bunch of little kids in the audience and it's like five.
Speaker 0: It's five to ten minutes at least of Mario on Ice for real.
Speaker 0: and Then after Mario on Ice it zooms back out to the the kid.
Speaker 0: but Mario and Ice is freaky.
Speaker 0: It's like The.
Speaker 0: the bad guy costumes are pretty good.
Speaker 0: The little kids are scary.
Speaker 0: the toad girls Some of them are alright.
Speaker 0: the princess talks in this weird voice.
Speaker 0: It's not a weird way that big boy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's one of those voices Which is kind of strange for like Princess Peach now that we know what she talks like Mario and Luigi's voices We're very definitely cartoon original captain Lou Albano style voices.
Speaker 0: That's good because that's the kind of Yeah, I like how Mario and Luigi talk in like the Mario and Luigi Superstar games where they're like What's the bottle?
Speaker 0: There's like gibbering Italian nothingness, it's just Italian noises that aren't words.
Speaker 0: but yeah They kill.
Speaker 0: they kill mr.
Speaker 0: Belvedere who's Koopa?
Speaker 0: and then You zoom back out to the scary 80s guy and he gets the girl.
Speaker 1: Don't forget Luigi.
Speaker 1: They don't jump on the bad guys and said Luigi has this like flamethrower and he just kills them all one by one.
Speaker 0: Luigi pulls a thing on this gun and like a spark bomb comes out and the bad guys just disappear.
Speaker 0: They must have a trapdoor or some sort of camera trick to make that happen because I don't know.
Speaker 1: this is one of the weirdest things I've seen in a while.
Speaker 1: just watch it and be Scared and if anyone knows what the hell that is the first one to tell us wins.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the site isn't very descriptive at all.
Speaker 0: Like where it came from.
Speaker 0: I guess it's just a video of Mario on Ice.
Speaker 0: That's the only thing I could think of it.
Speaker 1: if there was a Mario on Ice how come I was not there as a child?
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean I saw freaking like Beauty and the Beast on Ice.
Speaker 0: I think I saw at least at one Disney on Ice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I saw Muppet Babies live and I saw Sesame Street live.
Speaker 0: Oh Sesame Street live is the best of the count has his cannon.
Speaker 0: I saw that in the theater at Madison Square Garden when I was like three.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually like the Muppet one more.
Speaker 0: I never saw the Muppet one, but I made these.
Speaker 0: did I have the the guys in the little balcony going?
Speaker 1: It was Muppet Babies, oh Did have little baby old guys in the balcony going ha ha ha ha, you know, I don't even remember I was so young and I lived.
Speaker 0: I have no idea, you know, we got to do.
Speaker 0: we got Netflix a Muppet show.
Speaker 0: Yo, oh Yeah, so we got to do All right.
Speaker 1: So today we thought we would talk about a board game that Scott bought on a somewhat whim after playing once and we decided to play it with our friend Katsu.
Speaker 1: and And it's awesome, but it has a fatal flaw.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so a few weeks ago I played this game called fury of Dracula and it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's exactly like it sounds.
Speaker 0: it's it's about Dracula.
Speaker 1: It's really kind of cool.
Speaker 1: how the game works like playing.
Speaker 1: it is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a. it's not your typical board game.
Speaker 0: Where either?
Speaker 0: you know every.
Speaker 0: there are two kinds of board games I played in my life every man for himself where everyone's fighting against everyone else to see who can win.
Speaker 0: There's the other kind where you're trying to beat the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like there are a virus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there aren't too many games like this, but don't know.
Speaker 0: there's a third type of game, but I'll get to that Where you know the game itself has a winning condition built in and all the players are trying to manipulate Their pieces in such a way as to beat the game itself.
Speaker 0: Another type of game a board game that I know is Where there's a DM kind of like a hero quest where one guy or necromunda or doom the board game.
Speaker 0: Yeah Where it's like a walk around the map and kill guys and level up and collect items and there's a DM who kind of controls Everything and all the other players are cooperating but also competing for the best treasures.
Speaker 1: Or the Lord of the Rings game, which is every man for himself.
Speaker 1: But there's a secret winning condition where you could fuck everyone and become the Lord of the Rings game is try to beat the game But it's also every man for himself.
Speaker 0: Also every man for himself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you can win win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so fury of Dracula is a completely different type of game and that it's four versus one.
Speaker 0: It can also be three two or one versus one, but that it's one versus everyone else.
Speaker 0: One guy is Dracula and everyone else is the hunters trying to get track.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like Lord Golda Ming and Mina Harker.
Speaker 0: Lord Godalming, Mina Harker, Dr.
Speaker 0: Seward in Van Helsing.
Speaker 0: Yep, the four hunters trying to kill Dracula.
Speaker 0: So one guy has this there's a map of Europe and Dracula has a card for every spot on the map of Europe except for the church where he can't go and his well He has one for his own castle, but it's a special car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the castle see the thing is every card has the location on one side and a blank spot on the other side So you don't know where he is.
Speaker 0: But if he goes in the castle that card is double-sided.
Speaker 0: so you know where he goes.
Speaker 0: See the cards kind of enforce the rules and prevent, you know Dracula from screwing up.
Speaker 1: Yep It's basically a game of hide-and-seek.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Dracula goes around Europe and the hunters have to first find him.
Speaker 0: if they if Dracula can just stay He if he can run away from the hunters and not get caught by them.
Speaker 0: He can pretty much Kick royal ass like if time goes by where they don't know where Dracula is.
Speaker 0: He's gonna win.
Speaker 0: You know if you like is every time Dracula goes somewhere he leaves something evil there.
Speaker 0: So he has this trail That's X long and if the hunters don't come across Dracula's trail then the evil things in his trail mature and they can get Dracula a lot of points Like two points and he needs six points to win.
Speaker 1: Yep, and there's this day-night mechanic where like during the day the hunters are strong, but at night Dracula and his minions are strong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at night you don't want to like let up and try not to find Dracula cuz then you'll lose him.
Speaker 0: But at the same time you don't want to fight him cuz he'll bite you.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, and also the evil things in his trail are a little more powerful at night and all kinds of nasty stuff.
Speaker 0: But I truly it's.
Speaker 0: it's really fun for people you know working together and one guy at the table is Dracula trying to run away and figure out what to do and be secretive and Keep his poker face on.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There's definitely two games here.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're Dracula, I haven't actually been Dracula yet Scott's been Dracula once.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It seems like a totally different game, but at least from the hunters perspective It's you and three friends yelling and screaming and arguing and trying to figure out where Dracula is before he kills you all Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's real easy to figure out where he is and sometimes not so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of discussions Like alright, we know he was in Brussels.
Speaker 1: He was in Brussels two turns ago.
Speaker 1: Where did he go?
Speaker 1: I think he headed to Eastern Russia.
Speaker 1: Nobody's been over in Eastern Russia.
Speaker 1: You can't go back there.
Speaker 1: We these God of his fry trying to head for Ireland.
Speaker 1: Why would he go there?
Speaker 1: He has to go over the water and fuck the water.
Speaker 0: go anyway.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's a real lot of fun.
Speaker 0: the problem with this game takes the fucking ever.
Speaker 1: This game is like a three-hour game Like they're not kidding If generally whenever a game says how long it takes to play we cut that in half because we blow through games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if a game says one hour we play it in 30 minutes to 45 minutes.
Speaker 1: This game said two to three hours and took us three hours not even counting the time It took to teach me and Katsu how to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it took me a while.
Speaker 0: I think we spent a lot of time trying to figure out like what the different encounters meant because these little square encounters you have to learn what the symbols mean and the exactly what they do and all that and There are a lot of cards we had to stop and read.
Speaker 0: But even with that we still it wouldn't mean might have been able to cut it down to two and a half hours.
Speaker 0: getting rid of those complications, you know It still took a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm not sure if the fun of the game Completely mitigates the fact that it takes too long.
Speaker 0: There's also the problem that we played it late at night and we got tired.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even barring tiredness I could see how is.
Speaker 1: the game drags on I mean the tension rises but there's a point at which the tension just disappears and I'd rather the game end and not really care Who wins?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah that pretty much happens with any game no matter what.
Speaker 0: if it takes too long It's like I don't care anymore.
Speaker 0: Just want to finish playing this and do something else because you can only do it for so long.
Speaker 0: I also think that If you played with you know a full set of people that if you really got into it You can keep the excitement up of tree of you know, chasing Dracula a little longer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the primary fun of the game for the hunters is definitely interacting with the other hunters.
Speaker 0: Cuz you're not interacting with Dracula at all.
Speaker 1: Dracula sits there raising his eyebrows periodically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless he's Scott that he's staring intently at wherever he's hiding.
Speaker 0: Well, Dracula has a little tiny mini-map.
Speaker 1: it will get to that Alright, so I guess now we could just go into a kind of a technical discussion of the game itself and the mechanics within Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Now the map I mean is broken up into Eastern Europe and Western Europe Even though for some reason Italy is squarely in Eastern Europe.
Speaker 0: I don't know why that is.
Speaker 1: and maybe for game balance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are railroads all over the map.
Speaker 1: There are roads all over the map Reports.
Speaker 1: it has I mean as all of Europe even as Ireland.
Speaker 0: Yep oceans.
Speaker 1: There are big cities and little cities.
Speaker 1: Hunters can move by rails.
Speaker 1: They can move by roads.
Speaker 1: They can get in boats.
Speaker 1: Dracula can do anything except ride trains.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if Dracula rides on boats He loses blood and that's really the only way Dracula can lose if the hunters take away all his blood.
Speaker 0: So, you know if he has to run away to the ocean.
Speaker 0: He can usually lose the hunters at sea with by various means but at the same time He's gonna lose blood for doing that.
Speaker 0: so he can only do it so many times.
Speaker 1: Now every time a hunter goes to a city depending on what kind of city they and they're in larger smaller which hunter they are They can draw event cards and or item cards.
Speaker 1: Now items are things that they can just put in their stock and use to various effect things like holy water and crucifixes and garlic.
Speaker 1: They're all good.
Speaker 1: The best ones.
Speaker 1: I seem to think is the pistol.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the pistol is pretty good.
Speaker 0: The dogs are pretty good because the dogs can get rid of a lot of encounters, you know Some of the things that are really powerful like the holy water will be destroyed if you try to use them.
Speaker 0: See, it's like a one-shot super awesome thing.
Speaker 1: and then there are events.
Speaker 1: Now the deck seems to be.
Speaker 1: it's set up to where two-thirds of the cards are good events for the hunters And one-third are good events for Dracula and you draw from the bottom of the deck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well because on the back of the cards there's a symbol that lets you know if it's a Dracula event or a hunter event.
Speaker 0: So when you draw it, you don't know and looks at it.
Speaker 0: But if it's like a hunter event the hunters all look at it.
Speaker 0: And if it's a Dracula event Dracula looks at it.
Speaker 0: that way you don't know what the other team has.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's real scary.
Speaker 1: when you draw Dracula event, you know, fuck and you hand it over to him He looks at it and he smiles and then he puts it down face down and he just waits for you to continue with your Turn.
Speaker 0: well, it might be a play immediately event in which case he just reads it to you and then laughs Yeah, or it might be an ally in which case he puts it on the side of the board or throws it out.
Speaker 1: Yep Now there are multiple schools of thought in terms of events because on one hand there are more good events than bad events for the Hunters.
Speaker 1: so you want to draw as many events as you can all the time to get Dracula and some of those events are really Powerful like you.
Speaker 0: only there there are two ways for hunters to like immediately try to get Dracula with like superpowers of finding him And that's resolved which you get one resolve per day or events which can sometimes be as good as resolved.
Speaker 0: So, you know getting those events can really help you out if Dracula is really evasive.
Speaker 1: But at the same time the more events you draw the more events you're giving Dracula who has no other way to really get.
Speaker 0: Even he has one way to get events, but it's not easy.
Speaker 0: It's really kind of sketchy.
Speaker 0: So the main way of Dracula getting events is hunters drawing events from the bottom of the decking You know, yeah kill his events showing up.
Speaker 1: now the strategy I seem to see in general is that you should generally in the very early game take events because you need to track Dracula and You have no idea where he is.
Speaker 1: a lot of the events help you find him.
Speaker 1: at least they'll give you like the end of His trail.
Speaker 1: so, you know where to start or something like that.
Speaker 0: But once once you have an idea where he is Taking more events can you know hurt you because then he'll get away if the right one comes up.
Speaker 1: God the game.
Speaker 1: We played right away like right a freaking way.
Speaker 1: We found Dracula.
Speaker 0: Well, it was just random chance.
Speaker 0: You know I put my guy right next to the hunter hoping the hunter would go to any of the other four possible adjacent cities and then I would follow the Hunter around because they're always gonna try to go to someplace new.
Speaker 0: they'll you know, they think he was just there.
Speaker 1: He won't be there, but I thought before the game even started I'm gonna travel in circles because Dracula can't go to the same city twice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 0: I still get away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we caught him.
Speaker 1: we tracked him down its day.
Speaker 1: We're gonna go staking.
Speaker 1: then we drew an event and the event was Dracula can teleport anywhere for free.
Speaker 1: We about cried.
Speaker 0: Yep so happens.
Speaker 0: There is a certain amount of luck in the game But it can all it can be countered by a good strategy on the hunters and good strategy of Dracula.
Speaker 0: overall if Dracula Isn't good at getting away.
Speaker 0: He'll be caught and killed and if the hunters aren't good at finding him He'll get.
Speaker 0: Dracula will sneak up on them in the night and drink their blood.
Speaker 1: Now Dracula can leave these event tiles on the cards as he moves their encounter tiles.
Speaker 0: I think yeah.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Now base, I mean the way Dracula moves is he goes through his little deck of every city in the game.
Speaker 1: He takes this card of cities going to and he puts it face down on this track and then he can choose to put an Encounter on that.
Speaker 1: also face down if you go to a city You say I went to Brussels and then Dracula either has to show you the Brussels card from his little deck Which means he's not in Brussels or he hasn't been to Brussels recently Or he has to flip over whichever card in his track or in his catacombs.
Speaker 0: his Brussels Yeah, because if he's not holding it it must be either on the table in his track or in the catacomb.
Speaker 1: Yep, and if there's an event there, he flips over the event and now you have to deal with it.
Speaker 0: the events range from From wussy stuff to a guy with a rifle and a knife to kill you Yeah.
Speaker 1: or some bats or some fog or Some monsters a vampire.
Speaker 0: the new vampire is the tricky one because the new vampire If you come up on it during the day just dies.
Speaker 0: you kill it.
Speaker 0: If you come up on it during the night, it can kind of hurt you.
Speaker 0: But if you if Dracula puts a new vampire out in a city and you don't find that city and that city falls off the edge of the track And the vampire is still there Dracula gets one-third of the game closer to winning and that can.
Speaker 0: that's basically Dracula wins.
Speaker 0: Now you're in big trouble if a vampire falls off the edge So that that's Dracula's key Strategy is put the vampires somewhere the hunters won't find them and get them to fall off the edge of the map.
Speaker 1: now Obviously if you only have one of every card Dracula can't go to a place again until that card falls off the trail Mm-hmm, which means Dracula is forced to always keep moving.
Speaker 0: Dracula has a lot of restrictions on his movement Which makes it easier for the hunters to figure out where he is as they get information.
Speaker 0: You know a small amount of information plus knowing the rules of Dracula's movement can make it pretty easy to limit the places He could possibly be but it's it's never really possible without revealing a ton of information to a hundred percent know where he is and that's how he keeps getting away.
Speaker 1: is you know in That small percentage always being in the place The hunters don't try to go unless of course you corner him in a situation of well He's been here here and here and we know he's been there.
Speaker 1: The only place he could possibly be is here unless he used as a hiding card.
Speaker 0: Yep That's how if you get that's if you get a whole bunch of information.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean he has a couple of special movements like he can turn into a wolf and at night and jump to cities At night only.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if he used to use the card Yeah, he can't use it for a while and it informs everyone that he used the card.
Speaker 1: So, you know, ah crap He just jumped a city.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if Dracula hides that allows him to stay in a city for two nights Which is something you usually can't do but you won't know.
Speaker 0: he did that to you.
Speaker 0: It looks like he moved somewhere.
Speaker 0: But then if you end up in that city, there are two nasty things there now, yeah, it's not great.
Speaker 1: And there are all sorts of tricks like in Ireland.
Speaker 1: There's only two cities.
Speaker 1: So if he starts in Ireland for whatever reason he can stay there two or at most three days.
Speaker 1: if he hides one of those Days then he has to get in the water.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, of course I can think of a lot of tricks like starting somewhere other than Ireland Going for two days going into the water coming right back where you came from in the water.
Speaker 0: Oh, there are lots of nasty tricks If you look at the map real carefully like they're things you can do to really confuse the hunters.
Speaker 0: going to the Atlantic Ocean is one of them because if you Dracula goes the Atlantic Ocean you can pretty much tell when he's in the Atlantic Ocean based because when he goes out to sea he Puts these blue cards down and he loses blood and he can't put nasty things at the sea.
Speaker 0: And he goes the Atlantic Ocean and then he plays two more sea cards and then he plays a land card.
Speaker 0: There's like a million possibilities of where he could be.
Speaker 0: It's kind of scary You know.
Speaker 0: It's like you look at the map and it's like, oh wow He could be anywhere crap.
Speaker 0: That's how the guy when we played against him kept getting away.
Speaker 0: So you go to the Atlantic Ocean go to two more seas get back on land.
Speaker 0: Then we got to close back in the Atlantic Ocean.
Speaker 0: Now his blood but he got away.
Speaker 1: when you do run into Dracula or a minion you had there's a combat mechanism in the game.
Speaker 1: That's kind of subpar but it kind of works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the combat is kind of a. I mean you roll dice Which is the air part?
Speaker 1: Yep, you roll dice and then you refer depending on what an item card or attack card you used Versus what item or attack the opponent used.
Speaker 1: you have a little lookup table and you figure out what the event was.
Speaker 1: So you basically I play a knife card and he plays a claw card.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like advanced rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, if I have a claw and he has a knife and I win we look on his knife card Right for the word claw.
Speaker 1: No, we look at your knife your claw card for the word knife.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So if I play a claw and he plays a knife and I win we look on my card for the word knife and next To it.
Speaker 0: It says what happens and Vice versa.
Speaker 0: if his knife wins we look on his knife card for the word claw and we find out what happens.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: hunters have health.
Speaker 1: They can also be bitten by Dracula which basically kills them.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it basically kills me in a Harker.
Speaker 0: for the other hunters It can help and hurt them to be bitten But if they're bitten twice they'll die, but van Helsing can be bitten three times because he's a badass.
Speaker 1: Yep Now a hunter dying doesn't kick him out of the game it basically just fucks you because Dracula gets two points just like he'd matured a vampire and You lose all your items and you wake up in that Church of Jesus and Mary in Eastern Europe all alone And
Speaker 0: then you lose a turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which means you can't be looking for Dracula in that turn and he can't be in the church.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, yeah Mina Harker getting bitten and dying in our previous game is the main reason Dracula won even though we almost killed him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well Mina Harker starts out with one bite and one more bite will kill her.
Speaker 0: so a key strategy for Dracula is do I want to reveal my location and run right after her to bite her and kill her or Do I want to stay hidden and just try to wait it out and win?
Speaker 0: I Basically waited it out.
Speaker 1: And then when I had my chance I went after and bitter Yep, now each hunter has a power like a minor power and Val help van Helsing.
Speaker 0: I almost said van Halen Dude, we should replace it with van Halen.
Speaker 1: We should get a little van Halen now figure awesome.
Speaker 1: His power is one that he can be bitten an extra time.
Speaker 1: He's that badass and he can Take an action after he's already taken an action if he kills something.
Speaker 1: So anytime he kills something he gets to take another action.
Speaker 0: Well, normally if you go to a city You get to you move.
Speaker 0: Everyone's turn is move.
Speaker 0: take an action.
Speaker 0: Dracula's turn is move the clock.
Speaker 0: move Dracula take an action.
Speaker 0: but Dracula's action is putting the little encounters on the little car on the cities.
Speaker 0: the hunters.
Speaker 0: action is Taking event and item cards, but if there's an encounter in a city they go to.
Speaker 0: they don't take item and event cards.
Speaker 0: Their action is spent dealing with the encounter.
Speaker 0: Helsing gets the advantage that if he deals with an encounter like let's say there's some bats Normally you deal with the bats.
Speaker 0: your turn is over.
Speaker 0: van Helsing can deal with the bats and still take item and event cards.
Speaker 0: Cuz he's so cool.
Speaker 1: Yep Now Mina's already bitten and there's a mechanic where if you're bitten Dracula gets bonuses against you and he can see some of the cards you've got all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz he can control your mind and shit like that.
Speaker 0: But yeah There's one advantage to being bitten and that's that some the other hunters can hypnotize you to find out where Dracula is.
Speaker 1: yep, and because Mina's always bitten you can always do that.
Speaker 1: now Mina's actual normal power other than that is that she can basically draw two Events when she resupplies or two items.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Are you good the Lord?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't talk about training We didn't talk about trains, but there Dracula can only go on the roads or in the water.
Speaker 1: hunters can also use trains.
Speaker 0: That's basically how they catch Dracula once they know where he is.
Speaker 0: They use those trains and they catch right up to him.
Speaker 0: So we can't run away.
Speaker 0: All you can do is hide.
Speaker 1: the trains are semi-random.
Speaker 1: You have to roll this die and basically you either get to move one two or three spaces or you don't get to move at All or you lose your turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah The train can kind of suck.
Speaker 0: and the other thing is that trains in Eastern Europe suck and trains in Western your know trains in Western Europe trains in Eastern Europe suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Russian trains pieces of crap They're all yellow on the board.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's basically this one spot and it dies is two three And if you roll that number that is a one out of six.
Speaker 0: chance that you roll it, of course It's a six-sided die, of course, of course.
Speaker 0: and if you roll that number and you're in Western Europe you move three spaces.
Speaker 0: and if you if you're in Eastern Europe you move Two spaces.
Speaker 1: now the Lord's power is that he gets to roll the die again.
Speaker 1: if he doesn't like the result He's just so rich.
Speaker 0: Yeah But he has to suffer with the second result no matter what it is.
Speaker 0: So if he gets a one and he wanted a two or more and he rolls a zero oops Then doesn't he get a bonus against fighting people or something?
Speaker 0: He gets something else.
Speaker 0: It's not so useful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then there's dr.
Speaker 1: Seward.
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 0: Seward is who I was when I was a hunter.
Speaker 0: He's actually pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yep now there's a mechanic of instead of taking items you can rest which basically heals the hunter.
Speaker 1: and The drawback to that is that if you rest you draw two event cards and if they're good events for the hunters you throw them.
Speaker 1: But if they're Dracula events they take effect.
Speaker 0: So basically just it.
Speaker 0: basically letting Dracula draw two event cards.
Speaker 1: if you try to get your health back Now the doctor you only draw one if you're near the doctor when you heal or if the doctor tries to heal himself.
Speaker 0: Yep, so if you're thinking about getting some blood back the the doctor you had to go near the doctor.
Speaker 0: But at the same time that means you know when hunters get together they can like form hunting groups and stuff.
Speaker 0: But you're really limiting your ability to search for Dracula when you do that.
Speaker 1: Yep, you do that.
Speaker 1: Basically when you know where he is, you're hunting him down and he doesn't have any events left.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if all the hunters get together they can move together and you know take items and events together and if they do that They're really powerful.
Speaker 0: and if they catch Dracula like that, they can pretty much kick his ass.
Speaker 0: You know as long as me and Harker is not in the group then she'll just die Because Dracula will just go for her and forget about the rest and bite away.
Speaker 1: So I guess in conclusion this game is generally awesome and it's really really fun to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah but if you Get bored from sitting there too long Either the people you're playing with they're running out of energy or they can't concentrate on it that long Then it might not be the best game to play too often.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't bring this game to a party or It's something you want to plan ahead for be ready for and get all into it.
Speaker 0: if you're not all into it It's not worth it because you know if this game was an hour long you play it all the freaking time But because it's two or three hours you gotta you know Ration it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We're definitely not bringing it to Tarkov this weekend.
Speaker 1: There's no way we'd have a chance to play it.
Speaker 0: No, we'll bring Kayla's probably and something else.
Speaker 1: Yeah every other board game we own.
Speaker 0: No, not every one of them.
Speaker 1: Well, no, we're not bringing a strategic.
Speaker 1: Oh,
Speaker 0: but if you're looking for a good you know nighttime activity for you and for friends or You know, you got a weekend with nothing to do and a bunch of people are real bored But they're ready to get into something long and invest time into something great then Furia Dracula is really good and you know, it doesn't require as much Difficulty as like a war game or something, but it's just as much fun strategies.
Speaker 1: And once again in closing this weekend if you're in the Rochester area, we're going to be doing our first live Official show at a con at Tora con at the Rochester Institute of Technology.
Speaker 0: So show up and see us.
Speaker 1: if you're close by and if you miss that we're also doing a show at Otacon.
Speaker 0: Oh tuck on in Baltimore in August.
Speaker 0: Yep, and you know join the forum send us email.
Speaker 0: Don't forget we have a logo contest if you make the geek night's logo that we end up using we give you money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're actually looking at the submissions and talking about them and thinking and we're hoping to see more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't have any sort of deadline But that doesn't mean you just wait around forever because we're gonna pick one as soon.
Speaker 0: basically as soon as we see one.
Speaker 0: That's good enough.
Speaker 0: We're gonna pick it.
Speaker 0: So if you have one that's even better than that, but you don't get it in before then that's how you're gonna lose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, once we pick one, we're probably not going to unpick it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it's gonna be sort of a permanent thing.
Speaker 0: So, you know don't rush but don't be lax.
Speaker 1: All right slackers.
Speaker 1: and That was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.