Speaker 0: It's Tuesday December 12th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We talk a bit about the virtual console on the Nintendo Wii and more importantly ice hockey for the NES.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Man, I got to say the fact that it's December 12th, and I still don't need to wear a coat to work.
Speaker 1: I wore a coat To work a couple weeks ago, but today I just carried it around with me.
Speaker 0: It was 55 and sunny.
Speaker 1: It wasn't sunny where I was it was just gray all the time really.
Speaker 0: it was actually sunny down in Yonkers all day Everywhere I go.
Speaker 1: it's gray, but it's not cold definitely not cold.
Speaker 0: Well, the best thing is I looked at the forecast and not only is it gonna be sunny pretty much all week But it's supposed to get sunnier and warmer this weekend.
Speaker 1: They might be lying.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think any.
Speaker 0: as far as I'm concerned winter doesn't exist anymore.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: It hasn't snowed here, and it's not gonna.
Speaker 0: It's gonna stay 55 and sunny right up until May when it's suddenly gonna be 95 and humid again Yeah, and then we'll have snow in July instead now.
Speaker 0: It'll just never snow again.
Speaker 1: I think it's gonna snow.
Speaker 0: I'm absolutely certain it won't and in fact.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to put up absolutely nothing to back that argument up.
Speaker 1: What a great bet.
Speaker 1: that just shows how sure you are like.
Speaker 0: I'll bet a negative cent.
Speaker 0: no no I'll bet you a thousand space dollars.
Speaker 1: Oh great.
Speaker 1: That's worth so much.
Speaker 0: thousand space dollars is worth like negative a hundred real dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's not too good in space.
Speaker 1: They got too much inflation The expanding universe and all that was.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if that was funny or lame I don't know either, but I laughed.
Speaker 0: so I guess you win, okay?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: so in the video gaming news because there really isn't so much useful video gaming news lately.
Speaker 0: I mean stuff.
Speaker 0: We really want to talk about.
Speaker 0: we can talk for my video game news and my video game news But there's a bunch of little things that really aren't like.
Speaker 0: there's a story that the ps3 is Not really selling for much on eBay anymore.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of them out there yet the Wii is selling out and going for just as much money.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah, there's all those stories.
Speaker 0: But now the one I want to talk about is something that Takes me off on a number of levels and it's relevant compared to what we talked about yesterday.
Speaker 0: You see valve and it's infinite wisdom according to numerous sources has decided that they're going to put advertisements in counter-strike 1.6 and then in the future they're going to put these same advertisements in counter-strike source.
Speaker 0: They're going to have them on blank walls in the game on the scoring screen and in the letterboxed areas in spectator mode.
Speaker 0: They're gonna be dynamic.
Speaker 0: They talk more in detail about how they're gonna be dynamic and all that And they didn't really answer a lot of the questions I have.
Speaker 0: as to you know how the ads are going to be served?
Speaker 0: aka can I block them with a hosts file?
Speaker 0: Yeah, or you know, but what they're hot just exactly how they're gonna do this.
Speaker 0: Are they gonna let the ads be deformed in game?
Speaker 0: Because then I would totally just spray-paint pornography over any ads I saw.
Speaker 0: But if they don't let them be deformed and that really kind of takes away from the game It does, you know, it's really kind of weird because counter-strike has always been this free game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's made it a huge game in the first place.
Speaker 1: And what is it still?
Speaker 1: the number one online game?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think it's fallen from number one recently, but not that long ago.
Speaker 1: There still had to be tens of thousands of people playing counter-strike.
Speaker 1: I can't believe that there aren't.
Speaker 0: Oh if you if you add up counter-strike and counter-strike source together, it still has a lot of players.
Speaker 0: It has I'd say in terms of numbers of people.
Speaker 0: over time counter-strike has been One of the greatest runs in the history of a popular online FPS.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what it comes down to is the counter-strike has always been a free game.
Speaker 1: So everyone no one's willing to pay money for counter-strike.
Speaker 0: A lot of people did buy just counter-strike because they were dumb.
Speaker 0: Well, they didn't realize that you could go to the bargain bin.
Speaker 1: Well, you buy half-life half-life worth money.
Speaker 0: Well, you could buy half-life for like five bucks right before they start because they counter-strike used to just be a mod for half-life.
Speaker 0: You had to buy half-life and then counter-strike and all those other mods were free.
Speaker 0: Then half-life hadn't been sold for a long time, you know, it came out like these platinum collections and whatever But it wasn't an expensive game anymore.
Speaker 0: They decided to sell for like 29 bucks.
Speaker 0: Maybe it was less than that counter-strike in a box and it was brother bought that it was.
Speaker 1: it was the worst because they changed The weapon names.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah among other things.
Speaker 0: It was the weapon.
Speaker 1: names are still chain.
Speaker 0: It was just counter-strike and people bought that because they didn't realize that you could buy half-life Which includes counter-strike and every other mod ever for like five bucks.
Speaker 0: if that you could find it for free.
Speaker 0: usually Mmm, just go to someone's house and take it.
Speaker 0: They weren't playing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the worst thing was if you paid $30 for counter-strike, you didn't get half-life you couldn't.
Speaker 1: it was like oh shit.
Speaker 0: So I can pay five bucks for half-life and counter-strike or I can pay 30 bucks for counter-strike.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, shitty your counter-strike than the real one - but it didn't really matter.
Speaker 0: I mean counter-strike was Rampantly popular for reasons.
Speaker 0: We don't really need to get into until we eventually do a show on counter-strike.
Speaker 1: Oh, we should do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should.
Speaker 0: I had a lot to say about that game The good and the bad and hilarious most of the hilarious But the what bothers me and here's the real issue the fact that they're trying to put advertisements in this game.
Speaker 0: While it annoys me and bothers me and it would it's a big reason that I might not ever bother playing counter-strike again Even though it used to be one of my favorite games.
Speaker 0: I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna deal with Advertisements that I can't get rid of in a game that I paid for or got for free.
Speaker 0: if I didn't pirate it Now if I'd pirated the game, I might feel bad about it.
Speaker 0: But now they gave it away free and now they're changing it on me.
Speaker 0: What bothers me is that it's the same thing that happened with tribes - valve owns the game.
Speaker 0: They give it away for free.
Speaker 0: They sell it whatever but in order to play the game online They make you authenticate with these servers that they control that no one else can run.
Speaker 0: They effectively hold over me the power to just deny me access to this game at any time or Change it and not give me the option to unchange it or just take it away forever.
Speaker 0: Tribes the same thing happened.
Speaker 0: The game was taken away.
Speaker 0: You can't get CD keys anymore without a lot of hacking and various shenanigans.
Speaker 0: You cannot play tribes - online Even if you bought it in many cases
Speaker 1: Mmm,
Speaker 0: and the fact that they can change the game and put these ads in Despite the fact that the servers they provide don't really do anything And in fact the actual servers you pay on play on are provided by people like us running them in our houses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like on the one hand I can see the need for the ads in that.
Speaker 1: All right Counter-Strike is a game That's always been free.
Speaker 1: They have they run a lot of expensive powerful computers and they have a lot of developers working on it over time.
Speaker 1: You know all all the time to improve upon this free game just because it's so popular And yet they make nothing off of it.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except that other mods that were just as good Also made nothing or almost nothing.
Speaker 0: It didn't have to resort to this y'all.
Speaker 1: those develop because those mods were things developers made in order to get real jobs.
Speaker 1: and now Valve hired them all and is paying the money.
Speaker 0: Yeah except the thing is valve doesn't seem to remember or realize that Counter-Strike was pretty much the only reason people actually use steam.
Speaker 0: back in the day when steam was announced and came out it was almost universally reviled as being stupid and most people myself included only Downloaded it in order to make our ability to play Counter-Strike easier and better.
Speaker 0: Yeah and to me The only reason Counter-Strike even exists for them from a business perspective is to trick people into getting steam and then paying for other games.
Speaker 0: Of course, I guess it doesn't matter anymore.
Speaker 0: counter-strikes been on the decline for many years.
Speaker 0: A lot of people don't like counter-strike source.
Speaker 0: Hence.
Speaker 0: They keep playing counter-strike 1.6.
Speaker 0: Yep, and To me that was just the final nail in the coffin.
Speaker 0: if they actually put ads and counter-strike source I'll probably just never bother playing it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah to be perfectly honest.
Speaker 1: I really I know I haven't played counter-strike in years.
Speaker 1: I don't really have a need to play it.
Speaker 1: I mean if they didn't put ads in it, I might have pulled it out now and again.
Speaker 1: I probably never in my life ads or not become heavy into counter-strike again.
Speaker 0: Well, no because there are games like natural selection.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I every now and then have the urge to play counter-strike and I had a lot of good memories playing counter-strike.
Speaker 0: But if I have to sit there dealing with coke ads while I'm playing counter-strike a game that I barely want to play to Begin with there's just no way no way.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you're right about the whole DRM thing is like why should?
Speaker 1: it's a video game that I bought, you know If this patches I should be able to choose if I want those patches or not.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't be able to deny me.
Speaker 1: I mean technically they're giving you a license to play the game and they agree.
Speaker 1: But you know, there's the license agreement which means they can revoke it whatever whatever.
Speaker 1: but is it right?
Speaker 1: I mean, what if Nintendo gave everyone Super Mario Brothers back in 82, right?
Speaker 1: And then that Super Mario Brothers that we originally got for the NES Depended on some servers at Nintendo in order to play.
Speaker 1: and in 1985 they changed level 2 - 1.
Speaker 1: They just changed the level and now it was impossible for anyone anywhere to play level 2 - 1 in the old way ever again.
Speaker 1: And then let's say a few years later.
Speaker 1: They just turn Mario 1 off.
Speaker 1: now No one in the whole world can play Mario 1 ever again.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of control that valve has now has over games like counter-strike see a steam.
Speaker 1: It's really kind of control that people like Blizzard have of a World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: It's really a loss because a lot of our listeners and us really want to play tribes, too.
Speaker 0: We all own it or can get it for free because they actually gave it away for free.
Speaker 0: There's no reason Absolutely, no technical reason in the world that we couldn't run a tribes to server and play a game right now Except that they no longer give out CD keys and they're not maintaining anything.
Speaker 0: But even though they're not maintaining anything the game requires their servers to function even though those servers provide No gameplay mechanic whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I'm sure there are hacks and wares and all sorts of things that we can do but you know technically illegal and Annoying and difficult and not really I don't really want to deal with it.
Speaker 1: I'd rather you know, I don't want to deal with ads.
Speaker 0: I'm definitely not gonna deal with that hassle Yeah, especially not to mention dangerous since most hacks these days include some sort of malware.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're talking about windows here too.
Speaker 1: These things don't run on Linux.
Speaker 1: So well, I mean the tribes twos and counter-strike servers run on Linux, but the games not so much anyway, so my news is It's kind of weird because every video game site had this news all over the place today and I was like What's the big deal?
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 1: And then I was like, oh once I finally, you know sort of Consciously understood what they were saying.
Speaker 1: The news is pretty simple Dragon Quest 9 is gonna be on the DS.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 1: Yep, if you don't know what Dragon Quest is, it's Dragon Warrior which is.
Speaker 1: you know the game with the slimes and the Drake ease and the The big stone golems.
Speaker 0: I believe the word is Drake Drake II.
Speaker 0: You know English works, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah How is it spelled in the in the game?
Speaker 0: dr a ke.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it had either two E's or a Y. No, or possibly just dr a K.
Speaker 0: It was dr a ke whatever.
Speaker 1: It's a tricky.
Speaker 1: anyway If you don't know about Dragon Warrior, or maybe you've only experienced it in the u.s.
Speaker 1: It is Stupid huge in Japan.
Speaker 1: We're talking stupid huge on a level You can't possibly comprehend.
Speaker 1: as big as Halo were.
Speaker 1: Freaking Grand Theft Auto is here.
Speaker 0: That's bigger than Jesus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's how a big Dragon Quest is in Japan.
Speaker 1: There are laws that they made in Japan that you can't release this kind of game on certain days of the week Because people won't go to work and they'll go wait in line to get the game and play it all day.
Speaker 1: You know, this is the kind of shit that like halts the Japanese economy when Dragon Quest comes out now.
Speaker 1: Dragon Quest has always been on the most popular system.
Speaker 1: It was on the NES slash Famicom.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: think that was there an SNES one.
Speaker 1: I don't remember, you know There was a PlayStation 1 and then it was on the PlayStation 2.
Speaker 1: The fact that it's moving to the DS is basically saying the DS is now the number one system in Japan.
Speaker 0: PS2 is dead, which is pretty much true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind of crazy though It's like imagine if Grand Theft Auto and everything started coming out for the Wii and Wasn't on the ps3 or the Xbox 360.
Speaker 1: That's what this is.
Speaker 1: Like that.
Speaker 1: That is how big this news is now.
Speaker 1: They didn't actually say it's not coming out for the ps2 But the fact that they just said yes coming out for the DS and they didn't say anything else It's it's basically 90% sure that it's not coming out for anything else.
Speaker 1: The other thing that's interesting about this news Is that traditionally like Dragon Quest sub games have come out for the Gameboy like Dragon Quest monsters and dragon?
Speaker 1: rocket slime.
Speaker 1: Those are good games.
Speaker 1: But here is like the net the sequel in the main series of games coming out for the DS.
Speaker 1: that would be like if Final Fantasy 13 came out for the DS and didn't come out for anything else.
Speaker 1: It's insane.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like I've said many times for me until the week came out The DS was my primary gaming console.
Speaker 0: as in I played games on my DS in Situations where I'd normally play whatever game I opened at the time or whatever console I owned.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other thing is this game is gonna have some four player online co-op action.
Speaker 1: So really this might actually be a game that we're gonna want to buy when they bring it over to this side of the ocean.
Speaker 1: If they do which I'm sure they will they'd better because the game is just so huge and I love The other thing.
Speaker 1: the last thing I want to say is in this article They had this little light image and it shows a bunch of slimes holding up a Japanese flag and then one slime holding up an American flag to show the difference in popularity of the game and the two countries.
Speaker 0: Now does that represent any sort of number or is it just a graphic someone made?
Speaker 1: It's just a graphic.
Speaker 1: It's really cute with a bunch of slimes.
Speaker 0: Oh God.
Speaker 0: Yeah things of the day Man, I said it the way I used to say it.
Speaker 0: Okay, people seem to like that.
Speaker 1: I guess then whatever I don't really care.
Speaker 0: So go first or should I you know what I'll go first?
Speaker 0: mines real quick.
Speaker 1: Mine's also real quick.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, so USB has spawned a lot of very useful things.
Speaker 0: There's also spawned a lot of very silly things.
Speaker 1: Well, it's useful in that it's it's a plug that almost every device now has and it provides power as well as data.
Speaker 1: So if you want to plug something into USB, you can just get electricity out of it.
Speaker 0: So there are even devices like Flashlights that plug into USB.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm They're USB cell phone chargers, you know that they just charge your cell phone by taking electricity from the computer into the Cellphone there.
Speaker 0: Well, it just so happens that someone has made perhaps the most perfect Combination of stupid thing and useful thing ever.
Speaker 0: in the face of the Internet mankind and computing.
Speaker 1: It can't be the best.
Speaker 0: Well, you see what they did is they took a USB memory stick.
Speaker 0: You know one that holds memory.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and they took a humping dog Like a real dog like a little plastic dog.
Speaker 0: Okay, where his member would be is a USB port USB connector sticking out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you plug it into a USB device It will begin humping the data into the computer.
Speaker 0: That's just hilarious, I don't know what else I can say about that.
Speaker 1: I think that might be the best USB stick ever.
Speaker 1: definitely beats out the USB sushi sticks.
Speaker 0: all I have to say is some of the things that showed up as Related videos probably don't want to watch no.
Speaker 1: Oh god, then they're not donkey shows, but God Yeah, mine mine is a donkey show.
Speaker 1: speaking of donkeys.
Speaker 1: Oh My Thing of the day is pretty simple.
Speaker 1: It's Mega Man versus Donkey Kong.
Speaker 1: now You might have seen that video Halo versus Donkey Kong where the halo guys come in and they shoot you know with their guns and they take over Donkey Kong Pretty easily.
Speaker 1: Well, this one has Mega Man fighting Donkey Kong.
Speaker 1: and you know, if I compare this video with the halo one I think the Mega Man could kick the halo.
Speaker 0: guys asses easily How much damage Mega Man has taken in the course of his career.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's true and he is a robot so it doesn't actually do anything permanent.
Speaker 1: as long as he makes it out alive Dr.
Speaker 1: Light fixes him up.
Speaker 0: So I mean he's got all those powers.
Speaker 0: He can throw stuff like guts man and he can throw stuff like dust man.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Depends how many guys he's already beaten.
Speaker 0: Well, you know cannon wise he's beaten a whole bunch of guys.
Speaker 0: for some reason He just loses the powers all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what's up with that.
Speaker 1: by the time you're playing Mega Man 7 You think you should have like, you know, six times eight forty eight different weapons to choose from.
Speaker 0: see I think it's like Legend of Zelda where the timeline keeps branching and They're actually all those Mega Man's happen at the exact same time.
Speaker 1: No, actually they kind of they have this story that actually connects them all and that that's the cannon.
Speaker 1: It's kind of scary.
Speaker 0: So then why does he lose his cannon?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: This doesn't make sense.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go read online and so I'm sure there's an explanation for it that someone came up with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 1: Light and common in could be he is a crazy old man.
Speaker 1: Now the funny thing that if dr.
Speaker 1: Light, you know knew so much He wouldn't need to make Mega Man to solve the problem.
Speaker 1: He could just do it himself.
Speaker 0: All right, here's what I don't get.
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 0: Wily keeps breaking out of whatever hellhole they lock him in making giant robot masters to come and destroy the world.
Speaker 0: Why don't they the next time they catch?
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 0: Wily just shoot him.
Speaker 1: they did But then it was really like a robot or it was a clone or it was a. you know They didn't actually catch him because dr.
Speaker 1: Wily is too smart.
Speaker 1: He's all wily.
Speaker 1: He gets away.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure they caught him at least one at least in this instance.
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 1: Wily is pretty stupid.
Speaker 1: He chose Donkey Kong to be a robot master.
Speaker 1: considering Donkey.
Speaker 1: No, I think neither a robot nor a man.
Speaker 1: I think doggy cows a bad.
Speaker 0: primary problem was that being not a robot it took one Mega Man pellet To take him out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much Thing is I predicted accurately the end of this video and if you don't also predict accurately the ending of this video before it comes Up, I think you might have some mental difficulties there.
Speaker 1: If that is the case, I sentence you to play Mega Man 2 until you beat it two times.
Speaker 0: You know, I never beat Mega Man 2. you suck or four or five or six or seven or any of the exes or one.
Speaker 1: It should be five.
Speaker 1: five is the proto man one.
Speaker 0: See the other thing is I never even tried.
Speaker 0: I never liked Mega Man games.
Speaker 1: you suck.
Speaker 0: I own mega.
Speaker 0: I try guide Mega Man 3 because I traded some kid hide lied for it.
Speaker 1: Three's the second best one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I usually just cheated and ran around exploring glitches.
Speaker 0: I never actually tried to beat the game and that game was glitchy as all hell.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the glitches were great.
Speaker 0: I had more fun with the glitches than ever did.
Speaker 0: I never even got to dr.
Speaker 0: Wily, I don't think.
Speaker 1: one time I was playing Mega Man 2 and I was fighting bubble man and The gate opened up and I actually went backwards into the waiting room again.
Speaker 1: Then I went back into the bubble man room and it was all fucked up and I had to reset my NES man when I was A kid.
Speaker 0: I loved it when that happened.
Speaker 0: now, I hate it when that happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yep, the winds of change are Changing so we doing the show on.
Speaker 0: I think we're gonna do the show on the virtual console.
Speaker 0: Oh, alrighty see more specifically probably the greatest sports game ever to be made for any video game system ever Worth about a million space dollars is ice hockey.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The game is called ice hockey.
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's like in television.
Speaker 1: what's the name of the football game on television?
Speaker 1: It's not called Madden something something It's not called 10 yard fight.
Speaker 1: It's not called Tecmo Super Bowl, even though Tecmo Super Bowl is the best football game.
Speaker 0: It's called football Football.
Speaker 1: and what's the ice hockey game on the NES called besides blades of steel, which is almost as good.
Speaker 1: It's almost as good.
Speaker 1: It's called ice hockey.
Speaker 0: now You see the reason we want to talk about ice hockey is partly because we want to talk about the virtual console Which is both one of the best things and the worst things of the Nintendo Wii.
Speaker 0: Mmm You see the the concept is great.
Speaker 0: Nintendo has a very large library of old intellectual property.
Speaker 0: That is not making them very much money at all.
Speaker 1: If any yeah I used to complain like it's not right for them to make ROMs illegal.
Speaker 1: These things are no longer available.
Speaker 1: No one is making money off of this intellectual property.
Speaker 1: Therefore it is not morally wrong to just take it and copy it and keep it alive and in the world.
Speaker 1: But now that argument doesn't work anymore Which is good and bad.
Speaker 0: Nintendo is very smart and they realize from you know years of outcry that their fans Really like their old games and as they learn from releasing compilations of old You know Super Nintendo and such games for the GameCube people will buy Zelda 1 and Zelda 2 and ice climbers again and again and again because they love these games.
Speaker 0: People want to play old Nintendo games a lot.
Speaker 0: They sure do so in the Wii in addition to having you know All the games you can buy for it and the games you can buy for the GameCube.
Speaker 0: that works just fine on it.
Speaker 0: You can also buy virtual console games which range from NES to SNES to TurboGrafx-16 to Sega Genesis.
Speaker 0: They're based basically an emulator.
Speaker 0: you can just buy these games from Nintendo straight up legitimately a hundred percent accurate and play them in your Wii with Absolutely zero effort difficulty or problem whatsoever.
Speaker 1: That is what they do.
Speaker 1: have one significant advantage over emulators and that it always works easily.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, most people don't have any problem.
Speaker 1: if you know how to use an emulator.
Speaker 1: You don't have really a problem with NES and SNES Emulation because it's so well done that these days the NES and SNES emulators are so good that everything works great.
Speaker 1: But Genesis emulators even today, they're a little bit flaky.
Speaker 1: You know, you can't always get them to go full screen to work Right.
Speaker 1: There's no way you're gonna get Sega CD and 32x stuff to be a turbo graphics.
Speaker 0: I've never.
Speaker 1: even I'm pretty sure there are turbo graphics emulators, but don't ask me what to name one or how they work.
Speaker 1: It's you know, and I don't imagine that they work as well as ZSNES or SNES 9x.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz watch there's like a half of a person working on that project.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you've got MAME which works really well, but you know, no no MAME works really well when it works.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem with MAME is that since every arcade game is different that the controls are often confusing You need to reconfigure them for each game a little bit.
Speaker 0: Also many ROMs for various reasons are dumped incorrectly or formatted wrong and just don't work.
Speaker 1: Well, that's you have to go to the right places to download, you know The big ROM packs that have every MAME ROM ever.
Speaker 1: and yeah It's just too many MAME games and most of the games are not worth playing and also total speculation.
Speaker 0: Probably not true yet, but I could see this happening in the future.
Speaker 0: This is something that I really am hoping for.
Speaker 0: DS can connect to the Wii and theoretically there are a lot of ways they could use that.
Speaker 0: Say in addition to having Sega Genesis and all these games.
Speaker 0: They also have Sega Game Gear games And say you could download them temporarily to your DS to play them on the go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no reason.
Speaker 1: they couldn't turn the the Wii into like a DS download machine.
Speaker 1: So you could just turn on your Wii choose a virtual console game turn on your DS and click download play And then the virtual console game would go to your DS.
Speaker 1: There's no reason that isn't technologically feasible.
Speaker 0: I am certain that that is going to happen.
Speaker 0: I am absolutely certain that at some point maybe not right now maybe not for a year, but I Nintendo is definitely looking into that.
Speaker 0: That is my opinion.
Speaker 1: I'm not certain just because over in the history there have always been many things which are as equally important and intelligent to do that haven't been done that There's gonna be something just like that.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not everything that could happen is gonna happen because it's never been true.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm putting up a thousand space dollars instead of a thousand real dollars.
Speaker 1: I like space dollars Yeah, so anyway what's wrong with the virtual console, all right.
Speaker 0: Well, see I only have one Complaint at all about the virtual console and while it is a complaint for me and for people like me and people like Scott It really isn't a complaint for many other people who may not have the technological know-how here.
Speaker 0: But not I'm not saying that you know They have to compete with the free ROMs because that's really kind of a different world there.
Speaker 0: Well, and I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't complain if the games cost more than free because they have to cost more than free.
Speaker 0: The problem is they cost so much more than free that I couldn't imagine Paying that much money for one of these games.
Speaker 1: Well, you see here's the thing is I'm willing to pay money for video games and music and all this other stuff that you can get for free Because I'm not actually buying the game.
Speaker 1: at least the way I see it is if I buy music from say iTunes Right, which I'm not willing to do because this DRM and shit.
Speaker 1: But let's say iTunes sold plain old mp3s at 10 cents each.
Speaker 1: I would totally be willing to pay for that because It's easy and the easiness of doing it and making sure I'm getting the right song.
Speaker 1: and you know The selection of songs always being available downloading quickly always working not having problems Etc, etc.
Speaker 1: is worth 10 cents.
Speaker 1: I'm not paying for the music because I get that for free.
Speaker 1: I'm paying for getting the music conveniently as opposed to having do a pain in the ass Going on bittorrent getting songs.
Speaker 1: I don't want waiting too long, etc, etc, etc.
Speaker 0: Now that's why I think Nintendo really knows what it's doing with a virtual console one.
Speaker 0: Instead of using money you use points that are equivalent of what one cent per point.
Speaker 1: It's one cent per point.
Speaker 1: It's also one yen per point.
Speaker 0: So if you buy a bunch of these points and you're in the virtual console It'll list the games that are currently available to buy and if you buy one it costs, you know, 400 500 600 800 points.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't feel like real money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they also do that because you know, for example I had I had 2,000 points because I bought the.
Speaker 1: you know The 2,000 point card when I've got the Wii and I've spent 1900 points.
Speaker 1: now I've got a hundred points, but you can't buy shit.
Speaker 0: So I either lose a dollar forever or I'm eventually gonna buy another game and give them more money Except that that doesn't work forever because you can buy a specific number of points with your credit card.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I wanted to I could but you know by the exact number of points by one more game and then have zero.
Speaker 1: It never buy another game again, but you know, they that's the reason they use points like that.
Speaker 0: So one though Nintendo gets your money up front meaning they're making profits ahead of having a deliverable.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm to.
Speaker 0: the deliverables cost them practically nothing.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm sure they're paying money to run the servers that have these games on them but compared to the money They make from all the games coming out and they're basically breaking in.
Speaker 0: well think about it.
Speaker 0: even if a million people buy a I don't know 24 kilobyte game a Million times 24 kilobytes not so much bandwidth.
Speaker 1: No, not so much a big computer to handle all those requests.
Speaker 0: But yeah, yeah, they're probably not gonna all come at once.
Speaker 1: No Well, it seems like you know, they've been releasing the virtual console games Monday nights on Monday morning.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 0: Well, see that's that's the other thing The reason Nintendo is smart about this not saying it's good for me but they're releasing the games in tiny waves where it seems like people who want to use their virtual points that they've got and Just itching to spend them will buy the best of each available wave Either because they wanted to buy something or because they look through and the games they see.
Speaker 0: I mean if every game were available all the old crap games that no one ever cared about would never get bogged because no One would think to look for them except old codgers like us.
Speaker 0: now They'll see ice hockey and go ice hockey, huh?
Speaker 0: Cuz only three games came out that week and they're more likely to buy it just waiting for other games.
Speaker 1: Yep But anyway, yeah The virtual console games are way too high priced.
Speaker 1: if you realize that a hundred points is a dollar you can see that they're selling Sonic the Hedgehog one for like $8 something like that.
Speaker 1: It's pretty stupid.
Speaker 0: Sim City is eight bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah Sim City for the SNES eight bucks.
Speaker 0: now, I will say right now I doubt it does but if it's somehow Integrated the remote into that so I could use it like a mouse I pay bucks for that in a second.
Speaker 1: But I'm sure it does.
Speaker 1: I'm almost I'm 99.9 repeating percent, you know bothers me the most about that.
Speaker 1: Isn't that?
Speaker 1: Okay, they're charging eight bucks.
Speaker 1: or Sonic the Hedgehog or whatever they're charging for it.
Speaker 1: You can buy Sonic mega collection for the GameCube Which is exactly the same goddamn thing.
Speaker 1: only it also comes with Sonic 2 Sonic 3 Sonic and Knuckles Sonic 3d blast and dr Robotnik's mean bean machine.
Speaker 1: but but it's like 10 bucks at the game store.
Speaker 0: You can't just play that on a whim.
Speaker 0: You have to put the GameCube disc in and play gasp.
Speaker 0: Yeah convenience.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, you're paying for that.
Speaker 1: the the meager is convenience.
Speaker 1: Let's see if you were to buy all those games on the better on Sonic mega collection Which is 10 bucks GameCube game if you were to buy all the Sonic games that are in that Separately on the virtual console two of which are now available You can get robot next to me and bean machine and you can get Sonic 1.
Speaker 1: Let's see that would cost you at least 30 50 bucks Insane insane amount of money.
Speaker 1: or you can spend 10 bucks and get Sonic mega collection.
Speaker 0: See now there's also where Nintendo is gonna make a bunch of money because a lot of people don't realize that.
Speaker 0: In fact, a lot of people probably don't even realize that you can just emulate ROMs or get them on the internet for free.
Speaker 1: Yeah Or even if they definitely gonna make a lot of money off the people who don't know better that you know They don't even realize that those games can be had for free.
Speaker 1: They don't even emulator.
Speaker 1: What's that?
Speaker 1: Those people are gonna spend a lot of money on a virtual console.
Speaker 1: It looks like a good deal to them.
Speaker 0: So what I think is gonna happen is Nintendo is gonna just have these games up and they'll keep doing their thing Until they stop making crazy amounts of money.
Speaker 0: So they'll sell every game, you know five bucks eight bucks twelve bucks and then later They'll take all the games in different genres or different types or different waves or whatever bundle them up in little packages and sell the whole package for like a thousand points like super discounted.
Speaker 1: they should but who knows if They will that might be a long time off.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I probably will be but if they're smart they'll have this trailing edge where the price just keeps dropped.
Speaker 0: like the price will sit at Until everyone within reason who's gonna buy it at that price point buys it as soon as sales dry up It'll drop to the next price point.
Speaker 0: So everyone pays exactly what they're willing to pay for that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean even if you're really think about it They make a hundred percent profit effectively on any of these games that they sell unless it's a game They have to re get a license to or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, it's gonna be hard for the notice.
Speaker 1: other aren't a Capcom games.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen any Mega Man's or Street Fighter's or anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus I already bought the Mega Man and Mega Man X collection, so that's they're not gonna get those off of me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no way granted though if despite these high prices and despite all our complaining We've bought well Scott has bought several virtual console game.
Speaker 1: I bought three because they're the only three that are worth it.
Speaker 0: So I guess we're gonna talk about those three.
Speaker 0: All right, that's kind of a dual episode here.
Speaker 1: Well, the first one that I bought was Superstar Soldier, which is a turbo graphic 16 shmup game.
Speaker 0: We bought it primarily because it was a turbo graphics game.
Speaker 1: There was no way that I was ever gonna be able to play that game if I didn't buy it on the virtual console.
Speaker 0: It's an okay shmup and that's coming from a guy who hates shmups and it's got.
Speaker 1: the thing about this shmup that makes it really unique is the music which is really awesome like if It's definitely on Gradius 3 level of music here.
Speaker 0: That was one thing about the turbo graphics.
Speaker 0: A lot of the games had really good music really good.
Speaker 1: And the other thing about it is it has the normal shmup mode.
Speaker 1: you know where you fly around and you try to beat all the bosses and get to the last level and It starts off easy and then it gets really hard.
Speaker 1: So even if you're not a shmup master, you know, it deceives you and it pulls you in and then it says, aha I'm not actually a simple shmup.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I beat the first level without dying for me.
Speaker 0: That's crazy.
Speaker 0: I mean I die in the first level of Gradius 3 and then in level 2 Level 2 I made it about halfway through and then things started getting tough And then I got to that boss and he immediately killed me until all my lives were gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah The other thing that's interesting.
Speaker 1: it has another mode the other mode or the timed modes.
Speaker 1: There's like the three-minute mode and the five-minute mode and all it does is it says Okay play in this special level the cargo level for three minutes or five minutes depending on which mode you pick and See how high a score you can get.
Speaker 1: and it's actually really fun because the cargo level is very different from the normal levels And the types of bad guys you see there and all the different things that you can shoot.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of stuff to blow up.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's a lot of stuff to blow up and you can't really choose all the weapons.
Speaker 1: But and you only have five minutes and you got to try to beat it without You know just go as far as you can and I've only ever gotten so far in it.
Speaker 1: So I really wonder hey, how far does it go?
Speaker 1: Could I get like twice as far as I got now because I end up dying it like a certain point?
Speaker 1: So it's it's really intriguing that mode to see what's the farthest you can possibly get in five minutes.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good game though.
Speaker 0: If you like shmups at all, you'll probably want to pick it up.
Speaker 0: It's not that much money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the next game I got is Gunstar Heroes, which is a game by treasure.
Speaker 1: now If you don't know treasure is a game developer.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they still exist but they made a lot of awesome games mostly Sega Genesis games that are really really awesome like dynamite heady and Gunstar Heroes and I can't name any others, but they're all awesome.
Speaker 0: Well dynamite heady is pretty cool and Gunstar Heroes Well, I haven't actually played it yet looked pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah the way Gunstar Heroes works.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like Turrican or Contra or Strider, you know, you're a guy who walks around shooting stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep Metal slug metal slug is a good example.
Speaker 0: Just run to the right shooting a whole bunch of projectiles and a whole bunch of bad guys.
Speaker 1: now the interesting thing about Gunstar Heroes is that you have a whole lot of moves that you can do.
Speaker 1: you can jump you can slide You can like kick guys.
Speaker 1: you can grab bad guys and throw them at other bad guys.
Speaker 1: You can.
Speaker 1: you know all kinds of crazy shit, but the way the weapons work is the most interesting.
Speaker 1: There are four weapons.
Speaker 1: the homing weapon.
Speaker 1: five is right out exactly therefore, that's the rapid-fire weapon.
Speaker 1: fire the laser and the homing and You can get any two of these.
Speaker 1: you pick which one you want to start with and you get that always.
Speaker 1: But you can choose other ones.
Speaker 1: you find them in the level.
Speaker 1: You can also give up weapons to switch them out for other ones.
Speaker 1: now Let's say I get two homing weapons, right?
Speaker 1: I can choose to either use the homing weapon the other homing weapon or the double homing weapon, which is awkward.
Speaker 1: yeah What does that have to do with double homing double Hawk Good one.
Speaker 0: See I didn't play this game.
Speaker 0: So all I can do is provide inane commentary and color.
Speaker 1: Now here's the trick.
Speaker 1: you ready, let's say I get the rapid-fire weapon and the laser right.
Speaker 1: well now I can fire the rapid-fire weapon the laser or the rapid laser And that's why Gunstar Heroes is awesome because there's all these different combinations of weapons that are useful in different situations.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend getting the homing laser or the Rapid-fire fire.
Speaker 0: those are quite interesting now, of course last and least well by least I mean most awesome or least not awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah would be ice hockey which we bought 100% because it is worth a significant amount of money to have that game in the holster ready to go any time 24/7.
Speaker 1: also because I wanted to vote for it like, you know say yes, we care about ice hockey.
Speaker 1: See
Speaker 0: it's kind of like how anime world order always says, you know Buy the old crappy robot anime that you like Even if the DVD release isn't that good or whatever or the show was actually kind of bad just to tell the world that yes There is a market.
Speaker 0: bring us more.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and Also because I want to play it using Controllers that aren't shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's a big problem with emulating is that you have a PC or something plugged into your TV and you got to use some shitty USB gamepad.
Speaker 0: now they all suck.
Speaker 1: you could get an Xbox 360 gamepad theoretically to work But not easy not the most trivial of things.
Speaker 0: also really expensive for what you get.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a $40 for an Xbox 360 wired controller.
Speaker 1: screw that shit Yeah, and get a third-party Xbox 360 controller, but that's even worse.
Speaker 1: That's like good God.
Speaker 0: and then you know, there's all the Various gravis type gamepad things and for various reasons they all just suck.
Speaker 0: We'd go into great details to why they all suck But I've never ever Seen one that could sufficiently emulate an actual Nintendo or Super Nintendo controller.
Speaker 0: enough for me to not be continually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually the buttons are okay or at least sufficient but the the arrow part is not good at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah it's always either some disk or some inaccurate piece of shit or maybe it's like a Busted kind of joystick deal or you always end up hitting diagonals when he didn't want to because they made it wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean a lot of people use that Logitech thing with the dual analogs or they use the Microsoft Sidewinder on the PC.
Speaker 1: But I hate those things that they're not.
Speaker 1: they totally like kill my hands.
Speaker 1: I can't use that shit Now.
Speaker 0: the only option really for until recently was to really go to lick sang Good ol lick sang and get the lick sang.
Speaker 1: that's dead now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah and buy the USB to NES SNES Sega Genesis adapters.
Speaker 1: They actually are selling now NES SNES to GameCube adapters that you can use on the Wii.
Speaker 1: So if you want to use your NES controller to play a virtual console game, you can do that.
Speaker 0: I am so about that you go buy them then I probably will.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's pretty best.
Speaker 1: I think that's.
Speaker 1: the number one advantage of the virtual console is that you can play these games with Controllers that don't suck with real d-pads and real buttons that don't fuck up all the time Yeah, plus just the fact you don't have to configure them or anything like in the emulator.
Speaker 1: You always have to set the buttons.
Speaker 1: Yeah buttons are set.
Speaker 1: You're good to go.
Speaker 0: Any time we wanted to play emulated games Even when we had the old div with Linux and the good emulators on it every time we wanted to play We still had to sit down fiddle fiddle fiddle fiddle fiddle fiddle fiddle play Mm-hmm, and then we could play for an hour.
Speaker 0: We had to do that initial fiddle every time we wanted to play.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's like the virtual console.
Speaker 1: the games are overpriced.
Speaker 1: So you really had to be selective and saying okay This game is worth this slightly high price because it's convenient and there's no other way.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get this game and it's a really good game, but any other game like Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: I really like Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: I have Zelda 1 on that GameCube disc.
Speaker 1: I have Zelda 1 and some other places, you know, so it's not worth 5 bucks.
Speaker 1: But even if I didn't have Zelda 1 in those places still wouldn't pay 5 bucks.
Speaker 0: No, no See the thing is a lot of games like that When I can buy the old Gameboy Color or GBA version of that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can get for like 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna pay 5 bucks to get it just on my week.
Speaker 1: Yep, you can get the GBA version of Zelda 1 Because I originally released that at 20 bucks, which is insane and they went down to 15 down to 10. now I think you can get it for five.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah See it just comes down to the fact that again the DS is for many people a primary console.
Speaker 0: So if you have a game for the DS or you can get it for the DS There's no reason in the goddamn world to get it for the Wii Because you can just play the DS in your living room just as easily as you can play the Wii.
Speaker 1: Yeah Here's an example I screwed up.
Speaker 1: is I got trauma center for the Wii because it was so good on the DS.
Speaker 1: But I didn't realize that the Wii version was the DS version with some more stuff in it like a third more stuff.
Speaker 1: So now I got to get rid of the DS version because I don't need it anymore.
Speaker 0: See that's great for me because I never played the DS version.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna know I'm just gonna play the Wii version cuz it's better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is better.
Speaker 1: It's actually easier to play and has more stuff in it.
Speaker 0: It's not often.
Speaker 0: I'll complain about a game being too hard God damn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, God damn.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 0: ice hockey ice hockey is perhaps one of the most Ultimate and perfect tests of manhood that two men can use to determine the length of their manhood.
Speaker 1: You gotta understand this is a game where you have five players one of which is a goalie.
Speaker 1: the other four players You can configure.
Speaker 1: you can either make them skinny medium or fatty.
Speaker 0: now before we continue the issue as To the optimal loadout for your team has been perhaps one of the most hotly debated topics in the history of the NES.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean arguments would come to fisticuffs over this.
Speaker 1: now It seems that you know any Logical argument people.
Speaker 1: it seems to come down to.
Speaker 1: you need one skinny guy because the skinny guy wins face-off.
Speaker 1: So you have to have a skinny guy.
Speaker 1: and I have always stood.
Speaker 0: I always use fat guys for my face-offs, but that's just me.
Speaker 1: Oh, well skinny guys do better face-offs.
Speaker 1: That's in the game.
Speaker 0: All I'm saying is that it's not always to your advantage to win the face-off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, the medium guys are medium at everything.
Speaker 1: So whatever the fat guys are really good at shooting and they're really hard to knock down But they're slow as shit like it'll take you forever to get down the ice with those guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz remember the skinny guys are real real real real real quick.
Speaker 0: And the fact that the thing is the fat guys don't shoot harder by default They just can charge up longer and shoot a harder shot.
Speaker 1: Well, no in the same amount of charge up time a fat guy will shoot a harder shot.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but in general harder shot doesn't mean a lot It does.
Speaker 1: it depends, you know and the speed of the game.
Speaker 1: if you're playing on low speed hard shot can mean a lot But no one plays on low speed.
Speaker 0: low speed is for losers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other thing is that while high-speed might seem like an advantage.
Speaker 1: for the skinny guys It can often turn into a disadvantage making them harder to control in the high-speed games.
Speaker 0: See now the loadout I have used since I was a little child and I used to this day with great success is Three fat guys and one skinny guy because one if you ever pick the normal guy That just means that you're waffling.
Speaker 0: You can't decide.
Speaker 0: you want both sides You can't commit to one thing and you don't need more than one skinny guy because that skinny guy will always be there the moment You need to get away with the puck.
Speaker 0: He's always there.
Speaker 0: He's always ready.
Speaker 0: The three fat guys form this impenetrable wall of defense that no guy will ever get through to score on you.
Speaker 1: See, that's an okay strategy.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I used to play, you know, two fatties one medium one skinny, but Then like when we started playing in the college days I got bold and I thought I know I'll win with my skills and I won't need the fatty guys.
Speaker 1: and I've used two skinny guys and two medium guys and That will allow me to not always just get trampled by fatties because I got two medium guys And I'll have such skill with my skinny guys that I'll put it in the goal and sneak around all your dudes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except the problem was that the medium guys didn't really do much for you.
Speaker 1: They work they worked.
Speaker 1: I won many games of ice hockey with that strategy, but now I'm leaning back towards bringing in some fatties.
Speaker 1: Haha, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I might bring in one fatty and then like two mediums in a skinny or a fatty and medium.
Speaker 0: It is telling you three fatties.
Speaker 0: one skinny is the absolute perfect team.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that Just like how in Final Fantasy one the perfect team if you really want to beat the game super super powerfully is Fighter fighter red mage white mage and I'll stand by that till the day I die.
Speaker 0: two fighters Two fighters is nuts.
Speaker 0: You have no idea how nuts two fighters is.
Speaker 1: and then you gotta have a black mage.
Speaker 1: I don't see.
Speaker 1: it's almost like cast all fur and lit.
Speaker 0: You know what red mage can cast all the spells you need when you're low level and when you get to high level.
Speaker 0: Those spells are almost useless compared to the attacks of your dudes.
Speaker 1: Of course they're useless.
Speaker 1: a red mage is casting them.
Speaker 1: if you had a black mage you can guess nuke.
Speaker 0: No Because the other party I used a great effect.
Speaker 0: was fighter fighter white mage black mage or fighter red mage white mage black mage Fighter black belt black mage white mage.
Speaker 0: see the black belts, okay I have many reasons.
Speaker 0: I don't take him but I will point out as you take the thief You're retarded.
Speaker 1: you are retarded.
Speaker 1: if you take the thief Oh, yes, I must agree you get to use the Katana, but screw that.
Speaker 0: the cotton is almost nothing And you can find two of them in the game.
Speaker 0: So it's not like it's something special.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the black belt is definitely the awesome cuz.
Speaker 1: well he starts out early in the game.
Speaker 1: He's kind of weak.
Speaker 1: You can still pull him through and then as soon as he gets starts leveling up.
Speaker 1: god damn is he powerful.
Speaker 0: Except one.
Speaker 0: not so much defense and two.
Speaker 0: you can do almost as much damage with a fighter with the right weapon Mmm, almost as much almost as much.
Speaker 0: that's the key close enough to where it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: But then it's not the best if another one is slightly better.
Speaker 0: It's not because the fighter has so many other benefits.
Speaker 0: Anyway one the fighter.
Speaker 1: when he becomes a knight in ice hockey you have these guys All right.
Speaker 0: So as goalie I usually use the black mage.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: They're gonna release like Mario.
Speaker 0: Oh run for how that would be tight.
Speaker 0: That would be so time easy characters Like like the three and three basketball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want that so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would pay upwards at six dollars for that Six dollars.
Speaker 0: So see the other guy on your team You don't get to pick is your goalie and in the fashion of old-school sports games Moving the stick moves all of your guys.
Speaker 0: It moves your main guy precisely.
Speaker 0: it moves your other three guys in a very generalized sense.
Speaker 0: Like you're holding up They'll kind of go out and it'll move your goalie straight up in two dimensions Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Well your goalie can go forward and back a little bit mostly goes up.
Speaker 0: That's why I said two dimensions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he can go up and down Two directions.
Speaker 0: I said two dimensions, okay, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the goalie is kind of tricky because you know if someone's standing there with their stick raised up like they're gonna give a slapshot They could shoot that up.
Speaker 1: They could shoot it down.
Speaker 1: You don't know where it's gonna go.
Speaker 0: They could also DQ pass and then shoot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's really it, you know If you don't have defenseman just standing all over the place, which you can do by holding down one of the buttons.
Speaker 0: Nope, nope.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: That's not how you do it.
Speaker 0: It says in the instruction to hit the button five times in a row.
Speaker 1: No It doesn't in the Wii manual that I read because the manual is.
Speaker 1: that's another thing that's nice about virtual console games.
Speaker 1: It's the manuals for the games are built in.
Speaker 1: I just read it and it says to hold down this button maybe?
Speaker 0: Well according to multiple game faxes and multiple websites as I said the correct way to defend yourself on the original NES game At least is to press B repeatedly when you're on defense to gather players in front of the net.
Speaker 1: Yep air the Operations manual for ice hockey on the Wii says if you press and hold one Which is B then players will gather in front of the net.
Speaker 1: However, I tried to play do that yesterday and I don't.
Speaker 1: I couldn't really tell if it was working, right?
Speaker 1: So we're gonna have to do some more experimenting to figure out if the operations manual is wrong or if they change the controls.
Speaker 0: Yep, but case in point, I mean we can't really go into more detail because there's not so much to this game.
Speaker 0: It's very other than raw unbridled Skill and passion and hurting your hands a lot and fighting via Nintendo finger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of Nintendo finger.
Speaker 1: It's like Nintendo finger to get the face off Nintendo finger to win a fight Nintendo finger to do all kinds of shit.
Speaker 0: if you've got a Wii and You've never played ice hockey spend the five bucks.
Speaker 1: If there's one virtual console game you're gonna buy.
Speaker 1: if you're only ever gonna buy one buy this one just you know Because it's so awesome.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four Different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.