Speaker 1: It's Monday August 21st, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We discuss podcasting live on the road.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You might notice I sound like my old self.
Speaker 1: That's because I finally have a brand new pop filter.
Speaker 1: It is made out of a nice black pantyhose some duct tape an embroidery loop a bent coat hanger.
Speaker 0: That's fantastic.
Speaker 0: It's exactly the same as the old one only new.
Speaker 1: not only does it look better It doesn't smell like tonsillolith.
Speaker 1: That is key.
Speaker 0: That is key.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 1: God did that old pop filter smell like tonsillolith.
Speaker 0: Well, you're always hacking up all kinds of nasty shit.
Speaker 0: Not surprised.
Speaker 1: I Submit that you were the only person I've ever seen who farted on a microphone and then immediately tried to talk on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was.
Speaker 0: I wasn't thinking ahead right there.
Speaker 1: No But actually today both Scott and I got caught in the same Traffic Jam despite the fact that he works about an hour to the east and I work about an hour to the south.
Speaker 0: Well, we all come up to the same little east-west Interstate and then actually most days I don't most days.
Speaker 1: I take the Bear Mountain Beacon Expressway.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you?
Speaker 1: Because I just didn't good job.
Speaker 1: I have three ways home and I kind of randomly pick one every day.
Speaker 0: Maybe you should listen to the traffic report before you randomly pick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what I looked on the MSN Microsoft Whatnot?
Speaker 0: traffic report that you know what.
Speaker 0: there is no internet traffic that works.
Speaker 0: the only traffic that works is the local radio for where you are which sucks because you don't know the traffic of where you're Going if you're going a long distance.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean all the New York stations always say all the roads going into and out of New York City which would be good for me, but I Don't have time to sit like by the time the news would come on and they tell me about it.
Speaker 1: I'm already on whatever road I've committed to yeah And it's like.
Speaker 0: I know that there's sometimes an alternate route, but usually the alternate route is just out of the way.
Speaker 0: So you're either spending time sitting or spending an equal amount of time driving around.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the main problem.
Speaker 1: We were stuck five minutes from our house and our options were the i-84 which was completely stopped or the only other Road that goes east-west which had every other person in the world on it.
Speaker 1: Yep Good God I mean have you ever sat at a light and you're trying to turn left with a green arrow even and the green arrow comes On and traffic doesn't move at all because the cross street is full.
Speaker 1: and then the green arrow turns back to red and then five Minutes later goes green again, and then it goes red again and in all this time not a single car has moved.
Speaker 0: The thing is on that street.
Speaker 0: I think the lights are really just not optimal.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem is the lights are perfectly optimal unless all the traffic from i-84 tries to squeeze down route 52.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're really like.
Speaker 0: I am in favor of there being traffic cameras You know that watch traffic and that there should be people watching them and manipulating lights and things when crazy shit happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is there is cause for abuse of those traffic cameras, you know.
Speaker 1: Well, I note that New York City for the most part has traffic cameras everywhere and there have been pretty much no reports of them Being abused.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean New York City.
Speaker 1: whenever the traffic gets bad police appear and direct the traffic.
Speaker 0: That is another good thing.
Speaker 0: And no, I didn't see a single cop directing any traffic.
Speaker 0: You know why?
Speaker 1: because it wasn't New York City.
Speaker 1: and I'm not gonna say that New York City is the greatest place in the world.
Speaker 1: But you know what whenever there's a problem in New York City Someone deals with it either a cop or a guy on the street someone deals with whatever situation is going down.
Speaker 0: Yeah out here.
Speaker 0: They just no one did anything.
Speaker 0: You just let the traffic sort itself out.
Speaker 0: Who cares?
Speaker 1: No, a few people did stuff.
Speaker 1: They cut me off trying to get one car ahead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, funny, yeah, it was great.
Speaker 1: Okay The best part was I cut down a side street and I drove around.
Speaker 1: I got stuck because there's another accident somewhere else And I was driving around trying to find a back road that would get me anywhere and I ended up driving up a one-way street and coming around and coming back to the road.
Speaker 1: We were on exactly four cars ahead of Scott like ten minutes later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just driving around.
Speaker 0: I see a funny license plate.
Speaker 0: then I see another funny license.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's rim All right, yeah which started us arguing even more about car insurance.
Speaker 1: So if anyone has anything to say about car insurance traffic or indigent drivers I suggest you hit the phone.
Speaker 0: indignant.
Speaker 1: No indigent as in they don't have any money.
Speaker 1: not indignant.
Speaker 0: They're also indignant.
Speaker 1: some of them were.
Speaker 1: you know I have a story.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna tell today about the most indignant woman I've ever met.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're they're real.
Speaker 1: one of my pet peeves lately is indignant people the people who just seem to have this Entitlement to everything in the world and they cut in front of you in a line or something.
Speaker 1: They're like it's more what I want.
Speaker 1: I do what I want.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not just that.
Speaker 0: It's also like you try to tell someone something.
Speaker 1: you're doing this just cuz I'm black.
Speaker 0: It's like when I'm trying to inform someone or help them out or teach them something.
Speaker 0: You're trying to tell me how to play Mario soccer Exactly, and then they get all upset like oh, you don't tell me what to do, you know It's like you're not the boss of me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly Yeah, all right God, I have so many stories about indignant people.
Speaker 0: Okay, so news time news time.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, it's Monday science day and all that and first off We're not gonna talk about this because we I know more about quantum physics than I do about astrophysics.
Speaker 0: I know it's almost nothing about quantum physics.
Speaker 1: Zero as I was about to say, I know practically nothing about quantum physics.
Speaker 1: ergo I am NOT qualified in any way to talk about this other than that.
Speaker 1: I understand the Implications at least from a broad perspective.
Speaker 0: So you read the article.
Speaker 1: No, no, I mean I understand that.
Speaker 0: so you didn't read the article.
Speaker 1: Understand that the fact that this has been for the most part confirmed will have far-reaching consequences And that is actually a big deal.
Speaker 1: Scientists have determined and they're sure at this point I mean, they've confirmed it as far as something like this can be confirmed that dark matter exists.
Speaker 0: All right, genius.
Speaker 0: What does that mean?
Speaker 0: Well the normal Joe on the street?
Speaker 1: Well for the normal Joe on the street it means that there's matter you can't detect so easily.
Speaker 1: that's out there Don't don't?
Speaker 0: uh, is it gonna make a good basis for a sci-fi movie?
Speaker 0: Uh, you know what?
Speaker 1: There are already a whole bunch of sci-fi movies with dark matter.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: So see sci-fi doesn't matter if it's real or not.
Speaker 1: It is ahead of the curve.
Speaker 1: I Mean the thing here is just that it won't affect anyone except scientists.
Speaker 1: But it really from what I've gathered from my reading kind of makes a bunch of the theories We've been tossing around a lot more solid.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Does it mean we're gonna have spaceships that can take us far away very quickly?
Speaker 1: Actually, it means from what I can gather that that is actually more difficult than we expected now.
Speaker 0: So we don't like this.
Speaker 0: news is what you're saying.
Speaker 0: This is bad news.
Speaker 1: Well, it means that now we know that there's this matter out there.
Speaker 1: That's hard to detect if it's detectable at all in most cases and we can't seem to manipulate it or do anything with it.
Speaker 1: And it's in the way and we don't know what it is, but we know it's there now.
Speaker 0: So it's just bad news all around.
Speaker 1: I mean before we weren't sure if dark matter was there.
Speaker 1: dark matter was basically a fudge factor kind of thrown into equations.
Speaker 1: Now we know that.
Speaker 1: All right, there is actually something there.
Speaker 1: our math isn't wrong.
Speaker 1: There's just something there.
Speaker 1: We don't know much about.
Speaker 0: Do you can you say at all how we know?
Speaker 1: Not at all I can't.
Speaker 1: scientists did some sort of experiment and observe something.
Speaker 1: good job You're helpful, but I think that this is somewhat significant news.
Speaker 1: So I thought I would toss it out there.
Speaker 0: All right I have sort of a double news one old and one new.
Speaker 0: yeah, the old news which you may or may not know because it was like a week old is AOL released a bunch of search results on the internet so that everyone could look at them now.
Speaker 0: the way they did this is they Took.
Speaker 0: well not results, but searches, you know, like.
Speaker 0: so if you searched for food It would show up in the thing.
Speaker 0: They distributed the word searches for food.
Speaker 1: Someone is hungry who searches for the word food.
Speaker 1: What do you think?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna search for food.
Speaker 1: while you talk about your news I'll be Michael Godot here.
Speaker 0: All right, so AOL put all these search Queries on the internet.
Speaker 0: so, you know in case it was it's interesting to see what other people are searching for mostly porn.
Speaker 0: But they put them out and to make it anonymous they replaced every username with a number.
Speaker 1: Whoa, Yahoo looks really different from the last time.
Speaker 0: I went anyway, go on Yeah, so if you were happen to be user number five and your name was Joe They would replace the word Joe with the number five.
Speaker 0: So you knew that all the searches the number five or from the same person, but you didn't know who?
Speaker 0: This didn't work.
Speaker 0: So well because everyone was able to look and see.
Speaker 0: hey All of these were by the same person and then they looked at what the person searched for and they were able to figure out Who it was.
Speaker 0: So AOL got some flack for that, but the internet got mountains of comedy.
Speaker 1: Yes There was one case where it appears that a husband and wife were both cheating on each other.
Speaker 0: There was one the funniest one I saw.
Speaker 0: it was on something awful Which had which has a highlights a reel of sorts was one person from the same House was searching for.
Speaker 0: What do I do if my mother-in-law like grabbed my dick?
Speaker 0: and Then there were searches for the same house.
Speaker 0: Like I saw my mother-in-law grabbed my husband's dick.
Speaker 0: Whoa I saw.
Speaker 0: my mom grabbed my husband's dick not mother-in-law That would be all right.
Speaker 1: If you search for food one the top Google sponsored ad is a McDonald's snack wrap.
Speaker 1: Oh god, but Yahoo and Google have the exact same top three links.
Speaker 0: No, okay.
Speaker 0: So anyway, what happened today?
Speaker 0: is someone released a new Firefox extension called track me not.
Speaker 0: What track me not does is when you're not doing anything and Firefox is open.
Speaker 0: It just kind of does some searches on AOL Yahoo Google and MSN.
Speaker 0: So if anyone ever decides to release some search results or look through the search well search queries at either of those any of those Places then they'll say hey That's we don't know who.
Speaker 0: that is because there's so many crazy different searches going on all the time.
Speaker 1: Alright now I'm gonna put on my tinfoil hat here for a minute.
Speaker 1: And now let's assume that me being evil rim.
Speaker 1: Dr Chaos wrote this program.
Speaker 1: Now I would set it up so that it would search occasionally for very specific things That would be tied to each person who has downloaded my program in some way so that I could still track Everything in the event that something like this happened.
Speaker 0: Yep, you could do that.
Speaker 0: However, there are two things in your way.
Speaker 0: number one With this extension you can actually customize how and what the thing searches.
Speaker 0: So that's number one.
Speaker 0: number two Anyone who's intelligent can configure it to search for certain things and then monitor it with.
Speaker 0: you know Ethereal or whatever they want to monitor right and they'll know if you're evil.
Speaker 1: now, I put on my ass hat hat.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's say I want to get revenge on someone and I'm a really bad person.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I go to their computer and they probably use Firefox because if I'm a bad person, I'm probably dumb and as a result, I Probably hate someone who's smart who uses Firefox.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I install this plug-in somehow and I tell it to search for all this sorts of kitty porn stuff.
Speaker 0: You are the awesome.
Speaker 0: The winner is you as you have found why Scott has not installed this extension, ah, yes Also because I am not so paranoid and I don't care if people see my search queries.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm trying to think is you know what I know?
Speaker 0: porn sites.
Speaker 0: I don't need to search for.
Speaker 1: If someone wanted to know your porn searchings, I guess they could look at our DNS But we don't even have a caching DNS.
Speaker 1: So now we can't nope.
Speaker 0: No, I tried to turn the caching on it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the fuck to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never bothered because it doesn't matter for us.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well Yeah, it would be faster though.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I'll look into it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's all you.
Speaker 1: All right Anyway, my news is something that isn't.
Speaker 0: wasn't your news the dark matter.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: No, I was just throwing that out.
Speaker 1: Okay I have an actual news.
Speaker 0: I want to turn the dark matter out.
Speaker 0: Oh, no You Know Iran's gonna nuke Israel tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, supposedly Iran's gonna nuke Israel.
Speaker 1: Oh, no hide under your desk I hate to say it, but if it happened, that means that the internet scooped Iran.
Speaker 0: Well some guy in the Wall Street Journal writing an op-ed.
Speaker 0: That was kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: Oh an op-ed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I can tell that this is barely news because it didn't even hit FARC.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean if something doesn't hit FARC it effectively didn't happen.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep Alright, so this Irish company called Steer Ste o RN.
Speaker 1: I'm linking to their website.
Speaker 0: I think it's like storm but steorn That was the most useless Simile ever steorn.
Speaker 1: It's like Otakon, but it's pronounced Whatever.
Speaker 0: anyway Talk about the crazy company.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I said Otakon because I have the Otakon book in front of me and then I looked around for another word to say Yeah, anyone out there?
Speaker 0: I've heard a lot of people say like Otakon and Otakon Otakon you all need to STFU because it's Otakon Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yep, not Otakon this company.
Speaker 1: I'm linking to their website, but bear in mind that I'm only doing so in the most ironic sense.
Speaker 1: I'm linking to it solely so that you can make fun of this company.
Speaker 1: This is a real company at least it might be.
Speaker 1: it has recently come to my attention that a number of people Believe that this company is actually a viral marketing campaign for Halo 3
Speaker 0: could be and
Speaker 1: That is the most credible Theory I've heard so far because otherwise
Speaker 0: it
Speaker 1: means that this group of people who have put together this snazzy looking website and these nice Animations and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: It is a pretty snazzy website.
Speaker 0: Usually the scam idiot websites are much less.
Speaker 1: They tend to have many fonts and blinking red letters.
Speaker 0: It looked like myspace pages.
Speaker 1: The long story short is this company claims to have a perpetual motion machine and that they want to sell it to people Can't happen.
Speaker 0: Perpetual motion defies every law of nature.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: Now they even claim that our invention flies in the face of conventional understandings of physics.
Speaker 1: Yep, it does.
Speaker 0: Hey sure does which means it's not real.
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: it's made up.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I Invented a dragon.
Speaker 0: I grew it in a in a in a my bathtub.
Speaker 1: Really.
Speaker 1: Can I ride it?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Oh You can just invest in my company and then maybe one day I'll let you ride it.
Speaker 1: So I'll get to ride the dragon.
Speaker 0: No, it's prides dead already, but what I can make another one.
Speaker 0: if you invest enough money in my company We'll have to talk after the show.
Speaker 1: All right I like how we're making jokes today that are almost exactly like the jokes in the South Park.
Speaker 1: We just watched.
Speaker 0: are they really the thing with Butters?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: We just did that joke only with dragons.
Speaker 0: We did just do that joke.
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't have more to say about that other than that that that itself is not news.
Speaker 1: companies appear all the time with bullshit pseudo signs trying to sell it.
Speaker 1: The scary part is that there were people on the internet who were posting about this company as though This is some amazing breakthrough and they're really excited about it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I don't think they were kidding.
Speaker 0: So if it's true that it's a halo 3 thing then some of those people were there supporting it for sure.
Speaker 0: But there were definitely people.
Speaker 0: I saw the dig comments.
Speaker 0: They were people who believed it or didn't outright toss it out.
Speaker 1: god I got a gripe with dig and these stupid people who tend to use it.
Speaker 0: yes, so If you think there can be a perpetual emotion machine if you think that that is possible if you believe Anyone that who tells you that they have a perpetual emotion machine might not be lying.
Speaker 0: You are a doofus.
Speaker 1: yo things of the day.
Speaker 0: You didn't say thingy I didn't say anything.
Speaker 0: Also, that was our third take because because the second time I wanted to just say that I didn't have anything funny to say But you didn't like that.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't.
Speaker 1: so fuck you mainly because I thought you were saying that not ironically.
Speaker 0: No, I was saying it ironically.
Speaker 1: Oh Anyway, my thing of the day is something I've been kind of wanting to talk about for a bit and It's scary, but it's science related.
Speaker 1: There is a study done recently and the they asked a whole bunch of questions of people in generally industrialized nations And the main question they asked was essentially Did humans?
Speaker 1: Evolve from other species over time?
Speaker 1: something like that was basically a question to determine if you believe that evolution happened or not.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and of all of these industrialized and semi industrialized nations They did.
Speaker 1: like 30 countries The United States was beaten only by Turkey in terms of not believing in evolution.
Speaker 0: So anyone who agrees with Certain people that Americans aren't stupid.
Speaker 0: You're wrong Americans are stupid.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not even like it was close.
Speaker 1: America is at the bottom by far and pretty much every civilized country in the world has a very high Response rate to this question except the United States.
Speaker 0: and if you look at the top of the list You see the countries with the science and the making fancy things that had the better electronics.
Speaker 0: And at the bottom you see the countries with the Hicks and the religion.
Speaker 1: Well, let's see the winners here are Iceland Denmark Sweden, France, Japan, Britain, Norway, Belgium, Spain, Germany, Italy The Netherlands Hungary Luxembourg I could go on.
Speaker 0: so all the countries that enjoy f1 racing.
Speaker 0: Pretty much a correlation high-tech cars high-tech brain.
Speaker 1: The u.s was edged out by Cyprus just a little bit and Unfortunately Turkey is really really really way back there beyond the u.s Is pretty far beyond everyone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah It said I really would have liked if they would have added one or two like Developing countries a third world countries.
Speaker 0: Sorry politically correct you in.
Speaker 1: I would like to see China be asked to.
Speaker 0: yeah They gotta ask China.
Speaker 0: Did they ask Russia?
Speaker 1: I don't believe so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you gotta ask China in Russia and maybe the Ukraine and you got a India - India.
Speaker 1: Well, they they asked like all like Lithuania and all that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 0: That's fine But also I'd like to see like Afghanistan on there.
Speaker 1: Well, I'd like to see a more thorough study.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely more in some African countries also.
Speaker 1: I think they could have asked a bunch more questions because they were basically saying did evolution happen or not?
Speaker 1: and The really smart answer is probably Not yes But I guess anyone who would say no is pretty much definitely not on the right page.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also, you know, they should have checked to see what people thought the theory of evolution was Because a lot of people just don't understand the theory of evolution and they only disbelieve Colin me a monkey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly, you know, they don't believe in it because they don't know what it is.
Speaker 1: I mean if I thought that Granted granted there was another study I'm not gonna link to this one But one of the questions that they asked were do you believe that humans share at least 50% of their DNA with?
Speaker 1: most Americans said no Even though the correct answer is like 90% like 99.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like we're almost identical to chimpanzees.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: now once again Industrialized nations other than the US.
Speaker 1: this really isn't a problem.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm And all I want to say is that this really kind of frightens me.
Speaker 0: Anyone who says Americans aren't stupid you're wrong.
Speaker 1: Theoretically, they're not.
Speaker 1: this does not prove that they're stupid.
Speaker 1: It proves that they're ignorant.
Speaker 0: Ignorant and stupid is the same thing.
Speaker 1: No, they're not.
Speaker 1: ignorant means you lack knowledge.
Speaker 1: stupid means you lack the ability to deal with knowledge.
Speaker 0: There's a big difference whatever you want to define it.
Speaker 0: as I say Stupid is stupid is stupid.
Speaker 0: If you're not smart, you're stupid.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: That was brilliant.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That was pros Scott I'm very proud of you.
Speaker 0: You know what it was?
Speaker 0: It's stupid All right.
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 0: So I do this thing called cunu where I help people with problems with their computer.
Speaker 0: They just I am me kind of randomly and I help them cuz I'm not doing anything at work.
Speaker 1: how altruistic of you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and one question that I've had to deal with two or three times in my life not just on cunu is how do I defrag my hard drive in Linux?
Speaker 0: and the answer is you don't have to and people go WTF?
Speaker 0: I need to defrag my hard drive and I'm like, no you don't and sometimes they just don't don't understand.
Speaker 0: and The answer is Linux file systems don't need to be defragmented pretty much ever Because they are not stupidly designed you see in Windows.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's let me try to talk about this in non-technical terms.
Speaker 1: Even though talk too long.
Speaker 1: It'll turn into a news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to do it on doing this on tech day because we don't give high tech enough stuff for you know And some people like it.
Speaker 0: So here you go.
Speaker 0: You have a hard drive.
Speaker 0: all that's on the hard drive is zeros and ones and they stay there as long as you keep them There it's a big magnetic disk that spins fast.
Speaker 0: If you want to put files on a hard drive You need to have some system of arranging the zeros and ones.
Speaker 1: Oh some kind of filing system.
Speaker 1: Maybe a file system a system for having files.
Speaker 0: Yes That is exactly what you need a file system a way to arrange the zeros and ones on the hard drive so that the computer Knows where the files are and where to find the files and which zeros and ones equal which file.
Speaker 1: Well, I think one place where a lot of the confusion around file systems comes from is that Windows doesn't differentiate between Formatting the drive and making the file system.
Speaker 1: Yep, so most people when they hear format they think it means something very different from what format means to the rest of the world exactly.
Speaker 0: But a file system is a way of arranging zeros and ones on a hard drive Usually a hard drive but any other storage like a flash card or anything so that the computer knows where the files are.
Speaker 0: now Windows traditionally uses fat which is not the greatest one and Windows 2000 and XP and the newer windows use NTFS, which is super fat basically super duper fat.
Speaker 1: It's actually quite a bit different.
Speaker 0: It is quite a bit different, but it still needs defragmentation.
Speaker 1: It has the same problems for different reasons exactly.
Speaker 1: That's the best way to put it.
Speaker 0: Yes Linux can use pretty much any file system in the universe except NTFS.
Speaker 0: Well, no now it can use NTFS.
Speaker 0: They found a way really writing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Is it safe?
Speaker 0: Yep They uses a Windows driver, oh great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's hard to get it to work, but it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not worth it.
Speaker 0: I saw it's not what I wouldn't personally go through the effort, but if you need to do it, it's there.
Speaker 1: But the last time I tried to write to NTFS in Linux it involved you can only write the same number of bytes.
Speaker 0: Now you can do it full-on.
Speaker 0: But all right in Linux there the standard file system is ext2.
Speaker 0: There's also ext3 which is what everyone uses these days.
Speaker 0: There's also riser FS riser4 XFS, JFS.
Speaker 0: There's lots of different file systems to choose from and they all have advantages and disadvantages But none of the ones that are awesome for Linux.
Speaker 0: I mean you could use fat in Linux and then you need to defrag it But all the Linux ones do not need to be defragmented Now if you're not sure what defragmenting means and you want to know why Linux file systems don't need to be defragmented.
Speaker 0: My thing of the day explains it in a way where any idiot can understand.
Speaker 0: Well, not any idiot.
Speaker 1: I was about to say any idiot.
Speaker 1: I got some idiots.
Speaker 0: No any Literate and moderately intelligent human being can understand.
Speaker 0: so an IQ above 90 Yeah You'll be able to understand files at the general gist of you.
Speaker 1: put the files on the disk get in Get in Yep.
Speaker 0: So I think that if you want to understand a little bit more about how your computer works What defragmenting means and why Windows sucks?
Speaker 1: You should read this page now for those of you who listen regularly.
Speaker 1: last week last Monday In fact, we played the panel that we recorded somewhat drugged somewhat tired myself mostly hungover at Otacon.
Speaker 1: it was our second live recorded panel at a convention and Today we decided since we did have a lot of difficulty pulling this all off that we would talk a bit about the trials and tribulations of trying to do podcasts live on the road.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, I think this is actually gonna be good because I don't think anyone else has done a podcast about doing this.
Speaker 1: Yeah now, I mean, it's something we've done and it's actually really easy to do.
Speaker 1: The problem is it's easy to do.
Speaker 1: as long as nothing goes wrong Something will always go wrong.
Speaker 0: if you ever do anything live in your entire life something will go wrong.
Speaker 1: The fact is if you don't prepare for everything to go wrong, you're completely dick before you even started Exactly.
Speaker 0: And as we said in our panel many many times money makes everything better.
Speaker 1: Yes hire sound engineers and a full crew and they'll set you up a rig everywhere you go and you want to deal with anything.
Speaker 0: This is why concerts don't screw up because they have money.
Speaker 1: Alright, I guess we could talk about Tora Khan first because that was a much easier one and then Oda Khan was when we jumped To using other people's equipment.
Speaker 1: Yep Now for Tora Khan, we basically just brought Scott's laptop the mixer the compressor and three microphones.
Speaker 1: We plugged them all in we hit record on audacity.
Speaker 1: We turned around and we did the panel.
Speaker 0: Gee, that was hard.
Speaker 1: Well, it was basically the same as doing our normal podcast.
Speaker 1: The only difference was that we were in a different place We were using a different computer with a shittier sound card and there were other people watching gasp.
Speaker 1: Now the reason this wasn't difficult that one.
Speaker 1: it was a small room and two.
Speaker 1: more importantly We weren't doing anything else with the audio.
Speaker 1: We didn't have monitors.
Speaker 1: We weren't wearing headphones.
Speaker 1: We didn't have amplified speakers projecting our voices out to the crowd.
Speaker 1: The only equipment we needed was recording equipment.
Speaker 1: So if you ever do a small panel and you're a podcaster just bring your entire Podcasting rig set it up in the room and go.
Speaker 1: that's all you need to do.
Speaker 0: And of course if you can't bring your entire podcasting rig because it's big or you don't have a laptop or anything like that You can a buy small equipment Because all you need you need microphones you need mixing and you need recording.
Speaker 0: So buy the smallest things you can buy that do all that - You can borrow say a oh and now you're saying - Perfect.
Speaker 0: Great be you can borrow someone else's shit.
Speaker 0: so like if you're going to a college you can call someone there and say we need you to bring a laptop to our panel and Hopefully they won't.
Speaker 0: you know drop out on you as people are want to do
Speaker 1: Now, of course that isn't the difficult part other than you know The actual logistics of running the panel and public speaking and everything that we really don't want to get into today because today is tech Day, but rest assured we're going to do a show sometime soon on the public speaking and presentation aspects of all this.
Speaker 0: Yep, you know, we'll do an episode called like how to run a panel that doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it sounds good.
Speaker 1: Now the remember in the forums write that down will forget Yes, but anyway the panel that we did at Otacon was very different one.
Speaker 1: There's a very large room Very large.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I mean large larger than we wanted at all.
Speaker 1: Exactly - there was already equipment in the room.
Speaker 1: Otacon had already set up this whole AV setup where there are microphones everywhere.
Speaker 1: They were all put into this crazy equipment.
Speaker 1: Everything was amplified so we talked into the microphones and the speakers then project it out into the room and As a result we had to somehow integrate our equipment with their equipment.
Speaker 1: Now if you don't have a mixer or you're a solo podcaster Or you don't have any audio skill whatsoever There is really almost no way you're going to be able to deal with this unless the AV people are very nice to you And they have a bunch of cables and they'll help you out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not likely.
Speaker 0: I mean our guy did the minimal effort for us and that's because he knew what to ask for and we were asking for very Little.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean we basically asked can we record the panel?
Speaker 1: and the guy seemed to think that we wanted him to do it all and They were like, no, we have a mixer.
Speaker 1: We just need one mono feed from your stuff.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And he said, oh, okay, and he plugged into our mixer.
Speaker 0: Yep He gave us.
Speaker 0: the only need is a wire that came from his stuff to our stuff one wire.
Speaker 1: of course the equipment didn't work so behind us talking was a Kind of noise Yeah, but that was somewhat removed.
Speaker 1: Well, luckily that didn't affect the actual panel.
Speaker 1: I mean remember there are two concerns you have when you're doing this sort of panel.
Speaker 1: Firstly you have to worry about the panel itself.
Speaker 1: This should be your primary concern.
Speaker 1: if you're going to screw anything up You're much better off screwing up the recording part than the presentation part.
Speaker 0: absolutely, if you have to if you're it's time for your panel to start start if it's time for your panel to end and You should be there early to deal with all your audio shit.
Speaker 0: If you don't start get your recording set up and working before the panel starts Start forget it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, give up on it because the recording isn't worth it.
Speaker 1: not doing the recording doesn't lose you anything It's just a small opportunity cost.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Wasting the first half hour of your panel trying to fix that hum That won't even matter until you're trying to do post-production.
Speaker 1: Later is definitely not worth your time.
Speaker 0: No, you just destroyed half your panel.
Speaker 0: now No one's gonna be at it.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 1: And also when we say get there early we mean get there early.
Speaker 1: we got to our panel an hour before it started.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't have to get there that early.
Speaker 0: We probably could have gotten there a half hour before it started.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we were.
Speaker 1: more is safer.
Speaker 0: I mean there is a point at which getting there earlier is stupid like two hours early.
Speaker 0: You'd be dumb.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on what you're doing.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're setting up all of the audio for the room then yeah get there two hours.
Speaker 0: Oh, you probably need like three or four hours depending on the room and the equipment.
Speaker 0: Good thing those guys had semi good equipment already set up except for the mixer with the Wii U.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that wasn't that guy's fault.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't.
Speaker 0: that was the bad equipment.
Speaker 0: One piece of the equipment was broken.
Speaker 0: Everything else is awesome.
Speaker 0: He had all these compressors lined up and everything.
Speaker 1: Yep In fact, I used our compressor as a limiter instead of a compressor because I was worried that the super loudness coming out of his Equipment could hurt the Mac.
Speaker 1: So I made the compressor be a limiter.
Speaker 1: So if anything got really loud, it would cut off the signal and save the Mac.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it worked worked very well.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Now if you have extra equipment, you should bring it.
Speaker 1: if you don't have extra equipment, you should buy it.
Speaker 1: You should probably have one of every possible connector and then one of every possible connector again And then a whole bunch of cables that can connect between all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz you're never gonna know what they're gonna give you or what you're gonna have Available at the time or what you'll need or what.
Speaker 1: if suddenly you want to play some music at a panel you just patch right?
Speaker 0: In yeah, it's like you never know what you're gonna need.
Speaker 0: So bring everything you got, you know, a lot of people, you know They bring.
Speaker 0: you know trying to save space exactly what they think they'll need nothing more nothing less and inevitably one wire They need.
Speaker 0: you know It's better to have five or two ten wires sitting in your box unused than to not have the one wire you desperately need.
Speaker 1: Yes, I mean we brought Everything we had.
Speaker 1: we brought the Mac.
Speaker 1: We brought Scott's laptop just in case.
Speaker 1: we brought all of the podcasting equipment Every spare cable we have including a bunch of AV cables that we probably would not even need.
Speaker 0: Yep, we brought it all.
Speaker 1: it was way too much and we didn't even use a quarter of it.
Speaker 1: But having it saved us from all sorts of trouble.
Speaker 0: and if you really really really can't deal with Bringing a lot of physical goods with you wherever you're going.
Speaker 0: Your only option is really to buy smaller stuff Or to plan ahead.
Speaker 1: the problem is that the planning head one probably won't work because you can't plan for unexpected eventualities Yep, and two it probably won't work because you're gonna forget something anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and a lot of what it comes down to is just you have to know your shit.
Speaker 0: that way You know when you get there no matter what the weird situation is.
Speaker 0: You have to know enough that you can comprehend the situation and come up with the solution rather quickly.
Speaker 0: I mean if you just don't know then you're gonna waste a lot of time figuring it out and that's not good.
Speaker 0: That's really not good because you need that time to implement the solution not to figure it out.
Speaker 1: Yes Now in terms of podcasting on the road we bought a Mac mini pretty much expressly for this purpose.
Speaker 0: Well, we originally bought it to replace your computer, but it failed miserably.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: But now it serves as our media box and as our podcast box.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now the key is you've got to have some sort of portable rig.
Speaker 0: You really don't want to be bringing your own computer on the road unless you're like one of those wicked cool shuttle case land PC People.
Speaker 1: yeah, or if you have a really good laptop a really good laptop though Laptops without external sound cards tend to sound pretty bad and tend to be really noise.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the Mac laptops some at least they're supposedly have good sound cards But like my IBM ThinkPad has like the worst sound card imagine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good God.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: now in terms of having the computer, I mean the Mac mini is great.
Speaker 1: if you can get a laptop It's good.
Speaker 1: If you ever you fancy your best bet is to buy a solid-state recorder.
Speaker 1: But a good solid-state recorder will go for at least two to three hundred dollars Could even go for more than that.
Speaker 0: But a lot of the professional guys have a solid-state recorder that they use for everything.
Speaker 0: as the ultimate backup You know you have to get one of those ones that has like the XLR inputs and the compact flash card.
Speaker 0: And you know, these things are really awesome, you know, so they are worth the money they charge.
Speaker 0: You just can't get one if you're poor.
Speaker 1: and the other big concern in regards to bringing equipment is the display.
Speaker 1: Now we were going to buy a cheap LCD monitor and we didn't get around to it for various reasons.
Speaker 1: So we ended up bringing one of Scott's really nice LCD monitors.
Speaker 1: If you don't have a laptop You've got.
Speaker 1: don't just assume that wherever you're going is gonna have something you can plug your computer into because they probably won't.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean the room we were in did have a Projector and there was a VGA cable that we could plug into to use that projector as a monitor.
Speaker 0: the thing was is The Mac mini only had DVI out and we didn't bring the DVI to VGA adapter But that's okay because we brought a DVI monitor.
Speaker 1: Well, there was also the RCA we could have used.
Speaker 0: there was the RCA We could have used.
Speaker 1: yes, but the thing is if even if you think oh, I know they're gonna have a projector I'll just use that.
Speaker 1: I don't think I have ever been to a presentation Where the projector didn't somehow screw up while they were trying to set it up with a computer.
Speaker 0: See a lot of the thing is is I mark all of the 90% of those I mark down to people not knowing how to use audio-visual equipment.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, definitely.
Speaker 0: You need to know how to use audio-visual equipment needs to know how to wire it.
Speaker 0: You need to know how to you know change settings on it.
Speaker 0: You need to know how to change inputs.
Speaker 0: You need to know how to do all those things and you need to be able to figure out how to do it on Completely foreign equipment that you've never used before.
Speaker 1: thus in the very least once again get to your panel early Plug your equipment in look at it.
Speaker 1: Make sure it's working Now right along those lines.
Speaker 1: You if you think you're gonna use the projector bear in mind that now while you're talking you're gonna have this Audacity window open in the background distracting everyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you probably want to like, you know Turn the project if you're using the projector you want to write want to turn it on hit record then turn the projector off You know.
Speaker 0: and then when you're done turn the projector back on and click stop Of course, then now you can't monitor if anything goes wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is sort of imagine doing a four-hour Roundtable panel discussion ending it round of applause.
Speaker 1: you turn the projector on to save it and oh there was a Fatal exception or a beach ball, huh?
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 1: Good game grenade.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, having a monitor or using a laptop is definitely a good idea.
Speaker 0: I mean I was really worried about bringing the monitor And it was.
Speaker 0: it was sort of a pain in the ass to bring the monitor But in the end it was worth it because pain in the ass my ass I had everything else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's fun.
Speaker 1: now the other thing that really saved us and I'm glad we did it and we're going to do this at every panel we ever do ever is having an assistant.
Speaker 1: if There are two people in your podcast and you're trying to do a presentation Neither of you should be touching anything or doing anything other than talking.
Speaker 1: You should have a third person who's sitting back there fiddling with the computer the whole time when you're taking questions You should have a third person going around with the microphone.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean imagine if I was doing this podcast right now and I had to spend all my you know half my time.
Speaker 0: My attention is focused on this screen to see if things are fucking up and the other half the time I'm focused on what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: That's not gonna be too good because I'm not paying attention to what I'm saying And I'm only giving the audience half of what I should be giving them now.
Speaker 1: granted I'm doing that right now and every night on geek nights.
Speaker 1: I'm watching all sorts of things while we talk But it's one meter over there.
Speaker 0: What are you?
Speaker 1: two more meters?
Speaker 1: I just can't see him now because I can't put my microphone where I want to until I get a better microphone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those meters don't change so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I gotta keep an eye on the inputs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: it was much more important early on before we learned how to use microphones.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah But that sort of thing takes a lot of practice and even then it is distracting and whenever I get on a roll I stop watching.
Speaker 1: usually.
Speaker 0: yeah, but having an assistant is awesome Especially you just tell them what to look for and then if there's a problem they can signal you.
Speaker 0: and it's even better if they Can deal with the problem on their own and you don't need to do anything Yep, which our assistant could because it was in fact Nuri from the artist Ali podcast.
Speaker 1: So she knew exactly what she was doing.
Speaker 0: awesome.
Speaker 1: Now a whole bunch of other random things that you might may or may not be aware of.
Speaker 1: That.
Speaker 1: for example say you're doing a panel you're talking or you're on a stage you're talking You've got a microphone and there's speakers going out to the audience, you know, the big concert speakers the big black boxes that make noise don't ever walk in front of one of those.
Speaker 1: if you were carrying a microphone unless the microphone is switched to off and even then Don't walk in front of it because it's like a loaded weapon.
Speaker 1: It might be on.
Speaker 0: Yep, you got it.
Speaker 0: If you're about to walk in front of them, just stop look at your microphone, you know.
Speaker 0: Double-check like a hundred times to make sure it's off Run across really fast and then turn the microphone on or better chart out.
Speaker 1: what you're going to do is that you never have to Walk in front of those things.
Speaker 0: That's also a good idea If you can just walk around the back You know with your microphone get a cordless one.
Speaker 0: that way you don't need to worry about wires getting tangled when you do that.
Speaker 1: Yep In fact at our panel we were careful about that and then when we brought up all the other Podcasts just they could give little plugs about themselves.
Speaker 1: We warned them don't walk in front of the microphone in front of you.
Speaker 0: All this in last Monday's episode, but yeah, yeah There's a point at which someone walks in front of those speakers and it for only like a half a second.
Speaker 0: We were like goddamn you ruined the perfectness.
Speaker 1: now another thing you might not realize is that being I mean if anyone's ever been in theater or in a band in high school or Anything where you're on a stage where you're lighted where your mics where there are monitor speakers Anything beyond just sitting at a panel room in front of a bunch of people?
Speaker 1: You might not be aware that You're not going to be able to hear the audience very well in many cases unless the acoustics in the room are good or the monitors are set up right and You're probably going to have to deal with hearing your own voice coming out of the speakers at a possibly substantial delay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the room we were in was really big and we had a bunch of people there But not enough to fill the room.
Speaker 0: so there was this echo of the speakers bouncing off the far wall back to us and it was rather annoying and People talking to us.
Speaker 0: They weren't physically close enough for us to hear them because they weren't as loud as I am.
Speaker 0: So when they talked it came out of the speakers that were facing away from us Bounced off the rear of the room and then came back to us so we couldn't tell what the hell they were asking.
Speaker 1: Now the ways to mitigate this are one to have your assistant repeat questions to you, which worked wonderfully to to Be very good at reading lips and guessing what people are asking which at a panel that's kind of rudimentary.
Speaker 1: We were talking about podcasting on a very basic level.
Speaker 1: It was usually pretty easy to guess what people are saying.
Speaker 1: if you picked up one or two of the words they said Yep, first there's one point.
Speaker 1: I misjudged what someone was asking and answered a different question.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: More information is always better, but it's not just audio.
Speaker 1: if you're on a stage like a real stage You got to realize that those lights are going to be extremely hot and they're going to blind you.
Speaker 1: You won't be able to see anything and your eyes will hurt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're a professional you don't.
Speaker 0: generally you keep your eyes low and you furrow your brow and you know all kinds of things.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: I mean your best bet is either to read up on you know theater and stage and these sort of things and learn how to deal with all this stuff like the way the professionals do or Just do this a lot and honestly you'll get used to it real quick.
Speaker 1: Yeah As long as you try and you realize that These are problems everyone faces and you just have to overcome them.
Speaker 1: and I guess one other thing since we're kind of cobbling this episode Together somewhat half-assed Lee cobble cobble if you couldn't tell yeah, is that?
Speaker 1: Microphone discipline is is very important in a podcast But it's even more important live in many ways because at least when you're podcasting normally I hope that you've either got some sort of lavalier or else you've got the microphone either on a stand Or you hold it the same way every time you've got the pop filter Whatever you're using but it's very easy in your studio or at your desk to use the microphone consistently.
Speaker 1: If you're not using the microphone consistently when you're recording normally You probably shouldn't be on the road trying to record anything just yet because you're not quite there.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but anyway When you're doing a show live and I hate to make fun of Scott for this But I crack up every time I see the pictures from torque on You've got to be very aware of the microphone because if you're not used to using a microphone in front of a crowd It's very easy to move the microphone around a lot Which isn't always a big deal because a lot of times they'll use omni mics for this purpose.
Speaker 1: But more importantly in terms of how you look you might hold the microphone right in front of your face Like Scott did so.
Speaker 1: all the pictures of the panel show Scott standing there Holding his hand directly in front of his face with the microphone kind of blocking everything.
Speaker 0: I'm hip-hopping.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're hip-hopping non-stop rocking.
Speaker 1: I Bit the head off a dove in the tunnel of love.
Speaker 0: All right
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you're gonna do a live thing and you've never done this sort of thing before just do this alone and don't feel Embarrassed but go into your bathroom Hold the microphone and kind of pose with it move it around and try to find a way to hold it.
Speaker 0: That looks like all those people on TV look Yeah, and also, you know You also you can't take it too far away from your face because then it won't work.
Speaker 0: Your mouth your noise won't go in the noise hole.
Speaker 1: Now either.
Speaker 1: you can either you know, basically pick where you're going to hold the microphone.
Speaker 1: then before the panel Figure out all your levels based on that and then hold the microphone.
Speaker 1: that far away come hell.
Speaker 1: Now advanced techniques which really only apply mostly to vocalists and singers are that you can change the distance of the microphone Depending on what you're doing in order to act as your own gain.
Speaker 1: You know if you're yelling you put the microphone further away.
Speaker 1: If you're trying to do some sort of sensuous voice you pull it right up close and deep mic it.
Speaker 1: You move it around based on what you're doing.
Speaker 1: If none of that made sense.
Speaker 1: Don't try it.
Speaker 1: Just hold the microphone consistently.
Speaker 1: It's like bowling.
Speaker 1: you can do all the fancy stuff in bowling But for the intermediate and beginner skill level the best thing you can do is to be consistent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, throw the ball straight down the middle of the lane every time.
Speaker 1: Yeah at least throw it the same way every time even if it goes into the gutter every time as Long as you're throwing it the exact same way Then you'll be able to make simple changes to what you're doing.
Speaker 1: to hit For example, if you always throw the bowling ball and it always hits the pin on the far left and nothing else Take one step to the right and throw it the exact same way and now you're gonna get a strike.
Speaker 1: Maybe or at least you'll do better.
Speaker 1: Yep, if you hold the microphone the exact same way, then the next time you record you'll know kind of where to put the levels.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I mean in general Scott seems to be done with his episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you've resorted to gin mode.
Speaker 1: Granted I do that fairly often on the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you do.
Speaker 1: the basic advice we have is very simply Practice prepare and or spend money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, prepare is always number one because even if you set your Bill Gates without that prepare part, you're fucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you can hire all the assistants in the world But they can't actually say what you want to say unless you hire them to do the entire podcast for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like imagine if Steve Jobs died and you had to do his keynote tomorrow Even if you had all his mad bunnies and resources, you wouldn't pull it off without the preparing.
Speaker 1: It depends on who you are and what you're good at it does.
Speaker 0: but I mean I guess you have to know what the hell you're gonna be introducing.
Speaker 1: true But a little bit of optimism for all of you out there because I know a lot of people are new at podcasting.
Speaker 1: If you just do this constantly It's amazing how good you'll get at it and how quickly you'll get better at it Provided you try at least a little and you listen to what you're doing and try to make changes.
Speaker 1: I mean if you record your first panel and The audio sounds like this out undo that.
Speaker 1: Maybe you'll learn that.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got to turn my gain down.
Speaker 1: Oh, I gotta hold the mic further away.
Speaker 1: And actually I'll say now that What you just heard probably didn't sound nearly as bad to you as it did to Scott and I because we listen to the raw Audio, but what you hear goes through the compressor and the limiter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that really hurt.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, that's because you have those weird microphone or those weird headphones that you can't adjust so easily.
Speaker 0: I can adjust them just fine.
Speaker 0: They were worth the 20 bucks I paid.
Speaker 1: Yeah But just keep trying practice learn prepare Prepare get to things early buy equipment Don't suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now, well, I mean we just really talked about the technology.
Speaker 1: We kind of padded this episode out because there wasn't so much to say about it.
Speaker 0: I Guaranteed I wanted to talk about bit torrent, but no.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem was we already said we were gonna do this show All right.
Speaker 0: Well next week, we'll talk about bit torrent.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then in the future some Thursday We're definitely gonna talk about presentation skills in general, you know how to speak what to say how to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well probably another completely separate episode on Small weak solid-state recorders and how to do interviews on the road Which I realized now it was probably a better show to do because I have a lot more to say about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just don't know.
Speaker 0: I think we don't know a lot about the different like specific devices and their features.
Speaker 0: We have to research that a bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I know a lot about the techniques.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep I think we're good for today.
Speaker 1: tune in tomorrow when we'll be talking about something very fun.
Speaker 1: Oh Do you want to ruin it?
Speaker 1: You want to tell them?
Speaker 0: No, no, we'll let it be.
Speaker 1: All right All I have to say is that There might be some kobolds.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh, and there might be some babies.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh, and We might be having some dinner.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.