Speaker 0: It's Thursday May 11th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We're gonna finish talking about e3.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So the results are in on whether our podcast should have been three hours or not.
Speaker 1: yep, and almost no one voted.
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: there were like?
Speaker 0: 20 years.
Speaker 0: so people in the forum saying yay make it as long as you want.
Speaker 0: the only person who said don't make it long.
Speaker 0: With someone who emailed us absolutely every other person who responded of which there were many said make the podcast longer.
Speaker 0: longer is better All right.
Speaker 1: Then if we pay for more lips and we can do that we could have done it without more lips And you know it now.
Speaker 1: cuz.
Speaker 1: then we would have to post a lot more episodes.
Speaker 1: on the hosting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've been fine.
Speaker 1: We're on the edge of the hood on the lips and as it is now We're all right.
Speaker 0: now We're not anyway.
Speaker 0: someone also asked what the longest podcast ever is and I'm not quite sure There wasn't something.
Speaker 0: I tried like for 15 minutes to google it and I couldn't find it.
Speaker 0: however someone in our forums Linked to a couple podcasts that are on average pretty long and the longest one I saw was the bib and yaz podcast.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what this podcast is about but it I think I saw an episode that was like two hours and change or almost three hours.
Speaker 0: Yeah maybe we can find out what the longest podcast ever was or is and Beat it just once.
Speaker 1: that's real easy.
Speaker 1: All I have to do is use my little random tone generator and generate random tones that are one second longer than whatever that is And put it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is you know that counts in a semantic argument.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's also real compressible Mp3 wise.
Speaker 0: yeah, however if you the Guinness Book of World Records doesn't let you get away with stuff like the Guinness Book of World Records Is barely researched bullshit?
Speaker 0: Well, it's not about research.
Speaker 0: It's about you know.
Speaker 1: It's about worlds.
Speaker 1: blankie is blank.
Speaker 1: It's not anything that it is.
Speaker 0: they put in.
Speaker 0: the world's blankie is blank and then if you think you got more blankiness then You go, and you put up a challenge, and they have rules for each blank in his blank, and then you try to beat it.
Speaker 0: It's like an ongoing contest.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: I just remember when I was a kid that the Guinness Book of World Records was really the lowbrow entertainment.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was very lowbrow.
Speaker 1: I remember when they banned white lowbrow.
Speaker 1: They banned a long time ago all of the body Related ones because people were hurting themselves trying to set records like ate the most broken glass.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, our fattest.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I think early Bay currently has the fattest title.
Speaker 0: Okay So maybe one day.
Speaker 0: We'll make a long one.
Speaker 0: I don't care, but rim seems to be anti long podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just generally don't think it's a good idea.
Speaker 1: I mean I know if I were listening I'd probably just stop listening after an hour or so, but I don't have time to listen to podcasts anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I think the idea is that since it's a podcast not a radio show that people will pause it on their iPod and then Continue later,
Speaker 1: but by the same token by spreading it out into two hour and a half podcasts It saves us some effort down the road.
Speaker 0: I guess theoretically.
Speaker 1: But for all they know we did record the whole thing that night, and we just split it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no he didn't know we did, but I just want to say that you know.
Speaker 0: uh While I don't care if we actually do long podcasts or not If you really wanted long podcasts, and you're not getting them direct all your blame to rim.
Speaker 0: yep yell at me yellow rim Scott That's me.
Speaker 0: Oh no problem with the long podcast.
Speaker 0: I'm with you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if there's any problems yell at rim.
Speaker 0: Yeah People know which one of us is which right because other podcasts introduce themselves and everyone seems to.
Speaker 1: anytime there's been an argument.
Speaker 1: It's like they can equate the way we speak and the things we say on the show with the things we say in the forum.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seems like they can do that.
Speaker 1: But of course the guy who was trying to guess what we look like based on our voices thought I was Hispanic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know why I thought that.
Speaker 0: yeah, we are clearly not Hispanic Very very not Hispanic although we like Hispanics.
Speaker 0: Hispanics are cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we are not them.
Speaker 1: So news time yeah in the news now, I got some non e3 news.
Speaker 0: here I also have non e3 news because well there wasn't so much because like we're gonna cover all This stuff that was e3 news is part of the main bit.
Speaker 0: So the only real e3 news we can cover is like the side news, and there wasn't so much of it.
Speaker 0: at least it wasn't Prominent enough at this time for us to find it.
Speaker 0: See that like yeah next week all the news from all the tiny booths around e3 from the independent game developers is Gonna start crawling up as the Sony Nintendo Microsoft news is complete.
Speaker 1: of course It was also.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of news that is interesting, but really isn't worth getting a billing as a news bit.
Speaker 0: Oh clearly, that's like every day.
Speaker 1: Paris Hilton was there with her stupid game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Adam West was giving signatures.
Speaker 1: Adam West is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not a news bit.
Speaker 1: We could do a whole show on Adam West.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: That'd be scary.
Speaker 0: I Have to show you that.
Speaker 0: remind me to show you an animated gif from old Batman after the show, okay?
Speaker 1: But anyway, my news is something that happened and started a long time ago, but it finally ended.
Speaker 1: so that's the news.
Speaker 1: There is going to be no dot xxx domain.
Speaker 1: I can voted it down completely.
Speaker 1: I say it's great news.
Speaker 0: Well, see I didn't really care about you know, the Existence of the domain itself.
Speaker 1: I mean it's our hair from a technical standpoint Not even from a porn standpoint.
Speaker 0: as far as I'm concerned at the more top-level domains the better.
Speaker 1: No, the more top-level domains the more convoluted broken and stupid DNS becomes.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well that makes it more and more likely we should get some IPv6 in the house.
Speaker 1: That doesn't have anything to do with DNS.
Speaker 0: I thought that IPv6 had a newer better DNS to hide it.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 1: no no DNS is completely independent of IPv6.
Speaker 1: There are different layers and everything have nothing to do with.
Speaker 0: I know they don't have anything to do with each other But I figured that when they switch to IPv6, oh switch DNS to something newer better.
Speaker 1: No, because even if they quote-unquote switch to IPv6, that's not something that would happen immediately.
Speaker 1: It would be a long slow.
Speaker 0: I know that.
Speaker 1: I know that you can't just have a long slow change of something.
Speaker 0: Well, you know we need to do.
Speaker 0: we need to go check for RFCs for stuff like DNS 2.0.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: There's really nothing.
Speaker 1: DNS is fine.
Speaker 0: There's no way to make that better.
Speaker 1: There are ways to make it better But the ways to make it better in would have other negative side effects.
Speaker 1: They suck or would be difficult to implement or a lot of people will just say fuck you.
Speaker 1: We're not changing.
Speaker 1: DNS isn't really broken or anything.
Speaker 1: It works fine.
Speaker 1: The only people who complain about it now.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be interesting because I've noticed something about people who are first or second year IT students Because they post a lot on slash out about this.
Speaker 1: They always whenever DNS comes up.
Speaker 1: They always say DNS is horrible and stupid and broken and it's gonna die.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's honest last legs.
Speaker 1: We need to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: We need something better and I've noticed that most of the reasons they give for it being broken are really just them not understanding how DNS works.
Speaker 0: That happens with anything.
Speaker 1: Well, it seems that because DNS if you don't know how to come out of set it up and you're a you know Freshman in IT and you're building a DNS server It's kind of painful because you don't know the syntax of the text file you have to write.
Speaker 1: But once you learn the syntax of the text file and then you know why it's that way and why everything is the way it Is you go?
Speaker 1: Oh, all right.
Speaker 1: This is actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: It works fairly well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, DNS works.
Speaker 0: Okay, but you know as As with any computer geek, even if you have something that works just fine You're always looking for something that works better and awesomer.
Speaker 1: That's very much the difference between IT and CS on a very high level.
Speaker 1: broad fundamental planning perspective.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this Linux kernel is okay, but I need something else.
Speaker 1: pirate kernel universe Yeah, but like I I do IT for a living.
Speaker 1: like Scott is CS I am IT.
Speaker 1: We're both computer guys, but don't think that we do the same thing.
Speaker 1: We really can't do what either of us does.
Speaker 0: very well Like I know more about his stuff than he knows about my.
Speaker 1: yeah, you have proven that wrong a couple times.
Speaker 0: I know plenty about IT stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not like the master.
Speaker 1: you couldn't even get an NTP server working.
Speaker 0: I could.
Speaker 0: I got it working just fine.
Speaker 1: It didn't work and you complained about it.
Speaker 0: I knew how to do NTP.
Speaker 0: I just didn't know how to do super NTP.
Speaker 1: You didn't know how to do NTP.
Speaker 1: that works.
Speaker 0: You know, that's the thing is that I know how to do the basic normal level of everything.
Speaker 0: You know how to do but just not the really good level of you know Super you don't know how to do anything that I.
Speaker 1: what do you mean super?
Speaker 1: you couldn't make an NTP server go.
Speaker 0: I can make an NTP server go.
Speaker 0: I just can't make it go the way I want.
Speaker 1: How did you want it to go?
Speaker 0: I wanted it to Serve the time.
Speaker 0: I Wanted it to serve the time to other computers and also get the time from a different computer.
Speaker 1: That's like the simplest.
Speaker 1: that's all NTP does.
Speaker 1: that's the most basic.
Speaker 1: That is a three line configuration file.
Speaker 1: four lines if you want to be fancy.
Speaker 0: But I also wanted to have.
Speaker 0: I wanted to have like security things So other people couldn't get the time and no one could change the time.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: five lines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I put those lines in.
Speaker 0: I copied them from the internet.
Speaker 1: It didn't work cuz you probably copied the wrong lines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: I can make a computer get the time just fine.
Speaker 1: Anyway anyway, I The work I do is generally along the lines of make something that works and maintain it maintain uptime.
Speaker 1: Nothing should ever go down.
Speaker 1: don't upgrade something unless you have to.
Speaker 1: the network never ever ever goes down.
Speaker 1: if it goes down you Make it come back up immediately and the work.
Speaker 0: I do is computers.
Speaker 0: Don't already do X. They could do X Technologically speaking, but they don't do X. make them do X. make them do X better.
Speaker 0: make them do X even better.
Speaker 0: all right now There's a problem.
Speaker 0: They're not doing X perfectly.
Speaker 0: make it do it perfectly now.
Speaker 0: make it do it better now.
Speaker 1: these two Come into conflict in such situations as Rim wants the hosting to be up right now Scott wants to put a new kernel on it The kernel on the hosting.
Speaker 0: I don't go that far, but yeah You know I'll make something and it'll work well.
Speaker 0: And then rim will have to be in charge of making sure it continues to work well.
Speaker 0: And then I'll say all right I made a thing to make it work faster.
Speaker 0: and rim says Does that mean we need to turn it off and then turn it on again?
Speaker 0: and Scott says yes, and I go?
Speaker 0: Oh my god, and I say all right when it comes back up.
Speaker 0: It will be faster.
Speaker 0: Everyone who's sitting around while it's off can suck my dick.
Speaker 0: Anyway Skip this shit, so we can get to the e3 business.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be no xxx domain.
Speaker 1: I think that's great because it was a stupid idea.
Speaker 0: I think it was a good idea, but that a law to make people use it was a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Mostly well the problem.
Speaker 1: It's stupid to have that as a top-level domain because now you're making a domain That's based on the content.
Speaker 1: a top-level domain based on the content of the sites as opposed to the Identities of the people who create the sites.
Speaker 0: it's all right.
Speaker 0: so xxx domain shouldn't be for porn sites.
Speaker 0: It should be for people who are pornographers to make sites.
Speaker 1: no because that already exists.
Speaker 1: It's calm.
Speaker 0: anything commercial was calm, so why don't they have dot xxx?
Speaker 1: calm you can do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's good Anyone can do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyone could just buy dot xxx.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is that you know we need one in between there.
Speaker 0: So you could buy Joe dot xxx calm and then rim dot xxx.
Speaker 1: DNS was originally that way.
Speaker 0: I know it was.
Speaker 0: it's not that way anymore.
Speaker 0: The
Speaker 1: only reason it's not that way is because people got greedy and mostly because idiots who didn't understand DNS were in charge of companies making decisions about it and as a result They said why can't I just name things whatever I want not understanding the technical limitations and the reasons Why things were the way they were?
Speaker 1: hmm, but anyway?
Speaker 1: There's an unintended consequence of this dot xxx decision.
Speaker 1: now for some reason and mostly Fundamentalist Christians and anti-porn crusaders were advocates of this because then they wanted laws that would force quote-unquote Pornography to be under this domain.
Speaker 1: That was their goal.
Speaker 1: that way they could censor it and they wanted to screw anyone who tried to put porn elsewhere.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna argue about the definition of porn because I think we all agree.
Speaker 1: Anyway a lot of other Fundamentalist anti-porn people were against dot xxx because it legitimizes porn.
Speaker 1: That group was actually stronger in the US and the main reason that the u.s.
Speaker 1: Was against the dot xxx domain was because of the fundamentalists who were against porn.
Speaker 1: ICANN is an international body.
Speaker 1: the rest of the world saw ICANN's vetoing xxx as the u.s.
Speaker 1: pseudo Christian fundamentalist crazies trying to exert control over the Internet.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of rumbling going on in Europe about this Even though ICANN probably made the decision for reasons that have nothing to do with America.
Speaker 0: Yep People need to know about technology.
Speaker 0: There should be some sort of universal law where if you don't know about something you are Thereby prevented from making any decision about it.
Speaker 0: if you don't know about fires You cannot be the boss of the firemen.
Speaker 0: Yeah That is should be the law.
Speaker 0: if you don't know anything about guns You should not be able to do anything that has to do with any gun legislation or anything.
Speaker 0: That's the way it should be.
Speaker 0: if you don't know about technology You have no say when it comes to a technological matter.
Speaker 0: now you can argue about which matter requires which you know Field of knowledge.
Speaker 0: I don't care about that, but Right.
Speaker 1: I got this great idealistic idea, but I don't care about the details or the actual implementation.
Speaker 0: No, I don't care.
Speaker 0: That doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It's just the specific examples.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 1: I shake Rivera.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever The point is if you don't know about something you shouldn't be able to say anything about it because you don't know nothing about.
Speaker 1: No, you're allowed to say I don't know anything about that.
Speaker 0: That's the only thing you're allowed to say.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're also allowed to say will you tell teach me about it?
Speaker 0: No, you're not allowed to say that.
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 0: because I won't teach you.
Speaker 0: Learn on your own from a book.
Speaker 1: Let's get to your news because I'm actually this is something I know a lot about and I'm pissed off about.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I believe this is in the news again.
Speaker 1: This was killed a long time ago Okay.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the cover of Time magazine says something about autism.
Speaker 0: So I had seen this.
Speaker 0: actually, you know, how often does Scott see the cover of Time magazine?
Speaker 0: who reads no magazines and watches?
Speaker 0: No TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I happen to see it actually randomly, but I paid it no heed.
Speaker 0: I didn't really care.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: so then I'm listening to the Pendulette podcast today, which is awesome, which is awesome.
Speaker 0: It's actually a radio show that's an hour long, but they podcast it which is cool And he gets a Randy on the phone and I'm like, woohoo James Randy's on the phone.
Speaker 0: What up?
Speaker 0: And they start talking about this autism and I'm like, alright, what are they gonna say about autism?
Speaker 0: It's probably some magic hokey autism treatment, right?
Speaker 0: No, not some magic hokey autism treatment.
Speaker 0: all those those do exist and you shouldn't pay them any heed.
Speaker 0: Apparently the cover story that is extremely long and prominent in the latest issue of Time magazine is very very supportive of something called Facilitated communication and there is a facilitated communication Institute at Syracuse University.
Speaker 0: now, let me tell you what this is Because I see rim like inhaling I'm just.
Speaker 1: all I'm gonna say is one word Bullshit, yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: So you might know that autism is I guess a disorder that can vary in degree Depending on who you are.
Speaker 0: You can be slightly autistic which is called high High functioning high functioning autism, which means you're kind of like a normal person.
Speaker 0: only you're a little weird You know because you're a little bit autistic.
Speaker 0: So which means you can live a pretty much normal life, but people who meet you might go Hey, that guy's a little weird because he's a little bit autistic.
Speaker 0: Or you can be low functioning autistic, which means you're super autistic and you're basically just.
Speaker 0: I Don't want to insult anyone who is low functioning autistic, but you're really just like a gibbering Nothing.
Speaker 0: I like, you know, I really I'm not trying to be a fan, you know, usually I'm trying to be offensive I'm really not trying to be offensive, but that's you can't communicate.
Speaker 0: You can't read or write you can't do anything you can make noises and flail around and You just you're really not almost non-sentient.
Speaker 1: now There's Asperger's which is similar to autism But it's generally separate and there's still a lot of research going on.
Speaker 1: autism and Asperger's aren't very well understood yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're not.
Speaker 0: this is something that can be figured out by science and because it hasn't been figured out by science There's a lot of Randy going on now.
Speaker 0: the main problem with High functioning autistic kids is that you know, they have trouble in school because they're a little weird and We can do a lot about that.
Speaker 0: That doesn't even require science.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though kids in mind at this point There's there are a lot of misconceptions about autism out there.
Speaker 1: They're sure mainly coming from the movie Rain Man.
Speaker 1: Yeah Autistic does not mean super genius who just is weird.
Speaker 0: No, it does not there.
Speaker 1: I mean there are a few cases of people who have abilities like that.
Speaker 1: They're few and far between and most autistic people are not secret geniuses.
Speaker 1: that is correct.
Speaker 1: If you think they are you're.
Speaker 1: it's sad, but you're just deluding yourself.
Speaker 1: Kind of like the Shivo situation where oh look, she's following the balloon She's there and then they autopsied and there wasn't even an ocular cortex or a brain or anything.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's just nothing.
Speaker 0: So The problem with low functioning autistic people is that you can't communicate with them whatsoever.
Speaker 0: They're just basically Completely void of any human exist like, you know thinking human existence that other people can You know detect.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean there's brain activity.
Speaker 1: They're they're thinking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're they exist in their brain.
Speaker 1: We don't know how they exist, but they're there.
Speaker 1: It's possible.
Speaker 0: They don't know what they're thinking.
Speaker 0: We don't know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: We don't you know, all we know is they're making a noise They're moving around.
Speaker 1: It's you know, yeah, I mean they're people and something's going on.
Speaker 0: I can't read they can't write They can't do anything.
Speaker 1: Well, here comes Facilitated communication, right?
Speaker 0: So if you're imagine being a parent of a low-functioning autistic child You're pretty much.
Speaker 0: your greatest wish in the world is to communicate with this child in any way whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Facilitated communication Institute at Syracuse University.
Speaker 0: what they do there is.
Speaker 0: Let me let me just write.
Speaker 0: Let me read this little paragraph here with Chadwick helping to stabilize her right wrist and her mother watching a girl thought to be Incapable of learning to read or write slowly typed.
Speaker 0: I love mom.
Speaker 0: With Chadwick helping to stabilize her right wrist I'm doing the exact same thing Penn Jillette did with Chadwick helping to stabilize her right wrist.
Speaker 0: People are taking their heavily heavily autistic children to this Institute where other Completely normal people are holding the autistic child by the hand moving their hand around on a keyboard and Basically, it's like if I grabbed rims hand and I took his index finger and I pushed it down on the keyboard and make him Type rim is gay.
Speaker 1: You know what if this were Penn & Teller's bullshit?
Speaker 1: right now I can just picture like us doing that sort of bit or them doing that bit where it's spelling out bullshit Yeah, and then the typewriter comes up ding and then he holds it up and then they do their next bit.
Speaker 0: now Here's where it gets worse.
Speaker 0: If you think that somehow these facilitators are actually not typing for the children and that The they're just holding the child's hand in place so that the child can you know type as they want.
Speaker 0: here is something Randy did.
Speaker 0: Randy went and he had the facilitator leave the room and He went to the child and he said, you know, basically Truck truck type truck.
Speaker 0: I don't know if truck is the word but might have been house who knows.
Speaker 0: and he showed a picture of it.
Speaker 0: He's like truck truck truck truck truck truck truck, you know.
Speaker 0: Then he brings the facilitator back in the room.
Speaker 0: And what is the kid type?
Speaker 0: not truck type something else not truck.
Speaker 0: then The kid type something really really quickly.
Speaker 0: That's like this man.
Speaker 0: He's making me very angry.
Speaker 0: He needs to leave bla-bla-bla-bla-bla-bla.
Speaker 0: Huh Right now here's an even worse one.
Speaker 0: Are you ready?
Speaker 0: So someone else not Randy did a study.
Speaker 0: now There have been 45 studies and all of them has come to the same result and the same result is the facilitators are doing the typing Not the kids.
Speaker 0: the kids cannot communicate with anyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's really no question as to whether or not 45 Perfect scientific studies ready for this study.
Speaker 0: This is the like the study that is absolutely convincing to everyone.
Speaker 0: Someone went in and they would show a picture like a really like a children's picture to the facilitator.
Speaker 0: Then the facilitator believed that you know, the same picture was being shown to the child, but they switched the picture up.
Speaker 0: So they'd show a house to the facilitator and then they show a truck to the kid.
Speaker 0: then they would have the facilitator facilitate the kid in typing a hundred percent of the time.
Speaker 0: The kid typed the picture that was shown to the facilitator and never did they type the picture that was shown to the child ever.
Speaker 0: ha People are fooling parents of autistic children into believing they are communicating with their autistic children when in fact they are Communicating with some facilitator.
Speaker 1: now, there are two possible ways to look at this.
Speaker 1: either the people doing the facilitating Genuinely genuinely believe they're doing good like something.
Speaker 0: I think it's the Ouija board effect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the idiomotor effect.
Speaker 1: Yep Or perhaps even people.
Speaker 1: maybe they're con artists, but they think they're helping, you know, they fake it.
Speaker 1: But then the parent feels better and the kid, you know what the parent feels like.
Speaker 1: they're bonding with the kid.
Speaker 1: I love mom Wow.
Speaker 1: Look now the mom feels like there's hope.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: However Anyone who thinks the second thing is evil?
Speaker 0: Yeah, no Hope is better than false.
Speaker 0: Hope if you disagree with that come over here.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna beat you up Cuz you deserve a beating, okay No, hope is better than false Hope.
Speaker 0: get that through your head.
Speaker 0: if anyone disagrees I dare you to challenge us on that.
Speaker 0: challenge anyone on that.
Speaker 0: who is not evil?
Speaker 1: It's just really these people regardless of their motivation or taking advantage of parents who really I mean, there's nowhere they can turn.
Speaker 1: There's no treatment for autism.
Speaker 1: There's no way to help these kids.
Speaker 0: Nope So the parents are currently with current scientific science.
Speaker 0: There is no hope.
Speaker 0: you will never communicate with your child.
Speaker 0: it's sad but true and it's much better if you figure that out right away and deal with it as opposed to having this false hope and Many many painful emotional times through the course of your life.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's not to say you don't try.
Speaker 1: I mean still you go to the research institutes and let them do their tests and try But don't expect something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you get your hopes up about something in which there is no Hope you will consistently be let down and that's much much worse Emotionally speaking.
Speaker 0: then knowing there's no hope and thus when it turns out there's still no Hope you just carry on as usual and then if something actually turns up then you get excited now.
Speaker 1: We'd be on a much different tack here If the evidence were inconclusive or if the studies have gone both ways or if there were any evidence at all.
Speaker 0: 45 scientific studies and the two I just described to you I think are a hundred percent conclusive.
Speaker 0: you'd have to be an idiot to not understand what the hell is going on here.
Speaker 0: If I if rim is incapable of communication with human beings and I take his hand and move it around on a keyboard And use his index finger to push down keys that say something He's evil.
Speaker 0: I'm the one who's communicating not rim Steve.
Speaker 0: Oh Steve.
Speaker 0: Oh There you go.
Speaker 1: All right things the day Mine isn't so much.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: well, it's a cool thing But I don't have a lot to say about it.
Speaker 1: this awesome Mirage appeared in I think Eastern China Shanghai.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: basically it was a mirage of a whole city.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw pictures and I was like, whoa Is that real?
Speaker 1: Apparently this area was called the gathering place or the dwelling place of the gods a long time ago because the region the way the Atmosphere is in the water vapor.
Speaker 1: It's just very conducive to crazy mirages and illusions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like Mirage land.
Speaker 0: I think what.
Speaker 0: it was just a reflection of the city that was on the other side, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was cool though.
Speaker 1: Check it out.
Speaker 0: I saw a picture and I was like, holy crap a freaking mirage of real.
Speaker 1: it made it to dig.
Speaker 1: So I'm sure everyone's seen it already, but that's all I got.
Speaker 1: I just want to talk about e3.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my thing of the day is actually a video game.
Speaker 0: It's called plasma pong and if you go to plasma pong comm you can download it for free.
Speaker 0: and what it is It's only for Windows.
Speaker 0: sadly It's just pong.
Speaker 0: you play it on the PC.
Speaker 0: But you have two extra things you can do in addition to moving the paddle up and moving the paddle down.
Speaker 0: You can shoot plasma out of your paddle and you can suck plasma into your paddle.
Speaker 1: It's not nearly as dumb as that just sounded.
Speaker 0: No, it looks really cool like a wicked awesome screensaver and the gameplay is actually kind of crazy.
Speaker 0: because you have to like Said I'm trying not to say like what's with you in the light.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're lucky.
Speaker 1: I don't have a big shield.
Speaker 0: That's what I was gonna say is if you had a big shield.
Speaker 0: I would eat it like like Yeah So you spray this plasma and a lot.
Speaker 0: the higher the level you get to the more the ball is affected by the plasma.
Speaker 0: So the ball is just flying around never actually touching anyone's paddle But bouncing back and forth across the screen in the plasma.
Speaker 0: and you have to manipulate the plasma in such a way to get it To fly really fast off the other guy's side of the screen.
Speaker 0: so we can't stop it.
Speaker 1: Windows only.
Speaker 1: but if I get it to work in wine I'll let everyone know and tell them how to do.
Speaker 0: it seems like a pretty simple game.
Speaker 0: It should work nicely and it looks really cool.
Speaker 1: You know what the rule of wine is rule number one It will not work.
Speaker 0: rule number two Well, the other final rule of wine is if by some miracle you manage to get it to work It will work better than it works in windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the best thing about wine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's just things.
Speaker 1: either work or they don't and there's really no middle ground with wine.
Speaker 0: No, not so much All right.
Speaker 0: last time on our e3 coverage We talked about Sony and we talked about the DS and we pretty much covered everything in those departments and nothing has changed In those departments.
Speaker 0: yeah, thankfully because I was kind of worried that we were gonna do this big e3 show and then all this new information would Come out on the show floor and we'd have to go back and add all that stuff in.
Speaker 1: that is true for Nintendo but we didn't talk about Nintendo.
Speaker 0: you intend?
Speaker 0: Oh and Mike the Nintendo Wii and The Microsoft Xbox 360?
Speaker 0: there was some new tidbits on the show floor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually there was a lot for Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Oh a whole lot the more than anyone else at least.
Speaker 1: well in general.
Speaker 1: Here's here's the the general vibe of what's going on at e3.
Speaker 1: There are crazy crazy lines for everything Nintendo has constantly There is.
Speaker 0: you have to wait and in line for I think the guess was six hours to play with a Wii.
Speaker 1: I can play with a Wii right now for free.
Speaker 0: I know I don't know why people waiting in six lines six hour lines to do it if you want hell of a Wii.
Speaker 0: One guy was at his first e3 and he got in the Wii line and he says I'm not wasting six hours on my first E3 and he just said I just won't use the Wii at e3.
Speaker 0: I'll do everything else instead.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it really sucks for the journalists who have to use it to you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah now compare that.
Speaker 0: it will compare and contrast that to Sony and Microsoft where Sony and Microsoft booths the people were estimating you had to wait maybe five minutes to play anything you wanted Anything any game that was playable at Microsoft's or Sony's booth.
Speaker 1: five-minute wait other than Tendo.
Speaker 0: Six hour wait to use the Wii other than panels going around.
Speaker 1: E3 is basically just a cluster of people fighting to get into Nintendo's area at all times and nothing else.
Speaker 0: and This you know.
Speaker 0: people accuse us of being anti Sony Pro.
Speaker 0: whatever we tell it like it is if you're if we were biased or Anything we'd be saying Microsoft sucks even though they're not second.
Speaker 0: so much right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I really didn't like the Xbox when it came out But I'm starting to take a shine and the fact that I might buy one is kind of scary to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when you listen to us talk, you know, we are gonna say some fanboys things like oh my god We really like that.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: Like you might not like Wario where smooth moves, but that's our favorite thing in the world.
Speaker 0: so you can tell okay They really like Wario where and you might not.
Speaker 0: But pay attention when we say things like there's a six hour wait for Nintendo And there's a five hour wait for Sony and Microsoft.
Speaker 0: That's not fanboyism opinion.
Speaker 0: That's a fact.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like the At will.
Speaker 1: now, I mean we keep talking about the PSP like we never see anyone playing.
Speaker 0: is it like?
Speaker 1: yeah Well, but I was I used it properly.
Speaker 1: I didn't use it as a breakup.
Speaker 1: We see things like.
Speaker 1: that's a proper grammatical use of the word.
Speaker 1: like that's fine Let's get on with the show so you can go to sleep Alright, I just because there's people arguing about the PSP and I wanted to get this out.
Speaker 0: Alright get it out now before we start.
Speaker 1: the fact is that at e3 No one has PSP's.
Speaker 1: reporters have said this everyone has DS's and they're playing them constantly.
Speaker 0: That's a fact.
Speaker 1: That's not you know, I Said, you know, that was great All right, I guess we can't talk about this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mr Why interpret that fact as you will?
Speaker 0: but there are DS's everywhere and PSP's nowhere to be seen.
Speaker 0: at e3 The premier gaming event of the year there are DS's all over the place and no PSP's to be seen except for Sony's booth.
Speaker 1: Alright, so let's start at the beginning with Nintendo.
Speaker 1: cuz I I don't want to start with the stuff that was just announced.
Speaker 0: Well, I was figured we would do the system and then we do the games for the Wii.
Speaker 0: All right Well, no, let's start out with the GameCube.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a new GameCube game at the end of the year.
Speaker 0: Great Super Paper Mario.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Now if you played Paper Mario thousand-year door, you know that well.
Speaker 0: or any Paper Mario, you know that Paper Mario is on Mario RPG type game and The interesting thing about it is that Mario and all his friends are made of paper and the world is made of paper.
Speaker 0: So they do a lot of interesting tricks like Mario will tear a hole in the background and he'll sneak through a secret or He'll roll himself up like a piece of or fold himself into a paper airplane and fly and such.
Speaker 1: The games are also real heavy on the Nintendo style humor slash, you know world which we like a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, lots of Mario Joe.
Speaker 1: Nothing's better than a cute little girl Goomba.
Speaker 0: Yeah girl archaeologist Goomba.
Speaker 0: Yeah now in Paper Mario thousand-year door, there was a short sequence where Koopa King Koopa did some Mario Super Mario 1 style side scrolling and he got really ate a giant piece of meat and Became the size of the screen and smashed up a whole bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: But you you know, you controlled that for maybe five minutes of the game and that was it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Super Paper Mario is Not going to be an RPG.
Speaker 0: It's going to be a Super Mario platform game.
Speaker 0: However, everything is made of paper and has the same graphics that thousand-year door has and you can play as Mario the princess and Koopa Who each do their own different things?
Speaker 0: It's like a Mario - it's gonna be a really good.
Speaker 0: Well, I think you switch between them at will at least.
Speaker 0: I saw a video where Mario flipped over and the princess appeared Like in the middle of a level.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and I think I saw Koopa breathing some fire.
Speaker 0: and When the best thing about this game is there is apparently a power-up that not only makes you tremendously huge filling the screen But when you use this power-up, it returns the character to their 8-bit pixelated Sprite as opposed to the new shiny Paper Mario sprite.
Speaker 0: So imagine a giant Super Mario Brothers Princess Peach or King Koopa.
Speaker 0: that's like the size of the screen smashing everything that's worth it alone for whatever this game cost.
Speaker 0: So that's the GameCube news one new game gonna come out at the end of the year.
Speaker 0: Oh Also the Zelda game that everyone knows about will have a GameCube version.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Twilight Princess is going to be released at the same time, but separately on both the revolution and the GameCube.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people thought that there would be one GameCube because they said it's gonna be a GameCube game.
Speaker 0: They said that and they didn't lie.
Speaker 0: But people thought that there would be a GameCube version that if you played the GameCube version on the Wii you would get advanced features sort of like Mario, Zelda ages and seasons for the Game Boy Color.
Speaker 0: if you played it on a Game Boy Advance a few secret things showed up.
Speaker 0: That's not going to be the case.
Speaker 0: The Zelda game is gonna have a Wii version and a GameCube version.
Speaker 0: you buy one or the other.
Speaker 0: if you buy both You're just kind of dumb.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, so if you have a GameCube and you're not planning on buying a Wii for a long time That's the only way I can recommend buying the Zelda GameCube.
Speaker 1: now I we don't really need to talk about this game.
Speaker 1: everyone knows it looks like it's going to be awesome.
Speaker 1: several Nintendo people have said things along the lines of We think this is the best Zelda we've ever made.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's what they said and people had mixed reactions to them saying that some people are like, okay This is gonna be the best Zelda ever.
Speaker 0: and some people said Okay, they're being real defensive about this Zelda being so great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: the game looks really cool.
Speaker 0: It looks like Zelda.
Speaker 0: it looks like what everyone wanted Wind Waker to be but wasn't.
Speaker 1: yeah It looks like Zelda 64 taken to the technological and plot extreme.
Speaker 0: All I can hope is that it has more dungeons.
Speaker 0: That was my number one complaint with the recent Zelda games is not enough done.
Speaker 0: freaking.
Speaker 1: minish cap had three Frickin.
Speaker 0: Wind Waker had like four or five.
Speaker 0: not you need more dungeons.
Speaker 0: I want to seize SNES style Zeldas where there's like four dungeons followed by eight dungeons.
Speaker 0: Stuff like that.
Speaker 0: That's what we need lots and lots of dungeons.
Speaker 0: That's what make Zelda great a big overworld lots and lots of dungeons.
Speaker 0: Okay, let's talk about the Wii system and what they said about it.
Speaker 1: in those preference the conference they had was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: They had it in the Kodak theater, which is the place they have the Oscars Now.
Speaker 1: it started basically with Miyamoto In a tuxedo with a Wii controller Conducting an orchestra playing the Legend of Zelda but the orchestra wasn't real.
Speaker 0: the orchestra was a Part of a video game and as he was actually as he moved the controller differently You could see that he was controlling the temple of the orchestra.
Speaker 1: Yeah all the Wii controller.
Speaker 1: I'll say now that all almost everything they showed was not a pre-rendered demo where they faked it.
Speaker 1: It was someone controlling something with the controller.
Speaker 0: People were saying how the Metroid stuff that they showed was a video and not you know Someone actually playing the game at that moment, but it didn't look like a pre-render.
Speaker 0: It looked like actual gameplay video footage.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now the crowd went wild.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the crowd is, you know crazy.
Speaker 0: Okay, so The Wii.
Speaker 0: what do we know about the Wii that we didn't know before?
Speaker 0: Well, they confirmed a bunch of rumors.
Speaker 0: there is going to be a speaker in the Wii controller.
Speaker 0: What does this mean?
Speaker 0: It means When you shoot use the Wii controller as a gun and pull the trigger on it the Wii controller itself will make a firing noise.
Speaker 0: Now that's kind of cool But what's the use now?
Speaker 0: I figured this out when someone you know started talking about it And I think might have been the Engadget podcast.
Speaker 0: they were like, okay You have a Wii controller, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you're shooting a bow and arrow.
Speaker 0: Now when you're shooting a real bow and arrow, you have a string, you know, how far back you're pulling it.
Speaker 0: You can hear the string getting tighter and tighter with a Wii controller.
Speaker 0: Just pulling it back You can't really tell how far back you've pulled it and looking at the screen You can't tell because it's a first-person view twang.
Speaker 0: So this speaker in the Wii controller is actually necessary Because it will make a noise as you pull the bow string back to let you know how far back you are.
Speaker 1: Also when I finally get my lightsaber game because I have no doubt that there's going to be some sort of lightsaber game LucasArts said we're looking into it.
Speaker 0: That's all the news we've got.
Speaker 1: My Wii is gonna be going.
Speaker 1: wow And that's just awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't even think no one thought of having that speaker but Nintendo thought of it and now that you know about it It's so essential.
Speaker 1: I mean, I just think it's so key.
Speaker 1: imagine all the Mario Party WarioWare minigames You can have where one guy's controller makes a noise and everyone reacts.
Speaker 1: because of that.
Speaker 1: We got to figure out.
Speaker 1: you got to guess whose controller made the noise or do something.
Speaker 0: Someone suggested that you would talk into a microphone on the controller then pass the controller.
Speaker 0: Someone would push a button and the controller would play back what you said.
Speaker 0: then they'd have to say that into the controller and pass it around like a game of telephone and Silly things can happen.
Speaker 1: Nintendo's really.
Speaker 1: it's like they put so many things into this so that Developers making games have crazy options to do whatever they want to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah The problem is when developers try to use all the options instead of just trying to make a game That really needs the option.
Speaker 1: Yep, which luckily seems to have worked out for the DS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of early DS people games have made the error of forcing themselves to use every feature.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like bomber man God bomber man used the touchscreen and perhaps the stupidest way ever.
Speaker 0: But now they're coming back and it seems people realized what's good and what's not.
Speaker 0: so it shouldn't take them.
Speaker 0: I don't imagine too many screw-ups on the Wii now that they figured it out in the DS.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay What don't we know about the Wii?
Speaker 1: The price.
Speaker 0: we don't know the price and we don't know the release date other than it will be in October November December of This year.
Speaker 1: now once again Nintendo is probably gonna stick to their promise that it'll be less than two hundred and fifty dollars or less $300 no matter what.
Speaker 0: I think the only promise was it'll be cheaper than anything else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it could be $300, but I really doubt that.
Speaker 0: I really doubt it.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 0: Everyone's the best guess is two hundred two hundred fifty dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, someone on slash.
Speaker 1: I was like if it was a hundred and fifty that would just destroy the industry in my.
Speaker 0: I Think they're just waiting to see what the final word is on everything else before they decide how they can set their price.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I already know the price.
Speaker 0: everybody is waiting to reveal it.
Speaker 0: That way they can keep the news rolling.
Speaker 1: That's what I was about to say.
Speaker 1: They're probably because they've right before e3 they announced that they're calling it the Wii and there was crazy press buzzing.
Speaker 1: Then e3 crazy press buzzing.
Speaker 1: then they announced Smash Brothers crazy press buzzing.
Speaker 1: then they're gonna announce the date crazy Press.
Speaker 1: then they're gonna announce the price and they're always in the news until finally it's release day Plus they also get to announce.
Speaker 0: pre-orders are now available, you know, there's a lot of things They just announced to keep the news rolling.
Speaker 1: Yep, as opposed to Sony we're gonna release the ps3 in March.
Speaker 1: We're gonna release it in not March.
Speaker 0: yeah, I don't know what's better saying a date and then delaying it and then saying another exact date and then eventually sticking to one of Those exact dates or not saying anything and then eventually sticking to a date.
Speaker 1: Apple seems to do very well with the hey Guess what?
Speaker 0: We just did as opposed to hey It's available on the Apple Store as soon as we stop talking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like when the Apple Store goes down everyone knows.
Speaker 1: Oh something just happened.
Speaker 0: Yep What else do we know about the Wii?
Speaker 0: There won't be any load times.
Speaker 0: He's promised us no load times.
Speaker 1: Now, that's great.
Speaker 1: I mean even the GameCube had a few load times in some games, but those are tiny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it was mostly.
Speaker 0: No, the load times.
Speaker 0: I've noticed in games.
Speaker 1: I have where where there were FMV's and Basically FMV's Yeah, and it seems that third-party port games have load games much more often than first-party games or second-party games.
Speaker 0: Yep I think because of the flash memory in the Wii you're not gonna see load times at all unless someone really really sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's going to be a Wii classic controller.
Speaker 1: It looks like this white Super NES controller like a cross between an SNES controller and a GameCube controller, but it's all white and we colored and People who have held on to it said that it feels right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it looks like it feels right.
Speaker 0: I guess you're gonna use it for your virtual console games, you know, your old-school NES games Yep, which they finally released some pictures and talk about.
Speaker 0: the only thing I'm it's weird about this controller Is that it isn't wireless.
Speaker 0: you plug it into the bottom of the Wii controller where the nunchuck usually plugs into and I Guess does that mean you're kind of tethered to the Wii.
Speaker 0: is there gonna be something that lets you use both at once or switch?
Speaker 0: Between the two or I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of tiny details.
Speaker 1: We're really not gonna get until we get closer to the release date.
Speaker 0: Someone made a comment that Nintendo always screws up one little thing.
Speaker 0: That doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: on the NES they screwed up.
Speaker 0: You have to blow into the cartridges.
Speaker 0: Yeah on the SNES I don't think anything was screwed up.
Speaker 1: No, no, you know what was wrong with the SNES.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Some button now because I had no problem with that though I know a few people did but you could just yank the game out.
Speaker 1: It didn't matter.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Some not all the SNES is because they fixed it later.
Speaker 1: But a lot of them if you left him in the Sun they turn this horrible yellow.
Speaker 1: That's true because of the plastic.
Speaker 0: that's not a big deal now in 64 didn't have enough memory.
Speaker 0: They had to add an expansion thing the GameCube.
Speaker 0: What problems with the GameCube?
Speaker 0: I can't think of any Hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess not.
Speaker 1: some people early on said it overheated, but it just turned out they were idiots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the DS had a. the DS light has a problem with the GBA cartridge not fitting all the way in.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean that one at least is understandable because they they wanted it to be small and that seems to be what people wanted.
Speaker 0: Yep, the GBA the screen didn't have a light.
Speaker 0: people complained.
Speaker 1: Yeah I remember the penny arcade that came out the day after the GBA came out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the problem with the Wii is that the classic controller is gonna have to plug into the bottom of the normal controller.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, yeah, though from the looks of the virtual console I mean they showed screenshots of where when you play a game It'll show you a screen where it shows.
Speaker 1: here's what all the buttons are mapped to and you can probably change them.
Speaker 0: Yep The Wii controller is going to rumble.
Speaker 0: take that Sony.
Speaker 1: Yeah now think about that.
Speaker 1: Not only because it make noise not only is it perfectly tuned spatially to this console, but it rumbles.
Speaker 0: So when you get hit, you know, when you hit your sword against the other guy's sword you feel it go and it goes.
Speaker 0: Wow, all right The nunchuck thing.
Speaker 0: This is a rumor that was confirmed.
Speaker 0: We'll have.
Speaker 0: this will basically be equivalent to the PlayStation 3 controller.
Speaker 0: It can't tell where you're aiming it, but it can tell when you tilt it and move it around.
Speaker 0: That's good for a lot of video games.
Speaker 0: I imagine using it to dodge or throw you offhand weapons.
Speaker 0: Yeah Um Then we will have the Opera web browser eventually just like the DS.
Speaker 0: Well real soon.
Speaker 1: Yes I'm still.
Speaker 1: I really want it for the DS like I am.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I need it on the Wii.
Speaker 0: I have a computer plugged into my TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I guess people don't have a computer plugged into their TV.
Speaker 0: This will be useful.
Speaker 1: Most people don't.
Speaker 0: I mean We're really the minority Yeah, and I guess it'll be really easy to use because you can just aim the Wii controller at the links and click on them.
Speaker 0: It also I think will be cool because you'll visit the Nintendo website and such with your Nintendo product.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they could make some hookups in that department, you know?
Speaker 0: Maybe some sort of web integration sort of like Microsoft has with the Xbox 360.
Speaker 0: Here's one that people are seem to be confused about and I'm gonna try to shed as much light as I can as possible.
Speaker 0: We connect 24. the Wii is never gonna be turned off.
Speaker 0: basically You're always gonna have it on.
Speaker 0: it'll always be connected to the internet and powered on.
Speaker 0: even when you turn it off It'll be a little bit on.
Speaker 1: now I know.
Speaker 1: when the PlayStation 2 came out People had a lot of trouble with the fact that once you plugged it in and turn on that switch in the back It was always on with the you basically just suspended it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, red light green light, but people didn't understand that and they would always like turn their ps2 off hard Which wasn't good for it?
Speaker 0: No, not good at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though Nintendo is doing a lot more than just leaving it in suspend mode.
Speaker 0: Yes, not only will leaving it in suspend mode allow you to turn it on quicker So boot time will be almost, you know, even less exist and not that there was boot time on GameCube or anything.
Speaker 1: It'll be doing stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the kind of stuff they talked about is games can get patched and updated and new things will be Unlocked without you having to wait for them because they'll just happen when you're not using the Wii or using the Wii's network connection.
Speaker 1: Yeah, say you're online and Nintendo decides.
Speaker 1: All right, because it's uh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: pick a holiday Hanukkah Hanukkah Harry.
Speaker 1: They're gonna.
Speaker 1: they're gonna add a Hanukkah Harry thing to Smash Brothers for anyone who has it and they just do it on Hanukkah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they do it the night before Hanukkah.
Speaker 0: when you're not playing your Wii Still on and killing the little kids Hanukkah Harry sneaks in.
Speaker 0: that's it.
Speaker 1: Whatever he does.
Speaker 0: the example they gave was for Animal Crossing that you would have your Animal Crossing Village I guess would always be sort of on a little bit.
Speaker 0: So if someone sent you some Animal Crossing messages while you weren't playing Animal Crossing They would just come in because the Wii is always on.
Speaker 0: so they'd be downloaded whenever and then the next time you play Animal Crossing There they would be.
Speaker 0: look at that.
Speaker 1: That's huge, I mean I'm not a fan of those games so much anymore.
Speaker 1: Not not so much because I don't think they're cool because I don't have time for that crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't have time for Animal Crossing though I think I might play it once cuz I'm a little bit interested in some of the stuff.
Speaker 0: I don't know about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are the kind of games that I used to play religiously when I was a kid But now I just I can't do it.
Speaker 0: I can't deal with it.
Speaker 1: I can't even deal with like Sim City 2000 anymore.
Speaker 1: It just takes too long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just cheat but I think this is huge.
Speaker 1: just that the Animal Crossing people and the people who like these games Are a big segment of the market.
Speaker 0: now Animal Crossing sold crazy crazy in Japan.
Speaker 0: Animal Crossing DS sold crazy in Japan Crazy crazy and it sold really well in the u.s.
Speaker 1: To the fact that people could wirelessly interact.
Speaker 1: their cities was like this crazy thing for people.
Speaker 0: Now with the Wii and the your city is always there and it says on the Nintendo website Something we already knew is that the Wii can connect to the DS.
Speaker 0: now They never.
Speaker 0: they haven't given example of anyone doing this yet, but they did say that it's technologically possible.
Speaker 0: so you can just wait for Animal Crossing DS plus Animal Crossing.
Speaker 0: we kind of action going on.
Speaker 1: or you know The ultimate uber extension of Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles where you have a DS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's your TV all wireless and all online with other people.
Speaker 0: They'll make some cable that goes from the DS to the bottom of the Wii controller.
Speaker 0: Okay So that's pretty much the story with the Wii.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's everyone seems to like it.
Speaker 1: the games.
Speaker 1: They've demoed the games.
Speaker 1: They've got their people are raving about.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about all the games for the Wii.
Speaker 1: All right, they've got this sports game.
Speaker 0: Now my opinion of this sports game is it's it's called Wii Sports.
Speaker 0: It's got tennis golf and baseball.
Speaker 1: I think it's a great idea to have them bundled like this.
Speaker 1: It's very much the see what the we can do.
Speaker 1: game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's sort of like how you have solitaire that originally came with Microsoft Windows because Everyone had been using DOS and no one knows how to use a mouse.
Speaker 0: So they put out solitaire.
Speaker 0: that came with Windows Which you would no doubt want to try right away because it's a game and you would learn how to use the mouse by playing Solitaire.
Speaker 0: Wii Sports is the same thing.
Speaker 0: you learn how to use the wiimote by playing Wii Sports plus.
Speaker 1: it looks fun Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I really think though they that they should bundle Wii Sports with the Wii.
Speaker 0: It should be a free game that comes with the system.
Speaker 0: I mean, this isn't something people are gonna pay 50 bucks for maybe 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could see if they don't bundle it selling it for like 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: But think about it every time Nintendo has released a new peripheral that no one knew how to use.
Speaker 0: the zapper They put out duck hunt the super scope.
Speaker 0: They came with a super scope 6.
Speaker 1: Yep, the power came with Mario Paint.
Speaker 0: the mouse came with Mario Paint.
Speaker 0: the power pad came with track and field.
Speaker 0: now This is a new peripheral that's coming with a system.
Speaker 0: So it's a little bit different than a peripheral coming out on its own.
Speaker 0: But the wiimote should come with Wii Sports to teach you how to use the wiimote plus.
Speaker 1: think about what that would do in the market.
Speaker 1: It's been a long time since consoles came with games.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Well, what usually happens nowadays is the original console comes without a game and then later on they release bundle packs Like now if you buy a GameCube, I think it comes with Metroid Prime or something.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are different ones you can get like you can get the Pokemon GameCube that comes with Pokemon XD or whatever It's called.
Speaker 1: I just remember when I got my NES and it came with Mario Brothers Duck hunt.
Speaker 0: mine came with Mario Duck hunt and the red zapper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, red zapper.
Speaker 0: Yeah red zapper.
Speaker 0: All right There's one called project hammer and it's actually made by Nintendo and this game.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to say about this game.
Speaker 1: Um All I get things with a hammer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you basically someone said hey, you know, it'd be really awesome.
Speaker 0: If you see you could swing a hammer around.
Speaker 0: everyone wants to just run around smashing stuff.
Speaker 0: Let's make a game where all you do is run around smashing shit with a hammer for some reason.
Speaker 1: I keep picturing communist Mario I guess.
Speaker 0: yeah big-ass hammer.
Speaker 0: I think that's what this game is.
Speaker 0: There was one game.
Speaker 0: I think actually this game.
Speaker 0: They didn't show actual footage of.
Speaker 0: I guess I was wrong before.
Speaker 0: This is one game where all they showed were pre-rendered FMV's which it was something something disaster Which looked like every disaster movie ever.
Speaker 0: it rolled into one.
Speaker 0: I don't know how the game works.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about it.
Speaker 0: I think you manage disaster recovery teams or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't really look into that one Super Mario Galaxy.
Speaker 1: All right, they said.
Speaker 1: they've said more than once.
Speaker 1: It's not going to be a launch game.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's probably gonna come out soon after though It'd be sort of like how Super Mario Brothers wasn't a launch game for the NES.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most people don't really remember shine wasn't a launch game for the GameCube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the launch game for the GameCube was Luigi's Mansion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is alright, but it wasn't long enough at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was definitely more a tech demo than a game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep But yeah, Super Mario Galaxy looks like a really fun awesome Mario game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean just watching the scenes from playing the game.
Speaker 1: It just looks badass.
Speaker 0: It looks like they took the good parts of Super Mario Sunshine and left out the bad parts and put them in this game.
Speaker 1: You know because the only part I liked about Mario Sunshine really were those QB.
Speaker 1: but you know you go you go into the tube or the whatever to the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah secret of the the blankety blank.
Speaker 1: Yeah We have to run through.
Speaker 0: there's like a rotating cube and then a bunch of Platforms moving around the part where you didn't have your little water pack and it was all for me.
Speaker 1: I didn't like that water pack.
Speaker 0: No, so this Super Mario Galaxy looks like it's gonna be The you know cool part of Mario Sunshine with using the wiimote, which is plus plus.
Speaker 0: We'll see how it actually turns out.
Speaker 0: All you've seen are some, you know in-game footages, but at least there weren't bull shots.
Speaker 1: It looks like it'll be real intuitive to play.
Speaker 0: All right next up the ultimate party game not Mario party.
Speaker 0: WarioWare smooth moves now.
Speaker 1: way back when WarioWare came out for the Gameboy I thought that looks dumb.
Speaker 0: I didn't think it looks dumb.
Speaker 0: I said that I said that looks interesting.
Speaker 0: It's worth about 10 bucks because a bunch of really really tiny games.
Speaker 1: Once they made the GameCube multiplayer one, that was crazy.
Speaker 1: That was better than Mario Party.
Speaker 0: Yeah, WarioWare on its own isn't so fun.
Speaker 0: It's just something to sort of pass the time.
Speaker 0: Busy work as much as brain games is or any of those other ones.
Speaker 0: but WarioWare Multiplayer all of a sudden is an amazing thing.
Speaker 1: I mean all the.
Speaker 1: we have all these memories of going to the shore in Wildwood and sitting around in the beach house Just playing WarioWare long into the night.
Speaker 0: It's really no better party game than WarioWare.
Speaker 0: So WarioWare with a Wii controller that has you hula dancing and lassoing and jumping and lifting.
Speaker 0: So now instead of four people sitting around with GameCube or Gameboy's Controllers sitting in front of the TV pushing buttons going Oh Wario Which is a lot of fun now people are gonna be dancing around the room Jumping and swinging and all kinds of craziness that I can only imagine.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be fantastic All right.
Speaker 0: Here's one game that sort of surprised me excite truck.
Speaker 1: It looks fun Apparently.
Speaker 0: when I first saw it I said, oh there's some random truck game.
Speaker 0: then Reggie said it was excite truck and I was like Hahaha, it's a Nintendo game.
Speaker 0: It's you control it with the Wiimote and you tilt the Wiimote to steer the truck and there's a boost button and whatnot.
Speaker 1: That's one genre that Nintendo's been lacking for a long time semi realistic or non Mario Kart racing games.
Speaker 0: That's really the reason I want a 360 or a ps3.
Speaker 0: probably a 360 or maybe ps2 is to get the Gran Turismo and the forces and the real racing games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the Nintendo doesn't have them.
Speaker 1: I mean f-zero was fun and it is a racing game, but it's not that kind of racing game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a different kind of racing game that you also need, you know I think burnout is the competitor for f-zero if I'm correct.
Speaker 0: But anyway, this is the another kind of racing game, which is sort of the off-road you know high jump in freewheeling racing game and There really wasn't one of these that was ever any good in my opinion and this one Actually a lot of people at e3 say this is the most fun Wii game they played.
Speaker 0: So now my hopes are kind of up on this one where previously they were lukewarm.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now Red Steel.
Speaker 0: Oh, you wanna talk about Red Steel?
Speaker 1: I wanna talk about Red Steel.
Speaker 0: Red Steel is the game that everyone wants to play.
Speaker 0: It has the longest line at e3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean they showed original screenshots.
Speaker 1: they talked about the concept and I thought all right, that looks cool.
Speaker 1: Now that I've seen more and more of the gameplay this game looks like it's gonna be bad ass.
Speaker 0: It's basically an FPS where you use the wiimote to control the gun and/or the sword sword.
Speaker 0: So our sword, yeah Link's gonna have the sword too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this the game looks like.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of fighting But there's also a lot of like plot.
Speaker 1: figuring things out They said they guess a lot of people have likened it to half-life in terms of the plot is integrated into the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't see that so much.
Speaker 1: I saw that cuz.
Speaker 1: apparently one of the big parts of the game is if you'll be fighting like a boss and you have to Choose it like say you beat him in the sword fight and he's knocked his sword away Do you kill him or spare him?
Speaker 1: and then the consequences?
Speaker 0: that didn't seem.
Speaker 1: when I saw it cuz I watch said specifically that is One of the scenarios in the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw the scenario in the game and it didn't look to me Like there were any plot consequences.
Speaker 0: It was just.
Speaker 0: you didn't choose to do either way.
Speaker 0: You know you the guy shot the guards and then the boss coward.
Speaker 0: Which is it?
Speaker 0: it's less.
Speaker 0: it seemed to me like it was less a thing about plot.
Speaker 0: I didn't see plot at all.
Speaker 0: it seemed to me more of the bad guys in the game act like real people as much as they can.
Speaker 0: a Big mafia boss if you shoot his guards doesn't keep trying to kill you Like in so many games time cop, etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 0: The mafia boss goes.
Speaker 0: Oh shit This guy just hosed my guards and he carries behind the desk.
Speaker 0: That's what it's about.
Speaker 1: But I've seen.
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of comments from people who played it who said that it looks like it's gonna be like Half-Life.
Speaker 1: Many people have said those words.
Speaker 0: All right, we'll see I haven't seen.
Speaker 1: I want to play this game because I don't.
Speaker 1: I want.
Speaker 1: I want to see.
Speaker 1: I want to see exactly what it is.
Speaker 0: I think people just want it because it.
Speaker 0: you know it's a violent FPS tight game and there aren't any other games in the same genre taking advantage of the wiimote in the same way at This time that we know about.
Speaker 0: well, we'll see, you know, I'm sure that later FPS runaround killing guy games will be much better than Red Steel anyway.
Speaker 0: Metroid Prime 3 Corruption.
Speaker 0: Metroid Prime 1 was awesome.
Speaker 0: Metroid Prime 2 was more of the same which is awesome, but it wasn't more awesome.
Speaker 0: Metroid Prime 3 I'm pretty sure will be more awesome.
Speaker 0: Hooray, I'll buy every Metroid game no matter what it is pretty much except for Metroid Prime pinball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was about to say you didn't buy the pinball game.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna buy the pinball game Five bucks.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I buy it for five bucks.
Speaker 1: There aren't many games I wouldn't buy for five bucks that are made by Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Metroid Prime 3 is gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: FFCC we Not so much info on this one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's going to exist.
Speaker 1: Of course, it's also supposed to exist for the DS.
Speaker 0: Yep, I hope there's some sort of tie together.
Speaker 1: I really hope I would assume there will be.
Speaker 0: There's got to be.
Speaker 1: I mean they have.
Speaker 1: they've been very and in general Nintendo seems very forward-thinking about their tie togethers and they'll have tie togethers between games that were released fairly far apart.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but none.
Speaker 0: No one is still be in the old Sonic and Knuckles tie together.
Speaker 0: No one.
Speaker 0: Resident Evil Wii.
Speaker 1: I Lot of people have said that that looks bad.
Speaker 0: Well a lot of you say the words badass.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing is.
Speaker 0: as far as I know Resident Evil 4 people say was awesome.
Speaker 0: Every Resident Evil is out for the GameCube.
Speaker 0: every single Resident Evil ever is available on the GameCube.
Speaker 0: Resident Evil 5 is supposedly gonna be a ps3 exclusive.
Speaker 0: I heard.
Speaker 0: But this I've seen it announced for the ps3 and I haven't seen it announced for the Wii or the GameCube.
Speaker 0: so The question is is Resident Evil Wii Resident Evil 5 with Wii commands or is it a different Resident Evil with Wii command?
Speaker 1: I really think it's gonna be a different Resident Evil.
Speaker 0: I think it is.
Speaker 1: It's a good move for the people who make Resident Evil because then I'll just sell more games.
Speaker 0: Yep I Guess it's gonna be really cool.
Speaker 0: You know, you sneak around the house instead of you know Just the old-school way and then you shoot the zombies and zombies jump out.
Speaker 0: and now when you're scared You know if you get scared in a Resident Evil game you go Ah, but you don't you know.
Speaker 0: in your ah shrieking this jiggle the controller and lose your aim But with a wiimote in your hands if you get surprised you might drop that thing on the floor or something.
Speaker 0: Oh my god It's gonna get really good.
Speaker 0: Okay, two more Wii games left.
Speaker 0: Trauma Center we aka trauma center.
Speaker 0: Second opinion.
Speaker 0: I think it was called.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's a really clever title really clever name.
Speaker 0: The first game for the DS was good.
Speaker 0: It had some problems meaning it was too hard.
Speaker 1: It was Nintendo hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if I ever beat that one and I decide I want more of that.
Speaker 0: I'll get the Wii one and the last one The one that I'm looking forward to probably more than any of the others duck hunt Wii.
Speaker 1: Yep Now I've heard rumors that there's no dog in it.
Speaker 0: No, that's.
Speaker 0: I watched a video of it and the video which seemed to be a prototype of duck hunt We and not a complete duck hunt.
Speaker 0: We had no dog.
Speaker 1: There'd better be a goddamn dog.
Speaker 0: now Here's the thing about duck hunt.
Speaker 0: We.
Speaker 0: that kind of makes me go in if I'm playing duck hunt we I Really need to have a gun with sights on it.
Speaker 0: now at the Nintendo booth.
Speaker 0: There is this sort of display holster.
Speaker 0: They're showing where you insert the Wii controller into it and it gives it a trigger And you hold it like a gun.
Speaker 0: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because a lot of people speculated that they'd make something like that and sure enough they did.
Speaker 0: sure enough They did.
Speaker 0: who knows that?
Speaker 0: that'll be the final thing that's available But whatever I'm sure they'll test it.
Speaker 0: a lot thing is the video of duck hunt.
Speaker 0: We shows two ducks or a bunch of ducks and targets and clays flying around and two people are trying to shoot them at the Same time which is way cool because now you have competitive duck hunt.
Speaker 0: the thing is You see these crosshairs floating around the screen Now just watching the screen.
Speaker 0: I couldn't really see myself playing duck hunt that way.
Speaker 0: That's really hard to Use a crosshair to kill the ducks.
Speaker 0: I really need to have a sight on the Wii controller.
Speaker 1: crosshairs and games like that kind of screw me up.
Speaker 0: They screw me up big time.
Speaker 0: They might.
Speaker 0: you know other people might be okay with it.
Speaker 0: I might be able to get used to it but if I'm playing a gun game I need to have a sight on the gun and I need to aim at The screen though.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: I mean one if it's a prototype if it changes, or if that's an option.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just don't tell.
Speaker 0: I Don't think the Wii sensor can figure out your screen and if you're aiming exactly at the duck.
Speaker 0: So I don't think a sight would actually work on the device.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 1: yeah, we'll have to see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure it'll be okay.
Speaker 0: I'll play it in a store before I buy it.
Speaker 1: now of course there Was the game they announced after there, oh, yeah, we should probably talk about that.
Speaker 0: you mean the game they announced today Last night.
Speaker 0: yeah the game that I went well originally At the last eat.
Speaker 0: no the Tokyo game fair.
Speaker 0: I don't remember when they said that Smash Brothers we or Revolution would be a launch title that would be playable online.
Speaker 0: at the Nintendo press conference the other day They didn't say a goddamn thing about Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: not a word.
Speaker 0: when it was over I said where the fuck's the Smash Brothers?
Speaker 0: you promised you promise breakers.
Speaker 0: you and Hey didn't break their promise.
Speaker 0: Smash Brothers brawl was shown.
Speaker 0: well videos of it.
Speaker 0: well Actually, these are pre renders with very little gameplay, but it did show some gameplay.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: We're shown Yesterday.
Speaker 1: it looks like they didn't screw it up at all.
Speaker 1: looks like the same gameplay.
Speaker 0: It looks like awesome Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: and of course the key to any Smash Brothers title is the new characters.
Speaker 1: all right They won.
Speaker 1: not only there are a bunch of new characters.
Speaker 1: not only is it possible There will be more characters in addition to the ones they just no no not possible.
Speaker 0: guaranteed to be more characters.
Speaker 1: All right all right all right fine.
Speaker 1: You know what the the Smash Brothers, dude was talking like.
Speaker 1: yeah We've got a lot of ideas like they asked him in an interview.
Speaker 1: all right if there was one character You would like you would have added to this game.
Speaker 1: Who would it be?
Speaker 1: he was like.
Speaker 1: we're still adding characters.
Speaker 1: Yeah We would add we'd add him.
Speaker 0: there is a poll going on in Japan Asking the Japanese people what characters to add and people think the poll is gonna come over here next.
Speaker 1: all right if There are so many characters the thing is they got the character.
Speaker 1: I wanted the most okay.
Speaker 0: Let's start with Meta Knight.
Speaker 1: Meta Knight is awesome.
Speaker 0: If you don't know who Meta Knight is you've never played Kirby.
Speaker 0: Meta Knight is basically this little guy Who is the same shape of Kirby, but he's a knight like with a sword And I don't think he has a shield, but he has a mask and he's really badass.
Speaker 0: So that's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: that guy yes Pitts Pitt from Kid Icarus a game that is mostly forgotten to Nintendo fans.
Speaker 0: No, this is a game that is very remembered among Nintendo fans but has been neglected just as Metroid was for a while just as Earthbound was and it seems that Nintendo has this trend of a game is long lost and forgotten by Seemingly long lost and forgotten by Nintendo.
Speaker 0: the fans are still desperate for more of this game.
Speaker 0: They put the character in Smash Brothers, then they released the actual games.
Speaker 0: They put Roy and Marth in Smash Brothers, and they came up with Fire Emblem.
Speaker 0: I would put Samus in Smash Brothers the camel of Metroid Prime.
Speaker 1: I would bet money.
Speaker 1: There's going to be a new Kid Icarus game on the Wii.
Speaker 0: There's got to be a Kid Icarus game on the Wii where you use the Wiimote to shoot arrows.
Speaker 1: That's gonna be so awesome.
Speaker 0: It's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I can guarantee it.
Speaker 1: Kid Icarus is one of my favorite old games even though I'm not gonna pretend Kid Icarus was hard as fuck.
Speaker 1: It was harder than holy crap.
Speaker 0: is that game hard?
Speaker 1: I never ever beat it legitimately from start to finish.
Speaker 0: It was just barely beat the first couple levels.
Speaker 1: legitimately I can get to level 2 - 4. whoa.
Speaker 0: We should play it and we should good at it.
Speaker 1: We should.
Speaker 1: I've tried to get good at it.
Speaker 1: You can't with those freaking gravis game pads.
Speaker 1: We have.
Speaker 0: we'll go get some Xbox controllers.
Speaker 1: Yeah We're gonna buy an Xbox controller to play an emulation of an NES game.
Speaker 0: I find that we'll get an Xbox 360 also.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll be able to play Kid Icarus in the virtual console on our Wii.
Speaker 1: You know what I guarantee we will all right.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, oh, yeah, I Got one thing to say about this because actually Scott when there was a quiz on sprites a while ago He did not recognize a character who was from Kid Icarus, which I thought was a travesty.
Speaker 1: I note that if Pitt is in Super Smash Brothers, I Guarantee I guarantee there is going to be an eggplant wizard somewhere in Super Smash Brothers doing something bad.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: there is going to be some sort of someone gets turned into an egg.
Speaker 0: Maybe there'll be an eggplant item.
Speaker 1: That would be awesome.
Speaker 0: All right Samus without her suit on is now a character in Smash Brothers brawl.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's uh, it's hot real hot.
Speaker 0: I think that might be my new favorite Character to use because they used to use Samus.
Speaker 1: now you Samus without a suit plus Samus without a suit the way that I mean.
Speaker 1: they showed us straight up what she looks like this time And this is the cloak like the best representation of.
Speaker 0: we always knew what she looked like since the first Metroid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that was such a pixely.
Speaker 1: All right, it's a barely recognizable.
Speaker 0: So you play Metroid 2 and you see what she looks like and you play Metroid Super Metroid and you see the same.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the same but now it's good.
Speaker 1: It's really good.
Speaker 0: And then we saw in every other Metroid game what she looks like.
Speaker 0: There's no mystery about it.
Speaker 1: I never saw any of those Metro.
Speaker 1: I never played any of those.
Speaker 0: Well, then you suck.
Speaker 1: I actually don't like Metroid games.
Speaker 0: every single Metroid game shows you what she looks like.
Speaker 0: in some way I beat much like maybe Metroid pinball.
Speaker 0: I don't even know because I haven't played the only one I've seen of hers.
Speaker 1: I saw her in Metroid 1 and That's it.
Speaker 1: I never really played any other Metroid until I got the DS one.
Speaker 0: Well, she's all over the place.
Speaker 1: I've been playing on zero mission.
Speaker 1: That's about it.
Speaker 1: Yep, which is the same as Metroid 1 plus a little bit She had some kind of lightsaber II sword thing that looked cool in the in the FMV.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know what that's about.
Speaker 0: Maybe it'll be in Metroid Prime 3.
Speaker 0: Yeah, gotta throw a sword into every game.
Speaker 0: now that we have We mote gotta put a sword in every game.
Speaker 0: People love swinging sword.
Speaker 1: at some point is gonna be Luke and Darth Vader fighting and it's gonna be awesome At some point.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'll be Darth Vader.
Speaker 1: I'll be Darth Vader.
Speaker 1: Screw you me Darth Vader versus Darth Vader.
Speaker 0: I'll have to use my nunchuck to give you the you know neck grip of death.
Speaker 0: All right, so then Wario Wario it might be hard to resist using Wario.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because not only do they show him a farting in the video.
Speaker 1: Not only did Scott just fart in my room But in the interview with the Smash Brothers guy They asked the question so is Wario gonna have his fart power?
Speaker 1: and the answer I believe was of course Somebody asked yeah, where is he?
Speaker 0: when I have a lot of Wario games and I'm a big Wario fan When does Wario fart?
Speaker 1: He farts a lot in.
Speaker 1: Wario were touched.
Speaker 1: I know that And I think in some of these story things in the GameCube one it shows him farting.
Speaker 0: Oh, I never played that GameCube one.
Speaker 0: I heard it was actually kind of bad.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I don't know.
Speaker 0: I got to go play it and find out.
Speaker 0: It's probably really cheap now, but you'll get it cuz.
Speaker 1: they also asked in the interview Does Samus suitless Samus have any fart power?
Speaker 1: and then everyone laughed?
Speaker 0: Okay, I think that's it for the Wii, um now there's one more character.
Speaker 1: now the video.
Speaker 0: right the video.
Speaker 1: They showed and I have a sad anecdote from my work about this.
Speaker 1: But they showed the video of all these characters and then it ended but the lights didn't come on.
Speaker 1: And then it showed Some Metal Gear action of like Solid Snake talking to someone on the radio as Solid Snake is wanted And then it shows Solid Snake in his box in Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: And yes, he's a character in Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, Solid Snake.
Speaker 1: apparently this isn't a matter they had people asked a lot like so did you ask Kojima or how did this happen?
Speaker 1: and they were like.
Speaker 1: Kojima begged us to have him in the first one for the GameCube.
Speaker 1: It was just too late So we promised we'd put it in the next one and now we did.
Speaker 1: oh my god Like.
Speaker 1: they wanted Solid Snake in it and Kojima wanted Solid Snake in it.
Speaker 1: no one involved did not want Solid Snake in this game and The best part is that at work There's this one guy at work whose son is really interested.
Speaker 0: who's Solid Snake.
Speaker 0: I said, why is that guy in a box?
Speaker 1: I said hit Solid Snake and Meta Knight are the new characters of Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: and he said who?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I said pit from Kid Icarus.
Speaker 1: He said what I said, you probably don't know who Meta Knight is.
Speaker 1: He said no, and then I said Solid Snake, you know Metal Gear Solid.
Speaker 1: and he said, oh you mean snake Solid Snake.
Speaker 1: these newfangled kids have no I they don't recognize him as Solid Snake because in the games The voice acting.
Speaker 1: they just call him snake.
Speaker 1: Usually they don't call him Solid Snake every time.
Speaker 1: So when I said Solid Snake had no idea who was the other guy Super Joe?
Speaker 0: No, who's the guy the other gray Fox?
Speaker 1: No boss.
Speaker 0: There's a third.
Speaker 0: It was a fourth guy from which game?
Speaker 0: Metal Gear 1 Metal Gear 1.
Speaker 1: there's a whole bunch of guys.
Speaker 0: There's another guy with a funny name.
Speaker 0: I forget his name.
Speaker 0: They all have funny names I know But there's one in particular that I like.
Speaker 1: I forget the ocelot guy.
Speaker 0: No, he's not in solid one.
Speaker 0: He's in solid one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not regular machine gun.
Speaker 1: What's his name Billy?
Speaker 0: I think no forget it.
Speaker 1: Yeah big boss I didn't like so much.
Speaker 0: No big boss.
Speaker 0: No good.
Speaker 0: He was a bastard.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: One last thing about the Wii.
Speaker 0: I just saw a video online Where a guy took a camera and went from the beginning to the end of the line To for all the people waiting to use a Wii.
Speaker 1: we have two things to say about this video.
Speaker 0: number one The line was insanely long.
Speaker 1: The video is over two minutes long and it moves and kind of fast-forward walking down the line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's a long line.
Speaker 0: See it for yourself.
Speaker 0: Just search go on YouTube and search for a Wii line.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll put it on the forum.
Speaker 1: number two the sheer number of DS's seen in the line is staggering.
Speaker 0: there are probably more DS's in the line.
Speaker 0: then there were wheeze.
Speaker 0: They were waiting to play.
Speaker 1: there are probably more DS's in line than there are people at every other booth at e3.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think so at any given at any booth.
Speaker 1: I Could make a semantic argument at any little booth.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I didn't see a single PSP in a line.
Speaker 1: Of course, it was hard to tell for sure.
Speaker 1: It was hard.
Speaker 1: PSPs are all black and stealthy.
Speaker 1: We might not have seen it.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: There could have been PSPs in the line that we're hiding.
Speaker 1: However, it's weird.
Speaker 1: You can you let's think you can tell the DS people because there's always.
Speaker 0: you didn't even need to know they had DS's because you see six guys standing in a circle facing each other with their shoulders hunched Shoulders up and their hands up near their torsos and you know They all have DS's and they're playing Mario Kart slash Tetris slash something.
Speaker 1: Yep, and we paused.
Speaker 1: it wants to check in.
Speaker 1: Yep, look the DS is all around.
Speaker 1: Yep, but seriously this line.
Speaker 0: No god.
Speaker 0: This line was long.
Speaker 1: I've stood in shorter lines to ride crazy new roller coasters at Cedar Point.
Speaker 0: to be perfectly honest No matter how much I want to use the Wii.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have waited in that line.
Speaker 0: I would have gone and with like a little binocular to get looks at all the games from far away and I wouldn't have actually gone to use a Wii.
Speaker 0: I might have gone to use some DS's and the Nintendo booth and Go look at the other things in the Nintendo booth.
Speaker 1: I would have been like that one guy who said I'm just gonna do everything else at e3.
Speaker 0: Yep Absolutely everything else.
Speaker 0: plus if I went to e3 The stuff that I would want to look at the most isn't the major stuff that you're gonna see on the internet.
Speaker 0: It's all that little stuff in the back alleys with all the independent developers that you'll never ever ever see coverage of anywhere All the secret stuff.
Speaker 1: That's why you're not gonna go see Paris Hilton talking about her new game her new cell phone game.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, let's talk about Microsoft.
Speaker 1: All right, they put out a surprisingly good show.
Speaker 0: yeah, I thought that Microsoft was going to just announce a bunch of new games like Halo 3 and shit and That would be that because their consoles already out and it's already done.
Speaker 0: First everyone expected they announced the HD DVD player.
Speaker 0: They didn't say how much it's gonna cost or anything But it's gonna be an HD DVD player that you can buy and plug into your Xbox 360 to watch HD DVDs.
Speaker 1: Yep, there's been speculation that'll be between a hundred and maybe two hundred dollars at most which is cheaper than an HD DVD player.
Speaker 0: But of course you have to add the price of a 360.
Speaker 1: the thing is that's still cheaper than an HD DVD player.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is if you already have a 360 from last year and the HD DVD player comes out holiday season this year If you're looking and you already have a 360, are you gonna buy a ps3?
Speaker 0: Are you gonna buy the HD DVD player?
Speaker 1: Wait a minute is the chance blu-ray will succeed and then you have to buy it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there is also a chance.
Speaker 0: maybe Microsoft will release new 360s that have HD DVD players built in instead which I think would be really smart of them to do like starting next year.
Speaker 0: Right, you know making the new premium bundle have the HD DVD player Because by then the price of HD DVD will come down a lot.
Speaker 0: then bring the old Premium down in price and then I would buy the old premium at that point because I don't need an HD DVD player.
Speaker 0: You know That's not something they said they would do.
Speaker 0: that's something I said they should do just now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway the the game the list of games that they came out with in addition to all the other stuff.
Speaker 1: It really is enough for us to at least for me to consider when the second gen of the Xbox 360.
Speaker 0: Well, one of those games was kind of bled.
Speaker 0: but we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about the rest of the system stuff first.
Speaker 0: All right There's gonna be a camera sort of like the eye toy.
Speaker 0: Now what's the use of that?
Speaker 0: Well, obviously they could potentially make eye toy like games.
Speaker 1: Obviously when I'm playing Halo there will be a picture of my penis on my guy.
Speaker 0: Obviously, no, it's a video.
Speaker 0: It's like a webcam.
Speaker 0: So as you're playing Halo people, you know, you push the button to talk.
Speaker 0: people can see you talking.
Speaker 1: We'll see how well that gets used.
Speaker 1: how many people are just gonna be naked or the cameras pointing at a penis, you know It's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: a Wireless headset now.
Speaker 0: right now the headset for the Xbox 360 I think is wired and it's kind of you know It's like a big headset.
Speaker 0: this thing looks more like one of the Bluetooth headsets for a cell phone.
Speaker 0: We're just goes on one ear and a little tiny microphone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's cool.
Speaker 1: It's not anything special or innovative in and of itself, but it's definitely the next step in terms of technology.
Speaker 0: It's a significant improvement to the current Xbox 360 headset and the headset is very key to the Xbox Live experience.
Speaker 1: Yes, I mean for whatever anyone has to say about Microsoft.
Speaker 1: Xbox Live is a very slick thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, very slick.
Speaker 1: I mean I Early on I remember, you know Microsoft is making a console.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was the same way and even penny arcade were like Microsoft is making a console.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: This thing is gigantic.
Speaker 0: Controllers are terrible.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: But really the Xbox Live is cool and it's pretty well done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like the in the original Xbox and currently there really aren't so many games I want to play besides the racing games for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but The way Xbox Live works it, you know It's sort of like the Nintendo Wi-Fi and that just having it there really adds a lot to the games.
Speaker 0: But it seemed to me like the ps3 Internet thing.
Speaker 0: might you know be similar but from what it looked like that was more of a push for Sony's content their movies and music and They did a lot more of that and a lot less of the gaming type stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Sony really hyped up the.
Speaker 1: you'll be able to download things to your Pia or your ps3 to watch.
Speaker 0: Yep Well Microsoft supposedly is gonna have downloadable HD movie type stuff too.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, my analysis is this SOE Sony online entertainment is Crap.
Speaker 0: Well Sony online entertainment is the company that does ever quest.
Speaker 1: that has nothing to do with the PlayStation Yeah, but they will have something to do possibly with the online functionality the ps3.
Speaker 0: No one said that.
Speaker 0: where you getting there from I'll find the link there.
Speaker 1: Someone was talking about the developers from them or something.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're making an MMO That'll be on the ps3 because all Sony online entertainment does is make MMOs Like Star Wars galaxies and ever quest and shit and they got to make an MMO for this thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe probably but I don't.
Speaker 0: no one said they have anything to do with the Sony internet ness.
Speaker 1: I think it was a comment on slashdot.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone doesn't know what they're talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: now here's the best thing about the Xbox 360 in Scott's opinion the best thing.
Speaker 0: remember how they were taught.
Speaker 0: I was talking about how all I really want is racing games.
Speaker 0: They got this official Xbox 360 wireless wheel coming it.
Speaker 0: It's cool It's a really really good racing wheel and most systems in the past have had racing wheels that you could buy.
Speaker 0: The problem is is that the racing wheels are almost always third-party the GameCube and PlayStation.
Speaker 0: I think those actually a logitech racing wheel.
Speaker 0: that was labeled the official racing wheel But it's still a third-party product The kind of useless and crap or not really well-tuned and not every game supports it properly.
Speaker 0: but Microsoft releasing an official racing wheel is gonna mean that the major racing games which are Forza and Project Gotham and some others are going to support this wheel properly now.
Speaker 1: This is big because I like I like realistic racing games.
Speaker 1: Forza is very realistic as it is.
Speaker 1: If they have a wheel that is calibrated to that game and the developers made the game with that wheel in mind.
Speaker 1: That's gold.
Speaker 1: It's gold Jerry.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing about the wheel.
Speaker 0: It's like a typical racing wheel you clamp it down to a table, but you don't need to Plug it in to your system or anything.
Speaker 0: It's wireless.
Speaker 1: Oh wireless.
Speaker 0: I think it might need a battery or two.
Speaker 1: It'll have to because it's I almost guarantee it'll have force feedback.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, here's the thing about the force feedback.
Speaker 0: All right It will rumble and whatnot with just the battery.
Speaker 0: and there are pedals too that are also wireless and I guess those need a battery As well if you wanted to have actual force feedback.
Speaker 0: Right now people are saying you need to plug it into a power outlet to get the force feedback to work.
Speaker 0: No, that's a minus But at least you don't have to plug it into the system Which means you can still sit all the way across the room as long as there's an outlet on your side of the room and At least that is optional.
Speaker 0: Yep, so if you can't find an outlet near you you can still drive.
Speaker 0: You just won't have your awesome force feed watch.
Speaker 1: your house doesn't have the holes.
Speaker 0: the holes Jerry.
Speaker 1: It's been Seinfeld day for us.
Speaker 1: We've just been making some of course.
Speaker 0: He made the same holes joke two or three times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we made it during the day all day holes jokes.
Speaker 0: So Scott is all about the Xbox 360 or the PlayStation 3 for racing games.
Speaker 0: The Xbox 360 looks to be the cheaper more realistic solution.
Speaker 0: and now it has a racing wheel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus plus plus for Scott now.
Speaker 1: There's also a lot of talk about this shadow run game.
Speaker 0: We're not getting to the shadow run game yet, why not cuz we're not done talking about this system.
Speaker 0: What else is there?
Speaker 1: I didn't see anything else that I didn't.
Speaker 1: You didn't look at other stuff cuz I didn't care about much beyond racing games and shadow run.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, there's gonna be this thing called live anywhere.
Speaker 0: where?
Speaker 0: Xbox live will not just be for the Xbox.
Speaker 0: It's actually Microsoft Live, I guess.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, Microsoft Live is that other thing?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: So what are they gonna call it?
Speaker 0: It's called live anywhere And what it's gonna do is basically integrate your live account across your phone and your Windows Vista computer and everything.
Speaker 0: And what they showed using this was that they were gonna do simultaneous releases of you know the same game on Vista and the Xbox at the same time
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: The things they talked about were people playing Halo 2 on the computer and on the Xbox competing against each other.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the end of people playing FPS is on the console because the PC people just kick their asses with the keyboard and a Mouse.
Speaker 0: well, they said.
Speaker 0: in fact, this is a quote from the Microsoft guy will settle What's better the keyboard mouse?
Speaker 0: Once and for all.
Speaker 0: and they showed a screen where you know as a list of guys Joining a game and some of them had PC icons and some of them at Xbox icons.
Speaker 0: hmm, it seems like Microsoft is really going to Integrate its.
Speaker 0: you know, the Xbox is pretty much going to be a Windows gaming machine and Vista is also going to be capable of being a Windows gaming.
Speaker 1: Well from a business perspective, they really have to do something like this because despite the fact that the Xbox does really well It does lose some money.
Speaker 1: I mean if they sunk a lot of money in R&D into the Xbox Franchise the one the first one at least yeah, and the second one will probably make money because now it's the second gen is popular But they're still subsidizing the hardware most likely.
Speaker 1: Well, everyone's subsidize the hardware Yeah, but they may be.
Speaker 1: I mean there's speculation that they make the money back games.
Speaker 0: It's a razor blade deal.
Speaker 1: But as far as Vista There's a lot of talk that Vista isn't going to do so.
Speaker 1: well for a number I mean the corporations aren't really jumping over themselves to get this thing.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing PC games are kind of going Blair.
Speaker 0: All right, we've talked about this before.
Speaker 0: Yep People like me.
Speaker 0: Oh and a lot of other people are going to max and they're going to Linux because Windows is kind of Blair.
Speaker 0: But the only thing we really want Windows 4 is the games and so we keep Windows around for those games.
Speaker 0: Super hardcore gamer guys are always gonna do the super PC game thing with two video cards and crazy processors and Alienware machines Just because there's no way.
Speaker 1: Alienware you mean Dell machines.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Dell XPS machines Which is actually what Microsoft used or had on stage for their demos.
Speaker 0: Yeah What Was I saying?
Speaker 0: right because the PC will always have better graphics it'll always a better frame rate It'll always have all that stuff for all those games.
Speaker 0: and that's what this ultra hardcore guys do.
Speaker 0: I mean.
Speaker 0: who's the most famous gamer in the world?
Speaker 0: What's his name Thresh?
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: the fatality guy Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and what does he do?
Speaker 0: He plays PC games.
Speaker 0: He doesn't play Nintendo games or PlayStation games or Xbox games.
Speaker 0: plays PC games.
Speaker 1: To me the most famous gamer is I eat poo.
Speaker 1: Yeah I heard he got knocked off the top.
Speaker 1: Yeah, someone beat him.
Speaker 0: Oh, no but I mean look if you look around the world to consoles are really big in Japan in the US and Different consoles are big in different parts of the world.
Speaker 0: But console South Korea is pretty much PC game land.
Speaker 0: China PC game land.
Speaker 0: Europe mostly PC game land.
Speaker 1: South America Sega Genesis land.
Speaker 0: Yeah, China PC game land.
Speaker 0: PC games are big internationally and Microsoft is doing two things that are really helping this out People like us who really like PC games But don't have windows anymore and there aren't enough PC games to really justify us having a Windows PC that cost a hajillion dollars.
Speaker 0: The Xbox 360 is becoming the just Windows games machine now.
Speaker 1: This is part of the reason I'm really thinking about getting one as time goes on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not something I'll get right away.
Speaker 0: It's maybe something we'll get on the first price drop or two.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean if I get a Wii and rim gets into 360 Then it'll be fair deal unlike when I got a GameCube and he got a nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah thing is I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I would buy an Xbox unless we're in 50/50 because it's still a lot of money.
Speaker 1: I'm cheap.
Speaker 1: I'm a cheap bastard.
Speaker 1: You are real cheap But the point is my investment into the Wii is going to consist of me buying myself a controller Like I did for the GameCube.
Speaker 1: I have my controller and that's it.
Speaker 0: Mine's gonna be green.
Speaker 1: now Mine's gonna be green.
Speaker 0: Well, we're gonna get confused, aren't we?
Speaker 0: But the other thing I was talking about international ness.
Speaker 0: they're going to have Microsoft Live whatnot and Xboxes sold in South Africa Chile India Brazil Poland Hungary the Czech Republic and Slovakia.
Speaker 0: Those countries are Notorious for complaining about getting games way after everyone else and having a lot of gamers in them.
Speaker 1: They're mostly ignored by the entire gaming industry.
Speaker 0: Well, they're not ignored It's just they're delayed like Pete.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of gamers in South Africa.
Speaker 0: Like I've heard podcast.
Speaker 0: Well, they're always in gamers.
Speaker 1: They're not the target.
Speaker 1: They're a secondary.
Speaker 0: Just there aren't enough people there to have the stuff shipped as early as everyone else.
Speaker 0: So they get stuff months and months and months even after Europe gets them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Europe gets stuff late and overpriced as it is.
Speaker 0: So now Microsoft pretty much the only company who could do this is Because you know, you can get PC games to any.
Speaker 0: that's the thing about PC games.
Speaker 0: They get everywhere all at once.
Speaker 0: look at steam.
Speaker 0: Everyone gets half-life 2 at the same time It gets it in every language in every country.
Speaker 0: That's why you always end up fighting some Dutch guy and CS or some Swedish guy and they kick your ass.
Speaker 0: Microsoft is gonna get Xbox out to all those countries at the same time and some people might have Vista and they'll just play on their PC and some people have a 360 and play on their 360 if they're poor and that's gonna be big.
Speaker 0: You know your DS.
Speaker 0: it says play worldwide.
Speaker 0: that just means play against guys in Japan in Britain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Xbox Live is gonna really be worldwide play.
Speaker 0: It's you know PC gaming.
Speaker 0: I don't think we'll see a big resurgence But what it'll be is they'll be.
Speaker 0: the third platform will be Windows gaming as opposed to PC gaming and you'll be able to do your Windows gaming on a 360 or on a PC with Vista and I'll probably not do it on a PC with Vista because Vista is not gonna be good.
Speaker 0: Yeah for a lot of reasons that we talked about and a PC with Vista will be a lot more money than an Xbox Which is only going to go down in price from here on out now.
Speaker 1: It's interesting that Nintendo, you know Obvious what their strategies are and it looks very interesting and Microsoft is doing this sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Sony's not really doing anything new.
Speaker 1: They're just doing more of the same.
Speaker 0: Well, I think Sony's strategy is to you know, be what everyone else is all-in-one.
Speaker 0: They're like we're gonna be the Wii and the 360.
Speaker 0: We can do everything that everyone else does and beat them all because the problem is is they're doing there.
Speaker 0: It's basically a shitty Wii plus a shitty 360 Combined in.
Speaker 1: add a lot of horsepower power of shit power of obsolescence.
Speaker 0: Hahaha You know.
Speaker 1: and I got a rip on the ps3 one more time.
Speaker 1: God day it if you've seen pictures of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looked that someone described it as a Victorian era waffle iron.
Speaker 1: It's bigger than the Xbox.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's real big and real heavy.
Speaker 1: the original Xbox not the new one.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's huge It's it's weighs.
Speaker 0: I think what like twice as much as the original Xbox is a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it probably is comparable to the weight of my computer You know.
Speaker 0: and this isn't just it's a lot of this is our opinion that you know, you might think that a giant ps3 is great.
Speaker 0: But the general internet hum Note, there isn't a lot of people short of super PlayStation fanboys who are saying good things about Sony.
Speaker 0: Everyone is saying bad things about Sony.
Speaker 0: there hasn't been positive news about Sony in years.
Speaker 0: You remember the root kits and everything.
Speaker 1: It's just yeah, don't forget Sony infected their computers with their users their customers with viruses because they think they're criminals.
Speaker 0: Yeah So Sony is just.
Speaker 0: everyone loves to bash Sony and they're keep bashing them lately and they're going to continue to bash them the late.
Speaker 0: the general feeling of the game media is that Sony is acting arrogantly and they're relying on their name recognition to just carry their dominance over into the next generation and not actually Realizing they need to be better than everyone else.
Speaker 0: because and we'll see how it turns out now
Speaker 1: compare that to the buzz about Microsoft Which after the Xbox 360 was announced and then it was released and then it sold out the buzz disappeared and no one really talked About it, but now that e3 has come around again.
Speaker 1: The buzz is back and it's neutral to positive.
Speaker 1: There's very little negative buzz about Microsoft.
Speaker 0: Sony is really the only company that people love to bash Microsoft Especially Linux guys like us and we're not.
Speaker 0: yeah, what does that tell you?
Speaker 0: And of course the line to see the.
Speaker 0: we all can't deny this video of it.
Speaker 0: How can you deny?
Speaker 1: Yeah, five minutes versus six hours.
Speaker 0: There's something and the clapping at the Nintendo conference versus the Sony you can't deny there it is Black and white.
Speaker 0: if you deny this then you might as well believe that you know Very heavily autistic kids can talk to you and type to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not saying the ps3 is a bad platform.
Speaker 1: We're saying Sony is a bad company and they're doing stupid things.
Speaker 0: They're doing very stupid things and I predict they'll get their asses handed to them because the PSP is a cool piece And the press is saying very bad things about them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the mainstream press I mean investment types are saying the ps3 is so overpriced.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna buy it.
Speaker 0: Yep Alright, let's start talking about Xbox games.
Speaker 1: Alright shadowrun.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about shadowrun.
Speaker 0: Okay, talk about shadowrun Alright.
Speaker 1: there there were rumblings that I hadn't really heard until just now recently about Shadowrun game for the Xbox.
Speaker 0: Well, that was at their press conference.
Speaker 0: Yeah before the press conference someone saw something on it In the being prepared show floor.
Speaker 0: that said shadowrun.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then it exploded on the internet as shadowrun.
Speaker 1: That's all I know.
Speaker 1: and Then we found out and now a lot of fans of shadowrun have been complaining saying that they ruined shadowrun Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I like shed a little bit of my own light on that.
Speaker 1: for anyone who has never played shadowrun It is a role-playing game system like Dungeons & Dragons Forgotten Realms say or Dragon lance.
Speaker 1: It is a system coupled with a universe.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm The universe has a history that has come out from the base books Plus the source books plus the novels and all that stuff like every gaming world has yep.
Speaker 1: It is incredibly Convoluted difficult to follow full of a million things.
Speaker 1: It is cyberpunk futurism magic shamanism dragons Net hacking flying through cyberspace astral projections gods and shaman totems Politics everything everything everything everything all rolled into one, but it's mostly dark.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's very dark and dystopian.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's while it's everything It's not light and happy anyway.
Speaker 1: Really now people are complaining that the game that's going to be coming out for the Xbox Which they didn't actually tell us that much about it other than that.
Speaker 1: It's going to exist.
Speaker 1: They're changing the plotline the history of the shadowrun world a bit to make the game work.
Speaker 1: The details are unimportant because if you know if you care about shadowrun you already know and if you don't care you already don't care.
Speaker 1: But they're pushing some history events out and they're kind of changing the timeline and there's a giant uproar among the hardcore fans of shadowrun.
Speaker 0: Alright, well that's slightly different from what I was reading.
Speaker 0: What I was reading that people were upset that the game was not going to be in any way similar to the SNES game is Going to be a squad based combat game.
Speaker 1: Why would anyone complain about that?
Speaker 1: the SNES game was cool, but it was pretty terrible.
Speaker 0: all things considered People apparently wanted an RPG game and not a squad based combat game because apparently there is squad based combat games of the wazoo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true, too.
Speaker 0: People are saying at least the quotes that I saw in two places that this wasn't a slight changing of the shadowrun history.
Speaker 0: This was it's a fairly big change But it still are saying that they completely threw out everything shadowrun.
Speaker 0: and the only thing this has in common with shadowrun is The name.
Speaker 0: and why did they buy the license just for the name to sell the game if they're not gonna actually use any other Stuff?
Speaker 1: well the thing I don't think they threw everything out.
Speaker 1: It's that the type of game.
Speaker 1: It is doesn't really behoove.
Speaker 1: You don't care about a lot of the history of the game if you're making a game.
Speaker 1: That's more simply based on the combat.
Speaker 1: You don't care about?
Speaker 0: yeah, then why that people are saying why have the shadowrun?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying what people are saying.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I don't really care.
Speaker 0: one why have the shadowrun license for a game that doesn't need it?
Speaker 0: if you're not gonna use it You're just putting a name on that.
Speaker 0: try and sell it.
Speaker 1: I submit two things.
Speaker 1: one the name will sell To.
Speaker 1: the world that comes from has a lot of fodder from which to make a game.
Speaker 0: Yeah the thing that people are saying they're not using the fodder yet.
Speaker 1: three by the license.
Speaker 1: once then you know by use it Again.
Speaker 1: make more games about shadowrun.
Speaker 1: Maybe this game is very generic to test the waters of what do people think of shadowrun type games?
Speaker 0: But the thing is is that if you put it the label shadowrun on a game that Says you're trying to sell your you know a game is gonna sell to whatever people it's gonna sell to.
Speaker 0: normally Putting the shadowrun label on a game means you're going to.
Speaker 0: You're paying money to get that label in order to sell it to all the people who would buy anything with the name shadow.
Speaker 0: See now I don't think if you don't make a game that pleases those people.
Speaker 0: you're only going to piss them off.
Speaker 1: But the thing is there aren't that many shadowrun people.
Speaker 1: I love shadowrun, but I stopped only I didn't play it since high school.
Speaker 0: That's not what the internet seems to be happening all these shadowrun things.
Speaker 0: There are people coming out of the work everywhere commenting on this Oh, they are.
Speaker 0: but I mean if people didn't play shadowrun Oh, it would have been people play it.
Speaker 0: You know if people didn't know what shadowrun was people would say what the fuck is out of run.
Speaker 0: Why do I hear that?
Speaker 0: There's a shadow run.
Speaker 1: keep in mind that most of the people who came out really angrily are the heart are the dedicated fans of Shadowrun.
Speaker 1: people who aren't fans of shadowrun don't know much about it and don't care.
Speaker 0: It seems that they're.
Speaker 0: yeah, but why put the label on?
Speaker 0: if you put the label on it You're not going to get people who aren't fans of shadowrun to buy it.
Speaker 0: putting the label on it means We are going to pay money to sell this game to hardcore fans of shadowrun.
Speaker 0: If you make it in such a way the hardcore fans of shadowrun won't like it.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna buy it and you just spent money on a label you couldn't you could have avoided spending money on one.
Speaker 1: They probably got the license pretty cheap.
Speaker 0: Well, I think Microsoft actually owns the FASA corporation.
Speaker 1: Yeah Shadowrun doesn't make much money.
Speaker 1: our pen and paper games in general are not doing well.
Speaker 1: Dungeons & Dragons is far and away still the champion and shadowrun Really died for a long time after for a while after second ed came out.
Speaker 0: Yes It was vitalized for game died but apparently knowledge of the universe and interest in it is not dead.
Speaker 1: because Oh, it's not bad.
Speaker 0: There are articles everywhere that said they're gonna make a shadowrun game and if people didn't know what shadowrun was or care about it They would have said what the hell shadowrun.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I didn't.
Speaker 0: there's thousands of people going.
Speaker 0: Oh my god shadowrun.
Speaker 1: Whoo, what I'm saying is that a lot of people are.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of these people are like me.
Speaker 1: I played shadowrun a long time ago and I loved it and then it kind of died and I couldn't play it.
Speaker 1: But I still know about it and I like it and I've always wanted something to come back with it And now something's coming back with it.
Speaker 1: The name rekindles these things even though people don't play it so much now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the people who know the name.
Speaker 0: if they care about that name They know something about it.
Speaker 0: and being nerdy as only someone who knows about shadowrun is going to be nerdy They don't like it.
Speaker 0: when you mess with what it was if I release a game and I put the Star Wars name on it And it doesn't have lightsabers and x-wings and TIE fighters.
Speaker 1: You mean like Star Wars galaxies.
Speaker 0: People aren't gonna like that game Star Wars galaxies.
Speaker 1: They're gonna yell at me, which was just people dancing in the desert.
Speaker 0: exactly.
Speaker 1: See, I guess I'm a shadowrun fan But I don't really care much for the timeline because it's mostly kind of silly and convoluted.
Speaker 0: not saying it's not silly I'm just saying this is akin to someone buying the Star Wars label putting it on a game and then Taking out all the Star Wars stuff.
Speaker 0: it's like no one's gonna anyone.
Speaker 0: you're putting the Star Wars label means you're gonna try to sell it to Star Wars fans and If you don't have Star Wars stuff They're purposefully not going to buy it because of the type of people fans are I just.
Speaker 1: I think the game's gonna do fine And I'll bet this is only gonna be the first of a string of shadowrun games And I'll bet at least one of them will be an RPG at some point.
Speaker 0: Well judging by the you know internet talk about it It's a it's a mixed bag, we'll see until people actually get their hands on the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just have this feeling.
Speaker 1: this is a complete gut hunch that the game will do.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: This is a hunch like mr What's it from?
Speaker 1: Scotland Yard is hiding in the subway?
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 0: We'll see Halo 3 man.
Speaker 0: yeah If you do the halo rant we always do.
Speaker 0: or should we just sum it up really quickly?
Speaker 1: uh Real quick Halo is not innovative or new or good.
Speaker 1: It is doing things.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: that PCs did with FPS is almost a decade ago.
Speaker 0: Basically what happened in the history of FPS is is people grew up playing FPS and they played quake and everything.
Speaker 0: They were real FPS players.
Speaker 0: Then there was Goldeneye, which is the console FPS which is not much compared to the PC FPS But because it was on a console and as for player it didn't need to have everything the PC FPS has had.
Speaker 1: yep I mean compared to a PC game.
Speaker 1: It was piss-poor, but for a console FPS.
Speaker 0: It was great Yeah, and it's still one of the greatest console FPS is.
Speaker 0: so what happened was is You eventually got to counter-strike and the whole thing stagnated and kind of you know Stayed still for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it didn't die by far.
Speaker 1: counter-strike is still played by a lot of freaking people.
Speaker 0: It's one of the biggest games yep, but when halo came out It was like the resurgence of FPSing because there was finally an FPS that was accessible to a lot of people.
Speaker 0: the thing is People who played real FPS is like counter-strike and shit was like.
Speaker 0: most of them were like halo is crap, and I found this out Because most of the people I knew who played halo were either younger or people who weren't big into real FPS.
Speaker 0: And my brother who is the halo age yet He played counter-strike because he was my brother was like yeah, halo sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I remember playing halo, and it was just really really generic and kind of dumb.
Speaker 0: I mean tribes 2 is better than halo by a hajillion.
Speaker 1: tribes 2 is probably in my opinion the best FPS.
Speaker 0: I played the halo 1 PC demo.
Speaker 0: I remember and Even with the mouse and keyboard it was just this really easy walk around shoot guys game And it was kind of blah, and I know the multiplayer.
Speaker 0: you can have a lot of fun with vehicles and stuff.
Speaker 0: But unreal tournament, I like.
Speaker 0: I played unreal tournament 2007 demo and that was a lot more fun than halo multiplayer But still to halos credit it brought a lot of new people into the FPS genre.
Speaker 0: It's basically the easy FPS for wussies and real FPS players play something else and all the halo noobs play halo.
Speaker 1: Well the thing is people haven't really moved on in the FPS world and PCs because the best games are still counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're standing still.
Speaker 0: so it's like there's two tiers of FPS playing and halo is the lower tier.
Speaker 0: It's like the entry-level FPS.
Speaker 1: Now I wonder I mean it's hard to make a PC like FPS on a console mostly because you don't have a keyboard and mouse.
Speaker 1: You don't have the ability to change the game as easily over time with updates.
Speaker 0: You can't have really complex controls because there are only so many buttons, so you can't give people Jetpacks and a billion weapons and a bunch of sidearm grenades and all kinds of crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if anyone out there thinks halo is complex.
Speaker 1: I dare you I double dog dare you to play weapons factory or Mega-tf without a whole bunch of crazy scripts to run your freaking character for you while you're running around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you had.
Speaker 1: you would have like 20 keys bound to 20 esoteric weird Tribes - is complex enough tribes - had its own scripting language.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It was just the engine has a scripting language That's pretty much C++ because the way it's written Yeah, which was great compared to frickin half or not the half-life wasn't so bad.
Speaker 1: But quake - where you had to write in this stupid obtuse barely work scripting language that was laggy and buggy and crap Mm-hmm, but you needed to do it to play these games.
Speaker 1: There was no complex all right now.
Speaker 0: There was something mentioned.
Speaker 0: I think Great Grand Theft Auto.
Speaker 0: for now what happened was I'm sure everyone has seen on the internet the Xbox guy.
Speaker 0: what he did is he was like.
Speaker 0: you know he said something a lot.
Speaker 0: He was trying to make a joke and he said like girly man You have rubber duckies referring to Sony using a rubber duck and all their demos And he's like real.
Speaker 0: men get tattoos, and he shows he had a tattoo for Halo 2 and on his other arm He had a tattoo for Grand Theft Auto 4.
Speaker 0: I think someone else is doing a job of finding out what the tattoos are real or not.
Speaker 1: I saw on a report someone said that they are real.
Speaker 1: Wow But the report was.
Speaker 1: someone asked him if they were real and he said yes.
Speaker 1: Which may or may not be true tattoo?
Speaker 0: Professionals say the Grand Theft Auto one was a lot.
Speaker 0: the white color used in it was a lot brighter than any tattoo can be.
Speaker 0: So they speculated as to whether it was painted over to be brighter, or if it just wasn't real at all.
Speaker 0: Well it remains to be seen.
Speaker 1: we'll find out a year from now if you still got it now.
Speaker 0: Grand Theft Auto 4 they said sometime around the end in 2007. so it's a ways off.
Speaker 0: But what we know about it is we don't think it's gonna be exclusive to the Xbox 360. however It's going to come out for the Xbox 360 Before it comes out for anything else.
Speaker 0: it might come out for the PlayStation 3 and the PC on the same day as it comes Out for the 360, but it's guaranteed that when it comes out the day it comes out It'll be available on the 360 for sure.
Speaker 1: yeah This seems to be a new trend in exclusivity because you can't really Exclusive.
Speaker 1: games aren't really good for the people who make the games.
Speaker 0: They're good for the people who have the consoles so they have to usually pay you know the Developer to make the game exclusive to you.
Speaker 0: now what Microsoft is doing is They sort of made a compromise it seems with Rockstar because Rockstar doesn't want their game to be exclusive to the Xbox 360. unless the PlayStation 3 bombs then they don't care yeah, because that means less sales for them.
Speaker 0: So what it seems they've done is they made a deal with Rockstar where if you play on the 360 you're going to get some exclusive levels and things extra Through Xbox Live.
Speaker 0: of course.
Speaker 1: now as much as I don't always like that sort of thing It's definitely better than locking into one console.
Speaker 0: Yes better for gamers is better for gamers who want to play Grand Theft Auto 4.
Speaker 0: I don't want to play it.
Speaker 0: however What it's gonna Do is it's gonna do a Soul Calibur 2 effect.
Speaker 0: Soul Calibur 2 was in every system But the GameCube was the system to play it on because it had link.
Speaker 0: Grand Theft Auto 4 will be on all the you know the systems But the Xbox will be the system to play it on because it has these downloads.
Speaker 1: yep now I wouldn't be surprised long term if they made some sort of special Grand Theft for the Wii with the Wii controller.
Speaker 1: They could do something.
Speaker 0: they could drive eyes.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Rockstar seems to be the kind of company that won't do it unless a lot of people buy Wiis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which I think a lot of people will yeah, but the other thing is the people who buy Wiis aren't gonna.
Speaker 0: You know Nintendo's like yeah, you hardcore people aren't gonna buy Wiis.
Speaker 0: grandmas and kids and everyone else and girls are gonna buy Wiis.
Speaker 1: So it's more me hoping than me expecting.
Speaker 0: Yep, so those people aren't the types to buy Grand Theft Auto, but Rockstar smart.
Speaker 1: I mean they make games that make them a lot of money.
Speaker 1: So if there's a market for that sort of thing you can bet they'll do it alright.
Speaker 0: Microsoft really seems to be expanding the Xbox Live arcade deal.
Speaker 0: There was something about Lou mines live.
Speaker 0: I guess you'd play Lou mines on your Xbox and your cell phone and whatever and it'd be some sort of like Something with the webcam.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I talked about it that much because no one cares about DDR universe.
Speaker 0: so apparently Xbox is the system for DDR.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can see us downloading new songs.
Speaker 0: Hopefully they won't charge for them.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: They will.
Speaker 1: I guarantee it.
Speaker 1: I'd freaking guarantee they're gonna charge money for the songs.
Speaker 1: They'll have to because the songs are copyrighted.
Speaker 0: can see that sounds more like Sony's bag charging for the songs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the our game But there I don't see any way around it because the people who own the music are probably going to be pricks about it.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll see Viva pinata.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: when they showed this game People kind of went grumbly grumbly and then the ex the guy on stage was like, come on.
Speaker 0: It's an e-rated game and The crowd's reaction was like yeah, whatever It's from what people say it looks like an Animal Crossing type of game, which is like, alright You're trying to copy Animal Crossing whatever.
Speaker 0: but all the guy the press people seem to be saying I We weren't not cheering because it was an e-rated game.
Speaker 0: We weren't cheering because it didn't look that interesting.
Speaker 0: It's look like ghetto, you know, it's hard to tell Animal Crossing the little pin.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's hard to tell what they're trying to do with this game other than maybe Steal some of the people who want Animal Crossing over to the Xbox.
Speaker 0: yeah, maybe what's gonna happen is people buy an Xbox and instead of you know going out and Spending a bunch of money on a Wii for their kids They'll just buy Viva pinata for their already Existing 360 and then spend the rest of the money they would have spent on a Wii on more 360 stuff for themselves.
Speaker 1: Of course for the price of a ps3 you can just buy an Xbox and a Wii.
Speaker 0: But well, no, we don't know how much the Wii cost yet.
Speaker 1: I pretty much guarantee you'll be able to buy them both for the price of a ps3.
Speaker 0: Yep, people seem to be guaranteeing that it'll probably be true.
Speaker 1: In fact Microsoft themselves have come out and basically said yeah Sony socks, you should buy a Wii.
Speaker 0: Remember how before I was saying Sony it does the same thing as a Wii only crappier and does the same thing as a 360 only crappier.
Speaker 0: That would work out if the ps3 cost less than both of the systems combined because then it's like I can get both for less.
Speaker 0: but this is why get something that does two things and Each thing it does is shittier when I can get both of those things to the max separately for the same price or even less
Speaker 1: And this is Microsoft talking because they don't care if Nintendo is successful or not.
Speaker 0: it's like cell phone cameras work because it's cheaper than the price of a cell phone and a camera and Combining them is good because you have your cell phone everywhere with you.
Speaker 0: So now you have a camera everywhere with you and the camera is all of a sudden becomes more useful.
Speaker 0: Having a Wii combined with an Xbox Live is sort of useful.
Speaker 0: the same way having a camera on your phone is useful but If for the same price as a camera phone you can get a camera and a phone then the camera phone doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Yep, of course Nintendo wins all around because people could own a ps3 and a Wii or an Xbox and a Wii.
Speaker 1: Not many people are going to own Xbox and a ps3.
Speaker 1: Not many now because the games are gonna mostly overlap.
Speaker 1: aside from the exclusives every third-party game is gonna come out on both systems Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: In fact that could actually be a really bad point for Sony because yeah The PlayStation 3 has better graphics capabilities, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if a third party makes a game for the Xbox and the ps3 They're gonna make damn well sure it runs on the Xbox and I don't know how much extra effort they're gonna put into making it Look better.
Speaker 0: They usually they make it look better If you look at history of all the millions of games that are released on the ps2 and the Xbox.
Speaker 0: People always well almost always put in the extra effort to make it look better on the more powerful system.
Speaker 0: However, ever they don't.
Speaker 1: then the X the extra effort was easier.
Speaker 1: It's of everyone's keep saying it's hellishly hard to do anything with the ps3.
Speaker 0: development wise I still think you know.
Speaker 0: What happens is if you don't make your game look you've released a game for a bunch of systems and it doesn't look better.
Speaker 0: On the more powerful system all the press yells at you and gives you a worse review.
Speaker 0: Game developers will put in as much extra effort as they feel necessary.
Speaker 1: Well, they have always done Yeah, but we'll see how much extra effort they will do it.
Speaker 1: three scales.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of Levels of effort you can put in.
Speaker 0: they will do it until it becomes, you know cost prohibitive.
Speaker 0: Rest of the Xbox 360 games were kind of normal.
Speaker 0: You know the sports games a lot of peace a lot of games that would have been PC games But are now gonna be PC slash 360 games.
Speaker 0: Yeah What the 360 is all about.
Speaker 1: a lot of people also pointed out that the buzz at e3 is that people were saying?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the ps3 is more powerful, but the Xbox games looked better?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's interesting.
Speaker 0: The thing is is that you didn't see a lot of Ps3 game.
Speaker 1: we saw a lot of FMV saw a lot of FMV.
Speaker 0: You saw a lot of FMVs and bullshots for the 360 also.
Speaker 0: Yep, but there was gameplay footage that was seen and The opinion of most people is that right now a lot of the ps3 footage doesn't look that much better than 360 at games themselves.
Speaker 1: I really think we're just there's.
Speaker 1: they're diminishing returns.
Speaker 0: and if you're someone like us who doesn't care about graphics What matters is all the other stuff where Microsoft has a distinct advantage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course, we don't even have HDTV.
Speaker 1: So for us we don't care at all.
Speaker 0: No, I could care less of it at HD.
Speaker 0: So, you know the fact that the ps3 is 1080 whatever and the 360 is 720 doesn't mean anything to me.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be doing 480i All right, all the rest of the games are sequels franchises licenses usual type of games you see.
Speaker 1: yeah The only last thing we really would have talked about but I don't have much to say about it Even though some people have asked is will write spore?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is what I know about.
Speaker 0: will write spore because I don't pay attention to PC games so much because I'm Linux guy.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be PC game.
Speaker 0: If you don't know will write is the sims sim city?
Speaker 0: cool guy He makes good games.
Speaker 1: you make a little creature and then you like breed it and evolve it.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's like you start out with like a bacteria or protozoa and you can make decisions and modify and over time you know it evolves and grows and Eventually you get a society and you can see the effects carry through all the way to the end of the game.
Speaker 0: so if you give your protozoa like Three little feelers now your people when they when they evolve into an advanced life form now that advanced Life form was three arms Yeah, and yeah
Speaker 1: Madam and you have to deal with don't have
Speaker 0: to develop your whole society now around the fact that your guys have three arms And etcetera etcetera etcetera
Speaker 1: that we don't really yet even know too much about the game.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a lot.
Speaker 0: I could have read some more articles about it, but I did.
Speaker 0: I do the show.
Speaker 1: I read the article where they had some people who were at his little presentation thing and I didn't really gain much from it.
Speaker 0: They didn't really the games not ready yet It sounds like it might be a fun game.
Speaker 1: They people basically see me and they'd say it's a sandbox game.
Speaker 1: That is also kind of a like Sim Earth Sim galaxy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hopefully not a Sim Ant.
Speaker 1: Sim Ant was awesome and by awesome I mean it was awesome for five minutes, and then you'd already done everything you could ever do in the game.
Speaker 0: Here's hoping that Spore is fun, and here's hoping that it's not just a Windows game that I'll never play.
Speaker 1: I think we'll have to wait until there's more info about it Or maybe until we get it and play it before we can say much.
Speaker 0: Yeah Maybe I'll try to read some more stuff about it, and we'll do a quick preview on a future Tuesday.
Speaker 1: But for that Scott's a hacking up a storm here.
Speaker 1: I think he's getting sick or something but oh That's good.
Speaker 0: Everyone's gonna love to hear that.
Speaker 0: cuz I haven't been sick in how long a little while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I don't get sick very often.
Speaker 0: It's a rare event.
Speaker 0: No, no podcasting will be lost over this unless I am hospital ill.
Speaker 1: yeah But he's over there.
Speaker 1: hacking and coughing is making it kind of annoying.
Speaker 1: so I think we'll just stop here.
Speaker 0: I think we covered all the e3 stuff anyway you remember you can Figure out all the other stuff that happened at e3 by going to all the gaming websites.
Speaker 0: IGN and whatnot has all the info.
Speaker 0: game spot E3 buzz comm is really good.
Speaker 0: I've been using that a lot for the past week or so.
Speaker 0: yep though.
Speaker 1: So if if you haven't been following it It's kind of intimidating to go there from scratch because now you don't know anything.
Speaker 1: if I go there now It's like oh, there's a new thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a new thing.
Speaker 0: yeah But if you haven't been going there all along you just see the newest thing and it's hard to realize what all the old things Are.
Speaker 0: yeah, there are a lot of summaries.
Speaker 0: if you go to Kotaku and gadget Kotaku's joy stick.
Speaker 1: in my opinion Kotaku and joystick have a lot of just like oh here was a cool thing.
Speaker 1: Here's a video.
Speaker 0: I have to say that Kotaku has the most humorous coverage.
Speaker 0: they have things like a video of the food and a video of the line Joystick and engage you I think have the best real serious coverage so far.
Speaker 0: So check them out if you actually care about things and not don't just want to laugh.
Speaker 1: all right and on that note We're out of here.
Speaker 1: That's e3 and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.