Speaker 1: Hey, it's Monday October 2nd, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about very simply the news.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: This past weekend Scott and I had a weekend of the likes that we have not seen in about a year.
Speaker 1: We had a non podcast weekend the kinds of weekends We had every weekend before we started doing geek nights yet.
Speaker 0: There was no podcasting.
Speaker 0: there was no Convention going.
Speaker 0: there was no people coming over to our house.
Speaker 0: There was no us going anyone else's house.
Speaker 0: It was just doing our business.
Speaker 1: Yep on Saturday.
Speaker 1: We went up the road We played board games all day, and then we consumerized for the rest of the day.
Speaker 1: Yep We went to a mall we bought things with credit cards and cash.
Speaker 1: We went to a Best Buy and fussed with their sensors making them think that more customers came in than actually did.
Speaker 0: I Attempted to buy pants only to find that they are too expensive.
Speaker 1: I attempt.
Speaker 1: for my frugal nature I attempted and succeeded in buying bionic commando for the GBA.
Speaker 0: It came with Strider and Oh, whatever mighty fighter by a mighty final fight.
Speaker 1: It was bionic commando anything else.
Speaker 1: I would have paid the 20 bucks just for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll be reviewing that shortly Mm-hmm, and then Sunday we went apple picking.
Speaker 0: we got them apples there from the trees.
Speaker 1: Yeah apples and cider, you know donuts cider donuts.
Speaker 1: Yes pumpkins.
Speaker 1: We got some pumpkins.
Speaker 1: I think that my pumpkin because it's so understated as far superior to Scott's bullshit pumpkin.
Speaker 0: Why my pumpkin?
Speaker 0: puns your pumpkin.
Speaker 0: it's bigger by almost first off.
Speaker 1: when we're walking in to get pumpkin Scott's trying to talk tell me that you don't buy the biggest pumpkin you can reasonably fit into your car But in fact that you should get some kind of smaller pumpkin.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Well, what do you need this big giant pumpkin for?
Speaker 0: it's just a waste of space.
Speaker 1: now when it comes to pumpkins bigger Clearly is superior.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: No, I think you're trying to compensate for something with your giant pumpkin.
Speaker 0: I'm happy with a moderately sized pumpkin.
Speaker 0: I care more about the symmetry of the pumpkin.
Speaker 0: see but the thing is the niceness of the surface of the pump.
Speaker 1: The pumpkin you got is so pumpkiny.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like Cyclops.
Speaker 1: Everybody hates Cyclops because he's just too perfect and your pumpkin has that little handle coming off the top.
Speaker 1: My pumpkin the way it's situated is much more understated.
Speaker 1: It's a sleeper pumpkin.
Speaker 0: yeah, because There's nothing exciting about it.
Speaker 0: Just puts everyone to sleep.
Speaker 0: My pumpkins exciting and awesome and cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see what happens when the pumpkins actually have some sort of.
Speaker 1: I don't know how I could go with that.
Speaker 1: When we carve them and see who carves it better neither one of us has any sort of skill at that whatsoever.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm going to get the internet to help me in this.
Speaker 0: what you get a piece of paper and you shine a light Or you just get like a stencil and you trace onto the pumpkin and then you cut out along the lines.
Speaker 1: somehow.
Speaker 1: I think your original plan of hiring you go to make you a pumpkin was far better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's also a good plan, but we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: Either way, I'm a pumpkin will put in you my pumpkin.
Speaker 1: I think is going to be a traditional pumpkin.
Speaker 1: It's going to have two triangle eyes and a mouth with some pumpkin seed teeth in it.
Speaker 0: It's so lame.
Speaker 0: Oh and Mike my pumpkins totally gonna get a better candle.
Speaker 1: what my pumpkin is going to be a bomb.
Speaker 1: But Goblin my pumpkin is going to be full of gasoline and star phone.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Well, you can have that pumpkin far away from the house.
Speaker 1: I Was trying to think how many more pumpkin jokes I can make.
Speaker 1: there really aren't so many?
Speaker 0: no Not really.
Speaker 1: I mean we're gonna make some pumpkins.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 0: Everyone's got to get some pumpkin?
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I mean, I don't think pendulettes gonna be doing.
Speaker 0: they celebrate Halloween and other countries the way do in the US because we have listeners in other countries and They might not, you know be into the whole pumpkin Halloween thing.
Speaker 1: Well, I have a funny short anecdote before we get into the news about just that kind of question.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, you see when we were in high school now I'm not gonna mention any names, but there was a girl in my 10th grade social studies class Oh god, who was also in my 11th grade.
Speaker 0: I've heard this story.
Speaker 1: Well, no, you haven't heard this specific one.
Speaker 0: I don't think I've heard stories about this girl.
Speaker 1: Yeah this girl.
Speaker 1: Well once we're talking about Vietnam and the Vietnam War and we're talking and talking and talking about it, you know US involvement troops there how he had troops there for a while and Then he'd stops talking.
Speaker 1: the teacher, you know says blah blah blah troops there and he stops and there's silence You know and he's about to ask a question at the class.
Speaker 1: She raises her head and he's trying to ignore her.
Speaker 1: He's doing his best to ignore her because she has asked some dingers before.
Speaker 1: So she says her name and she looks at him and very earnestly asks, so are those troops still there?
Speaker 1: And he said yes her name they are.
Speaker 1: she goes really and he goes no they're not.
Speaker 1: So there are all sorts of stories, I mean that is probably the least funny of the stories about this woman.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not even a woman.
Speaker 1: She was a 10th grader along with me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but one day we're talking about the 4th of July Independence Day u.s.
Speaker 1: Breaking off from Britain the first time.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and She.
Speaker 1: she said we start talking about this and she asks very seriously.
Speaker 1: How do other countries celebrate their 4th of July?
Speaker 1: And the teacher without a beat say me I forget what he said, but he made some crack about Britain celebrates it.
Speaker 1: All right But yeah Yeah.
Speaker 0: So Halloween pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you can tell we had throwaway Thursday followed by throwaway Monday.
Speaker 0: We're throwing away the days until CityCon this weekend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this weekend is this whole week.
Speaker 1: starting last Thursday is pretty much just gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway CityCon is this weekend.
Speaker 1: Yes, we are going to be there.
Speaker 0: It's going to be wicked awesome because we are going to make it wicked awesome regardless of what goes down.
Speaker 0: Even if we get there and it's a cardboard box in the side of the road We will provide you with the happiest three days in the cardboard box you can get.
Speaker 1: in fact I think in the future we're gonna do an episode on that about what to do when life gives you shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, aka make shit exactly.
Speaker 0: but no come to CityCon and Utica, New York.
Speaker 0: If you are within throwing distance this weekend Friday Saturday and Sunday CityCon calm si Ta con.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be plugging it all week.
Speaker 1: Try the veal.
Speaker 0: Yep Okay news that all right now.
Speaker 1: this is news.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna talk about it mostly because I Became aware of it through my dealings with this company and it's not widely reported at all.
Speaker 1: In fact, I've seen no mention of this anywhere other than the forums of Libsyn.
Speaker 1: but Libsyn the company we use we contract them to do all of our media file storage for geek nights and Aside from a somewhat rocky start.
Speaker 1: They are an incredibly good company.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're pretty good.
Speaker 0: I mean without companies providing this exact service podcasting would largely be the domain of incredibly rich people and It would be much fewer many fewer podcasts with many more ads granted geek nights would probably be going just the same.
Speaker 0: yes, it would just cost us more and Have an ad maybe.
Speaker 1: but a lot of podcasts are on Libsyn.
Speaker 1: They're very good service and for the most part.
Speaker 1: I don't have to deal with them at all because there are never problems anymore.
Speaker 0: Used to be problems early in the back in the day it kind of sucked but now they're all good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean they've got great stats.
Speaker 1: Everything's great.
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 1: No problems at all.
Speaker 1: We love Libsyn.
Speaker 1: Mmm, and we're not plugging them for any reason because we actually pay them for the service.
Speaker 1: It's not like we're getting anything from them that they're not being compensated duly for.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: This isn't an advertisement This is an honest whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, I was on their forums because I was trolling about something.
Speaker 1: I forget exactly why I was there.
Speaker 1: It's not like I go there for support and I got to say Libsyn gets a lot of shit from their customers.
Speaker 0: That's entirely unwarranted Because the customers don't know shit.
Speaker 1: most of the customers are problems with Libsyn or people who hate Libsyn are people who just don't know Anything about podcasting at all.
Speaker 1: You should see some of this.
Speaker 1: But apparently there's a problem where recently this group calling itself perverted justice.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh was going around sending emails Angry emails to any Podcaster they could find who they knew was on Libsyn because they didn't feel that Libsyn was addressing their concerns.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: now I'm gonna sum up.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna read.
Speaker 0: so they were trying.
Speaker 0: so Libsyn did something bad to perverted justice and perverted justice tried to get Libsyn Customers to fight Libsyn and join their alliance.
Speaker 1: They're basically trying to bully Libsyn into doing something.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: now the crux of the matter and I'll state right now that we do not support what is going on here.
Speaker 1: This is very much a I don't agree with you, but I defend to the death.
Speaker 1: You're right to say it.
Speaker 1: It has to do with child pornography.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh.
Speaker 1: All right Now apparently I got a funny story.
Speaker 0: Is that just remind you something?
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: when I say the word child pornography The last thing I want to hear is you say I got a funny start.
Speaker 0: I know cuz this the way you said.
Speaker 0: that reminded me of 10th grade.
Speaker 0: You ready for this?
Speaker 1: Okay, I don't think I don't know if we're gonna break the law here.
Speaker 0: No, no in 10th grade.
Speaker 0: I had this class.
Speaker 0: It was a for, you know for my social studies, whatever requirement.
Speaker 0: Yeah It was like like current events.
Speaker 0: history of you know recent history.
Speaker 0: Okay, and the teacher was mad cool.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: D. Felice.
Speaker 0: He was the first libertarian I ever knew.
Speaker 1: Did you and this mad cool teacher have some sort of illicit?
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: So on every Friday instead of actually teaching the class We had a current events game where what you had to do is write down Questions at five questions with answers about current events and then you'd make teams and you know He would bring the questions out and you try to answer him and whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever team one got bonus points.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: It's funny because I think every 10th grade social studies class had the same thing going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there's one kid and one one week.
Speaker 0: He was just getting all the answers wrong.
Speaker 0: He was just.
Speaker 0: his name was Mark and he was just like, oh you got it wrong.
Speaker 0: Oh, I got it wrong.
Speaker 0: I got it wrong, right.
Speaker 0: and There was a news story that week about a teacher at another at another school in the state of Connecticut Who got fired for having child porn.
Speaker 0: I think it was like a college professor had child porn on the computer and he got fired.
Speaker 0: So they questioned it.
Speaker 0: finally markets, you know They come back to him and they're like.
Speaker 0: they got this question like, you know, so-and-so was fired.
Speaker 0: Why did he get fired and he goes child?
Speaker 0: And the way you said child porn like, you know pulling it out of the hat was just like that, all right.
Speaker 1: So aside from the child porn story that Scott just told us yeah, there's this podcast called.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say the name of the podcast cuz I don't want you to actually go check it out.
Speaker 0: I don't want to promote them in any way, you know, even though I do have like I don't want to listen to it But I want to know what they say.
Speaker 0: Well, what is there to say?
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of people Assess the situation here.
Speaker 1: Basically this podcast talks about Changing laws to make sex with younger children legal and changing the age of consent and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: So they're not so.
Speaker 0: they're not giving you instructions on how to trick kids to get into your van And they're not telling you the URLs of websites of child porn.
Speaker 1: Well from what I can gather I mean I have not listened to it either but from what everything I've read and other people who have done research It seems that the podcast talks about some sick things and the podcast is creepy and scary
Speaker 0: I imagine it is
Speaker 1: but it does not advocate any illegal acts and technically nothing It does is illegal in any way shape or form.
Speaker 1: Alright now Libsyn's policy which I did not know regarding the content of podcast is very simply if you're paying them money Unless the podcast you were putting up is actually in violation of United States law.
Speaker 1: They will not in any way prevent you from doing business with them and that is as it should be.
Speaker 0: being liberated Syndication I mean Libsyn.
Speaker 1: they even had a statement to the effect of we don't like this But we're not going to get rid of one of our customers just because you disagree with them.
Speaker 0: Yep I think that's the way it has to be.
Speaker 0: if you're gonna call yourself liberated syndication You can't really have a different policy.
Speaker 0: Can you know?
Speaker 1: Even better the way Libsyn is handling.
Speaker 1: This is that they did investigate the podcast to make sure they weren't doing anything illegal.
Speaker 0: Wow Wonder how they must have given the guy who had to listen to that podcaster raise Beyond that.
Speaker 1: actually apparently what they did is they made the guy who does the podcast transcribe all of his episodes.
Speaker 1: That's so they could read them.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Furthermore.
Speaker 1: They told this perverted justice group of Interesting folk that if they have concerns as to the legality of a podcast they should contact the FBI immediately who will work directly with Them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that sounds good to me.
Speaker 1: So I guess I would like to say that this news here which I bring up mostly because I really Have a lot of respect now for Libsyn because they stood up for something that is horrible and despicable But yet it is the people person's right to talk about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's the only things that really need standing up for are horrible and stupid things because no one needs to stand up for something That's not horrible because no one's gonna try to bring it down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one of the arguments I would make is that what if there were a podcast about overthrowing the government of the United States or about communism libertarianism or something?
Speaker 1: those things are just as anathema to some people as this and This isn't illegal.
Speaker 1: And if we want to have a First Amendment, you know the right to speak freely Then we have to accept all of the consequences of having that including speech.
Speaker 1: We don't want to hear speech.
Speaker 1: we find offensive speech.
Speaker 1: We might think is dangerous.
Speaker 0: Yeah And if you don't like it, no one's making you listen to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can talk all you want.
Speaker 0: We don't have to listen to you either.
Speaker 1: I mean there there are reasonable limitations to speech But the key words are reasonable.
Speaker 0: If someone made a podcast where they gave specific instructions on how to make a nuclear weapon and then an or Biological weapon and they told you go make one now and then go set it off here at this time That's not okay.
Speaker 0: Yes But if you're just gonna say please please please please let our horrible perversions Be legal instead of putting us in jail where we should be you can say that all you want But we're still gonna come and put you in jail where you should be.
Speaker 1: so I guess I mean Libsyn gets a lot of crap for a lot of things.
Speaker 1: but Stand up for Libsyn on this one because I think that they're doing probably the most Ideological thing they can do.
Speaker 1: they're standing up for what they've said.
Speaker 1: they'll do Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right, so Jan Lech Johansson Aka DVD Jan DVD on a or DVD John to all of you Barbarians.
Speaker 0: Yes DVD Jan is a famous dude.
Speaker 0: when he was 15 years old He cracked CSS which allowed everyone to copy DVDs.
Speaker 0: DVD Jan is the basically the reason that you can play DVDs and Linux Basically, yes, the reason that you can rip DVDs to your hard drive is DVD Jan.
Speaker 0: anyway He at one point, you know broke Apple's DRM on.
Speaker 0: you know the iTunes stuff But then they you know, they fought back and Apple was got ahead and now other people are doing that.
Speaker 0: However, DVD on stopped being a punk kid and now he's got a company and what he's done is he has reverse engineered The Apple DRM, but he's not putting out a tool like, you know fair use for WM or you know QT fair use that allows you to you know, turn your you know iTunes store purchases into mp3s.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: He is making it so that other companies can distribute Music and songs that are protected with Apple's DRM.
Speaker 0: because right now if you want to make a song That has Apple's DRM protection on it.
Speaker 0: The only way you can do it is letting Apple do it for you in the iTunes store.
Speaker 0: Now if he succeeds in doing this without getting sued He will be able to open up or any of his customers will be able to open up a music store on the internet That will put out music that is DRM and will work on iPods.
Speaker 0: That is sort of huge Because a lot of the problem is people who want to make a music store need to use some sort of DRM if they want.
Speaker 0: You know licensed music from companies.
Speaker 0: But the only DRMs they can use are either make your own DRM and then what player is that gonna work on?
Speaker 0: Well, you need a player So you can use Windows DRM which works on all those, you know, whatever players the what are they called?
Speaker 0: Plays for sure players.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much anything.
Speaker 0: that's not an iPod that you can buy in the store is plays for sure.
Speaker 0: And then there's the.
Speaker 0: the Zune is gonna have a different DRM on it the Zune DRM.
Speaker 0: So, you know if most players out there are iPods which makes it really hard to be a music store That sells DRM stuff because no one has a player for your DRM files.
Speaker 0: So this one that you know people can already compete with the iPod.
Speaker 0: There's no problem there, but we DVD on succeeds in doing this people be able to compete with the iTunes music store.
Speaker 1: now a lot of people might say Oh, but won't it still be illegal to use this stuff?
Speaker 1: And the answer is complicated.
Speaker 1: But in most countries there there are a lot of laws that there's basically a loophole where if you reverse engineer something It is perfectly legal to recreate the functionality that you figured out on your own.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's a really a tough call on the legality of this because real tried to do this before Back in the day and Apple made them stop, you know, basically they said okay.
Speaker 0: Okay, we'll stop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but by the same token DVD yawns not in this country right now and If anything a lot of companies especially Chinese companies Well might just start making stuff that supports this and fuck all what Apple cares about.
Speaker 1: Apple can't sue them.
Speaker 0: Yeah So be on the lookout for online music stores where you can legally buy music with DRM on it.
Speaker 0: So I wouldn't buy it but that is playable on an iPod.
Speaker 0: That's gonna be in the.
Speaker 0: you know, wonder why it doesn't exist now.
Speaker 0: Well DVD on is gonna make it happen and possibly stick it to Apple.
Speaker 1: some things of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh, I got a mighty good thing of the day right here.
Speaker 0: Oh, do you now?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well what this is?
Speaker 0: it's a typical bathroom rules joke.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is an old joke.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was a flash Executable going around when I was in high school that did.
Speaker 1: this made the same basic joke.
Speaker 0: I had a friend in high school who wrote up a large document.
Speaker 0: That was basically this joke.
Speaker 0: but Essentially the joke is it's not it's sort of a truth and a joke and that this is how things go in a men's bathroom For the most part.
Speaker 0: yet The biggest the most part of the joke that always seems to stay true is the stall selection or the urinal selection.
Speaker 0: You always want to have at least a one urinal buffer between you and other guy.
Speaker 0: Go to the ends first and then the middle and you know all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except I pretty much completely ignore that and I just pee somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah often often between two people see Three categories.
Speaker 0: There's you know, there's a minority of guys but still a large number but a minority who Have a problem going to the bathroom.
Speaker 0: Like if they're next to someone they can't go they have a problem.
Speaker 0: I'm not one of those people.
Speaker 1: I had that happen once but that was cuz I held it for too long.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah long car ride.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then there's the kind of guys who you know, they go wherever they don't care they'll stand right next to you and look at your wiener and pee.
Speaker 0: they're scary.
Speaker 0: and Then there's the people who are kind of normal, you know They don't.
Speaker 0: they won't stand next to someone if they don't have to but they don't really care if they have to you know.
Speaker 0: And if every urinal is filled except for one and they got a pee they pee.
Speaker 0: What do they care?
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually, that's me.
Speaker 1: There was a time our marching band in high school was on the way back from a big competition or something And we all really had to pee like ten school buses full of kids.
Speaker 1: So we pull up on this rest stop we all get off and we all run into the bathrooms.
Speaker 1: There were two urinals and one stall for the guys.
Speaker 0: Oh, I heard the story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and like a hundred guys, so, you know the lines going.
Speaker 1: and finally this kid, I'm not no names here But one of my favorite kids in high school says fuck this.
Speaker 1: and he runs in and pees in the sink.
Speaker 0: He's the winner.
Speaker 1: and then everyone peed in the sink and the guys were done almost 45 minutes before the girls.
Speaker 1: That's all I gotta say.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this video it.
Speaker 0: they made it using the Sims and SimCity.
Speaker 0: It's a little machinima it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: and They made the same joke about you know it's using urinals and how to operate in the bathroom and then they took it a step further and then a step further and It gets pretty funny because you don't expect where it's going even if you've heard the joke before.
Speaker 1: There's also a lot of little subtle jokes in it.
Speaker 1: Throughout like it talked the narrators like blah blah blah blah Awkward situations in the restroom blah and if you notice the guy sitting in one of the stalls is naked Yeah, and the other guy kind of just notices that.
Speaker 0: yep Or the one where it says if you go into a urinal If you go into a stall and you find that the previous guy didn't flush walk out and go to another one gasp thrice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, there's a VG cats the.
Speaker 1: I'll make that a thing of the day someday.
Speaker 0: Well Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: So real quick not much I can say about this other than that.
Speaker 1: I'm disappointed in the propaganda at the top of this page.
Speaker 1: I'm linking to my thing of the day because while the works that are presented are wonderful things They are trying to somehow use this as propaganda for Aposto-farianism when we all know that the ramanites hold the true noodly appendage.
Speaker 0: I don't know I don't know.
Speaker 1: So these are a bunch of flying spaghetti monster carved Halloween pumpkins Oh my god of varying quality.
Speaker 1: I'll admit most of them are pretty piss poor.
Speaker 0: It's kind of hard to carve out a noodly appendage in a pumpkin.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, the thing is I was kind of hoping to see.
Speaker 1: you know people who are really good how they'll scrape out the pumpkin But leave the skin there so they have shading on their things.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I know exactly what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: No one made that kind of flying spaghetti monster.
Speaker 0: Ah Maybe someone will.
Speaker 0: Because the way that works is you know You take the skin off the pumpkin and then you shave Deeper in parts that you want to have a brighter color and you shave less deep or you want the darker color And the candle shines easily through.
Speaker 0: the parts that are shaved a little bit.
Speaker 0: I mean that are shaved a lot and the parts that are only shaved a little bit It's you know, the candle goes through less.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one guy kind of did it.
Speaker 1: The problem is that it's really it's hard to do that And if you screw up you're done until next.
Speaker 0: pretty much need to make like, you know Sort of like this topographical map.
Speaker 0: or like you draw lines and then you know say this one is X deep and this one is X deep times to you know, yeah The problem is in addition to that you also need the manual dexterity the physical skill and the artistic eye.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we lack all four.
Speaker 0: done done done done done.
Speaker 1: Our pumpkins are gonna be so lame Mine's gonna be okay.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: I'll bet money.
Speaker 1: Your pumpkin will be lame.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I'll go gonna go buy some extra tools.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Even if a man doesn't know what to do It doesn't have any talent or anything.
Speaker 0: if he has the tools he can do something.
Speaker 1: Yeah more damage.
Speaker 0: That's right It's all about tools.
Speaker 1: So we were trying to come up with what to talk about today Because Mondays are real easy except when we don't feel like doing any research which is all the time.
Speaker 1: No every now and then we've been all set to do a Monday.
Speaker 1: Sometimes yeah, and if we do a tech news roundup just bam bam bam.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem with tech news roundup is that everyone likes them.
Speaker 0: people love that as like the best Monday we ever do Yeah, but like every other podcast just does that as their podcast.
Speaker 0: So what do we want to?
Speaker 1: you know, well not to not to sound full of you know egotistical leanings, but More than one of our listeners which actually means two of our listeners have said Independently of one another that we do twit better than twit.
Speaker 0: You know what this week twit didn't do to it really I didn't notice.
Speaker 0: well They kind of did they the they.
Speaker 0: they were at the podcast Media Expo and they just kind of talked to a bunch of podcasters stuff.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh They didn't they didn't.
Speaker 0: I mean they went over some tech news, but not a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: Not like they usually do.
Speaker 1: so we're going over ideas and you know We have about 20 Mondays in the queue, but each one of them requires some sort of build a computer.
Speaker 0: I had a computer works.
Speaker 0: part 3.
Speaker 1: We have a lot of shows we've got planned that just require a little bit of research and planning because they're the kind of shows Where we'll actually be more informative than we normally would.
Speaker 0: Yes, send us more Monday show ideas and not the same ones over and over again.
Speaker 0: Like you've been sending.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we know IT security.
Speaker 1: We're still trying to work out what to cover to make that interesting to those of you who aren't techie.
Speaker 1: Well, not being completely useless to people who are techie.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 0: There's an existing podcast called security.
Speaker 0: Now you can listen to that and it's a whole podcast.
Speaker 0: all of basically that would you know be the same thing?
Speaker 1: We would do only yeah, if anything we tend to provide overview and humor.
Speaker 0: Yes, if anything That's what you hope you provide.
Speaker 0: and rust hurricanes rust hurricanes Taking the wrong podcast.
Speaker 1: You can't hold ten rust hurricane.
Speaker 0: You can't hold ten rust hurricanes strong.
Speaker 1: But we were.
Speaker 1: I'm sitting in work not doing anything because there was no work for me to do today and I asked I was Like can I do some work?
Speaker 1: and there wasn't any.
Speaker 0: I was oh, yeah, I was home all day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: My office was empty.
Speaker 1: All the Gentiles were at work and everyone else was at home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, in case anyone doesn't know today was a Jew holiday non-sequitur Not really kind of.
Speaker 1: it wasn't a non-sequitur at all.
Speaker 1: I just said it was a Jewish holiday.
Speaker 0: And yeah, anyway, I was born Jewish But that was a sequitur Scott, I guess I guess but the problem is just what we started talking about.
Speaker 0: You know tech Monday and now we're talking about Jew day.
Speaker 1: I was getting to that.
Speaker 1: All right I was getting to that.
Speaker 1: cuz you see I'm sitting at work and I'm messaging Scott ideas for the Monday show and They were all ideas that we didn't feel like doing today.
Speaker 1: well tonight and then I thought I'm looking through the news because I also needed a news in the thing of the day and I realized Well, actually I realized it when I saw an old piece of news on dig.
Speaker 1: This is what started it all.
Speaker 1: I saw this piece of news from like eight years ago and it was on dig like it was brand new and it had a bunch of digs.
Speaker 1: so I'm like what the hell.
Speaker 1: so I comment this is horse shit and old.
Speaker 1: and then I buried it and Then I realized that there seems to be this cycle lately of like news will exist.
Speaker 1: You know something happens like Scott stabs a guy or or some terrorists attack someone and then there's this flow of how the news gets Disseminated and it seems that it's very different nowadays from the way it was even a few years ago Mmm, so we kind of just want to talk about how we get the news how you probably should get the news and just stuff about The news.
Speaker 1: we didn't really plan this out at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is this is totally cuff off of off my cuff.
Speaker 1: I'm not wearing any cuffs.
Speaker 1: Oh, like I'm wearing a tattered button-up shirt.
Speaker 0: That's how off it is.
Speaker 1: Well, my shorts are tattered - I didn't even realize that.
Speaker 0: So when it comes to reading news, I'm gonna try to keep this Technology internet kind of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not gonna talk about newspapers We're going to talk briefly about radio.
Speaker 0: Yeah There are generally different kinds of sources that you get news from.
Speaker 0: there's the direct source.
Speaker 0: Some guy comes over to your house and he says I saw this thing going on down the street or you see something happening with Your own eyeballs.
Speaker 1: now see that's eyewitness.
Speaker 1: and then primary.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the two best sources you can get that's pretty much, you know Guaranteed to be true unless the guy who says the primary source is insane Or neti in some way.
Speaker 1: then there are secondary sources like CNN, you know, we heard that a guy saw.
Speaker 0: Or you know the AP news wire Yeah, which just gives its news directly to CNN who copies that news and perhaps rewrites it Without changing the information course, then they're the tertiary sources aka the people blogging or making shit up.
Speaker 1: Yeah Which surprisingly?
Speaker 0: I guess not surprisingly is becoming more and more common and people seem to believe that more than CNN's and things for some reason I guess because you know the way it's written and presented feels more honest and genuine than the assumedly conspiratorial news networks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the conspiratorial left-leaning yet right-leaning Vast conspiracy.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean I love how the people on the far right in this country accused the media of being left-biased and the people on the far left Accused the media being right bias.
Speaker 0: You know what that tells me.
Speaker 0: if people on the far right think it's too far left and the people on the far left thing It's too far, right?
Speaker 0: It's probably in the middle.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: No, it's it's very much leaning toward money.
Speaker 1: Ah Fox News doesn't care if a conservative or liberal is in power or a Communist or dictator or whatever.
Speaker 1: they care about making money.
Speaker 1: So they do things.
Speaker 1: they get people to talk about them and watch Fox News.
Speaker 1: Money money money money is the sole driving force of conventional media.
Speaker 1: Don't think otherwise ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder what makes you know, because we do know it's pretty Objectively true that Fox News is slightly right-leaning, you know, at least I wonder what it is About being slightly right-leaning.
Speaker 0: that means more profits than being slightly left-leaning.
Speaker 1: Well, I've heard some people say that it's because the Republicans have more money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time most of the Republicans watching news are poor hicks in the woods?
Speaker 1: not necessarily no no Yeah, granted.
Speaker 1: Uh, no not many tech savvy people watch the news anymore.
Speaker 0: That's definitely true.
Speaker 1: See we could get into this whole thing about Republicans and Democrats Which wouldn't really be entirely accurate because we are neither Republicans nor Democrats and hate both of them.
Speaker 0: That's right anyway, so those are the another kind of place you can get your news from is like slash that which is sort of an Editorial news aggregator.
Speaker 0: I think that's really what we're gonna talk about is mostly the news aggregators, which are websites and other places that collect news from around wherever and into one place.
Speaker 0: so instead of having to go around the world to every single news site in the universe to get the interesting tidbits because if you Go to any news site like a site that is providing the news semi-directly like CNN there's maybe five good stories and a hundred crap stories and If you had to go through the effort of picking out the five good stories without reading any crap You're gonna be there for a long time, especially if you're doing it to a whole bunch of news sites.
Speaker 0: I mean you could spend your whole day doing that every single day your life and never finish.
Speaker 1: Now what I mean?
Speaker 1: this idea of slash dot dig bark.
Speaker 1: Some people would say bb spot.
Speaker 0: They're not really not really Reddit.
Speaker 0: yeah, there's a lot of them.
Speaker 1: drudge Hey drudge, they're all varying levels of really.
Speaker 1: it comes down to.
Speaker 1: there are two factors on any sort of news source especially on the internet.
Speaker 1: there is speed of delivery how quickly the news gets there and Accuracy, they're usually in an inverse relationship the faster you get it the less accurate It will be and vice versa.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you go to if some guy puts the news up as soon as it happens He hasn't.
Speaker 0: there hasn't been a lot of time for him.
Speaker 0: No one could have possibly fully verified that story in such a short amount of time.
Speaker 0: I mean He could have.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: only it's like if I hear something happen in the in the room next to me and I go and I put a news story about what I heard and then I go look for a second and I see something and I make a Like.
Speaker 1: Scott comes into my room and I'm laying on the ground and there's red on the floor And he assumes I'm dead and runs away.
Speaker 1: He comes back with the police and I'm just playing with ketchup.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly Exactly.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: I mean it can go both ways.
Speaker 1: in terms of the quick sources I mean, I remember when drudge reported that a dirty bomb had gone off in like Baltimore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and yet I remember when some guy on the realm told me that princess Diana was dead and no one believed me For like four hours And then she was dead and everyone went nuts and my family to this day couldn't figure out how I got that so quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really you know.
Speaker 0: What it comes down to is as a person you have to be able to tell when news is likely true and likely false.
Speaker 0: You know if someone Randomly says, you know princess Diana died.
Speaker 0: Well It's probably true because unless they were making jokes about Diana or something How would something so random just this this guy just decided to say that
Speaker 1: yeah See a lot of people just have a sense for we're kind of gonna go over more if you don't just have a sense of When to be credulous and when not.
Speaker 1: here are all the tips.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Generally one thing you have to consider when someone tells you a piece of news no matter where you get it from is What would they have to gain by tricking me?
Speaker 1: Why would this person want to lie to me about this news?
Speaker 1: if you can't think of a reason?
Speaker 1: They're probably not lying.
Speaker 1: However Fark.com has proven the.
Speaker 0: the horrible exception to that There was your example just before.
Speaker 0: the dirty bomb was also an exception true, but but Fark.com I mean Drog.
Speaker 1: it wasn't that he lied.
Speaker 1: It was just that he got the information wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I think he actually does kind of have.
Speaker 0: a reason is that he will take any news He hears that is as sensational as possible and put it up as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: But with Fark someone on Fark one day in the middle of this other thread posted that Damon Wayans was dead dead seriously and Ever people started believing it, you know, why would someone lie randomly out of the blue that Damon Wayans was dead?
Speaker 1: Yep, and it turned into this huge thing.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: It's an old dead cliche.
Speaker 1: It actually hasn't been on Fark in a while.
Speaker 1: I urge all of you Farkers who are also geek nighters to bring that back.
Speaker 1: No someone out there tomorrow posted Damon Wayans is dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to see if I have any sort of power like Stephen Colbert does.
Speaker 1: I probably don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe Pete will post it.
Speaker 0: I know he farks maybe you'll probably get one or two.
Speaker 1: The thing is I wouldn't be able to tell if that just wasn't someone anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll have to price a in our forums that they did it and then link to it.
Speaker 1: but anyway look at the source and the most important thing you can do aside from looking at the source and trying to figure out if they have a reason to lie to you is Very simply to see if anyone else is reporting on the same news.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Remember there was a news story There's about like the dogs that were zombies or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Russians had like frozen.
Speaker 0: It was I think it was in an Australian newspaper and the article was only on this one site and it didn't link to anywhere and there was a picture of a Living dog and it was just a bunch of words and there was no other site reporting this.
Speaker 0: there was no nothing.
Speaker 1: In fact, I remember that one because they used the word boffin and I'd never heard that word before and I actually had to look It up.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's exactly the one I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah now that apparently that specific story has made the rounds before Mm-hmm, and there's a couple stories like that like just today on dig.
Speaker 1: There was a story about Water that has been microwaved kills plants, but water that was boiled doesn't.
Speaker 1: therefore microwaves do something bad to water.
Speaker 1: Why complete horseshit been totally debunked a million times, but there it was on dig with like a thousand digs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there are fake news stories that go around.
Speaker 1: however in all cases unless it's some sort of vast conspiracy by a government which honestly I don't think any government in this world has the Sheer power to silence that many people to have that big of a conspiracy.
Speaker 2: The government look the government the US government does do things with news that are not cool like they make those fake news stories and Then all the news stations take them and put them on the news on the TV news as if they were news stories.
Speaker 1: Yeah Or we do psyops in other countries and we've admitted to it in the past and so of other countries where it will put fake News out in order to confuse other countries, but they're not.
Speaker 2: if that's the best they can do.
Speaker 2: They're not doing mass cover-up conspiracies to make you use microwaves and kill and so you'll die.
Speaker 1: So if you if one of these stories comes out if you can't find any other sources, it's probably not true.
Speaker 1: now The thing you gotta watch out for here is there were like ten sources for that dog article.
Speaker 1: However, they were all just blogs or things that themselves linked to the original or linked to another thing that linked to another thing and they all came back to the original.
Speaker 1: there was no Other independent source and there was no journal writing.
Speaker 2: Yep You have to.
Speaker 2: if you have a news story you have to count the independent sources.
Speaker 2: Follow all the links.
Speaker 2: if it's someone talking about a story that they found in another website.
Speaker 2: That is not a source.
Speaker 2: It has to be a place.
Speaker 2: Someone who got the information from this the place the information comes from and is sharing it with you directly That's what counts.
Speaker 2: and if there's only one of them or in fact if there's very few of them and they're all saying the same Thing it's probably not true.
Speaker 2: It's probably just about one guy made it up and another guy heard it and hearsay.
Speaker 2: If you see the same story in a whole lot of places, that's when you know, it's true.
Speaker 1: Also, if you see a sore likely true if you see a source like Reuters or AP wire It's probably at least been fact-checked.
Speaker 2: Yes as opposed to tossed up on the internet without a care.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of people who report on AP wire stories will just make stuff up beyond that or get wrong.
Speaker 1: But the actual AP wire or Reuters story is usually mostly factually correct.
Speaker 2: Yeah, a lot of times we'll go to CNN and you'll see a story or I'm tired of saying CNN Fox News Fox News And you see a story and it says via AP wire, right?
Speaker 0: That you will usually be a rewriting of Another story.
Speaker 2: that was the original AP wire story.
Speaker 2: You see you can subscribe to the news wire, which is it's a lot of money.
Speaker 2: You won't do it in your house, but every news station does it in the country.
Speaker 2: You pay money and his wire comes in, you know back.
Speaker 2: you see in all these old movies like a ticker tape that's ticking like And it's just this tape that has the news written on it and just kind of slowly types itself out.
Speaker 2: Well nowadays it's computerized and all that and we're not using that old-ass technology, but it's still a wire.
Speaker 2: It's not.
Speaker 2: actually it's a set of wires tubes.
Speaker 2: wires in tubes do wires.
Speaker 2: Yes, and They just get the stream of news stories coming in as they happen as they're reported by the AP.
Speaker 1: one thing a lot of people don't realize anymore is that most of the news you see from the mainstream media is either an AP wire or Reuters story that they rewrote a little bit to make it look like they're also UPI.
Speaker 1: Yeah UPI.
Speaker 1: or it is a story that looks like some locally produced thing But actually was produced by one of a few companies that they then mail out to all the news Agencies and they play them like ads but they make them look like they were actually from that agency.
Speaker 2: Yeah, let's say you're watching your local news, you know your your guy down the road reporting.
Speaker 2: You know the.
Speaker 2: it's only broadcast in your area of your state news.
Speaker 1: Yep a cat was found today.
Speaker 1: It was returned to its owner after a horrible ordeal on the street.
Speaker 2: Here's what's happening at the high school down the road, you know.
Speaker 2: And then you'll see like the cooking guy and he gives you like a five-minute cooking tip.
Speaker 2: Alright that cooking guy is on the news and like a 200 other news stations around the country He makes that news bit and then all these other You know local news stations buy that bit and put it in their show to fill up time.
Speaker 2: That's where that comes from.
Speaker 1: So where do we rim and Scott the almighty gurus of news gathering get our news many many places?
Speaker 1: I Personally mostly for geek nights, but also for everything else I read bark slash dot.
Speaker 1: I go to dig occasionally if I really need some news and Google news.
Speaker 0: I Fart frequent slash dot Google news Slash I said slash that already good game.
Speaker 0: I go to dig but I'm really good at figuring out what's good and what's not on dig.
Speaker 0: and Then I go to a whole bunch of blogs, but I don't go to like, you know, I'm some guy.
Speaker 0: I have a blog.
Speaker 0: I go to engadget or Kotaku which are basically just specialized news aggregator blogs.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: they'll go and find all the video game news and They'll take the interesting ones and they'll post links to the real news on IGN or wherever the real video game news comes from.
Speaker 0: Cuz I don't.
Speaker 0: IGN is not a pleasant website to go to no good God.
Speaker 0: No, yeah, and then they'll post a funny quip.
Speaker 0: So it is entertaining and also informational.
Speaker 1: See I read fart for the same reason.
Speaker 1: I remember.
Speaker 1: there's the whole balance between Accuracy speed and all that in terms of knowing what's going on right now.
Speaker 1: You know the breaking news like something happened.
Speaker 1: OMG as in.
Speaker 1: you know If something important is happening right now that you should know about.
Speaker 0: The
Speaker 1: fastest way to know about that in my opinion other than sites like drudge, which to me are a little too Jumping the gun a little too inaccurate or you know listening to police scanners all day Is simply to read Fark because whenever there's actual news it is on Fark within minutes.
Speaker 1: Yep, partly because there are Farkers everywhere and they'll post I just saw a building blow up long before the news post that a building blew up.
Speaker 0: one thing I got to say though about all these blogs I read is that you have to really read them carefully.
Speaker 0: For example, there will be a hot there will be a headline that says We price 250 and then there'll be a question mark.
Speaker 0: That means it might be they don't know.
Speaker 0: now a lot of people would see that headline and go Oh we prices 250 because they're dumb.
Speaker 1: I'll decode this real simply if you ever see a headline that asks a question that news article is probably bullshit.
Speaker 0: Well, it's just.
Speaker 0: it's just someone speculating.
Speaker 0: It's not actually information.
Speaker 0: The problem is a lot of people don't read carefully so they get the wrong information.
Speaker 1: well, not only that but most articles like that that ask the question like we $250 Sony going out of business Intel buying AMD.
Speaker 1: They're not actually reporting on anything.
Speaker 1: It's not even a rumor.
Speaker 1: They're just gonna have some op-ed speculation bullshit in order to get some ad revenue.
Speaker 1: because it's a topic That's hot right then and people are looking for news on it.
Speaker 1: Yep Almost always if you see a headline like that on the internet, that's what it's all about.
Speaker 0: So don't even bother reading a story that has a headline with a question mark.
Speaker 0: another thing you have to do That's very important.
Speaker 0: when you read a news article Look at what site it's on because when you're using something like slashdot or dig you're reading news stories from different websites all over The world, you know, so if they link to a story on CNN, well, that's pretty reliable.
Speaker 0: They link to a story on news max news max, you know Go, you know after you see the story.
Speaker 0: if the story doesn't seem too plausible Go to the home page of that news site and see what other stories they have.
Speaker 0: It is very likely that you know on the internet you will drive at news sites that are horribly horribly slanted.
Speaker 0: I mean Fox News, whatever.
Speaker 0: there are sites that are outright like Nazi news sites.
Speaker 0: They exist and they will say, you know, they'll have news like, you know Jews killed a million people today Yep, or like the Republicans eat babies.
Speaker 0: So, you know and sometimes those news kites that are just crazy Will have a news story that is a little bit crazy But you know is hits just the right nerve and ends up on dig or something.
Speaker 1: One that went around widely a while ago In fact, it went around twice.
Speaker 1: was this story that Bush had said to someone that the Constitution was just a goddamn piece of paper?
Speaker 1: Yeah now while Some people many people would like to believe that he said that and he may well have said it there was absolutely no Credible source that he actually said that.
Speaker 1: and all of that shitstorm Came back to one site that if you read it carefully was just an op-ed and didn't even claim that he said that.
Speaker 1: No, it was just blown.
Speaker 0: I was a satirical op-ed.
Speaker 0: But the point is yeah, but it was presented in a way.
Speaker 0: It was presented in a way.
Speaker 0: That's why it tricked me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I bring it up because it tricked Scott.
Speaker 1: He did.
Speaker 1: he comes to me.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: you see what Bush said I'm like because the
Speaker 0: guy he wrote an op-ed and if you look at it carefully you realize it's it's a satire, but he presented it as a news story and Once you click on the site, you could see oh, this is a mad lefty site.
Speaker 0: They were they just make shit up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz we're not.
Speaker 1: don't ever think that we would say that the left is okay And it's only the right who does this stuff.
Speaker 0: Everyone this if you go to like, you know If there's a news story that says Bush rapes, baby, and it's on buck Bush calm.
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: It's fake.
Speaker 0: It's probably not true.
Speaker 1: So hopefully the next time you see something reported somewhere you'll at least be able to tell if it's fake or not.
Speaker 1: Luckily, we haven't had I mean a lot of our listeners.
Speaker 1: you send us a lot of email Suggesting things the day in news and we read them and usually we you know save away or something We've already seen a little while ago.
Speaker 1: Someone suggested a thing of the day that in fact was a thing of the day four months ago, ah but No one has really sent us bullshit news.
Speaker 1: So maybe our listeners are really all awesome.
Speaker 0: Maybe they are.
Speaker 0: maybe they are but I have seen bullshit news post in our forum.
Speaker 1: true true, but they haven't sent it to us personally?
Speaker 0: No, no They have.
Speaker 1: I give them credit.
Speaker 1: plus places like forums are the best place because even if you're lazy if news you think it's shady Look in the comments of a site like Fark or slash dot or maybe dig but dig users tend to not really Research at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, look for me on dig.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but go to slash dot and if a store is bullshit There'll be a whole bunch of people saying it's bullshit right away.
Speaker 0: That's another useful thing.
Speaker 0: actually is slash dot and dig.
Speaker 0: they have these friends features.
Speaker 0: Now there are other uses of the friends features I'm not going to talk about but if you make someone your friend and you read a story you'll usually see their comments away way up top and that's a really easy way to see what people you know and trust say about the story.
Speaker 0: if they posted a comment and They're definitely, you know, if you're friends with someone and you're not stupid and if you're listening to geek nights I'll assume you're not stupid then you can probably trust that their comment is more accurate than you know.
Speaker 1: The the comment the some comment of the masses who I mean this assumes you keep the company of smart people Which I can't imagine why you wouldn't.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean don't always trust your friends say Unless you trust that your friends are smart.
Speaker 1: So the moral don't listen to us.
Speaker 1: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 2: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 2: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 2: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.