Speaker 0: It's Monday December 11th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk a bit about internet advertising.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Once again, we're back from a crazy awesome weekend this time up in Albany at the northern geek house with the Matt crosses.
Speaker 1: But you know what the next two weekends?
Speaker 1: Nothing, nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well semi nothing nothing big like not going to a party not going out of town or anything I think on Sunday.
Speaker 1: I'm like going to my parents house for Hanukkah or something, but that's that's essentially nothing.
Speaker 0: That's perfectly fine.
Speaker 0: on Sunday.
Speaker 0: I plan to go down to the city with Emily to buy a rice cooker Mm-hmm and such.
Speaker 1: you can come also if you want if you're.
Speaker 1: if you're back We'll see.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was gonna figure out what I'm doing over the Christ mass holiday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 0: I'm still looking cuz I keep getting airfare deals, but it's a trade-off between how much money I'm willing to spend to be inconvenienced by the airlines.
Speaker 1: Seriously, I Don't know if I were you.
Speaker 1: I don't know what I do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well we got a good argument with that right before we left the man cross party over the weekend.
Speaker 1: We did but pretty much it came down to.
Speaker 1: we agree, but we have very more strong-willed.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much half the crew is like yeah, fuck those airlines I'm not gonna pay lip service to that.
Speaker 0: and half the crew is like I want to get where I'm going.
Speaker 0: So principles not so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like we had the same principle, but if it was it's stupid.
Speaker 0: So I won't do it versus it's stupid.
Speaker 0: So I'll do it because they didn't convenience me inconveniences me less than the altar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in other words in the 60s you both would have been like, you know screw this Racism, but we would have sat in the front of the bus and they would have taken it and sat in the bag Except that we're white.
Speaker 1: Yeah that so except for the whiteness.
Speaker 0: so we got to sit in the front anyway.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: You got my point.
Speaker 0: I get your point.
Speaker 0: I get your point during Vietnam.
Speaker 0: We would have been across the border.
Speaker 0: Well Either that it would be in jail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, possibly one of the two.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I would have done.
Speaker 1: I know how many did it?
Speaker 1: Well, he got pardoned eventually, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, did anyone actually go to jail for a long time for draft dodging in Vietnam?
Speaker 0: Well considering they all got pardoned No, but it wasn't pardoned for years after.
Speaker 1: so I mean you could have been in there for like, you know a while.
Speaker 0: Well, I know a lot of them just stayed in Canada because Canada is kind of nice place.
Speaker 1: I know that.
Speaker 1: but the ones who didn't make it to Canada the ones who got caught and went to jail I'm sure there was someone.
Speaker 0: you'd have to be pretty dumb back then to get caught trying to get to Canada.
Speaker 1: I know I didn't have the highest technology for finding people.
Speaker 0: You could have probably just ran away to Montana and not gotten caught even today in this modern day and age Most of the US Canadian border you can just walk across or drive your car across.
Speaker 0: No one's even watching.
Speaker 1: Just don't go where there's a major road.
Speaker 1: if you try to go over like a big bridge or a real fancy highway You're gonna get to go through a giant block.
Speaker 1: granted.
Speaker 0: granted even as recently as a few years ago I mean I used when I was RIT used to drive back and forth between Detroit and Rochester through Ontario.
Speaker 0: see everyone a lot of people in the US and around the world.
Speaker 0: they look at a map of the US and The map usually leaves out, you know, Canada and Mexico And I don't seem to realize that a big part of Canada juts way way down right next to Michigan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are parts of Canada that are farther south than New York and Michigan.
Speaker 0: Yep, and in fact, there's a lid basically a nice land bridge between New York State and Michigan.
Speaker 0: You can go straight between the two via Canada Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And the last time I went the last several times I went the border guards would literally just wave you through if they were even there.
Speaker 1: Supposedly now it's worse.
Speaker 1: I haven't been in a since Pango cons.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, actually the very last time I went through Canada It was a pain in the ass Because they asked me a bunch of questions and they almost like they held me for a while asking me questions.
Speaker 0: The line took forever and now you need a passport to go across.
Speaker 1: Is that really true now?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the D day has happened yet, but they've started asking for him at border crossings.
Speaker 0: So say numerous relatives.
Speaker 1: But there's still places like out in like the north of North Dakota you mean the rest of the u.s.
Speaker 0: Northern Coast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know your coast northern, Idaho You can.
Speaker 1: it's just trees and then there's a sign that says welcome to Canada and it is trees and you just keep walking.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a little fence and a guy and he says hey, what's up, man?
Speaker 1: It's my job boring.
Speaker 0: Hey Hey, I can't really make fun of Canadians because they bring hockey to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good hockey.
Speaker 1: supposedly like a fifth of Canadians have something to do with hockey.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I wish my job had something to do with hockey.
Speaker 1: Oh shit ice hockey came up a virtual console today.
Speaker 1: I gotta go buy it when we go downstairs.
Speaker 0: Uh, oh shit.
Speaker 0: You just remembered that again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just remember how many times today if you've told me that that's coming out and I haven't turned on the Wii So I totally forgot man as soon as we finish the show, that's the end of the night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it might be right.
Speaker 0: so get into some actual news here.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much any of you know about arson, but for a long time these Arson that's when people burn shit down that they're not supposed to.
Speaker 0: yeah I see I grew up in Detroit now fire.
Speaker 0: when I grew up in Detroit It was a fairly bad place.
Speaker 0: Not as bad as you know, the race riots of the 70s and 60s and all their problems then but still I Don't know how because a lot of the world doesn't seem to have this holiday I guess and in fact in even in New York, most people really even if they'd heard of the holiday they never Associated it with the things that people in Southeast Michigan associated with.
Speaker 0: but there was a holiday called devil's night fire, which was the night before Halloween and in like in the suburbs of Detroit the Tradition on this holiday was to go around and egg people's houses and TP things and do pranks That it is a.
Speaker 1: it is a holiday everywhere.
Speaker 1: The thing is we don't celebrate it.
Speaker 1: So Seriously, it's sort of like haha.
Speaker 1: It's devil's night.
Speaker 1: Maybe one house gets TP low See even in the suburbs much more juvenile devil's night.
Speaker 0: There'd be roving bands of kids attacking houses furiously with chicken eggs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's much more juvenile out here where people are more civilized.
Speaker 0: Well, you see in Detroit, you know people celebrated devil's night by burning people's houses down Mass arson.
Speaker 0: lots of people got killed every year police patrols with riot guns everywhere.
Speaker 0: people garden their houses.
Speaker 0: It was actually a pretty scary thing.
Speaker 1: And then the next day everyone's happy and getting candy.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it was Detroit to the next day.
Speaker 0: It was business as usual.
Speaker 0: Yeah But arson was in fact when we used to live in downtown Detroit and one of the houses we lived in was fire bombed Not that long after we moved out of it.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh.
Speaker 0: Yeah semi randomly What someone bad must have moved in or something someone bad must have moved in you say?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure someone bad moved in.
Speaker 0: we might have to do Detroit week.
Speaker 1: I don't know much about Detroit.
Speaker 1: I never even been there.
Speaker 0: Oh Something if you ever go out of town, I think I'll do Detroit week.
Speaker 1: I could do a whole.
Speaker 1: we're gonna go out of town for a week.
Speaker 1: so you can do four podcasts about Detroit.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll just at least do Detroit.
Speaker 1: what anime manga and comics came from Detroit?
Speaker 0: I could think of some.
Speaker 1: what video games had to do with Detroit?
Speaker 0: Well, essentially Grand Theft Auto All right, yeah, but but my father also was a fireman.
Speaker 0: I come from a long line of firemen and I'm the first non fireman.
Speaker 0: and I mean I watched backdraft when I was a kid And I never actually saw that movie.
Speaker 1: I just knew it was the movie with a lot of fire and firemen.
Speaker 0: It's actually a pretty good movie.
Speaker 1: I don't know much about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's actually went on like the backdraft ride at Universally, I did as well.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Anyway, so, you know we talked about because there were arson investigations often in Detroit Most of which would go unsolved, but there was a science to it.
Speaker 0: There's always been a science to it and a lot of people have been caught convicted and put in jail for murderous arson and arson various fire related crimes due to the very exact science of Analyzing a fire and figuring out how it started.
Speaker 1: Yep They can pretty much go look at a fire these guys and say this is a gas fire It started in this spot and then this burned and then that burned etc, etc.
Speaker 0: well, the news here is that that science had a lot of pseudoscience bullshit shoved in with it and Recent evidence and recent studies have not only shown that many of the assumptions of arts and science were completely wrong But they've proven that a lot of people were probably innocent of crimes.
Speaker 0: They were convicted of.
Speaker 0: No, I was just gonna ask no Yeah They recently they've discovered a lot of like a lot of the quote-unquote telltale signs of arson are All I mean, they often indicate arson but not always and there are very very easily Happenable.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure where I was going with that said possible.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, I'm common Reasonable.
Speaker 0: No, I wanted to make up a word there.
Speaker 0: Okay, I mean I could go on with the ottel.
Speaker 1: ottel Your word is not polysyllabic so it's perfectly chromulin.
Speaker 1: not at all.
Speaker 0: Not at all.
Speaker 0: Not at all Defy you to deny the chromulants of the word happenable.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's not possible for me.
Speaker 0: fail English.
Speaker 0: So basically these people if you know, they have these telltale signs like if This happens if we find this evidence then definitely was arson because like the biggest one that I remember I can come up with I'm not I don't have the article in front of me.
Speaker 0: If a fire burns very quickly They would assume arson because fires can't spread that quickly without an accelerant like gasoline or kerosene.
Speaker 0: Oh It turns out there's a lot of situations where a fire could spread extremely rapidly and would look just like there was an accelerant But there wasn't.
Speaker 0: oh so Hopefully people who've been in jail Convicted of arson that they might not have committed will be released under this and I guess this Illustrates again the only reason I am against the death penalty and it's simply that I don't trust the legal system Considering how many times we have found a new science that then proves a whole bunch of people innocent.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, you know, it's all gonna come down to.
Speaker 1: do.
Speaker 1: you have a lawyer and did you hear this news?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what.
Speaker 0: the answer for me is at least yes, yeah, so if the house burns down I didn't do it Or maybe you did and you're just smart enough to use this news to get away with.
Speaker 0: What would I stand to gain by burning down a house?
Speaker 0: I'm renting for which I don't have renters insurance.
Speaker 1: You could buy insurance Huh?
Speaker 0: RIM bought insurance.
Speaker 0: his house burned down.
Speaker 0: six minutes later.
Speaker 1: I There's some guy out there who got insurance and the next day his house burnt down by accident and got busted at arts And that would totally suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you come home with your insurance check.
Speaker 0: your house is on fire.
Speaker 0: God damn it.
Speaker 1: Okay Apparently, you know it for all we know.
Speaker 1: at least until recently We thought that humans hadn't evolved in a long time because there really isn't any selection pressure.
Speaker 1: I mean people don't die that you know, whether you have a slight mutation this way or a slight mutation that way You're pretty much gonna survive long enough to reproduce Unlike case in point that case in point, but there are exceptions to that like sub-saharan Africa.
Speaker 0: there are there are but anyway.
Speaker 1: but anyway, they have discovered scientists who are all smarter than we are.
Speaker 1: a Recent instance of human evolution as in not long ago people were evolving because They started herding cattle.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, really?
Speaker 1: Well, what happened was people herded cattle which meant they had cow milk.
Speaker 1: now most people.
Speaker 1: The way their genes worked is they produce the enzyme Lactase or lactose not lactase.
Speaker 0: lactase ace means enzyme.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: I knew ace meant enzyme.
Speaker 0: That's what I was weird because music saying like oh god I thought of a cheesy poster for a science classroom.
Speaker 0: a big guy like a scientist with a beaker and his thumbs up.
Speaker 0: Enzymes, they're ace.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah anyway Yeah, I'm proud of that.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was great.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Your body produces an enzyme called lactase one of many enzymes your body produces and if lactose gets in you the lactase goes Hey lactate.
Speaker 1: the lactase says Hey lactose over there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what I'm gonna bust you up and it busted up so you can digest it.
Speaker 1: if you don't make Lactase which people used to not make it You can't eat lactose or else you get grumbly cuz you can't digest it and it makes you go all in.
Speaker 1: And that's what lactose intolerant people are like.
Speaker 1: It's a genetic thing.
Speaker 0: Most of the time Ah, if I was lactose intolerant, I don't know what I would do.
Speaker 0: I probably kill myself.
Speaker 0: I like cheese More than anything.
Speaker 1: I'm like possibly stab ice cream and milk and cheesecake and yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah don't like cheese sour cream Fresh all that good stuff.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't like cottage cheese me either.
Speaker 1: so it used to be back in the day that People would produce lactase when they were very small because they would be drinking breast milk and they would need to digest that when they Were babies, but when they were no longer babies their body would stop making the enzyme because no more milk to drink.
Speaker 0: Your babies can't drink this milk.
Speaker 1: Your babies can't drink this milk.
Speaker 1: when people started hurting cattle and Taking cow's milk They would drink it and people who were lactose intolerant and did not produce lactase into their older age tended to be at a disadvantage because drinking milk would give them diarrhea and dehydrate them and such.
Speaker 1: and there are all sorts of situations where Being able to drink cow's milk provided a significant genetic advantage such as oh shit.
Speaker 1: There's a drought.
Speaker 1: Oh wait, I could drink the cow's milk.
Speaker 0: So if there's a drought.
Speaker 0: You drink the cow's milk.
Speaker 0: Where's the cow getting the water?
Speaker 0: It needs to make that milk and where is it getting the water?
Speaker 0: It needs to to a little drought not a big to water the grass.
Speaker 0: a big in his little backyard.
Speaker 1: A little drought you say the point is over the course of thousands of years.
Speaker 0: You were fine And my brother and I were arguing about what we do if there's no water in the world and my brother's answer was well We'd fill the pool with pop instead of water.
Speaker 1: You had just the syrup though.
Speaker 1: The point is being able to digest lactose and Keeping that enzyme in production throughout the rest of your life provided a incredibly significant genetic advantage so much that 99% of Swedish and Dutch people All right can still produce lactase even when they're older and they're not lactose intolerant.
Speaker 1: Huh and back in the day everyone was lactose intolerant except for a few people.
Speaker 1: so anyone who thinks that Evolution isn't happening right now.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not happening right now as far as we know, but it can happen.
Speaker 1: It can happen fast.
Speaker 1: It can happen all over the place even to people.
Speaker 1: in semi recent times things of the day That was weak.
Speaker 0: What do you want every day?
Speaker 0: I said I yell something like things of the day or things of the day, and I thought I'd make stuff a little bit Whatever.
Speaker 0: cuz it's got to be annoying to hear me yell things of the day.
Speaker 0: You know what I should do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you just stop doing it all together.
Speaker 1: No, cuz we let the music do its own thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're getting a lot of new listeners.
Speaker 0: It kind of works out.
Speaker 0: What we should do is I'll take the I'll do one of those radio sound effects of the things of the day day day Right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day this is actually It came up on dig today.
Speaker 0: So many of you who you know dig dig all day might realize that I've seen it.
Speaker 0: But for a long time, I've been a big fan of the Upright Citizens Brigade and their particular brand of sketch humor.
Speaker 1: They are quite humorous Especially the episode with the holes in the sheet and the bucket.
Speaker 0: you can do anything if you do it through a hole in the Sheet.
Speaker 0: that's right.
Speaker 0: or the poo on a stick.
Speaker 0: Honesty a classic very classic, but there was one sketch that Scott had never seen and I would make offhand references to it on a fairly regular basis.
Speaker 1: and one day Scott asked me.
Speaker 0: what the fuck are you talking about?
Speaker 0: and I explained the skit and while it's funny being explained unless you see it, it doesn't really have the full comedic value.
Speaker 0: and Randomly today on dig someone linked to a video of the said skit.
Speaker 0: I Really don't want to ruin it other than that.
Speaker 0: It is quite hilarious and it involves a bunch of friends sitting around snowed in at a ski lodge or a house or somewhere Talking about the worst thing they've ever done that no one else knows about.
Speaker 1: Well the worst thing they've done to the other people in the room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, none of them know about.
Speaker 0: so, you know there's kind of a thread that links all of them together and Then the last guy has pretty much the worst thing that could ever be.
Speaker 1: I Could think of worse things but it's about the worst thing you could.
Speaker 1: it's gonna happen in that show.
Speaker 0: It does like it a little bit too fat.
Speaker 0: our door.
Speaker 1: It does quite like in itself to the Battle of Faradore.
Speaker 0: So you might you might be God that con.
Speaker 0: yeah You might be able to make an educated guess as to what the horrible thing is and all I can say is You might want to mix in the 13th floor with that I never saw that.
Speaker 0: You know, it surprises me how few people saw that movie.
Speaker 0: I mean it came out pretty much the same time as the matrix had a similar plot and as a result just no one saw It.
Speaker 0: when in many ways it's a better movie in terms of exploring that idea I'm sure it's not better in terms of awesome action.
Speaker 0: It is not better in terms of God.
Speaker 1: lots of guns Anyway, alright, so I was looking for a thing of the day and you know what?
Speaker 1: I saw lots of things of the day and I got one for like Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I got one for Thursday.
Speaker 1: Oh god, if you had a great one for Thursday.
Speaker 0: If you look in my dig and my delicious, you'll see more things of the day than I have days of the week.
Speaker 1: But I didn't have one for today.
Speaker 1: So I came across this one randomly and we're gonna use it.
Speaker 1: This is a video of the 2005 national hammered dulcimer champion.
Speaker 1: His name is max The B roll teller.
Speaker 1: He's playing a song called the apple juice, which is my favorite beverage and it's a song He wrote while he was at college now.
Speaker 0: This guy's fast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you don't if you don't know what a dulcimer is cuz I didn't know what a dulcimer was until just now.
Speaker 1: It's a musical instrument.
Speaker 1: It's basically a box full of strings of varying lengths.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a trapezoid shape and there are two types of dulcimers.
Speaker 1: one of them you pluck the strings.
Speaker 1: This kind you hit the strings of the hammer.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like a piano without keys kind of sorta like a piano that has a midget inside and every time you hit a Key, he gets hit with a spike and then he hits a string with a hammer.
Speaker 0: Yeah only without the midget.
Speaker 1: So basically this guy's got hammers and he's hitting strings with hammers really fucking fast like he should play his isle of phone or something cuz goddamn or a marimba or Steel drum because he can hit it real fast.
Speaker 1: Basically, you know if the song isn't the greatest song and the audio quality on the YouTube video and the recording really makes it slightly Annoying to listen to just because the audio quality screwed up.
Speaker 1: But just watch the guy swing the hammers real fast and you go.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: There is a man with talents.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: And you also learn what a dulcimer is which is also good to know.
Speaker 0: So today we were as always on Monday trying to come up with a topic since we didn't really want to launch into another series on how computers work just yet and We realized something that was actually requested of us a while ago and we can talk about an aspect of it.
Speaker 0: Very very Greatly and at length.
Speaker 0: We would like to tell you a little bit about the lost history of advertising on the internet and How it's not really a problem anymore at least for people like us.
Speaker 1: Well, mostly not a problem anymore.
Speaker 0: I haven't run afoul of problems in a long time.
Speaker 1: Well, there did you see just yesterday or recently they're putting ads and counter-strike, oh, yeah Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 0: I just won't play counter-strike anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, not the old one at least I don't think they're putting in counter-strike source.
Speaker 0: I think they know better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who knows?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: You see a lot of you today.
Speaker 0: Well, actually I noticed that many people I know or meet even geeks If I go to their house now use their computer and I go to a website like Fark or slashdot or livejournal or anywhere.
Speaker 0: There's a million ads flashy screaming moving around ads all over every website on the internet and It's always startling and it's to the point where I almost can't use computers to other people's houses.
Speaker 0: Because on my computer pretty much for the last eight years.
Speaker 0: I don't see ads ever.
Speaker 0: There's no ads on the internet.
Speaker 1: I also don't see ads ever Pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and The internet used to not be this way.
Speaker 0: I mean when the internet not when it first started but when we first got on the internet There really weren't ads at all.
Speaker 1: Like a website would have an ad at the top Yeah, I mean I would first use like old prodigy or old AOL and you wouldn't see ads.
Speaker 1: I mean Maybe they might advertise their own stuff like you'd be in one AOL channel and it would tell you to use another AOL channel Or to tell you to log in at 8 p.m.
Speaker 1: Because something was going on.
Speaker 1: But there wouldn't be ads like buy coke.
Speaker 0: I was about to say drink coke buy McDonald's food smoke.
Speaker 1: You don't even see those ads nowadays.
Speaker 1: I still have yet to see a drink coke ad or a eat at McDonald's ad in the internet other than the coke website Which is basically just a coke ad.
Speaker 0: of course, of course, but but yeah, they're really there weren't ads on the internet and All.
Speaker 0: of course.
Speaker 0: also there wasn't a lot on the internet.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I Mean most people would go to a small handful of sites Then they try to search for something on Alta Vista dot digital come up with 10 broken links Give up and then go to bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, imagine back in the day search engines.
Speaker 1: You said broken links.
Speaker 0: Yeah search engines Imagine if you went to Google typed in I don't know Faradore and the first three links were just broken.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, and the internet?
Speaker 0: I mean this there was free content and all the free content was either People in colleges with money putting stuff up companies trying to do goodwill on the internet or more often Geocities and fortune city.
Speaker 1: Oh Geocities.
Speaker 1: Yeah in those days.
Speaker 1: You could get a website for free without paying money.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's really limited in what you could do with the website given and you were given only a very small amount of space.
Speaker 0: I remember when geocities upgraded Upgraded to a full two megabytes of space.
Speaker 1: I remember when it upgraded to ten megabytes from two megabytes.
Speaker 1: That was holy shit.
Speaker 0: That was nuts.
Speaker 1: It was even more nuts when there would be sites like crosswinds.net would give you unlimited space For and it was.
Speaker 1: it was just the same Yep.
Speaker 0: But even then like all these geocities sites originally they'd made they'd ask you to put a little geocities banner somewhere on your site Saying hey, this site is hosted on geocities.
Speaker 0: in case you couldn't tell from the URL That was really.
Speaker 1: the first kind of advertising was putting little tiny thingies on your site like view this site with Netscape Instead of what you're using or the blue ribbon campaign one of the most famous internet campaigns.
Speaker 1: Yeah free speech on the internet.
Speaker 1: Whoo.
Speaker 0: Yeah consider this completely unrelated back.
Speaker 0: Then the idea that the internet was protected free speech was not exactly understood by a lot of people and a lot of municipalities and Even the US government many times tried to basically outlaw free speech on the internet.
Speaker 1: And would they failed because we were smart?
Speaker 0: Yeah But there wasn't really advertising other than people advertising things they liked or people advertising their friends or their own websites.
Speaker 1: And then came things like link exchange.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Do you remember link exchange?
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 1: I wonder what's that link exchange?
Speaker 1: Let me go look it up.
Speaker 1: You can tell people what link exchange was.
Speaker 0: You know what I'd heard of it.
Speaker 0: I avoided it at all costs.
Speaker 0: I really had no interaction with it at all.
Speaker 1: Didn't you see it on every single website?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I ignored it.
Speaker 0: see I was already back then jaded and even when ads weren't commercial.
Speaker 0: I ignored them when ads started becoming commercial.
Speaker 1: I continued to ignore them until it took me to Microsoft.com Small business slash hub really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, let me hold on Yeah, but I pretty much ignored ads a hundred percent up until I realized that with technology I could block them.
Speaker 1: Oh Wow, yeah Microsoft Okay, cool.
Speaker 0: Good game.
Speaker 1: So link exchange was this thing where you'd go to people's websites and you would see banner ads.
Speaker 1: They were thinner banners than we have the standard banner size now But they were quite kind of long and next to the banner would be this blue square.
Speaker 1: that said le for link exchange.
Speaker 1: The way link exchange worked is you would join link exchange.
Speaker 1: You would create a banner and put it up on the site.
Speaker 0: now these banners didn't move they didn't have flash They didn't jump around.
Speaker 0: They didn't play music.
Speaker 0: They were just a little picture.
Speaker 0: that said come check out my thing.
Speaker 1: yep, you would then put a link exchange banner on your site and What it would load random banners from link exchange and that other people, you know had joined and put them right in that little ad box.
Speaker 1: Then your banner would show up on other people's websites And I think later they changed it so that the more people visited you the more people who visited your page The more people would see your banner on other pages.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the Corporations hadn't really figured out this whole.
Speaker 0: Hey, we can advertise on the internet thing.
Speaker 0: So as a result almost all the advertising was just people trying to get their stuff out there in mostly non-commercial fashion.
Speaker 0: Then came the age of advertising where bit by bit Websites appeared that were free But they had ads on them straight up ads Like.
Speaker 0: I mean there were ad networks that were kind of like link exchange where you put in a script or there are web rings.
Speaker 0: Oh web, we don't need to talk about that.
Speaker 0: Okay, we'll do a whole separate show on that whole side of the internet okay, but ads started appearing like a company would advertise their hosting on slash dot or I caught some news site would advertise a thing on FARC.
Speaker 0: people would advertise their little shop selling t-shirts.
Speaker 0: and Then corporations started really advertising and filling up previously useful websites with advertising.
Speaker 0: garbage Banners got bigger and bigger and bigger different sizes all over the place.
Speaker 0: There used to be a semi Unofficial agreed-upon standard as to where ads went on websites.
Speaker 0: that went totally out the door.
Speaker 0: People would just stick ads wherever they could and it got to the point where eventually smart people said, you know what?
Speaker 0: this just isn't worth it.
Speaker 0: and a lot of people would either like turn off images in their web browser or Modify their host file to block ads straight up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz a lot of ads I mean.
Speaker 1: earlier There were a lot of different ad systems.
Speaker 1: There was like ads.
Speaker 1: There was double-click which is still around double-click.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had a fire there.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of them, you know But they eventually got pared down to just a few as they bought each other and died out and all that jazz.
Speaker 1: So you were able to use your host file to block just a few places and get rid of most ads.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: bear in mind also that while these ads were big and in the way They weren't animated yet and more importantly there was no such thing as a pop-up or a pop-under.
Speaker 0: No one thought of that.
Speaker 0: No one was obnoxious about it on the internet yet.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And then one day I was surfing with Internet Explorer because it used to be the best web browser around and This window pops up with an ad in it.
Speaker 1: Well people had pop-ups so they didn't use them for ads.
Speaker 0: they use them for piss-poor navigation.
Speaker 1: They use them for piss-poor web design.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we could do a whole thing about the early days of web design when frames were the almighty shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you think myspace is bad and it is.
Speaker 1: Go back to their late 90s and look at all the frames and pop-ups that were there on purpose.
Speaker 1: and there were parts of the website.
Speaker 0: Yeah Where a website would trap you like a website would have a navigation bar and if you clicked on a link to another site That site would load in their frame instead of getting rid of the website because they wanted to trap you in their frame.
Speaker 0: So you'd see their navigation bar forever Mmm, usually on purpose.
Speaker 0: It wasn't even people doing it by accident.
Speaker 0: People just didn't understand how to make a website.
Speaker 1: Well, they figured hey, this will keep people at my website.
Speaker 1: They'll remember to come back because there weren't tab browsing in those days.
Speaker 1: So, you know chances are someone clicked on a link that you're never gonna see them again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of websites had escape frames buttons on them where you could escape from other people's frames.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and during all this Pop-ups started appearing and more importantly ads that were either interactive or animated.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the animated stuff really started to get out of control when sites like was the money tree.
Speaker 0: Oh god, okay.
Speaker 1: There was a site and basically I was actually addicted to site for a few months Really?
Speaker 0: I was addicted to it for about 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: Well, it was because every day at school I had time to sit in a computer lab and those computers really weren't capable of anything except loading web pages.
Speaker 0: So you have to remember it was a different time you understand.
Speaker 0: Or 98 Where The dot-com boom and all these people running these ad companies thought that Advertising was not only a viable business method.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying advertising a product.
Speaker 0: I'm saying advertising in and of itself.
Speaker 0: They would sell advertising and then they would pay people or somehow trick people.
Speaker 0: Look at that advertising in order to prove to the people they sold the advertising to that it worked Because before with television and radio there was no way to really know how many people saw an ad.
Speaker 0: with the internet You could count exactly how many people clicked on that ad or how many people downloaded it.
Speaker 0: and the marketing people who didn't understand technology Thought that these were great metrics and couldn't imagine that they weren't so accurate.
Speaker 0: So it started turning into this thing where they would do anything possible to trick you Into clicking on an ad or seeing an ad Knowing full well that you didn't want the product and you would just get pissed off because they didn't care.
Speaker 0: It didn't hurt them.
Speaker 0: It only hurt the person's buying the ad space.
Speaker 0: so Dollar Tree Probably the epitome of this.
Speaker 1: Yeah dollar tree or money tree or whatever.
Speaker 1: the site was hundred from ever now but was a website where there was a tree a picture of a tree a rather high resolution picture of a tree for the time for the time 97 or 98 and the tree had leaves.
Speaker 1: but the leaves were dollar bills and you would click on this tree and each pixel of the tree was a different spot to click on and Only one spot on this tree in which you could click.
Speaker 1: there was a prize where you could win a lot of money.
Speaker 0: It was only like 500 bucks.
Speaker 1: It was it was money.
Speaker 0: It was a lot of money to me when you know in 1997 or 98.
Speaker 1: So you what you would do is you would click on this tree and then it would take you to another webpage and then a few seconds later, you would go back to the tree and click on it again and supposedly you would keep clicking on this tree until you won money and Basically you just ended up visiting their website many many times and making them lots and lots of money on ads
Speaker 0: because every site that Every page in the site had ads all over it and you'd look at these ads and the advertiser.
Speaker 0: Well the person buying the ad with the actual product didn't really pay attention Didn't realize that you didn't care about the ad at all that you ignored it that you probably blocked it.
Speaker 0: You were just clicking to get the $500 that you couldn't actually win.
Speaker 1: You could.
Speaker 1: it was just really hard.
Speaker 0: I never knew anyone winning that money.
Speaker 0: I'll say it straight up if I had run something like that.
Speaker 0: There would have been no prize.
Speaker 1: I also would have had no prize.
Speaker 0: There's no way to verify if the prize existed or not because I mean if you have procedurally generated content or something You could just lie Straight up and very well could have been a lie, and I knew that.
Speaker 0: yeah, we're not saying it anyway We're not we're not.
Speaker 1: it could have been real.
Speaker 1: It might not have been.
Speaker 0: who knows I was pretty sure it wasn't when I was.
Speaker 0: even if it wasn't real the odds of winning were so stupid You would have had to sit there Yeah, but there were also a lot of guys where they would pay you like pennies per hour To whenever you were surfing.
Speaker 0: run this program that would put banner ads at the bottom of your screen.
Speaker 1: There were computers that you could get for free But as law the only condition was that you had to have these ads Taking up like half your screen all the time and when those days the resolution was low So you were losing like a good quarter your screen space making your computer difficult to use.
Speaker 0: now this a correspondent entire cottage industry.
Speaker 0: People figuring out ways to run these programs without the ads actually appearing yet still getting the money and the free computers.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, the free computers the money the gifts all the points and stuff that these companies are giving away.
Speaker 0: You know this was when people didn't seem to realize that Advertising on the internet does not work the way they thought it did.
Speaker 0: no it didn't so then as ad ad revenues started Dropping partly because people didn't really click on these ads because the ads are usually stupid And almost everyone looking at them was just trying to scam someone out of money.
Speaker 0: If not just ignoring them straight up They started trying to trick people into clicking on the ads.
Speaker 0: They would start making pop-up windows.
Speaker 0: you'd be browsing and this window would pop up and the window Inside of it would have a picture that looked like a windows 98 pop-up window with a little OK button and a cancel button.
Speaker 0: But if you clicked on that it took you to a website full ads Great, or it took you to some company's product though see there was no spyware really back then.
Speaker 0: you have to worry about that.
Speaker 1: There Wasn't real?
Speaker 1: there wasn't super spyware.
Speaker 1: I mean there were some Java applets that might load and if you click yes They would fuck you over, but that was about it.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like it is now.
Speaker 0: no and right around this time is when smart people on the internet said we've had enough and shortly Thereafter pop-up blockers appeared now.
Speaker 1: the most pop-up blockers in those days though were crap like using them was worse than not using them.
Speaker 0: They just didn't let windows pop up which meant you couldn't go to most crappy websites.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it made it.
Speaker 1: nowadays They're basically no crappy websites that use that.
Speaker 0: so there were debates on the internet.
Speaker 0: You know pop-up ads.
Speaker 0: are they moral?
Speaker 0: Is it okay to block them?
Speaker 0: is it okay to close them.
Speaker 0: am I obligated to click on them?
Speaker 0: Webmasters would ask you to click on their ads.
Speaker 0: they would furthermore try to guilt you into clicking on the ads.
Speaker 0: There are people I knew who would say it's wrong to go to a website and not click on every ad they present because they Need that money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are people who would say that blocking ads was sort of like driving on a highway without paying the toll.
Speaker 0: The thought see that argument while I disagree with it was at least better than you were obligated to click on the ads of any Website you visit.
Speaker 0: not just look at him, but click on him.
Speaker 0: Yeah to me.
Speaker 0: That's just as dishonest.
Speaker 0: now You're just stealing from the advertiser because there's no way you clicked in good faith.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean basically what was in those days the only way to make money with the webs?
Speaker 1: because it was real easy to make A website relative to doing other work, and it was fun, and it that still is true.
Speaker 1: But the only way to make money from a website was to either Rob essentially Rob from advertisers people who wanted ads or sell shit and Selling shit was already covered by Amazon and eBay, and it still is yep.
Speaker 0: So you know this is a major all raging.
Speaker 0: and then some people got clever.
Speaker 0: they started having these Pop-unders that weren't as intrusive.
Speaker 0: they pop up a window in the background behind your web browser.
Speaker 0: So then at the end of your surfing session you close ie and there'd be 25 windows waiting for you.
Speaker 0: Great all of them full with advertising bullshit, and then one day this monkey appeared And there was this boxing glove, and it said hit the monkey win like $500.
Speaker 1: I think that had something to do with money tree calm.
Speaker 1: if not I'm not sure cuz my money tree calm had monkeys, but that the ad started getting straight-up fake.
Speaker 0: They would just lie and say Win the tic-tac-toe game and get a thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: There'd be a little tiny pixel of an asterisk next to that thousand dollars and on the website.
Speaker 0: It would say something like thousand Banana dollars.
Speaker 0: that aren't actually worth real money and can't be redeemed for anything While you're here by this DVD player DVD players.
Speaker 1: then If they were selling what it would have been a bajillion dollars.
Speaker 1: there were DVD players Which is like a hajillion bajillion monkey dollars.
Speaker 0: there weren't actually that much money either.
Speaker 0: it depends not really.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean we didn't have a DVD player But I wanted one because I wanted to buy the DVD box set of record of lotus war which was less than half the cost Of the VHS box set.
Speaker 1: it took up less space which is the biggest problem, but when I was a kid space didn't matter.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I didn't even consider the fact that I had to store all the stuff I owned.
Speaker 0: I did see I didn't.
Speaker 0: I had invented space.
Speaker 0: my room was big.
Speaker 0: I could stick stuff in the house basement.
Speaker 1: It's still a concern of mine to this day now.
Speaker 0: It's a concern hence.
Speaker 0: We're getting rid of all that old VHS action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway things went on and nowadays We have like I say there's like three or four kinds of web ads these days.
Speaker 0: what the kinds?
Speaker 0: I blocked the kinds.
Speaker 0: I block.
Speaker 0: and Google Adsense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which I now block.
Speaker 1: yep The kinds are really.
Speaker 1: they have.
Speaker 1: pay-per-click is where you get money for every time.
Speaker 1: so much so It's.
Speaker 1: it's really weird because there's multiple parties involved in advertising now like if you put Google ads on your site now You've got the person who paid Google to get the ad Google and you who's putting the ad on your website, and how does the money go around?
Speaker 1: how does Google make money?
Speaker 1: It's crazy, but somehow it works.
Speaker 0: kinda kinda.
Speaker 0: you see Just fast forward a bit you want to go over the all four kinds you came up with.
Speaker 1: I Think I came up with four kinds.
Speaker 0: all right because I mean all I want to say is that the internet now for the unprotected Is a sea of?
Speaker 0: Absolutely shit.
Speaker 0: tacular ads of adorning every single website in the world.
Speaker 0: yeah except front row crew calm Which has zero ads and will never have ads.
Speaker 1: no this pay by clicking this pay by impression Which is less often these days.
Speaker 1: There's just There's like straight-up time like run this on your site for a few months or like affiliate You know put this better on your site forever because we're partners yep, and then there is the famous pay by like Registration which is every time like this.
Speaker 1: These are actually the most profitable kind of ads which is why you see them the most often.
Speaker 1: Are the ads for casinos and stuff.
Speaker 1: or let's say I have a website and I put an ad for the online casino on my website.
Speaker 1: Let's say you click on that ad I don't get shit.
Speaker 1: Let's say you look at that ad I don't get shit.
Speaker 1: Let's say you click on the ad and then you join the online casino, and then you gamble $200 then I get like 50 bucks, which is huge 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have a friend who use that on his porn site to great effect.
Speaker 1: Yeah Because I think about it.
Speaker 1: you get four people who click on an ad in your site and then join an online casino And gamble and then you get 200 bucks.
Speaker 0: That's crazy Yeah, but I mean there's these ads everywhere.
Speaker 0: I mean if any of you block ads I Suggest that you turn off your ad block just for a day and try to surf the internet.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much intolerable It's painful.
Speaker 0: I mean even penny arcade has horrible ads all over.
Speaker 1: even dig has ads at the top really yeah.
Speaker 0: I really really really really I've never actually gone to dig without ad block on.
Speaker 1: I know that this actually this company federated media, they're they're like the Somewhat reasonable ad company on the internet That does lots of ads for big-name sites that we know.
Speaker 0: See I guess what I would say because I mean we didn't really go into a technical discussion We didn't actually go over the history We just kind of rambled about ads.
Speaker 0: but the moral of the story very simply is that to make the internet tolerable?
Speaker 0: You pretty much you just run Firefox run ad block run the filter set G And then you won't see any of these ads at all and they won't bother you ever again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean when you really think about it the Google Adsense Which doesn't have big images that flash and you know blink at you and all that sort of shit.
Speaker 1: You know people tolerate it just because Google was like.
Speaker 1: aha We can make ads that are not as bad as the other ads and therefore people will think that we're doing good.
Speaker 1: We're not actually.
Speaker 1: we're just doing less evil.
Speaker 0: Let me it's not really evil.
Speaker 0: They have the right to put ads on websites they do.
Speaker 0: I have the right to modify how I look at a website.
Speaker 0: However, I want you do in fact most websites I go to Especially if I go like myspace or something.
Speaker 0: I'll set up my web browser where it changes the background to black no matter what the background was.
Speaker 0: It changes the text to some lighter color no matter what the text was.
Speaker 0: it changes the font to something else Whatever it was.
Speaker 0: so I can just read the website whatever information.
Speaker 0: there was a lot of websites I block images from just because I don't want to not even ads.
Speaker 0: I just don't want to deal with whatever formatting or something clever.
Speaker 1: They decided to do well You're real broad brush of their ad block.
Speaker 1: Oh, you'll like go to a website, and if there's like one ad you'll say block every single image this website ever loads.
Speaker 0: Well not from the website, but from the if.
Speaker 0: the.
Speaker 0: if I see a domain and an ad came from that domain I'll block that domain at the second highest level Because I the thing is very few websites other than art websites have pictures I want to see.
Speaker 0: I mean I guess Fark has the icons.
Speaker 0: But even then if I block all images from Fark There's text that says exactly what the icon said.
Speaker 1: so I don't really need those images not really, but without them It's sort of more painful to browse a little.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, it's a little easier on the eyes.
Speaker 0: now a lot of people have tried to argue with me that I'm denying revenue to people But in the end I'm actually saving the advertisers.
Speaker 1: because yeah, you got to think about it We're not screwing over who we screwing over here.
Speaker 1: We're screwing over some guy who's screwing over an advertiser.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I don't I will say this right now.
Speaker 0: I've never in my life followed an ad on the internet with the intention of Purchasing a product or even considering a product.
Speaker 0: I have to specifically decided never to purchase products that might otherwise have been a good product because I disagreed with the methods of advertising like the X can.
Speaker 0: the x10 camera was a cool little product, but they Started the trend of annoying ads.
Speaker 0: they were the most annoying ads I'd ever run into and even though I kind of wanted their product Refused to ever do business with that company because of the horrible things they did to the internet.
Speaker 1: yep And they will forever be famous for spending too much money on it.
Speaker 0: So me not seeing your ads is a good thing for you as an advertiser Because I will probably like your product less if I see an ad for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean when you really think about it Right you've got let's say coca-cola wants to put ads on dig.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: if I block ads Well that means that coca-cola will not give money to dig Because dig didn't play the ad to me which is good for coca-cola.
Speaker 1: if I look at the ad and I'm not good.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: now I hate coca-cola, and I'm hating dig and etcetera etcetera and coca-cola has to give dig money.
Speaker 1: So really in that situation in which I don't block the ad.
Speaker 1: Dig gets screwed and coke gets screwed.
Speaker 1: well dig gets money and coke gets screwed.
Speaker 0: Someone always gets screwed because yeah I can't imagine many people who actually follow ads on the internet with the intention of purchasing products.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: it happens Occasionally very rarely like I'll search for something on Google like usually when I'm looking to buy something You know like I want to buy a product where can I find it?
Speaker 1: and then I'll search on Google for the product and either frugal will take me to the product page or The goo like it's something that's kind of difficult to find an online store for.
Speaker 1: it's like huh who online sells this kind of shit Yep, and then there'll be an ad for it on Google in the search.
Speaker 0: to me That's different because it's pull instead of push.
Speaker 0: if I see an ad for a product I'm generally going to dislike that product or that company because they had the audacity to try to advertise to me.
Speaker 0: But if I require a good or service I will seek it out.
Speaker 0: And if I decide to seek something out I'm gonna do all the requisite research.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna find the product I want and then I'm going to purchase it Like car ads annoying me more than anything in the world because if you are ever Influenced in your purchase of a car or a vehicle because you saw an ad for one That's really you got ripped off.
Speaker 1: Well, you know this could be in a very very small chance.
Speaker 1: You didn't know well that the car that you saw an ad for was the right car for you.
Speaker 1: There's a small chance of it.
Speaker 0: But if you're gonna buy a car you do research as to what cars exist in your price range And then you choose one accordingly.
Speaker 0: you you should be.
Speaker 0: you should be able to on your own find all the cars that exist in Your price range without having ads telling you they exist even when you're not trying to buy a car.
Speaker 1: Well the point of car ads is to trick stupid people into thinking that X car is cool Whether that car is in the price range or not.
Speaker 0: a reason I bring them up And I wish I could remember the article in.
Speaker 0: but I read somewhere that pretty much the primary driver In what in North American advertising is car ads like.
Speaker 1: far and away There are more car ads than pretty much every other kind of ad.
Speaker 1: yeah on the internet It's like our ads on the radio on television and then who knows yes current soda and fast food.
Speaker 0: But the article claimed that car ads were not just number one, but we're far and away number one.
Speaker 1: They're incredibly number one like by a trillion.
Speaker 0: Yeah granted I wouldn't know that unless I read the article because I you know don't see ads.
Speaker 1: Well I would have known because they used to see ads but not watching TV.
Speaker 1: I don't see him anymore.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 0: You know what a lot of people block ads on the TV, too.
Speaker 0: It's called TiVo or YouTube those things.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: do DVR is still successfully block ads?
Speaker 0: uh yeah But basically you have to do it manually, but you can always skip or fast-forward through the ads.
Speaker 1: So there's no more.
Speaker 1: there isn't a DVR available anymore that automatically skips ads like they used to.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We I used to have when I was a kid a VCR That if you told it to record it would figure out where the ads were in a show and wouldn't record them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wonder does myth TV still skip the ads it must write?
Speaker 0: not odd.
Speaker 0: I assume.
Speaker 0: so I don't know.
Speaker 1: yeah I got I kind of research on the see.
Speaker 0: the thing is all those things like myth TV and DVRs were made totally obsolete to Me by YouTube and BitTorrent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hate to say it.
Speaker 1: Oh well I guess If I had a lot of monies honestly that.
Speaker 0: and Netflix Yeah between those three I have no reason to ever get something off a TV.
Speaker 1: Well if I did have a lot of money Then there would be no reason not to get TV or a dish or something.
Speaker 1: and then I could watch Hockey's and f1, but if I had a lot of money.
Speaker 1: I just go to hockey games live Yeah, that too, but at the same time You know there's more on TV.
Speaker 1: You know you can't what if you can't go to the Stanley Cup finals the faraway?
Speaker 1: You know stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: playoff games You know go watch the away games of your favorite team because you go to all the home games.
Speaker 0: But at least on websites it is absolutely trivial to block 90% maybe 95% of all the ads that you will ever be encountered with with Firefox adblock and filter set G And you have no reason to feel bad about screwing the website that you're.
Speaker 1: no You know what because you're helping out the person who bought the edge.
Speaker 0: You can choose who you want to get screwed because you can tell adblock to not load the ads at all or to Download them and just not show them to you Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so you can choose if you want the advertiser to think your ad was shown or not.
Speaker 1: Usually they get paid by clicking though these days and not by showing so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a lot of people still go by impressions or at least they they track impression.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they definitely track everything They can and if they're going by click.
Speaker 0: It's not like you were gonna click on the ad anyway mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Oh well Ads on the internet are crazy.
Speaker 1: They've come a long way.
Speaker 1: They're still crazy, but now we don't have to look at them Now as one final quick metabit.
Speaker 0: I'd like to point out to all of our listeners particularly the 38% of you who aren't using the feed who are downloading the mp3s for geek nights Manually from the website every single day, and there are a lot of you.
Speaker 1: yeah now There's nothing wrong with listening to the show that way that's cool.
Speaker 1: You're listening to the show.
Speaker 1: We're happy.
Speaker 1: however There's a better way.
Speaker 1: There is a better way.
Speaker 1: subscribing is Beneficial to you.
Speaker 0: now one and we didn't even realize this until someone pointed out But the feed has all the information about the episodes.
Speaker 0: You know the title what it's about the track all that stuff is in there mm-hmm And if you just download it manually the id3 just contains You know the date information like when it was put out and when it came and what season it is and all that It doesn't have the titles.
Speaker 0: And we never noticed that because most people use the feed and some sort of feed pod catcher thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean even if you don't have iTunes and an iPod or an mp3 player at all there are pod catching softwares you can use like juice receiver and Doppler and it'll
Speaker 0: make your listening experience a lot better at least if you're listening on a daily basis if you're going through the archives You're probably better off going to the website.
Speaker 1: Yeah But if you're someone who listens to the new geek nights every day or once a week if you're you know just don't listen to Tuesday or just Monday or something like that you should probably start using a subscribing pod catching software of some sort.
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: Though for all of you who continue to download Directly from the website which I just realized one reason for at least some of that is that the feed only has the most recent 100 episodes so there are about a hundred and twenty hundred and thirty episodes that aren't in the feed.
Speaker 1: Hey, you want to know a secret trick?
Speaker 1: Instead of subscribing to the you know all geek nights feed if you subscribe to the Monday feed the Tuesday feed The Wednesday feed and the Thursday feed you'll get the past 400 episodes.
Speaker 0: basically yes You'll get the past 100 Mondays 100 Tuesdays hundred Wednesdays hundred Thursdays and when those fall off I guess in the far future will probably make archival feeds per season just for iTunes ease of use.
Speaker 0: But for now you got to use the website.
Speaker 0: so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna fiddle around with ID threes and Come up with an automated way to put some of that information in the ID 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably just write a little script that uses the ID 3 program or whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah So changes are coming.
Speaker 0: if you're downloading the podcast manually at least look into getting a feed catcher.
Speaker 1: You don't have to but try it out.
Speaker 1: You might not realize what you're missing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no benefit to us.
Speaker 0: We don't care, but it'll help you out.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all The RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.