Speaker 0: It's Thursday December 7th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and I'm rim and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: We discuss gift giving and receiving.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well seeing is how the first annual geek nights Well, not really geek guys, but front row crew holiday party hosted by the Macross is is happening this weekend.
Speaker 1: Scott and I went out to buy our gifts for the secret Santa that is being run and boy Did we get some awesome shit?
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean driving up the road.
Speaker 1: You know on our way cuz we have to when we decide to go Consumering as opposed to just our normal shopping, you know Like going to the mall or go into those stores that sell coffee in addition to whatever they have.
Speaker 1: It's a deal.
Speaker 1: It's a big deal.
Speaker 1: Like we get ready we go.
Speaker 1: We venture out into consumer land with all the appropriate weapons.
Speaker 1: We shield ourselves from the horrible radiation of edge with our eyes and you know as we were driving up We didn't really know what to get.
Speaker 1: we were kind of really at a loss as we'll talk about during the main bit, but once we got to a store and We started seeing items we could purchase and ways we could combine them.
Speaker 0: It really started to click Yeah on the way up.
Speaker 0: We said hey, why don't we go and check out that place?
Speaker 0: We hadn't been to in a while.
Speaker 0: or how about that place?
Speaker 0: You know because we got the road we want to.
Speaker 0: it takes a while to get up there like 10-15 minutes.
Speaker 0: So we want to make sure that if there's someplace to go up there We go there all at once to make as few trips as possible.
Speaker 0: And I don't think we're going back up there for a while.
Speaker 0: god.
Speaker 1: No, not until after the new year at least.
Speaker 1: I will not go anywhere near a mall from this point forward me either.
Speaker 1: But not only do I have my secret Santa collection, but I have an entire Presentation ready as I will unveil each item and explain its purpose.
Speaker 0: Wow I I just got some really awesome stuff and I'm not gonna make a present.
Speaker 1: Scott stuff is pretty awesome And I hope that whoever gets it will allow us to use some of it in some way for a future.
Speaker 1: awesome.
Speaker 0: I just hope whoever gets it appreciates it because I know some people would appreciate that sort of thing and be like ah Yeah, and some people would be like WTF mate.
Speaker 1: Well, you know it's like at my work when I worked at IBM We did a secret Santa thing for the department holiday party which actually that was a really good time hanging out with those people and I Gave see a lot of people really like alcohol there.
Speaker 1: So I got a bunch of Alcohol, but not really there was actually no alcohol.
Speaker 1: There were old wine and liquor bottles filled with water hidden in a bag.
Speaker 1: So it was obvious that it was liquor, but it wasn't really liquor.
Speaker 1: And hidden inside was an anime DVD.
Speaker 1: The guy you got it was kind of pissed.
Speaker 0: So in other words you were guaranteed to give anime to the biggest alcoholic there something like that.
Speaker 1: Well, of course the other guy who knows a bit about geekery and all that who actually ended up with the anime DVD his gift was actually The Star Wars Christmas special in the Ewok adventure.
Speaker 0: He is the winner.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone realized why that was funny except me.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they did once they tried to watch it.
Speaker 1: God I watched the Ewok adventure on TV.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Have you ever seen it?
Speaker 0: Kind of it's just.
Speaker 0: I know what it looks like.
Speaker 1: It looks like he walks.
Speaker 1: Yes And kids have an adventure.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so anyway, I'll let Scott do his news first.
Speaker 0: My news should have been a thing of the day, but it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: So you're basically getting two things of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had two news isn't two things of the day, but then Scott Discovered another thing of the day and there was no way to delay this.
Speaker 1: and in fact, I will say right now To anyone in the front row crew and extended front row crew is going to be at the Macross holiday extravaganza this weekend.
Speaker 1: You will not say a word about Scott's thing of the day to anyone Unless you know that they have listened to this episode of geek nights because I imagine we are going to attempt this.
Speaker 1: But anyway, Scott can do his news first.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my news is apparently in Toronto where you do not want to go.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go to Toronto.
Speaker 0: I don't want to go.
Speaker 1: children do not have faces.
Speaker 1: They have cigarette ads.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It is a bad place.
Speaker 0: And that tax on wicker goods, yes, I do not want to tax on my wicker good so I will not go to Toronto.
Speaker 0: I do not want this Unless it is this one specific case in which I would go to Toronto where they have not 100 not 200 250 no, but 1,200 people playing capture the flag downtown In
Speaker 1: in the streets running around
Speaker 0: as in exactly in the streets running around like lunatics.
Speaker 1: that sounds like unmitigated awesome.
Speaker 0: it Appears to be unmitigated awesome.
Speaker 0: It looks like unmitigated awesome.
Speaker 0: The idea is unmitigated awesome and for some people like us it would be unmitigated awesome But in reality it is mostly a fucking mess.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's that good kind of mess that involves the crowds of people out in the street who aren't rioting Exactly.
Speaker 1: I mean if you see a crowd of people in the street like a big crowd of people standing on cars yelling Especially in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Setting fires to cars tipping them over odds are any group of people that's yelling is trouble.
Speaker 1: Seeing a group of people yelling that not only was not trouble but was in fact Anti trouble at least as far as I'm concerned probably not as far as the authorities were concerned.
Speaker 0: Yeah, either way capture the flag is awesome for many reasons and we should do a whole episode on capture the flag because I could.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all I'm gonna say is that I'm watching this video and I'm looking at their rules for capture the flag.
Speaker 0: You know, you can only have five people guarding the flag, etc, etc.
Speaker 0: They didn't have the best rules for a 1,200 man game.
Speaker 1: They probably didn't put that much thought into it compared to the amount of thought that should have been put into it.
Speaker 0: This was actually, you know, it was probably a better flash mob an idea that it was a game of capture the flag And I can't really blame them for that.
Speaker 1: Well capture the flag in its purest form Really?
Speaker 1: I mean unless you modify the rules or Do something fun like full contact or make the rules very clear and codified as to what constitutes someone being captured and Exactly what you have to do to get the flag and all those sorts of things The game ends up being a very arbitrary messive.
Speaker 1: I got you.
Speaker 1: now you didn't.
Speaker 0: yeah The best catch of the flag ever played was at summer camp, but that's a story for another time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll tell summer camp was fascist about its capture the flag which Ironically was called revolution and they play it on the 4th of July every year.
Speaker 1: Ooh Yeah, we played a lot at band camp and when I was a Cub Scout at a Boy Scout camp once that ended it.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll tell those stories on another day.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah along with some dodgeballs.
Speaker 1: Now the sad thing is it said well, I guess it's good for Canada.
Speaker 1: It says a lot about the people of Toronto even though their children have cigarette ads instead of faces They all wear three-piece suits and they carry black balloons.
Speaker 1: But in Toronto the fact that this flash mob happened and the riot squad didn't appear I mean this shit would not go down in the US if you tried to get this together on the streets of New York or LA or Detroit
Speaker 0: not in a smaller city like a Rochester or Buffalo.
Speaker 1: police would be there in a second and even if they didn't bust heads thinking it was a riot They would probably cite you for creating a public nuisance or a danger or there'd be liability issues.
Speaker 1: You'd all get sued.
Speaker 0: I can almost guarantee that someone would be in jail not prison not prison But jail like in the police station overnight for a few hours Yeah, I would pretty much put the odds of that at a hundred to zero.
Speaker 1: yeah so I can use the nullity Right Cuz I got some actual news here.
Speaker 1: so a lot of us in the IT and CS world and basically a lot of people in the corporate world have realized that for the most part the corporate world is a scam in that your job performance is Generally tied to how many hours you work and how many asses you kiss as opposed to how good you are.
Speaker 1: Yes now doubly, so is the problem that let's say you're really really good at your job and They would give you an assignment that they assume would take I don't know 16 hours to and some and change full working days to complete.
Speaker 1: now Let's say you're an intellectual powerhouse and you complete that job in a half hour.
Speaker 1: Now in the current corporate world your options at this point if you don't have other projects to work on is to Sit there and look busy because if they know that you're not working, they'll think you're a slacker.
Speaker 1: They won't think oh, I should give him more work.
Speaker 1: They'll just think you're a slacker and if you leave early, they'll probably fire you Mm-hmm now and if you start doing things that aren't work, hey, they'll fire you Yep.
Speaker 1: Now a lot of companies handle this in better ways like IBM where I worked.
Speaker 1: It was it wasn't full flex time or anything.
Speaker 1: But there was generally this sense of show up when you need to leave when you need to if you get your work done.
Speaker 1: That's great.
Speaker 1: And that's all we care about.
Speaker 1: So you work long hours when long hours were needed.
Speaker 1: you leave early when you've done everything and there's nothing to do.
Speaker 1: Some companies take it a lot further and say that you can work whatever Hours you want at any time during the week as long as you put in your 40 hours over the course of the week.
Speaker 1: Best buy of all companies has taken this perhaps to the most awesome extent It could be taken and I will wait anxiously for the results of this widespread social experiment.
Speaker 1: You see in their corporate headquarters, they're experimenting.
Speaker 1: Apparently they've been doing this on different scales for some time with total flex time Not even work whenever you want as long as you get your 40 hours in it's purely.
Speaker 1: you have a list of tasks.
Speaker 1: Complete these tasks.
Speaker 1: That is all Wow, so if you decide to work, you know 12 hours Monday and Wednesday.
Speaker 1: get all your work done.
Speaker 1: Maybe you show up Friday morning for a meeting once a week And other than that, you don't work as long as you're completing all the tasks you're assigned.
Speaker 1: They don't care.
Speaker 1: In fact, they're heavy with you because all they want is the work.
Speaker 1: They don't care to have you in the office wasting your time and their time doing nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wouldn't If I had that job, that'd be the best job in the whole world.
Speaker 0: I basically do all the work as quickly as I possibly could working.
Speaker 0: You know reasonable hour days.
Speaker 0: if I couldn't if they gave me more work that I could finish in a few eight hour days You know from working nine to five with an hour lunch break, then there's a problem getting too much work.
Speaker 0: But if I could finish the work, which I bet I could I just wouldn't come back in unless there's a meeting and I'd wear some sort of Emailing mobile device to know if I had to do anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that's the one thing I miss about IBM that now that I'm working in other industries I can't really work from home and I can't.
Speaker 1: Most of my throughput and output is more dependent upon other people and them actually doing their piece of something than on my awesome.
Speaker 1: I can do all of my work in fairly short order and It would be great if I could just leave work early whenever I wanted but yet still show up when I need to do work.
Speaker 1: hmm and Best buy seems to be having a lot of success with this and I don't see too many drawbacks other than Obviously, you'll probably have some people who will scam the system and not do any work.
Speaker 0: You'll obviously have some people who you know You'll quickly realize people who aren't coming in don't have enough work to do.
Speaker 0: You'll give them more work You know, which is not the greatest always because you might give them too much work and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the way around that is say you've already got a level of productivity with your current In a I don't know nine to five eight to four hours.
Speaker 1: So you don't ever assign more work than that.
Speaker 1: You already have a baseline that works for your company.
Speaker 1: So by providing the flex time and asking for the same amount of work All you're doing is making happier more productive employees as a whole.
Speaker 1: I'll bet they'll end up doing more work just because they have the freedom.
Speaker 1: Yeah If I knew I could leave work whenever I wanted and show up whenever I wanted I'd be much less averse to pulling late hours when they needed it and just making the time up later.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm on the other hand though.
Speaker 0: I could see a problem in this system.
Speaker 0: You're really dependent on having your managers be smart.
Speaker 0: for example if we were managed by someone in a system like this and we got all our work done in like Really quickly and the manager was dumb and he sees that we don't show up for two weeks.
Speaker 0: He's like, huh?
Speaker 0: Those guys don't have any work to do.
Speaker 0: I don't have any work for them to do.
Speaker 0: They haven't been here in two weeks.
Speaker 0: What do we need them for?
Speaker 0: Let's fire them and then they've just fired the smartest people there.
Speaker 1: Well, see this what the smart people do is you figure out right away Who the smart people are in your organization?
Speaker 1: Who you need to actually care about and who you can ignore and most importantly whether or not your direct report boss is smart or not And you tailor your activities accordingly.
Speaker 1: if they are smart you do exactly what you would have done.
Speaker 1: Anyway, if they're not smart you uh pad it out and you finish the work, but you turn it in Way late when it was expected to be turned in and you show up occasionally and pay lip service to the fact that you might Be working.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just hate having to do shit like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you'd have to do it a lot less under the system.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 0: It's true and you know what the best part is.
Speaker 0: I can actually fucking get shit done like cleaning the house or Doing laundry.
Speaker 1: I get the feeling that people who don't do or people have trouble with work.
Speaker 1: You know people who a lot of people who do work at jobs as opposed to people like us Many cases don't have to do so much.
Speaker 1: They actually do need the full 40 hours to do their given job.
Speaker 0: Some people do.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: Think most of the people I've worked with in the course of my life have used most of the time Doing the same amount of work I did but they took the full 40 hours and I would usually do it in a lot less time Or they'd be really slow about it.
Speaker 1: Like we need this done and they won't just immediately get out it and finish it right away They'll be like, okay, and then a week later they'll look at it and then a couple days later They'll go out and look at the place They're supposed to do the thing and then they'll go to the water cooler and talk for a while And then they'll just do a voltage of BS and finish the work, you know a month later
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: I'll.
Speaker 1: literally if I'm given an assignment I do it as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: So I'm done with it.
Speaker 1: I don't have to care about it anymore.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I wish I had assignments.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually works really ramping up.
Speaker 1: They're starting to give me actual Interesting work to do.
Speaker 1: I've been rather pleased with this.
Speaker 1: I hope this trend continues until you finish all the work Yeah, but even when I finish all the work if I ask for more work I've been given it in recent memory You got to be careful.
Speaker 0: if your company just turns into a bunch of people who outsource all the labor You might end up doing the work of the whole company.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: then I'll demand a huge raise because I now have a high truck factor.
Speaker 0: I just demand to be to see.
Speaker 0: you'd be like I do all the work here.
Speaker 0: I should be in charge.
Speaker 0: make me the CEO.
Speaker 1: actually the CEO is pretty smart.
Speaker 1: I gotta hand it to him and he's here.
Speaker 1: Honestly, he's a lot smarter than some of the upper management.
Speaker 1: I have met in other companies.
Speaker 1: I've worked for.
Speaker 0: that's cool.
Speaker 1: So I have no beef with him.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't want to be in charge of the company because I don't know enough about business to do that.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you'd want to make his monies.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd be happy to be the CIO.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you made his money's like I could just stop working.
Speaker 0: We could all stop working and we could just podcast all day.
Speaker 0: We had bunnies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or maybe some radio station will pick us up and we'll go pro and that'll be the end of that.
Speaker 1: Well, I You can't do ten atomic sit-ups You don't want to do even one.
Speaker 1: So tell us about your thing of the day Scott.
Speaker 0: Okay, my thing is better than yours, so I should go second.
Speaker 1: Oh, you want me to go first?
Speaker 0: You want to do an atomic sit-up first be my guest.
Speaker 0: I'm not doing any.
Speaker 1: so.
Speaker 1: a small town somewhere.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna bore you with all the intimate details of this story because the overall message is the important part.
Speaker 1: The basic gist of it is that a town had a backpack mail system where kids going to school.
Speaker 1: They would come home like once a week with a folder with flyers and announcements and stuff from the town.
Speaker 1: You know community groups the city government all those things.
Speaker 1: they would send information home with school kids.
Speaker 0: when I was in elementary school We did that.
Speaker 0: you'd get all kinds of flyers that you would bring home and you know Most of them you just threw out.
Speaker 0: but some of them are important like the Little League sign-up sheet and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So a long time ago since this town is very small and super Christian and conservative.
Speaker 1: a lot of the church groups got together and along with help from Jerry Falwell's organizations and various groups like that put forth lawsuits and demanded that local churches and local religious groups be able to use this system because it's open to the community as a community service and therefore They shouldn't exclude religious things from that.
Speaker 1: the town caved in instead of fighting and just let them do it.
Speaker 0: See our town.
Speaker 0: I don't think religious stuff went out in the school papers.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, but this town allowed it under the guise of free religion.
Speaker 0: All right, whatever.
Speaker 1: That's not the story.
Speaker 1: this year A local pagan group decided to send out their flyer through the thing advertising a Yule Festival.
Speaker 1: for anyone who was interested in learning about alternative Cultures and the way they celebrate holidays around Christmas, you know a really cool thing for those types of people.
Speaker 1: the Christians in the town are Super super crazily outraged about this.
Speaker 1: Yes So the town came back and said well You're the ones who allow this to happen.
Speaker 1: either all religions get it or none of them.
Speaker 1: Do you decide?
Speaker 1: Huzzah, and that's it.
Speaker 1: I just find it utterly hilarious.
Speaker 1: It is not often that you see someone so duly and dutifully hoisted by their own petard.
Speaker 0: We should need to send out some atheist flyers home with the kiddies Except our town doesn't do anything like that.
Speaker 1: So we don't have to worry.
Speaker 1: We already won that battle.
Speaker 1: Hooray.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I had never before today heard of that which is known as the atomic sit-up and I am sorry That I have not for if I had learned it many years before if I mean if I had learned this in middle school There are probably like a hundred opportunities in my life to do this to people who wouldn't have known what was coming
Speaker 1: God and it
Speaker 0: would have been the most hilarious thing ever because I would have been the guy Who does the atomic sit-up to people?
Speaker 1: It's almost as bad as the guys in my high school who got people to do the elephant dance all the time.
Speaker 0: Where's the elephant dance?
Speaker 1: The elephant dance is too complicated to explain without diagrams.
Speaker 0: All right, as long as it's not as bad as the cookie we can let it go.
Speaker 1: It's nothing like that.
Speaker 1: All right, so Before Scott goes on I just want to say again to any front row crew members and friends We're going to be at the Macross party.
Speaker 1: Don't mention to anyone what an atomic sit-up is or act like, you know, and like it's not a big deal Because depending on the crowd and the circumstances we might attempt this.
Speaker 0: It'll probably require some people to be slightly intoxicated, but that will just make it better.
Speaker 1: It's Scott Johnson Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's not even gonna be there.
Speaker 0: No, he's not.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: So the I will describe to you now What an atomic sit-up is and you will watch this College humor video to get the full effect of just how hilarious this can be.
Speaker 1: you can't do ten of them.
Speaker 0: No, you can't.
Speaker 0: this is how you do an atomic sit-up.
Speaker 0: You're ready.
Speaker 0: first you find someone who is reasonably athletic and wants to take a dare, you know in this video They use military man, and you say I bet you can't do an atomic sit-up.
Speaker 0: and they go What's an atomic sit-up?
Speaker 0: and you can't eat a hundred peeps exactly.
Speaker 0: and you say this is what you tell them that All they have to do is do a sit-up while you hold their head down to the ground with like a towel over their Eyes or something like that.
Speaker 0: All right or a pillow on their faces, you know, not suffocating them Just like the top of their head and they you know.
Speaker 0: so you get them lying on the ground.
Speaker 0: you make sure they put their arms down on the ground and their knees are up and You hold their feet down like they're gonna do a sit-up and then you take a towel or a t-shirt And you put it over their eyes and you hold their head against the ground.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 1: so far so good.
Speaker 0: Here's the part where you trick them.
Speaker 0: You're ready.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: You can't spoil someone.
Speaker 0: a daring person hopefully a fat person fatter the better will stand and Straddle the person laying down and reveal their buttocks in a prime position.
Speaker 0: Then you say alright go and the person will attempt to sit up Not being able to see and you will resist their head with the towel or a t-shirt or whatnot.
Speaker 0: then as Their face is pushing towards the buttocks you release said shirt or towel sending their face into yon crack of doom releasing much hilarity for all.
Speaker 1: now the scream of humor and Horror that comes from this group of people.
Speaker 0: what you have is humor and horror.
Speaker 0: both are key.
Speaker 1: I Seeing this live is one of my life's minor ambitions.
Speaker 1: now, I agree though I'm going to go one step further and I think that perhaps the perfect thing to add to this is just the barest barest touch of chocolate pudding real chocolate pudding to the affected area so that the person goes.
Speaker 1: ah And I realized that instinctually I would reach for my face and wipe it off is kind of a I don't know primitive cleansing measure.
Speaker 1: If I was subject to this joke and I did that and my butt my face touched someone's butt in that manner You know the nose basically going between the cheeks I would immediately grab my nose between my cheeks.
Speaker 1: now if I pulled my hand away from my face and saw Anything that hinted at any sort of contamination of any kind I would probably vomit.
Speaker 1: This is comedy gold.
Speaker 0: it is comedy gold.
Speaker 0: indeed college humor is the win.
Speaker 1: I mean what?
Speaker 0: where the atomic sit-up this weekend?
Speaker 0: I hope not.
Speaker 0: I hope there are plenty of people who don't listen to this episode so that we can pull it off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so anyway our main bit today.
Speaker 1: we were inspired.
Speaker 1: I mean we had a whole other thing.
Speaker 1: we were gonna talk about Self-appraisal and how important that is.
Speaker 1: now a lot of people are bad at it and now there's scientific evidence Pointing to why people are bad at it, but I'm not gonna talk about that.
Speaker 1: That's too serious and real.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about holiday gifts because as we said before we spent the last couple hours seeking out Holiday gifts for a secret Santa.
Speaker 1: that is supposed to be funny.
Speaker 0: Well, I think there's a one thing that I really want to discuss and that Mostly personally is the worst thing that can possibly happen in terms of gifts.
Speaker 0: You see I'm not big on the gifts.
Speaker 0: I mean when I was a kid sure I love getting toys cuz I didn't have money and I you know.
Speaker 0: But now I have money and I buy myself almost everything I want so I don't care about gifts so much.
Speaker 0: However Almost the worst thing in the world is when someone gets me a gift that I don't want.
Speaker 0: You know cuz I don't want to return it and I hate being dishonest and Saying I like it when I don't because that usually means I'm gonna get more of it And I also.
Speaker 1: it's just like.
Speaker 0: I also hate being honest and saying this sucks.
Speaker 0: You suck buying me gifts when someone was trying to do good.
Speaker 1: It's just like the old episode of Andy Griffith where aunt B makes her famous pickles and they taste like kerosene Exactly and no one wants to eat him but then and veal feel bad.
Speaker 1: So they decide the solution is to eat all the pickles and act like they love him and eat so many of them That she runs out of pickles and isn't able to enter the pickles in the pickle contest.
Speaker 1: Therefore she's happy that people liked her pickles, but yet no one else is subject to them And then they won't have to eat them ever again.
Speaker 0: So she makes more.
Speaker 1: Yes She makes a lot more because they liked him so much exactly.
Speaker 0: So what do you do in this situation personally?
Speaker 0: I haven't done this yet So I don't know how it'll work out But I'm thinking about taking a policy because it works for my mom.
Speaker 0: Like if you get my mom a gift she doesn't like she'll.
Speaker 0: she won't actually be like, oh, I love it She'll be kind of like And no one seems to have a problem with that.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's cuz.
Speaker 0: she's a Jewish mom.
Speaker 1: I was about to say she can get away with it.
Speaker 0: It's because she's a Jewish mommy and somehow if you get her a gift she doesn't want it's your fault.
Speaker 0: So I got to try and make people feel like that.
Speaker 0: I got to make people feel guilty for getting the bad gift as opposed to Feeling bad when someone gives me the bad gift.
Speaker 0: I got to do the reversal.
Speaker 0: What do you think?
Speaker 1: See honestly That hasn't happened to me in a long time.
Speaker 1: I mean it used to happen occasionally when I was.
Speaker 0: it hasn't happened to me much, but it does happen.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is gifts have my.
Speaker 1: the way I receive gifts and the way gifts work in my life has changed a lot since I you know moved out of my family's house when I was in high school.
Speaker 1: See now I really generally dislike giving gifts because of a holiday.
Speaker 1: Like I hate it when I'm obligated to give a gift like oh, it's Christmas me I have to get you a gift.
Speaker 0: an arbitrary date on the calendar is not a reason that I should be somehow forced to Give someone money or goods or service.
Speaker 1: that it's more that I get people gifts fairly often.
Speaker 1: I like getting people gifts.
Speaker 1: I like buying things that people like or getting someone something that I know they'd like.
Speaker 1: but I Hate it when I have to give a gift when I'm not inspired to give one.
Speaker 1: I don't have a thing in mind already Like if I see something that I know someone's really gonna like and I want to get it for him I just get it like alright, this would be great and it might be like the middle of March.
Speaker 1: I don't know and I just give him this gift like hey check this out.
Speaker 1: But if it's suddenly Christmas and I don't have anything in particular to buy them It seems like anything I get would be hollow Because I kind of just bought it because it was the holiday as opposed to buying it because I knew it was something they really Desired.
Speaker 0: I think that's also partially because the holidays are hollow to us because we don't give a shit about them.
Speaker 0: But to someone who cares about the holidays the gift won't be hollow, you know I mean, it'll still be hollow to us because we'll still feel like it's a gift with nothing But that nothing when they get the gift will be filled with this holiday They care about.
Speaker 1: don't be using the royal.
Speaker 1: we here I as even though, you know, it's super atheist I am I still like Christmas.
Speaker 1: It's a real.
Speaker 1: it's a good time of the year.
Speaker 1: it always meant getting together with friends and family and having a good time and eating a lot of food and I don't even mind Christmas gifts, especially in the manner that we are giving gifts this weekend, but we'll talk about that later.
Speaker 1: yeah, well That's something different and like Thanksgiving I celebrate and a few Bert will actually only one Maybe two birthdays do I actually celebrate and no one of them is not my own.
Speaker 0: I'm not really a fan of birthdays either.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is and this will sound bad, but last year I Honestly forgot about my birthday yeah, and I just went to work and I did all my business and I came home and someone mentioned that was my birthday and I was like what.
Speaker 1: Oh crap it is Like.
Speaker 1: once I turned 22, I just stopped paying attention and I often forget within one year how old I am.
Speaker 0: I forgot how old I was for a while like between 23 and 24.
Speaker 0: It was like Now I'm currently 24 we're 24.
Speaker 0: We're almost 25.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be 25 in January.
Speaker 0: I mean 25 in April.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're young ins.
Speaker 0: Not really now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're pretty young.
Speaker 1: We're only a quarter maybe a third of the way through our life.
Speaker 0: It feels like yesterday.
Speaker 0: I was like, ah, there's no way it's gonna be forever until my car insurance gets cheaper.
Speaker 0: Now my car insurance you deeper in like five months.
Speaker 1: I feel like like a week ago.
Speaker 1: I was in high school thinking wow, the good days will never end.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine having a real job somewhere or having responsibility and it seems like five minutes ago I was at RIT going.
Speaker 1: these are the best days of my life.
Speaker 1: Fuck if they're ever gonna end Game over.
Speaker 1: See that's why we're doing this podcast.
Speaker 1: geek nights.
Speaker 1: for us is just a continue.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hopefully It's more like putting quarters in a different game because one machine broke.
Speaker 0: I thought we could play Dig Dug forever.
Speaker 0: But no now we must play Galaxian.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though to be perfectly honest I would say that my life and probably your life too are just as good as they were in college just in Different ways like some areas on the web graph That is our lives went down and others went up and the same area is covered by the graph.
Speaker 0: I like those other areas better.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: see remember what areas do we have now that we didn't have before?
Speaker 1: Lottie money fans every convention we ever wanted to go to?
Speaker 0: No homework.
Speaker 1: Remember as much as we loved college and as awesome as it was.
Speaker 1: Remember though when we paid for all that all that slacking off at the end of the quarter where there would be two weeks straight Of us doing homework and labs, you know, I just really don't remember the homework like everything was easy.
Speaker 0: Anyway, every now and then talk about some gifts some more.
Speaker 1: Yeah But it just it's hard for me to give a gift if I'm not inspired to get a gift like.
Speaker 1: I'll see something and think Wow, that'd be the perfect gift for so-and-so and Then I get it for him.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I did the same thing only don't actually buy it.
Speaker 0: I tell someone else to buy it.
Speaker 1: He luckily and I'm very glad that a while ago for the most part my family used to always send me cards and gifts even after I'd graduated college and Over time they've stopped doing.
Speaker 1: I mean I still talk to my family a lot and I want to visit them and fly out to Arizona and fly out to Michigan and have them come out here and all that.
Speaker 1: I talked to my grandpa as often as I can and I like my family But I don't like the whole gift thing like.
Speaker 1: I hate it when a relative I haven't talked to in a long time sends me a check for 20 bucks or Mails me just like a Christmas card that they signed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 1: it doesn't feel like that means anything to me at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah cards or something else.
Speaker 0: I mean my mom always see she's got like this hang up with the cards, you know It's like whenever it was any kind of thing.
Speaker 0: She would always call me and be like, you know, it's such-and-such send a card, you know It's such-and-such send a car.
Speaker 1: See I don't do the card thing anymore.
Speaker 1: Oh if I want to if I have a holiday thing, I'll call someone or I'll call people or maybe I'll give them a gift.
Speaker 1: But I'm never just gonna send it.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll write a letter.
Speaker 1: a letter is fine But a hallmark card to me is just like.
Speaker 0: well the most the biggest thing I have against the cards is that you're paying $4 for a piece of cardboard.
Speaker 0: some I mean if they're on sale $2 for a piece of cardboard.
Speaker 0: Now
Speaker 1: that's not to say that I haven't gotten some very awesome cards in my day But I will say that every card I've gotten that I cared about Wasn't just some hallmark card that someone signed like I'm holding one right now that I got from Emily a while ago and it's actually a whole letter in here just happens to be on a card and that is awesome.
Speaker 1: I but a lot of relatives seem to just send me a hallmark card with maybe a really lame joke on the front.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of the jokes are funny But if I wanted to be entertained like that I could read a webcomic or I could just go to the card store and read the cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean maybe it's it's the 90% of the cards are lame.
Speaker 1: See once I got to college I stopped celebrating most holidays other than you know, like around Christmas time.
Speaker 1: I'd go see my family, but I wouldn't celebrate Christmas.
Speaker 1: I just celebrate being with my family and that was the time I went to see them and then I moved out of college and I stopped even celebrating that I really the only holidays I celebrate are yellow the sky day international talk like a pirate day Thanksgiving because Thanksgiving is a holiday that involves eating a lot of food.
Speaker 1: That's a great holiday.
Speaker 0: see before college We celebrated a shit ton of holidays because it was a Jew and Jews have a shit ton of holidays Just so we can get out of doing other stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, we I mean we weren't.
Speaker 1: my family was very much not very Christian.
Speaker 0: if they really weren't Christian You aren't really Jewish except for celebrating holidays.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, it was the same thing like we celebrated Easter and Christmas and all those things partly because when I was young I went to a Catholic school, but we didn't celebrate him for religious reasons.
Speaker 1: No one said the word Jesus on Easter.
Speaker 1: They said the word Easter Bunny mmm.
Speaker 0: Anyway, when I first started going to college, you know, they tried to keep up the holiday action But they pretty much gave up on that pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: and now that I'm out of college I mean now there are some holidays where in college I wouldn't go home or anything and now I will go home because home is just an hour and a half away or so But not really any more celebratory in any sort of way.
Speaker 1: Well, I celebrate but I celebrate different ways.
Speaker 1: like this year Christmas I'm still seeing.
Speaker 1: hopefully I'm gonna fly out to Arizona to see my mom.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I thought you weren't gonna do that.
Speaker 1: I want to.
Speaker 1: it's just a matter of getting good airfare.
Speaker 1: If I don't I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: shouldn't you have bought the tickets a while ago?
Speaker 1: No, because actually deals flying out there on jetblue come up fairly frequently at the last minute.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh Plus the the real plan is because I haven't seen a good deal like even way back when I was looking.
Speaker 1: I never really caught The deal.
Speaker 0: you're gonna just have to shell out if you want to go.
Speaker 1: My plan and I've done this before is that instead of going out on the actual holiday when everyone else in the world Including all those people who don't know how to deal with an airport are flying.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go out in January when no one's flying.
Speaker 0: How's your plan?
Speaker 0: last year and it didn't work?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the airlines suck.
Speaker 0: Whose fault is that?
Speaker 0: the airlines?
Speaker 0: you for taking the shit airline?
Speaker 1: Because I'm not gonna pay I don't care how much I want to do something.
Speaker 1: if it costs more than $300 to fly somewhere I pretty much won't go.
Speaker 0: You're stuck in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Forever then.
Speaker 1: yeah, well, I mean, I'm maybe I'm special occasion like a holiday Like if I was traveling somewhere for a month, it'd be okay.
Speaker 1: But if I'm flying somewhere for a weekend, maybe a three-day weekend.
Speaker 1: I'm not paying more than $300 to fly there.
Speaker 1: I don't care what it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess that's all right.
Speaker 1: I mean I paid $160 to fly to Raleigh for an amazement and That really really sucked.
Speaker 1: I felt so bad about paying that cuz I could have driven there for less And it would have taken less time after all the delays at the airport, but I digress dun dun dun.
Speaker 0: I digress.
Speaker 1: gifts gifts So probably my favorite kinds of gifts to get now because I really don't give holiday.
Speaker 1: gifts are gifts for someone I really care about.
Speaker 1: that means something to them or to me or to both of us, you know like a gift that just comes up that's natural and makes sense or a hilarious gifts.
Speaker 1: Hilarious gifts are the best you see at the Macross party and it seemed like a lame idea until we all really got into it.
Speaker 1: We're having a secret Santa and being the front row crew.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna call it the secret Hanukkah, Harry everyone's putting a lot of Humorous thought into exactly what they are buying for this party.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean the problem is if you're not giving a gift Specifically to a person you need to get something that could be good for anybody.
Speaker 0: and that's kind of hard to do Because what's good for everybody?
Speaker 0: Well a book Even a video game a really good one isn't good because they might have it Yeah, or they might not have the system.
Speaker 1: now people might say oh a gift certificate That's perhaps the lamest gift you can give someone.
Speaker 1: that's worse than cash.
Speaker 0: better Give them money if you're gonna do that because at least then they can choose the store.
Speaker 0: I mean if someone gave me like a Walmart gift certificate, I'd be like, I'm not going to Walmart You just gave me nothing.
Speaker 1: but that's also kind of I mean just even cash is really lame.
Speaker 1: now say they were creative about it.
Speaker 1: Say the limit on the Secret Santa was 25 bucks and you give someone $25 worth of pennies.
Speaker 0: hilarious exactly.
Speaker 0: now see that's what it really is about gifts is.
Speaker 0: as a kid gifts are important because they're your Primary means of acquiring goods mostly entertainment goods that you cannot acquire on your own.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hate to say it but when I was a little kid Christmas was a spawn point.
Speaker 0: Yeah as an adult with money Gifts really hold.
Speaker 0: it's not like I need stuff.
Speaker 0: if I need something I can get it on my own.
Speaker 0: I don't need someone to give me a gift to give me physical goods because I've got them.
Speaker 0: so if you're going to give me a gift the actual giving of the gift has to have some sort of humorous or entertaining or Emotional value of some sorts, you know, like yeah, I could have bought it at the store.
Speaker 0: but because you are giving it to me at this moment of in time in this fashion and because of what it is and the method of Delivery we are all happier for it.
Speaker 0: And that is that is what you must execute with an adult gift.
Speaker 1: Yeah like I mean Emily gave me her old keyboard a while ago as you heard on the show and I've been playing with it a lot and I Think it's really awesome.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: I own a piano and if I wanted to buy a keyboard I would have gone out and bought one and I didn't really need one to buy it.
Speaker 1: But the fact that she gave it to me and that was a thoughtful gift and that I've gotten so much Enjoyment out of it.
Speaker 1: That was a good gift.
Speaker 1: or like if someone goes on a vacation and They bring back like a really cool little souvenir and they give it to someone like I bought this in London in a blah and it's shaped like a blah.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: That's an awesome gift.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of times it's not.
Speaker 1: it depends with the souvenirs because no it has to be a good super.
Speaker 0: Yeah Sometimes people go somewhere and they'll come back and they'll be like here's a t-shirt with the name of the place I went to.
Speaker 0: oh, no, no.
Speaker 1: No, I'm talking like the the DS eraser that you were given.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, little things like that.
Speaker 1: Like actually I remember when Dan went to Japan way back.
Speaker 0: We heard our IT and he came back and he got me just a little Totoro pencil board And I think he actually bought like a whole pile of cheap crap and gave different things to different people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as he didn't actually plan it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was still cuz.
Speaker 1: back then I didn't own any anime stuff I didn't have any pencil boards or anything.
Speaker 1: and he gave me this little trinket from Japan and I learned at that point that I really like little trinkets from Japan as you can tell if you look at my desk Which has almost as many trinkets from Japan as it does useful things.
Speaker 0: man trinkets from Japan.
Speaker 0: It's like I really hate getting useless stuff, but god damn you Trinkets in Japan.
Speaker 1: It's like give me a loose useless piece of plastic whatever.
Speaker 1: But if that useless piece of plastic is of a Japanese animated character, it's awesome.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's up with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no logic behind that one.
Speaker 0: It's not good.
Speaker 1: but I think really my my favorite kind of gift-giving is the humorous gift-giving, you know, the Secret Santa the Bachelor party joke gift.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a party joking.
Speaker 1: granted those can also be really lame.
Speaker 1: a lot of people go to like Spencer's and they buy like the over-the-hill toilet paper or the over-the-hill cane.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's the stuff that's.
Speaker 0: if it's a generic gift if the gift would work for anyone Then a lot of it is pretty much lost.
Speaker 0: It has to be like a specific and personal thing for anything to come of it.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like you got to buy something like ah, there's something about that.
Speaker 0: that makes it funny.
Speaker 0: Like if I bought a Pokemon doll and just gave it to you not funny, but if I bought you ten Pokemon Holding each other now that is something to it.
Speaker 1: That's that's probably the perfect example exactly or like in our group.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna do this.
Speaker 1: This isn't my Secret Santa gift, but I talked it up and I actually kind of got the benefit by talking this gift up.
Speaker 1: I effectively got to give two gifts because the comedic value of the gifts is far greater than the monetary value Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So my real gift I have and is ready to go the gift I talked about.
Speaker 1: see we have an inside joke in the crew about hobo wine.
Speaker 1: I think we've talked about it before Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: after yuko bought us some $2 MD 2020 that we all sampled and it was quite Ode hobo.
Speaker 1: It was really not good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was.
Speaker 0: I feel like drinking some right now.
Speaker 0: Just kidding.
Speaker 1: We've got it still Do we really?
Speaker 0: Yes, it's still good.
Speaker 1: I don't think it goes bad.
Speaker 0: Why has to go bad?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: might not refrigerated alcohol.
Speaker 0: We'll check it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know how we'll tell.
Speaker 1: Give it to a hobo.
Speaker 1: I know some hope but let's just.
Speaker 1: I got it.
Speaker 1: Let's just leave it on the street corner because those hobos walk by all the time.
Speaker 1: Let's see if someone takes it.
Speaker 0: We'll watch it where the camera some weekend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll just keep an eye on it.
Speaker 0: Let's go get a camera.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah That's the only thing of monetary value other than a Ferrari in a house that I don't have.
Speaker 0: and a new computer that I don't Have is a nice video camera because I have no clue.
Speaker 0: It's not that I can't afford one It's I have no clue what to get.
Speaker 1: But the hobo wine thing became kind of an inside joke for the crew.
Speaker 1: so I thought my secret Santa gift would be a ratty flannel shirt tied to the end of a stick like a bindle and Inside of it would be $20 worth of hobo wine.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of fucking hobo wine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you couldn't lift that in the flannel shirt.
Speaker 1: I could lift it.
Speaker 0: I don't know the stick would break.
Speaker 0: You need a big seemed like a 2x4.
Speaker 1: I got I had the stick ready.
Speaker 0: Did you really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, wow that stick I was I was playing with on the back deck that big thick thing That could do it.
Speaker 0: That would be kind of crazy though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but see the idea of that joke is really funny, especially to someone in the crew.
Speaker 1: So I already got all the benefit of actually getting that gift without having to do anything exactly.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, you don't actually need to give physical goods.
Speaker 0: That's not what it's about anymore.
Speaker 1: You know, it sounds stupid But it's the thought that counts is probably the biggest axiom of gift-giving in the world.
Speaker 0: unless you're a little kid in which case Goddamn it.
Speaker 0: You need some fucking video games and not underwear.
Speaker 1: Yes socks.
Speaker 1: Press a. what the hell is this?
Speaker 0: And I think that's the problem is you know Until kids until there's no more child labor laws and kids can go work and make their own money and buy their own games You we need to give them.
Speaker 0: goddamn gifts and if a kid already has everything well your kid doesn't need me more stop giving them.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I mean the the the sentiment behind a gift or the thought behind a gift and I guess now that we're adults matters A hell of a lot more than what the gift is.
Speaker 1: and as a result Instead of giving gifts we seem to have much more fun.
Speaker 1: Just getting together with our friends Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean if we could all just think of hilarious gifts and tell them to each other.
Speaker 0: That would be just as good.
Speaker 1: Yeah So we're having this holiday party and pretty much no one's.
Speaker 1: not many people are given.
Speaker 1: other people like I got this gift for you I got this gift for you and I got this gift for you.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: we're all gonna present our hilarious gifts to the group.
Speaker 1: Disseminate them however, we will and then play guitar heroes too while we're drunk.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Sounds good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you won't be drinking though.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: Ah, what if I get some grog?
Speaker 1: Some my hobo wine.
Speaker 0: It's all right.
Speaker 1: You tried the hobo wine.
Speaker 1: It was bad Real bad, I've drank worse things.
Speaker 0: I should go buy some grape juice In the bend the glass bottle and drink that.
Speaker 1: I got some sparkling apple juice for the people who don't want to drink champagne But it's sparkling.
Speaker 1: That's the point of champagne.
Speaker 0: I don't like sparkling.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: it fizzes.
Speaker 1: And what's wrong with fizz?
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's wrong with it.
Speaker 1: I'd like you to say it out loud on the air.
Speaker 0: That's what I was just trying to make sure that people understood that.
Speaker 0: that that you already knew.
Speaker 0: Yeah I already know is a it is not comfortable.
Speaker 1: So what do you mean by not comfortable?
Speaker 1: You're saying that fizzy beverages beverages that are carbonated in some way harm you.
Speaker 0: they do indeed.
Speaker 1: so you're saying that you feel physical pain when a carbonated beverage is placed into your mouth a Carbonated beverage that the vast majority of Americans drink on a daily basis and love.
Speaker 0: Many do yes.
Speaker 1: Yes And this causes you physical pain in a very small way But enough of a pain to where you refuse to drink any such thing.
Speaker 0: I'd like to avoid it.
Speaker 1: Okay, I just wanted to get that out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I guess in closing you can look ten gift horses in the mouth, but you can't fool them twice.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: Are there two birds in the bush or three?
Speaker 1: I don't know but I killed more than one of them with a stone.
Speaker 1: Okay, whatever This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.