Speaker 2: It's Monday August 7th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 2: tonight is a very special geek nights as we're not here And we're trying something very new.
Speaker 2: if this goes well this may happen more times in the future.
Speaker 2: We have some guest hosts for the show.
Speaker 2: Yes, we were just at Otacon.
Speaker 2: it ended yesterday Which means we are not going to be able to make a podcast today.
Speaker 2: So we are in fact currently sleeping on the beach somewhere in Wildwood, New Jersey.
Speaker 2: Yeah, if you're in Wildwood, New Jersey feel free to come find us.
Speaker 2: We'll be here for a few more days but regardless.
Speaker 2: Previously we offered anyone who had the ability to podcast the opportunity to create their very own geek nights episode and We had some takers our friends over at simply syndicated who made from the movies.
Speaker 2: You should see podcast which we have appeared on twice.
Speaker 2: yes They like our show so much that they decided to make their own episode of it And this is what you will be hearing very shortly.
Speaker 2: So first off if you are a new listener to geek nights You may or may not have found us through Otacon and all of the shows and events we did there.
Speaker 2: be sure to check out the website www.frontrowcrew.com And bear in mind that while all this week are going to be geek night specials.
Speaker 2: if you want to listen to a more standard Normal episode look for any episode that doesn't have the word special in the title.
Speaker 2: There are about a hundred and sixty of them out there either in iTunes or on the feed or on the website itself.
Speaker 2: also if you're Looking for our Otacon coverage It will be beginning next Monday And we'll go for approximately two weeks as we are currently out of town And we don't have the ability to upload let alone edit anything together.
Speaker 1: thus without further ado It's Monday 7th of August and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we'll be discussing stupid dumb Apple fanboys, and why geeks make the best boyfriends.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Hello everybody welcome to geek night hello.
Speaker 1: My name is Richard, and I'm Alison.
Speaker 1: let's explain.
Speaker 0: okay Let's do that.
Speaker 1: so at the beginning you had just heard rim and Scott explaining that this isn't a normal episode of geek nights at all.
Speaker 1: You know we are The guest podcasters yeah, and we are part of.
Speaker 1: we're not all of.
Speaker 1: we're part of movies.
Speaker 1: You should see rim and Scott have actually been on our show a couple of times anyway, so the chances are you might hurt them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hurt us hurt us indeed, so hopefully you did you know because they did some really good spots for us.
Speaker 1: I was pleased with them.
Speaker 1: actually last week's show last week's city of God check it out.
Speaker 0: It's a good show.
Speaker 1: We will plug later.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: We'll plug later, but that's those anyway Richard and Alison from movies.
Speaker 0: You should see.
Speaker 1: we should say hello to Craig Mike and Tristan who are also part of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they are.
Speaker 0: they should have been here tonight, but we have a little mishap.
Speaker 0: yesterday The clutch burn out in the car.
Speaker 1: well basically every one of us who owns a car has had it die in the last two.
Speaker 1: That's right, so nobody's going anywhere, and we didn't want to do this over Skype.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: No that would have been crap.
Speaker 1: so Basically, we're just gonna do a normal episode of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah excellent so shall we kick off?
Speaker 0: We should.
Speaker 1: so we start with the news.
Speaker 1: okay happening well this week.
Speaker 1: Top of the Pops.
Speaker 1: yeah a British institution absolutely played its last episode After 42 years, that's the significant thing I suppose.
Speaker 1: if you don't know what top of the Pops is it's basically a weekly music show That's been on TV for the last 42 years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where banners go on and they do the top 10 countdown and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: It's basically the the TV equivalent of the chart show they tell us.
Speaker 0: What it's number one on a Sunday and What used to happen is top of the Pops was on a Thursday?
Speaker 0: And it got you geared up and buying records ready for the chart to be announced on Sunday.
Speaker 0: so it showed you everybody who's in the chart showed you how many places that had gone up and gone down and It really was something that was really part of my childhood and my teenage years.
Speaker 1: I never watched it.
Speaker 1: You know really never once have I sat through an episode of top of the Pops.
Speaker 0: It was my entire week the focus of my week when I was a kid like 10 12 years old.
Speaker 0: I loved that show and it would be the one thing that was guaranteed that I could watch Uninterrupted in the house.
Speaker 0: that was my program, and I think pretty much every teenage girl That type did until something happened in the UK and music started getting really really crap.
Speaker 1: and oh you mean the late 80s?
Speaker 1: well yeah and Actually mainstream music the very late 90s up until now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had the Brit pop thing which made everything exciting again and And the MTV thing I guess took quite a bit away from shows like top of the Pops.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what they're saying.
Speaker 1: killed top of the Pops, and I think that's perfectly fair for them to say I think it's fair.
Speaker 1: You know who cares about a once weekly music show when we've got 24-hour music?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can get to see your favorite videos 25 times a day if you channel serve the right channels And so that kind of led to the demise.
Speaker 0: But my favorite days of top of the Pops were back when I was a child because you used to have these Horrific dancers on there were they pans people pans people.
Speaker 1: Let's explain about pans people.
Speaker 1: This is a very special part of our history part of our social history British culture, and it's embarrassing it really is.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they have kind of equivalent naffness in other countries around the world.
Speaker 0: I think we can get away with it.
Speaker 1: There was never naffness to this degree.
Speaker 0: right go on pans people were a group of Young women who were probably aged about 18 to 30 and and they were quite Posh, oh yeah like it.
Speaker 1: They were a bit poncy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were dancers and Back in the days before video promos were available for pop songs in the charts.
Speaker 0: These women used to come on and do very literal Dancers that were about the song.
Speaker 0: So you got some amazing kind of dancers.
Speaker 0: I can't remember what the song was but it had dogs in it.
Speaker 0: For some reason it had puppies in it or something like that and and sure enough They had puppies on the stage in their dance.
Speaker 0: It was just the most ridiculous thing ever Trying to get these shout suits to stay still while they're doing massive leg kicks and stuff.
Speaker 0: It was horrific.
Speaker 0: But I think that everybody loved him because they're a bit sexy really and it was the most leg and body that had ever been.
Speaker 1: Run she's thing on TV at the time by a long way.
Speaker 0: Horrendous costumes.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, it was horrific.
Speaker 1: You're probably Google pans people and see all of this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think baby doll 90s and that kind of thing very funny.
Speaker 0: You have to see it The facial expressions to go along with this song.
Speaker 0: It's just cheese on a stick.
Speaker 0: It really is expertly done, but that's kind of what made top of the pop so special.
Speaker 0: It was a very British thing.
Speaker 0: It was very British dance troupe and it it was just the cream of cheese.
Speaker 1: It really was.
Speaker 1: you see the problem.
Speaker 1: Here's an issue I had with it, right?
Speaker 1: The bands that play on top of the pops when they do so-called live Performances and doing the thingies with my fingers.
Speaker 1: this speech marks with my fingers the live performances, right?
Speaker 1: They're not doing live performance.
Speaker 1: No, they were at best.
Speaker 1: They recorded that performance earlier on in the day.
Speaker 1: But probably and I've seen this a lot.
Speaker 1: They sing the album version.
Speaker 1: They've blatantly just brought a CD with them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that, right?
Speaker 1: So they're miming and we know they're miming.
Speaker 0: It's happened by spectacularly on there as well where the dot machines Just gonna just sat there with blank expressions on the faces.
Speaker 0: the song plays in the background like what's going on all about Eve.
Speaker 0: That's who it happened to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, brilliant.
Speaker 1: That one's played on TV quite a lot is yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah It's just a nice little Example of the naffness of the program, but they're miming.
Speaker 1: we know they're miming.
Speaker 1: They know that.
Speaker 1: we know they're miming right.
Speaker 1: So essentially what it becomes is they're just doing a dance to their song.
Speaker 0: It's kind of we know it's like watching someone play a guitar.
Speaker 1: We know nobody.
Speaker 1: we know there's no music being performed in front of us.
Speaker 1: Nothing at all.
Speaker 1: We know.
Speaker 1: essentially what they're doing is dancing for us.
Speaker 1: They're just dancing in a way that look that they're playing at being a band But it's getting 15 year olds a chance to have a look at.
Speaker 1: well That's what it's there.
Speaker 1: Is it because the entire studio is there for you pay a fortune to get your song on top of the Pop so that it gets promoted.
Speaker 1: Oh, come on.
Speaker 0: Is it fair to say that?
Speaker 1: Of course, it's perfectly fair to say that.
Speaker 1: It's massively fair to say that because when will young one pop idol?
Speaker 1: Oh him there was massive Controversy over the fact that they were trying to pay for him to have two songs on the same episode, which no one has ever done.
Speaker 0: Was that a double-a-side job II?
Speaker 1: that was yes, right.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: He wants to get married actually.
Speaker 1: Oh, let him.
Speaker 0: That's what I say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's the?
Speaker 0: do an album?
Speaker 1: We should explain for anyone that doesn't know Williams gay.
Speaker 1: So getting there is an unusual, but he's allowed to do that here, which is special.
Speaker 1: Where were we?
Speaker 1: so yeah, so everyone who's on it is doing a little dance for us right from Christina Aguilera To the Gallagher brothers in Oasis.
Speaker 1: They're just doing a little dance for us, which is weird.
Speaker 1: I find that weird because again, we all know that but we pretend that they're playing live.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess Which is just crazy and always kind of made me want to buy songs a little bit more When I'd seen them, I want to see the videos.
Speaker 0: When videos first came out, they were amazing and you got to see things like oh god dire straits The MTV one, you know the money for nothing which was just the most amazing thing in the world when it came.
Speaker 1: There was nothing like that being seen.
Speaker 0: so so we started replacing pop stars with videos and you wouldn't get as many live Performances at.
Speaker 0: well not live.
Speaker 0: You get a video.
Speaker 0: you kind of felt a little while after you were being a little bit cheated.
Speaker 1: You actually want to see the band videos of the biggest cheat in the music industry Bar nothing because they're advertising to get you to buy the single.
Speaker 1: and now we're paying for videos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're paying to buy Advertising to make us buy something else.
Speaker 0: It's crazy.
Speaker 0: I'd much rather see a performer actually mime in front of me then see the same video.
Speaker 1: Dance for me.
Speaker 1: come on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what we need.
Speaker 0: I think you know in America with was it Dick Clark in America?
Speaker 0: he had like a show kind of like that whether you have a Band on and they come and play in front of a live studio audience and then you get to see it at home.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like, you know Just a live pop show and the only thing that we've got like that now in this country is like Jules Holland And he's not playing pop.
Speaker 1: He's playing the stuff jazz and blues Good stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the good stuff good stuff.
Speaker 0: My thing is right.
Speaker 0: when I was a child I thought I'd always loved Top of the Pops.
Speaker 0: No, I did because I thought this this rules and this is where music is.
Speaker 0: no, I mean, no you haven't always loved it I haven't always loved it.
Speaker 0: I fell out of love with it when I started thinking I can't cope with British pop culture.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's what's done it.
Speaker 1: in a final nail in the coffin in a program that only plays music you'd governed by What music's out.
Speaker 1: that's.
Speaker 1: if there's nothing good out there's nothing you can play and nothing you can do.
Speaker 1: so maybe again Simon Cowell the root of all evil in the universe where the shit pop music has destroyed Top of the Pops.
Speaker 1: if You trace every bad thing in the universe that happens it goes back to Simon Cowell.
Speaker 0: You really don't like him.
Speaker 1: everything everything pick anything you want I will trace it back to Simon Cowell and the decline of the British pop music industry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely very orange.
Speaker 1: He is and his waistband is far too high.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: And he's a No I just opposed him generally and everything about him, but enough enough.
Speaker 1: Jimmy Saville, sir Jimmy said night of the realm who?
Speaker 1: Introduced the very first Top of the Pops episode for two years ago The Top of the Pops God Stone's right-wing Moron, I love Jimmy Saville for one reason one reason alone.
Speaker 0: He's the first man to get two turntables and Put two records on and try and play them simultaneously.
Speaker 0: So he's the first ever proper turntable DJ.
Speaker 0: it lasted for one song and the entire equipment blew up.
Speaker 0: and it was Upstairs at the Otley working men's club in Leeds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it happened in 1962.
Speaker 0: I believe that's amazing.
Speaker 0: So for that reason alone, Jimmy Saville.
Speaker 1: Yeah God the oldest man still smoking cigars Since what's his name died?
Speaker 1: Who?
Speaker 1: that is not famous cigar smoke the cigar smoking comedian very much know after him.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Bob Hope know after him.
Speaker 1: maybe I don't know Should have thought that through more before I started saying it But he he was the guy who turned out the lights on the last episode in only the crap way the BBC could do.
Speaker 1: How should we finish it?
Speaker 1: We'll wait till the opening the closing credits have finished and we'll have sir.
Speaker 1: Jimmy turn the lights Actually filling up.
Speaker 1: I didn't see it, but you can imagine it.
Speaker 1: Can you?
Speaker 0: yeah I'm quite upset by this little frail old man in his running suit.
Speaker 0: And he's got a running suit and he's jangly jangly jewelry jewelry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all of that and his cigar turning the lights out.
Speaker 1: It's over now.
Speaker 1: That's probably Dyson.
Speaker 1: That's really sad very very old though, so well it would just be time but looking at his picture I think he is dead.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, he's missed his mom since she went the old Duchess 40 years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's mr.
Speaker 0: A lot, you know.
Speaker 1: As he said sir, Jimmy said top of the pops belongs to the world now.
Speaker 0: It does what?
Speaker 1: How does that mean?
Speaker 0: Cash mine back to all those wonderful top of the pop seam jeans that you've only had.
Speaker 0: Paul had.
Speaker 0: castles top of the pop seam Will stay in my head forever and ever and ever.
Speaker 1: amen fair enough.
Speaker 1: I can't remember any of them.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I can.
Speaker 1: I can know I'm thinking about and remember all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, nevermind get that It was a wicked show and I'm I'm gonna miss it retrospectively seen as I stopped watching it about ten years ago.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm just old.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah middle-aged old me.
Speaker 1: Oh looking at this news report going back to the crap music I think it's worth noting that the last song played on top of the pops was Shakira.
Speaker 1: Shakira and Wyclef Jean's hips.
Speaker 0: don't lie hips.
Speaker 0: Don't lie.
Speaker 1: There's a mark of good music.
Speaker 1: It's good, isn't it?
Speaker 0: Here tell me I had too many pies And they're not lying.
Speaker 1: I'm too gentlemanly to agree with him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you're not gentlemanly enough not to laugh.
Speaker 1: It's hard not to laugh.
Speaker 1: Let's move on moving on Things of the day.
Speaker 0: That's so exciting.
Speaker 0: I am so here so excited by that little piece of music.
Speaker 1: It's incredible.
Speaker 0: It's wicked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: I have to confess right the first episode of geek nights.
Speaker 1: I ever listened to.
Speaker 1: yeah The thing that I actually enjoyed the most Was the closing credits music really?
Speaker 1: I Don't mean that like when I joke the film is really bad and I say that the best bit was when it faded to black.
Speaker 1: Okay, I mean actually the music.
Speaker 1: I really enjoyed it really.
Speaker 0: I really like that.
Speaker 1: I can't ask them more about where it comes from.
Speaker 0: Okay, so my thing of the day your thing of the day is this really cool little video.
Speaker 1: Have you got the link prepared for it on YouTube?
Speaker 1: Let me do you know what it?
Speaker 1: no Hang on, you know what the video is called.
Speaker 1: Well, that'll do.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: I'm being overly cautious.
Speaker 0: Oh This little video is entitled collaboration 2001.
Speaker 0: I must stress that the collaboration is spelled with a K.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's good.
Speaker 0: Right and And and 2001. there's quite a few files on there from collaboration.
Speaker 0: It seems to me I don't really know but it looks like a Korean sort of youth culture festival Korean American youth culture festival Where they go and they do street dance and that kind of thing and generally have a good time and show off their mad skills.
Speaker 0: and this little clip is of Three guys who do some body popping.
Speaker 1: It's yeah, it's body popping.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what we call it.
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 1: I don't know Robotic dancing.
Speaker 0: I'm calling it body popping because I don't know what else to call it.
Speaker 1: You see we say body popping and I think Back in the 80s with all the pop in the color Which is a little bit of it is in there, but this is a master class.
Speaker 0: There's two guys who were on first and you think they're all right.
Speaker 0: You think they're pretty good.
Speaker 0: They've got some moves and stuff and then this guy called Nathan from Santa Anna Comes on and just throws down the maddest moves I've ever seen a human being contort themselves into.
Speaker 1: this is certainly something that has to be seen to be believed.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think the guy's body is amazing.
Speaker 0: He can command it to do pretty much what he wants to do and he goes up from being like a solid piece of wood To something that's liquid and melting.
Speaker 0: He's Absolutely astounding and I've seen it so many times now, but the guy just makes me go Every time I see it, it's awesome.
Speaker 1: It is it's just amazing.
Speaker 1: I want to say something more intelligent about it than it's just amazing.
Speaker 1: You do get the feeling that this kid might have been in some kind of accident or something.
Speaker 1: I can understand the how I can't make my body do the robot bit and the dancing Yeah, but when he just try when he just puts himself into a position like when he does that bit with his shoulders Yeah, I think well, why can't I do that?
Speaker 1: Cuz what is it about your body that mine doesn't have?
Speaker 1: or mine has that yours doesn't?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's that I love this bit.
Speaker 0: You'll know it when you see it that he kind of makes like there's something underneath his jumper.
Speaker 1: See, that's clever.
Speaker 1: That's skillful.
Speaker 1: I get that.
Speaker 1: I can't do that.
Speaker 1: I'm happy with that.
Speaker 1: That's okay But you know the bit.
Speaker 1: why can his body do things?
Speaker 1: mine can't.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: he's built in a strange way.
Speaker 0: He's a tall thin guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, very lean and he's got huge broad shoulders.
Speaker 0: He's probably only about 15.
Speaker 0: That's a shocking thing about this guy.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's what it is.
Speaker 1: I'm just too old and creaky and sort of Arthritis II.
Speaker 0: he's quite tall compared to the compare as well.
Speaker 0: Who's clearly an adult and he's not.
Speaker 0: he's a child.
Speaker 0: He's holding himself like a child.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you just know that Nathan from Santa Anna has been popping these moves in his bedroom for months Before he went to that Something I don't know.
Speaker 1: Good money to see him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hope he's still dancing cuz that might buy can move.
Speaker 0: he can mold his body wherever he wants it.
Speaker 1: It's a shame top of the pops is finished.
Speaker 0: It is he should have been on there.
Speaker 0: He should have been one of Pam's people in a little baby.
Speaker 1: Don't know that Embryo at the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not not even that.
Speaker 1: Not not even a sperm.
Speaker 0: I could see him in a Southwestern with an umbrella.
Speaker 1: enough of them enough of those pans people.
Speaker 1: But yeah, yeah, you should check this out.
Speaker 1: What's it called again?
Speaker 0: Collaboration spelt with a K 2001. these are the files on there as well of other kids doing you know real skillful stuff, but Nathan from Santa Anna he rocks.
Speaker 0: He's my favorite.
Speaker 1: Do we know where that is Santa Anna?
Speaker 0: It's I don't know.
Speaker 1: Do you even know what accent you're doing when Santa Anna?
Speaker 0: It's the man who's on the stage.
Speaker 0: Okay I don't know where it is.
Speaker 0: I guess some people in America might know where Santa Anna.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we don't.
Speaker 0: okay, it's not near how us.
Speaker 1: no, no Let's move on then.
Speaker 1: Okay, my thing is what you got now.
Speaker 1: This is something that It's actually to me.
Speaker 1: it's a video of everything that is wrong in the world today.
Speaker 1: I Think You know say never mind Simon Cowell ignore him.
Speaker 1: I think what this video shows is just the problem with the world as it is and that is I Don't know fucked up middle-class white boys.
Speaker 0: You think they're middle-class.
Speaker 0: I got a video camera from somewhere and I say I don't think they're middle-class.
Speaker 1: you see I look at them.
Speaker 1: I think your mum's an accountant your dad is a doctor and you don't like it.
Speaker 0: You see I don't get that at all.
Speaker 0: I get parents are divorced Dad's not at home They're doing spliffs and fat since they were about 12.
Speaker 0: They've got no prospects No, hope in life.
Speaker 0: and this is literally them with a borrowed mates all stolen Come card.
Speaker 1: These are the kids that are gonna rob our kids in 20 years, aren't they?
Speaker 0: Yes, dear.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: It's all kids like them.
Speaker 0: Let's say that kids very like them.
Speaker 0: Mmm, because we're talking about a particular subset of British culture here that is known as a chav We should explain the chav.
Speaker 0: We should.
Speaker 0: There's a really really good website Call.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah chav town.com that chav chav chav and it will tell you all about what a chav is what they wear how they speak where they go what they buy and the rest of it.
Speaker 0: it's an entire subculture and These choice young gentlemen that you have a particularly fine examples of breed.
Speaker 1: Yes It's.
Speaker 1: it's part of believing that.
Speaker 1: well Maybe that you're better at something than you perhaps are.
Speaker 0: I think It's a striving of getting out of the crappy shitty life that you live because let's not make any bonds about it.
Speaker 0: I think these guys are poor and I think they come from a poor background and it's about striving to get out.
Speaker 1: We've not even said what they do yet.
Speaker 1: That's my fault.
Speaker 1: I apologise.
Speaker 0: This is funny.
Speaker 0: They're rapping.
Speaker 1: It's basically a video of three kids Rapping.
Speaker 1: they're called the kersal massive k-e-r-s-a-l massive.
Speaker 1: They're three of them and in actual fact they're quite, that's massive.
Speaker 1: They're quite small as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean especially what's his name?
Speaker 0: little Kev not Kev our little Kev.
Speaker 0: He's about 12 so we can deduce from the little video that we've got.
Speaker 1: but this is a prime example of what happens when you give everyone a voice and As wonderful a thing as that is that we have the freedom in the world for everyone to have a voice.
Speaker 1: We realize perhaps that not many people have a great deal to say yet say it anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's what this shows.
Speaker 1: I think You know, I get the whole being poor and rapping your way out of the ghetto Whatever not that they live in a ghetto.
Speaker 0: These guys are not three M&Ms.
Speaker 1: M&M can do such a thing because the man is actually to be fair.
Speaker 1: whether you write like rap music or not He's shit out of what he does.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, I couldn't do that.
Speaker 1: He's not in a million years.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: You've got my time.
Speaker 0: These guys do this isn't M&M style rap?
Speaker 0: This isn't like that kind of American twang rap that you know, no these guys are rapping with black British accents Which just makes it even funnier cuz they're talking in it.
Speaker 0: Is it all that kind of crap?
Speaker 1: This is this is part of the most annoying thing that is happening in this country at the moment.
Speaker 1: Is this this overbearing need to respond to any part of conversation with the words?
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 1: is it hello?
Speaker 1: Is it no what it's always questions.
Speaker 0: Example was that girl when I asked her where she worked and she says I'll work on one just the road daughter Dora, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I asked you.
Speaker 0: weird anyway But that's the kind of language that these kids talking.
Speaker 0: it's not like an American rappers Hip-hop accent.
Speaker 0: It's black British hip-hop accent, and it's very silly.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing that winds me up about it is that it's totally made up.
Speaker 1: It's not like it is completely Made up and it's not like these people actually have these accents or actually come from a culture like that In the backseat, yeah, cuz I ain't they're not even old enough to drive a car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're talking about the mom's clear at one point and I mean we're talking Shop a car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he opens up by talking about getting on the bus with this saver card.
Speaker 0: It does In on board with me.
Speaker 0: D.
Speaker 1: See you are not living on a mile.
Speaker 0: You got you got stabbed on a mile.
Speaker 1: Yeah Actually, yeah.
Speaker 1: People who've been listening to geek nights for a little while will remember the tale about the guy who had his appendix out.
Speaker 1: I was that guy and actually as per Either Rima Scott's recommendation.
Speaker 1: I think it was rim.
Speaker 1: I have actually been saying I was stopped on eight mile.
Speaker 1: But this whole thing this the curse or massive and it is the worst rap that was ever done Isn't it?
Speaker 1: and people have actually parroted it now parried parroted parroted Didn't feel right didn't feel right.
Speaker 1: they've like.
Speaker 1: they've done the Star Wars kid treatment to it and it's been done a thousand times on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Now there's a glove puppet one.
Speaker 1: There's all sorts of things.
Speaker 0: I like the cyber one.
Speaker 0: What was that one?
Speaker 1: This what that's?
Speaker 1: It's a weird news thing.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: other people can check that out.
Speaker 0: There's some really good ones on there.
Speaker 0: So Definitely check out the curse or massive.
Speaker 0: It's the funniest of baddest and not in there.
Speaker 0: It's really bad.
Speaker 0: good kind of way is it I?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's like when I was doing that job at the school in Barnsley and I was walking down the corridor of the school.
Speaker 1: we had our cameras with us and One of the kids jumped out and went are you gonna film me?
Speaker 1: I'm a gang star and my only response to him was kid you're 12 and you from Barnsley get over.
Speaker 1: That is it?
Speaker 1: you are not from the hood.
Speaker 1: you are from Darfield a small mining town in the north of England.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry He wants coke and he wants bitches and on the back of his mum's cleo God.
Speaker 1: this is why we normally talk about movies, you know, because we just get angry It's true.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 0: And do you know what?
Speaker 0: It's the thing that chavs do the kid chavs What do?
Speaker 0: they stand outside the spa shop clutching a two pound coin going?
Speaker 0: Yeah got some cider in it.
Speaker 1: Guess some cider guess?
Speaker 0: no, I won't buy you side.
Speaker 0: No, what did you say that guy?
Speaker 1: There was a little kid outside the shop and he was Little roly-poly kid.
Speaker 1: He must have been about 14, but he was a little.
Speaker 1: he was the fat kid in his class.
Speaker 1: You know the little pink face with his little bobble at home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, think Cartman in real life that was him.
Speaker 1: and they were like, can you buy some Stella?
Speaker 1: And I said no look if you don't drink beer, you'll lose weight and girls will like you And you won't need to drink beer anymore with him who quite frankly looks like he's been sipping antifreeze.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna say to these kids Because you're the little chubby kid.
Speaker 1: I get it I was a little chubby kid but drinking beer outside a Convenience store is not gonna help.
Speaker 1: No, that's not gonna get you.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's just really annoying.
Speaker 1: it is not the way to advance your life and Somebody needs to make this very clear to you now.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like made the convenience store that the youth club I mean.
Speaker 1: for God's sake get an xbox.
Speaker 1: at least you're improving your hand-eye coordination.
Speaker 0: I have to agree with you here.
Speaker 0: Go the way of the geek go that way Cuz.
Speaker 0: get online do World of Warcraft do whatever.
Speaker 0: just don't stand out the side spa shop asking strangers if they'll buy you Piss off juice and rapping on YouTube and rapping on YouTube.
Speaker 1: most importantly of all stay off the internet, please And you're not supposed to have access to.
Speaker 1: Right, it's it's made so that you have to be able to work a computer to get on to it.
Speaker 1: And I you're not.
Speaker 1: you're not there yet.
Speaker 0: Somebody probably is yeah One of the massive.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's probably the guy just off camera that we only just see for like five seconds.
Speaker 0: Well, is it?
Speaker 0: and he goes I?
Speaker 0: Puts it up on the Internet.
Speaker 1: Okay, so everyone should watch the curse on massive and have a laugh.
Speaker 1: and please believe that not all English people are like.
Speaker 1: We're being very the British Business culture, let's move on.
Speaker 1: I'll play that music again.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'm supposed to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay Brilliant.
Speaker 1: I bloody love that music.
Speaker 0: You can't see that it's good.
Speaker 1: it's good that we're not a video podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz that would be tragic.
Speaker 1: so a Main topic main topic.
Speaker 1: This was quite tricky Because although You're quite geeky.
Speaker 1: I am as girlfriends.
Speaker 1: Go you're very good.
Speaker 1: Um, as far as as geekery goes you're excellent without without going too far Right.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So on a scale of one to ten, how geeky am I?
Speaker 1: You're sort of six.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: I'm happy with this.
Speaker 0: I played worried.
Speaker 0: if I was a seven I'd be upset.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was an eight.
Speaker 0: I'd be in counseling if I was a nine and that'd be you if I was ten.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's fair to say.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm not a ten.
Speaker 1: I'm not I'm not No, no.
Speaker 1: No, there's no anime up on these shelves.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: There's a couple of things Let's be honest, but it's not bad.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's things like Spirited away.
Speaker 1: Yes, I was moving castle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, both of which I still need to sit down and watch.
Speaker 1: you do But you know, there's I would be fair to say this far geekier than me.
Speaker 1: There's no comic books in the toilet.
Speaker 0: We met a geek a few weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Can you remember he had like one of every computer.
Speaker 1: that was incredible?
Speaker 0: Was uber geek though, wasn't he?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we found ourselves in this guy's house for one reason or another.
Speaker 1: We were seeing a friend of ours who was in his house.
Speaker 1: Yeah And this guy we start talking and he's like you like computers.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you've got to see these.
Speaker 1: Oh One of every computer ever made pretty much most of them worked as well.
Speaker 0: he just kept getting another one out and another one out and it'd be like from 1982 and 1987.
Speaker 1: he had every Nintendo ever and they were all plugged in and working in his living room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were playing Donkey Kong Weren't we?
Speaker 0: Yeah Fantastic.
Speaker 0: I mean that guy plays World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: He's got the beard.
Speaker 0: He's got the anime.
Speaker 0: He had the most anime I've ever seen in one place at any one time.
Speaker 1: to be fair looking at him Where he wish to walk into a comic book store in Springfield and find him sat behind the counter.
Speaker 1: Now actually I my ex when I got my xbox chipped a couple of years ago The guy who did it actually was comic book guy.
Speaker 1: He was this big fat guy sat on the barstool behind the counter in the game show.
Speaker 1: He had even had the greasy ponytail and the beard and everything.
Speaker 1: It was fantastic.
Speaker 1: He I can't remember what it was about But he even connected corrected my pronunciation of a technical term.
Speaker 1: I was in there.
Speaker 1: He was comic book guy.
Speaker 1: and you just want to say to these guys like cuz you must know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's seen The Simpsons.
Speaker 1: He's seen comic book guy.
Speaker 1: He can probably quote every episode to me And so he must know he must sit there looking at himself at the screen at himself.
Speaker 0: Do you know who I think I am?
Speaker 0: Comic book guy.
Speaker 1: maybe Episode ever.
Speaker 1: Why are we doing bad Simpsons Impressions?
Speaker 1: I can't do Impressions.
Speaker 1: So we're talking about dumb Apple fanboys.
Speaker 0: We're talking about you.
Speaker 1: This is a unique phenomenon within the technical industry.
Speaker 1: I believe in that Every company has its fans.
Speaker 1: every at.
Speaker 1: every company who makes stuff has people who only buy people who are brand loyal.
Speaker 1: We know what.
Speaker 1: Mike for example only has Sony stuff in his room.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: I keep trying to tell him that Sony are and the second force of all evil Other than Simon Cowell, but he keeps buying it because it's all already there and he likes it to match.
Speaker 1: But Apple fanboys are a law unto themselves.
Speaker 0: This is very very true and something that is is becoming more apparent to me the longer I live with you.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: I wasn't always like this.
Speaker 1: It has to be said.
Speaker 0: I know you caught a bug.
Speaker 1: I caught a bug about a year and a half ago I think.
Speaker 1: cuz I work in a production company and when we all got together to begin with out of the four of us three of us worked on PCs religiously and there was Luke who had a Mac and At the time it was this weird little g3 blue Purple kind of rather girly affair that didn't really do anything and compared to the PC I had at the time it was well shit quite frankly and it crashed all the time.
Speaker 1: recently we have Smashed it up with a big bat, which was quite sad.
Speaker 1: No, we didn't.
Speaker 1: we should have done that actually and put it on YouTube with this slew of other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, watch me smash my Mac videos.
Speaker 1: But I think it was also then hurled off something big tired of being fun.
Speaker 1: It was fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah I've lost track now.
Speaker 1: the g3 sat in the corner of the office the g3 sat in the corner of the office And then we we sort of bought our own or all our new equipment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Part of that was brand new spanky g5 power Mac that one that's up right there.
Speaker 1: No, that was that's my one the one in the office The new one and this was unlike anything I had ever seen before in my life.
Speaker 1: actually for the first six months We sort of we were speaking behind each of those backs about Luke going, you know, we've got to get him on to PCs.
Speaker 1: What's this Mac shit?
Speaker 1: He's got going on.
Speaker 1: We can't be having this, you know I don't care how compatible is.
Speaker 1: don't want it Don't want it.
Speaker 1: got to get more and then I used it and three days and nights later I was physically removed from it because other work had to be done on it and that was pretty much it.
Speaker 1: and then those of you who have bought one will probably relate to the Stories of going to the Apple Store page over and over again building your ideal spec.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: I remember this Clearly.
Speaker 1: do I get the slightly bigger hard drive or the bigger graphics card?
Speaker 0: I can recall one night when you sat here and did that very task.
Speaker 0: over and over again over and over again We were coming up with figures that were near 12,000 pounds or that was my dream system was your dream system and you were really going for it.
Speaker 0: you're going for the top end of everything and every add-on that you could get.
Speaker 0: that was New and zippy and I want I still do that.
Speaker 1: I still do it.
Speaker 1: only my ideal system is now sixteen and a half thousand pounds.
Speaker 1: That's just which is crazy for a computer.
Speaker 1: I mean really what does it do?
Speaker 1: Is it that much faster than mine?
Speaker 1: Probably not to be fair.
Speaker 0: You can buy cars for that.
Speaker 0: You can buy nice car.
Speaker 1: You can buy houses for that in some places.
Speaker 1: Let's be honest.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can which is ridiculous.
Speaker 1: Do I buy a power Mac or a house?
Speaker 0: Well given where that house would be in a really crummy area I'd actually get the Mac again.
Speaker 1: get the Mac and you can live in them as well.
Speaker 1: They're that big.
Speaker 1: They've got a bedroom on sweet.
Speaker 0: They don't.
Speaker 1: The next one will have.
Speaker 0: no they don't.
Speaker 1: Steve will bring it for me.
Speaker 0: He won't.
Speaker 1: so let's talk some more about How this is, you know, the more I'm talking about it.
Speaker 1: I'm actually starting to feel ashamed of myself.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you see I was hoping that this might come out because this is good therapy for is it?
Speaker 1: This is gonna make us stronger as a couple I'm hoping so.
Speaker 0: maybe I'm hoping so because we're gonna both get to air outside of the story And you're going to realize that you're quite sad.
Speaker 1: Well, let's explain how it starts because as I say, I wasn't always like this.
Speaker 1: it starts with seeing it for the first time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is a rather beautiful machine.
Speaker 1: No, I don't want to get into the whole.
Speaker 1: I think they're brilliant.
Speaker 1: So you should go out and buy one.
Speaker 1: I'm not I don't want to talk about you that a lot Yeah, but I'm not in this case.
Speaker 1: I'm just talking about the experience of being The dumb fanboy rather that I'm not I don't want to get into which is better.
Speaker 0: Just explain what it's like when you look at that.
Speaker 1: so for me you start building it and then it starts because You get yours and then something else comes out and you think well Wish I got that one because that's happened to you already.
Speaker 1: That's happened to a lot of people already.
Speaker 1: There was Craig who bought his g5 and then the week after the new one came out Yeah, and then my dad bought one of those and then the week after the Intel one came out.
Speaker 1: Two very upset people who are now very happy.
Speaker 0: you see that that marks on the downside for Apple.
Speaker 0: I think the quick no, no, no, no, no, that's.
Speaker 1: that's completely unfair.
Speaker 1: How often do you let Packard release a computer with the next Intel processor in?
Speaker 1: How often do they all do that?
Speaker 1: We only know with Apple because there's there's like two different machines and because Everybody watches them so closely Fools like me.
Speaker 1: this is that the key RSS feed Updating every 30 minutes linked to Mac daily news.
Speaker 1: This is the key Richard Yeah to get rumors about things that are never ever gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh And it's just stupid made-up things that make the news and we get so excited But you look at them and you just go straight away.
Speaker 0: Well, that's not real.
Speaker 1: I know I do that but then I get excited.
Speaker 1: This is what's so stupid about it.
Speaker 1: I'm not a dumb person.
Speaker 1: I can I can read things and decide and well think with education that that's stupid.
Speaker 0: and You see the rabbit and you start running.
Speaker 1: you want it.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's just like this.
Speaker 1: this latest one about the phone where there's this news report came out that this guy who knows a guy who's a Technology did a photo shoot for Apple allegedly and Allegedly photoed what he just described as the best-looking phone he's ever seen in his life.
Speaker 1: But it's probably a complete load of toss.
Speaker 0: But what did you say there was in the car going?
Speaker 1: I know it's probably not true, but it's coming.
Speaker 1: That means it's coming next.
Speaker 1: What the hell is this about what?
Speaker 1: how does it happen what?
Speaker 1: what has it done to me?
Speaker 0: You've got that nice silver shiny beautiful box there and I'm going to agree with you.
Speaker 0: it's Aesthetically a beautiful machine.
Speaker 0: Oh when you turn it on the screens are beautiful and You've got that and then you realize it's a beautiful thing.
Speaker 0: And beautiful things are very intoxicating and you want more beautiful things, especially when the beautiful thing looks rather beautiful Alongside the other beautiful things.
Speaker 0: Yeah And then they bring out another beautiful thing that is equally beautiful alongside both of those beautiful things and suddenly have to have every beautiful thing that has an Apple logo stamped on it.
Speaker 1: and then they give you stickers so that you can put Apple logos on Things that shouldn't have Apple logos on them.
Speaker 0: Yeah What we got?
Speaker 0: we got a little girly pink paper box on the mantelpiece that's got an Apple sticker on it.
Speaker 0: I put it there.
Speaker 0: I am not infected by the Apple pug, but I put that sticker on that there box.
Speaker 1: Frank has an Apple guitar.
Speaker 0: No, he doesn't Gibson guitar.
Speaker 0: it's got an Apple sticker on it.
Speaker 0: What why?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know I can't tell you.
Speaker 0: I you know, his people are getting Apple tattoos.
Speaker 1: Now that's too fast too far.
Speaker 1: You see if you come back here with no Tattoo no, it's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll be trouble.
Speaker 1: I'd expect to be kicked out for that to be perfectly honest.
Speaker 0: But oh, yeah, you know, yeah, I'm glad you've realized what's coming to you before so you've got.
Speaker 1: no I wouldn't do it.
Speaker 1: I don't want that because the moment I get it done is the moment they bring out the I poo and Stock prices crash through the floor.
Speaker 1: and that's it.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: Although I think they could actually bring out the I poo and it would sell in its millions.
Speaker 1: just to poo in a box With an Apple logo on Probably would people wouldn't buy one and people would dismantle it and go.
Speaker 1: there's clues to the new Apple phone in the firmware of the I poo, but
Speaker 0: the interesting thing is that before you bought it we drive 45 miles to the nearest Apple store for you to look at it in that glass box
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: Fawn over it until you've got enough money to afford
Speaker 1: it.
Speaker 1: It's not my fault That the only Apple store is 45 miles away.
Speaker 0: It's the fawning.
Speaker 0: It's not the journey.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's on the other side of the pen lines.
Speaker 0: I have no money in my pocket.
Speaker 0: I want deeply what is in that store.
Speaker 1: So I'm just gonna go and stroke one.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go stroke it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna look at it fawn and then walk away and go and have a look in game see what secondhand games have got.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because that's your other geek spot on that trip.
Speaker 1: That's half over because that was part of a quest to find an Xbox version of Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 And you've got a very old game.
Speaker 1: and are you telling me now that oh, yeah The quest is half over but as soon as I get a copy of fusion frenzy, we can all relax?
Speaker 0: Are you telling me that when you've got fusion frenzy the frequency of your visits into not one?
Speaker 0: Branch two branches of game with two branches of game in the same mall Are going to reduce?
Speaker 1: yes, I promise You promise.
Speaker 0: did you hear that everyone everyone?
Speaker 0: This is being recorded on the 7th of all.
Speaker 1: Don't be so Yeah, I promise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'll stop reading my daily news.
Speaker 1: Yeah You see this all hit home for me right.
Speaker 1: the effect of the Apple fanboy Will call it the Apple fanboy effect Happened to my friend Andy our friend Andy Who came to me and said rich?
Speaker 1: I want to get a computer.
Speaker 1: What should I get?
Speaker 1: and I just smiled.
Speaker 0: You did I'd say you love that.
Speaker 0: Get a Mac.
Speaker 1: to the point where when I went to the Apple store last time to get my iPod sorted Which is another thing we'll talk about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I said to the guy behind the counter, you know I should get commission for all the max I sold and he looked at me In the most deadpan way and said have you any idea how many times I hear that every day?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well then there's more than you.
Speaker 0: I feel.
Speaker 0: rest assured now that there is more than you and I'm pretty sure that there's lots of people like you listening to this podcast right now identifying themselves and Shaking their heads in shame squirming.
Speaker 1: Shake your head in shame.
Speaker 1: Yeah What effect has it had when a company can provide you with such a thing as an iPod?
Speaker 1: That since January I have had three.
Speaker 0: you've had three of them not one and not three because you're greedy.
Speaker 1: No, that's three because three of them broken.
Speaker 1: That's why they haven't been dropped down the toilet.
Speaker 1: They haven't been smashed or driven over the car.
Speaker 1: I upgraded the firmware and they broke.
Speaker 1: now granted They just gave me a new one.
Speaker 1: We just go in.
Speaker 1: I say my input is broke.
Speaker 1: They go.
Speaker 1: Here you go Here's a new one.
Speaker 1: Absolutely one of the company Their customer service.
Speaker 0: cuz yeah handled you so well, and they've just said here's a new night.
Speaker 1: I'm potentially very difficult to handle and are you not giving me what I want sort of way?
Speaker 1: Yes you are especially when you're somebody who I've given money to yeah, and You're the guy that hand the phone to and say rich Power call center who are still crying After that last one, you're so harsh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't know what it does.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's simply using them.
Speaker 1: That does it.
Speaker 1: First of all, I don't think it actually pleases that many people.
Speaker 1: I think you know as even rimming Scott have said There's massive problems there.
Speaker 1: I think I would agree not with the iPod with the max now, right?
Speaker 1: Sorry I jump back there and tell anybody.
Speaker 1: so There are.
Speaker 1: there's some of them.
Speaker 1: there's some massive issues with some of them.
Speaker 1: I mean when we were using Andy's MacBook yesterday when he put it away.
Speaker 1: Did you feel how hot the kitchen?
Speaker 1: You could have just fried an egg on the work Something out of Ghostbusters.
Speaker 1: You could have just done that.
Speaker 0: I don't know how long you've been using it for but it can't be however long.
Speaker 1: that was ridiculous.
Speaker 1: If that had been on your lap, you'd have been rubbing some aloe vera on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and believe you me that can lead to some nasty injuries.
Speaker 1: If I had to pick an area of my body to burn my lap wouldn't be it?
Speaker 0: Well, your testicles are such a great area to be heating up anyway.
Speaker 1: That's the age-old thing about laptops about they make you sterile and stuff like that?
Speaker 1: I don't believe they do.
Speaker 1: but the Mac book will fry your nuts right there and then I Mean the one.
Speaker 0: one thing about that area of the body is it's outside for a reason to cool it down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, last thing you want to do is heat it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if Steve Jobs came to the door now and said I'll give you this Mac book But I'm gonna have to take a listen away.
Speaker 0: You twat me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, come on, love get your cut.
Speaker 0: I can't just.
Speaker 0: I can't believe that.
Speaker 0: but you would when he Really straight swap me for a MacBook Pro?
Speaker 1: Yeah, my book Pro.
Speaker 1: I mean if it was just a Mac book, I'd want a big hard.
Speaker 1: This is I wouldn't really swap you.
Speaker 1: That's unfair.
Speaker 1: I'm only joking.
Speaker 1: Geeks make the best boyfriends.
Speaker 0: geeks make the best boyfriends.
Speaker 0: Yeah They do.
Speaker 1: they do.
Speaker 1: How good am I?
Speaker 0: You're a fantastic boy.
Speaker 1: Let's be honest.
Speaker 0: You are You're great.
Speaker 0: Look at you doing a little victory dance.
Speaker 0: You are because I'm a geek Because you're a geek.
Speaker 0: It's part of the culture it is and and we always know about things are arriving and things that we want and You know about new software releases and you know this that the other and you always make sure that I'm up to date and stuff Like that.
Speaker 1: most of the time you just sat there rolling your eyes really Yes, dear with that kind of expression.
Speaker 1: It's like yes I know you do it, but I'm okay with it because you sit there and let me do it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I let you do it and about about 30% of it.
Speaker 0: I think goes in.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Very well, thank you.
Speaker 1: Very well indeed.
Speaker 0: I do very well cuz I'm a six.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'd do terrible if I was a five but at six about thirty percent of it sticks in my head and I know what you're talking about and I kind of get what you're saying, but this the Moment that a tech word speak comes up that I don't understand.
Speaker 0: rather than asking most of the time I just skip it.
Speaker 0: Did you skip?
Speaker 0: um, yeah, I'm sorry, it's that old I zone you out kind of thing again, but it's Not again.
Speaker 0: No, that's fine.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry, but it's true.
Speaker 0: If you if you're talking about Technical bits and pieces to do with motherboards.
Speaker 1: I just kind of like when do I don't talk about?
Speaker 0: I'm just trying to give an example of something and I can't give an example because I own it out Usually Mac Daily News Mac Daily News.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean It's name says everything.
Speaker 0: It's Mac Daily News.
Speaker 0: It's daily news to you.
Speaker 0: Do you hear you're always there?
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 0: it's usually hit in the morning before like BBC national news and you always tell me when I get home from what you Tell me what's gonna cite it to you in tech.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: We're not not.
Speaker 1: it's not as if I'm not busy.
Speaker 1: It's not as if I've got nothing better.
Speaker 0: This fuels your entire enthusiasm for what you do.
Speaker 0: Well, I knew love listening to and Watching and reading about geeks geekology Technology being a nerd geekology the study of geeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the things that you do like when when An Apple rumor comes out or there's sly talk of secret invitations being sent out There's going to be a special event.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and Steve Jobs is going to do a keynote and And you count down the days Have a widget that can't stand to develop a widget.
Speaker 1: Yeah that counts down the days.
Speaker 0: So it's not just you.
Speaker 0: you all like you don't get together because I don't think you ever leave home.
Speaker 0: I think you just stay.
Speaker 1: Exactly, look what we're doing.
Speaker 0: We're geeking across the Atlantic And we haven't gone anywhere.
Speaker 0: We're still in a living room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you do y'all hook up over the internet And talk about what's come in and what could possibly be Steve saying in this time?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I tell you what, I can predict a couple of things.
Speaker 0: I can predict what he's gonna wear.
Speaker 1: That's it's becoming a game now.
Speaker 1: It's like this big thing.
Speaker 1: I should do a website right here.
Speaker 1: is we we?
Speaker 1: we Wait, every time there's a big Apple event coming out people can post their like top three what I think is gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then the winner gets a prize.
Speaker 1: That's crap idea.
Speaker 0: Fund a prize.
Speaker 0: That's a rubbish.
Speaker 1: Well, we get lots of hits and we make I don't know Forget it.
Speaker 0: Okay, we could make a prize.
Speaker 0: I suppose rubbish.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yeah, that's when my broken iPod.
Speaker 0: That's what you do though, I can remember I was racing back from your parents house To see the keynote live because you didn't want to wait for it and then we got back and because every Geek in the world was sat streaming the same piece of video We got about three seconds at a time before it cut again,
Speaker 1: but I sat there for four hours watching those three seconds of the time
Speaker 0: By the time we'd seen it it had been reported.
Speaker 0: we could have just read it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, it's reported quicker than you get the video.
Speaker 1: now You can read a live blog faster than they put the video.
Speaker 1: The thing that frustrates me is that when a new thing comes out you want to hear it on the video?
Speaker 1: You want to see Steve go?
Speaker 1: Oh, and there is one more thing.
Speaker 1: But by the time the videos out you've got to go to the website to get it and they've put the new thing on the front Page of the website.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you've got to sort of not look at the screen and try and hit the button To go to the video page.
Speaker 1: If you were going to a website to watch a TV episode and on the front page of the Website was the last scene of the film Watch the first episode of 24. in the last episode Jack died.
Speaker 1: It would be pointless.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm not gonna mother.
Speaker 1: so that's what it is.
Speaker 1: But we still watch and I've watched many of them several times and even old ones.
Speaker 1: I know and I don't know why.
Speaker 0: you like his style as well as much as you hear.
Speaker 0: you enjoy hearing him talk about his Thing.
Speaker 0: you enjoy style.
Speaker 1: you like his present love him or hate him.
Speaker 1: The man is a fantastic presenter.
Speaker 1: He does well on stage.
Speaker 1: Yeah More rumors surrounding the clicky thing.
Speaker 1: Apparently it's not an actual clicky thing.
Speaker 1: Apparently it goes to a room behind the stage that switches a light on that says you switch that thing over now or That's just upsetting because I really wanted the clicky thing to be a real thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: I think you see some people say there was one he did where it broke Yeah, and he had to make a joke about Apple.
Speaker 1: doesn't make the clicker thing.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: so Let's go back.
Speaker 1: You know, we've talked about this for half an hour now.
Speaker 1: We haven't really discovered anything new other than I hate myself.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you one thing that did elevate you though.
Speaker 0: You didn't go whole hog with the old Apple thing.
Speaker 0: You didn't get that crappy phone.
Speaker 1: That oh the iTunes phone.
Speaker 1: no, I would I didn't get that.
Speaker 0: you didn't get that.
Speaker 0: so, you know completely suckered.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm sat here surrounded by a power Mac and an eyesight and an iPod in there.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know, that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah The computer that's behind me wishing it was an iMac.
Speaker 1: Oh you wish it was an iMac.
Speaker 0: No you wish it was an iMac.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want me to get an iMac more than I want to get an iMac.
Speaker 1: It's easier if everybody's using the same.
Speaker 0: Completely agree with you, but I am pointing out a fact here.
Speaker 0: You want it for me more than I want.
Speaker 1: You see this is something people don't understand especially in America.
Speaker 1: Is that I chat is an incredible instant messenger program.
Speaker 1: it Some I'm sure that everybody has a different opinion to me and everyone in the world who hears this is just gonna know I chat.
Speaker 1: It's appalling.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But you like it.
Speaker 1: it's my favorite one, but the trouble is I can only speak to Tristan or my dad.
Speaker 0: Right, if I got it we could.
Speaker 1: and if we're in the same room Well, not just for you, but when I'm away and stuff.
Speaker 0: So you can speak to Tristan my dad.
Speaker 1: and So the plan is if I get everyone that I know on to a Mac then we can all use I chat and I don't Have to have stupid MSM messenger.
Speaker 0: That's so much cheaper than MSM message.
Speaker 1: We are like the only country in the world where MSM messenger is a big thing.
Speaker 1: no one uses it in America.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they all they're all on aim on AOL and stuff which is why I chat works in America because everyone's on AOL.
Speaker 1: Okay, but here MSM and it sucks ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't use it on MSN.
Speaker 0: Can you?
Speaker 1: I can use MSM but it's like the most basic.
Speaker 1: So we have to do Skype for video to video thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not even seen that working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually.
Speaker 1: No, no Should we wrap up?
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's wrap up.
Speaker 0: I mean we were gonna talk a little bit about.
Speaker 0: you know, the geeks do make good boyfriends and despite all your Apple love and well Apple frenzy You are a very good boyfriend for all the reasons that are on Craigslist.
Speaker 1: should we give a?
Speaker 1: Basically, there's a. there's a list on Craigslist, isn't there of why geeks make of why geeks and nerds are worth it?
Speaker 1: That's a very long URL to give out.
Speaker 1: it is but if you do it, I'm sure if you google why geeks and nerds are worth it Then you'll probably get it.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of reasons here.
Speaker 0: I mean some of them.
Speaker 0: Really you all over.
Speaker 0: Just give me a couple And My romantics and you give them credit for really I'm yeah you are.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it says here Okay, true their idea of romance might be to make up a spiffy web page with all the reasons why they love you.
Speaker 0: You haven't done that.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna do that.
Speaker 0: You've built pages and I'm on them.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a different thing.
Speaker 0: But is it?
Speaker 1: yeah, it's not very far away.
Speaker 1: Well, you're in the podcast.
Speaker 0: What do you write?
Speaker 0: My name's Wally, isn't it?
Speaker 0: And and everything's Wally.
Speaker 1: That's just a joke.
Speaker 0: Okay, you've got brains.
Speaker 0: you've got brains.
Speaker 0: I love the fact that we can have intelligent conversations and I don't at any point Despair that you're being stupid.
Speaker 1: No, no, I Really enjoy.
Speaker 0: I really enjoy that.
Speaker 0: I couldn't cope with you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you ain't clever and it takes cleverness to be a geek it certainly does.
Speaker 1: god we're good You know, we should be in charge of everything.
Speaker 1: Really just me help.
Speaker 0: Am I gonna get?
Speaker 0: it was redecorating and stuff like that with that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't know there.
Speaker 1: You see you see I'd like to say lots, but I think in truth in truth We know that I'm probably more of a hindrance.
Speaker 0: That's true Saying Go play with your Mac.
Speaker 1: Yeah while I plaster go and go and download podcasts.
Speaker 0: Yeah while I Paint these floorboards.
Speaker 0: I can do stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you do choose not to because that's your domain.
Speaker 0: Well, not the domain with a paintbrush or a tool in your hand, I suppose And you're not a gardener.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's so dull and it takes so long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm my see-through complexion hates the Sun.
Speaker 0: see you you're a nerd.
Speaker 0: you have nerd skin.
Speaker 0: You can't be outside for too long.
Speaker 0: She just come out in horrible blisters like angel the vampire.
Speaker 0: Yeah Only more nerdy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if he wore glasses, I don't like glasses.
Speaker 1: Well, I should.
Speaker 0: you should.
Speaker 1: I don't wear them as often as I. Let's end this.
Speaker 1: Let's do the wrap-up.
Speaker 1: So we've been rich and Allison from movies.
Speaker 1: You should see.
Speaker 1: yes Well, we discuss a movie.
Speaker 1: You should see that was from our earlier really crap promo that we did where it was just me going.
Speaker 0: We've moved on.
Speaker 1: we have only just You can check us out at simply syndicated comm slash movies.
Speaker 1: You should see Remnants got her on there a couple of times City of God attack the gas station.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're both still up there.
Speaker 0: Yes, they're still available for download.
Speaker 1: So check that out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it, isn't it?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So thanks for a minute Scott for letting us do this.
Speaker 0: This is really enjoyable.
Speaker 0: You know, you've been dying for this.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, this is you know, talk about interactive media.
Speaker 1: This is what you want.
Speaker 1: Jeremy Clarkson won't let me go and do a top gear.
Speaker 1: No, we won't.
Speaker 1: we won't do that.
Speaker 1: No, there's no point me pointing at the telly Say that you're doing that.
Speaker 0: So, okay I'm not gonna get to present a big brother eviction night and get to be mean to someone But here we are on gate nights, I think it's amazing.
Speaker 0: I think it's fantastic.
Speaker 0: I've had a wicked night.
Speaker 0: I hope I hope you've enjoyed us.
Speaker 0: Bye.
Speaker 0: Goodbye.
Speaker 2: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 2: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 2: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 2: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 2: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 2: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 2: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.