Speaker 0: It's Wednesday September 27th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We review Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I got to say I had a slightly Disappointing experience a little while ago today when I decided out of the blue because I haven't played Mario Kart for the DS in Quite some time really I mean the game kind of played itself out.
Speaker 0: I just didn't play it for a while.
Speaker 0: So I decided I wanted to get on a Nintendo You know Wi-Fi network and own some punk-ass bitches.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven't used that Wi-Fi a lot lately.
Speaker 1: You know a lot of games that should have used it didn't use it and a lot of games Just haven't come out that use Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: that are good games.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think we're just gonna have to wait for the Pokemon.
Speaker 1: That's when it's really gonna get used constantly.
Speaker 0: Well, I got sick of Metroid pretty quick and then this Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: All right, Mario Kart is probably my favorite game on the DS.
Speaker 0: still other than you know Advance Wars DS and Castlevania DS Those other better DS games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem actually I really like the game.
Speaker 0: the problem is game.
Speaker 0: I went online and for the life of me, I couldn't start a game.
Speaker 0: There was just no one playing.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean we've checked on the Nintendo website and there were about a hundred people playing.
Speaker 0: Yeah a hundred that's bad That's not enough.
Speaker 1: I know but the thing is if they had a better matchup system It should theoretically take a hundred people and make 25 games or people.
Speaker 0: you realize that what happens?
Speaker 0: It's not that there were a hundred people on at the same time.
Speaker 0: a hundred.
Speaker 0: It means that over the course of that hour a hundred people logged on Probably tried to play a game for like a minute or two and then gave up.
Speaker 0: because if I don't get a game Or two I just give up because obviously it's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird because I'm used to playing games online.
Speaker 1: You know on Steam if even if you try to play a less popular game like ricochet there's a server with some people on it and the people can clump together when they have this sort of automatic system where the.
Speaker 0: I think the difference here is more that with those games the server People can come and go and it doesn't disrupt the game at all.
Speaker 0: You can't just come and go in a set of Mario Kart match.
Speaker 1: I know I mean I can understand why they have their game matchup system this way.
Speaker 1: But now we're seeing.
Speaker 1: you know The true effect of that is that Wi-Fi play of a game dies out because people can't Get games set up even when there are a bunch of people playing.
Speaker 0: so granted I know a lot of people would still use it, but they'll use it with their friends.
Speaker 0: You know on a weekend, which we keep saying we'll do we just never have the freaking time to do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, someday.
Speaker 0: I will own some punk ass geek nights bitches.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, we got some news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so a Lot of people have been yelling about fan subs and digital anime sales and all that lately.
Speaker 0: Anime world order recently did a big thing.
Speaker 0: They were talking about, you know, how do you deal with the piracy problem?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're responding to some listener email.
Speaker 1: that listener didn't know shit.
Speaker 0: Actually, we were gonna send them a feedback about that and then as we talked about what we would say We realized that we would have basically made an entire episode of geek night.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna do a whole episode about anime distribution in the u.s Yeah, probably in some time in the future.
Speaker 1: But anyway ATV has put out a new Service called ATV universe.
Speaker 1: It's an unpackaged media download service.
Speaker 1: Basically what this means is you pay ATV money and they let you download anime.
Speaker 1: Now here's the details.
Speaker 1: They've got a whole bunch of series including Gilgamesh area 88 Princess Tutu that are $25 an episode and they've got a movie and an OAV that are available for $20 for the whole OAV or the whole movie.
Speaker 0: They've also got a free.
Speaker 0: you can get guy for the bio boosted shit fest For free.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can.
Speaker 1: you can watch the guy for for free.
Speaker 1: The guy was not the worst anime ever.
Speaker 0: know that that title reserved solely for it's better than MD guys.
Speaker 0: I must say, you know MD guys provided a lot of entertainment.
Speaker 1: You know the guy for entertained me what back in the day the hell's wrong with.
Speaker 1: not now now it's crap.
Speaker 1: But back in the day, I kind of like, you know, I hadn't seen too many shows with a guy wearing armor.
Speaker 1: So So guy wearing armor was enough in those days.
Speaker 0: nowadays not so much at least with MD guys to have a football uniform.
Speaker 0: This is just some are diver is actually a cool armor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a bio boosted armor.
Speaker 1: How can you anyway?
Speaker 0: It's no match for a rust hurricane.
Speaker 1: yes now here's what I got to say about this particular service.
Speaker 1: number one It's dubs only it seems number two.
Speaker 1: It's only available in the US.
Speaker 1: So there's no.
Speaker 1: What's it called re-importation to Japan?
Speaker 1: You you're actually buying it.
Speaker 1: when you paying the five bucks you get it.
Speaker 1: It's not a rental like some other services are you know, like some of those unlimited music services But this DRM.
Speaker 0: they don't say what the DRM will be.
Speaker 1: they don't say the DRM is but this DRM.
Speaker 1: now, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: even with the DRM This is gonna fail because it's five bucks an episode.
Speaker 1: five bucks an episode means $20 for four episodes.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: No one buys DVDs for $20.
Speaker 1: Everyone buys their DVDs for less than that.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna pay for less than a DVD for $20.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially when you get a DRM encumbered thing with no goodies and no physical media.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean anime world order hit on a lot of this.
Speaker 0: So one we're not gonna play their promo just because I really don't like podcast promos in general.
Speaker 0: But you should go listen anime world or anime world order calm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we like them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they were talking a lot about this and the one thing they hit on is the collector mentality Which in my opinion is very rapidly dying in terms of anime DVD collecting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we need to do a whole episode on the collector mentality.
Speaker 0: But the thing is you can't ignore it and the fact that they're charging the same amount for something that gives you less.
Speaker 0: I mean to quote Lord of Pi who posted in the forums on animators network about this quote Five freaking dollars an episode and it's still dub only are you guys insane?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if the D it's if they were charging $2 an episode 250 Then it would be cool because you're paying less.
Speaker 1: you're paying 10 bucks for you know Four episodes which is less than what a DVD costs.
Speaker 1: You're getting less than what a DVD offers and you're paying less.
Speaker 1: it makes sense You know, you're getting a DRM encumbered file with no subtitle track.
Speaker 1: But if you're getting less than what a DVD offers and paying more than what a DVD costs No one's gonna use this.
Speaker 1: who has half a brain except to watch the guy for free.
Speaker 0: now I actually agree with one of the people who wrote or said or spoke or something into anime world order about What if there were a Napster like service where you had unlimited access to all the anime someone put out for a monthly fee.
Speaker 1: That'll be cool.
Speaker 0: download and watch.
Speaker 0: now Clarissa really poo-pooed it and while her critique of that idea was valid it was valid from her perspective as a fan and I would just like to note that Scott and I and I think there are a lot of anime fans like us We Netflix is the single primary reason we don't buy anime anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean we do buy anime.
Speaker 1: What is a crazy deal when it's a really good show?
Speaker 0: We don't buy anime the way we used to that.
Speaker 0: There was a time when if I wasn't if I wanted to see a show I'd plunk down 2025 bucks to buy the first DVD to see if I liked it or if I wanted to watch a show.
Speaker 0: I'd wait until I saw those and that anime on sale and I'd buy the box set.
Speaker 0: now any show.
Speaker 0: that isn't crazy amazing.
Speaker 0: There's no way in hell.
Speaker 0: I would buy it.
Speaker 0: I just put it in the Netflix queue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then if we watch something on Netflix and it's super awesome And we want to own it to watch it again rather than Netflixing it again Cuz that's just dumb to Netflix something twice, you know.
Speaker 1: What we'll do is we'll put it will write the name down and then a few years later at a convention when we see the slim Case box for super cheap.
Speaker 1: We'll pick it up Now.
Speaker 1: if there was a way to get it for super cheap online and download the whole thing You know with subtitles and everything and no DRM's or even maybe with DRM's.
Speaker 1: probably not though We would do it but not if you're gonna charge more than the DVD.
Speaker 1: I mean, I got all of Zeta Gundam for $40.
Speaker 1: that ran it 50 episodes less than a dollar an episode.
Speaker 1: You can't charge five dollars an episode.
Speaker 0: I don't like having all that anime around the subscription service would be great because then I want my anime and I say I want To watch, you know Ghost in the Shell standalone complex again.
Speaker 0: So I log on and I just start watching it cuz I can watch as much anime as I want from the service for a Monthly fee.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And if I want to show it to someone else, I'll download it again.
Speaker 0: We'll watch it.
Speaker 0: We'll have a good old time but I don't want to have to buy and keep those physical DVDs around mostly because There was a point in my life at which I moved from Rochester, New York to Beacon, New York And after driving a 24-foot semi truck down a twisty mountain road for five and a half hours I don't want to own stuff anymore.
Speaker 1: No, I really don't want to own stuff either.
Speaker 1: But you know they just make the bit way people do business just makes it practical to buy and own stuff and Impractical to do things the way I'd like.
Speaker 1: and until that changes I really have no choice if I want to do certain things.
Speaker 0: So I think it was also Daryl on AWO to keep pimping them where he said something to the effect of Maybe it was general.
Speaker 0: I don't remember who said it That the industry should really look at how much a show that they sell for like some stupid stupid price Sells versus a show for the normal price.
Speaker 0: because I have a feeling that whenever they discount a show You know to like 30 bucks for the box set they probably sell crazy crazy numbers of shows that otherwise wouldn't sell.
Speaker 0: because I'll buy almost any show if it's 30 bucks for The whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just about any show.
Speaker 0: It has to be a pretty bad show for me to not shell out 30 bucks for the box set.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: I think what really the anime companies need to do is they should bring over the show.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait American anime company American one.
Speaker 1: Well, the Japanese ones have a lot of things they're doing wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if the American companies what you should do is you have you already have licensed a bunch of anime.
Speaker 1: a Lot of this anime is either no longer available on DVD, you know, it's hard to find on DVD is a long-lost show.
Speaker 1: I mean the shows that you were putting out on DVD in the 90s.
Speaker 1: Where are they now?
Speaker 1: The only shows that are really selling you're the hot new shows.
Speaker 1: the Naruto's the bleaches the Inuyasha is all that trick.
Speaker 1: So take all those old shows that you know The DVDs are already made and done with and put those all of them online for download at a cheap price.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much a pure profit at this point because you still have the licenses for those shows But you're not doing anything with them.
Speaker 1: You should have everything you own making money for you all the time.
Speaker 0: or how's this?
Speaker 0: I thought about this just now and I've seen people do half-assed attempts at this But I've never really seen it on the scale.
Speaker 0: that would make them a lot of money.
Speaker 0: They the companies in the US should as long as the licenses didn't expire anything like say uh, eska flown a right Eska flown a was one of the top shows when it was coming out.
Speaker 0: It was crazy popular and a lot of people have forgotten about it.
Speaker 0: What if they took eska flown a?
Speaker 0: they made You know the thin pack.
Speaker 0: not even a collector said just a cheap thin pack.
Speaker 0: They've mass produced it again They put it all out over the market and they coupled it with a huge advertising campaign about.
Speaker 0: this is classic awesome freaking anime.
Speaker 1: You don't even need to do that.
Speaker 1: just when you go to make a limited run bring it to a convey bring it to all the conventions and sell it.
Speaker 1: and You know, you're really at because you've already paid for the license and you've already made the profit on the show long ago You just.
Speaker 1: the only cost is the printing and the press.
Speaker 1: You know of the boxes and and the DVDs and the cases and all that jazz and the mastering of the DVDs You know.
Speaker 1: and you could just use the old DVDs, whatever.
Speaker 1: Just print up a whole mess of them and sell them at some stupid price like 50 bucks for a whole show.
Speaker 1: We're 40 bucks for a whole show and you'll rake it in.
Speaker 1: I mean if that guy's selling anime for five bucks a DVD is profiting Then you got to be profiting if you're selling them at like ten bucks a DVD plus like in the case of an old Good classic like escaflowne.
Speaker 0: You've already paid for the license.
Speaker 0: You've already paid for all the work except reprinting it yeah, and That this I'm sure shows like that would sell especially because you know There are a lot of people who get into anime on.
Speaker 0: you know The Inuyasha and whatever crap is on right now Because it seems like the stuff that's popular right now in America among new anime fans is kind of crap though I'm definitely gonna temper that with the fact that I liked a lot of crap.
Speaker 0: when I first got into anime I liked a lot of crap.
Speaker 1: I just said I like the Guyver.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Can't be friends with you anymore.
Speaker 0: All right, that's just.
Speaker 1: I think we should move on to another news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my news really isn't related to anime at all.
Speaker 0: I'll just skip it.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz I want to keep talking about this.
Speaker 0: Okay But really I mean a show like that.
Speaker 0: It'd be really easy to make it popular again.
Speaker 0: and all these people who you know They're just on the verge of transitioning from watching the crap to watching the good stuff You know in my mind at least in our, you know, cultured minds the quote unquote good stuff.
Speaker 0: And if there were like signature series classic series gold series Like here's the old anime that was crazy awesome and popular in the 90s.
Speaker 0: This is the stuff that the people who are two are older than you watching anime watched back when they were your age Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I think some sort of ad campaign like that definitely stressing that this is the real stuff This is the good stuff.
Speaker 0: All that other stuff just got you to this point where you can see this stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really think they could make a lot of money and I wish I was in charge of.
Speaker 1: maybe I should start an anime Company, you'd have to collect all the licenses that the current anime companies aren't using and then try to sell them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or I wonder if I could just get a job with some anime company and then convince them to do this.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'm pretty sure it would work.
Speaker 0: I'm almost certain.
Speaker 0: I would bet a significant amount of money on it.
Speaker 0: Of course, I don't have any money to bet.
Speaker 0: So yeah, yeah, I'll put all the money I've got my pockets right now toward this.
Speaker 0: I will do things of the day.
Speaker 1: How is this a great thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Even though it is not related in any way to anime manga or comics not at all.
Speaker 0: However, I will say that I have watched this entire thing twice.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I watched it once and I was glad when I found out I didn't have to watch it again.
Speaker 0: I only watched it again to make sure that I didn't miss anything because I will never need to watch anything like this At least for another five years while the idiots of the world work diligently to create enough material to make part two.
Speaker 1: Yes, well, I'm sure you may or may not know it is one of my favorite hobbies to peruse YouTube and Google video in search of what is known as Owned videos.
Speaker 0: now this came out of a lot Well, but this you might get argued that this came out of like the style projects.
Speaker 0: Yeah originally, but to skip a whole internet history lesson this came out of these photoshops which weren't really photoshops.
Speaker 0: if you found a picture of someone getting in the vernacular owned as in Getting their full comeuppance in some way or in other way in some way getting totally hosed by something Photoshopping the word owned onto the picture and putting it on Fark.
Speaker 1: Yep now go again to Videos on the internet that are funny and YouTube has really helped this along and so is Google video.
Speaker 1: But prior to that, you know There were still websites like College Humor and others where there would be videos and on peer-to-peer networks there would be videos win a max and such and These videos would be very short one to two minute videos that usually involve someone getting hurt such as puddle jumper.
Speaker 0: Yeah see there was this set of them like this set of these videos that Circulated the internet far and wide and pretty much everyone our age has seen all of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah bus Dodge bus Dodge 2000 which is at RIT death chaos.
Speaker 0: What's it?
Speaker 1: That's that's different.
Speaker 1: That's not an owned video, but some of it has some owning in it.
Speaker 0: In the similar vein to the owned video
Speaker 1: it is now Someone very smart a very smart person who is much smarter than we are went around the Internet's mostly the youtubes and Google videos and they collected 450 owned videos 450 idiots hurting themselves 450 guys on bicycles falling down and hitting their heads
Speaker 0: Yamakazis failing to make that critical leap across two high buildings
Speaker 1: People at weddings fainting
Speaker 0: a whole section of people getting hit in the balls with balls.
Speaker 0: It is just an idiot jumping down an escalator landing on his face and breaking it Someone deciding that the best thing in the world they can do is run up to a jack-o'-lantern Full of gasoline and on fire and hit it with a golf club.
Speaker 1: Yeah he took Four hundred and fifty owned videos and combined them into a single 33 minute long owned video.
Speaker 1: If you watch this you will not need to watch another owned video for probably the next five years.
Speaker 0: I also think you will lose any sense of compassion for any human being that harms themselves Due to no reason other than their own stupidity.
Speaker 1: Yes, that's pretty much what this is for.
Speaker 1: It will also make you laugh hysterically unless you're a bad human being in which case See, the thing is really well crafted and well timed.
Speaker 0: I mean it's set up in all these sections like there'll be a section of people getting hit with balls.
Speaker 0: There'll be a section of people almost getting owned but not getting owned Like a fee and a few of them like you cringe like oh, oh wow that oh my god.
Speaker 0: But then right after that there's a really funny one just like a guy's pants fall down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now there are.
Speaker 1: you know, I've seen a lot of owned videos in my day and I'd say 99% of them made it into This compilation.
Speaker 1: However, there were some that didn't make it into the compilation and I hope those will be compiled in the future.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now a little warning.
Speaker 0: technically this is a snuff film because I am sure that at least one of those people died It.
Speaker 1: some of those people had to have died or come near death.
Speaker 0: Luckily it is.
Speaker 0: there's no other than well No, there's really no obvious like wow that guy's dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also though there's one that with this train where you're certain that you're gonna see someone die Like oh my god, this is oh, you're about to look away and then nothing bad happens and the guy totally dodges the train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty crazy Very crazy, but all this is is a video of people doing stupid shit in some way or another and getting hurt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually getting hurt.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they barely escape pain.
Speaker 0: See now I wouldn't enjoy a video like this at all except for the fact that most of the people involved It's not like these are people who are just innocent normal guys getting hurt Seriously, it is innocent people getting hurt in minor and funny ways.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean or stupid people harming themselves Horribly.
Speaker 1: Yeah for some reason it's like if I see a video of a guy like, you know Getting bumped on the head walking down the street by like, you know some punk kids I get all like.
Speaker 1: hey, you know if I see someone getting hurt and it wasn't their fault Like let's say, you know a building just collapses on them I'm like, oh shit.
Speaker 1: but if I see someone do something to hurt themselves like that idiot who is wearing the polyester banana suit and set himself on fire with rubbing alcohol and got you Know horribly horribly burned and was like, you know, like should have gone to the hospital.
Speaker 1: I just laughed because he did it to himself.
Speaker 1: and that's what owned videos are all about.
Speaker 0: now fitting with the owned video That my thing of the day is the exact opposite.
Speaker 0: This is the one guy I mean.
Speaker 0: a lot of these stunts in the own video are people getting hurt trying to do very dangerous or very difficult things like Skateboarding in loops or you know jumping bicycles over things and all sorts of dangerous shit.
Speaker 0: Yep, but this is a video of the one guy the one out of a four hundred and fifty who tried to do these things Didn't die and got very good at it.
Speaker 0: this guy whose name is Ryan leech and the lifestyles of the rich and fabulous.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, this guy is probably the almighty god of Doing weird stunts with mountain bikes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you've seen those guys at the stunt bikes.
Speaker 1: You know the ones with the the pegs and they're really the small wheels and you know They do all kinds of stunts of those things, you know, they grind down rails And then all currently go up ramps.
Speaker 1: This guy has a mountain bike meant for mountain biking Yeah, and he does some crazy shit with it crazier than those stunt bike guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, good god I mean, I'm an amateur mountain bike.
Speaker 0: I've been biking for almost my entire life.
Speaker 0: I've been mountain biking for a long time like not nothing crazy.
Speaker 0: Don't get the wrong idea.
Speaker 0: I'm not like this crazy mountain biker.
Speaker 0: I'm actually pretty tame but I enjoy it a lot.
Speaker 0: and when Scott shows me the video I'm thinking alright He's never been mountain biking.
Speaker 0: This is probably lame.
Speaker 0: I doubted Scott I doubted him and the video starts.
Speaker 0: the guy does a couple of minor stops whatever.
Speaker 0: that's kind of tricky But it's not so bad.
Speaker 0: and then he does some pretty freaking amazing things.
Speaker 1: suddenly Most of what he does is he rides his mountain bike on very narrow railings without falling off.
Speaker 0: Yeah not even just riding but like he's on some railroad tracks like he's on the the bar the Railroad and then he hops his bike up and like two spins around now And he lands on the other Railroad track and he just starts riding.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like he'd let he's on one rail and he jumps in the air with the bike and lands on the other rail and he jumps distances on his bike that I Have tried to do things of an order of magnitude less danger and hurt myself severely.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we're not talking like horizontal distance.
Speaker 1: There's like in vertical distance There's one.
Speaker 1: he can go from a standstill and jump his bike like five feet in the air.
Speaker 0: He I saw he dropped at least 15 feet onto a slope at one point and was just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: I mean this guy's nuts.
Speaker 0: This is an amazing video and you should watch it.
Speaker 1: They really need to have some sort of competition for this sort of thing.
Speaker 1: I want to see if anyone else is better at.
Speaker 0: you know what this guy there just was.
Speaker 0: it's called the internet the winner that guy I mean, I'm a Christian there.
Speaker 0: Ooh, but I need to get that station.
Speaker 1: Thank you, ma.
Speaker 0: I'll be or II so in case you didn't catch what we've decided to talk about today.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about one of the newer anime we found that is Probably very close now to my top 10 comedy anime ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, it's actually not that new isn't it from like 2005?
Speaker 0: Not 1990?
Speaker 0: oh, no, this is I'm looking at the guy.
Speaker 0: I'm not looking at the show.
Speaker 0: Never mind.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's in 2005.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a. I mean, it's a fairly recent anime, but I love it, but December of 2005.
Speaker 1: It's Freaking Larry February February, whatever it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: The show is called gag manga Biore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's also known as Masuda Kosuke theater because the guy who created it is Masuda Kosuke.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was directed by Akitaro Daichi.
Speaker 1: Akitaro Daichi is actually a pretty hot director.
Speaker 0: I think he directed fruits basket and He did a whole bunch of things.
Speaker 0: I've never heard of Jubei-chan, he was the director of screenplay.
Speaker 1: It was a director of kotocha.
Speaker 0: Yep Whole bunch of other stuff never heard of.
Speaker 0: Oh God, he did storyboards retention universe.
Speaker 1: He was the Cameraman on grave of the fireflies.
Speaker 0: Hey, he did storyboards for an episode of mushishi.
Speaker 1: He directed elf princess rain.
Speaker 0: We got to review that.
Speaker 1: fucker sure do all right, so he's directed some other crazy crazy anime.
Speaker 1: I got to say this guy he's the director and original creator of now and then here and there.
Speaker 1: Wow Yeah, I wouldn't expect that.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Now if any of you out there have seen both elf princess rain and now and then here and there Would you have ever in a billion years thought that the same guy directed both of them?
Speaker 0: not ever.
Speaker 1: I mean to put it very very simple Hell you would you couldn't have told me the same guy directed fruits basket and Gog manga VR.
Speaker 0: But princess rain is a show that is I can't describe.
Speaker 0: It's just beyond silly.
Speaker 1: It makes.
Speaker 1: I'm so cool smart.
Speaker 1: I'm so cool.
Speaker 1: I'm so smart.
Speaker 0: But that show makes Excel saga look like a serious tragedy.
Speaker 1: It sure does.
Speaker 0: and yet now and then here and there is Nothing more than children being raped and ravaged by the horrors of war with absolutely no Possible redemption.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what that is.
Speaker 1: So that's that's where guts who made Gog manga VR.
Speaker 1: now, what is Gog manga VR II?
Speaker 1: well It's it's an episodic show.
Speaker 1: some of the episodes carry into others, but not much and they're very short episodes You know and the opener and the closer combined are usually as long as the episode itself.
Speaker 0: I mean this shows like five minutes long and It's basically a wacky wacky comedy, you know in terms of wacky wacky comedy It's actually a as Emily told us and we then did a little research on our own.
Speaker 0: It is a very specific type of Japanese comedy.
Speaker 1: Yes in in Japan There is a type of comedy called Mon's eye.
Speaker 0: now It's had different names over the years and different kanji and all this stuff, but don't worry about that.
Speaker 1: Basically what Mon's eye is at its core is a style of comedy in which there are is a duo two people.
Speaker 1: One of them is the straight man And one of them is the goofy guy just like, you know, Evan Costello and all those olds to old-school American comedy teams and It's the tsukomi and the bokeh.
Speaker 1: Yes The bokeh is the funny guy and the tsukomi is the straight man.
Speaker 0: Now the typical humor generally is along the lines of the funny guy says something stupid He's usually forgetful or slow or just dumb or weird or insane and just says things that don't make sense Or things that are dumb and the straight man just basically yells at him like wow, you're stupid to the stupidest bad I've ever met.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: How could anyone be as stupid as you and interrupts him and hits him over the head.
Speaker 1: Yeah now in as among Adele you might remember these scenes where Tomo-chan would you know hit or you know?
Speaker 1: slightly slap Osaka and then say something like what the hell?
Speaker 1: or Yeah, they were making fun of Monzai comedy because Monzai comedy has been associated with Osaka.
Speaker 0: It was to to quote a probably the least credible source in the world from Wikipedia here quote in recent times Monzai has often been associated with the Osaka region and Monzai comedians often speak with a Kansai dialect during their acts, right?
Speaker 1: So what Tomo-chan is doing?
Speaker 1: the joke is that you know because Osaka is from Osaka He's trying to do this Monzai act, you know to show that you know, she's more Monzai funny than Osaka is I guess and that's why it's not funny to us.
Speaker 1: and you go what the hell what the hell?
Speaker 0: But I mean that it if you haven't seen these shows it might sound like it's stupid But if you haven't seen Abbott and Costello, it sounds like the stupidest thing ever.
Speaker 0: you got a role with this.
Speaker 0: Yeah You gotta just watch this show with an open mind and I guarantee you'll be laughing by the end of the first episode Which is probably the best episode.
Speaker 1: the way Gog manga biore goes is you know?
Speaker 1: mo basically the format of an episode is there's some sort of setting and some sort of set up for a plot and There's one character who is the straight man and one character who is crazy.
Speaker 1: and the crazy person See in got at least most of the time in Gog manga biore seems to be saying things seriously like something serious Something serious like and the straight man is go who you know is intelligent and isn't a crazy person is going.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I'm going to visit the Emperor of China I'll advise you I'm going to bring him.
Speaker 0: I don't remember what the episodes without but I'm going to do something really really really really really really really stupid.
Speaker 0: There's like what but it'll kill you.
Speaker 0: Oh my god What's wrong with you is like.
Speaker 0: and then I'm going to blah blah blah blah and the show just goes nuts from there.
Speaker 1: a Good example of the show.
Speaker 1: I think is the second episode really the second episode the one with the the girl who draws the?
Speaker 0: No, that's in them.
Speaker 0: That's the second half of the first episode in the second half of the first episode Ruin the first half of the first episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the first episode is probably the funniest thing in this show.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna explain the second half of the first episode to give you an idea why this is funny.
Speaker 1: Here's the setup.
Speaker 1: The straight man is a guy who runs a company that sells bread I think or some sort of cookie or something and In the cookie is included a collectible dokka Mon sticker.
Speaker 0: Doki mod is obviously play on Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Yes, now he has one employee who was drawing the dokka Mon stickers.
Speaker 1: who is the not straight person the bokeh.
Speaker 0: The thing is she acts very calm the whole time and very serious and he just loses it.
Speaker 0: Yes They're playing these reversed roles.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So she says something like, you know, he's like why look at this Takara kun that you drew.
Speaker 1: takara kun is like the ash Ketchum and he's like look at the one in the anime.
Speaker 1: Why aren't they the same, you know?
Speaker 1: and he says, you know How come you haven't drawn any monsters the monsters of the reap but kids like in dokka Mon.
Speaker 1: Why are all the stickers takara kun?
Speaker 1: and she's like takara kun is the only one in my dokka Mon world.
Speaker 1: And then she says it perfectly seriously and he's like, oh my god How am I supposed to sell bread with all these stickers?
Speaker 0: Oh my god, like she starts going like she's touched saying crazy things.
Speaker 0: She's like the epitome of scary fanfic writing fangirl crazy person.
Speaker 0: But she's saying it in this that kara kun is the only person in my dokka Mon world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't like any of the monsters.
Speaker 1: and dokka Mon Look when I tried to draw the monsters They're not very lively and she got a picture of like a chicken cooking over a fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like she's drawn the dragon from the show dead cooking over a fire and the guys just like what you're insane.
Speaker 0: Yeah now again, it might not sound that funny with us describing it There is no way I can express to you how hilarious the show is because there's no.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like trying to Describe a joke without telling the joke exactly exactly now in future episodes There's a lot of stuff that kind of plays on Japanese history and old Japanese stories a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yes, the one I really like to talk about is everyone remembers when you know Perry and the black ships coming and opening up Japan.
Speaker 0: But there was another man sent somewhat later named Harris.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one really remembers hair.
Speaker 0: Well, Emily remembered Harris, but she knows a lot about Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I heard his name maybe once before watching this show.
Speaker 1: But people in Japan know who Harris is because they learn about him in history class.
Speaker 0: So Paris is there and he's talking about how he wants to be known in Japan.
Speaker 0: He wants to make his mark like Perry did and he has this Japanese guy with him as the advisor.
Speaker 0: And he gets to the point where he's like I know how I'll be remembered and he opens his notebook and he's drawn this Geiger as horrid like monstrosity of a monster train like it's got this Medusa face on like this this fucked up thing and he's very calmly.
Speaker 0: he's like I will build this and I will ride about in Japan and blah blah blah blah blah blah blah And then people will remember me.
Speaker 0: I will have a legacy and the Japanese guys like what.
Speaker 0: that's crazy.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: This is insane.
Speaker 0: You can't build that.
Speaker 0: and then he pulls the book down and there's a window behind the book and he's already built the thing And it's sitting out there and all of its horrid glory ready to go and then it just gets crazier from there.
Speaker 1: I think that's actually the second episode with Harris.
Speaker 1: in the first episode with Harris He's like, I know I'll run around naked and he runs around.
Speaker 0: He's like, I know I'll eat some dirt.
Speaker 0: That'll make the Japanese notice me and the guys like they're noticing you, but they just think you're insane.
Speaker 0: What the hell's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: I should just kill myself.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just.
Speaker 1: it's a bunch of jokes Just like that and it's it's just crazy stuff happens Which is funny and then the one normal guy watching the crazy stuff happens reacts in a funny way and it's funny again.
Speaker 1: and Any one of these jokes would get old if you know, you tried to carry them on for a long time.
Speaker 1: But since each episode is maybe five minutes and some of the jokes only go for half an episode You know, it gets funny.
Speaker 1: and then as soon as the joke runs out shows over watch the next episode.
Speaker 0: Yep, like the first episode because I really can't ruin or even talk about what goes on in the first episode with the stickers.
Speaker 0: I hope I'm not hyping it up too much, but I Almost I couldn't breathe laughing.
Speaker 0: but because it like a little funny thing happens and a weird thing happens and a funny thing happens and as you're watching like you're you're kind of chuckling a little bit like hey, yeah, and With every few seconds as some more things happen the laughter grows and like the feeling of humor in your gut Grows and grows and grows and grows and grows and then it tapers off at the end.
Speaker 0: You know the guys walking out to his car to the end of the episode and then at the very end The very last thing that happens is like the little boy pulling his finger out of the dike and the dam collapses And you just lose it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, another thing you had to know about this show is that the pacing is very fast.
Speaker 0: I mean they talk like this.
Speaker 0: They just keep talking as fast as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: You can almost barely understand what they're saying.
Speaker 0: if there were some tells everybody be able to deal with it all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the sub thought I mean if we knew Japanese you'd probably be okay, you know, cuz it's like the micro machines guy.
Speaker 1: We can understand what he's saying But barely yeah, the subtitles are gonna disappear pretty quick.
Speaker 1: if you want to get everything you can out of an episode You're probably gonna need to watch it twice unless you're just really good at reading subtitles and looking at the pictures because there's a lot Of also subtle jokes that are hidden without the episode that you have to yet to be quick about like in the very first episode.
Speaker 1: You know it like pans across this room with four characters and their names are written in very small subtitles Like, you know someone the bear eater or something like that?
Speaker 1: These are all like market marketing executives in a company and one guy's like John the human computer in Jake the chain wielder.
Speaker 1: and if you don't if you don't look closely You're not gonna see the joke that hey that guy's name is chain wielder.
Speaker 0: or even listening to what they're saying I mean in the Harris episode, you know He's built this monstrosity and they're about to take it out across Japan and a reign of terror and the guy's like.
Speaker 0: I'm going to sit in the control booth with blah blah blah blah blah and a comfortable leather chair.
Speaker 0: You will sit on this platform and the bottom of the machine that will be moving up and down Incredibly fast to the point that it will probably kill you and the guy's like.
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: but that's just crazy.
Speaker 0: Why does my scene have to move up and down and the guy's like?
Speaker 0: well obviously because it's attached to the wheel.
Speaker 0: Yeah But then he goes on and he talks about how there are only two options.
Speaker 0: now, this is just like a throwaway.
Speaker 0: There are only two options in the control booth.
Speaker 0: The first option is bomb the wrong place.
Speaker 0: The other option is self-destruct.
Speaker 1: Why would you make those buttons?
Speaker 0: Why would you make?
Speaker 0: I Hope that's not just an error in the translation But I don't think it was because Emily watched the episode with us.
Speaker 0: but bomb the wrong place.
Speaker 0: What kind of mind thinks of a joke like that?
Speaker 1: Someone who's making fun of the u.s Who makes devices that has a button?
Speaker 1: This is bomb the wrong place.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he was making fun of the u.s.
Speaker 0: Or if he's just insane.
Speaker 1: I don't know but It's it's hilarious.
Speaker 1: I mean it is a gag manga.
Speaker 1: It's not meant to be serious.
Speaker 1: It's just wacky wacky wacky.
Speaker 0: now I would also like to say that I mean I like the opening song.
Speaker 0: I really like it.
Speaker 0: I like it too, but the closing song.
Speaker 0: I mean you'll be last priceless.
Speaker 0: Now That is just a sampling of the closing song because someone Different sings it in every episode and it is different in every episode.
Speaker 0: I mean one time it's like this animated thing one time.
Speaker 0: It's this sketchy animation of a fat guy Singing it and this other guy pinching his nipples.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't ask me about that.
Speaker 1: one.
Speaker 0: one time and I fell off the couch laughing it was it was this robot this poorly animated robot and Super imposed a normal person's lips singing the song and for some reason it was just disturbing and hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just a different voice making that series of noises every time and you know in a very short show where the opener And the closer take up a significant portion of the time in the episode It's good to see that the closer is actually worth watching.
Speaker 1: You know the opener.
Speaker 1: you can watch once and it'll be okay, even though it's a crazy opener.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean some shows are like that and some shows aren't like Wolf's reign or Evangelion.
Speaker 0: the openers were just useless Absolutely useless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you've seen him once.
Speaker 1: you've seen him the whole show you're done.
Speaker 0: I mean, oh, it's a naked ray And she's spinning while someone sings flying me to the moon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least in Gundam seed, you know the opener changes.
Speaker 1: So you have to watch all the different openers and closes But you still need to watch them once.
Speaker 1: and Gog manga B or E you can watch.
Speaker 1: every closer is different.
Speaker 0: You can at the end of every show you stay for the closing and at any moment when you think all right This joke is played out.
Speaker 0: They immediately change to another joke.
Speaker 1: Yeah the timing of joke changing is pretty much spot-on.
Speaker 0: now if we haven't sold you on the show which I don't know how well we Can because it's really really hard to explain this type of humor
Speaker 1: pretty much You're either going to find it absolutely Hysterical or you're gonna think it's the weirdest thing you've seen in your life and that anyone who likes it and laughs at it is Fucked up.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'll say very simply if I showed that if you showed this to anyone who wasn't familiar with Japanese culture or anime and at least some way the only possible thing they could say to you is what the fuck was that?
Speaker 0: exactly Now I guess if we haven't sold you on it if you like, I don't know Cromartie High School or Excel saga or Abbott and Costello or elf princess rain.
Speaker 0: Oh god, I'll princess rain You will probably enjoy this show
Speaker 1: Probably now,
Speaker 0: of course last not least we're gonna be plugging this pretty much for the next two weeks But next not this weekend, but next weekend October
Speaker 1: 6 7 and 8
Speaker 0: We are going to be guests at sita con.
Speaker 0: Sita con in Utica, New York.
Speaker 1: It is the SUNY Institute of Technology anime club convention, it's a bit east of Syracuse on the throughway.
Speaker 0: It's you know upstate.
Speaker 0: It's really easy for everyone to get to.
Speaker 0: I know we have a lot of listeners at RIT.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend you go to this convention But we are going to be guests.
Speaker 0: we are doing among other things a Anime match game show which people from our team may remember being run very successfully, you know, it's kind of based on a 70s match game.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be on this huge Podcasting panel with among other people perhaps my favorite cop-fought podcast in the world fast karate for the gentlemen And they're rust hurricanes.
Speaker 1: What's up, David?
Speaker 1: Joe?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've listened to about ten of their episodes in the past four days.
Speaker 1: David Joel calm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean they are about as professional as we are Unprofessional.
Speaker 1: They They're pretty unprofessional but the thing is but that's what makes them awesome.
Speaker 0: It doesn't hurt their show at all.
Speaker 1: It doesn't because their shows all about what they say and nothing else.
Speaker 0: their show is about being unprofessional.
Speaker 0: They're unprofessional professionally That's damn right, but and a whole bunch of other people.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember who all we're gonna.
Speaker 1: entertainment system The the band.
Speaker 1: that's awesome Martin long the video game pianist one half of the ninja consultants Aaron from the weekly anime review podcast the night shift Podcast.
Speaker 0: yeah, happy house of hentai happy house of hentai.
Speaker 1: and you know, I don't know them I don't know if they're good people or not, but I'm not about to listen to a hentai podcast.
Speaker 0: Sorry Yeah, unless it might be funny.
Speaker 0: It might have nothing to do with hentai.
Speaker 1: That is a possibility I'll have to invest.
Speaker 0: I mean Dave and Joel have nothing to do with karate or gentlemen.
Speaker 1: Oh, they have much to do with gentlemen.
Speaker 1: You are quite mistaken.
Speaker 0: Anyway We're also going to be doing you know a geek nights meet-and-greet panel which Will be interesting because I don't know how many of our fans our fans have already know us are going to be going to this Con.
Speaker 0: so it might just be fans.
Speaker 0: We pick up at the convention.
Speaker 1: It might just be us hanging out in a room going.
Speaker 0: We're also doing a podcasting workshop.
Speaker 0: Yep, and We're going to be sitting on a your favorite anime sucks or something to that effect panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got to see how that done.
Speaker 1: a hundred percent sure about that.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we're probably.
Speaker 0: we're probably going to be doing something hilarious with Dave and Joel Yeah, and maybe someone else.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I haven't gotten the full details on everything yet.
Speaker 1: So we're giving you the Unfinished details.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's it called the rough?
Speaker 1: What's the word for?
Speaker 1: not a hundred percent sure again.
Speaker 0: ninety-five percent sure.
Speaker 1: no preliminary.
Speaker 0: Yeah preliminary works.
Speaker 1: What's the one that most people use?
Speaker 1: a tentative?
Speaker 0: tentative?
Speaker 1: Um What?
Speaker 1: there's another word that's a synonym that I'm missing.
Speaker 0: come up with plenty of words.
Speaker 1: I know but there's one synonym.
Speaker 1: That's the one I'm looking for.
Speaker 0: Well, you haven't given me enough to give you a synonym.
Speaker 0: That'll probably work.
Speaker 0: the projected plan.
Speaker 1: No Yeah, hold on.
Speaker 1: I'm getting to the website.
Speaker 0: Hold on what website?
Speaker 0: All right, we're not Way to go.
Speaker 0: yep, you know if it weren't for the fact that we'd be stealing there'd be a thought bird right about there.
Speaker 1: There would be.
Speaker 0: well today is just the anime world order and fast karate for the gentleman episode of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we might as well just let them do our super chill.
Speaker 1: What do we need us for?
Speaker 0: Well, I'll say one.
Speaker 0: both of you out there YouTube podcasting duo trios.
Speaker 0: I don't want to leave Clarissa out.
Speaker 1: should watch guy like colors is assumed to be the one left out when it's a duo Because Clarissa is always the voice of reason.
Speaker 0: I know I mean I don't.
Speaker 0: I often disagree with her But she's always the reasonable one whenever Gerald and Darryl go off on a rant.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: If you put her on fast karate, I don't know what would happen.
Speaker 1: Oh god.
Speaker 0: Okay, I think someone would die And I don't think it would be her.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: it wouldn't work because it's a show for gentlemen and she's a gentle woman.
Speaker 0: But regardless go to sit a con.
Speaker 0: It's a first-year convention.
Speaker 0: This is the first time they've done it and it's a three-day thing.
Speaker 0: I really wanted to succeed because the only other big good con up there at all in upstate, New York Right now is Tarkan, which is only a one-day shindig.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're paying our way for.
Speaker 1: you know The hotel and our gas and stuff.
Speaker 1: So if you go and buy a badge, you're actually paying for our hotel room indirectly Sorta, so help them out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus I mean meeting us in person.
Speaker 0: I have to say that all the fans we've met so far have been really cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you're really cool, you'll come see us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Utica, New York because I got to say hanging out with the front row crew The only thing better than that is a rust hurricane Shit, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.