Speaker 0: It's Wednesday April 19th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about two anime zegapane and air gear.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Well like we've said this weekend.
Speaker 0: We're heading out to Rochester to do a live show at ToraCon Hooray, I have to drive for many hours Yeah, but with a whole bunch of people it'll be fun and tiring.
Speaker 0: at least It won't likely be like our last foray into Rochester, which was an unmitigated failure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the first time I think we ever screwed something up, but it really wasn't so much us a hundred percent
Speaker 0: yeah, well it was more that we planned everything out and we decided to go to Rochester and do a thing and Somehow through no fault of our own the thing we'd planned to do was cancelled by the people who were supposed to be doing it Thus leaving us in the lurch This time.
Speaker 0: they can't cancel it because I know there are hundreds and hundreds of people who are also coming to do the same Thing and if they cancel it will rally those hundreds of people and teach them a lesson.
Speaker 0: Yep a lesson involving fire.
Speaker 1: Involving fire that's that's a good lesson.
Speaker 1: I was expecting to teach him a different lesson Involving acid, but that's a fire lesson is good, too alright, so It's Wednesday.
Speaker 1: I got some comic news here.
Speaker 1: apparently Some comic books of the American variety are gonna start doing product placements like in the olden days.
Speaker 0: No, not obscure comics or like little indie comics that need money.
Speaker 1: we're talking like the new x-men yeah, like characters will have like a Nike swoosh on their shirt and such and There's like it bombs outside.
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 0: All right, we're sorry if we sound a little distracted at this point But there is apparently a small world war going on outside our house.
Speaker 1: I was about to make the same joke.
Speaker 0: you bastard That's what happens when you live with the same geeks for long enough.
Speaker 1: So yeah, but seriously like there's a major shelling going on down the road We get we really don't know what's going on, but and we're gonna try to ignore it.
Speaker 0: But just so you know if we periodically sound distracted is because there's fucking explosions going on outside.
Speaker 1: Yeah We're not even joking.
Speaker 1: you might hear them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're pretty loud Alright, so comics comics product placements.
Speaker 0: now this product placement isn't in like the obscure crap.
Speaker 0: This isn't like the new x-men or whatever comics are popular with you young kids in other words the unobscure crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, so the point is is that some people are like product placement is evil.
Speaker 1: Oh my god what the fuck and other people are like.
Speaker 1: Product placement is just fine.
Speaker 1: It even makes it more real why you know instead of having some generic ass clothing It's more like the real world where everything's brand up now to me.
Speaker 0: There are basically two kinds of product placement.
Speaker 0: I generally break it up into the good kind and the bad kind or more likely the indifferent kind and the hateful kind.
Speaker 0: I mean on one hand.
Speaker 0: There's alright say in a script a guy drinks a soda from a can and it doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: It's not important to the plot.
Speaker 0: It's not like dr.
Speaker 0: Peppers the cure for AIDS at the end of the movie.
Speaker 0: So if the guy if dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper pays whatever to make that can of dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper can instead of mr.
Speaker 0: Pibb can I don't care Because it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: he was drinking a soda.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Now if it's like that national treasure movie where not only is everyone in the movie drinking like Dasani or Aquafina, I don't know which one it was but they were drinking one of those bottle.
Speaker 0: Well, I didn't even notice.
Speaker 0: so I noticed it because there's one scene where he's like he's looking at something and he can't read it.
Speaker 0: so he grabs of one of the bottles of water and holds it up in front of the camera like a magnifying glass and Like the camera zooms in and focuses on the label for a second and it's like wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay If that happens, that's definitely out of place.
Speaker 1: But the thing that really gets me is when they do product placements Let's say Pepsi pays for a product placement, right and Coke doesn't.
Speaker 1: all of a sudden I mean sure it makes sense That if say it was a comic taking place at one college that Pepsi bought out the college everything would be Pepsi But Pepsi didn't buy out the world.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna place brands in there if you want to talk about realism You got to put all the brands in there.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean there should be a Pepsi machine next to a coke machine.
Speaker 1: That's that's realism.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then Pepsi won't pay.
Speaker 1: No shit.
Speaker 1: See that's the problem is.
Speaker 1: the other problem is that They you know, you should be able to put those things in there without paying or getting paid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is that I want to make a comic and have all kinds of different real brands in there.
Speaker 1: I should be allowed to do that.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean back in the day.
Speaker 0: a lot of video games wanted to do that sort of thing and the companies would always say no.
Speaker 0: So you were forced to have these like generic made-up like cola cora stuff floating around coral Cola.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Was that?
Speaker 1: that's the star tropics?
Speaker 1: I think the island was named coral Cola or something.
Speaker 0: Ah star tropics was a good game.
Speaker 1: They need to bring that shit back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though the game is now just tedious and difficult It's not so.
Speaker 1: at least you get the yo-yo action in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you also get the tedium.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's alright.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so yeah comic nerds are in an uproar over this and I'm fine with that because I Don't really.
Speaker 1: I don't read any of the comics that are gonna get ads in them.
Speaker 0: I just don't like comic nerds.
Speaker 0: Yeah there's a big difference between a comic geek and a comic nerd.
Speaker 0: comic nerds the people who read like the 1970s spider-man and they they swear by and they think it's awesome.
Speaker 1: Worst advertisement ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right All right, so I commute about Five minutes.
Speaker 0: Scott commutes about an hour.
Speaker 0: He used to commute about an hour into the city.
Speaker 0: Yep And it's my opinion that an hour is probably the longest commute.
Speaker 0: I could stand without Freaking out and killing everyone in the world.
Speaker 1: if my commute was any longer that room wouldn't be here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now there's some contest.
Speaker 0: I think Midas put it on.
Speaker 0: I don't really care where they were trying to find whoever in us had the longest commute of anyone.
Speaker 1: Well, it's obvious.
Speaker 1: see some guy probably uses a helicopter or something.
Speaker 0: no, it's some dude who drives Seven hours total every day to his job with Cisco.
Speaker 1: What what what the hell?
Speaker 1: How did you sit in the?
Speaker 1: I can barely sit three and a half hours like a day trip?
Speaker 1: Like I'm going somewhere.
Speaker 0: three and a half hours is almost to Rochester.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm here.
Speaker 0: It's crazy in three and a half hours.
Speaker 0: I caught them now.
Speaker 0: The thing is the contest was you know that you had to verify it.
Speaker 0: I have a sneaking suspicion a tiny suspicion that this is not entirely legitimate.
Speaker 0: My I have this feeling that it's possible that he does indeed work at the Cisco.
Speaker 0: That is 168 miles from his house.
Speaker 0: I Goddamn those explosions outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'll get the sandbags ready.
Speaker 0: They're really loud.
Speaker 0: if we suddenly scream and go off the air Well, you will never hear it because we won't be alive to put the episode up.
Speaker 1: But oh geez I guess radio has an advantage.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: No, yeah Now I it's possible that he might in fact drive to this place occasionally But I wouldn't be surprised if he just thought you know telecommutes most of the time.
Speaker 1: I got a feeling.
Speaker 1: I mean it could also be a situation like this one lady who works in my company.
Speaker 1: she has a house in Florida a house in Rhode Island and a house in Tarrytown and Most of the time like during the week She's in the Tarrytown house because she'll go to New York City or she'll go to the office that I'm at Which aren't too far away from Tarrytown.
Speaker 1: But on the weekends, she goes to her Rhode Island house And then I guess she also goes to her Florida house sometime.
Speaker 0: See now, that's cool.
Speaker 0: Like if I had a What the hell?
Speaker 1: I don't know but it was a contest for longest commute.
Speaker 1: I would say I live in Rhode Island and my office is in New York City, haha No, they apparently did some sort of checking.
Speaker 0: they had to verify and they had all sorts of crap about it Mm-hmm, but in general I've discovered that Americans commute longer than any other nationality.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: It's because we have a lot more land to traverse.
Speaker 0: It's not just that New Yorkers have the longest average commute of anyone.
Speaker 1: Well because you look at the state of New York and most of the people are working Closer to the city and most of the people live farther away from it.
Speaker 0: So well, actually almost half the people live in the city and half the people live everywhere else combined.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but that's but more than half the people work in the city.
Speaker 0: The problem is just that Americans in general seem to have this aversion to living near any sort of industry at all.
Speaker 0: So as a result, we've got these like suburban communities surrounding places where actual work is done And you can't actually live somewhere where there's a job.
Speaker 1: I Would love to live closer to my job.
Speaker 1: The problem is I don't want to live in a shithole.
Speaker 1: if there was a nice place to live near the job Other people seem to not want to live or maybe no one just want.
Speaker 1: no one thinks anyone wants to live near the job So they don't build a nice place there because then no one will live in it.
Speaker 0: The other problem is that jobs require people from all sorts of different places Mm-hmm, and those people might not all want to end up living together or for whatever reason don't want to live there or there aren't enough people.
Speaker 0: like a place where you'll find a job somewhere and There's a company that hires say a thousand people But you couldn't sustain all thousand people living in that area.
Speaker 0: like there aren't enough services or anything Nope, so those communities just don't appear and everyone has to commute Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean honestly, I've been poking around for jobs for the last several months.
Speaker 0: I have not found a single job worth taking that is not in New York City.
Speaker 0: at this point I have not found a single one not one.
Speaker 0: the closest job that isn't in New York City is in Yonkers Which is basically in New York City.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's just like this little weird Sort of crazy city thing above New York.
Speaker 1: That's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: It's a really nice place.
Speaker 0: I've never been down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it has all sorts of weird laws that apply to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, God, I'll have to pay point five percent commuter tax if I work there.
Speaker 1: It's a really strange thing.
Speaker 1: Yonkers is.
Speaker 0: yeah to the people who decided how Yonkers taxes work.
Speaker 0: You can die in a fire.
Speaker 1: It's not just taxes.
Speaker 1: There are other weird things about you.
Speaker 0: I don't care about the rest of it cuz I would never live there, but I don't think it just even being there is weird I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's just an okay place.
Speaker 0: Their taxes are weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, but people just really the worst thing is most people who commute in this country commute by car Meaning.
Speaker 0: they can't do anything else with that time.
Speaker 0: that time is lost.
Speaker 1: You can listen to things on the radio or a podcast like this one or something, but that's about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that amazes me.
Speaker 0: I mean if I have a commute like that, I'm taking a train or something so I can do something with my time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used to take the train but now there's no train that goes where I go.
Speaker 0: Oh, there'll be a train that goes close if the MTA has its way.
Speaker 0: It'll probably be finished in the next decade.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's not really good enough.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: it'll take you to Danbury.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then how do I get from Danbury to where I work which is like a half hour?
Speaker 0: Oh, well, obviously you buy in a car and you keep it parked at the train station there.
Speaker 1: How do I get from here to the train station?
Speaker 1: It's no good.
Speaker 1: I'll need two cars.
Speaker 0: I can't do that Though it looks like I'll be commuting on the train to Yonkers.
Speaker 0: great.
Speaker 0: This job is really cool-looking, but that's all beside the point.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the point is other than I really Think people commute far too much in this country And I think that things need to be done about that or at least to make commuting less detrimental to life.
Speaker 1: One day I'll get a job or that's close to my house or a house close to a job or something.
Speaker 1: I'll be all set.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just seems that so many people like put their job before all else or like they live their life around their job.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz they don't have anything else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the people only geeks have something else the people where I work now currently It's like most of them have absolutely no Actual life outside of their job.
Speaker 1: like they come to work and they're like at least I'm not home with my wife Or maybe they actually have a family but then all they've got is job family But they don't.
Speaker 1: the family doesn't do things besides.
Speaker 1: generic American family watch TV crap.
Speaker 0: well, I guess the worst thing is that most of them seem to really not like their spouses and It seems like it's not kosher to ask them.
Speaker 0: Well, why did you marry them or why are you still married?
Speaker 1: That's weird.
Speaker 1: I mean like all that kind of stuff is like foreign to me cuz like, you know sure sometimes my dad will be like Don't let your mother know or don't tell your mother.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's part of it ever like damn wife.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, I don't have that action.
Speaker 1: So it's all weird.
Speaker 1: I don't know people like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should read the internet.
Speaker 0: I mean more than I think they're at this point is like 60% of all marriages end in divorce.
Speaker 1: It's also weird like all my aunts and uncles and you know, what are my parents friends all these married people?
Speaker 1: They don't seem to be no one's like that.
Speaker 1: They're all Married stay married kind of happy people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, relatively speaking.
Speaker 0: Some of them are better than others But maybe just all the people I work with maybe they're all just bitter old engineers.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's how IBM does it to them.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I. it's a complicated thing.
Speaker 0: I could do a whole episode.
Speaker 0: I'm very surprised.
Speaker 1: some subliminal IVM things like hate your spouse hate your spouse.
Speaker 1: IVM is better.
Speaker 0: The worst thing about it is that they always say things like one who's getting married and he's spending, you know Obscene stupid amounts of money on the marriage and I was like I could run an awesome wedding for like two gray.
Speaker 0: And he was like are you kid?
Speaker 0: You don't know anything.
Speaker 0: You'll get married and have a family and blah blah blah blah blah Like everyone's always like yes, you'll get married and then you'll be miserable.
Speaker 0: Hahaha It's like they can't imagine that people could actually have a real relationship.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like people saying uh, you'll go to college and then you'll see well, what if I don't go to college?
Speaker 0: Or it'll be a conservative when you grow up and you realize how things work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I get that a lot really.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: It's like people like you're only liberal because you're young.
Speaker 1: Well, there is that old somewhat true saying that you know, if you're a socialist and you're 20 and all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind of true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, kinda the problem is that I'm.
Speaker 0: I don't see my political views changing significantly over time.
Speaker 0: No, if anything I see them solidifying into a hateful mass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I see.
Speaker 1: Also, I guess people just seem to think that like laws of society or somehow also laws of the universe.
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's more that people at least in terms of the specific thing on marriage and these people with their long commutes and their horrible jobs is that they're fairly miserable at least that's my opinion and They can't imagine that other people or they couldn't deal with the fact that other people actually aren't miserable or didn't make the same mistakes.
Speaker 0: They did so.
Speaker 0: they assume that everyone makes the same mistakes or everyone does the same stupid crap and then they feel okay about themselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz they all like commiserate about that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, my wife sucks Oh, my husband sucks and then they all get drunk and go out and whatever.
Speaker 0: hmm I'm ranting.
Speaker 0: I'll have to do let's not be those people.
Speaker 1: Hey if anyone's out there and you're those people Call me.
Speaker 0: I Think it'd be really hard for us to become those people.
Speaker 1: Yeah would be.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, I mean my life is generally awesome And if my life were ever not awesome I would do something about that.
Speaker 1: the only thing on Awesome about my life is the job and it seems that these people the job is the awesomest thing they've got.
Speaker 0: My job is just a means of putting money into my wallet which I think it can then spend on having fun with.
Speaker 1: you know Friends me too, but on the same token I actually want a job that where there's something to the job and not just sitting there doing nothing all day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you know you lose time in the car.
Speaker 1: I don't want to lose more time at the job.
Speaker 0: Well work on other projects.
Speaker 0: I am now just don't go to work.
Speaker 1: I can't do that.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: They'll eventually find out.
Speaker 0: so by then you'll have found a new job.
Speaker 1: I haven't even looked yet.
Speaker 1: I probably should.
Speaker 1: I've actually gotten offers because people still have been sending me offers ever since I Graduated college and started looking for a job.
Speaker 0: I've had like this stream of offers I will be trickles in all the time logged into my old RIT email account and there were like seven or eight job offers that I'd never.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm logged into my old CS email and there were job offers in there, and I was like oh Well these are sucky job offers at least all right.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna do your Java Oracle whatnots.
Speaker 0: yeah, if you were like yeah, you want to do some novell network for us.
Speaker 1: I'm like no Hey come and help us do our You know Microsoft visual whatnots.
Speaker 0: All right, we've gotten way off topic.
Speaker 0: I blame the explosions.
Speaker 1: So we think of the day explosions.
Speaker 0: Let's do the things of the day, and then let's do the anime all right.
Speaker 0: So things of the day.
Speaker 0: now that we're getting back on topic here Dare laugh dare ding.
Speaker 1: They're laughing their dinger.
Speaker 0: That's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: ding-ding-ding.
Speaker 0: It's long and I'll say right now that there are obvious Incredibly obvious edits in it, which I'm not sure if we're done for time or for setup or what have you?
Speaker 1: I think some of them were done for time and some of them might have a tiny bit of cheating going on.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't matter cheating or no.
Speaker 0: It's fairly impressive and fairly interesting.
Speaker 0: It's a Obviously German video of a massive and convoluted and very slow-moving Fire based Rube Goldberg machine.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of fire and a lot of fuses and a lot of liquid chemicals mixing to create fogs and mists and a few of the Mechanics they use multiple times which is boring.
Speaker 0: It's very neat though that is very slow and very in but very precise and more importantly.
Speaker 0: It's very very I guess crude looking Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's really hard to just watch it.
Speaker 0: It's a half-hour long.
Speaker 0: You don't have to watch the whole thing and no it doesn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: It just stops.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the best part was the wheel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's one and not there a bunch of wheels that roll.
Speaker 1: There's one wheel that just keeps going one wheel that it's like Usually you have a wheel.
Speaker 1: it rolls it hits something and then you move away from the wheel.
Speaker 1: This is a wheel that moved.
Speaker 1: then then it did something to make it move more.
Speaker 1: Then it did something to make it move more.
Speaker 1: then it did something to make it move even more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it stops, and we're like all right now.
Speaker 0: It's just on fire.
Speaker 0: What's cut?
Speaker 0: wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Are those rockets tied to the side of it?
Speaker 1: The Rockets go off and the wheel keeps going and then yeah That's the best part is.
Speaker 1: so just try to skip to the wheel and once you've seen the wheel Everything after that is sort of more of the same.
Speaker 0: It's fun though.
Speaker 0: I have one complaint that everyone who's linked to this and I found this this morning But people have been linking to it all day, and they're linking to the wrong thing.
Speaker 0: It's not death laugh dare ding.
Speaker 0: It's dare dare dare dare.
Speaker 0: Why did you think it ours an F?
Speaker 1: Probably one guy did a misspelling and everyone just copied with.
Speaker 1: that guy said yeah.
Speaker 0: So if you see anyone linking to this with an F. I Die in a fire.
Speaker 1: yeah Oh my god.
Speaker 1: You can see how many freaking spelling errors getting the headlines on dig and proceed to get a bunch of digs There's.
Speaker 1: there really needs to be a thing if you have a spelling error in your headline on dig you can't get digs.
Speaker 1: Judge me the rule.
Speaker 1: Anyway my thing of the day You might have noticed that there's this video.
Speaker 1: That's real popular on the internet like it's crazy popular of this dude juggling three balls to the tune of Golden slumbers now.
Speaker 0: I thought it was fairly impressive when I saw it.
Speaker 1: I also thought it was impressive when I saw it now.
Speaker 1: Let me submit background information is a comedian named Chris bliss.
Speaker 1: He's actually a pretty cool comedian.
Speaker 1: I never heard his comedy, so I don't know if it's funny.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's funny to someone.
Speaker 1: he's because he's famous.
Speaker 0: He's a cool guy at least.
Speaker 1: yeah, he's doing this thing where he's trying to get Monuments of the Bill of Rights and all the state capitals and then in more places because he's all cool like that.
Speaker 1: so definitely not a schmuck and in part of his show is juggling three balls to this Beatles song and It's if you don't know anything about juggling and you're just a normal schmuck like us.
Speaker 1: It's pretty impressive, and that's why the video has gone around the net now.
Speaker 1: There's a guy named Jason Garfield I think his name is and What happened was?
Speaker 1: Penn.
Speaker 1: I heard on his you know Penn Gillette.
Speaker 1: I heard on his radio show.
Speaker 1: according to him he saw the video of the guy juggling three balls and told this guy Jason Garfield to do it with five.
Speaker 1: and Because they they're jugglers, and they know that juggling three balls wasn't so great.
Speaker 1: and You know to us it looked great, but to people who knew stuff about juggling it was crap.
Speaker 1: So there's another video called dis bliss which takes the audio From the very popular video like right out of the video with the audience and everything and it shows this guy juggling five balls to the same song and everything and it's Much better.
Speaker 0: the best part is the very end of the video when he's like try with ten there And he juggles ten balls normally for like a second, and then you're like oh shit.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I guess it's just an illustration of the fact that Things can become very popular on the internet if people don't know a lot about the skill or the background of whatever happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that these two videos combined illustrate a lot of things.
Speaker 1: Primarily they illustrate that it's real easy to fool and amaze people who don't know anything Well.
Speaker 0: like look at when we used when we go to Wildwood and dance on the DDR machines.
Speaker 0: They're years and years ago when DDR still wasn't really well known outside of you know geek centers and cities.
Speaker 0: so there'd be a DDR machine on the boardwalk in New Jersey and Like people like no one knew what it was like there'd be one kid like trying to play the game and failing there'd be a crowd.
Speaker 0: So Scott and I would get up on the machine and do our normal thing because we're actually both of us really really good At DDR dance dance revolution.
Speaker 0: if you don't know we need to show about DDR.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we do.
Speaker 0: so we start we dance.
Speaker 0: You know our crazy awesome dances, and the crowd is like yelling and screaming like whoa whoa my god Those guys are awesome, and it was just DDR and we're good But we're not as good as some of those crazy people out there like DJ 8-ball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not even close.
Speaker 1: They saw that they would just like pee their pants.
Speaker 0: yeah But because they didn't know they they thought what we were doing was crazy, and there are a lot of people out there.
Speaker 1: I know some of them who will Get mediocre or slightly above-average skills at a wide variety of things But not have insane skills at anything and then they will shock and amaze completely normal doofuses with their slightly above-average skills as The three ball guy is doing when the people with the real skills of five balling are Not noticed maybe because they're rarer
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: you know, but I'm sure if the five ball people come out of the woodwork, then you know they'll also shock and amaze.
Speaker 0: Well, there's also the point that until recently the internet was the realm mostly of geeks or people who are good at internetting Or good at computers.
Speaker 0: so whenever a non computer awesome thing would appear on the internet the people who generally Propagate or promote those sorts of things would go whoo.
Speaker 0: and the people who are actually good at those things Don't really know or care about internet memes and cliches, and they have no idea.
Speaker 0: What's floating around out there.
Speaker 0: They got no clue, but now as Cool people or internet types or geeks are getting older and doing things other than just their you know computer geekery They're noticing that hey There's this internet And I can be on it too.
Speaker 0: so now you have the guy who can juggle the crazy number of balls And he sees the people juggling three balls and goes huh, I can beat that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that Overall this is a really good Two videos to compare and contrast and many times compare and contrast like in middle school Yeah, and many times in the future.
Speaker 1: I see myself You know in discussion saying this is just like those two juggling videos.
Speaker 0: Here's why black I'll admit that that is.
Speaker 0: this is an effect that I've often used to my advantage because I'm a Modern a mediocre at best piano player.
Speaker 0: I'm alright I can just doodle around But when I'm an anime conventions And I sit down in front of piano And I know like two or three anime songs that I can just bust out and it looks like I know what I'm doing So I'll just sit down and you know doodle a bit, and I'll play like the utenna theme.
Speaker 0: people go whoo wow and then I'm very careful to like walk away from the piano before anyone tries to get me to play anything else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's more to it, but let's go Alright, so today.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about two fairly terrible anime.
Speaker 1: They're not that terrible now.
Speaker 0: They're not.
Speaker 1: they're not as terrible as What was the terrible show?
Speaker 0: well the one with the harem or the one with the harem both?
Speaker 0: How about the one with the boobs in the harem?
Speaker 1: that one yeah?
Speaker 0: Okay, I mean they're.
Speaker 0: these aren't that bad.
Speaker 0: They're not like horrible.
Speaker 0: They're not the kind of show that we would just turn off because we can't deal with it But they're the kind of show we won't watch anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you might.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's still at the line where you might want to watch one episode at least to know what we're talking about Especially if it's your kind of thing.
Speaker 1: I mean one of these shows might be up your alley.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we'll tell you when a show is not worth watching at all to anyone and these shows are just above that line.
Speaker 1: Alright, so the first show is zega pain.
Speaker 0: Yeah emphasis on the pain.
Speaker 0: the show's not good.
Speaker 1: No, it really didn't grab me.
Speaker 1: I mean at first I thought the show had promise because It was somewhat serious.
Speaker 0: what you thought the show had promised?
Speaker 0: the screen the screen Capture that was put in the icon on the desktop was a giant robot face.
Speaker 1: And you thought the show because I read the synopsis of the show online and it had something to do with robots and fairly serious Sci-fi something.
Speaker 0: it's like a matrix But you don't know who's where and a boy with a giant robot and a little bit of gratuitous boobage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the gratuitous boobage was unnecessary alright.
Speaker 1: Let's explain this show.
Speaker 1: So this is kid, and he doesn't seem to be too popular at school.
Speaker 1: Oh wait.
Speaker 0: No the show starts with that weird sci-fi robot battle.
Speaker 1: Okay, sure the show starts with a sci-fi robot battle in space.
Speaker 1: one of the end like one guy is half Disintegrating and this girl dies and then a robot explodes, and it's bigger than any nuke I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: it's hard to tell what's going on.
Speaker 1: It's it's sort of like the cryptic.
Speaker 1: Either what?
Speaker 1: what happened in the past a long time ago, or what's going to happen in the future?
Speaker 1: Sort of you'll find out about this later, but that's the real plot clip.
Speaker 1: you know one of those?
Speaker 0: Yeah, then it cuts to generic high school show generic high school show.
Speaker 1: this guy doesn't seem to be too popular.
Speaker 1: He does some annoying things.
Speaker 1: You know doesn't have a lot of friends, but he has like a you know one friend Who's a girl who's I guess been the childhood friend typical and this other you know kind of?
Speaker 1: Mickey kind of guy like Mickey from Wootena.
Speaker 0: yep Yeah, there's been a lot of characters like that lately.
Speaker 0: the doctor in ergo proxy really gives me that feel to kinda a little bit.
Speaker 1: But yeah, this is one guy like that, and they're shooting a video for something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't really matter, but it gets to the point where he sees a girl like dive off the high dive.
Speaker 1: He's a girl standing on the high dive from across the school, and he runs over there because apparently He's the captain of the swim team and also the only member of the swim team.
Speaker 1: So if he sees someone going in the pool.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Are you ready to join the swim team?
Speaker 0: Now at this point I'd like to say that I really don't get why they've made the pool like this Focal point of all the whatever that's going on.
Speaker 1: I don't know either if there's a metaphor Associating with the pool.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is, and I'll also say this yeah an underwater kiss is hot.
Speaker 0: That's a really cool thing.
Speaker 0: you can't hold your breath that long.
Speaker 0: Oh my god anyway.
Speaker 1: So this girl standing on the high dive apparently I'm gonna ruin the whole first episode.
Speaker 0: watch out It's fine.
Speaker 0: his show's not worth having not ruined.
Speaker 1: This girl standing on the high dive Isn't real like no one else saw her and when she tried to talk to him.
Speaker 1: He couldn't hear what she was saying.
Speaker 1: so That's that.
Speaker 0: yeah other plot happens.
Speaker 0: It's really mother crap.
Speaker 1: No one can see whatever.
Speaker 1: she reappears in his apartment Reappears she can talk everything's cool.
Speaker 1: She takes him to another world brings him in a giant robot.
Speaker 1: they team up in a giant robot They fight other things and they win.
Speaker 0: It's all very quantum like everything's holograms like it's a game.
Speaker 0: And he asks like is this a virtual world?
Speaker 0: and she says a typical anime cryptic answer of no.
Speaker 1: He's like where are we?
Speaker 1: and she's like pretend you're playing the latest VR game or something.
Speaker 0: Oh, he asked something like it's again cuz she says the words.
Speaker 0: you can think of it that way for now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: so it's either some sort of parallel dimension or Quantum leap space some crazy bad shit.
Speaker 0: This is not like the freakin negative whatever with captain Marvell.
Speaker 1: yeah, anyway, the robot is called the zaga pain.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, we really figure out what's going on.
Speaker 1: It's pretty invincible.
Speaker 0: But the show's gotten me enough to where I want to know what the plot is.
Speaker 0: It's it pulled a fancy lala the show.
Speaker 0: I don't care about.
Speaker 0: Dinosaurs I'm curious about.
Speaker 0: you know like now I got to find out what's up with the dinosaurs zaga pain.
Speaker 1: I don't really care about the show or at all.
Speaker 1: the characters mostly all suck.
Speaker 1: the robot looks cool I guess but I just want to know what the hell.
Speaker 1: What's their explanation for this parallel world?
Speaker 0: the robot is kind of generic though?
Speaker 0: It reminds me of the fighting from like candidate for goddess.
Speaker 0: It reminds me of kind of like crap CG cell shaded weekly.
Speaker 1: I don't care about what it looks like like how it's animated, but it reminds me of like zone of the enders type of stuff.
Speaker 1: Whatever, it's a robot it shoots thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of the world's is as a blazing sword.
Speaker 0: There's some sort of fake world or something.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: they took a generic robot show that had nothing going with it and added just a little bit of weird sci-fi Mystery something to make it more like Ava and Raza.
Speaker 1: fine Yeah, and then at the end of the show like he's teleported back to the normal world in the swimming pool And he kisses the girl underwater underwater, and that's the end of the episode.
Speaker 0: It's really all we can say about that show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tell you what happened in it because they're real that's it unless you want to be roped into either watching us crappy show or Scouring the internet to find out what's going on in the show from synopses.
Speaker 0: Don't watch it.
Speaker 1: I recommend if my recommendation for the show is that you find a picture of the robot to see what it looks like and Then find a synopsis on the internet to find out what the deal is with this alternate world, and that's the end of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right the other show we watched is Possibly it's one of the most painful non harem shows.
Speaker 0: I've seen in a long time.
Speaker 1: All right, it's um.
Speaker 1: It's in the initial D Genre Also known as the Hikaru no go John Prince of tennis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where there's some sort of special interest You know whether it.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: It's actually slightly different.
Speaker 1: It's more than the yugioh genre because it's a fake special and yeah because initial D at least it's a show about cars.
Speaker 0: So it's a real thing.
Speaker 0: and then they talk about cars in a somewhat yugioh, or what was that other one dragon drive?
Speaker 1: I think yeah.
Speaker 1: It's where they make something up to be interested in and then they make up how to be good at it and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: So that so basically it's it's in my opinion a generally stupid genre to begin with because in this case It's not like cars and initial D or go where it like.
Speaker 0: you know it.
Speaker 0: It's a real thing so you can just make up plot around it.
Speaker 1: What was the moshang one?
Speaker 0: Oh?
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah instead.
Speaker 0: They make up a thing and then whenever they need a crazy Plot device they make it up.
Speaker 0: They make a thing up like oh he did a double black blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: That's crazy.
Speaker 0: Oh well He did it with his super blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: yep They just make shit up.
Speaker 1: cuz what they made it up.
Speaker 1: It's like if you make up a sport And then you make up a show about your made-up sport And then you make up the rules in your made-up sport And then
Speaker 0: you make up why every
Speaker 1: episode you can just come up with some crazy technique or some crazy situation.
Speaker 1: because well You're making all the rules I mean silly while initial D is silly and breaks a lot of rules.
Speaker 0: at least it's grounded a little bit in reality.
Speaker 0: like you Can kind of drift a car like that and you can kind of do the things he does to it.
Speaker 0: somewhat possible degree somewhat Yeah, somewhat the car.
Speaker 1: No goes really at least the car No go I've seen is really grounded.
Speaker 1: You know you play go you can play go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can play go.
Speaker 1: not well, but But air gear is Something else.
Speaker 0: so first of all they made up this thing which is basically rollerblading.
Speaker 0: But the rollerblades have like nukes in him or somethings.
Speaker 0: they have this power plant and they can roll you around.
Speaker 1: all right wait Slap right here.
Speaker 1: didn't I come up with the idea of rollerblades having motors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then wait wait.
Speaker 1: What did you say?
Speaker 0: I said that that is silly dangerous stupid and horrifying.
Speaker 0: and why is it?
Speaker 0: well the main reason?
Speaker 0: To not get in front of.
Speaker 0: you haven't rollerbladed.
Speaker 0: when you rollerblade or ice skate.
Speaker 0: They're very similar You push so the motive force comes from your leg, and you push out.
Speaker 0: you're pushing down You're propelling yourself forward and the wheels are just there to reduce friction when you're gliding.
Speaker 0: If a rollerblade was rolling for you now the motive force is a pulling force Coming from the rollerblade and you would basically just fall over and die.
Speaker 0: it is almost impossible to do what this show wants to do in the first place all right so without some sort of magic or Technology that we don't have yet.
Speaker 1: So continue talking about what happens in the first episode of Erica because I'm not all too sure.
Speaker 0: yeah Well, they made up.
Speaker 0: first of all they make up this thing.
Speaker 0: so air gear our rollerblades with like fuel cells or something in Them and they have motors, and you can move them.
Speaker 0: apparently you can also fly.
Speaker 0: Really the characters are flying like literally flying leaping from like rooftop to rooftop spinning around in the air.
Speaker 1: You look like they're flying.
Speaker 1: it look like they're just making really big jumps because the rollerblades Let them go so fast and they get on a roof, and then they just aren't ignoring the physics of that.
Speaker 0: It's just They.
Speaker 0: they jump too far.
Speaker 0: They're effectively fly.
Speaker 0: It's like Superman.
Speaker 0: He can leap tall buildings yep, and then they made up this whole subculture around these things and Complete with like these rituals.
Speaker 0: like the main plot point one is that he finds the air gear that is the people he's living with Have.
Speaker 0: he steals him when he wears them, and he's kind of good at it.
Speaker 0: He might be one of those prodigies - they make up this whole gang culture around these things and then they make up this thing where like if you Slap your sticker for your gang on top of the sticker for someone else's gang.
Speaker 0: It's a challenge, and he accidentally does that and challenges someone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then the challenge is just this other stupid thing and the show just goes nowhere fast.
Speaker 1: yeah, basically the guy is to race and The really only redeeming part of the show that I found was the fact that he lives With these four girls who are kind of you know, it's it's it's not a harem so to speak.
Speaker 0: yeah, they'll hate him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it could be a harem, but it's not.
Speaker 1: oh wait.
Speaker 0: There's that one girl who likes him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a half harem.
Speaker 1: It's a half harem, but it has that funny element of you know a guy living with Four girls who are humorous in different ways.
Speaker 1: they remind me a lot of the neighbors from yotsuba You know because you had the older girl who like you don't want to get dangerous with her because she'll kick your ass the really little girl who's just like cynical and Worldly.
Speaker 1: yeah, it seemed like that you know which is kind of kind of funny because they have rollerblade skills I guess or air gear skills.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're they're members of Sleeping forest.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah, I don't know why I remember that The show is just bad.
Speaker 1: if you really like No rollerblades you won't like this show because it has nothing to do with roll.
Speaker 0: you like this show.
Speaker 0: I got nothing to say to you.
Speaker 1: you know who might like this show are the people who like all like the normal fighting shows like bleach and Naruto, but You know like those you have to be able to like those shows so much that you'll like a bad one of those shows.
Speaker 0: Well bleach at least seems to have good characters.
Speaker 0: It may not have anything.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 0: It's true It's got good characters and good art.
Speaker 1: this show I think the only person you could say is a good character was the Probably the second oldest sister the one that was all crazy evil.
Speaker 1: I was like getting mad at him and yelling at him right away.
Speaker 1: all the other characters are boring.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I the show is just bad bad bad bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the youngest sister has a good Look to her, but she's not interesting character and the main character is just generic anime, dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's like pathetically generic.
Speaker 1: Oh god.
Speaker 1: He's just like Painfully generic.
Speaker 1: alright, so air gear if you actually recommend you're gonna what.
Speaker 1: you should watch the first episode if you don't have anything better to do because You'll I don't know You'll get something out of it.
Speaker 0: Don't watch this show alone.
Speaker 0: It'll break your brain.
Speaker 0: It's stupid.
Speaker 0: Watch it with a bunch of people so you can all yell at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not funny because it's funny But it's so terrible that You don't laugh at the terrible things in it as you do in like a zombie movie or something But you laugh at how shitty the show is in itself.
Speaker 0: I mean we were watching got to the point where Katsu was yelling about the fact that they were jumping from rooftop to rooftop and breaking Those roof shingles in Japan which apparently are really expensive and hard to replace.
Speaker 0: yeah, and Katsu was like wow that sucks that bastard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there is a there's a little bit of gratuitous Boobage, but not too much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not too much though.
Speaker 1: They got pain had more.
Speaker 1: I don't know a little bit more.
Speaker 0: I think this show had a little bit more.
Speaker 1: I don't really remember too much of it in this show.
Speaker 1: all I remember is when he you know the usual Crash land on top of some some girl.
Speaker 0: Why does that happen?
Speaker 0: Why is it in every show that's stupid?
Speaker 0: the guy like bumps into the girl and then he pieces faces laying in her breasts.
Speaker 1: It's a Japanese teen fantasy.
Speaker 1: It must be.
Speaker 0: I had better fantasies than that when I was a teenager.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you what.
Speaker 1: yeah, my fantasies went a lot farther than that.
Speaker 0: It wasn't my fantasies weren't non-concessual All right, so that's all we really have to say about these two shows.
Speaker 0: They're both bad.
Speaker 0: don't watch him.
Speaker 1: We got a whole crap ton of anime in our hopper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think you can understand How many episode ones we have to go through now?
Speaker 1: I think like this past week or so has been like I don't know what to say Like it must be like the harvest like all the anime is now fully grown and I'm going through the fields with the giant Like.
Speaker 0: well, we didn't.
Speaker 0: we didn't find him while they were on the air and now they've fallen off the side of the board and Matured.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Well, if you listen to all week of geek nights instead of just anime day you'll get that one.
Speaker 0: no, maybe yeah, but Yeah, yeah, and of course next Thursday, we'll have her coverage of Tora con where we're doing a live show there Which we may or may not record.
Speaker 0: We probably will record it and we're gonna interview people and all sorts of fun stuff.
Speaker 0: We'll probably have stories for the entire week But our main coverage will be on anime day Wednesday since anime day and it's an anime con.
Speaker 1: All right Yeah, do the?
Speaker 1: you know the usual stuff Frapper map.
Speaker 0: Yeah forum.
Speaker 0: Actually the forum.
Speaker 0: I don't really need to tell you to join it anymore.
Speaker 0: Everyone's joining and the forums great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you're not joining you're missing out.
Speaker 1: Maybe soon I'm gonna start like Posting secret goodies that people who aren't joined can't see because I have a feeling a lot of people are reading the forum But aren't getting accounts.
Speaker 1: So there's gonna be at least one secret bonus thing for people who join.
Speaker 1: So even if you're not gonna post anything Join and you'll see secret stuff as opposed to just reading them without joining.
Speaker 0: Yeah We'll make some sort of members only Discussion thing like total FARC.
Speaker 0: only it'll be free because we would never charge money for something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'll be cool.
Speaker 1: Encourage people to join in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course, then we can have the super ultra version that you can pay for But we won't really.
Speaker 1: it'll be like penny arcade, you know This is our podcast is only available to our super extreme penny arcade members, which include everyone who's listening right now You know.
Speaker 0: So Once again Tora Khan Rochester, New York at the Rochester Institute of Technology.
Speaker 0: It's a one-day con.
Speaker 0: It's Saturday only.
Speaker 0: It was great fun last year and it was much bigger than I could have ever expected.
Speaker 0: Yep, and of course in the near future.
Speaker 0: We're also gonna be at an amazement, but that's a ways out.
Speaker 1: Well, you're gonna be there.
Speaker 0: Yeah and Otakon will both be at for our geek nights extravaganza.
Speaker 0: Whoo.
Speaker 1: Oh the Logo contest is still going on.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Don't think that we're not looking at anything we get.
Speaker 1: We're just not going to rush anything and we're not gonna say anything about anything you submit because if we help someone That's not really fair.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like, you know, you you know, we can give general suggestions to everyone but we can't you know give comments on individual submissions because that's like Helping you to win individually.
Speaker 0: Just remember focus more on the idea than the final execution.
Speaker 1: yeah, you want to get something that's you know geek and night Into one maybe some sort of geek night.
Speaker 1: yeah, like just taking the words and trying to arrange them in a clever way is good, but you know, I got a Someone who combines the ideas together into a visual thing.
Speaker 0: That's a gestalt.
Speaker 0: It must be a gestalt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that that's what's gonna win it for you.
Speaker 1: There's my.
Speaker 0: That is now the word of the day.
Speaker 0: if you don't know what that word means look it up because I'm not going to tell you.
Speaker 0: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-15 37.
Speaker 0: geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.