Speaker 1: It's Wednesday August 16th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight it's Otakon.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well tonight is very special geek nights because tonight is Otakon.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: Otakon was two weekends ago.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: We're going to go back in time and relive Otakon 2006.
Speaker 0: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: Well, we're not crammed to an elevator with.
Speaker 0: you're going to Otakon I assume.
Speaker 2: So have you ever been to Otakon before?
Speaker 0: also One.
Speaker 0: you might notice as you may have noticed all week that I sound slightly different from usual.
Speaker 0: It is again because I do not have a pop filter.
Speaker 0: Someone stole it or more likely I lost it at Otakon.
Speaker 1: Well, how much did it cost?
Speaker 0: it cost five cents plus one fifth of a pair of two dollar pantyhose?
Speaker 1: That's not much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I got to go out and get a new pantyhose and a new embroidery loop.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll just buy some Pop filters are like 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: I am making a new one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, maybe that's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless a microphone I get that's good comes with one that would be good anyway.
Speaker 0: now I said it's a special geek nights partly because we're going to break from tradition a bit and tonight We're just going to talk about Otakon.
Speaker 0: No news.
Speaker 0: No things of the day.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter because all the things of the day I have in waiting are video game related Yes, and all my news is crap.
Speaker 1: There's no good news.
Speaker 0: and also you can basically consider everything we say today to be a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you really want some anime news, I mean I was probably just gonna read something from anime news network.
Speaker 1: So just just go read that website And you'll be okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah now don't be worried starting tomorrow We're gonna go right back to the usual schedule with the news the things of the day the meta bits all that stuff.
Speaker 0: we're doing this partly because Otakon episodes tend to be long and - because many times a lot of the people who were listening to this episode will only listen to this episode because a lot of people from Otakon are probably listening right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also it takes a long time to sum up four days of activities into Less than two hours, hopefully.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see if we even finish this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if we add news and things of the day, it's gonna be even longer.
Speaker 0: So let's get right into it Yep, so without further ado we left for Otakon 2006 at what 7/8 in the morning.
Speaker 1: That's about right.
Speaker 0: Yeah every year.
Speaker 0: We try to get there by noon on Thursday.
Speaker 0: It's basically a four-day event for us.
Speaker 1: and Well, it was pretty good drive except for the fact that there were four people in my car Which is fine for people can fit in my car, but it was myself or people's worth of luggage does not fit in my car.
Speaker 1: Well, it mostly fit mostly fit, but I couldn't see that well out the back window.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I once drive drove like 800 miles with my car so full of stuff.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even see out the right side of my windshield.
Speaker 0: Wow, yeah, it was really awesome.
Speaker 0: Anyway, my house and my me not so much.
Speaker 1: There were a lot of cops on the road.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think there were more cops.
Speaker 0: However in Delaware the state we were in the least than it all the other states combined.
Speaker 1: Well, actually we were in percentage of the state.
Speaker 1: We were in most of Delaware.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell Every single police officer in the state of Delaware was on the road.
Speaker 0: We were on trying to pull us over.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I 95, you know, it's like you get a million.
Speaker 1: No one's like 90% of the people driving through Delaware on I-95 are not stopping in Delaware unless they want to buy something that 0% sales tax.
Speaker 1: and You know, they're from another state.
Speaker 1: That is not Delaware.
Speaker 0: Therefore Delaware wants money.
Speaker 1: it's basically a bunch of cops lined up in Delaware ready to steal money from the other states and Jersey and Maryland were not light on police activity either.
Speaker 0: Yeah In fact Baltimore has bit by bit been getting worse in this that there are pretty much red light cameras at almost every major intersection in the Inner Harbor.
Speaker 1: now Don't run red lights in Baltimore.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And when I say don't run red lights I mean don't run green lights because the lights basically go green green green green green yellow red.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and there's.
Speaker 0: no It's such a scam but that is a topic for another day.
Speaker 1: We got to Otacon without incident and we parked the car.
Speaker 2: Katsu has finally joined the front row crew.
Speaker 2: How long did it take you to get here?
Speaker 2: Several hours.
Speaker 2: I got held up because of traffic accidents.
Speaker 0: Did you kill anyone?
Speaker 2: No Do you plan to?
Speaker 0: Maybe Yep, and now they're.
Speaker 0: the options in parking are basically park expensively at our hotel or park cheaply a block away And you know what?
Speaker 0: We're lazy and we have money.
Speaker 0: So we parked at the hotel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's weird because theoretically if you read the sign my understanding is that the park at the hotel is $21 a day.
Speaker 1: Isn't that the way you read the sign?
Speaker 1: In fact, that is exactly what the sign says and I think a year or two year last a year ago at Otacon 2005 We scammed them by forgetting the ticket and we paid like 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: Well, the guy said 20 bucks and I said, okay, and then he let us go.
Speaker 1: Yep this year I handed them the ticket because we were just so tired.
Speaker 1: We didn't even want to try the scam.
Speaker 0: Also, we couldn't talk.
Speaker 0: There's no way we could scam people when we couldn't talk exactly.
Speaker 0: So literally we couldn't talk.
Speaker 0: the only person in the car who could actually speak was Yuko And she was not about to help us scam someone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I handed him the ticket and they asked for $21 and the ticket said I was there since Thursday.
Speaker 0: so hey now it's not just that we're misreading all the policies or signs because two years ago and Three years ago.
Speaker 0: We paid quite a bit of money to park there.
Speaker 1: Yes, we did.
Speaker 1: It was a lot of money.
Speaker 0: So I'm not sure exactly what's going on But you know what park at your hotel's parking lot if you stay in the Renaissance.
Speaker 1: Yes parking under the Renaissance is a good place to park and it's a nice lot.
Speaker 1: I mean if you go to the very bottom level of the lot There's a bunch of spaces and you're pretty close to an elevator and there's some guys down there who wash your car if you pay Them which is cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, yeah, so then, you know, we hung out.
Speaker 0: eventually the entire front row crew gathered and we had a little pool party.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had.
Speaker 0: in fact we took over the entire pool.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: The worst part was that we wanted to use the hot tub But we couldn't use it as much as last year because if too many people get into the hot tub The water is displaced and it covers the air intakes with water and then the jet stop working.
Speaker 0: Pete alone could pretty much make the jet stop working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so not too many people could go in there and a lot of non front row crew people were in there.
Speaker 0: So, however, there were more front row crew people than other kinds of people in the pool that night.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 0: We were one massive massive nest of people who can't see without their glasses
Speaker 1: and there weren't a bunch of screaming kids in there So that God
Speaker 0: last year
Speaker 1: And of course I have it but right before the pool party we were in line to get badges
Speaker 0: Which
Speaker 1: we do need because they are not stinking
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: before we go any further I would like to note that throughout this episode.
Speaker 0: I'm going to be tossing in relevant interviews and audio from the convention Coolness, but anyway on Thursday the temperature in Baltimore with the heat index was what a hundred and five.
Speaker 1: It was officially too damn hot degrees out.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: God was it hot now despite this woman It is motherfucking hot.
Speaker 0: despite this not only did people wait in line since some god-awful hour But there were people Cosplaying in the Sun in line.
Speaker 1: There were not many but they were there.
Speaker 0: I'm here in the hundred degree plus weather outside of Otacon for people trying to get in for their pre-registration on Thursday.
Speaker 2: Now, what is your name Lindsey Kieffer?
Speaker 2: And who are you dressed up?
Speaker 2: as actually this is part of my costume I'm actually gonna go as a Shinsengumi member.
Speaker 0: Oh now Shinsengumi from any particular anime or just the idea from Veroni Kenshin Beautiful.
Speaker 2: now you're wearing right now a full heavy looking black outfit.
Speaker 2: Is it actually that heavy?
Speaker 2: No, not really.
Speaker 2: Actually, the sleeves are pretty airy.
Speaker 2: So so how you make it out in this heat?
Speaker 2: I'm actually doing surprisingly well, but it wouldn't hurt to have a water bottle right now.
Speaker 0: So is your first Otacon?
Speaker 2: No, actually I've been here several times before coming for my fifth year now.
Speaker 0: So we're here in the pre-reg line for Otacon Thursday night.
Speaker 2: now What's your name Paul?
Speaker 0: and you're currently cosplaying as a green shy guy.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: Well, what do you think the temperature is right now?
Speaker 2: Oh, I'd say it's about 95 97.
Speaker 2: How are you doing this?
Speaker 2: I would die.
Speaker 0: I'm dying now and I'm wearing shorts.
Speaker 2: Oh the the mask makes it very hot.
Speaker 2: I must say, um, I noticed the mask is not on right now.
Speaker 2: No, uh, I Was walking down the entire line with it on and I was just sweating the entire time.
Speaker 2: So you're aware how long the line is in front of you, right?
Speaker 2: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah How long have you been here in line?
Speaker 0: Um, about 20 25 minutes.
Speaker 2: That's not bad at all.
Speaker 2: No, not really All right.
Speaker 2: So then one last question.
Speaker 0: This is your first Otacon.
Speaker 0: You've been here before?
Speaker 2: I was here last year Actually, so you think it's gonna be better worse I can't tell right now.
Speaker 2: be warmer at least yeah.
Speaker 0: Now luckily Otacon did something very nice that the line was very long and there were a lot of people there.
Speaker 0: So well before they were scheduled to let people in to get registrations They opened the doors and brought much of the line into the well Not much because the line was massive but as many people as they could into the air conditioning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there were some people there who waited since like the crack-ass crack of dawn and way earlier than they possibly needed To wait which is kind of sad.
Speaker 1: because when did we get in the line?
Speaker 1: I mean the line was open at five, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, we was five to nine.
Speaker 0: We waited till about quarter after six and by then the line was moving steadily.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean a quarter after six we got in the line and we were physically Like maybe I don't know a football field from the door.
Speaker 1: Yeah, barely Yeah, and you know the line just moved so fast that you know within I'd say less than a half hour.
Speaker 1: We had our badges.
Speaker 1: So the people who get and wait in that Thursday line way at the front.
Speaker 1: What are you thinking?
Speaker 0: I mean Seriously, I'm here with two lovely ladies who have just gotten their free registrations.
Speaker 2: Now, how long did you have to stand in line to get it this early?
Speaker 2: Forever okay.
Speaker 2: I got here like two and she was here.
Speaker 0: Did you get in line at two or did you?
Speaker 2: yeah, I got in line around ten o'clock.
Speaker 0: Wow Were there people already in line?
Speaker 2: when you got here there weren't too many There weren't?
Speaker 2: you miss means there were people in line.
Speaker 2: people in line the person the first person got in around Three or five a.m I think so.
Speaker 2: Are you dealing with the weather?
Speaker 2: It's a little warm.
Speaker 0: I've noticed.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we had to send up set up like a 10th or outside the convention center Just to keep us from the heat while we're waiting.
Speaker 2: It's pretty bad like umbrellas and like sheet tape to a wall and like chairs and like just create shade.
Speaker 0: So is this your first old account or you've been to him before?
Speaker 2: this would be my fourth year?
Speaker 0: Excellent.
Speaker 2: This is I'm not sure I can't I Fantastic.
Speaker 0: So here's a question.
Speaker 0: What do you think about the musical act?
Speaker 0: They're gonna have this year.
Speaker 2: I'm excited, but I was a little disappointed that they're holding it so far off-site.
Speaker 0: But at the same token, it's an actual concert arena.
Speaker 2: They were able to bring them in but I don't like the way Otakon is handling the concert situation The fact that I cosplay.
Speaker 2: I don't want to keep on changing in and out of costumes to go there.
Speaker 2: True in the morning.
Speaker 0: I mean if you really like them, it's worth it, but I don't like them enough to do that.
Speaker 0: So are you guys going to be cosplaying this weekend, what are you cosplaying as?
Speaker 0: very briefly if you'll go from digi-chart Anytime from the OS town girls, but yes, we avoided all that.
Speaker 0: I mean we brought our DS's didn't even really have a chance to play them in the line.
Speaker 1: Nope Not at all.
Speaker 1: In fact, the only things we did in the line were enjoy the cosplays that went running by like Little Mac.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: That was one of the best cosplays I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there's pictures of it on the flicker.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a guy dressed exactly like Little Mac from Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now when I say exactly I mean exactly.
Speaker 0: he had a pixel face over his face.
Speaker 0: That was so well done and well positioned that if you zoom in on a picture of him No matter how far you zoom in it just looks exactly like Little Mac.
Speaker 1: Yep, it Is perfect and there was a guy running behind in front of him with.
Speaker 1: you know The bicycle or I think I had a scooter instead of a bicycle, but he had a little boombox playing Yep, and it was so cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're not.
Speaker 0: we're gonna mention the cosplays we saw off and on but Rest assured there were many many many amazing cosplays.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Alright, I'm here with the dude dressed up as dr.
Speaker 0: McNinja.
Speaker 2: No, I take it.
Speaker 2: you read the comic.
Speaker 2: Oh, yes, I have now.
Speaker 2: When did you decide to do this cosplay when I found that I had a lab coat in my closet?
Speaker 0: How long you been reading?
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 2: McNinja Oh for like for about five months now.
Speaker 2: It's like how long it's been out.
Speaker 1: I know there any other webcomics.
Speaker 0: You're it.
Speaker 0: I'm just curious.
Speaker 0: Excuse me.
Speaker 0: Do you want other webcomics to read?
Speaker 2: Oh eg cats penny arcade Perry Bible's fellowship.
Speaker 2: Yes This comic sucks In 8-bit theater.
Speaker 0: All right, so I guess one question.
Speaker 0: How's Otacon going this year?
Speaker 0: I mean your cosplay now, it's hot outside.
Speaker 0: How's the con going?
Speaker 2: It's not pretty good so far.
Speaker 2: This is actually my first time at Otacon Really?
Speaker 0: Have you been to the dealer's room yet?
Speaker 2: I saw the line back there and I'm not trying to go on that line.
Speaker 2: Any idea how big it is.
Speaker 2: I seem on a brochure and like yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: So if this is your first I would've got is this your first anime con or no?
Speaker 2: I've been to the big Apple anime fest which kind of closed down before.
Speaker 0: Yeah What was the first anime you ever saw that you knew was anime?
Speaker 2: That's gonna have to be Akira.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What was the first anime ever ever?
Speaker 2: Of Ever would probably be a cure also Like the first one ever made first one ever made Check gets work.
Speaker 2: It's a better guess than some people have had.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, so that was Thursday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Thursday was mostly a front row crew pool party.
Speaker 1: It was a pool party and it was a nighttime party and it was a line to get badges.
Speaker 1: No the badges.
Speaker 1: Usually at Otacon, you know, they have a whole bunch of different badges to choose from with art from different anime.
Speaker 1: And you know usually, you know, there's a cute one and there's a girly one and a Gundam one robot one An almost yaoi one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and usually they have to do with newer shows and popular shows of the time You know and sometimes an obscure show.
Speaker 1: this year the selection for badges was ass.
Speaker 0: I mean, I am NOT one to complain about Otacon.
Speaker 0: I consider Otacon to be the greatest anime convention I've ever been to.
Speaker 0: but good God where the badge is crap.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of them were new shows which okay.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: that's a word.
Speaker 0: they were new shows and I'm making quote marks with my fingers because they're the shows that are Currently being released on DVD or on TV in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Yeah it's great.
Speaker 0: now the problem with this is that the shows that are currently coming out in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Are Earlier in the year and last year in Japan and that was a drought for us anime wise and it wasn't that much really good To watch.
Speaker 1: my real problem was that it's okay If you use shows that are currently being released in the u.s But you should you know, try to cover at least one from each major genre of anime.
Speaker 1: I mean, I chose the speed graph for one which is not a show that's really worth finishing.
Speaker 1: I mean you could just watch a few episodes of that.
Speaker 1: show is done.
Speaker 0: Did we review speedgrapher?
Speaker 1: No, but it's.
Speaker 1: it's one of the only Shows that I actually recognized.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I kind of figured what a couple of the shows are.
Speaker 0: I picked a random badge this year.
Speaker 1: Yeah weird.
Speaker 0: The other thing was that I mean every year forever.
Speaker 0: Whenever we saw the badge selection, it was always whoo, and there was a big debate like oh check it out They got that and they got that.
Speaker 0: or oh, there's Nesca floating water over this year.
Speaker 0: Everyone went And we all looked at each other to make sure that we were all seeing the same thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean like is there?
Speaker 1: maybe they have twice as many badges this year.
Speaker 1: Is there another board?
Speaker 0: I need to look at or something though At least there are a bunch of explanations for what happened and hopefully we'll talk to some Otakon staff and get some more official answers.
Speaker 0: But I've heard that one the industry pretty much decides what the badges are because they are the ones who did.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is they're the ones who give permission.
Speaker 0: You can't just use anime on a badge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: and so generally from what I gather Otakon will tell the industry hey, we need badges send us art and we'll pick some things.
Speaker 0: and I heard that one the industry sent the badges that they want or they've sent the anime that they want to promote Which sadly is not the anime I care about.
Speaker 0: but that that is understandable - apparently they did not send Most of their art in the proper format for Otakon to use.
Speaker 0: thus Otakon was forced to ignore most of the submissions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Otakon really whoever does the badges should like get on the industry earlier and be like.
Speaker 1: these are the badges We want send us art for these shows.
Speaker 1: We need at least one robot show one showing in fighting show one show Joe drama, you know.
Speaker 1: one kitty show One cutesy show one crazy comedy, you know That's what they need.
Speaker 0: someone in the Otakon forum said there should be a policy that every year there is one Gundam or giant robot fashioned bad.
Speaker 1: Yes that way no matter what I can default to the robot badge.
Speaker 0: now the bet.
Speaker 0: the most telling sign that the badges really were kind Of mad this year was that the one badge that everyone recognized was the Hellsing badge.
Speaker 0: That badge ran out almost immediately Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I heard other badges.
Speaker 1: We're all plentiful.
Speaker 0: Yep, and honestly throughout the whole con I had no idea what my badge was until someone told isn't it Trinity blood.
Speaker 1: Yeah I watched the first episode of that show.
Speaker 1: I say it's crap, but that's just.
Speaker 1: that's a quick review right there.
Speaker 0: Now the other problem here is that we're watching like pretty much what's on TV in Japan right now.
Speaker 1: Now if there had been a Nana bad, I would have snatched that up.
Speaker 0: a good god There should have been a Nana badge.
Speaker 1: there should have been.
Speaker 1: It should have been.
Speaker 1: you know, in fact, there should have been two Nana badges a serious one and kind of a goofy one.
Speaker 0: You Know what?
Speaker 0: I would have been happy if they made all the badges Nana.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right Let's stop spending so much time talking about the badges.
Speaker 0: Well, the badges are one of our few complaints about Otakon say are one of the few complaints.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: I will note in other general con stuff that the Otakon con book was full color.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's something going on with the full color publishing because first kinetic on was oh our book is full color And it was super cheap.
Speaker 0: and now suddenly Otakon is full color.
Speaker 1: It does look like it's from the same printing company.
Speaker 1: Can we find out what company prints these things?
Speaker 0: Probably I didn't look into that at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm looking for like a publisher a printer on here, but I can't find one at all now.
Speaker 0: the other thing they've done with the con book this year is that the book had very little in the way of Otakon scheduling stuff or stuff about Otakon and it was mostly articles written by people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it also had fewer ads.
Speaker 1: I mean it's less ads but if you were ads than previous years Usually the Otakon con book is just loaded with ads.
Speaker 1: this year not so many.
Speaker 0: It was pretty much just straight-up informative.
Speaker 0: and then a whole bunch of fairly Interesting articles about the con or about anime or about Japanese films in general.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which I thought was cool.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think last year wasn't there.
Speaker 1: There was an article about the the Philippine.
Speaker 1: Every year there was a lot of action stuff and that's what they showed.
Speaker 1: in the live-action room was a lot of Filipino Live just this year.
Speaker 0: the sheer number of well-written articles.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I think there are three of them.
Speaker 1: They were pretty big too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also in previous years, you'd usually see people walking around with the con book and their little pocket schedule.
Speaker 0: this year I did not see a single person who hadn't just registered walking around with the con book.
Speaker 0: They all carried around the new format pocket schedule.
Speaker 1: Oh, the new pocket schedule is the bomb I had.
Speaker 0: the only gripe at all I had with it is that you can't get Saturday folded correctly.
Speaker 0: Exactly that the main crease the biggest crease in the entire thing goes right through the middle of Saturday.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: This is perfect.
Speaker 1: This is a thousand times better than the previous Otakon thing.
Speaker 1: In fact, every convention should have something just like this.
Speaker 1: However, you need to have the folds match the days so that someone can easily go BAM Friday BAM Saturday BAM Sunday without unfurling a giant piece of paper.
Speaker 0: Now the other thing is that it was very very large and while it folded folded easily like a map.
Speaker 0: I know some people had some difficulty refolding it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's people who don't know how to fold
Speaker 0: But to the easy way to mitigate that I mean this thing was huge and it had not only the schedules But all of the con information including descriptions of all the panels and descriptions
Speaker 1: of all the panels and all the showings Which is terrific.
Speaker 0: if they had to though, they could have gotten rid of the description to the panels and showings.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they could have put those in the con book.
Speaker 1: I mean it was handy to have them there, but I didn't really need them at the con.
Speaker 1: You know, I could have looked those up in the in my hotel room.
Speaker 0: true But we're the kind of people who do a lot of research ahead of time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know other people don't is true?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it really.
Speaker 1: it doesn't matter where those things are as long as they are available, you know.
Speaker 1: But definitely in this thing it was handy to have the schedule printed in an easier to read format not with those oval things and Also the hours of operation were printed nicely and one of the sides.
Speaker 1: However, there was a little bit of confusion Where they printed what it say it said like Sunday 1 p.m To close you should net you shouldn't do that.
Speaker 1: You need a time there, but that's the only.
Speaker 1: that's a tiny ass complaint if I ever seen one.
Speaker 0: Now as for the con in general, it had slightly over 22,000 people this year.
Speaker 1: It was like 300 more people than last year, which is essentially nothing.
Speaker 0: That means no one was turned away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one was turned away.
Speaker 1: But also Otakon isn't growing as rapidly as it was before.
Speaker 0: I mean they grew by 1% Yep, but then again, there could be a lot of reasons for that.
Speaker 0: I mean having a limit on the con at all is a certainly Chilling factor for people who may or may not be sure if they're gonna go.
Speaker 0: The fact that they've gotten rid of group discounts the fact that they've gotten rid of one day passes probably really cut down.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah The one the lack of one day passes probably did kill a lot of the thing is I think the lack of one day passes is Fine.
Speaker 1: I do think it's fine.
Speaker 1: It's but a convention so large.
Speaker 1: I think you're perfectly justified in doing that.
Speaker 0: Yes, I mean they've saved so much time and money and effort and people who want to be there for three days have such a Bigger advantage now in terms of actually enjoying the con.
Speaker 1: I do still think that to appease the dealers that they should have some sort of Sunday dealer room pass.
Speaker 1: You know where you can go to the dealers room and not do anything else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I suggested that last year too and the main reason is there might be a slight logistical problem with it, though.
Speaker 0: well the main reason they don't is that the reason they got rid of day passes primarily was because it's a nightmare for the security people to Mm-hmm and to.
Speaker 0: They'd have to keep all of these stuff.
Speaker 0: They use to differentiate in place to have Sunday things.
Speaker 0: Yep, in addition to that now They have to worry about the fire code on Sunday instead of just knowing that there aren't enough badges to break the fire code.
Speaker 1: Yeah See that the solution that I would come up with is one that no one would probably agree with who actually has to work at The con but would be to have a special after-hours dealers room open only, you know.
Speaker 1: So like at like two or three you close the dealers room except to a bunch of people who paid for dealers room only.
Speaker 0: You know, yeah, but the logistical concerns of that are insane.
Speaker 1: Yes, they are.
Speaker 1: or like maybe open the dealers room on You know for like certain hours before it really opens on Friday.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I say just don't worry about it.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to change something that works so well.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 3: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah now in terms of staff Despite the fact there were more people at Otacon there were fewer staff and I have to say it was noticeable.
Speaker 1: Yes, it was.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It could have been just that the staff shirts didn't stand out as much but I'm fairly confident that there were much fewer staff at Otacon this year and according to the official statistics there were less staff.
Speaker 1: Okay, and you can't really blame Otacon that much I mean you can put a little blame on them for having less staff because it did hurt the con noticeably that there were not enough staff and They could have done more to recruit more staff but at the same time you got to blame the fans because the staff are all fan volunteers, so People aren't volunteering enough time to Otacon and they should get on that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well then again, I mean our friend Scott Johnson just joined the staff.
Speaker 0: So we're all getting in on that action.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So we're not shit talkers.
Speaker 1: Is that what you're saying?
Speaker 0: something like that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you should.
Speaker 1: if you think Otacon isn't you know needs more staff Don't complain about it unless you are signing up to be staff.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean when we did our critique of Connecticut a while back the first thing the Connecticut staff told to us was People like you need to join the staff basically.
Speaker 1: Yep It's like if you complain about a con not having enough staff or having shitty staff and you don't join the staff or attempt to Join the staff of that convention.
Speaker 1: You can shut up.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that's all I got to say about that.
Speaker 0: But despite the lower number of staff the con went very smoothly.
Speaker 0: I don't think there were any major events other than people passing out from the heat.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean there were.
Speaker 1: there were some incidents that were beyond our vision probably behind the scenes.
Speaker 0: Yes, there was one.
Speaker 0: anonymous staffers explained to me that something happened with the staff whereupon There was a. they kept calling it a crisis and I don't know exactly what happened.
Speaker 0: But a number of staff were laid up dealing with some sort of problem Saturday afternoon.
Speaker 0: Ah Whatever I don't.
Speaker 0: I think it involved.
Speaker 0: it was an internal matter and I don't know anything more than that because everyone was very Anonymous and very vague about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only thing that got me about Otakon staff was I think we were in the panel room once right and you know in the panel room is the cool panel guy.
Speaker 1: What's his name?
Speaker 1: Dragon Master will ooh, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Yeah, and he was sitting there and this other staffer pretty high-level staffer because you know, they're high-level staff for when they have a radio He thought necessarily no not necessarily but I mean at Katsu khan they give the gophers Radio.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow But yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, he comes in and he like introduces himself to the other guy and it's like okay too high-level staff never met each other.
Speaker 1: Maybe they should do like Otakon should have at least one Some sort of coordination beating before the car.
Speaker 0: No The way the reason that happens that Otakon is very delegated and compartmentalized.
Speaker 1: it is it is.
Speaker 1: but still You should you know get to know the other people that you have to work with, you know, cuz there's no way.
Speaker 0: There's like 500 staffers.
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 0: And most of them don't live anywhere near Baltimore.
Speaker 1: Most kelly's the highest-level people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the highest-level people do know each other for the most part.
Speaker 0: Yeah still I kind of weird that you know Scott I point out that our radio does not mean high-level staff.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: You know, what means high-level staff?
Speaker 0: if they always look busy.
Speaker 0: They're not dealing with crowds They're listening to a microphone stoically or they're listening to a headphone stoically and then they suddenly disappear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is a high-level staffer.
Speaker 1: Anyway What else went down?
Speaker 0: I mean there were no major issues that I'm aware of and the con was generally well-run.
Speaker 1: I think the only other real problem with the con was that there were certain there were lines for certain events that caused light trouble and more more staff could have made that smoother and Possibly some sort of system that someone could have come up with might help it.
Speaker 1: I think all they really need to do is put you know Make the people do the swirly lines around some tape on the floor.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, they're easier ways than that.
Speaker 0: I mean an amazement has a no line policy where you're not allowed to stand in line And I don't really want to talk about it in great detail because that would really take away from all the.
Speaker 1: oh I'm saying is that there there there were events that were incredibly popular and long lines formed for certain panels and showings and that a Sis there could be a system in place to prevent the trouble that is caused by that.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the problem here.
Speaker 0: Most of those lines were completely unwarranted.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because other than panels that have a limited number of people who can get in there was absolutely no reason To line up for the dealers room or to line up to get into the artists alley.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, let's talk about the dealers room line Friday morning.
Speaker 0: All right, so and then we'll we'll skip a bit in our list here.
Speaker 0: But yeah Friday morning the dealers room opened.
Speaker 0: actually in the afternoon it opened late.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's see When do the official hours say it opens?
Speaker 1: dealers room on Friday opens at noon now it closes at 8 p.m.
Speaker 1: So it stays open later than any other day on.
Speaker 0: people lined up the moment the con opened.
Speaker 0: In fact before the con opened a line that had at least a thousand people in it formed outside the con Trying to get into the main entrance.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now these people were all stupid because we walked right up to any of the other entrances and walked right in because as every piece of literature about Otakon says at The moment the con opens any member with a badge can go in any door.
Speaker 1: now There was a couple doors where they were preventing us from getting in despite our badge possessions and that was ass.
Speaker 0: No, that made perfect sense because those specific doors and there were only three of them Empathy directly into places where people line up.
Speaker 0: They also are right near registration and right in the middle one near registration.
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about the ones down in the tunnel area.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those were surrounded by the line for registration.
Speaker 0: There are a lot.
Speaker 0: there is a great number of people without badges in a Massive mob right outside all of those doors and those doors go directly into lines.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all right.
Speaker 0: They had good reasons for that and every other door was open.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, but despite this at least a thousand people lined up stupidly to get in and we told a few people, you know You didn't have to stand in that line and they didn't believe us.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh well Anyway, but the dealers room two people lined up immediately and sat there for at least four hours before they could get in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like what do you think?
Speaker 1: I mean if you're if you're gonna wait in line to go to the dealers room the line should be like at the last hour.
Speaker 1: the dealers room is open on Sunday because that's when they start giving the shit away at.
Speaker 1: you know rock bottom prices and Nowadays, you can just walk in and get a cacti or any time you want.
Speaker 1: The ton berries are plentiful these days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was nothing rare at the con at all.
Speaker 1: There are no rare things that are going to sell out that you can't get.
Speaker 1: So what the hell is the point of going into the dealers room right away?
Speaker 0: The best part is I didn't record this.
Speaker 0: well I recorded this interview but it came out kind of crappy because the key people I talked to were kind of shy and quiet or The other people I talked to were really loud but far away and it didn't work.
Speaker 0: But of all the people who were sitting pretty much right near the front of the line to get into the dealers room meaning they had Been sitting there for about four hours Mm-hmm does the con opens at eight and the dealers room opens at noon?
Speaker 1: Why would you sit there for four hours when for the majority of the con?
Speaker 1: You can just walk into the dealers room with no line at all.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: I asked them this like are you here to get anything specific?
Speaker 0: Why are you waiting for the dealers room?
Speaker 0: You know, what's the special thing?
Speaker 0: You think's gonna sell out and no one had anything.
Speaker 0: They just wanted to go into the dealers room and they really didn't have any reason.
Speaker 0: like I tried to ask him You know, there's nothing to do.
Speaker 0: Are you?
Speaker 0: you don't have any panels to go to two later?
Speaker 0: They didn't really have any answer for me.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: I guess they're just consumer whores.
Speaker 0: I really didn't get it.
Speaker 0: I couldn't get out of these people why they were in line for the dealers room.
Speaker 0: a Few people didn't know that it didn't open until noon.
Speaker 0: They got out of line when they found out from me while I interviewed them.
Speaker 1: Those people were intelligent yet ignorant.
Speaker 0: There was also a large group of people just playing DS's and drawing penises on picto chat in the line.
Speaker 0: So they were doing something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, hey if all you wanted to do was play DS Cuz.
Speaker 1: nothing else is interesting.
Speaker 1: The line was a great place to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are all kinds of people at.
Speaker 1: DS is ready to play.
Speaker 0: I felt bad for the staff or who had to deal with that stupid line.
Speaker 1: what they should do is they should just say there is no dealers room line.
Speaker 1: or You know, maybe find a way to open the dealers room when the con opens on Friday.
Speaker 0: I know that'd be hard But I can see a lot of very good reasons why they wanted the dealers room to open late.
Speaker 0: Because the dealers room being open when the con opens.
Speaker 0: That's the first thing most people go to and as a result any panels that are Friday morning get completely decimated.
Speaker 1: I guess I guess.
Speaker 1: but if you lay it by an hour instead of four hours, I think the way it was was fine.
Speaker 0: Just don't let people line up for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course then again You know what?
Speaker 0: Let people line up for it because that keeps people who aren't the brightest bulbs out of everyone else's way Friday morning.
Speaker 1: Mmm, maybe they should.
Speaker 1: and well the thing was at the line for that dealers room, right?
Speaker 1: It was directed in the building and then out, you know towards the escalator area.
Speaker 1: Maybe they have directed it out the tunnel to the street.
Speaker 0: They couldn't because out that tunnel was the registration.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if they bent the registration line towards the base Because you can't line up outside of the Convention Center grounds.
Speaker 0: Remember what happened at during the or before the Laraku concert two years ago?
Speaker 0: Yeah, when the state police came.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know They handled it the best they could other than not letting people line up.
Speaker 0: I can think of a whole bunch of ways to solve the line problems But I think we'll talk about that more when we try to interview some of the staffers in the coming weeks.
Speaker 0: Okay, so Let's go to the geek nights meetup.
Speaker 1: All right, we had a geek night's meetup out on the patio.
Speaker 0: a few people showed up Yep, and rather than talk about it right away.
Speaker 0: I'll just play the things that they said.
Speaker 2: cool My name is Kyle.
Speaker 2: If you're on the forums, my name is fantastic.
Speaker 2: My sister Lindsay is here with me.
Speaker 2: Hey She is on neither, but she's been listening to a whole lot of episodes.
Speaker 0: All right, so here's the basic right now.
Speaker 0: What is your favorite anime ever?
Speaker 2: favorite anime ever?
Speaker 2: I Want to say bebop just but everybody says bebop and so I'm gonna go with flcl.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What do you think is the best anime ever done objectively?
Speaker 2: objectively bebop?
Speaker 2: All right, awesome.
Speaker 0: What was the first anime you ever saw?
Speaker 2: Do we count Voltron?
Speaker 0: Alright Voltron counts, but after Voltron Voltron.
Speaker 2: I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I had all the little lines that connected together and it was awesome.
Speaker 0: What was the first anime you saw that you knew was anime?
Speaker 2: I knew it was anime that would have to be Gundam wing.
Speaker 3: Ah All right
Speaker 2: your
Speaker 1: 2000 Adult Swim stayed
Speaker 2: up every night.
Speaker 0: What was the first anime the first anime the first anime ever made?
Speaker 2: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: Um Yeah, I know Name any director of an anime aside from Miyazaki aside from Miyazaki Miyazaki Uh Koike Kazuko, okay.
Speaker 2: Haven't seen any of his stuff, but I know of him.
Speaker 2: Have you listened to anime world order?
Speaker 3: I have listened to anime world order.
Speaker 0: What do you think anime world order?
Speaker 0: cuz they're here and we're gonna make fun of them like we always do.
Speaker 2: I like anime world order.
Speaker 2: I haven't seen a whole lot of the stuff that they've seen but they're introducing me to new things every day.
Speaker 2: Have you ever seen MD guys?
Speaker 0: No, did you hear their review of empty guys?
Speaker 0: did?
Speaker 0: did it make you want to see MD guys?
Speaker 2: ever Good I did not accept that it was the second worst anime ever I've heard.
Speaker 2: that said I didn't know any details.
Speaker 1: the little like hateful self of me kind of wants to see it Just because you got to see it.
Speaker 0: Your first con - yeah now, what was your first anime?
Speaker 0: Dragon Ball Dragon Ball or Dragon Ball?
Speaker 2: see Dragon Ball because of him Was it?
Speaker 2: oh good I was about to say Dragon Ball, that's cool, but now You know, I I grew up on him watching something on TV and I'm sitting there trying to get the remote.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so I kind of grew on you over time.
Speaker 0: Eventually, yes, what's your favorite anime name?
Speaker 0: a couple that are really good either old ones or once you're watching right now.
Speaker 2: Well, because I've really gotten anime lately.
Speaker 2: I like Ghost in the shell standalone complex, I like Fullmetal Alchemist just because.
Speaker 0: and I liked fruits basket but Those are my.
Speaker 0: yeah now you watch the anime if you read the manga Not really.
Speaker 2: I really want to.
Speaker 2: I'm about to start buying.
Speaker 2: Hey guys, this is bolt matrix from the forums.
Speaker 2: I'm in Baltimore I live here and uh, just you know what if you're not here you suck.
Speaker 0: So, what was your first anime the first one you ever saw that you knew was anime Speed Racer.
Speaker 0: Wow What was the first anime ever made?
Speaker 2: That would have been Tetsuza an astro boy.
Speaker 0: Can you name any directors of anime?
Speaker 0: Other than Miyazaki?
Speaker 2: other than Miyazaki.
Speaker 2: Oh God, the scary thing is I can't pronounce his name.
Speaker 0: Try it.
Speaker 2: I think we'll know who it is.
Speaker 2: No, you don't want Ikuhara.
Speaker 2: No, I'm thinking of the guy that did Robotech and I can't come up with his name, but there's also the guy that did.
Speaker 2: uh Fuck me What are you watching right now, I am watching Erica seven xx-holic.
Speaker 2: Oh Fuck I am watching bleach but in fast-forward.
Speaker 0: Ulta waramaru.
Speaker 0: So, what's your favorite anime?
Speaker 0: give or take Transformers.
Speaker 0: without a doubt that was not the answer.
Speaker 0: I expected that's awesome.
Speaker 0: What do you think of the new transformers movie?
Speaker 2: I am totally stoked.
Speaker 2: My podcast is the only transformers podcast, but I won't plug it.
Speaker 0: if you don't want plug your frickin podcast.
Speaker 2: Got that TF wire comm TFW re.
Speaker 2: we're the only transformers podcast out there.
Speaker 2: So, yeah, I'm actually gonna be asking you questions about it to help us improve.
Speaker 2: Now do you listen to anime world order?
Speaker 2: I listen to it religiously.
Speaker 0: did you?
Speaker 0: did you hear their MD guys of review?
Speaker 2: I laughed my balls off.
Speaker 0: Did it know?
Speaker 0: Did you think I never want to see that show or did you think I want to see what they're talking about?
Speaker 2: I actually saw it many years before they said it and I was sitting there going.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I got to say the fans of geek nights who actually hung out with us at Otakon were the people who I'd kind of Picked out in the forums over the course of you know, the last many months as people who are generally agreeable to me.
Speaker 0: So Peter, how's Otakon treating you so far?
Speaker 2: You have anything you like to say to our listeners out there?
Speaker 0: What do you need for dinner tonight?
Speaker 1: Slayer yeah, there are some other people in the forum who are agreeable to me.
Speaker 1: They did not show up, but the people who did show up were generally awesome.
Speaker 0: We're not going to give you the list of people but suffice to say there's a group of about five or six people in the forums Outside of the actual front row crew Who Scott and I have found we can count on to say the kinds of things we would say even when we're not there.
Speaker 0: Yep We actually haven't been there much lately due to being busy with life.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Okay, let's talk about what was in the dealers room.
Speaker 0: Oh, you don't want to talk about the meetup More to say about it.
Speaker 1: I mean we played audio of it and that was pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well aside from that we also hung out with the anime world order people.
Speaker 0: Yeah Gerald and Daryl Some things happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll talk about.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about that.
Speaker 0: And also I'd like to give a plug for Next week probably Wednesday, maybe Thursday.
Speaker 0: I'm not exactly sure yet, but I recorded well.
Speaker 0: We recorded two separate long round tables that were actually we use the real equipment instead of that crappy recording bit One with a whole bunch of webcomic artists including a guy who does Dominic Deegan seer for hire It's in classic guy who does that and I know who does fallen and a few other people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I promised that a week from tomorrow.
Speaker 1: We would do the.
Speaker 1: what is the front row crew episode?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So I guess the next two Wednesdays are gonna be recordings from Otakon one involving webcomics and one involving clown pistols.
Speaker 0: and in addition to that round table, we recorded a Kind of late-night half drunken us talking about anime and anime cons thing with anime world order Ninja consultant and fast karate for the gentleman fast karate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's slow karate faster.
Speaker 0: now Once again, I have things to say about that round table, which I think I'm going to play a short clip from tonight.
Speaker 0: But the whole thing will be available at some point next week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we'll just.
Speaker 1: I figure we would do that a week from today or two weeks from today.
Speaker 0: true But I might play the relevant clip from it tonight.
Speaker 1: I think that's a good idea Alright, so in the dealers room.
Speaker 1: It was a dealers room.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It was a massive.
Speaker 1: as always The industry area was kind of like sparse.
Speaker 1: I mean Bandai wasn't there and Viz wasn't there and those were like my big places.
Speaker 1: that's where I go.
Speaker 1: Viz has the bags and You know Bandai has the robots and they were not there.
Speaker 0: In fact, there was almost no free stuff this year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean now the thing is no Khan has had free stuff for a while.
Speaker 1: I Don't know what's up with that.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't think the industry is doing so well But here's the thing.
Speaker 1: if you go to in all the panels a lot of the industry panels In fact, pretty much all the industry panels what they did is they would do trivia and free stuff.
Speaker 1: that's like the big thing at panels now is trivia and then giving away DVDs and But they're not giving away.
Speaker 1: like the free goodies in the dealers room.
Speaker 1: The artists alley is still giving away free goodies, but not the dealers and not the industry.
Speaker 0: what the hell now in terms of what?
Speaker 0: We bought I mean the dealers room was impressive.
Speaker 0: as far as Otakon dealers rooms go it is big.
Speaker 1: But they didn't fill the dealers room, but they did have more dealers than last year.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, well I didn't buy much just because I bought everything I wanted to buy this year at anime next and to an extent at a con.
Speaker 1: I mean I pretty much bought anything I wanted there and there wasn't that much that I wanted.
Speaker 1: that I didn't already have.
Speaker 0: I kind of wanted the Death Note box thing.
Speaker 0: I just didn't get around to buying it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it's just too much money.
Speaker 1: It's like I wanted the original Galaxy Express 3 9 movie poster, but for 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: you can yeah You know, but almost the entire front row crew each bought the giant robo box set.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were selling all of giant robo.
Speaker 1: I have Vogler in this plastic eyeball for I think 30 bucks But another guy had it for 25 and another guy had a used one.
Speaker 1: That was beat up for 10.
Speaker 0: Yep And at least seven of us bought it.
Speaker 3: Yep and buy right DVD.
Speaker 3: who is the ultimate seller of cheap DVDs?
Speaker 3: Those are the guys who sold the $5 DVDs and everything you can buy from their website.
Speaker 3: But then you have to make a minimum order of like a whole mess of DVDs.
Speaker 3: But if you see them at a con you can buy just one DVD for five bucks.
Speaker 3: They were selling among many other very cheap box sets The Zeta Gundam box set which comes with a ton of shit in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, didn't it come with like 12 pencil sharpeners?
Speaker 3: Yeah, it came with 12 robot pencil sharpeners, which are much more robot than pencil sharpener.
Speaker 3: I don't know why they even put the pencil sharpeners in there because they're just robot toys Through a specific scene for family guy.
Speaker 3: They were selling this box set for 40 bucks.
Speaker 3: Now this was like supposed to be a $200 box set.
Speaker 3: now 40 bucks 50 episodes Plus swag as less than a buck an episode and free swag.
Speaker 0: now wasn't it the one with the broken subtitles?
Speaker 3: Yeah, there are a few problems with the release.
Speaker 3: I mean, it's not a perfect amazing release.
Speaker 3: However, Zeta Gundam is probably as far as I've been told I'm gonna watch it to find out the Gundam series period like the best one and This is the US release.
Speaker 3: it's what you know and it's watchable, I mean, it's not the worst ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see what I watch it because so far Much of the Gundam I've watched has been pretty bad, but I've watched you know f91.
Speaker 0: Yeah Wing was actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: I kind of enjoyed wing.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm seed was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, G Gundam can die in a fire.
Speaker 3: G Gundam could die in two fires and a thousand fiery son.
Speaker 0: My favorite gun him is still war in the pocket.
Speaker 3: Yeah, that was a good one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: Of course it was.
Speaker 3: no.
Speaker 3: no my favorite though I think right now is like the eighth MS team.
Speaker 3: still is that one?
Speaker 3: You know was just.
Speaker 3: the robots were more like tanks and they were just generic war machines and it wasn't about robots at all.
Speaker 3: You know Gundam seed would be my favorite but half the show was about robots and about you know, crazy Gundam stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright now right along with the dealers room is the artist alley Which every year is usually one of the highlights of my con experience.
Speaker 0: Now before we talk about the artist alley I'm going to play a whole bunch of interviews done both by us and more importantly by our Correspondence in the field.
Speaker 0: Kate and Adam aka art boy.
Speaker 2: Hi, this is Kate correspondent for geek nights here at Otacon 2006.
Speaker 2: I'm with chai otherwise known as Lianne PC here for chai.
Speaker 2: chai Chai studios, okay We're talking today about her lovely artwork.
Speaker 2: Let me tell you the inking is amazing and I highly recommend you check out chai studios.
Speaker 2: comm Alright chai.
Speaker 2: What kind of artwork you normally do?
Speaker 2: I do a lot of mixture of Asian themes pieces and characters with more of a realistic feel to it.
Speaker 2: I love doing more old-school fantasy pirate artwork ninja artwork the whole Fun little based in history.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but then taking it to a whole new extreme And it looks like you use an anime type style, but not No Doesn't nicely?
Speaker 2: I end up getting a lot of people who are just like a fan art banner.
Speaker 2: So I do play around a lot with that.
Speaker 2: But I was very influenced by Japanese anime and Japanese woodblock prints growing up.
Speaker 2: So that has found a way into my style.
Speaker 2: Oh interesting.
Speaker 2: Do you do any etching into the woodblock yourself?
Speaker 2: Um, I actually do not do woodblock prints.
Speaker 2: I did do lithography for a while and I do actually do screen printing where I try the style of Wood blocks and do it on fabrics and clothing my fashion design.
Speaker 2: Have you ever thought of bringing any of that to Otacon?
Speaker 2: I Actually have not done that because a lot of people aren't quite so interested in original fashions at Oda.
Speaker 2: Oh, really?
Speaker 2: Is that the trend you think or is it just price issues?
Speaker 2: I think it's price issues.
Speaker 2: when you're a freelancer Kind of go with what is definitely price efficient and what you know will sell where you're at.
Speaker 2: So I actually bring a lot of that.
Speaker 2: I do fashion shows in the New Haven and Boston area, so I always bring that stuff to those but I don't bring my Portfolio collection of anime themed artwork there either because they'd be like, um, how is this high couture?
Speaker 2: That would be an issue.
Speaker 2: Alright, so where are you from?
Speaker 2: I'm actually currently located in western, Massachusetts in Ludlow, which is next to Springfield But I was a navy brat.
Speaker 2: I'm from everywhere.
Speaker 2: What cons do you frequent?
Speaker 2: Most of the New England ones.
Speaker 2: I do anime Boston and Otacon every year.
Speaker 2: I also do con bust and I did kinetic on for the first time this past year.
Speaker 2: and how many Otacons have you been to?
Speaker 2: I've been here.
Speaker 2: I. I Have been attending Otacon since 1998 So quite a veteran.
Speaker 2: Yep.
Speaker 2: I only started doing artists alley.
Speaker 2: However about two years ago.
Speaker 2: So it's still new for me.
Speaker 2: And do you take Commission?
Speaker 2: I do.
Speaker 2: What's the strangest and or most perverted and or silliest Commission request you've ever gotten?
Speaker 2: That would be for a zombie cow pirate in chibi form.
Speaker 2: And did you complete the mission?
Speaker 2: I did and I was quite amused because he informed me that the cow was also purple.
Speaker 2: That's an odd request.
Speaker 2: I'd have to say how much did it cost for that specific Commission?
Speaker 2: $10?
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 2: What's the most perverted request you've ever gotten?
Speaker 2: I Am yeah, I'm doing a wife of venom piece right now.
Speaker 2: Yes, it's the bathing suit is the venom Aspect from Marvel and like.
Speaker 2: oh, it's very interesting very confusing to me.
Speaker 2: Okay, but I see you do some yaoi and some shown and I that that is not exclusively what you do.
Speaker 2: Do you find that that sells better at cons?
Speaker 2: And sometimes people at cons are always looking for their favorite pairings that they're never gonna see.
Speaker 2: and I actually have two pairings that From Naruto that people never really see not even in doujinshi's.
Speaker 2: and what pairing would that be?
Speaker 2: Kakashi and Asama?
Speaker 2: Yeah, so so for yaoi and shown in i-fans.
Speaker 2: I think it's a really nice thing, but it's also nice that you mark it off and you give a warning.
Speaker 2: So, you know your art is child friendly too.
Speaker 2: Just don't go into those sections.
Speaker 2: I have large Disney stickers covering up the center bit.
Speaker 2: Haha interesting Have you ever had to draw a giant member a giant pulsating member?
Speaker 2: No, I refuse those.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah, you don't do those.
Speaker 2: Um, I have a point where I'm like, okay, I'm sorry I think you'll be more better served by the tentacle porn down the.
Speaker 2: So your integrity is not for sale.
Speaker 2: No, unfortunately not.
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 2: All right.
Speaker 2: Thank you very much Chai.
Speaker 2: I hope everyone checks out Chai Studios at CHISTUDIOS.COM And thank you so much for doing an interview for Geek Nights.
Speaker 2: Oh, by the way one last trivia question What was the first anime?
Speaker 2: I knew this one Astro Boy.
Speaker 2: All right, this is art boy from Geek Nights and I'm here with mr.
Speaker 2: Troy, mr Troy who has a very interesting setup here.
Speaker 2: What's what are you doing here?
Speaker 2: This booth looks like some video games going on.
Speaker 2: Yes, this is a game that we're working on called dig jetpack attack and when I say we I mean pop snot That's.
Speaker 2: it's in terror.
Speaker 2: entire area right here.
Speaker 2: Now.
Speaker 2: What kind of system you run in here?
Speaker 2: I've never seen a box like that.
Speaker 2: um, this is a America media systems G box.
Speaker 2: It's a. it's a basic PC running now Windows XP.
Speaker 2: I have four USB controllers hooked up and two screens So that when you play the game you can either fight on the top of the screen or on the bottom screen.
Speaker 2: So it's like a dual screen action.
Speaker 2: You gotta go in there.
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 2: All right.
Speaker 2: What kind of game is it?
Speaker 2: It's a Basic platform shooter.
Speaker 2: It's still in early stages.
Speaker 2: So like you can't really hide behind anything but um You basically just run and shoot each other.
Speaker 2: Cool, and you guys got a website.
Speaker 2: Um, yes, we just kind of opened up a few days ago.
Speaker 2: So the website's not really done, but it's going to be pop snot calm.
Speaker 2: That's P. O. P. S. K. N. O T. Not as in likes not not as it's not right.
Speaker 2: Got it.
Speaker 2: All right.
Speaker 2: Hi, this is Kate a correspondent for geek nights.
Speaker 2: I'm here with Sebastian who is selling friends.
Speaker 2: Don't let friends cosplay t-shirts.
Speaker 2: Hi, Sebastian.
Speaker 1: How you doing?
Speaker 2: I'm doing quite well yourself, sir.
Speaker 1: I'm bored right now, but not doing too bad.
Speaker 2: Yeah, and we're here at artists alley at Otacon.
Speaker 2: How many Otacons have you been to?
Speaker 1: This is my second one.
Speaker 2: And did you go to the one the previous year?
Speaker 2: Yeah How many other cons have you been to?
Speaker 2: I've been to anime USA and katakan once this past year And for a bit of trivia, what is the first anime ever made?
Speaker 2: I have no idea.
Speaker 2: It's Astro Boy.
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 2: We have someone from the side saying Astro Boy.
Speaker 2: It is Astro Boy.
Speaker 2: Now why do you have the hate from the cosplayers?
Speaker 1: it's not really hate.
Speaker 2: it's a jab at everybody who takes Cosplaying way too seriously.
Speaker 2: Can you give me an example of someone who took cosplaying way too seriously?
Speaker 2: I don't know about too seriously But there's people who see it as as
Speaker 1: a joke
Speaker 2: and who are cosplaying and there's the people who actually get mad at us
Speaker 0: for
Speaker 2: having this shirt on sale, and I think that's the people
Speaker 0: who need to lighten up and Realize
Speaker 1: it's just
Speaker 2: like a hobby.
Speaker 2: or you know, it's not It's it's not real.
Speaker 2: It's you know, it's something to do.
Speaker 2: It's a fantasy.
Speaker 2: Yeah, and what do you have to say to people who cosplay outside of their body type ie?
Speaker 2: incredibly fat women in skimpy clothing or Incredibly ugly hairy men in skimpy clothing or really anyone who shouldn't be in skimpy clothing and skimpy clothing.
Speaker 2: They need to stop because Anything that they wouldn't wear outside of a con should not be worn All right.
Speaker 2: This is art boy.
Speaker 2: You're You're you're Phil finder in the field.
Speaker 2: I'm currently trying to find in the fan art area who has the filthiest most horrible fan art and tried to interview them and ask Them why God why but I haven't found anybody yet.
Speaker 2: and unless the artists keep putting me in different directions and saying well We don't know where anybody really filthy is like we have some soft stuff, but nothing really terrible.
Speaker 2: So and right now I'm going to head over to the fan art Art show and head into the adult area and see what people there have to say because you know I'm going to go where no man has gone before.
Speaker 2: All right.
Speaker 2: This is art boy.
Speaker 2: I have now entered the den of iniquity that we know as the adult area in the Otacon Art show and so far it's actually rather tame.
Speaker 2: There's not a hell of a lot going on in here.
Speaker 2: Hang on one second All right, this is a second take.
Speaker 2: this is art boy.
Speaker 2: You are Phil finder in the field.
Speaker 2: I am currently walking through the adult art area at Otacon.
Speaker 2: I entered expecting horrible horrible things, but really it's not that terrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's not a lot of.
Speaker 2: there's a lot of pornography around.
Speaker 2: it used your staff But what's your name?
Speaker 0: Maxwell Maxwell?
Speaker 2: Why do you think there's such a low turnout of a filth this year?
Speaker 2: It just depends on which artists come.
Speaker 2: And would you say this is pretty tame compared to what we've seen in the past.
Speaker 2: sex my first year kind.
Speaker 2: This is your first year at Otacon.
Speaker 2: Yes, sir.
Speaker 2: Oh, you know what you're missing.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I think that Somebody's been here before because I think that some of this artwork that would be considered the dope really isn't.
Speaker 2: I mean We got.
Speaker 2: we have some Final Fantasy characters here who are really just holding towels in front of them.
Speaker 2: It's suggestive it just hold towels if I'm looking terrible.
Speaker 2: Yeah, there's a new yosh character lounging in a bed.
Speaker 2: There's one thing that's selling for like $500 that looks like the frame cost more than the artwork.
Speaker 2: I mean, it's just sort of sad.
Speaker 2: I don't see if I can find anybody who's into this kind of thing trying to interview them.
Speaker 2: You know, sometimes if you see an artwork, there's a minimum bid very high.
Speaker 2: It could just be the artist is you know what not for sale.
Speaker 2: put a minimum bid.
Speaker 2: That's true.
Speaker 2: That's a good idea.
Speaker 2: So tell me you're here in the adult area of Otacon.
Speaker 2: What brought you into this area?
Speaker 2: What were you hoping to find?
Speaker 2: Because last year they actually had a few that were pretty good, but it's only that's as much as last year I guess normally Past I have come in here and it's just been like a den of iniquity full of filth of all imaginable kinds.
Speaker 2: Yeah, would you say this year sort of a disappointing turnout?
Speaker 2: Yes a little bit like they're good, but last year There's just so much variety.
Speaker 2: Were you looking for something specific this year or just whatever tickled your fancy?
Speaker 2: Yeah browsing.
Speaker 2: All right, cool I'm gonna keep on looking around.
Speaker 2: you have anything to say about the turnout this year for the?
Speaker 2: for the adult area I'm a little disappointed.
Speaker 2: I love hentai and I I just see one that I would really think of buying just because it's two bondage girls.
Speaker 2: What do you think about these Final Fantasy ones?
Speaker 2: I mean, would you classify those as really adults?
Speaker 2: Not really because First of all, I don't like guy hentai.
Speaker 2: second of all They're not naked.
Speaker 0: I Is good the Good But you know, no and no nudity.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's pretty tame in the news here And even we even have a Rama looks like a Rama one-half inked on rice paper on which there are No nipples and no sex going on either.
Speaker 2: Oh, just she's kind of riding Rama.
Speaker 2: All right, let's see if anybody else is anything to say here in the the adult section.
Speaker 2: let's see we have a suggestive Oscar seen that a thousand times and Wow, there are numerous numerous panels that are completely Completely empty.
Speaker 3: What are your feelings on the empty panels here?
Speaker 2: We could have drawn it Gravitation gravitation.
Speaker 2: Yeah Sean and I are if you're looking for mega mix that Before.
Speaker 2: yeah What's last year's compared to this year's much better.
Speaker 2: they had way more stuff way more stuff.
Speaker 2: Yeah Would you say that that you normally find things that are also more suggestive and if I may more filthy here?
Speaker 2: Because I think that what I've seen coming from an art background is pretty tame.
Speaker 2: Think it's like sort of marginally because people still like to keep it pretty like I find like more like I mean More the hardwood stuff.
Speaker 2: It's just like in the dojinshi.
Speaker 2: You don't really see it a lot on the like the walls.
Speaker 2: If they had a couple of hardwood pieces last year, but definitely this year.
Speaker 2: It's totally flat like This stuff might as well be outside.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I see walking around here.
Speaker 2: I see like it's like a full.
Speaker 2: There's a full display that is empty.
Speaker 2: There's another full display.
Speaker 2: That is Mostly empty as there are a couple of framed things which aren't I'd say are more suggestive.
Speaker 2: as opposed to a doll This could be like out on the out on the tables.
Speaker 2: There there are three.
Speaker 2: there are three completely empty displays and all in all a pretty sad showing Pretty pretty sad showing and a disappointment to a hand-tied pants everywhere.
Speaker 2: if I might go so far This has been our boy your fill finder in the field for Otakon 2006.
Speaker 3: Wow, I never listened to those interviews and you know, I still haven't listened to them.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I didn't really listen to them either.
Speaker 0: I listened through them a little bit while I Man mashed the absolute hell out of them to make them not sound bad because that Sony recording bit is starting to become my arch Enemy.
Speaker 3: Ram and Scott are not responsible for the content of the interviews.
Speaker 3: You just listened to.
Speaker 0: yes I mean I trust Kate and Adam very much and I'm pretty sure the inner I mean.
Speaker 0: I skimmed through them and it seemed like they interviewed some really interesting funny people and I like Adams a filth finding mission Very much Despite the fact that he dropped and broke my Sony ICD p320.
Speaker 0: good.
Speaker 3: It deserved it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: It didn't deserve it.
Speaker 0: Sony deserved it.
Speaker 0: This is like the poor crippled kid that Sony crippled.
Speaker 0: This could have been such an awesome piece of hardware and Sony's DRM ruined it.
Speaker 2: Yeah, speaking of DRM As an IT professional DRM can blow me outstanding.
Speaker 2: I agree with that.
Speaker 0: How many of us are IT professionals or computer programmers?
Speaker 2: Who's?
Speaker 2: who's the Neil Luddite?
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah scientists Where I work here in Baltimore We do not allow iTunes installed because of the DRM will actually cause problems with the machine setups because the DRM is running in the background and we have Certain software on the machines that let us know what the fuck people are doing and that DRM will actually Cause that software that we built ourselves to go.
Speaker 2: no good so We've actually figured out a way around it.
Speaker 2: I can't say what it is because I want to keep my job But we struggled for about a year with this with the Apple DRM and we're running into other issues now with DRM because now we're recording meetings
Speaker 0: and we're
Speaker 2: actually doing video casts and I work for a subsidiary of a very very very fucking large Multinational corporation and the DRM of other products is causing problems with our in-house
Speaker 0: stuff.
Speaker 0: that was from our Geek nights meet up.
Speaker 0: a few of our listeners and some of our front row crew members had some things to say about DRM after an argument that had broken out in our forums a while ago about it.
Speaker 3: Anyway back to the artists alley.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 3: Yeah, the artists alley this year.
Speaker 3: It was pretty good.
Speaker 0: I mean, I was very much impressed with the caliber of art in the artists alley itself.
Speaker 0: It seemed to be above average.
Speaker 3: It was definitely above average.
Speaker 3: Also, the artists alley was really big and the layout was really good and they get people got a lot of table space but there were some empty tables in the back corner.
Speaker 3: now, I realized the artists alley did sell out when they first allowed signups and Because some people didn't pay or you know copped out that it left empty tables that were not filled.
Speaker 0: Yep now the thing is there are quite a bit more cop-outs than usual and my best guess is that one after the whole OMG Otakon is banning fan art.
Speaker 3: lol riot that happened and then that might have had a small effect.
Speaker 3: Yeah, like I don't think because I don't think the news of that was that widespread It was.
Speaker 0: but the the thing that I wanted to mention that about is that I noticed who was Conspicuously absent from the artist alley this year.
Speaker 0: all those artists who just mass manufacturer basically traced things or Naruto headbands are generally all the people who kind of say the Naruto headband manufacturers were not there.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, there was a guy making him but he wasn't making Naruto once.
Speaker 0: he was making just weird funny custom ones.
Speaker 3: Ah Aha, but there were the people who made like the hats.
Speaker 3: remember those people.
Speaker 3: Yeah, they were in the dealers room.
Speaker 3: They moved.
Speaker 3: they actually made a company.
Speaker 3: they moved on up.
Speaker 3: Yeah, so yeah, there were a bunch of people absent.
Speaker 3: however I do think that they if you notice the time when they announced that there are a bunch of cop-outs and openings Was real close to the con.
Speaker 3: I think they should have had the deadline for paying up and you know You know not copping out a little earlier to give people who you know might have been on the waiting list more.
Speaker 0: We were offered as geek nights a table in the artists alley Just because we had a panel and we could use it for geek nights.
Speaker 0: We decided early on that we didn't want it Because we figured we didn't want to deny an artist a chance to be in the alley.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And then the artist alley sold out.
Speaker 0: so we felt very justified and smug in our altruistic decision.
Speaker 0: Then right before the con we find out oh noes There are artists alleys tables and by then it was totally too late for us to put together a geek nights thing.
Speaker 3: Yeah, it's like if the artists alley sells out right the freaking day you open it for sign ups.
Speaker 3: You should require that everyone cough up the money within a couple, you know Maybe three to four weeks if they haven't paid up.
Speaker 3: by then You got a clear amount and have a waiting list and all that good stuff.
Speaker 0: Seems that Otakon generally is very very forgiving of stupidity among its members.
Speaker 3: Yeah I mean they stopped.
Speaker 3: basically what they do is instead of having like smart systems and forcing people into them They just try to make it so simple that there's less you can be stupid with, you know They eliminated group memberships, which was a great thing.
Speaker 0: group memberships have caused nothing but problems at any con ever Yeah, but they only cause problems because of stupidity.
Speaker 3: So rather than force people to be smart or punish them for being dumb.
Speaker 0: They just eliminate your chance to be dumb, you know, well with the group discounts It's not just that it screws stupid people.
Speaker 0: smart people also screw Otakon.
Speaker 0: Just think about it.
Speaker 0: You just go in the forum find ten people are all going to.
Speaker 3: oh, yeah That's a separate issue.
Speaker 3: But you see I'm talking about the general, you know dealing with stupid people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well thing is it seems like Otakon will always put forth the maximum effort to help anyone.
Speaker 3: Yeah I mean which is which is good and bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if one I see a lot of cases where like one person screws up their registration and The staff the high-level staffers will personally track down what happened and then email the person back right away.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and All I can say is that Otakon has some of the most dedicated and amazing staff of any convention I've ever been to.
Speaker 3: Yeah, I think it's a great policy to help anyone who has any amount of trouble.
Speaker 3: However, I do not think that you should it.
Speaker 3: there's a line at which you say, okay We can't give you any more personal help beyond this level because then it would be denying someone else of something, you know And you know trying to give someone that extra Excessive amount of time to pay for their artists.
Speaker 3: alley is keeping someone else out of the alley, you know.
Speaker 3: And there's like.
Speaker 3: you got to put a deadline and say that's it, you know.
Speaker 3: Yeah, I mean if you really want set a deadline and then the real deadline is a week later You know to allow for the latecomers, I think they do that too.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 3: Yeah, but you get my point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I get your point.
Speaker 0: But despite that I mean the caliber of art was amazing.
Speaker 0: I was very impressed with a lot of the artists.
Speaker 0: I saw I took a whole bunch of business cards.
Speaker 0: I plan to commission several of the artists I met later on Even though the one person I wanted to commission the most said that she doesn't take commissions.
Speaker 3: How could you not take commissions?
Speaker 0: It was it was the girl who had those that black metal work stuff I wanted all right.
Speaker 0: I wanted a full-size utenna rose that I could put in my window.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, like just the full, you know, the black like silhouetted utenna rose Yeah, and she explained that she doesn't do commissions and I didn't have a chance to.
Speaker 0: you know Try to convince her otherwise, so maybe I'll try later.
Speaker 3: Uh, did you get her website or whatever?
Speaker 0: I have her business card.
Speaker 3: Yeah, the art show was also pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yes You see I was worried because all the cons I've gone to this year so far had pretty mediocre art shows.
Speaker 3: Basically no art show to speak of.
Speaker 0: yeah But even the ones that had an art show they just there were a lot of those bootleg kind of look.
Speaker 0: someone traced a cell.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: You're such a talented artist.
Speaker 3: Yeah, the art show at Otacon this year, you know They didn't fill up all of the space they had for it with art Which is you know, it makes the art show look smaller than it is because you have all these empty spaces Which is good because that way the art show can be as big as it needs to be But it also it makes it feel small when it's not.
Speaker 3: you know what I'm saying?
Speaker 3: Yeah Anyway, there was lots of awesome arts in there.
Speaker 0: Yep of note There were these power of girls things that I've been on all of them and I was outbid.
Speaker 3: There was a little Phoenix right in a frame that I bid on and lost.
Speaker 0: There was a kid Koopa being beaten up by all the other Koopa kids.
Speaker 0: That was awesome and I bid quite a bit of money and yet I was outbid.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I bought the print.
Speaker 0: I'm very happy.
Speaker 3: Yeah, speaking of that kid Koopa print there were Two artists in the artists alley that were quite particularly awesome And I want to give them the mad props mostly because they stay drew sketches in the pirate book.
Speaker 0: Oh the pirate book.
Speaker 0: for anyone who isn't aware of our pirate book.
Speaker 0: This was Scott's idea and he is its minder Mm-hmm.
Speaker 3: I got a blank sketchbook and I'm gonna take it to all the conventions.
Speaker 3: and at the conventions I go to the cool artists the particularly awesome ones and I say Will you draw anything you want as long as it is piratey in some way in this book?
Speaker 3: and Eventually, this book will be full of piratey goodness.
Speaker 3: so far I think most of our artsy friends have drawn something in it Have they?
Speaker 0: we forgot to ask almost everyone during the week of awesome there.
Speaker 3: a few of them did and a few of them did.
Speaker 3: Not you know, it's not like we're not gonna see them again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not hard to track down.
Speaker 3: There are if there are friends they're gonna draw something in it and if you know But you know the rest of the pages have I think there's like three or four friends who still have to do it and then From then on it's all I got to say.
Speaker 0: the best thing in that book is still that bone beard.
Speaker 3: Yeah, okay a bone beard.
Speaker 3: It was drawn by the guy who did your kid Koopa and he also did the print I bought from him Which was like Galactus verse.
Speaker 0: I forgot about that.
Speaker 3: It's got Galactus and then it has you know The Katamari king of the universe guy and then it has the silver surfer and a little Katamari.
Speaker 3: It's sort of like this, you know It's very well done.
Speaker 3: Yes, that guy's name that awesome.
Speaker 3: Awesome guy who drew bone beard the ghost.
Speaker 3: I guess that's what we're calling him.
Speaker 0: Well, he has a bone beard of little bones.
Speaker 3: I know it's so great.
Speaker 3: I'm gonna scan it in and put it on the internet.
Speaker 3: His name is Brandon Kramer and his website is Brando k.com br a and D. Okay, ay dot-com and it's awesome.
Speaker 3: You can actually see the kid Koopa and the Galactus and stuff on his website on some section on there.
Speaker 3: The other awesome person who was an awesome artist.
Speaker 3: I was in the art show And there was this whole section full of these incredibly cute pay like illustrations.
Speaker 3: It was just like oh my god Like every single one of them was like, oh my god.
Speaker 0: And I look that would that for those of you who think Scott is just this horrible Crotchety asshole that is a side of Scott you rarely see.
Speaker 3: And I was you know, it was.
Speaker 3: I realized.
Speaker 3: hey all of these are by the same part.
Speaker 3: Well, it's not hard to tell they were all by the same person, but they were too awesome.
Speaker 0: Just the way she draws her eyes just really sets her characters off.
Speaker 3: Yeah It wasn't your typical anime art and the quality was like ten steps above just about everything else there in terms of skill Involved and everything, you know, and I looked and the name on all of it was Katie Osoyeki, I don't know how to pronounce the last name and I'm sure
Speaker 1: she'll
Speaker 3: forgive us but Osoyeki, whatever.
Speaker 3: and I was like, oh my god.
Speaker 3: I wonder if that person is here.
Speaker 3: Well, they must be here.
Speaker 3: So I went over to the artist alley info booth and I said does Katie Osoyeki have a table?
Speaker 3: and sure enough she did.
Speaker 3: so I went to find her and she was awesome and She drew a little girl in the buyer book that goes are I'm a pirate And she has a little parrot and whatever it is quite high quality.
Speaker 3: Yeah, I'll scan it and put on the internet also.
Speaker 3: She is too awesome.
Speaker 3: You can go to her website, which is Katie o katie o dot k?
Speaker 3: u i ki dot net.
Speaker 3: she also has a Deviant art which you can find if you just search for Katie.
Speaker 0: Oh Yep.
Speaker 0: Also our friend Carla was in the artist alley.
Speaker 0: Our friend cat was in the artist alley.
Speaker 0: our friend Brian Carroll of instant classic was in the artist alley.
Speaker 0: Our friend I do who does fallen was in the artist alley sharing a table with our good friend Nury who does Artist Ally the podcast and she was selling her awesome dice jewelry.
Speaker 0: Yes She came up like killing selling dice jewelry at an amazement and she started like making dice jewelry.
Speaker 0: That's exactly what it is.
Speaker 0: Like little earring with a d8 or a pen.
Speaker 0: Scott Johnson bought the best piece.
Speaker 0: It's a d30 Just like on this bling chain, it's basically a black rope with a d30.
Speaker 0: at the end of it It looks like such a 70s swinger thing.
Speaker 3: It does it's.
Speaker 3: so It's not really something you want to wear.
Speaker 3: I mean, I maybe a d20 I would wear on a shorter rope.
Speaker 0: I think the thing Scott Johnson bought is great.
Speaker 3: It's great for him.
Speaker 3: He's got a giant hairy chest like a 70s swinger.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is I think that is the perfect because if you go to a club wearing like a 70s shirt With the top unbuttoned a bit and wearing that around your neck that that'll be the awesome.
Speaker 0: because if any girl Talks to you despite that she is cool guaranteed.
Speaker 3: or if a girl comes up and says she knows what it is Like why do you have a d30 on your neck then?
Speaker 3: That's the one.
Speaker 3: see you once he's like, what's that?
Speaker 3: Those are not the ones.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You want to.
Speaker 0: why does that dice not have dots on it?
Speaker 0: Why does it have numbers?
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyone who knows, you know die notation really really really is a cool person Mm-hmm, but she was telling these things left and right.
Speaker 0: good God.
Speaker 3: Okay, so artist Ally was awesome.
Speaker 1: I spent a lot of time there as did.
Speaker 1: I didn't get tired of it.
Speaker 1: I just kept walking around finding new awesome thing.
Speaker 0: In fact Sunday after we'd completely lost our voices we ran into a girl who was doing caricatures there.
Speaker 0: She works at some amusement park and she's an anime fan.
Speaker 0: so she did I forget her name or I'd plug her but she decided to do anime type caricatures and We didn't really get to talk to her so much and I wanted to interview her.
Speaker 0: Neither one of us could actually talk.
Speaker 0: so we kind of stood there and gestured as she talked to us for a while Yep, so that was artist Ally.
Speaker 1: Yes in the video game room.
Speaker 1: We talked about that yesterday.
Speaker 1: So we're skipping over that.
Speaker 0: Yep, if you want to hear our coverage of gaming at Otakon check out yesterday's episode.
Speaker 1: Okay, let's talk about the showings now.
Speaker 0: the only thing I Actually watch at Otakon was Osamu Tezuka's porno.
Speaker 0: It was well, it's not really pornographic It was just it was in the over 18 showings and many people call it a hentai though It's more just an erotically charged animation.
Speaker 1: Yes It's called Belladonna and is not something that's easy to get or see and I wish I would have known about it because I would have gone To it.
Speaker 0: I watched a good 15 minutes of it and with Adam art boy, and it was really cool and I really kind of want to see it.
Speaker 0: in total.
Speaker 0: the problem was it was raw and My knowledge of Japanese extends to say is raw.
Speaker 0: It was raw.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't know that.
Speaker 0: luckily my knowledge of anime Japanese is good enough to where I kind of figured out what was going on and that there was a Demon.
Speaker 0: and because I kept the eye, you know when you're an anime fan There's words you hear all the time and I heard a lot of those words.
Speaker 0: So I could kind of figure out what was going on.
Speaker 0: and in terms of actual Japanese The only thing I can understand at all is dogs and cats and saying what their names are or whether or not I own them.
Speaker 0: There were no dogs, but someone was something at some point.
Speaker 0: Okay, and someone said someone's name.
Speaker 1: I Watched three things at Otacon.
Speaker 1: They were all live-action Asian movies.
Speaker 1: The first one is Lady Terminator, which I saw.
Speaker 1: 80% of Lady Terminator is a bad movie.
Speaker 0: She mates and then she terminates.
Speaker 1: that is the tagline.
Speaker 1: basically, you have like this 80s chick just kind of walking around shooting people and occasionally she'll trick some guy into having sex with her and Basically the guy just gets like this blood bukkake face and dies Blood bukkake.
Speaker 1: I think there was some sort of snake in her snatch that bit the guys and caused the blood bukkake to happen.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure but the movie is basically some Detective guys cobs running around trying to fight this 80s terminator.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever It was pretty lame But right after it we I watched art of the devil - and you don't need to see art of the devil one.
Speaker 1: to see art of the devil - Because art of the devil - was just sort of like this horror gross-out movie and you know what?
Speaker 1: Compared to things like ichi the killer it was
Speaker 3: tame
Speaker 1: but compared to 99% of movies out there this had some pretty gory scenes the best among which was when one guy had Propane torch put to him while he was sedated with muscle relaxants and all of his flesh was basically completely burned off especially on his legs.
Speaker 1: and then the lady took a washcloth and basically Wiped the flesh off his leg and you saw a bone and everything.
Speaker 0: At this point, I think I was wandering around with Adam somewhat intoxicated interviewing people at the rave.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and That's a good movie to go see if you're liking the ultra violence in the gore.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, the horror wasn't too.
Speaker 0: That was really the best tasteless movie this year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not really gonna summarize the plot of it because the plot is just kind of whatever but yeah There were some gory scenes that were pleasant for if you like gore.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the last movie I saw was sex inferior.
Speaker 1: I didn't see the whole thing base.
Speaker 1: I waited a while to see it because I had high expectations.
Speaker 0: now Meanwhile, they had been pushed back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this time was the day changed the time on it.
Speaker 0: So a good half of the crew was waiting for this movie and I showed up and once again I was somewhat intoxicated because it was late at night.
Speaker 0: And yeah, so they're all waiting to watch this movie and I come over and I decide that it is not worth it.
Speaker 0: So I went back to the room to record what ended up being the webcomics roundtable instead.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm sex inferior.
Speaker 1: I watched about maybe a half hour of it and Basically what it was.
Speaker 1: It was sort of an old movie, which I thought it was a newer movie.
Speaker 1: I guess I was wrong and It started out with the woman and I don't remember anything until the major scene of the movie was basically this woman is completely naked and She has a sword and in slow motion She chops up a bunch of dudes Kill Bill volume 1 style But not as many dudes as Kill Bill volume 1 88 and her.
Speaker 0: yeah, so she only got what like 86 85 More like 15.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there was blood and bouncing boobs everywhere and then the movie basically consisted of Some consensual sex some Non-consensual sex.
Speaker 0: what's the deal with consensual sex in an ultraviolet movie?
Speaker 1: and then lots of chopping people up in blood and a really lame Political Yakuza plot?
Speaker 1: that was yeah.
Speaker 0: see the thing is whatever.
Speaker 0: I hung out most of that night in the room with cool people recording a whole bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: and Now right before this Scott specifically had chided me when I said I wasn't going to watch this movie.
Speaker 1: You didn't see any of the movies.
Speaker 1: you had to go see at least one ultraviolet.
Speaker 0: I saw belladonna.
Speaker 1: that wasn't ultraviolet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: Honestly, the tradition isn't going so well because there haven't been so many Worthwhile violent movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Hey Otakon listen up.
Speaker 1: You got to find the most violent and horrible movies You can and put them on Saturday night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what it's a it's your duty.
Speaker 0: You realize if they follow the progression of trying to beat every year, they'll end up with snuff films.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: and then what there's nothing worse there's nothing more than that.
Speaker 1: They'll get a time machine and like videotape the Holocaust and bring the tapes back to us.
Speaker 0: That's really just a high production value snuff film.
Speaker 0: I guess yeah Yeah, but I so all right, he yells at me why are you gonna not see this movie?
Speaker 1: this movie's gonna be awesome Ah, but the problem I think is that the descriptions in the Otakon con book They conflicted slightly with IMDB and that they were much more positive.
Speaker 1: and now I see that Everything in the Otakon con book is described in a positive light.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so then I'm waiting in the room.
Speaker 0: You know we're recording this we're finishing up this or this one roundtable and we're about to start another one.
Speaker 0: when the anime world order people are gonna arrive and Scott and everyone return and the words out of everyone's mouths are basically wow.
Speaker 0: That was a waste of time.
Speaker 0: Goddamn, I could have been asleep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, well I seem to recall last year when I walked out of whatever the hell that violent movie was.
Speaker 1: Oh It was something else is something else.
Speaker 0: part two and I remember that as I walked out you said to me Where are you going rim?
Speaker 0: You're breaking the tradition.
Speaker 0: and then when you arrived at the room several hours later, your words were wow.
Speaker 0: That was a waste of my life.
Speaker 1: Hey, you know what?
Speaker 1: It's my tradition that every year I'm gonna have three days or four days of awesomeness.
Speaker 1: I got a waste two of those hours at least doing something.
Speaker 0: All right Otakon if you want to mess with Scott of geek nights All you have to do is show the worst crap you can find at midnight on Saturday and he'll be there.
Speaker 1: I will be.
Speaker 0: just show like I don't even know like some.
Speaker 1: how else am I supposed to become an expert on this topic?
Speaker 0: If I don't sit through at least some of this shit good God, okay Peter what do you have to say to everyone out there about Otakon?
Speaker 0: Now at this point we had actually recorded another good hours worth of content.
Speaker 0: Well, actually a good 45 minutes and We realized that there's no way we can cover all of Otakon 2006 in only one episode.
Speaker 0: so rather than have a really lopsided distribution, we've cut it off now and Next Wednesday on anime day.
Speaker 0: We will continue with the remainder of our coverage which will include Among other things a long long discussion about panels that Otakon and our feelings on them the concert the rave our hotel room and the crazy parties we had the roundtables and interviews we had the assassination attempt that was undertaken by anime world order against geek nights one fateful night.
Speaker 0: and finally the geek fable of our Sunday Which I don't really want to get into other than the fact that We have discovered that when both Scott and I lose our voices social order around us breaks down Quickly, so of course once again, you can listen to our panel that we recorded live at Otakon on Monday.
Speaker 0: This previous Monday this previous Tuesday yesterday you could have heard all about video games at Otakon.
Speaker 0: today is the first half of our coverage of Otakon and Tomorrow a very important episode.
Speaker 0: we're going to talk about some interesting things that we did in Wildwood, New Jersey When we were bored and we realized that we like hacking computers.
Speaker 0: So why not try to hack the boardwalk?
Speaker 0: and that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 3: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 3: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 3: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 3: It's actually recorded at night.