Speaker 0: It's Thursday October 26 that this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight with our brand new and mostly configured Compressor we bring you our pre Halloween Halloween special.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Great googly moogly.
Speaker 0: We got a compressor and rim.
Speaker 1: We talked about it already and rim forgot to hit record.
Speaker 0: I was so excited about the new compressor that I just totally didn't hit record on the computer.
Speaker 1: So let's talk about it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, god damn is it fancy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we had our old compressor and it was like 70 bucks including You know shipping attacks and all that and we couldn't actually get the power cable for it from the company.
Speaker 0: They're on backorder.
Speaker 0: So instead of you know, not having a compressor for another couple weeks We just upgraded and bought a real real fancy compressor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's actually two compressors in one in each of them is fancier than the single compressor We used to have.
Speaker 1: by that we still have but can't power.
Speaker 0: Yes, though soon.
Speaker 0: We'll be able to power that one and I'm going to set up an awesome three compressor setup.
Speaker 0: That's gonna kick the dog dick of a new bits his ass.
Speaker 1: We're gonna have to go out and get like seven compressors.
Speaker 1: I'll be like, yeah the more compressors we have the better.
Speaker 0: a frickin be a wolf cluster Eventually of compressors will compress the audio to the point that all geek nights will be is Hi guess so Yeah, I got to say though I mean our old compressor had some lights on it and they would move around a bit.
Speaker 0: But there are some goddamn lights on this compressor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm really liking the lights.
Speaker 1: It's giving me something to look at while we do the podcast instead of rims.
Speaker 0: ugly ass My ass is quite covered at the moment.
Speaker 1: Well your ugly ass face.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I face away from you.
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: That's exactly why I'm looking at the damn lights.
Speaker 0: Yeah So anyway in the news I would have saved this for you know a video game day.
Speaker 0: But it's kind of urgent because if Walmart doesn't fix its mistake tonight or tomorrow.
Speaker 0: You might be able to take advantage of this.
Speaker 0: Walmart made a mistake.
Speaker 0: They are currently selling Guitar Hero 2 for $79.92.
Speaker 1: Well right now there's a picture of one Walmart selling Guitar Hero 2 and you can see clearly There's a bunch of Guitar Hero 2's on the shelf.
Speaker 0: Well, there are reports in forums that other Walmart's are doing the same thing.
Speaker 0: It may not be all Walmart's We don't know exactly what the story is But if you live near Walmart and you want Guitar Heroes 2 As much as I hate everything that is Walmart go see if you can pick it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, normally I would not encourage shopping at Walmart under any circumstances But this gets close to the line at which shopping at Walmart is okay.
Speaker 1: I mean they got a game out, but how?
Speaker 1: when's Guitar Hero 2 supposed to come out?
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: it's supposed to come out a while from now.
Speaker 1: It's not like a few days early.
Speaker 1: We're talking a lot of days early, and you know Walmart does have a reason to come out two weeks from now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, two weeks early.
Speaker 1: God damn if some imagine if Walmart was selling Wii's.
Speaker 1: I mean it's one for Twilight Princess Gamecube two weeks early.
Speaker 0: I mean imagine you know someone comes over to your house, and they're like man.
Speaker 0: I can't wait to get Guitar Heroes next week, and you're like man.
Speaker 0: I unlocked the whole game three days ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you have a ps2 Man, it might be worth it to go to your Walmart and see if they got the game on the shelf.
Speaker 0: I'll probably have some sort of follow-up on Tuesday once we find out exactly what the deal was.
Speaker 1: of course We don't have a ps2 and if we did well, we probably would have bought Guitar Hero 2.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, you know it's kind of like.
Speaker 1: probably would have bought Guitar Hero 1.
Speaker 1: Yeah, here's the thing I don't get.
Speaker 1: Guitar Hero comes in a box with a guitar, right?
Speaker 1: What if you bought Guitar Hero 1 and you already have two guitars?
Speaker 1: Can you buy Guitar Hero 2 sans guitar?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure you can but I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know you can buy.
Speaker 0: Donkey Kong is with or without the Kongas.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That is true That is true, and the people who made Guitar Hero are not stupid.
Speaker 1: We should try to get Donkey Konga.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's not worth it that the Wii's coming.
Speaker 0: I imagine there will be similar better games for the Wii.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think Donkey Konga is just something we'll have to pass over.
Speaker 1: We'll get some drumming games or use the wiimotes as drumsticks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I was gonna save this news for Monday just like rim was gonna save his for Tuesday, but Ubuntu edgy F came out today.
Speaker 1: ish and Let me tell you this is not like.
Speaker 1: it's an official Ubuntu release Number six dot ten because it's October 2006.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh But it is not, you know the recommended default Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: you should use Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: dapper Drake still has the three year support agreement or whatever how many years they decided.
Speaker 1: so if you have a system that is important, like I don't know the server that runs your Website or your company's mail server You're gonna want to use dapper Drake because well, it's guaranteed and supported and all that good stuff.
Speaker 1: But edgy effed if you are using a desktop computer for Linux or if you're gonna try out Linux to see if you like it edgy effed is Like.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I was didn't think it would improve on dapper that much.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: Is it 10,000 times better than dapper Drake?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, let me put this in perspective.
Speaker 0: I didn't even pay attention to the fact that a new Ubuntu was gonna be coming out anytime soon Because dapper Drake was pretty good.
Speaker 0: I was very happy with it And I just didn't expect that the line of desktop Linux would have been crossed with such a little fanfare.
Speaker 0: This Linux this Ubuntu Ubuntu is pretty much above the line as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 1: I would give this to my parents without a second thought The only that like let me count the ways in which it improves upon dapper Drake.
Speaker 0: I got the big one that I want to say right now because it's gonna jump out of me.
Speaker 0: All right sound works like it does in Windows.
Speaker 0: It just doesn't work like it does in that It just freaking works and it sees all your sound card.
Speaker 1: It works like a million times better than it did before.
Speaker 1: There was a problem in Linux in which if you had more than one sound card or if you had Sound cards with multiple devices like for example my sound card it has analog holes Which normal speaker holes.
Speaker 1: it also has an optical hole, you know for the fancy surround sound optical cables the digital TOS link whatever and That's a separate device.
Speaker 1: That's device 0 comma 2 whereas the normal sound card is device 0 comma 1 or 0 comma 0.
Speaker 1: Ubuntu Edgy F just detected it automatically and works and it also has a new dialog box that allows me to manually choose That particular hole.
Speaker 0: now while Scott's right and that it's not exactly like Windows I guess my point is that for most of you out there at least 90% of you It's functionally just like Windows because you won't have to do anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah There are.
Speaker 1: there was a huge problem and people having to jump through hoops to get their sound cards to work.
Speaker 1: That is gone.
Speaker 1: Also people who want to use that crazy AI GLX fancy 3d shit.
Speaker 1: It's now 10,000 times easier.
Speaker 1: All the software that you probably want to use like Banshee, which is almost equivalent to iTunes It's basically 90% exactly the same as iTunes new cache the thing that's basically like quicken.
Speaker 1: all that that software has been Updated to the newest versions.
Speaker 1: dapper Drake didn't have that stuff updated to the newest versions so you were stuck using version like 10 when version 11 is out and a version 11 is 10,000 times better than version 10. and not only that but Ubuntu comes.
Speaker 1: Edgy F comes with the real version of Firefox 2 with the right icon And it's the real deal.
Speaker 0: take that ice weasel.
Speaker 1: It is the real Firefox 2 from Mozilla Unmodified beat.
Speaker 1: that beat that I didn't have to do shit.
Speaker 1: It was just there today today.
Speaker 0: Oh, no Yeah, we got it.
Speaker 0: Scott's got a thing of the day that's coming up for Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I could say a lot more awesome things about why edgy EFT is a thousand times better than dapper Drake But I'll tell you a few of the bad things just just to round it out.
Speaker 1: It's still.
Speaker 1: if you want to have dual monitors, you still have to jump through a few hoops.
Speaker 1: It's not super simple.
Speaker 0: Yeah as opposed to Windows.
Speaker 0: We're honestly it just works without any effort.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though you can't do everything you want to do, but it works.
Speaker 1: It's a good thing.
Speaker 1: I know how to set up dual monitors And yeah, but other people don't know.
Speaker 1: so it might be a little tricky.
Speaker 1: They have to edit a text file.
Speaker 1: Oh, I had to add like a few lines to a text file.
Speaker 0: God kind of Superman.
Speaker 0: Do you think we are?
Speaker 1: Gnome screensaver is still the default screensavers.
Speaker 1: You have to uninstall it and install X screensaver to get a real screensaver program going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's easy to do.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's not difficult in the least.
Speaker 1: and What was the other problem I had?
Speaker 0: were there any other problems?
Speaker 1: there was?
Speaker 1: it was just so minor.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I don't really remember it right now.
Speaker 0: If you don't like brown.
Speaker 0: It's still kind of brown.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's still kind of ugly.
Speaker 1: You have to go to gnome look org and get a new theme that you easily install.
Speaker 1: You know it.
Speaker 1: it's pretty much dapper Drake with a lot of problems fixed.
Speaker 1: a lot of problems fixed.
Speaker 1: If you oh right wireless cards are still hit or miss.
Speaker 0: of course That's not the fault of anything other than the wireless card manufacturers.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but if you have a wireless card that just works it just works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, luckily not as many people put Linux on their laptops as the desktop.
Speaker 1: actually you'd be surprised that all the questions I get are people trying to put Linux on laptops.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz that's what's hard.
Speaker 1: a lot of people don't bother well And also a lot of people get the old laptops for cheap And they try to put Linux on it.
Speaker 1: cuz you can't put Windows on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can know all the old laptops come with a spyware infected version of Windows 2000. great Possibly a spyware infected version of Windows 95 a. oh yeah You realize I had Windows 95 a. I ran to the point that when B came out I did not update.
Speaker 1: see I went from Windows 3.1 to 95 B. Wow Because I had USBs.
Speaker 0: See I didn't.
Speaker 1: yeah a lot of people don't know this.
Speaker 1: Windows 95 a couldn't use USB ports.
Speaker 0: Windows 95 B Could kinda use USB or kind of being the operative word.
Speaker 1: that wasn't until Windows 2000 that USB worked for real.
Speaker 0: It was kind of scary things of the day Man, it felt real good to say that loud again to not have to worry about clipping or anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a. it's a good feeling to just be able to say what you want to say how you want to say it with No worries.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah And imagine trying to have free speech when you can't say you know or else it'll get screwed up.
Speaker 0: You know yeah Michael.
Speaker 0: You know yeah, all right, so stay the course All right, I think in my course.
Speaker 0: I think I'm geek nights.
Speaker 0: We really need to sort of to the left.
Speaker 0: Oh, no see we got to stay the course.
Speaker 0: my strategy all along has been to stay the course All right.
Speaker 0: actually no my strategy was never to stay the course.
Speaker 1: Well, what was it all right now?
Speaker 0: We don't always get that political other than when we you know yell about politics.
Speaker 0: Oh, but I'm not.
Speaker 0: this isn't a thing of the day for a political reason Regardless of any of our listeners or our feelings about it.
Speaker 0: my thing of the day is this ad put out by the Democratic National Committee.
Speaker 0: now it shows video actual video of our dear leader President Bush saying that in Iraq We have to stay the course and it shows him saying it dozens of times over the course of years in different situations And interviews.
Speaker 0: all right then When it shows a very recent one where he says very clearly my strategy was never to stay the course.
Speaker 1: Maybe he was lying before.
Speaker 0: well the thing is oh the.
Speaker 0: a lot of times in recent memory a lot of the Republican and I don't really want to use right and left because that doesn't really fit.
Speaker 0: But the Republican current non normal conservative neoconservative Republican rhetoric has typically been to accuse people on the other side of being liars all the time or equating them with the enemy or whatever, but historically Democrats and Not left-wingers, but you know what I mean tend to be Tend to not fight back so strongly.
Speaker 0: it's rare to see someone who isn't on the neoconservative side attack someone and I was very surprised to see this ad put out by the Democratic National Committee That pretty much in video straight up calls out a Republican for lying.
Speaker 1: It kind of reminds me of how an eagle they hire the guy who's usually the campaign guy for the Republicans To work on his campaign.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so uses the Republican getting elected strategy in the Democratic campaign.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess if nothing else I really want to see a lot more Both sides of our government actually taking the other side to task when they do something wrong Or they say something bad or they lie.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean it's one thing.
Speaker 1: when we had like the negative campaign ads and everyone was like all these negative campaign ads suck You want the positive ones?
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, that's true that.
Speaker 1: but the problem was is the negative campaign ads of the past were all So and so didn't blah so and so blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: It's just like name-calling.
Speaker 1: It's like he's a doodoo head.
Speaker 1: vote for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other guy sucks vote for me.
Speaker 1: This is let's show in video, you know Demonstrating someone else lying because you could do this for any politician in all of Washington.
Speaker 1: You can make a video just like this.
Speaker 1: So I want to see all those videos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe it'll get people riled up because you really can't argue with it.
Speaker 1: It's like there.
Speaker 1: he is there.
Speaker 1: he lied.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: It's like when I watched What was that movie?
Speaker 1: outfoxed.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, like I don't watch TV.
Speaker 1: So I didn't realize Fox News was that biased.
Speaker 1: like people said shit all the time I didn't pay attention because I didn't watch news on TV.
Speaker 1: I still don't.
Speaker 1: but I watched and there was that guy and they showed him saying shut up.
Speaker 1: Shut up You know, they showed him saying I didn't tell I never tell anyone to shut up and then they showed for like five minutes.
Speaker 1: All he did was say shut up.
Speaker 1: Shut up.
Speaker 1: shot as he told guests on his show to shut up And I was just laughing hysterically and I was like, oh Okay Now this isn't a partisan issue any politician.
Speaker 0: I want to see this happen, too.
Speaker 0: In fact, were I in some crazy alternate bizarro world to run for president of the United States?
Speaker 0: Or if someone awesome were to run?
Speaker 0: I would love to see someone Pledge that if they were elected any time they spoke to the American people at a press conference or publicly They would first have themselves put under oath by a judge.
Speaker 1: That's what I would do.
Speaker 0: I mean imagine that I would love to see anyone have the pure testicular fortitude to do that.
Speaker 1: I Would definitely do it right away because as soon as you do that, you know you stick to it and you you got huge balls.
Speaker 1: But then with the real long-lasting effect is let's say the president does it and the guy's president.
Speaker 1: for eight years He's not president anymore then someone else's president and they don't do it.
Speaker 1: They don't swear under oath every time they speak in public.
Speaker 1: aren't people gonna say, huh?
Speaker 1: How come you didn't do do it?
Speaker 1: The last guy did he didn't lie to us.
Speaker 1: now You can't lie to us either and the guy's like, oh shit It forces every president to have giant nuts.
Speaker 1: If just one president has giant nuts.
Speaker 1: or you know, if a congressman does it then you know Everyone will start expecting other people to do it also or governor or anyone.
Speaker 0: It has another interesting effect in that.
Speaker 0: now I mean currently it's not illegal to lie in this country unless you're like on court or unless you're Slandering or libel anger.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah all that.
Speaker 0: but in general, I mean if I asked Scott Scott How are you doing today?
Speaker 0: And Scott says purple monkey dishwasher.
Speaker 1: That's not lying.
Speaker 1: That's just dodging the question Yeah, which is lying would be saying great when I was feeling like shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but people do that all the time.
Speaker 0: It's not against the law.
Speaker 1: No perfectly legal.
Speaker 0: The president should be perfectly legal can lie to the people.
Speaker 0: There's no no legal reason.
Speaker 0: He can't say whatever he wants other than a few specific exceptions to the people
Speaker 1: and in some cases He probably should lie, you know I mean Let's say someone asked him a question and it would look really bad if he didn't answer the question at all and just dodged it.
Speaker 1: But saying the true answer could be dangerous Like like.
Speaker 0: is it true that we have a spy named John Smith in North Korea ready to assassinate Kim Jong-il and he's like?
Speaker 0: No, it's not true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean he can't say no comment because then people go Unless.
Speaker 0: now there's the whole no comment thing.
Speaker 0: There are government's policies to always say no comment about anything like that.
Speaker 0: That way it's not if they say no comment all the time that them saying no comment doesn't mean anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know but you get the idea.
Speaker 1: there are occasions we're saying no account you.
Speaker 1: it's better just say no.
Speaker 0: But now I mean Congress can't easily Impeach a president just for lying at a press conference the way it's currently set up.
Speaker 0: He has to do something illegal essentially.
Speaker 1: But if he swears to not lie with under oath with a judge Then if he lies during the press conference after being under oath, well, then that's a perjury.
Speaker 0: I mean, I I swear I did not have sex with that woman Monica Lewinsky And you know, normally I used.
Speaker 1: I would think I'm not a hundred percent sure on what the the law is for perjury And while I would think that you know, it only counts if you're testifying in a court.
Speaker 1: It counts when the president's you know, swearing to uphold the Constitution is inauguration.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so why wouldn't it count if he did it any time?
Speaker 0: Well, the the simple truth is that in reality Congress can impeach a president for any goddamn reason.
Speaker 0: They feel like yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean remember when.
Speaker 0: well not remember cuz we weren't around when Johnson was impeached back in reconstruction days.
Speaker 0: Yep, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right, whatever.
Speaker 0: You've got a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Do you not?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So seeing as Halloween's coming real quick.
Speaker 1: It's coming Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I got a little Halloween thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: I don't think this is a real commercial.
Speaker 1: He could mainly cuz the guy says fuck a lot, but it could be real I guess super late night TV cable TV somewhere.
Speaker 1: This is an ad for I assume a not real Clothing store.
Speaker 1: well costume store.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's a girl's costume warehouse.
Speaker 1: It is is real Scuzzy, New York salesman kind of guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah sexy nesses And he's like we got every kind of girl's costume.
Speaker 1: we got sexy nurse sexy nun Sexy cat, you know sexy every sexy devil.
Speaker 0: You can't wear sexy costumes.
Speaker 1: You can't wear ten sexy costumes and the guys like it's so hilarious cuz the guys like Come on down here.
Speaker 1: I got some fucking costumes to sell.
Speaker 0: I got a big fucking sale going on here.
Speaker 0: Come on Come on Come on.
Speaker 1: It's pretty funny commercial.
Speaker 1: Thank you College Humor for yet again being a great selector of internet humorous videos.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean College Humor.
Speaker 0: we perused it fairly often in college But it was only when we were really bored and we wanted low resolution videos of people getting hit in the balls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there wasn't much to it.
Speaker 1: nowadays It seems to be that it's not a YouTube or a Google video, but what it is, it's sort of a really awesome They picking really good ones really often, you know, they had what other good ones did.
Speaker 1: they have recently the Street Fighter thing.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: The Street Fighter with that's the one Don't see.
Speaker 0: Okay So it's considering that Halloween falls on a gaming day and it's also the beginning of season two We figure today Thursday the Thursday before the holiday Halloween weekend that we would talk about.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, now sadly I actually haven't really had a chance to celebrate Halloween much since I left high school.
Speaker 1: I haven't had a chance to celebrate much since I got into high school.
Speaker 0: I mean at RIT.
Speaker 0: We never celebrated it.
Speaker 0: We just kind of some people who wear costumes.
Speaker 0: We had the big cosplay at the anime club, which I could I have some stories from.
Speaker 1: yeah I think actually I heard somewhere recently the Halloween is the fastest growing holiday yet at the same time It's the fastest dying holiday.
Speaker 0: from what I've seen fewer kids trick-or-treat now than ever.
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I think it really depends on the area that you're in and the time of day and the type of people You know, I mean it seems like the suburban Protect your kid.
Speaker 1: Crazies are not letting their kids go out because they're really afraid and they'll drive their kids around in their cars during the day.
Speaker 1: But in areas where people are all cool, and they're not you know afraid of the outside world You know The kids are go super like the kids that do trick-or-treat are doing a badass job of it like they'll go to an apartment complex and do the whole thing just Every single place to get a zillion candies.
Speaker 0: Well, actually when I grew up in Detroit, I mean when we lived in Detroit straight up You couldn't go trick-or-treating around the neighborhood.
Speaker 0: So it was kind of funny and sad at the same time, but all the more Not really affluent, but all the people who were afraid of the neighborhood would leave and
Speaker 1: on Halloween
Speaker 0: They'd go to Lakeside Mall in the suburbs and they set up a Halloween there where all the stores had candy And they all the kids would come and trick-or-treat at the mall instead of walking around downtown Detroit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, our mall always had All kinds of trick-or-treating going on But I only think we only did that once most of the time.
Speaker 1: we just walked around to the same houses that we always went To and got the same candy.
Speaker 1: We always get.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean I used to dress up when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: pretty much once I hit high school I stopped dressing up entirely and I'd still go out on Halloween.
Speaker 0: even when I was a senior in high school I still went out on Halloween.
Speaker 0: We didn't go trick-or-treating or anything.
Speaker 0: We just wandered around the neighborhood or out in the woods in a small posse of punk kid Causing all sorts of punk kid trouble.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seemed to.
Speaker 1: it looks like what's happening to me or To me, it looks like what's happened.
Speaker 1: I don't know how to say this at all.
Speaker 0: All right, where's mr.
Speaker 0: Period when you really needed?
Speaker 1: Yeah, seriously, mr.
Speaker 0: Shoots and leaves.
Speaker 1: lingual Isn't dead lingual is dead.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 1: Yeah Great.
Speaker 1: so it seems like what's happening to Halloween is that there's a lot less kids trick-or-treating actually going on But there's a lot more 20 30 year olds going out and having parties and getting costumes like they're selling a lot more costumes to Adults and college people now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're having parties and there's a lot less kids trick-or-treating going on Even though that still does happen a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got to say the last time I actually dressed up for Halloween was I believe it might have actually been my senior year High school, but I want him in my junior year.
Speaker 0: I don't remember but I dressed up as dr.
Speaker 0: Jekyll.
Speaker 0: I wasn't actually gonna dress up, but I decided at the last second because I was nominally going to a party with someone I knew I should probably dress up.
Speaker 0: So I took you know my suit and keep saying, you know, see what you did to me.
Speaker 0: No, no and some black pants.
Speaker 0: You can't say 10, you know I put on a fancy three-piece suit and then I put a black cape on over it.
Speaker 0: cuz I had a nice cape and I Borrowed one of my mom's walking like nice fancy silver-headed walking canes and I just said I was dr Jekyll and everyone thought it was a really good costume.
Speaker 1: Okay Yeah, I think I must have dressed up at some of those anime club things in college for the Halloween costume contest.
Speaker 0: I don't remember you ever actually dressing up.
Speaker 1: I think I did a couple times.
Speaker 0: You dressed up as a katani when we were freshmen.
Speaker 1: that was a good plan to katani costume.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that worked well.
Speaker 1: But I think I don't know if I did.
Speaker 1: it wasn't like I went trick-or-treating or anything.
Speaker 0: I thought I think we do more cosplaying than we do Halloween.
Speaker 1: I think it's not a really remember and it most of my costumes from when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I think once I you know what I had a lot in elementary school I would have those costumes where you would just buy at the store in a little box and it came with a plastic mask Of the rubber band that would go around your head and then like a big plastic thing.
Speaker 1: You would just pull over your body.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Jerry Seinfeld is a whole thing in his stand-up about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had.
Speaker 1: let's see which ones that I have.
Speaker 1: I still have some of these.
Speaker 1: I was Voltron once.
Speaker 1: that was the best one.
Speaker 1: Wow I was Voltron with big plastic Voltron mask and a Voltron suit.
Speaker 1: See when I was I was a centurion.
Speaker 1: once.
Speaker 0: I think we both had the exact same centurion cost.
Speaker 1: I think I still have that centurion costume.
Speaker 0: I have it somewhere.
Speaker 0: Wait, you had the other one with the red missile.
Speaker 1: No, I was the yellow guy with the green.
Speaker 0: I was the blue guy with the red missile.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the missile was just this Phallic looking piece of plastic that stuck on the arm and to shoot it You pulled it off the arm and you threw it at your little brother.
Speaker 1: I think one year I was a Robin Hood or something or a merry man or a forest, dude.
Speaker 0: Actually, you know what?
Speaker 1: It's like my leg.
Speaker 0: I suddenly remembered the full chronology of all my costumes.
Speaker 0: All right, shoot out of the blue the first costume I can remember.
Speaker 0: my parents dressed me up as raggedy Andy Oh pun when I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I think they still have the costume.
Speaker 0: and then my mom actually made my brother and I we wanted to be Ghostbusters.
Speaker 0: instead of buying.
Speaker 1: I was just gonna say I can't remember if I actually did a Ghostbusters costume or just everyone else in the world did one and not me.
Speaker 0: now all my friends also dressed up as Ghostbusters.
Speaker 1: It was like some one year where Ghostbuster was the costume to be.
Speaker 1: here's the thing.
Speaker 1: everyone in the world had a proton pack.
Speaker 0: Everyone I knew who was a Ghostbuster just bought a plastic proton pack and bought the car.
Speaker 1: No I think if I did do a Ghostbusters costume because I don't remember if I did one or not I did I still have the plastic proton bag So I think I would have used it.
Speaker 1: but everyone else I knew was making proton packs like everyone had different proton packs of varying shapes and sizes and duct tape and cardboard and God-knows-what.
Speaker 0: I think it's the areas we lived because where I was everyone bought it except my mom was awesome And she made my brother and I perfectly accurate to the movie Ghostbusters costumes right down to the name tags and a uniform and the proton pack was badass.
Speaker 1: Say if we had Skype right now I would call my mom because she probably remembers every single Halloween costume I ever wore and she could just tell us.
Speaker 0: Yeah So then I dressed up after that as an army man With a little 45 and Everyone else was also dressed up as an army man.
Speaker 1: Oh, I remember my last Halloween costume as I went to the to the store and I got one of those rubber masks.
Speaker 1: you know that covers your whole head and has hair on it.
Speaker 1: and I bought the Sickest ugliest one I could find like it was.
Speaker 1: so it was like it's scared with my little sister.
Speaker 1: She was like don't put it on.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and I wore that for like all around town and people would be like you.
Speaker 1: I Just bought the scariest mask at the store.
Speaker 0: So after the army man, I wanted now this dates me in terms of my anime fandom.
Speaker 0: This was I think this was fourth grade.
Speaker 0: I wanted to be vampire hunter D Oh.
Speaker 0: and my mom tried to convince me that no one would know what the hell I was and I shouldn't bother.
Speaker 0: And then I thought oh I'll just make the costume on my own.
Speaker 0: and I don't know what my little kid brain was thinking because I assumed that I would look exactly Like D when I when I made a costume, you know, it's really weird though and all my years as a kid You know kids who dress up as Ninja Turtles.
Speaker 1: They dress up is you know?
Speaker 1: Transformers and okay.
Speaker 1: No one.
Speaker 1: I don't remember a single kid ever dressing up as Mario ever Do you?
Speaker 1: I think I remember Sonic the Hedgehog's?
Speaker 0: Actually, I remember two different kids who dressed up as link and my little brother one.
Speaker 1: There were links.
Speaker 1: there were links.
Speaker 1: there were no Mario's.
Speaker 1: do you remember a Mario ever?
Speaker 1: Like I hadn't seen no one did a Mario costume until recently when it was all cool with the cosplay action at the conventions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the cosplay action that Daryl Surratt is trying to Undermine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're really.
Speaker 1: it's kind of weird because now that I think about it.
Speaker 1: It's like wow, I should have been Mario.
Speaker 1: How could I not have been Mario?
Speaker 0: see it's weird because we didn't see our video game culture as special when we were kids.
Speaker 0: It wasn't nostalgic.
Speaker 0: It wasn't awesome.
Speaker 0: It wasn't even cool.
Speaker 0: It was just the way you were.
Speaker 0: Everyone was that way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Voltron wasn't special either, but I dressed up as him.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it was.
Speaker 0: I think maybe it was because there weren't Mario costumes.
Speaker 0: No one thought of it.
Speaker 1: I don't know man.
Speaker 1: I don't know cuz Mario all dressed up as Ghostbusters and those weren't nostalgic.
Speaker 1: They're brand new.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's because video games were just so ingrained and so part of our daily ritualized lives.
Speaker 1: I don't know there.
Speaker 1: I feel like there should have been a Mario costume back though Since I didn't dress up as vampire hunter D.
Speaker 0: What do you think?
Speaker 0: I dressed up as you'll never guess vampire hunter D's hand.
Speaker 0: No, oh god.
Speaker 0: I wish I was that clever.
Speaker 0: No, actually my brother and I dressed up as Arabs Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Now the reason that might sound odd.
Speaker 0: my grandparents traveled extensively.
Speaker 0: I mean they spent a long time in Australia.
Speaker 0: They very seriously considered emigrating there.
Speaker 0: They spent a lot of time in the Middle East in Egypt.
Speaker 0: And while they were there they bought full silken wondrous garments and they brought my size my little brother's size and they brought them back and We wore them that Halloween because they were authentic clothing silk and awesome.
Speaker 0: They were the most comfortable things I've ever worn.
Speaker 1: we should dress up as Arabs and just walk around town on Halloween.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I don't want to spend Halloween in Gitmo.
Speaker 1: I know seriously.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's fucked up Seriously fucked up, you know, seriously, you know, it's seriously fucked up, you know Serious, you know, yeah.
Speaker 1: It seems now though that any time a costume comes up It's always a video game or an anime like or possibly an underwear pervert, but it's all video game anime costumes.
Speaker 1: now What's up?
Speaker 0: I have not dressed up in a non video game anime costume since I got out of high school With the possible exception of the lamest costume I ever wore Which is well when I went to the st.
Speaker 0: Mark's holiday or Halloween parade with Emily a while ago I didn't really have a costume.
Speaker 0: So I nominally dressed up as a pirate by wearing a pirate van.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I guess pirate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not pirate is also included.
Speaker 0: and ninja I wore black blue black jeans a Pirate bandana with the skull and bones on it and a shirt with a skull and bones on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty much pirate.
Speaker 1: ninja.
Speaker 1: anime video games occasionally comic books and that covers 99% of costumes besides the generic skeleton.
Speaker 1: sexy which sexy devil sexy Ness sexy nun.
Speaker 0: Yeah Though in terms of I mean one fun story about me and dressing up as things is that at the RIT anime club We had a tradition of having the Halloween costume contest Which was basically a mini cosplay totally off-the-cuff voted on by the people in the crowd.
Speaker 0: not terribly official or anything But it was always great fun.
Speaker 0: It was Halloween.
Speaker 1: So we had a showing.
Speaker 1: anyway, you know, whichever Thursday was closest to Halloween.
Speaker 1: We had a meeting where we showed an anime that was usually Halloween related.
Speaker 1: take the x-train Yeah, so all we did was we said hey on the Thursday closest to Halloween wear a costume to club and we had all the people in costume line up.
Speaker 1: they all you know took a step forward one at a time and Then everyone voted on which costume was the best and someone won a prize.
Speaker 0: now freshman year I didn't dress up as all at all because I had no reason to.
Speaker 0: I didn't need to whatever.
Speaker 0: After that, I was on the executive board of the club So I had to dress up.
Speaker 0: the thing is I didn't have any time I didn't have any skill and I didn't have any money.
Speaker 0: Yep, so let's go through the three costumes that rim wore at the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: the Oh my god is the movie cast.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: No, that's the second one.
Speaker 0: Oh see here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I spent less than $2 on any given one of these costumes.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So first off sophomore year I was the facilities coordinator of the club.
Speaker 0: We were gonna dress up as what Star Ocean?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah It was Star Ocean and I was the dude.
Speaker 1: I wore rims trench coat and I bought a sweater and a white shirt at the Good Will a sweater vest and a white shirt at the good.
Speaker 0: Did you even know what character you're dressed up as?
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: It's the guy.
Speaker 1: it must be the only guy in Star Ocean with a trench coat a white shirt and a green Vest.
Speaker 1: he's some sort of doctor scientist guy or something.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, Scott Johnson dressed up as the kid the guy who has the two dragons coming out of his bag.
Speaker 0: So me and Greg Hartman.
Speaker 0: All right We were set up to be the dragons meaning we were just stand behind him.
Speaker 0: So because we both didn't have money weren't a goodwill?
Speaker 0: I bought a $1 red sport jacket and he bought a dollar fifty blue sport jacket.
Speaker 0: I then printed out the words were dragon in red and blue.
Speaker 0: We taped them to our chest and we stood behind him.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: That was my first costume.
Speaker 1: I remember that now that was great And it was.
Speaker 0: it was pretty infamous for how bad it was.
Speaker 0: So the next year around we're doing oh my goddess That's the whole eboards dressing up as oh my goddess.
Speaker 1: Well the movie specifically.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, so there's that big bad guy who wears like the white robes and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sell us soap.
Speaker 1: So you got a big white sheet and you wrapped it around yourself and I was a little bit more ghetto than that.
Speaker 1: No, no, and then you had that truck the square slash diamond of White felt with blue felt glued to it and you cut a hole in the middle and put it over your head.
Speaker 0: Well, see the thing is the.
Speaker 0: the sheet that I wrapped around myself was actually the curtain from the kitchen.
Speaker 0: Right, right I pulled the curtain.
Speaker 0: cuz remember I made the first costume a week in advance by buying that sport jacket the next year.
Speaker 1: I Got out of key made the costume the day of right before right before club.
Speaker 0: I got out of class and I had 45 minutes before I had to be at club setting everything up.
Speaker 0: I made that costume Including stopping at the store on the way home from class.
Speaker 0: in that time It was it was the most ghetto thing in the world.
Speaker 0: I even took a piece of felt in the shape of that thing on his forehead and glued it to my own form.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you glued up a blue diamond of felt to your forehead.
Speaker 0: I remember and here's the thing the costume actually looked pretty good from about 40 feet away.
Speaker 1: Yeah As long as you were far away and you couldn't see the stains on our curtains and you didn't realize that it was felt Glued together with Elmer's glue like from the back of the club.
Speaker 1: the thing looked great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, until you got up to me and you realize that hey that's just Peeling felt and you're wearing some white pants with a curtain wrapped around your waist.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's something I learned in high school from when they were building the the set for the school play.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Farrell who was in charge of that would always if you screwed up, he'd always say you can't see it from your house Because at a play no one's up close.
Speaker 1: They can't see stuff from far away.
Speaker 1: So if you as long as you put it together well enough the small details don't really matter.
Speaker 1: people aren't coming up to inspect it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except people.
Speaker 0: the problem was I couldn't walk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz it was tight and I can't walk in a tight dress in that little shuffling kind of gate I would have just fallen over.
Speaker 0: so I kind of stood still at the front of the room announcing people.
Speaker 0: awesome, of course, I remember also that Lisa and Kat were dressed up and Incredibly not terrible costumes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some people actually spent time on their cows.
Speaker 0: You mean everyone but us.
Speaker 1: Yeah They had awesome costumes and we didn't know.
Speaker 0: the club after seeing this costume and remembering my previous year's costume Realized that I was a cheapskate and rims.
Speaker 0: terrible costume became a tradition in the club.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: So the third year comes around and now I'm the president of the club I'm the top dog and the club is talking about what they think I'm gonna wear and how little money they think I'm gonna spend.
Speaker 0: So we decided to do Final Fantasy 8 Mmm.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy 8 great Just what we need more Final Fantasy costumes and giant swords.
Speaker 1: Isn't that the one with the sword with the gun in it?
Speaker 0: Yes, the one with the sword in the gun.
Speaker 1: Grumble grumble grumble.
Speaker 0: So we all pick things.
Speaker 0: that turned out that I happen to own a hat that looked exactly Like the hat that Irvine wore in the game and I had a brown trench coat, of course You never played the game.
Speaker 1: So you didn't know who Irvine was.
Speaker 1: someone else had printed out a picture of all the characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I saw this character who looked pretty much exactly like me.
Speaker 0: and because many people don't remember this Well, actually many people don't know this because they didn't know me in college but up until my senior year I had Australian Cowboy hat out of leather that I wore a lot.
Speaker 1: There's a funny story about that hat.
Speaker 1: freshman year.
Speaker 0: That's gonna have to be a geek fable for some day in the future.
Speaker 1: I think you just tell it right now.
Speaker 0: It's pretty short now because we've gone on long enough and that story can be told at length if need be Alright, plus I have other stories about that hat and how the Hat finally died.
Speaker 0: But I didn't actually get to wear the Hat with this costume because for various reasons the Hat no longer fit on my head.
Speaker 0: In fact, I didn't realize until I tried to put it on right before Club, haha.
Speaker 0: So I had spent about two dollars on the previous year's costume and this year I didn't have much money at all as in I had like eight bucks left and a repossessed car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my car was repossessed.
Speaker 0: I got it back a week later, but that should be a geek fable also.
Speaker 0: Yes, it should be.
Speaker 0: That was actually pretty hilarious.
Speaker 0: So The way I made this costume is I first off I put on some blue jeans and then I made Chaps out of felt and glued them to my blue jeans.
Speaker 0: Then I put on my trench coat.
Speaker 0: Well, I had my trench coat.
Speaker 0: I took some fake fur and I kind of taped it around my neck kind of like his trench coat was Wow, and then the the kicker.
Speaker 0: he wore this kind of blue shirt underneath kind of like von von Allen escoflone.
Speaker 0: I made the front half of a shirt out of felt complete with all the little leather things on it and I duct-taped it To my chest and put the trench coat on over it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Wait directly to your chest with your hair directly to my back where there's no hair.
Speaker 0: The shirt was on my chest.
Speaker 0: the duct tape went around my back and held it in place.
Speaker 0: Okay, and again from about 40 feet away the costume looked okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you got up to me, it looked pretty piss poor Especially when I revealed to the club that I was only wearing 50% of a shirt.
Speaker 1: Wow, I really I don't remember that so much.
Speaker 0: But yeah, well you weren't there in club space afterward when stories that I'm not gonna tell happened, but it was fun.
Speaker 1: Well, why wasn't I there?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Well part of it was you weren't allowed in club space when you when nothing was going on because you quit the you quit the EA ship.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I was still hanging out there sometimes.
Speaker 1: I wonder what was going on.
Speaker 0: I don't think we allowed you up there anymore.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: you didn't get to see.
Speaker 0: It was pretty there only like four of us up there at the time when I finally took the thing off and I think everyone In club, however heard the screams of agony as I ripped the duct tape off of my back.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah, I'm not good at dressing up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually I'm pretty good.
Speaker 0: now the matter is just money.
Speaker 0: now that I have money I can make awesome costumes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can too, but I need time which I don't have.
Speaker 1: Let's see any other funny Halloween stories.
Speaker 1: we got geek fables of Halloween.
Speaker 1: I can't really think of any right now.
Speaker 0: We've got funny stories, but they're all more related to anime or gaming than they are to actually Halloween.
Speaker 1: I remember one Halloween.
Speaker 1: I played puzzle pirates all day at my parents house while Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't even know what I'm gonna do this Halloween though this weekend.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be carving pumpkins.
Speaker 1: Yep, we haven't had a pumpkin to carve in years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, me either.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll carve something wicked awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if only we had someone to help us make that.
Speaker 1: I mean our friend Yuko made some badass pumpkins back in the day And well because she's an artist so she just draws something awesome on the pumpkin and then carves it out.
Speaker 0: And I know Emily can make a badass pumpkin.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'll imagine just about everyone else we know can make a badass pumpkin.
Speaker 1: I might go get the internet to help me making badass pumpkin.
Speaker 0: I imagine that's going to fail.
Speaker 0: I'm going to make a traditional jack-o-lantern Fair and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.