Speaker 1: It's Wednesday August 30th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We bring you the secret panel from Otacon 2006 meaning the webcomics roundtable that we've recorded in the Renaissance Hotel on Saturday night.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So there's something I gotta get off of my chest things that are boobs hurt in this community.
Speaker 1: more so now is that?
Speaker 3: How long are we gonna carry on with this inside joke that is impossible to share with the world?
Speaker 1: Because it may someday be shared with the world Let's try to make some progress in that area actually though.
Speaker 1: I do have something I get off my chest.
Speaker 1: I would like to say that Protein supplements and protein bars are perhaps the vilest Constructions known to man, that's why I don't eat them good.
Speaker 1: fucking God do those things not taste good?
Speaker 3: Well, I mean what tastes good in the world?
Speaker 3: ready sugar.
Speaker 1: There's ice all right and fat.
Speaker 3: that's what tastes good.
Speaker 3: protein does not taste good.
Speaker 3: protein doesn't taste like anything.
Speaker 1: No protein can taste good.
Speaker 1: protein.
Speaker 1: you realize Scott is a very broad category of things.
Speaker 3: Yeah, but you know the proteins are generally a collection of amino acids.
Speaker 1: I've got some of the best tasting meats are extremely lean and have very little fat in them at all.
Speaker 3: Yeah, but without.
Speaker 1: so what do you think?
Speaker 3: without any fat the me?
Speaker 1: so uh so what do you think is in those meats?
Speaker 1: Meat okay, and what does meat made out of?
Speaker 0: Meat?
Speaker 1: yes, yes meat is made out of protein Among other things.
Speaker 3: yeah, then how come they don't make a meat bar that tastes good.
Speaker 1: You know what they do.
Speaker 1: It's called jerky.
Speaker 3: Haha, then why are you eating a nasty ass protein bar?
Speaker 1: because I needed more protein.
Speaker 1: see the thing is more jerky.
Speaker 1: See that.
Speaker 1: the thing is just that my diet for most of my life has not been Inconducive to any sort of Non-aerobic exercise because I tend to eat a lot of carbohydrates and very little else.
Speaker 3: Well, that's what the food pyramid says to eat.
Speaker 1: Yeah Which means that I've been my scrawny self for a long time and now I need a little bit of protein because I'm trying to Lift a few weights, but do you want to be like a muscle man?
Speaker 1: No I just want to stay in shape for Basically my entire body is in shape as in.
Speaker 1: no just my legs are in shape and the rest of my body was kind of weak You know running and biking and all that.
Speaker 3: so what do you?
Speaker 1: so let's I always feel funny because I got my tiny little like 10-pound freeways, and then there's Pete who could probably just bench-press me.
Speaker 3: all right, so let's say you're not weak anymore.
Speaker 3: What do you?
Speaker 3: what are you gonna do with your newfound strength powers?
Speaker 3: You're gonna go become spider-man.
Speaker 1: You know how much time I'll save by opening doors more quickly?
Speaker 3: okay, that's Less time than you spent lifting weights.
Speaker 1: I believe I don't.
Speaker 1: this is another inside joke, but I'll open the hell out-of-doors That's for sure.
Speaker 1: The only thing I wanted to say is that protein bars and protein supplements taste like assholes.
Speaker 3: It is a general rule of thumb that 90% of foods that say they are nutritional or advertise themselves to being nutritional taste like ass or have no flavor at all and In the book of Scott that means they should not be eaten.
Speaker 1: but anyway We're gonna go real light on the news and the things the day today because we are finally going to air the Secret panel that we ran at Otacon 2006.
Speaker 3: you
Speaker 1: see we generally if you listen to our coverage of Otacon or fast karate for the gentleman's coverage of Otacon or anime world orders coverage of Otacon You might have gotten the impression that many of us did not particularly care for the vast majority of the panels that happened at Otacon?
Speaker 3: Yeah, of course again, you can't blame Otacon for that.
Speaker 1: Oh, not at all.
Speaker 3: Well, you can blame them a tiny bit for not Caring.
Speaker 1: Otacon's panels despite their problems were not as bad as the panels at lesser cons We attended.
Speaker 3: that is definitely true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we you can listen to our old con reports to get all that.
Speaker 3: but the point is that in general at pretty much every anime convention that we know of that we've been to and many of our Accomplices have been to Panels are like accomplices.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 1: Although you should have said maybe henchmen cohorts I don't know.
Speaker 3: panels are sucking lately in general overall.
Speaker 3: There are still good panels.
Speaker 3: There is still absolutely terrible panels, but the average is going down.
Speaker 1: So what we did is well actually what I did because Scott actually was out.
Speaker 1: I think you were watching a terrible.
Speaker 3: I was watching some terrible ass movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well Scott was doing that.
Speaker 1: I was getting myself nice and drunk and then all the webcomic artists I know and the webcomic artist friends of the webcomic artists.
Speaker 1: I know Ended up in our hotel room.
Speaker 1: So I decided alright, I'm gonna do that thing.
Speaker 1: I said I do that I didn't think I'd actually do and Actually sit them all down with microphones and kind of interview all of them and it turned into what I think is a pretty good Panel,
Speaker 3: I think That the had the advantage of alcohol which normal panels do not have.
Speaker 3: I think alcohol while I don't drink It would make every panel more interesting.
Speaker 1: See the thing is you really couldn't tell that anyone had been drinking.
Speaker 1: if you listen to it though I have not listened to all of it and I will say that Conrad is like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, regardless of the amount of alcohol in him.
Speaker 3: I guess that's absolutely true.
Speaker 3: I Haven't listened to.
Speaker 3: I listen to the end because I showed up for the end of it.
Speaker 3: Yep, but that's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as opposed to the roundtable you help me run where you kind of just sabotage the whole thing.
Speaker 3: I was mad tired.
Speaker 3: I wasn't sabotaging on purpose.
Speaker 3: I was trying to do good.
Speaker 1: Well, the funny thing is in this one that we're gonna play.
Speaker 1: You know on this episode you can really hear My voice pretty much in the final throes of it dying because my voice is squeaking all over the place.
Speaker 1: And as you all know, we both lost our voices on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Yeah Okay, I blame podcasting.
Speaker 1: Oh So anyway to keep it brief in the news.
Speaker 1: the anime manga comics web comics news.
Speaker 1: My news is very brief very to the point.
Speaker 1: death note volume 7 came out in English.
Speaker 3: now It's been out in Japanese for a long time.
Speaker 1: This would not normally be news.
Speaker 1: However, for those of you who have read it You will know why I'm bringing this up as news and for those of you who haven't I will simply say that when you read Death note 7 be prepared to read the whole thing in one go and be prepared.
Speaker 3: Death note 7 is perhaps the most important and best volume of death note.
Speaker 3: well, it contains the most important and best chapters of death note.
Speaker 3: in my opinion it also begins the turning point.
Speaker 3: that sort of starts phase 2 where the manga changes gears from being one thing to being another thing and I'll reserve my opinions of phase 2 for another time.
Speaker 3: But let it be known that there are two moments in the manga that are basically Tremendously important.
Speaker 1: if you thought some of that stuff with penber early on was a big deal.
Speaker 1: You haven't seen anything.
Speaker 3: Yes, and both of these moments receive double dual page spreads.
Speaker 3: The first moment should be very early on in the ma in volume 7 and the second moment should be much later on in volume 7. now the first one is my favorite and the second one is the most important.
Speaker 1: see the second one was a Moment when I realized that there was a character in this manga that I had been a little Sympathetic to and I kind of liked and I didn't like that character anymore.
Speaker 3: after that point all Yeah, the first part was when I realized that You know that my favorite one cuz.
Speaker 1: well true that part too because then you realize oh I didn't.
Speaker 3: oh It was like OMG OMG doo-doo-doo double page spread and then the next page it's like oh Yeah, you can tell we I've been wanting to talk about this since what?
Speaker 1: over a year ago when we read this yeah And it's finally out in English meaning sometime in the near future.
Speaker 1: We are going to do a show on death note.
Speaker 3: We will do a show on the first half of death note with spoilers spoilers.
Speaker 1: I got some things that I got to get off of my chest things that are hurting this community more.
Speaker 3: So now Okay speaking of manga and other comics I don't know how long this has been on the internet.
Speaker 3: Oh, it's only been on the internet since August 18 2006. cool this is a list of the 2005 so last year comics and graphic novel bestsellers from one to a hundred and Number one is full metal alchemist volume one.
Speaker 1: This is in English, by the way You're not gonna read the whole freaking.
Speaker 3: Oh, I'm not but basically it's Naruto Naruto Naruto Sin City Star Wars.
Speaker 3: And then the whole rest of the list is Naruto Sin City fruit basket Star Wars Kenshin Dn angel inu yasha And death note.
Speaker 1: now, of course the ultimate question here is how many underwear pervert aka superhero comics?
Speaker 3: Yeah, because I mean look this is the hundred best-selling graphic novels and comics in the u.s.
Speaker 3: In the year of 2005 and the top of it is completely dominated by manga except for Sin City and Star Wars and There is some scattered.
Speaker 3: Calvin and Hobbes is about and I think one far side and maybe a peanut now Way at the bottom way at the bottom.
Speaker 3: number 99 is our crumb.
Speaker 3: Okay, and there's some Calvin and Hobbes down there, but number 66 is the first.
Speaker 3: so there are 65 manga and other stuff.
Speaker 3: Number 66 is Batman hush volume 2 the best-selling underwear pervert comic or graphic novel of the year.
Speaker 3: number 48 was Attack of the deranged mutant killer monster show goons that sold better than every single underwear.
Speaker 3: pervert 63 was Warcraft the Sunwell trilogy 1.
Speaker 3: God God from Tokyo pop.
Speaker 3: it sold better than every underwear pervert.
Speaker 3: What yugioh number one sold better than every underwear pervert?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know mega Tokyo volume 3.
Speaker 3: Oh Outsold every single underwear pervert except that single Batman beat it by two spots on the list.
Speaker 1: you know what this means?
Speaker 1: it means that the Not the comic industry in regards to underwear perverts aka superheroes or super - heroes Isn't doing so well.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: And I think the way to sum it up is that when we went to free comic book day to get our free comic books The proprietor of the comic book shop We went to seem somewhat angry that we were not willing to purchase his underwear pervert comics that we just wanted our free.
Speaker 3: No, here's the best thing ready.
Speaker 3: The second underwear pervert on the list is Batman hush volume 1 at number 76. the third Underwear pervert is Batman Dark Knight Returns, which is actually really good.
Speaker 3: It's Batman written by the Sin City guy.
Speaker 3: I have it and it's damn good.
Speaker 3: You should read it, but it's number 85. and The only other underwear pervert on the entire list is 89 Watchmen Watchmen.
Speaker 3: perhaps the greatest underwear pervert comic ever was outsold by mega Tokyo volume 3 Warcraft something volume 1 and A whole shit ton of manga.
Speaker 1: I hate to say it, but it makes me really happy partly because I really don't like underwear pervert comics in general and I'm kind of glad that I'm not alone in this sentiment.
Speaker 1: and too though It makes me a little sad that Watchmen really needs to be widely read because Watchmen is excellent.
Speaker 3: Yeah, the general problem I have is that you know There's a whole genre of comics that involve underwear perverts and as in any genre Some of them are damn good like Watchmen and Batman Dark Knight Returns.
Speaker 1: I don't think the word some.
Speaker 1: I think the word one would suffice.
Speaker 3: No, there are a few.
Speaker 1: Oh three.
Speaker 3: There are more than three but not many percentage wise less than 1%.
Speaker 3: Yet the comics they have stores stores dead.
Speaker 3: They have an entire distribution company dedicated to one genre in one medium and in the United States There is an entire medium that is dominated by one genre and a better selling.
Speaker 3: Uh Genre in the medium.
Speaker 3: I guess manga is not a genre, but it's a. it's a subset of a medium of you know graphic Whatever.
Speaker 3: Yeah.
Speaker 3: Yeah is Kicking its ass yet.
Speaker 3: The market won't change.
Speaker 3: They're still dominating the comic book store with superheroes if they were cat if they were smart at all.
Speaker 3: Look at these numbers.
Speaker 3: if you were going by what sells you wouldn't you would cancel every freaking superhero book.
Speaker 1: Well that leads right into the things of the day because God's thing of the day is quite Underwear pervert II.
Speaker 3: Yeah, you know, it sure does piss me off.
Speaker 3: Those combo companies do not make Economically wise decisions.
Speaker 3: that would benefit my entertainment anyway.
Speaker 3: Yeah, but here's a good example of what's wrong with underwear pervert comics and why they're not so great.
Speaker 3: This guy did a pretty cool thing on his blog.
Speaker 3: he took Watchmen a great comic.
Speaker 3: we just talked about it two seconds ago and He redid the cover and four pages of Watchmen.
Speaker 3: He redid all the text in The style of writing that is known to be fit Stan Lee with you know random bolding of words and Crazy made-up words and that this precisely what I hate about underwear pervert comics.
Speaker 3: yep, so he takes a great underwear pervert comic that doesn't have the things that are hated and he adds the hated things and It just.
Speaker 3: it really just shows you Like if you didn't if you don't notice it reading a normal underwear pervert comic you look at this and you go.
Speaker 3: Oh That's why they're stupid.
Speaker 3: look at that.
Speaker 1: You know the bowling wouldn't be so bad if it wasn't that they bolded random words instead of useful words or words that made sense.
Speaker 3: But this just shows how they took the standard of what superhero comics are took it and merged it with the greatest pinnacle of superhero comics and it turns to crap.
Speaker 3: and It's just.
Speaker 3: the concept is just so perfect.
Speaker 3: It's golden you.
Speaker 3: I got you got to look at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's especially Special to me after you might have heard my rant on another podcast a while ago about the balding.
Speaker 1: Yep, because I was unable to finish reading a comic recently because the balding just bothered me so much I couldn't force myself to read and that was just the balding let alone the writing style and other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't even get to the plot or the characters of the writing or the art or anything.
Speaker 1: The balding alone stopped me.
Speaker 1: All right, you know what.
Speaker 1: now I'm gonna actually pass on having a thing of the day today.
Speaker 3: Well, you suck cuz.
Speaker 1: I didn't have anything particularly relevant to anime manga comics web comics and I don't want to Start another trend of having super super long episodes because we I think we tried to wean ourselves off of that just before Otacon Mmm, plus I have to do a whole bunch of editing to make this thing listenable before it goes up.
Speaker 3: The problem is it's hard not to make a long episode when we're playing a record pre-recorded bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, I hope you all enjoy it.
Speaker 1: They talk about a wide variety of topics and they introduce themselves, so I won't bother reintroducing them before.
Speaker 3: Yeah, I'm gonna have to download this and listen to it.
Speaker 1: So we're here at Otacon 2006 with a variety of slightly drunk to completely drunk web comic artist web comic aficionados anime fans general ne'er-do-wells and Conrad.
Speaker 1: So, I guess everyone who's here could introduce themselves so we can at least tell whose voice is whose.
Speaker 1: I am Of course rim your favorite host of geek nights.
Speaker 0: My name is Brian Carroll.
Speaker 0: I do instant classic.
Speaker 0: My name is Mookie.
Speaker 2: I am the writer and artist of a Dominic Deegan Oracle for hire.
Speaker 7: I am my I'm I do.
Speaker 7: I do a comic called fallen.
Speaker 1: Hi, I'm cat.
Speaker 1: I actually do nothing.
Speaker 6: My name is Connor krailing.
Speaker 6: I have no discernible skills or talents, but I was invited here tonight to talk to you about things Good things.
Speaker 4: My name is Laram Lancaster, and I used to take part in committee But now I just simply feature in it.
Speaker 1: So we're not doing anything particularly Big here, but I guess I'd like to get impressions of Otacon the artist Ally the con in general.
Speaker 1: I mean some of you go to more cons than others.
Speaker 1: So I guess I won't direct this to anyone in particular first, but How was Otacon?
Speaker 1: Why are you here?
Speaker 2: well Otacon is the biggest convention of the year for a lot of us here on the East Coast and speaking personally And someone who makes a living off of his webcomic.
Speaker 2: This is where most of my income usually comes in.
Speaker 2: So as this as in every year I have a fabulous time because most of the people who don't go to any convention Most people who go to only one convention a year come to this one.
Speaker 2: You just meet everybody whether you want to or not.
Speaker 0: I Agree with that.
Speaker 0: It's also my biggest convention.
Speaker 0: I do about two or three a year and Although I don't usually have that much of a big representation here I usually use it to meet up with my friends webcomic friends people.
Speaker 0: I only see about two or three times a year themselves We talk fascism communism the whole nine yards food.
Speaker 1: This is actually my third con and I still don't know why I go but I'm here and it's a good time.
Speaker 1: I see people and I do things.
Speaker 1: So most of you spend your time in the artist alley.
Speaker 1: I take it at the convention, that's true.
Speaker 1: Now, how is that?
Speaker 1: I mean the artist alley tends to be a very eclectic collection of artists of all different stripes ranging from complete fan artists to totally original works.
Speaker 1: What do you guys do in the artist alley aside from obviously selling art, I mean do you promote yourselves?
Speaker 1: Do you just socialize?
Speaker 1: is it networking?
Speaker 1: What is the artist alley?
Speaker 1: Why are you there?
Speaker 2: The artist alley is so fascinating because it is so many different things.
Speaker 2: once it is all those things people promoting themselves original artwork fan artwork and networking and you don't really have to do.
Speaker 2: you don't really.
Speaker 2: you don't really have to really go out of your way to do any of the more socialist parts of it because Fascinatingly enough.
Speaker 2: It always seems just come to you because the artist alley By nature is just so diverse.
Speaker 0: I think this is actually interesting because Me and Mookie earned different sides of the coin with artists alley.
Speaker 0: people will go to artist alley seeking out Mookie Whereas I am looking for promotion myself.
Speaker 0: So whereas Mookie, I don't think you're really Promoting yourself.
Speaker 0: You're already promoted.
Speaker 0: You're more there for the Public Yeah, and I'm there for the promotion.
Speaker 0: so I think that's interesting on two sides.
Speaker 1: So in terms of self-promotion Does it ever feel awkward trying to promote yourself?
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a fine line between selling something you do and you know be coming off as a person who's trying to sell something You do.
Speaker 1: do you walk that fine line?
Speaker 1: Do you ever like you're giving us feel to someone and you just feel awkward while you're doing it?
Speaker 1: or you wonder if maybe you?
Speaker 1: Overstepped a line or something?
Speaker 0: Well in terms of the actual line I'll just answer It's I'm kind of like it's not really like a carnival where you know I'm on the dunking booth shouting at people to go hit me down.
Speaker 0: Hand me three dollars and throw a ball at my target.
Speaker 0: it's um, I Guess the line is crossed between if you seek them out or if they seek you out like my my display.
Speaker 0: this year I spent a long time on it.
Speaker 0: So be I was bringing people to it and Therefore I can promote myself that way.
Speaker 2: There I mean some people I think are a little too aggressive.
Speaker 2: in the artist Sally I mean my first year ever at Otacon I was next to a guy Who wasn't doing so?
Speaker 2: well?
Speaker 2: so he would literally yell at people who were walking across walking even remotely near his table and Saying you come here you come here and they would drink they would.
Speaker 2: Because a lot of geeks are very shy and when someone's yelling them to do something, they'll probably do it.
Speaker 2: So you had them flyers.
Speaker 1: do any of you ever go?
Speaker 1: I mean, this is obviously an anime convention which tend to be very broad-based.
Speaker 1: Do you ever work at?
Speaker 1: art might not just miss work, but do other convention maybe comic centered conventions or other?
Speaker 1: Types of conventions.
Speaker 1: Are there any different from anime conventions?
Speaker 1: You even go to them?
Speaker 2: I go to I I go to one every year.
Speaker 2: That's more of a sci-fi more sci-fi fantasy and almost Ren fair centered icon on Long Island.
Speaker 2: The the sci-fi fans are much different much different than the anime fans there are much more Selective in what they spend their money on.
Speaker 2: they're a lot less willing to show you how enthusiastic they are.
Speaker 2: A lot of few of them like I feel like they some of them.
Speaker 2: they can look down their nose at you.
Speaker 2: But the anime fans are starting to creep in.
Speaker 2: a Lot of them start.
Speaker 2: anime fans are starting to creep into that convention too and whereas anime fans are tend to be very Enthusiastic and open and almost accepting of new things the older school sci-fi fans Are more pushing them away, and I don't I think they should be.
Speaker 2: I think they should be more accepting.
Speaker 2: another convention I went to was Wizard World Boston Which I failed at miserably.
Speaker 2: Wizard World Boston had a bunch of comic fans And it was so strange because there was one guy dressed up the entire weekend as the Green Lantern and these people at this Convention flipped
Speaker 1: wait so
Speaker 2: one guy in costume,
Speaker 1: so he was dressed up as the Green Lantern for all three days.
Speaker 2: No one day, okay, okay?
Speaker 2: One guy just showed up one day and drew an immense crowd because everyone's making a huge deal.
Speaker 2: look There's somebody in costume at an anime convention.
Speaker 1: How often do you see that?
Speaker 1: No, I went to Philly Wizard World.
Speaker 1: as opposed to a Philly Wizard World I emphasize the wrong syllables there.
Speaker 1: Philly Wizard World was a scary convention that we devoted a great deal of coverage to.
Speaker 2: I went to Wizard World Boston.
Speaker 1: They're basically the same thing as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: yeah just different locations and we ran into the situation where anime cons you know I pull out a microphone I try to interview someone and The ten fangirls around will run over in.
Speaker 1: Oh interview me next year.
Speaker 1: oh my god.
Speaker 1: At Philly Wizard World I Couldn't get anyone to interview with me.
Speaker 1: I'd like even without the microphones in my pocket I'm just some dude at the con and I walk up and I try to ask someone like like hey How you doing, and they just look at me with this look of who are you and why are you talking to me?
Speaker 2: Very different crowd.
Speaker 2: I prefer the anime crowds tenfold to the Comic Con so not Comic Con comic book convention crowds.
Speaker 1: So How is the social atmosphere in the artist alley?
Speaker 1: I mean obviously you all I?
Speaker 1: Noticed that people who come for the artist alley tend to stay in the artist alley most of the con and yet Enjoy themselves immensely and I all the best stories from conventions.
Speaker 1: I hear things that happen in the artist alley late at night when the crazies come out.
Speaker 7: Yeah, I I'm in in for the the social aspect of the artist alley.
Speaker 7: I really couldn't care less if I made money because the money is really secondary to me.
Speaker 7: it's just mostly meeting people who I know on the internet and Being able to meet other webcomic people.
Speaker 0: Actually, I have an interesting story about that.
Speaker 0: I Shouldn't have even attempted to do this But I was fighting with Kinko's today And I just so happened to meet an artist from the artist alley who I had no idea who it was.
Speaker 0: at the Kinko's just they were also messing up his work, so we kind of had that common interest and He was having his stuff printed down.
Speaker 0: We just he saw my badge had artists written on it And we just kind of struck up a conversation in terms of what's going on.
Speaker 0: So like that kind of social it's very very friendly, you know everyone's very accepting.
Speaker 0: even though he didn't know my work I didn't know his.
Speaker 0: I'm not that much into anime, and he was an anime artist But it we still had.
Speaker 0: you know it was very very social environment.
Speaker 1: so to change directions entirely for a moment now All of you are at an anime con right now, so I guess if you do enjoy anime What was the first anime you ever saw like?
Speaker 1: what was it that?
Speaker 1: Got you into this either into anime as a fan or into the subculture of anime as in you're going to conventions now on a regular Basis, okay, I'm gonna say this for the record.
Speaker 1: I do not really enjoy anime I I used to when I was in seventh and eighth grade, but I remember in sixth grade.
Speaker 1: my gateway drug was Pokemon.
Speaker 1: I watched it when I was 12 years old, and I wanted to be that For me.
Speaker 6: um I used to deliver my papers early on my paper route so I could get home and watch Dragon Ball Z.
Speaker 7: My dad is Japanese, and I grew up on Doraemon and The original Dragon Ball on Unsubtitled untranslated, I would just watch it with my dad, and he would translate it for me at key points.
Speaker 0: actually Every morning in middle school when I lived in Florida Dragon Ball Z came on at about 6 30 in the morning, and I will admit this right here.
Speaker 0: I've never admitted to anybody.
Speaker 0: I watched very several several several episodes of Dragon Ball Z Not even knowing what it was and I don't regret it.
Speaker 1: I Have been dating this boy
Speaker 7: for two and a half years And I never knew that
Speaker 2: for the record his
Speaker 6: power level
Speaker 1: is above
Speaker 0: 1 million.
Speaker 0: This is the best place.
Speaker 0: kind of You're dead to me.
Speaker 0: the internet to kind of my.
Speaker 0: we can see my face and my shame.
Speaker 4: My gateway drug was one of the stranger ones.
Speaker 4: it was Evangelion Because if you if you sink your teeth into Evangelion, and you like it you're.
Speaker 4: you're smooth into anime But if you find Evangelion, and you hate it you get turned off forever.
Speaker 4: It's one of those hit-or-miss ones because it's just so crazy and creepy and strange.
Speaker 7: My I like the Doraemon where they found the dinosaur egg, and then they raised the dinosaur.
Speaker 1: What that was oddly specific?
Speaker 6: Yes, Ava was crap.
Speaker 2: my my summer going into my freshman year of high school the sci-fi channel did their weekend festival of anime Which comprised of three films.
Speaker 2: I watched them twice.
Speaker 2: It was robot carnival lens man and vampire hunter D.
Speaker 1: You realize that we that is the exact same thing.
Speaker 1: that was the first anime I ever saw robot carnival robot carnival lens man vampire hunter D's.
Speaker 2: watch the same festival on the sci-fi.
Speaker 1: I think we did.
Speaker 1: I was in fourth grade.
Speaker 2: Oh my god.
Speaker 2: I was.
Speaker 2: I was gonna go.
Speaker 1: how old are you?
Speaker 2: I'm only 24 Nike boobily mushrooms, I'm older than you Mustache.
Speaker 1: I look like I'm 30 haha.
Speaker 1: Alright, so in terms of you know anime fan I'm coming to Otakon.
Speaker 1: now many of you go to other con state.
Speaker 1: Kineticon is a big example.
Speaker 1: How does Otakon compare to the other conventions in terms of how they treat the webcomic artist or the artist how they run the artist?
Speaker 1: Alley how much you enjoy going to the convention and how much business you do.
Speaker 1: a lot of topics there?
Speaker 1: But I hope we'll get some good.
Speaker 2: I think Kineticon is the best example.
Speaker 2: I think of a. I think Kineticon is like the Boston of Conventions in my opinion.
Speaker 2: It's the biggest little convention.
Speaker 2: I've ever been to the people there.
Speaker 2: I mean the convention is growing and it's getting big, but it still has the feel To me at least of a really small Personable convention, I think that's the lure of a. I think that's the lure to it for a lot of people.
Speaker 2: not to mention that It is Amazingly friendly to web comics.
Speaker 2: a big convention like this.
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 2: It is amazingly good for business Amazingly good for sales and exposure, but it is.
Speaker 2: it is in my opinion a lot less personable Just for the sheer size.
Speaker 0: What kind of has to be in that case?
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's not really blaming anybody It's just it's just a numbers thing.
Speaker 2: Big it's like a big corporation can't be as people friendly as say like Joe's diner down the street.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I live in Hartford.
Speaker 0: So I mean Kineticon is a very very kind of no-brainer con for me is very stress-free.
Speaker 0: No, I mean me knowing the people who run it personally.
Speaker 0: I've kind of taken my own personal, you know I've had my fingerprint on Kineticon itself, you know They let me run my film festival now, which we just had our first year of and we're gonna have it next year as well.
Speaker 0: so And along with that, I mean, I'm helping a lot of the other people who are not local to the area.
Speaker 0: I help them around stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So in terms of the con I'm not sure how much of me being a local person factors into that but Otacon is definitely a lot bigger a lot more stranger in a strange town kind of thing.
Speaker 2: I Think we should take this time to introduce someone just walked in to the room.
Speaker 2: Well, actually we should let him introduce himself, I suppose.
Speaker 5: Well, why would you go and do something silly like that?
Speaker 5: No, no seriously, all right, I'm not actually Grom that's just Mookie's, you know thing.
Speaker 5: My name is actually Garth.
Speaker 5: the last name is Graham, but if you spell it funny without like the second a you do get in fact Grom.
Speaker 5: Yes, exactly And I as everyone in the room, I think knows but people listening don't I do the webcomic community About the Kineticon thing Garth and I attended two cons one con just before Kineticon and one con and then Kineticon itself.
Speaker 4: and This kind of goes back to your question about the comic-con thing.
Speaker 4: Is that?
Speaker 4: our first convention as community was wizard con Philly Last year and So we had.
Speaker 4: we had attended Webcomic we'd attended conventions as guests as attendees, but we'd never been behind the table yet.
Speaker 4: And so going to wizard con Philly Straight up as a comic convention and then coming to Kineticon It was a very stark contrast between the two and who we met who we talked to who came to talk to us.
Speaker 4: And I definitely agree with the two people that have already talked about how How small and and how familiar the people Kineticon were versus the bigger?
Speaker 4: The bigger con that is is wizard con as well as the the crowd and the people that you meet there Since this is a free-form and this also kind of touches on the larger versus smaller conventions.
Speaker 5: There was something asked about at comic-con.
Speaker 5: Was there that I missed?
Speaker 1: we were talking about Philly Wizard world and the other wizard world and how different they are from anime conventions.
Speaker 5: Oh, yes.
Speaker 5: Okay.
Speaker 5: Yeah Yeah, two different worlds.
Speaker 5: completely Comic books are not the same as manga basically how shell-shocked.
Speaker 7: comic-book fans and sci-fi fans are versus anime fans and how personable.
Speaker 7: and if anime fans tend to be over.
Speaker 7: comic-book fans and sci-fi fans who kind of tend to stay away from each other They're citing the comic-book fans are in sci-fi as well are very.
Speaker 5: they're very into themselves very into their their work not their work, but the Their interests and nothing else.
Speaker 5: There's less of a community.
Speaker 5: I think going on there It's very very people.
Speaker 5: look at the merchandise and look at the comics whatever they happen to be.
Speaker 5: You know the con for and that's about as far as it goes.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess why do you think that is?
Speaker 1: why is the science fiction and American comic not so much the indie comic?
Speaker 1: But the old, you know, we like to call them underwear perverts But the superhero comics versus indie comics and webcomics.
Speaker 1: and why are the communities so different despite the fact that they have many Similarities in terms of what they actually are?
Speaker 0: I could take a stab at this one.
Speaker 0: I think it has to do with just the for which ones cater towards which audiences.
Speaker 0: I mean the anime Community seems to be centered around.
Speaker 0: I Mean, I'm not gonna this.
Speaker 0: I don't mean this to sound insulting But a lot of this.
Speaker 0: a lot of the anime culture comes from online and comes from the younger crowd as well And a lot of that caters towards just inhibition in general and I think with sci-fi being more of I guess a personal interest and People who like sci-fi usually tend to meet in real life not on the internet.
Speaker 0: not it's just I mean This is just me kind of shooting the brie and a lot of this right phrase, but it's like Anime community just seems to be built on inhibition in general.
Speaker 0: So with that inhibition comes a lot of shared passion and a lot of common interests.
Speaker 0: I mean this is coming from someone who doesn't even have the common interests But I see the passion in them and I respect the passion, you know, like any other Sci-fi fans.
Speaker 2: I think it's almost like a code word between them and they're very careful about I think who they let into the club So to speak.
Speaker 2: so I think a lot of them are very guarded against a lot of these Youngsters so speak Who are just running?
Speaker 2: blindly Enthusiastically towards anything new and cool-looking whereas they have always been very careful as to what they choose what they Tend to like.
Speaker 2: and I think it's just.
Speaker 2: I think it's just generational really I think if the at if the sci-fi fantasy crowd became a little more accepting of the anime crowd, I think Maybe a whole new sort of convention would be born a hybrid almost a sci-fi anime convention.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised our friend Conrad hasn't chimed in with something about 4chan at this point.
Speaker 0: I I have nothing to say about 4chan.
Speaker 1: I Like.
Speaker 6: three years ago when I was a freshman in college I discovered this website off a link to a very from a very Questionable webcomic that I was reading at the time called the lounge.
Speaker 1: I thought you're gonna say questionable content make some kind of joke.
Speaker 1: No, no No It was very.
Speaker 6: it was a very questionable webcomic that I read during high school and I found a link off of it and I started Visiting it because back in the day it used to be funny and now it's a pile of crap and I've disowned it entirely.
Speaker 1: Now what exactly is 4chan?
Speaker 1: I've been I've been studying it like and I I would say I don't know.
Speaker 1: I like Jane Goodall among the Apes.
Speaker 5: It's where images go to die.
Speaker 5: Well, no, not really.
Speaker 5: they just get shared around in a giant pile, but what kind of images?
Speaker 1: that's why that's why Everything mostly pornographic.
Speaker 1: Oh, I mean, I guess the way I would go with this Is that like you all are very savage.
Speaker 1: the internet, you know webcomics and such.
Speaker 1: but you know FARC calm or versus slash dot and how like there's levels of how contiguous the conversations are and how much Someone who is not into the crowd can follow them.
Speaker 1: and like someone who doesn't know about FARC culture could not read FARC and understand It easily.
Speaker 1: 4chan is beyond even my.
Speaker 1: I have no idea what these kids are talking about.
Speaker 1: It's like a foreign language and now I know how my grandparents feel about computers.
Speaker 6: Be fair some of the boards on 4chan aren't terrible boards.
Speaker 6: I do visit wallpapers occasionally to grab you know Fresh wallpapers when I need them and technology can be an actually useful source of information.
Speaker 0: read it for the articles.
Speaker 2: Generally, you know I've entered a slash s every now and then.
Speaker 6: no but but the popular boards are all crap because they're just over completely overpopulated With 13 year olds.
Speaker 6: I can't deal with it.
Speaker 1: Well, so the popular things are crap, but if something's obscure then it's suddenly cool.
Speaker 6: No, no No, because 13 year olds don't care about technology and they don't care about wallpapers.
Speaker 6: They just care about posting up their favorite porn image.
Speaker 5: Yes, you can the internet is for porn.
Speaker 5: Oh Come on.
Speaker 5: I was gonna try and start a musical here, but fail on me.
Speaker 1: You guys you think any of us can drink?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I've been in a musical born I can sing Bob Seger because he uses exactly three notes.
Speaker 0: Nice I've been in the Cradle Rock.
Speaker 0: Don't judge me That's about unions.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with that?
Speaker 6: Did anybody else notice that the panel sucked this year?
Speaker 1: Yes I think to say about the bukkake panel.
Speaker 1: That was like the most popular panel.
Speaker 1: What was all right?
Speaker 1: That was an unfortunately named panel that would not have been allowed to have that name and people noticed it.
Speaker 1: do-it-yourself.
Speaker 1: bukkake is just a hentai drawing panel that they called it something controversial in order to get people to show up kind of like how 4chan staged a fake fight at their panel last year.
Speaker 5: Nice didn't they have a hentai drawing panel?
Speaker 1: There were multiple hentai.
Speaker 6: it was last night at 10 p.m.
Speaker 6: And I was in attendance to that panel.
Speaker 7: one of our friends won a prize For what the best hentai know the scariest dick what what?
Speaker 1: wait a minute as in The one they drew a skip the scary.
Speaker 1: Okay I was going to ask the one with which they were equipped by whatever being may or may not have created them or the one that They constructed out of his drawing.
Speaker 0: I was in person a hence.
Speaker 0: I was drawn.
Speaker 0: This is crossing a line.
Speaker 1: I would think Well, I guess in terms of panels, what do you guys think of panels and anime cons?
Speaker 1: I mean, it seems that panels are generally used.
Speaker 1: what comes in general?
Speaker 1: They're generally supposed to be at least the way most kind of seem to see them as fans trying to Show something off or do something.
Speaker 1: Should they be more controlled?
Speaker 1: should only people who know what they're talking about or experts be allowed on these panels?
Speaker 1: should it be anyone?
Speaker 1: Should they be more strict more loose?
Speaker 1: Because obviously a lot of people agree that the panels are generally not so good these days and what can be done about that?
Speaker 1: I mean you many of you speak on panels.
Speaker 4: So I think that one of the best examples of a finely done panel is heroes and villains Done by someone in this room Because he knows what he's talking about.
Speaker 4: He draws from everywhere good bad, he doesn't just talk about his own stuff and Then he opens it up and and does point-counter point with people in the audience.
Speaker 4: That's what panels should be.
Speaker 4: panels are not.
Speaker 4: just look what I've done.
Speaker 4: I'm really cool.
Speaker 4: It's supposed to be a level of discussion based on Shared information and so you lay forth the information ahead of time and then you discuss it.
Speaker 2: I'm gonna kiss.
Speaker 2: you fall in the mouth, you know he's talking about my writing.
Speaker 2: unique heroes and memorable villains panel and Panels are magnificent in what they are in what they can achieve for you.
Speaker 2: That heroes and villains panel for me at least has gained me a ton of new readers.
Speaker 2: People have come up to me afterwards and says I don't know what you're due, but I'm going to find out now because Because I loved your panel It's a great way for people who are just getting started in web comics or anything to get some exposure and some FaceTime.
Speaker 2: Ideally They are I think a boon to conventions and one of the real drawing points because conventions that are just a big dealers room Like wizard world Yeah, any of those many any of those dealers any of those conventions that are just a big dealers room that have no panels.
Speaker 2: No one likes them.
Speaker 2: But there are very good examples of bad panels and I'll let the assembly take care of that.
Speaker 1: Someone has been waiting with bated breath to speak on this time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just way too opinion.
Speaker 0: Mookie Your keyboard there was ideally because like obviously you're this is gonna be one of those.
Speaker 1: This is why communism fails speeches.
Speaker 1: Panels are great on paper, but the computer is my friend.
Speaker 0: I've attended Mookie's panel twice and it is the ideal panel.
Speaker 0: It's a person.
Speaker 2: I'm not saying I'm gonna be blush I'm really.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying this wonderful panel.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying this to complement you but well, I mean it is an informative panel.
Speaker 0: it speaks on personal experience and while other people it's.
Speaker 0: It's information that's being shared about a subject.
Speaker 0: The problem is is that I'm my very little knowledge of panels.
Speaker 0: I've attended a few I've been on it.
Speaker 0: I've attended the webcomic ones both in the audience and on the stage.
Speaker 0: This year the webcomic panel, which I've only heard rumors of.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually attend it, but there was only There was.
Speaker 0: well, here's I heard that there was.
Speaker 0: only in seeing the schedule - there's only one person actually on the panel who had Anything to do with a webcomic and that was Matt Boyd from Matt call who doesn't really like to talk that much.
Speaker 0: So That he I know I heard Ian ran But Ian made a run for it.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many other people were on this panel But there were at least three including him and one of them um is a webcomic critic which Which you really can't have because it's just no more than a Fanboy talking about a medium which he really doesn't understand anything about.
Speaker 0: so And especially with webcomics which are you know idealistic and just so self-congratulatory as it is You know You you need some people to actually have some sort of criticism and who know things about storytelling I'd love to see Mookie actually take control of that panel as well.
Speaker 0: Although he kind of does it already.
Speaker 0: but Well for anyone What they're talking about being the panelists.
Speaker 1: for anyone in our forums who have witnessed the epic arguments that have occurred in the forums of The front row crew forum the the fact that we agree almost entirely on this point is amazing because I've been to numerous panels recently where I or someone I know is actually an expert on the subject that they're talking about and People do pet like.
Speaker 1: there's a panel on the Nintendo new system though We and the person doing it didn't really know anything about the way didn't really wasn't a Nintendo expert or anything.
Speaker 1: they were just some dude who decided to run a panel about something they thought was cool and they didn't know anything and they just kind of rambled on stage or The come this panels where people don't know what they're talking about But the audience always assumes that anyone up on the stage with a microphone knows what they're talking about.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of it has to do with the fact that a lot of people just like the idea that they're panelists.
Speaker 0: They don't even care about the panel itself.
Speaker 1: I like the fact that I'm a panel.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, you're talking about, you know It helps.
Speaker 1: I mean Usually yeah, I guess I would honestly really like to see panels be more.
Speaker 1: I guess I don't want to say credentials because I'd hate to Get to that point where you need to prove that you know what you're talking about to get on a panel.
Speaker 1: But maybe some sort of you know show something a panel you've done before or can tell if you you know what you're doing.
Speaker 0: You're not.
Speaker 1: so you think that you'd think that.
Speaker 1: I do think that ideally most of the most panelists aren't the person who's running the panels.
Speaker 0: Never meets anyone involved in the panel until the day the panel The audience the audience is gonna know that the guy upstage is cold bullshit.
Speaker 1: No, you know, the audience have no idea.
Speaker 0: I don't have.
Speaker 2: that much depends on how confident the guy is.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, it's confident.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't want to rag on the geeks be guy because he's a cool guy.
Speaker 1: we've we've got on his show and he's been on our show, but Though this Nintendo revolution we panel he did he didn't know anything about.
Speaker 1: he was kind of talking.
Speaker 1: okay, the audience were asking him the kind of questions that you would ask at like a Nintendo press conference as though he would know the Answers and he kind of BS half of them.
Speaker 1: But the audience really does think whoever's up on the panel is just an expert and they're there by the grace of whatever gods Run the panel, huh?
Speaker 2: I'd like to say I mean just kind of Segueing a little bit and maybe a little.
Speaker 2: I'd like to just I guess throw out to the assembly.
Speaker 2: I guess I'm growing just generally distaste.
Speaker 2: I'm sorry.
Speaker 2: I Have a growing distaste for general web comics panels in general, honestly I agree entirely.
Speaker 1: web comics are.
Speaker 1: they're not necessarily a fully mature medium But they're out there.
Speaker 1: It's not like you need to explain to people what a webcomic is.
Speaker 2: Well, no, it's not.
Speaker 2: It's not that.
Speaker 2: it's that when anime conventions law or any conventions.
Speaker 2: lump all the web comics guests together and Put them on a hey meet your favorite web comics guests.
Speaker 2: the last few that I have been on with the exception of Well, I guess maybe one a few years ago have been terrible.
Speaker 2: and it's not because the people who are on the panel are terrible People.
Speaker 2: what ends up happening is it becomes very unfocused.
Speaker 2: it because and and I'm gonna sound so elitist by saying this and I really don't mean it but a lot of the veteran webcomics get mixed in with the newcomer webcomics and a lot of the veteran webcomic errs know to keep their answers kind of
Speaker 0: brief
Speaker 2: and This is no fault of the people who are just getting started in webcomics who want to get their faces out who want to say Something.
Speaker 2: that's memorable, but when one person asks a question that could be answered in under a minute By one person up there, but of course everyone wants to chime in if you've never been on a panel before So the same question gets answered the same way over the next half an hour.
Speaker 1: So, how do you all feel about say having professional moderators at panels like that?
Speaker 1: do you think someone who is actually there to cut people off or Direct the conversation aside from people are on the panel.
Speaker 2: I think that's I think it's a great idea.
Speaker 2: It was tried this year at the uber webcomic panel at Kinetic on but it It just kind of got a little out of control because there were more panelists than then.
Speaker 2: I think is healthy.
Speaker 5: It's always sad and I've noticed this at a lot of webcomic panels that I've been on, you know, the general webcomic panel that we kind of been all talking about is that they're More often than not.
Speaker 5: it seems to be that there are more panelists than people in the audience.
Speaker 0: Plus you what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: adding an editor to web comics.
Speaker 5: That's against everything we stand exactly.
Speaker 0: that's what it has to be disorderly for this to work.
Speaker 1: The web comics is an ideal Brian.
Speaker 6: You're a madman a Speaking strictly as a panel goer.
Speaker 6: I would rather see panels better distributed and better organized rather than seeing a moderator.
Speaker 6: I would rather see as Mookie stated veteran webcomic artists to get like with veterans and Beginners with beginners.
Speaker 6: that way people can pick who they want to see pick what answers they want to know rather than having a man Stand in the middle and try to sort it out while it's going on.
Speaker 1: I'm talking more in terms of panels that exist.
Speaker 1: I mean there are people who know their stuff, but they're not good public speakers.
Speaker 1: There are people who like a wonderful show or a wonderful comic and they just they can't.
Speaker 1: they don't know how to massage a crowd.
Speaker 1: And I'm talking about more.
Speaker 1: have someone who know like professionals who know what they're doing to direct the conversation So that people who have something to say can get it out without Sounding dumb even when they're obviously not dumb.
Speaker 1: They just don't know how to deal with a crowd or with You know a situation where someone who's loud takes over a panel because there's no moderator to shut them up.
Speaker 2: I absolutely agree with that.
Speaker 2: some people who are just all talk and no substance Can easily overshadow one of the most brilliant writers who just gets really nervous and fun of everyone.
Speaker 2: the reason why he does his work In front of a webcomic.
Speaker 2: I'm sorry behind a computer screen is because maybe he is afraid of crowds.
Speaker 2: So I agree with you completely on that.
Speaker 4: One of the things that Connecticut did not this past year, but two years ago was they had their meet-and-greets with Two or three comics at a time and the interesting thing about that was Is that you could say hey?
Speaker 4: I want to go see Dominic Deegan and Mac Hall and Vg cats all in one panel, and then you know that you're only dealing with that small group of people with only those small Questions.
Speaker 4: now I realize I just picked very strange combination but instead of having 50 people on a stage when you ask what's your inspiration and Have everybody answer you could at least you could do and it would feel strange in with 50 people on stage to ask.
Speaker 4: so Mac Hall What do you think about this?
Speaker 1: and have nobody else be able to answer that question?
Speaker 1: yeah?
Speaker 4: It could move faster, but you would feel as a questioner from the from the audience.
Speaker 4: You would feel
Speaker 1: rude to everyone
Speaker 4: else on the panel to ask
Speaker 2: that that format did not work for me.
Speaker 2: I they they paired me up a kinetic.
Speaker 2: that was a very noble idea.
Speaker 2: that kinetic on did to pair up webcomics.
Speaker 2: I got paired up with Tim Buckley of control alt delete and Brian Clevenger of 8-bit theater two very good friends of mine by the way.
Speaker 2: I love them both to death, but the that year The questions were all to the questions that were asked.
Speaker 2: to quote the three of us They answered and by the time they got to me.
Speaker 2: by the time I opened my mouth someone else was already asking with those two guys another question, so I was the third wheel.
Speaker 0: See that's interesting because that that format actually worked out for me.
Speaker 0: You were paired up with two other people.
Speaker 0: I was paired up with one other person and Yeah, but that was purely purely by luck.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It was by luck, but it did work out.
Speaker 0: I mean well also and it done them to that what?
Speaker 0: Happened two years ago was that they had all the groupings of webcomics And then they had their uber webcomic panel.
Speaker 0: so all the meet-and-greet stuff got all the stupid You know random questions that are always asked.
Speaker 0: it got them all out of the way with all the smaller Inspiration all those.
Speaker 5: what's your favorite fruit?
Speaker 0: that's why.
Speaker 0: that's why two years ago the uber webcomic panel was great because
Speaker 1: All of the
Speaker 0: bad questions were covered out of the way and then all the important ones were done at the uber panel, and I was paired up with Scott ransomware of eg cats and It was one other person And it was a very controlled environment.
Speaker 0: everyone was there for them, but I'm It was by pure luck that it worked out for me.
Speaker 0: Just because Scott's kind of a shy guy.
Speaker 0: I'm not Conversation turned to me stuff like that, but I mean I think it would work that kind of format Just if you tweaked that and not just rely all on the uber webcam panel Especially because the webcam panel is repeated the same in every convention.
Speaker 0: It's all this the same questions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was the thing I've noticed.
Speaker 1: the most is that I mean if you have a generic panel It's just we are webcomic artists.
Speaker 1: people always ask the same questions no matter what.
Speaker 1: How do you feel more about having the webcomic panel where that's the webcomic panel?
Speaker 1: our topic at this convention is Blah about webcomics or blah about whatever and then it's just kind of more round table kind of like this only with a lot less alcohol.
Speaker 5: I'm actually yeah, that sounds like fun.
Speaker 5: Well.
Speaker 2: Yeah, because we all everyone All this alcohol, but I'm the only one with a glass of wine.
Speaker 1: so honestly everyone here Yeah, all right I love drinks and Conrad.
Speaker 1: as the conversation went on everyone was so into it that they all kind of just put their drinks down And did forgot about it.
Speaker 2: I think you're right where to represent.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say I drank steadily throughout this entire conversation.
Speaker 2: Anything to make the general webcomics panels more focused.
Speaker 2: I am all for.
Speaker 0: yeah I think if the topics were good because a lot of me the topics are kind of limited.
Speaker 0: also There are more time because the last thing I would want to see is a webcomic a panel where the topic is like promotion You know because for an audience obviously they don't care about the promotion.
Speaker 1: I mean what if it's a audience of aspiring webcomic artists, that's true It depends on your audience.
Speaker 0: But I mean I guess that would be the best one for I don't know Otakon because there'd be a lot more Much bigger pool to choose from.
Speaker 0: the topics were good.
Speaker 1: You can have a panel about anything at Otakon and people would go to it.
Speaker 4: I think an interesting thing would be to group the webcomics.
Speaker 4: I made a weird list a minute ago, but if you group the webcomic Genres sort of like by people who do One-shot-a-day joke strips you did people who were maintaining a high in-depth storyline.
Speaker 4: if you grouped if you if if and when
Speaker 1: you in
Speaker 4: as as the the convention staff if you were to control
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 4: And with with some level of finesse hopefully
Speaker 2: who was
Speaker 4: at the panel what the topic would be you could sort of move the conversation along like you're saying
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 4: And maybe you wouldn't need
Speaker 1: an uberwebcomic panel or
Speaker 4: maybe you could Deal
Speaker 1: with
Speaker 4: those groups of people individually throughout and just say okay for one question for this
Speaker 3: Audience
Speaker 4: so you don't have one question for 50 people.
Speaker 4: you have one question for 20 people and then you have the next question for 20 people and then you have the next question like that.
Speaker 1: I don't You would.
Speaker 4: you'd have to really work at it, and I haven't put in enough time or thought into how it would work out.
Speaker 4: I'm just making up ideas.
Speaker 0: I think people just have to stop looking at webcomics as a concrete thing.
Speaker 0: I mean if we're gonna.
Speaker 0: It's just people see webcomics, and that's I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I was trying to say like that.
Speaker 0: They say like seeing baseball It's just a sport.
Speaker 0: so it's like they use that to cover all sports.
Speaker 0: so a Webcomic is a webcomic is a webcomic doesn't quite work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean as a as a completely non webcomic artists.
Speaker 1: to me my perspective That's the genre that's it I Mean.
Speaker 1: I guess my perspective purely as a fan of webcomics and a friend of webcomic artists seems to be that the general webcomics panel Existed when webcomics were a new thing and people were like what's this all about.
Speaker 1: or oh my god my all the webcomic artists.
Speaker 1: I love her there, and it's just amazing and they can ask these questions and now it seems like it's just an unnecessary thing.
Speaker 1: like now Podcasting is kind of new and a podcasting panel Seems like it has a great draw.
Speaker 1: But two years from now if people are still doing generic podcasting panels They would be I think just as I don't want to use the word useless, but useless as generic webcomic panel.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, you think of it like if you were to have an anime convention.
Speaker 5: Just one panel that just says anime panel And that's it To explain to all the people coming to the anime convention what anime is.
Speaker 5: yes right exactly what influences?
Speaker 7: to watch anime Same thing and especially at a convention like kinetic on that seems to have made his claim to fame.
Speaker 7: being The webcomic friendly convention.
Speaker 0: having a generic webcomics panel seems kind of useless Because they've gotten away almost gotten away from the webcomic catering.
Speaker 0: They had the webcomic catering when they were doing the several panels grouping people together.
Speaker 0: now It's just the one big you know panel, but they invite all of us.
Speaker 0: Oh well.
Speaker 0: I live in Hartford.
Speaker 0: I Still want them to pay my plane fare.
Speaker 0: I'll drive to Bradley Airport have them swing me around in the air.
Speaker 0: land me get a cab right?
Speaker 1: No, you just go to the airport hang out in the lounge for four hours Grab you by the ankles, and I'll swing you around in the air.
Speaker 2: How's that?
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 0: I'd go to Connecticut for that Sexy.
Speaker 0: let's have you give me a band.
Speaker 4: I Actually had a brief conversation with with Matt Daigle the con chair of kinetic on earlier And he said that this year was a very strange year for scheduling Because a lot of people were either not showing up Friday Because they couldn't get off work Or they had to leave before Sunday even started so they could get back or something along those lines.
Speaker 4: So it was very strange To try to arrange things that I mean even guests that were showing up.
Speaker 4: We're asking questions through email of well if I buy a three-day pass do I get a discount if I'm not gonna be there Friday or something like that?
Speaker 4: and He he was very confused by it because they hadn't had this issue in other years And they could split things up across multiple days whereas in this convention It seemed like Saturday was the main King day.
Speaker 1: Well actually in terms of I mean I go to like every freaking convention now and in terms of the convention.
Speaker 1: I guess industry Smaller conventions are for most people a one-day affair and as we saw with the New York Comic Con debacle when it just collapsed under its own weight Because the fact that they didn't expect people to show up and everyone in the world showed up Saturday Unless a con is large like Katsu khan oda khan even kind of and kinetic on is getting there.
Speaker 1: They're very close to being the I guess big con category.
Speaker 1: that It's very.
Speaker 1: people won't take a vacation day from work to go to the con all three days And it really is economical to go one day.
Speaker 1: So all the cons that aren't an oda khan are having a huge problem with the fact that they have more people Saturday than and All the other days combined, but if they put programming on Friday a lot of people don't show up to it.
Speaker 1: I Don't know if there's an answer to that other than become a bigger con or that is a bigger problem.
Speaker 2: I think more for like the the fall and winter conventions as opposed to the summer conventions Friday programming.
Speaker 2: for obviously summer conventions don't aren't hassled as much because people are out of school.
Speaker 2: A couple of conventions are smart enough to start their programming on Friday at like five or six o'clock in the at night Because that's when people are out of work and out of school out of class.
Speaker 2: And I've gone through the lines.
Speaker 2: Yeah So it's it's seasonal size and I guess Look, I'm basically run out of questions.
Speaker 1: You guys want to wrap up I can.
Speaker 1: Well, you should come to our live show tomorrow at 10 in panel 4.
Speaker 0: I've actually just not too long ago figure out the pun of podcast Project.
Speaker 7: I had to tell him I think that's witty.
Speaker 5: I hated it.
Speaker 0: I hated the term before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem with it is that so many people, you know, they hear.
Speaker 1: Oh you have a radio show.
Speaker 1: I'm like, yeah It's a podcast.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I don't have an iPod broadcast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's awesome.
Speaker 0: Love technology, it's a pun a pun cast Uncast puns, I said again, I love puns.
Speaker 1: So I guess we'll wrap this up now with one fun question for everyone and then I'd like everyone to go around and once again introduce yourself and say what you do whether it's a web comic artist or or I don't know being a general narrative.
Speaker 1: Well, so What is your favorite movie ever?
Speaker 1: or and independent of that?
Speaker 1: What do you think is the best movie ever?
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 1: And then What you do and who you are.
Speaker 1: We'll start on this side of the room because Brian here is very excited.
Speaker 7: Carol is going to talk for three hours.
Speaker 5: Not only will he tell you what his favorite is.
Speaker 5: He'll tell you why.
Speaker 0: See if they match up best and favorite.
Speaker 0: no Hate your favorite movie.
Speaker 1: I know my favorite movies suck, but I understand that they suck and I love them.
Speaker 7: anyway I'm not allowed to play World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: No, you're not sucks.
Speaker 1: It does You are.
Speaker 4: so I have a hard time picking Of my favorite movie But I'd say that that one of the ones that's coming to mind off the bat is the Incredibles.
Speaker 4: That one really impressed me As opposed to one of the movies that I think is one of the best Even though it bored the heck out of me in places.
Speaker 4: 2001 was put together really really well.
Speaker 4: I last saw it several years ago, and so I don't necessarily have the The analysis and and and the strength of mind to really remember it But at the time I thought it was well put together.
Speaker 1: And of course, who are you and what do you do again?
Speaker 4: My name is Laram Lancaster and I feature in committee My favorite movie ever.
Speaker 1: I really can't I?
Speaker 1: I mean you can't name the name a. well, our favorite movie of mine has to be the imposters which is written and directed by Stanley Tucci because You know it I love you.
Speaker 1: But um, I Just I just think that the the movie is remarkably well put together and you know, just it's just fun.
Speaker 1: I just find it extremely fun.
Speaker 1: I think one of the best movies ever made Citizen Kane Cheers.
Speaker 1: Yes Because I it's just.
Speaker 1: I don't know just everything I. it's hard for me to put in probably into words Why I like it so much.
Speaker 1: I just do because I am NOT in the frame of mind to properly tell you right now Yes, you squared I I'm I'm cat.
Speaker 1: I really don't do anything, but I consider myself part of the genre.
Speaker 1: vous street team.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh Stay tuned for my panel on how to become as important as a webcomic artist without actually doing anything.
Speaker 6: That'll be a highly attended panel, um My perhaps my favorite movie of all time and I'm gonna get lambasted for this.
Speaker 6: I Love Last Samurai Tom Cruise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I said it.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 6: I I love this movie.
Speaker 6: I hate Tom Cruise as a person But I think he's a good actor and even like the movie despite the fact that it started.
Speaker 6: white man is the last samurai.
Speaker 7: Everyone a gaijin was the last person standing at the last battle.
Speaker 0: white men are immune to machine guns.
Speaker 6: Brian Carroll, I hate you, but But what?
Speaker 6: perhaps perhaps one of the best movies of all time in my opinion was the usual suspects.
Speaker 6: because yeah
Speaker 1: As Brian
Speaker 6: brought up as Brian brought up I love the unreliable narrator I love the idea that you you can't trust the person telling the story and at the end of the movie you feel like you Haven't learned anything like the whole movie was just a waste of time almost Well, no, no, not a waste of
Speaker 1: time,
Speaker 6: but
Speaker 1: but it was
Speaker 6: all a lie.
Speaker 4: Yeah, it was all a lie.
Speaker 0: You don't know if it's true or not.
Speaker 1: spoilers by the way for the usual suspects.
Speaker 1: Oh shit Okay, so I don't take So.
Speaker 6: I don't take up any more of anyone's time.
Speaker 6: My name is Conrad.
Speaker 6: I have again I have no discernible skills or talents.
Speaker 6: I'm part of c-squared with cat and we pretend like we're important.
Speaker 6: And he's also a member of the genre food street team kind of I call it the genre food pit crew But nobody likes that.
Speaker 3: suck a punk.
Speaker 5: Yeah I'm really impressed.
Speaker 5: you guys got in on this.
Speaker 5: I really am.
Speaker 5: you guys have got to run this panel on how to become important without doing anything.
Speaker 6: So sorry to everybody listening something.
Speaker 0: and then you can't Paris Hilton of webcomics Have a drive a car into an Olympic to an Oscar party pool.
Speaker 6: I Stole a popular webs comics car a webcomic artists car.
Speaker 6: one time does that count?
Speaker 7: Who mine?
Speaker 7: whoops Wait you mean I gave you the keys to my car.
Speaker 1: yeah You Still have my car keys.
Speaker 1: yes Why not?
Speaker 6: C squared ain't nothing to fuck with?
Speaker 5: um Right.
Speaker 5: so back onto the topic of favorite movie and the best one.
Speaker 5: I Am NOT the person to answer this question Like I was.
Speaker 5: no I can't.
Speaker 5: I like too many movies Tonight tonight, I'm going wait.
Speaker 5: no oh right right To my my good friend Brian my favorite movie at this particular moment in time is in fact Constantine.
Speaker 5: if for no other reason because I have your cancer The one plot point I needed explained to me.
Speaker 0: that wasn't the only thing that movie.
Speaker 0: that wasn't explained.
Speaker 5: I don't know how you missed it man, but we're gonna have to watch.
Speaker 0: The whole movie was full of explanations.
Speaker 5: Oh Yeah, so Constantine yeah that Favorite movie at this particular moment.
Speaker 5: the next moment might be something as silly as like I robot followed Possibly by you like singing in the rain.
Speaker 5: you knows Moses supposes you.
Speaker 5: Moses supposes his toes as a roses.
Speaker 5: Correct as Odd as that is.
Speaker 5: um and once again.
Speaker 5: I am Garth Graham I am the artist and creator of the webcomic community, and I came late to this conversation much to my chagrin Wish you may is not actually taking place in some sort of fancy studio.
Speaker 1: It is in one of our hotel rooms Laundry everywhere.
Speaker 2: My favorite movie ever made is the adventures of Baron munchausen by Terry Gilliam.
Speaker 2: It's such a wonderful fantasy that just eschews most all reality and just tells the and tells of the immense power of Storytelling even if it's a total lie.
Speaker 2: But who knows I just love Baron munchausen for the adventure that it takes me on and that I just can leave reality behind.
Speaker 2: One of the best movies.
Speaker 2: I think ever made was the Iron Giant.
Speaker 2: If you had a small bit of clapping at I that movie is such a tearjerker even though It's not a very sad ending.
Speaker 2: I cried.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah, I cry.
Speaker 2: I think every time I watch a movie I cry a little earlier into the movie, so I think eventually I'll just cry with a opening credits roll It to you, and you'll start yeah, or just say Mookie the Iron Joe.
Speaker 7: oh Hey, I get Mookie's mic this time.
Speaker 7: Oh you you didn't tell what you do as if no one doesn't.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 2: I don't like to brag.
Speaker 1: Oh My guys are so they money.
Speaker 2: I am Kazu.
Speaker 2: so say my name is Mookie.
Speaker 2: I am the writer and artist of Dominick Deegan Oracle for hire.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 7: at this particular moment in time with my whimsical nature my favorite movie has to be everything is illuminated Which is which is an excellent excellent film with excellent excellent music if you ever ever have the chance to see it I. it's a very really really whimsical movie, and I kind of love it to death, and it's beautifully shot and Probably I Because I'm dating Brian Carroll.
Speaker 7: I have to say citizen Kane is the best movie ever made.
Speaker 7: but But in my personal opinion.
Speaker 7: I think That in my world the best movie ever made is wings of desire Which I don't think anyone in this room has seen except for myself.
Speaker 7: in retrospect It was actually a huge probably should have been a huge influence of my comic.
Speaker 7: It was eventually made into a horrible horrible American remake called City of Angels which I hope none of you have seen.
Speaker 7: I hate Nicolas Cage.
Speaker 1: oh God think of the good old song Oh What oh is that you'd let me keep going.
Speaker 1: I eventually would have done something.
Speaker 1: it was somewhat like that song almost No, I don't believe you.
Speaker 1: well It would have been as close as my voice is gonna get after three days of shouting at all of my friends.
Speaker 7: Wings of desire.
Speaker 7: it's a beautiful beautiful movie.
Speaker 5: I Have this horrible curse of filling in everything that movies or stories or books or anything leaves out.
Speaker 5: so I take I go I go Like latch on to the parts those shining jewels in all the crap that I that are awesome And I build up what should have been instead of what is and I ignore that.
Speaker 5: So I think I would actually really really like this movie that I did not know City of Angels was based on as City of Angels was actually kind of enjoyable.
Speaker 4: actually I have seen it.
Speaker 4: They showed it.
Speaker 4: they showed it to us in architecture so that we would know Where that movie came from because they had a film series that they were showing us great classics And that was one of them.
Speaker 7: It was made like the 80s.
Speaker 1: Well not to rush you but garage band for anyone who doesn't use max is Somewhat terrible and we don't have more than about 10 more minutes of recording before it arbitrarily decides to stop.
Speaker 0: I can make this fast By the way, I'm.
Speaker 7: I do From the forums.
Speaker 7: you probably may or may not know who I am.
Speaker 7: I've been mentioned on geek nights a couple of times.
Speaker 7: I do a comic that nobody should read called fallen You shut up.
Speaker 4: I Would like to apologize to Brian before he starts my knowledge of movies.
Speaker 4: I probably have watched fewer movies in my lifetime than he watches in a month.
Speaker 4: So when I talk about movies I know and favorite things.
Speaker 4: I'm sorry Brian.
Speaker 0: I passed no judgment on you.
Speaker 0: The best movie ever made hands down and I can argue this point by counterpoint is Citizen Kane by Orson Welles 1941.
Speaker 5: The even tastier when they're when you're dead.
Speaker 0: that is a quote that no one should know without knowing Who is saying who's being parodied on that?
Speaker 0: I know a lot of people do.
Speaker 0: My favorite movies of all time, however are listed in no particular order Citizen Kane the most dangerous game.
Speaker 0: Metropolis the original metropolis Fritz Lang not the anime remake, which I've never seen.
Speaker 0: Rashomon and usual suspects.
Speaker 0: Stranger is a great movie But it's not one of my favorites.
Speaker 0: F for fake is another going by Orson Welles and also touch of evil But we're small.
Speaker 0: and another favorite a lot of them come from different decades which I'm trying to keep with a theme if I were to make a top 10 list.
Speaker 0: But those are my favorite movies.
Speaker 0: everyone go see Citizen Kane.
Speaker 0: it is a jewel of the cinema.
Speaker 0: Back to the future is my childhood.
Speaker 0: Also, I've got to give I will say that I have to give a shout out to Robert Zemeckis Even though I don't like the movies he's making now.
Speaker 0: Back to the future is a wonderful wonderful franchise.
Speaker 0: I like them all equally.
Speaker 1: Excellent, and of course who you are what you do.
Speaker 0: Hi, I'm Brian Carroll.
Speaker 0: I consider myself the curator of instant classic.
Speaker 7: He hates all your favorite movies.
Speaker 0: I'm Brian Carroll, and I hate all your favorite movies And that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 3: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 3: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 3: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 3: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 3: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 3: It's actually recorded at night.