Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, May 9th, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we drop the bob-omb and bring you our coverage of E3.
Speaker 1: Let's do this!
Speaker 0: This morning, I pulled my car into the parking lot at work, and I see something.
Speaker 1: It wasn't E3, was it?
Speaker 0: No, it was not E3.
Speaker 0: And I saw it out of the corner of my eye, and it took like a full like 10 seconds for me to go.
Speaker 0: "hah-wah-hah-wah,".
Speaker 0: and I looked again, and yeah, there's a Ferrari in the parking lot at work.
Speaker 1: Which one?
Speaker 0: It's an F430, it looks like to me.
Speaker 1: Huh.
Speaker 0: And I was like, huh, what's that doing there?
Speaker 1: You should have jacked it.
Speaker 0: I don't know how.
Speaker 1: I don't know, you get into it, and you hotwire it, and then you jack it.
Speaker 0: It's not that easy.
Speaker 0: It's a Ferrari.
Speaker 0: It's not like, you know, jacking a freaking Hyundai on the street.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I took two pictures of it, and they're on my Flickr.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott messaged me at work and says, "Hey, there's a Ferrari
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 0: I don't know who it belonged to, it drove away when I wasn't looking, and it's not like one of those V12s that you can hear when it leaves the parking lot, so.
Speaker 0: And I was kind of in the building, so.
Speaker 1: All I could think of was a moment at Otacon this previous year, where everyone else, they were all standing in line, Scott and the whole front-reel crew, waiting to get their badges.
Speaker 1: I already had my badge, because, you know, I got in free, and I didn't have to do anything.
Speaker 1: So I was walking back to the hotel room with a, "Fuck you guys, I'm gonna take a Nat
Speaker 1: deal.".
Speaker 1: And on my way back, I get a call from Scott.
Speaker 0: You get a call, like, right after you leave us.
Speaker 1: I'm around the corner.
Speaker 0: You're with us, and you walk around the corner, and then I see a red hotiroku.
Speaker 1: So he calls me, and he's like, "There's a red
Speaker 1: hotiroku.".
Speaker 1: And I stop, and I look, and then it comes around the corner and drives past me, and I go, "Yeah, I just saw it,
Speaker 1: cool.".
Speaker 1: And then, apparently, everyone around them was like, "What the hell?
Speaker 1: He called his friend to tell him there was a
Speaker 1: hotiroku?".
Speaker 0: Yeah!
Speaker 0: Fuck yeah!
Speaker 0: So, um, that's the last thing we're gonna talk about on today's show that is not E3 related.
Speaker 0: Weeeee!
Speaker 0: And we're not gonna refrain from making too many Wii jokes.
Speaker 1: Wii 3!
Speaker 0: I can't wait to hold the Wii, to get the Wii in my hands.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna hold it, I'm gonna swing it around, hopefully I won't put anyone's eye out.
Speaker 0: Okay, so news.
Speaker 1: Alright, so in the news, we have some E3 news, obviously.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: The entire rest of the world outside of California just stopped, and everyone stood in place, while E3 went on, so nothing else happened at all.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, considering that we're probably going to talk at length about Sony, Microsoft, and Nintendo.
Speaker 0: So everyone knows, this podcast might be really, really long.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Longer than most geek nights, and most other podcasts, actually.
Speaker 0: So, be prepared to listen for a while.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna split it up into three separate ones.
Speaker 0: We're giving it to you all in one go.
Speaker 1: Which is gonna be great three weeks from now, and we have nothing to do on a Tuesday.
Speaker 0: I know, no.
Speaker 0: Next Tuesday we'll probably take care of all the other E3 tidbits that come out during the show, because the actual show doesn't start until tomorrow.
Speaker 0: This is just the three major press conferences we're talking about.
Speaker 0: And then the week after that, we'll probably have the new Mario Bros.
Speaker 0: for the DS, and we'll talk about that.
Speaker 0: Tuesday, not the Monday.
Speaker 0: So we'll be good.
Speaker 1: But since we're gonna cover Nintendo, Microsoft, and Sony in the main bits, we're gonna cover some non-Microsoft Sony/Nintendo news.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Now, you all know Red Octane.
Speaker 1: They are famous for their Bimani stuff.
Speaker 0: Well, they were originally coming to rent video games sort of a Netflix style, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they weren't that successful, but I signed up for them.
Speaker 0: Do they still do that at all?
Speaker 1: I don't actually know.
Speaker 0: I don't think they do.
Speaker 1: All I know is that way, way back, when I was a freshman in college, Red Octane was around, and I wanted to get import games for the PS1 that I had just bought.
Speaker 0: I know, Red Octane still has Game Rental.
Speaker 1: Oh, cool.
Speaker 0: Netflix style, yeah.
Speaker 1: Because when I had them, they were actually really good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Red Octane is a game rental company, but what they eventually did is they sold DDR pads.
Speaker 1: Well, what happened is that they sold a couple of DDR things, and they sold, like, accessories for PlayStation games, in addition to having the rental system.
Speaker 1: I guess they noticed that, far and away, the only people who signed up with them got the import games, and far and away, people wanted all the DDRs that weren't in the US.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was the-- Red Octane.
Speaker 0: somehow, by chance, in making a game rental service, and selling dance pads, became the easiest and best place to get DDR equipment.
Speaker 0: if you were a DDR fan.
Speaker 0: So when DDR exploded, Red Octane got the green.
Speaker 1: Because back then, we didn't have any DDRs.
Speaker 1: So I signed up for Red Octane, and for a month, all I did was get various foreign DDRs, copy them with my Plex store, and then send them back immediately.
Speaker 0: That's a good way to go.
Speaker 1: I then quit my free trial one day before I would have had to pay.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: That's how I got every DDR, and we played them extensively.
Speaker 0: If you want to get every DDR for the PlayStation 1, sign up for Red Octane.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Red Octane became the premier place for DDRs and stuff.
Speaker 1: They make the best non-cobalt flux blue pads you can get.
Speaker 0: So then they got into the business of making DDR pads.
Speaker 1: Which was extremely lucrative.
Speaker 1: Their soft pad is awesome.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend it to anyone who likes DDR.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you're really hardcore, you can get the hard pad.
Speaker 1: So then, Guitar Hero.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they said, "Hey, we're doing really well.
Speaker 0: Let's actually make some
Speaker 0: games.".
Speaker 0: So they made In the Groove, and In the Groove 2.
Speaker 1: Which are kind of terrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, In the Groove 2 is good.
Speaker 0: Eh.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you're probably-- Where'd you change your mind?
Speaker 1: No, they're great, but they're just-- They've got some gimmicks in them.
Speaker 1: They're not that easy to find.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: Anyway, then they made Guitar Hero.
Speaker 0: 'Cause they was, you know, keep going with the Bimani deal.
Speaker 1: Guitar Hero was the sleeper hit, for anyone who doesn't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think everyone knows about Guitar Hero.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Guitar Hero is at every con now.
Speaker 1: It's as ubiquitous as DDR used to be at the early cons.
Speaker 0: Well, 'cause they think they was guitar freaks, but no one really got into it.
Speaker 0: And I think Red Octane had a bunch of Guitar Freaks guitars lying around.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's the same guitar used in Guitar Hero or not, but-- Well, people really got into Guitar Freaks.
Speaker 1: The problem was, it was hard to get.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So Red Octane made Guitar Hero, and they made it real accessible.
Speaker 1: Anyway, to make a long, long, long story short, before we go any further on the history of Red Octane, they just got done bought out by Activision.
Speaker 0: Yep, Activision just bought Red Octane, just ch-ching!
Speaker 1: Straight up and suddenly, and they announced it today.
Speaker 0: So, what does this mean for Red Octane?
Speaker 0: Not much.
Speaker 0: They're gonna let Red Octane keep doing its business, 'cause it's doing good business.
Speaker 1: Activision doesn't do such good business, so if Activision decided to screw with Red Octane, that's the end.
Speaker 0: Yep, so Red Octane's gonna keep doing its good business.
Speaker 0: They're gonna put the Activision label, obviously, on future Red Octane games, maybe help Red Octane out by publishing the games with Activision's mighty publishing powers, but-- I'm not worried that any trouble will come of it, because if it does, the internet will explode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one's gonna let anything happen to good ol' Red Octane.
Speaker 1: So, uh, is there any other non-Nintendo Sony/Microsoft news?
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's also DDR-related.
Speaker 0: There's going to be, according to Konami and their press conference that happened just now, um, there's going to be a DDR television show.
Speaker 1: We're not sure just yet what this entails.
Speaker 0: There's going to be a live, live television show based on Dance Dance Revolution.
Speaker 0: The name of the show will be called Dance Revolution.
Speaker 1: Gasp!
Speaker 0: It'll be on CBS this fall.
Speaker 0: Um, I'm not sure-- But I see torrents of the first episode and a Geek Nights episode talking about the first episode of the show.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure what it could be.
Speaker 1: I mean, I could see them having, like, songs of the day or songs of the week that they show on screen and show people dance, they get cool people to dance 'em, and then maybe they're gonna sell the songs they show on the show on the Xbox 360 over the internet thingy.
Speaker 0: I could see it being a game show.
Speaker 0: I could see it being a kids' show.
Speaker 0: I could see it being an instructional show.
Speaker 1: A tournament show.
Speaker 1: A workout-type show.
Speaker 0: A game show.
Speaker 0: A workout show.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: It could be a bunch of different things.
Speaker 0: But whatever it is, I'm gonna be looking out for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though we don't play DDR so much anymore.
Speaker 0: No, but we would if it didn't shake our house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sad, but the floor--our house is great--but the floor does not stand up to 250 to 170 pound men jumping up and down repeatedly.
Speaker 0: Yep, uh, that's why we need a basement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or we could just, you know, go to the arcade, but you never wanna go.
Speaker 0: It's too much money.
Speaker 0: I paid for the stupid pad.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna pay for the arcade.
Speaker 1: What, the pad you can't use?
Speaker 1: You might as well just play in the arcade.
Speaker 0: No, I'm paying twice.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: So, things of the day.
Speaker 1: I got one little bit.
Speaker 1: It's obviously from E3.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's hard to find a thing of the day from E3.
Speaker 0: I mean, I may find some remix videos somewhere, but they haven't been finished yet, so you're gonna have to give me another few days on those.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so basically, I just wanted to take something--something that happened at E3 that I wouldn't have talked about any other place, really.
Speaker 1: Now, Kotaku had this, and they noticed, and I've noticed that many other people reporting on E3 have said something similar.
Speaker 1: As far as anyone can say, no one other than Sony had PSPs at E3.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: No one saw anyone playing one.
Speaker 1: They did, however, see that almost every line, almost every waiting room, almost every lobby was filled with people playing wireless, Tetris, or wireless whatnot on the DS.
Speaker 0: Picked a chat.
Speaker 1: The DS pretty much dominated E3.
Speaker 1: Almost everyone had one.
Speaker 0: Well, because the thing about the PSP is it's a one-man show.
Speaker 0: If you take out a PSP, you're all--you know, even if everyone else around you has a PSP, you can't do anything with them.
Speaker 0: You're all alone.
Speaker 1: It's like-- Well, there are games that use the wireless.
Speaker 1: They're just not very good.
Speaker 0: Are there really PSP games that use wireless to play with other people near you?
Speaker 1: Supposedly.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: What games are those?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know either.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, but-- The one guy I met at a con who had a PSP said there were.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 1: I didn't bother him about it.
Speaker 0: Well, even with the loading times and all that, I mean, it's a lot easier to get a game of Tetris together, especially when the--'cause the--there's no way the PSP games have the download play, where you don't need the cartridge or the UMD.
Speaker 1: Oh, no way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there you go.
Speaker 0: That's the answer.
Speaker 0: One guy has Tetris.
Speaker 0: Boom!
Speaker 0: Ten DSs come out.
Speaker 0: There.
Speaker 0: That's why--.
Speaker 1: Well, plus, honestly, the PSP just--the games it has seem to be the same games that the PlayStation 2 has.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's more news on that later.
Speaker 1: They're the kind of games that you sit down and just play.
Speaker 1: You can't play that with people because you'll just be sitting there playing your GTA--.
Speaker 0: Not a lot, but not as many as a DS, but quite a few.
Speaker 0: The thing is, you don't bring them to social situations 'cause they're not useful in social situations.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only people who--the only time you see PSPs about in number are on, like, subways and commuter trains.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you see a PSP when you see, you know, an iPod or something.
Speaker 0: Someone's on a train.
Speaker 0: Someone's--a kid sitting in the back of a car.
Speaker 0: That's when you see a PSP.
Speaker 1: Of course, you see the DSs there, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 'cause the DS does that, and it's good at the cons and all that stuff, so... Alright, my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: At the Nintendo conference, you might have remembered there was an AOL contest.
Speaker 0: And the contest was whoever--you just entered your name and whatnot at AOL, whatever.
Speaker 0: And if you won the contest, you would go onstage at E3 this morning, and you would be the first person who is not a developer or a whatnot.
Speaker 0: I keep saying whatnot today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what the hell.
Speaker 0: What the hell, yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, um, you so, uh, like, uh...
Speaker 0: Like, like whatnot, you know?
Speaker 0: The first consumer to use the Wii.
Speaker 1: We were all about that.
Speaker 1: I mean, I hate AOL.
Speaker 1: I hate online contests.
Speaker 1: I hate lotteries.
Speaker 1: I entered that contest.
Speaker 0: I entered the contest.
Speaker 0: I didn't win.
Speaker 1: Obviously.
Speaker 0: Apparently what happened was, it wasn't just one person.
Speaker 0: Three people won the trip out to E3, and they were all sitting at the Nintendo conference.
Speaker 0: One of the three was randomly picked by Miyamoto.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was randomly or not, but they said, I guess he picked out of a hat, or they had a card with the name on it.
Speaker 0: Sort of like the Oscars.
Speaker 0: And there were three kids there, and they were both 20-something guys, which is kinda--or they looked like 20-something guys.
Speaker 1: Both?
Speaker 1: I--weren't there three?
Speaker 0: There were three.
Speaker 1: You said both.
Speaker 1: Both implies two.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: You suck.
Speaker 0: All three of them looked like schmucky guys, but one guy was a real fat bleh guy, and another guy was a slightly fat bleh guy.
Speaker 1: Fat like the, uh, scary fanboy from club back in the day.
Speaker 0: who-- Fat like, I was like, God, like, you know what I'm saying, like-- Like Mr.
Speaker 1: Earlobes, who we won't actually name on the air.
Speaker 0: They were fat in a way--he was fat in a way where I said to myself, God, I hope he doesn't win so I don't have to look at him anymore.
Speaker 0: So the fat guy who didn't get to go on stage at E3 and use the Wii is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Way to go, fat guy.
Speaker 1: I can see Miyamoto sitting there in his head, he's like, I can't pick that kid.
Speaker 1: He'll break the stage.
Speaker 0: They picked the best looking guy from my cursory glance at the three fools.
Speaker 1: You know what, to anyone out there who, you know, inner beauty and all, but in the real world, looks count.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one's gonna pick you to go on stage at their very important press conference if you're a fat, ugly schmuck.
Speaker 1: Or you've got like nine eyes and six fingers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, watch, this fat guy is a Geek Nights listener, he'd be like, hey, that was me!
Speaker 0: And he's actually a cool guy or something.
Speaker 1: You know what, if you're that guy and you listen right now, we'll put you on the air and apologize.
Speaker 0: Well, I won't apologize for calling you fat, I'll just apologize for calling you a schmuck.
Speaker 0: Maybe you're not a schmuck, but you're fat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, do something about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you might want to exercise or something.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's start talking about our favorite current existing system, the Nintendo DS.
Speaker 1: It is my primary gaming console currently.
Speaker 0: As it is mine, and there are no signs that it will fade.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, the other day, for whatever reason, I pulled out Advance Wars and I started playing it again.
Speaker 1: And I remembered that, oh yeah, every game I've bought for this system so far, except WarioWare Touched, has been badass.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep, if WarioWare Touched had multiplayer, it would be badass.
Speaker 0: And hopefully a new WarioWare DS will come out, but one wasn't announced at E3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, however, we got the revolution Wii one, but...
Speaker 0: We're gonna get to that.
Speaker 0: We will.
Speaker 0: Don't spoil things.
Speaker 0: Oh, I just want to say, before we start going here, we're not here on Gig Nights to inform you.
Speaker 0: We are not the news story that tells you what happened at E3.
Speaker 0: We are the Slashdot comments under that story.
Speaker 1: Yes, we're not even gonna link to a lot of the things we talk about, because it's everywhere.
Speaker 0: So, here's some hints.
Speaker 0: Number one, go to E3buzz.com.
Speaker 0: E. the number three buzz dot com.
Speaker 0: Basically, they took all the RSS feeds of all the major video game news sites and combined them into one site, so you can watch what goes down at E3 in real time.
Speaker 1: I pretty much just had it open all day.
Speaker 0: I had it open, and I used the Reload Every Firefox plugin.
Speaker 0: Go to GameSpot dot com, they have good stuff.
Speaker 0: Read Kotaku and Joystiq.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you want a good summary, like you just want an overview of the things worth noting, Kotaku is probably your best bet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Kotaku and Gadget has good stuff when it comes to hardware.
Speaker 0: You know, they partner with Joystiq as the same company.
Speaker 0: They have really good live blogs at the press conferences.
Speaker 0: So, you'll get some information from listening to us talk, but we're not gonna give you the full lowdown.
Speaker 0: We're gonna give you the commentary and what we say about stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically just reactions.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: DS.
Speaker 0: The DS Lite, which we already kind of knew this, but they announced it for 100% real.
Speaker 0: On June 11th of this year, for $130, you can get a DS Lite in the USA.
Speaker 1: Now, never in my life have I fallen to that "ooh, the console you just bought came out again slightly shinier, buy it" mentality.
Speaker 0: I didn't even buy the Game Boy SP.
Speaker 0: I still don't own one.
Speaker 0: I use the regular old GBA for, you know.
Speaker 0: Now I kind of think maybe I'll get an SP because I have some old Game Boy and Game Boy Color games that I can play on it.
Speaker 0: And I kind of want to buy up some used Game Boy Color and Game Boy games to play on it.
Speaker 0: And it's also good because we'll still probably use it for the GameCube uplink.
Speaker 0: You know, especially if we want to play the old FFCC or Four Swords on the Wii.
Speaker 0: With the backwards, you know, because they have GameCube holes on the Wii, you can still do that.
Speaker 0: You can play Pac-Man vs.
Speaker 0: on the Wii.
Speaker 0: Oh boy.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I'll probably get an SP when they're like super mega cheap.
Speaker 1: But I gotta say, I'm really thinking about getting the DS Lite.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: If there's a really, really good trade-in deal.
Speaker 0: Like, if you give us your DS, we'll give you a DS Lite for 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'll do that.
Speaker 0: But if the trade-in deal's kind of shitty, like they don't give me enough for my DS, I'm gonna give them the finger.
Speaker 0: And then what I'll do is I'll wait for my DS to like die.
Speaker 0: And this, where the touchscreen is busted and the screens are starting to fade.
Speaker 0: Then I'll go and I'll just buy a DS Lite with cash and maybe give my DS to someone else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm really thinking of just buying a DS Lite, giving my DS to someone.
Speaker 1: Probably Emily if she wants it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you really just want a DS Lite and you really want to give a DS to Emily so you can play with her.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Twofer.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The only drawback, and I don't want to harp on this because we've talked about it before, is the fact that the GBA slot is a little smaller.
Speaker 0: That really kind of makes me sad because I just bought the cool Rumble Pak and it's gonna stick out.
Speaker 1: The Rumble Pak is kind of dick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think if more games start to use it, I'm gonna want it.
Speaker 1: It is not a Rumble Pak.
Speaker 1: It does not rumble in an effective manner.
Speaker 1: It does, however, act as a subwoofer.
Speaker 1: If you play Princess Peach and you put the Rumble Pak in, it uses it to make music and it's kind of cool.
Speaker 1: It's really loud too.
Speaker 0: I think that if more games start to use it, I'm gonna want to have it in there.
Speaker 0: But as it is right now, it's a give or take type of thing.
Speaker 1: I just like having the GBA game in there as kind of a backup game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's always good too.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy Tactics Advance and, I don't know, Princess Peach, so I can switch it up.
Speaker 0: But the other thing is that if maybe I'll get an SP when they're really cheap, then I'll use that because it's a little smaller and more comfortable to hold for that type of game than the DS is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the batteries last longer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they charge on the same wire.
Speaker 0: So maybe I'll get an SP for GBA in the old games and just use my DS for DS games only.
Speaker 1: Or, honestly, I might just buy a Micro.
Speaker 0: Oh, Micro, that's a good plan too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because when Evan was up and we saw it, the Micro screen is really, really, really, really good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem with the Micro is that it only plays GBA games.
Speaker 0: It doesn't play the colors in the old games that I want to play.
Speaker 0: And it doesn't hook up so easily to the FFCCs and the...
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you get an SP, then I'll be fine with my Micro.
Speaker 0: That's true, that's true.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: So, let's go down the list of some of the DS games that we previously did not know about.
Speaker 0: that have been announced at E3.
Speaker 0: Most of these are gonna be Nintendo titles because that's the website I went to look at for the list.
Speaker 1: And those are the games we tend to care more about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, if you look at the DS games that I bought, the only really great ones that aren't Nintendo licenses are like Phoenix Wright, which is Capcom, and such.
Speaker 0: And I don't think Capcom had their conference yet, did they?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: I'll have to go tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go and look up and see what Capcom did and maybe I'll throw a news in tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 0: Okay, ready?
Speaker 0: Chibi-Robo for the DS.
Speaker 0: I've heard good things about the GameCube game.
Speaker 0: I'm sure the DS game will be more of the same.
Speaker 0: I haven't played it yet.
Speaker 0: Maybe I will when it's ultra-cheap.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's gonna be a buy-at-full-price game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got nothing to say about that game.
Speaker 0: Children of Mana.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: There have been a couple of Mana games, I think, for the GBA, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, if there were, I didn't pick them up.
Speaker 1: I played the, uh, once in a game.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think there was one for the PlayStation 2 that was like Tree of Mana or something like that.
Speaker 1: The only ones I ever played were SNES.
Speaker 0: And then there was like Sword of Mana.
Speaker 0: is the original, right?
Speaker 0: No, Secret of Mana is the original.
Speaker 0: So there was like Sword and Tree.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: Don't quote me on that.
Speaker 1: For anyone who doesn't know, they're the games that are walk-around hit guys, kinda like Final Fantasy, but more like...
Speaker 0: It's between Final Fantasy and Zelda.
Speaker 0: But the original, the thing about it is the original.
Speaker 0: SNES allowed three players to play together.
Speaker 1: If you had that special thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, two players could play together normally.
Speaker 0: And then the third person would just kinda hang off the edge.
Speaker 1: Which I'd actually never done this as a child, but now us and our friend Katsu have bit by bit been playing the game with the multiple player action.
Speaker 1: Also, uh, Final Fantasy Legend and Final Fantasy Adventure for the Game Boy.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy Adventure games are the same games as this.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They just rebranded them because Americans, they figured the name Final Fantasy would sell.
Speaker 0: I think people know what Secret of Mana is.
Speaker 0: Anyway, a new game in the Secret of Mana series called Children of Mana is gonna be on the DS.
Speaker 0: And I normally wouldn't be interested in this, cause I'm not only semi-interested in the GBA one, and not at all interested in the Playstation one.
Speaker 0: But it's gonna have that simultaneous, cooperative multiplayer action that the original Secret of Mana had.
Speaker 0: Because the DS is all wireless.
Speaker 0: So now I'm all about this game.
Speaker 1: Woo hoo!
Speaker 1: Yeah, because one, we've really been hurting for fun, cooperative games.
Speaker 0: Mhm.
Speaker 1: Two, I mean, games like that were fun on the consoles, except for the fact that you have one screen and multiple people who want to go in different directions, no matter what.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: The DS will allow that.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And it will be beautiful.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be something called Clubhouse Games, which looks like a bunch of card games like Rummy and Poker and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever, but if it was- Cause most people who are like casual gamers on computers and such, they mostly play like little crap card games and chess and checkers and backgammon and all that crap.
Speaker 1: Plus, honestly, if a game like that were ten bucks and allowed download play, I might just pick it up and throw it in the bag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, that way even a doofus, you know, can pick it up, play, uh, maybe it's got hearts in it.
Speaker 0: That'd be worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Hearts would be great on the DS.
Speaker 1: Especially since when I actually play hearts in person, we often forget to count the hearts.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, Custom Robo DS.
Speaker 1: I got Custom Robo- We disagree a little on this game.
Speaker 1: I say it's ass.
Speaker 0: It's not complete ass.
Speaker 1: It's mostly ass.
Speaker 0: It's mostly ass.
Speaker 0: Custom Robo is a game where there are a whole bunch of them in Japan, and from what I saw of them, especially the GBA version, it looked like an okay game where you customize a robot and then you fight in a kind of interesting combat.
Speaker 0: They finally brought out a GameCube Custom Robo, so I got it.
Speaker 0: It didn't live up to what I saw of the GBA one on the internet.
Speaker 1: The combat was just pretty poor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just, like, you customized your robot, and it was sort of a rock, paper, scissors, and whatever you chose, and everyone could see what you were choosing, and it wasn't so great.
Speaker 0: Not a lot of skill-based combat going on.
Speaker 1: And the single player, I still can't believe that you unlocked things in that game.
Speaker 1: I can't believe you played that horrible game.
Speaker 0: I played it all the way through once, I didn't play through the- you have to play through a second time to get the rest of the stuff.
Speaker 1: That game had some of the worst plot I've ever seen in a game.
Speaker 0: There wasn't- it's not much of a plot.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Custom Robo DS, I would get it if it looked more like the GBA stuff I remember seeing on the internet, but it looks pretty much just like the GameCube game, and the description is just like the GameCube game.
Speaker 0: Only the graphics are DS quality, so Custom Robo for DS, I'd avoid this.
Speaker 0: DK King of Swing DS.
Speaker 0: DK King of Swing was a GBA game where Donkey Kong would swing around doing stuff.
Speaker 0: I played it in a store for like a minute, and it was kind of boring and bleh.
Speaker 0: So I don't know why they're bringing out a DS version, maybe they can- Maybe it was- it must have been popular.
Speaker 0: Maybe they'll make it interesting because you'll swing DK using the stylus and all that.
Speaker 0: But, um, I don't know why this game is cool.
Speaker 0: If anyone knows why DK King of Swing is a good game, tell me.
Speaker 0: DS Air.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually see anything about this until it went to this one page on the Nintendo website.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of game that we don't have yet on the DS.
Speaker 0: It looks like a real fighter jet flight sim for the DS.
Speaker 0: Like, oh, there's an F-16, look at it go.
Speaker 1: The last good fighter jet game I've played was this thing for my 486.
Speaker 0: I just- we'll have to see more of this game, because it could be really bad and terrible to control the jet, but it also could be really awesome where you dogfight your friends with wireless.
Speaker 1: Well, there's also those, uh, flight games that Katsu always talks about for the PlayStation 2.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to pick up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those seem like one-player kind of bleh games to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they look fun, though.
Speaker 1: I want a game where I can fly a fighter jet, I haven't had a game like that in a long time.
Speaker 0: Microsoft Flight Simulator we'll talk about later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fuck you.
Speaker 0: Um, Elite Beat Agents.
Speaker 0: This looks like a beat kind of DDR game, but instead of dancing with your feet or anything, you kind of do the beat with the stylus.
Speaker 0: And from what I saw in the pictures, it was like, draw a circle, you know, move around to different positions on the beats, etc.
Speaker 0: So, it's like DDR for your stylus.
Speaker 0: It might be cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll have to see it.
Speaker 1: I'll definitely play it in a store before I actually play it.
Speaker 0: Alright, here's a really good game.
Speaker 0: Hotel Dusk Room 215.
Speaker 1: Alright, this game gives me the Phoenix Wright vibe.
Speaker 0: I saw the screenshots of this game and I said, "That's Phoenix Wright plus Deja Vu plus Pandora Directive Tex
Speaker 0: Murphy.".
Speaker 1: I think they've realized that, because for anyone who isn't aware, games like Phoenix Wright, you know, the very text-heavy adventure games, is a genre of gaming that's huge in Japan.
Speaker 0: Huge.
Speaker 1: And never really made it over here.
Speaker 0: Not at all.
Speaker 1: Even though there were hundreds of them, like for Nintendo and Super Nintendo and computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, these kind of adventure games are mostly, there's a bunch of text telling you a story, and you either have to solve a puzzle to continue and get the rest of the story, or you can slightly choose your own adventure a little bit and get the rest of the story.
Speaker 0: And that, the choose your own adventure ones are a little better because that way you play it multiple times to get all the endings.
Speaker 1: Yep, some of them are really, really advanced with crazy branching stories.
Speaker 0: Some of them have puzzles and choose your own adventure.
Speaker 0: Those are the best ones.
Speaker 0: This, I can't tell, but it looks like it has some puzzling.
Speaker 0: And all the characters look like someone drew them in a manga and then cut them out with a scissor.
Speaker 0: Which is really cool.
Speaker 1: I think they've realized, I mean Phoenix Wright was kind of a risk.
Speaker 1: No one really knew how the American market would end.
Speaker 0: Everyone knew that was gonna, I knew.
Speaker 1: Well, no one in the industry knew.
Speaker 1: They were like, "Will people play games like
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 0: Hells yes.
Speaker 1: Well, considering that Phoenix Wright sold out and was re-released, I have a feeling that this game is going to be the start of a torrent of similar games.
Speaker 0: Indeed.
Speaker 0: So, this game looks like Phoenix Wright, but maybe a little better, maybe a little worse, a little more serious.
Speaker 1: Looks a lot of detective action.
Speaker 0: I'll probably pick it up right away because it probably disappeared just like Phoenix Wright did and I don't want to risk not having it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a Kirby DS.
Speaker 0: There's already a Canvas Curse, we know.
Speaker 0: This is not a Canvas Curse.
Speaker 0: This looks like a real Kirby game, like Kirby's Adventure and Kirby's Dream Land.
Speaker 0: I didn't like the Kirby Magic Mirror for the GBA.
Speaker 0: It was too non-linear and hard to figure out what the hell to do.
Speaker 0: Hopefully this one isn't like that.
Speaker 0: It's more, hopefully it's more like Kirby's Adventure, which is the best Kirby game ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really have to agree on that.
Speaker 1: I was playing it the other day.
Speaker 0: You were playing Kirby's Adventure?
Speaker 1: Yeah, on my computer.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Kirby's Adventure rules.
Speaker 0: If you haven't played Kirby's Adventure for the NES, you gots to play that.
Speaker 0: If you don't have an emulator or whatever, you can get Kirby Something Nightmare for the GBA.
Speaker 0: It's the exact same game, pretty much.
Speaker 0: So, get that.
Speaker 0: Legend of Zelda Phantom Hour class.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think we talked about it already.
Speaker 1: At least mention that it's coming out.
Speaker 0: I think it's pretty obvious.
Speaker 0: Everyone buy it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Even though the Minish Cap was kind of blah, I don't think this will be that.
Speaker 0: This won't be that.
Speaker 0: Because even if it's blah, like Minish Cap, it's going to have the touch screen action, which makes it all good.
Speaker 1: Usually.
Speaker 0: Solving Zelda puzzles with a touch screen.
Speaker 0: You can give me one touch screen Zelda puzzle and I'm set.
Speaker 0: I'll give you 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: An RPG named Magical Vacation.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to say about it.
Speaker 0: It's an RPG.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: I think it might have some sort of multiplayer something, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: There wasn't enough information about it.
Speaker 1: Of course RPGs, we do know that on the GBA we're getting Final Fantasy V and VI.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep, yep.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of excited.
Speaker 1: Because Final Fantasy IV for the GBA was great.
Speaker 1: It let me play through the game of my childhood without the annoyance of playing through the game of my childhood exactly as it was.
Speaker 0: I'll let you buy all those and then I'll play them as I want.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Goddamn monitor keeps turning off.
Speaker 0: Alright, you might know of this Flash game you can play on the internet called Zuma.
Speaker 0: It's kind of popular.
Speaker 0: A lot of people pay for it and have it on their cell phones.
Speaker 0: It's been quite profitable for everyone who's been involved in it.
Speaker 1: I'd actually never heard of it.
Speaker 0: I only played it once when it came out and then I saw people playing it around.
Speaker 0: It's, you know, nowadays these casual little tiny games that you put on a Flash website and you charge people like 5 bucks for a real download.
Speaker 0: Like that Diner Dash, they made a bunch of money off that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: You know, and all those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of money in that business.
Speaker 0: Cell phone games.
Speaker 0: Zuma is one that kind of hit it big where these balls go in a spiral and you kind of grab the balls and match up the colors.
Speaker 0: I'm not exactly sure how it's played.
Speaker 1: In terms of gameplay, I don't like these games.
Speaker 0: I don't like these games so much either.
Speaker 1: They're very much not a matter of skill so much as a matter of once you know how to play you can pretty much keep playing forever.
Speaker 0: Well the games are, they serve the same role as Sudoku does.
Speaker 0: It's just busy work, you know, for mindless people to do with their hands.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Occupy your mind and kill time.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: You mustn't kill time, boy.
Speaker 0: So they're going to put out Zuma for the DS but they're not calling it Zuma probably because they don't want to get sued.
Speaker 0: They're calling it Magnetica.
Speaker 0: And you'll probably be able to control the game with a touch screen.
Speaker 0: This is another game that all the people who buy brain training and clubhouse games can get on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a game to buy your mommy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Next to her Nintendogs.
Speaker 0: Mario 3 on 3 Basketball DS.
Speaker 1: I saw some bits about this and I'm really excited.
Speaker 0: Like, I said like, I don't like basketball games.
Speaker 0: Well I like NBA Jam.
Speaker 1: I never even liked NBA Jam.
Speaker 0: Oh I love NBA Jam Tournament Edition for the Sega Genesis.
Speaker 0: That was a good basketball game.
Speaker 0: Double Dribble was a good basketball game.
Speaker 0: Every other basketball game except maybe Jordan vs.
Speaker 0: Bird but I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: But every other basketball game, not good.
Speaker 0: Very not good.
Speaker 1: I mean all the new basketball games really seem to go for the "look how realistically we emulated the sweat on this player that you're supposed to know is named
Speaker 1: Space.".
Speaker 0: We have all the right tattoos and all the right players.
Speaker 0: We're so hip-hoppin'.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Not much game there.
Speaker 0: This looks like it could be a really fun Mario sports game.
Speaker 0: If we learned anything from Mario Soccer which we still have to get but it's still 50 bucks and it's only worth about 35 bucks.
Speaker 1: Well there's a reason it's still 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And if we learned anything from Mario Tennis and Mario Baseball and Mario Golf, Mario 3 on 3 Basketball is going to be a good time.
Speaker 0: Six people with DS's playing basketball.
Speaker 0: This is going to be good stuff.
Speaker 1: Because all these games, it's like they take a sports game, the sport itself, but they abstract it to where you can play it in a fun way like as a video game but it's still recognizable as the sport.
Speaker 1: As opposed to the EA sports games which try to emulate the sport as perfectly as possible which usually makes a really shitty game.
Speaker 0: Okay, Mario vs Donkey Kong 2.
Speaker 0: I don't know if anyone else played Mario vs Donkey Kong but let me just tell the story of this game real quick.
Speaker 1: I actually have never played it.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 0: I'll give it to you.
Speaker 1: Have you ever played Donkey Kong 3?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the one where you use the bug spray.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right up Donkey Kong's ass.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 0: You make him climb up those bamboo sticks.
Speaker 0: Okay, back in the day for the Game Boy, the Game Boy, the Game Boy, there was a game called Donkey Kong.
Speaker 0: This was not just a replica of the original Donkey Kong.
Speaker 0: What it was, was you played the original Donkey Kong and after that there was this other game which involved Mario trying to navigate these dangerous levels to get a key and put it in a door and eventually at the end you got Donkey Kong.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I've ever played it all the way through but there were these complex puzzle platformers where it wasn't just, you know, like Mario Bros.
Speaker 0: You have to run fast, don't get hit by bad guys, don't fall in holes, and collect coins.
Speaker 0: It was, you know, solve the puzzle in order to get Mario through.
Speaker 0: You were still platforming walking and jumping and climbing ladders but you had to really think about how to get to the other side of the level by pushing blocks and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: They brought back this concept only recently with the game called Mario vs.
Speaker 0: Donkey Kong on the GBA where Mario has to navigate these dangerous levels in a platform puzzler and collect these present boxes and get a key and open a door.
Speaker 0: And then every few levels he has to get these mini Marios to follow him around the level and get them into like a treasure chest which is another difficult type of puzzle.
Speaker 0: And then after that Mario has to fight a boss which is another difficult type of puzzle but it's also mostly platforming with the bosses.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be, the first Mario vs.
Speaker 0: DK on the GBA was kind of fun and I wasn't sad for paying money for it.
Speaker 0: So if Mario vs.
Speaker 0: DK 2 for the DS can incorporate enough touchscreen awesome action to make the puzzles more fun or more difficult and interesting.
Speaker 0: And if it has enough puzzles, because this could be a game where it's really good but it's too short and it's not worth the money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kind of like Princess Peach which I really liked but now I'm at the end of the game and I'm just, I have no desire to beat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if this game is long enough it'll be worth your money to pay for it.
Speaker 0: If it's not long enough, just get the Game Boy 1 used and then get this one used a few years later.
Speaker 0: New Super Mario Brothers, we'll talk about that in two weeks when we get it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we all know this game is going to be awesome.
Speaker 1: I mean, right before E3 it's like there was no video game news except they kept releasing little bits about this game.
Speaker 0: On the official website they were releasing a video every few days and every time they released a video it got on dig.
Speaker 0: So, this game is going to be insane.
Speaker 0: I don't think you'll need to pre-order it but I do suggest you head over to your local game store on Tuesday or Wednesday.
Speaker 0: So a week from now and just grab this game the day it comes out or you'll be sorry.
Speaker 1: Now all told, the DS was exploding for a while.
Speaker 1: It's like double exploding now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, listen to all the things we're saying here.
Speaker 0: Look at all these DS games coming out.
Speaker 0: Whatever we're going to say about their other three major consoles, the PSP is dead and the DS is the king, holy crap.
Speaker 0: The PSP is dead as a gaming system really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a cool little piece of technology and we're really not trying to disparage our-.
Speaker 0: We'll still talk, there's some things to say about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not much.
Speaker 0: Not much.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Pokemon Mystery Dungeon Blue and Red.
Speaker 0: This looks like it's going to be a real Pokemon game which we haven't had in a while.
Speaker 1: So not just some sort of Pokemon puzzle bullshit?
Speaker 0: No, it's actually going to be a Pokemon RPG from the looks of it.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of curious because I've never actually played a Pokemon game.
Speaker 0: I'll give you Pokemon Red but you need to play it on a non-DS because it's a Game Boy game.
Speaker 1: I got my GBA.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Pokemon Mystery Dungeon Blue is going to be a DS game and Red is going to be a GBA game.
Speaker 0: So that's going to be kind of interesting.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's going to be some sort of, if you have them both in a DS, something happens.
Speaker 0: I'm almost positive that there's something going to happen trying to sell people both games.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: If I was going to get it, I would only get the blue one.
Speaker 0: But the point of this is that unlike the other previous Pokemon RPGs where you were a trainer and you collected Pokemon, in this one the plot seems to be that you were turned into a Pokemon.
Speaker 0: So now you're a Pokemon training other Pokemon but also yourself.
Speaker 0: So that should be interesting.
Speaker 0: There's also going to be a DS game called Pokemon Ranger.
Speaker 0: There isn't a lot of information about it but just screenshots.
Speaker 0: It looks like it's going to be Pokemon Stadium DS which is kind of bleh.
Speaker 0: Alright, you ready bitches?
Speaker 0: Motherfucking Star Fox DS.
Speaker 1: Woo!
Speaker 1: I'm all about that.
Speaker 0: I'm going to be flying my Arwing straight up your ass.
Speaker 1: Man, I remember when Star Fox came out for the SNES.
Speaker 0: That was fantastic.
Speaker 1: They kept hyping up how it was a new technological blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And whether you remember it or not, Star Fox 64 was the game that unveiled the Rumble Pak for the N64.
Speaker 0: And the multiplayer in that was nothing short of awesome.
Speaker 0: But Star Fox Adventure and Assault for the Gamecube have been moderately disappointing.
Speaker 0: Especially when compared to Star Fox 64 which is holy crap.
Speaker 0: So here's hoping that Star Fox DS brings back the Star Fox 64 and the SNES Star Fox that we once knew.
Speaker 1: I envision, I mean we don't know, but I envision various multiplayer co-op or competitive wireless actions.
Speaker 0: Oh if it has co-op, that's god damn.
Speaker 0: Four people trying to beat, oh that would be so great.
Speaker 1: If it can be me and my crew with women.
Speaker 0: Hey Nintendo people listening, co-op Star Fox.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd buy it.
Speaker 0: I'd buy it.
Speaker 1: We'd all buy it.
Speaker 0: Alright, you know that Tenchu Ninja whatever game?
Speaker 0: They're making a DS one, it looks kind of bleh.
Speaker 0: Yoshi's Island 2.
Speaker 0: They brought out every Mario game, well they brought out Mario 1, Super Mario Brothers.
Speaker 0: Mario Brothers, non-super.
Speaker 0: And the lost levels for the Game Boy Color.
Speaker 0: Then on the Game Boy Advance they brought out Doki Doki Panic Mario 2 USA.
Speaker 0: Mario 3, Mario World, and Yoshi's Island.
Speaker 1: I still gotta get that Mario 3.
Speaker 0: I gotta get that Mario 3.
Speaker 0: So now on the DS they're bringing out the one missing game, Yoshi's Island 2.
Speaker 0: Hooray.
Speaker 0: A lot of people seem to be really happy about that.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: A lot of people seem to like Yoshi's Island, I never played it that much, but supposedly some people consider Yoshi's Island to be like this amazing platformer of all time.
Speaker 0: I think I have to play it more to see what they're talking about.
Speaker 0: I've only played like the first few levels.
Speaker 1: I doubt it's better than Mario 3.
Speaker 0: Or Mario World.
Speaker 0: But it seems like it's just Mario World.
Speaker 0: but you can throw eggs.
Speaker 0: I gotta get to the later levels to see if there's anything I'm missing.
Speaker 0: And I'll play Yoshi's Island 2 to see what's up.
Speaker 0: And last on my DS list.
Speaker 0: FFCCDS.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: Now I know we've told the story, but Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles was an amazing game that we played straight through start to finish over the course of a weekend.
Speaker 0: It seems that the original Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles for the GameCube suffered because of its Game Boy Connection thing.
Speaker 0: Now I thought the Game Boy Connection thing was really cool, but apparently all the people complaining about, "Oh man I don't want to have to have four GBAs and four friends and all that,".
Speaker 0: even though everyone should have had a GBA already, that kind of won out.
Speaker 0: And very rarely were people able to get four people to actually play this entire game.
Speaker 1: However, if you could pull it off, that was one of the defining gaming experiences of my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I put that right up there with the first time I beat Zelda 2.
Speaker 0: So because of that, we'll probably do the same thing with the FFCCDS and the FFCC Wii.
Speaker 1: FFCC on the DS has one big advantage, because the GameCube, the connector for the GBA to be connected to the GameCube was nice, but it was slow, a little high latency, it couldn't really do the high powered awesome things you'd want.
Speaker 1: It was more like a proof of concept.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you couldn't look at the GBA screen and the real screen at the same time.
Speaker 0: so much.
Speaker 0: You're either looking down or looking up.
Speaker 1: And you were really limited by the fact that all the main gameplay was still on the TV.
Speaker 1: It was hard to hide big things from other players or do interesting things like that.
Speaker 1: The DS removes all those limitations.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got two screens right in front of your face, the main gameplay is on the top screen and your inventory and stuff is on the bottom, and woah.
Speaker 1: I mean, imagine this, we don't know exactly what the game will be like, but the only reason they had the buskit in FFCC originally was that the players can't stray from each other or the game doesn't work.
Speaker 1: There's no need for that in the DS version.
Speaker 0: Yep, and considering the plot, there shouldn't be a need for that.
Speaker 1: Now they might have some sort of thing like that anyway for various gameplay reasons, but the fact remains that you'll be able to, technologically at least, have multiple players in multiple places simultaneously.
Speaker 1: Of course, that's the same thing about the four swords that may come for DS's and the sort of mana things that'll come out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, that's the DS rundown, or at least the Geek Knight's DS rundown from E3.
Speaker 1: So, the conclusion here, the moral of the DS bit is that the DS is exploding and awesome in Nintendo++.
Speaker 0: If you don't have a DS right now, I recommend you buy a DS Lite on June 11th.
Speaker 1: Or hell, you can get a used regular DS now for like 70 bucks.
Speaker 0: If you're cheap, go for that one.
Speaker 0: Hells yeah.
Speaker 0: But, uh, that's how it's gonna play out.
Speaker 0: If you don't have a DS and you go to a convention or a LAN party or anything, all those people with DS's, man, whatcha gonna do?
Speaker 1: I can't wait to load a con.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be insane.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's take a break from Nintendo for a bit.
Speaker 1: We'll be back about the Wii.
Speaker 1: The Wii-volution.
Speaker 0: But we're gonna take a break.
Speaker 0: You won't notice because it'll just be a skip in the audio or whatever.
Speaker 0: Okay, now let's hear from our good friends at Sony.
Speaker 1: Now, the Sony abortion of a press conference release.
Speaker 1: whatnot, god we keep saying whatnot, happened yesterday.
Speaker 1: It is probably well known that Sony did not really overwhelm anyone with their offerings.
Speaker 0: I think every single video game magazine, video game blog, editor, writer, everywhere, the number one word they were using was underwhelming.
Speaker 1: Yes, I saw the word "tepid response" in more than one report.
Speaker 0: So this isn't, don't say "oh you Nintendo fanboys" even though we are sort of Nintendo fanboys kinda.
Speaker 1: Sony fanboys, Sony fanboys at the Sony thing who have been waiting for this since they first heard that there was gonna be a PS3.
Speaker 1: When a PS3 was a glimmer in some executive's eye.
Speaker 1: They were there and they didn't even clap.
Speaker 0: Now we're not saying there aren't any Sony fanboys who are all about this because there are plenty who are all about this.
Speaker 0: We're just saying that the general mood of the marketplace and the media, gaming media seems to be "oh bleh".
Speaker 1: Non-gaming media was even "bleh" about this.
Speaker 1: Media that don't know anything about the gaming market and were just reporting on what Sony's doing because they're a company.
Speaker 0: Now when it comes, let's first talk about the clapping.
Speaker 1: Alright, so Sony comes out and they're like "here's all our stuff" and they unveil little bits and they show little preview things.
Speaker 1: But mostly they just talk numbers.
Speaker 1: Numbers that gamers don't care about.
Speaker 0: And when Sony talks about numbers, they always talk about shipments.
Speaker 0: They don't talk about sales, they talk about shipments.
Speaker 1: They're like "we've shipped XPSPs and we've shipped XPS2s blah blah blah".
Speaker 1: And they've shipped a lot of PSPs, but they haven't sold a lot of them.
Speaker 0: I'd like to point out that at the Sony conference, if you watch it or look at pictures of it, there's this giant screen with what is obviously a powerpoint.
Speaker 1: And they've just got numbers.
Speaker 0: A lot of numbers and a lot of bullet points and it's kind of bleh.
Speaker 0: At the Nintendo thing, they had the freaking giant Nintendo logo with the lights behind it that was always there.
Speaker 1: They had the freaking Miyamoto conducting that orchestra.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're learning from Apple.
Speaker 0: Sony is still doing their boring old businessman show.
Speaker 0: Even Microsoft put on a better show.
Speaker 0: Microsoft's show's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I don't see myself buying an Xbox 360 anytime soon, but Microsoft, I'm kind of impressed with the Xbox 360 in general.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm kind of interested in some of the stuff they're offering.
Speaker 0: The Sony, I can understand their business strategies and such, but a company with a hundred...
Speaker 1: Alright, Scott, understanding Sony's business practices is like understanding why a crazy guy keeps hitting himself in the head with a hammer.
Speaker 0: 'Cause he's crazy.
Speaker 0: Okay, so, let's, uh, where can we start with Sony?
Speaker 1: Well, we'll keep going with the clapping here.
Speaker 1: It's a nice thread.
Speaker 0: Alright, alright.
Speaker 1: So then, they announced the price point of the PlayStation 3.
Speaker 1: And for anyone who doesn't know, it is $600.
Speaker 0: It's $600?
Speaker 0: Alright, there are two different PS3s that you can buy.
Speaker 0: One of the PS3s is $600, and one of them is $500.
Speaker 0: Now, the $600 one has a 60 gig hard drive and has everything.
Speaker 0: The 20 gig hard, the $500 one only has a 20 gig hard drive.
Speaker 0: I guess maybe that doesn't make a big difference.
Speaker 0: It might if you have a lot of games, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well, considering that a Blu-Ray disc can hold like 35 gigabytes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this isn't such a big, whatever.
Speaker 0: The 20 gig one, the other problem with it is that it does not have a slot to put in flash cards.
Speaker 0: Like SD flash, you know, memory sticks, etc.
Speaker 0: That's a fucker, because how are you supposed to integrate it with your PSP and shit?
Speaker 1: It's also missing the HDMI port.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have the HDMI port, and it doesn't have a wireless card.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so basically...
Speaker 0: So you have to plug it in with an ethernet cable if you don't buy the $600 one.
Speaker 1: I can't see anyone buying the $500 one, except for people who are so poor.
Speaker 1: they can't afford a PS3, but they just have enough money to buy the $500 one.
Speaker 1: It doesn't even look like it's going to be upgradeable.
Speaker 0: And I want to talk about the Engadget, what they said, and I think it rings pretty true, is they said if the freehand Wii controller is Nintendo's selling point on the Wii, then the HD is the selling point on the PS3.
Speaker 0: And if the cheaper $500 one doesn't have the HDMI port, it's like if they had two different versions of the Wii and one of them just came with GameCube controllers.
Speaker 1: I gotta hand it to Sony.
Speaker 1: When they announced this, it made the Xbox 360 look affordable to me.
Speaker 1: It made it look reasonable.
Speaker 0: And it made it look pretty good, too.
Speaker 1: So I think, hey, for $400, I can get a badass Xbox 360, and there's some games I'm actually kind of interested in now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and when we talk about the Xbox 360, you'll see they got a lot of new stuff in the line.
Speaker 0: that makes me go, "Huh, maybe this isn't all ass.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll maybe move into that
Speaker 0: area.".
Speaker 1: Well, honestly, I'm thinking that the Xbox 360, not now, but within a year, I could see myself buying one at a slight discount, maybe a used one, or the streamlined re-release they're going to have.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: Not only is the PlayStation 3, the real one, $600, because we're not going to talk about the GIMP version, it's 600 euros in Europe.
Speaker 0: So usually, because euros are worth more than dollars, and pounds are worth a lot more than dollars, like one pound is like $1.60-something.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Well, honestly, there's a bunch of extra news about that because I don't want to get off on a tangent, but China and Asia in general have for a long time said, "Eh, we might not peg the yuan to the dollar anymore.
Speaker 1: What are you going to
Speaker 1: do?".
Speaker 1: But no, everyone knew they wouldn't.
Speaker 1: Now it looks like they're really going to do it, so the dollar's been dropping, more so than usual.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: I've been waiting for them to unpeg it.
Speaker 0: That's what I want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it'll be good for everyone in the world, except, uh, Americans.
Speaker 0: Woohoo!
Speaker 0: Alright, so... You know, they're pretty big on the PS3.
Speaker 0: That's the system in many other parts of the world, this PlayStation.
Speaker 0: They're really big on Nintendo in Europe.
Speaker 0: so much.
Speaker 1: Though I think they will be now.
Speaker 0: They might be.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: It costs the equivalent of almost $800 for the PS3 in Europe.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that Europe and the rest of the world outside of Japan and the US and North America and places is going to be real big on the Xbox, and I'll explain why in a little bit.
Speaker 1: $800 fucking dollars for the cost.
Speaker 1: Well, here, look at the $600 figure.
Speaker 1: For the cost of the PS3, I could probably buy a Revolution Wii, a Wiivolution, you know.
Speaker 1: Another one for my other kid, if I had a kid, so the two kids wouldn't fight over it.
Speaker 0: And how many DS's?
Speaker 0: Like, how many DS lights?
Speaker 1: Oh, God, 20 PS.
Speaker 1: Or you could buy one Revolution and, like, eight or nine games for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, way to go, Sony.
Speaker 0: And you can get all four controllers for your Revolution, too.
Speaker 0: I mean, your Wii.
Speaker 1: Yeah, keep in mind that this $600 figure, as far as we can tell, only comes with the system and one controller.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Now, let's talk about that controller.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: The fact that it costs $600 is not the bad news.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: The controller!
Speaker 1: Now, remember way back, they showed us the Boomerang version of the controller, and they said this is going to be the controller.
Speaker 0: And then I had a really popular thing on my blog where I found in an old GamePro magazine, there was a Boomerang controller back in the day, and I posted a picture like, "Sony ripped off these other people who made a Boomerang
Speaker 0: controller.".
Speaker 1: Well, instead, one, Sony ripped off themselves.
Speaker 1: It looks exactly like the DualShock with an extra button.
Speaker 0: It is the DualShock controller and has an extra PlayStation button right in the middle of it.
Speaker 1: Except it doesn't have the DualShock in it.
Speaker 0: They took it out.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that's because they got sued, remember, about the two vibrators?
Speaker 1: They could have put a different thing in, because Nintendo doesn't infringe, and it would have been trivial to make a rumble thing that didn't infringe on that patent.
Speaker 0: Yep, but there is another reason why there is no rumbling going on.
Speaker 1: Now, before we say the reason, I'm sure some of you know.
Speaker 0: I'm sure everyone knows.
Speaker 1: Consider that part of the reason people like the DualShock is that it had rumbling in it.
Speaker 1: That was, like, a good thing.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: The fact that there's no rumble at all really isn't great.
Speaker 0: Rumbling is one of those things, or when it came out on Starflex 64, like I said, I was kind of blagged, because it needed this rumble pack to pay extra money, and I was like, "Eh, it doesn't do anything.
Speaker 0: It uses the gimmicky crap.
Speaker 0: It doesn't enhance the game in any
Speaker 0: way.".
Speaker 0: But after playing a lot of GameCube games, especially Metroids and Eternal Darknesses and Resident Evils-- Yeah, even F-Zero.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even F-Zero.
Speaker 1: I mean, some people use rumble stupidly.
Speaker 0: Mario Sunshine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, it'll be Super Rumble or off.
Speaker 1: But if you make the subtle little rumbles, like, you're driving a car, and there's this tiny subtle rumble--.
Speaker 0: Mario Party uses it well, even.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, rumbling can make a game really good in a way.
Speaker 0: You don't even notice the rumbling, but it enhances, you know, through your feeling senses in your hands, you know.
Speaker 0: You'll, like, be worried about something, or you'll take a hit, and then it'll shake.
Speaker 0: And you won't think consciously, "Ooh, it's rumbling!
Speaker 0: Ooh, look at
Speaker 0: this!".
Speaker 0: 'Cause you're not paying attention to rumble packs anymore now that they're inside the controller where you can't see them.
Speaker 0: On the N64, you pay attention.
Speaker 0: Now you don't pay attention.
Speaker 0: But without it, you notice when it's gone.
Speaker 0: You go, "Oh, it's not rumbling," as soon as it's not there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it really adds to the immersion in the game.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, Sony got rid of that.
Speaker 1: They pissed on that game.
Speaker 0: The reason they got rid of that is 'cause they've put in three axes of accelerometers inside the controller.
Speaker 1: The Sony, who said repeatedly that the revolution was stupid, and that their innovative controller was just a bullshit gimmick, ripped the gimmick off blatantly.
Speaker 0: Well, people are saying on the internet that they're not ripping off Nintendo, 'cause what Nintendo has done is in the Wii con- the nunchuck part of the revolution control- of the Wii controller, actually has the same accelerom- or, an equivalent accelerometer setup to what the PS3 controller's going to have, where you can tell when you tilt it forward, back, left, and right, and, you know, wiggle it up and down.
Speaker 0: But it can't tell where you're aiming it, and it can't tell where it is relative in space.
Speaker 0: The revolution controller, the actual Wiivolution stick, the... The, what are we calling it?
Speaker 0: What are we calling it now?
Speaker 1: Let's call it the stick.
Speaker 0: Oh, the Wiimote.
Speaker 0: The Wiimote.
Speaker 1: Wiimote.
Speaker 0: So the Wiimote can actually tell where it is in space, so it's a pointing device.
Speaker 0: You can aim with it, you can swing it, as opposed to just tilting it.
Speaker 0: So, the PlayStation controller will probably be good for racing games, flying games, et cetera, but it's not gonna be good for shooting games, sword fighting games...
Speaker 1: Now, you might think that, but, by the same token, I'll note that controllers like that, and Microsoft brought this up right away when they were asked about what they thought of Sony's controller, they made controllers like that a long time ago.
Speaker 1: They did.
Speaker 0: Logitech and Microsoft made them for the PC.
Speaker 1: And there were even games that made use of it.
Speaker 1: And they found that having a standard controller, the type of controller you hold in two hands, like, you know, every controller out there except the Wii, doesn't really work so well.
Speaker 1: It's not intuitive or easy to manipulate it in such a way that you can control a game.
Speaker 1: It's just annoying and hurts your wrists.
Speaker 0: Because you're trying to do that while also trying to manage all the buttons.
Speaker 0: People who had experience using the PlayStation 3 controller at the show said that they didn't know where to put their thumb.
Speaker 0: Should they put them on the analog sticks?
Speaker 0: Take them off?
Speaker 0: You know, they couldn't figure out what the hell to do with it.
Speaker 1: So... Also, accelerometers and things like that and controllers of that level, you know, low-end consumer technology, they're not the most accurate thing, so it's kind of... You gotta... I don't think it's... It's very awkward to play with a controller like that.
Speaker 1: And think about how many people, when they play games, just subconsciously move the controller around while they're playing.
Speaker 0: Well, that's good, because that's what you want people to do, is people move the controller while they play.
Speaker 0: It's something you naturally did back in the NES.
Speaker 0: That even said that during Nintendo's conferences.
Speaker 0: Do you remember back when you had an NES and, you know, the first time you picked it up, you would tilt the controller or, like, pull it back?
Speaker 0: Naturally, because you wanted your guy to move that way.
Speaker 1: God, my little brother... I should try to find some old home videos.
Speaker 1: But, I mean, we were both really big gamers when we were kids.
Speaker 1: And I would sit there and play and I'd move the controller around.
Speaker 1: He would stand in front of the TV and have this full-body motion.
Speaker 1: Like, when he was cornering, his whole body would bend and he'd hold the controller up.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: It worked for him, but...
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the point of the Revolution controller, the Wiimote, is that you can take people's natural body movement and turn that into the game control.
Speaker 0: So, that's what you have to go for.
Speaker 0: The thing is, is that the way the Sony is gonna do it isn't gonna work so well.
Speaker 0: Because, for example, it can tell when it's being tilted.
Speaker 0: But it can't tell if you hold it tilted.
Speaker 0: So, let's say I'm playing a racing game, right?
Speaker 0: So I tilt it to the right to turn right and I hold it in a tilted right position.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have to do some wicked programming to know that I'm still holding it tilted right.
Speaker 1: And even if you do that programming...
Speaker 0: It only can tell when it's moving.
Speaker 0: It can't tell what its orientation is at any given time.
Speaker 1: Plus, with a system like that, if you don't make it really well and put a lot of time in the development process, it's not gonna be intuitive.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be awkward because it won't mesh up perfectly with the game.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of PlayStation games just aren't gonna use it at all.
Speaker 1: Well, considering that it really looks like they threw this feature in at the last minute...
Speaker 0: It seems a lot of the things that Sony does, it doesn't look like they're testing it on people.
Speaker 0: It seems that... I don't know what their attitude is, but the way it looks to me is that because they're so big at number one, they're just like, "Uh, anything with the PlayStation name will sell a bajillion.
Speaker 0: We don't actually have to make something quality or new or anything.
Speaker 0: We can just, you know, copy a little bit of the Xbox people and what they're doing so that they don't beat us in that department and copy a little bit of what the Nintendo's doing so they don't beat us in that
Speaker 0: department.".
Speaker 1: Yep, that way in the marketing they can say, "Yeah, we have motion control and
Speaker 1: whatnot.".
Speaker 1: They'll probably call it something, just like the revolution.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, "We got everything.
Speaker 0: You know, we got what they got, we got what they got.
Speaker 0: We're number one.
Speaker 0: We can do it all.
Speaker 0: Buy
Speaker 0: us.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Alright, so let's talk about what else they got going on.
Speaker 0: The PlayStation 3 will come out November 11th in Japan and November 17th in the USA.
Speaker 0: My brother's birthday is November 17th.
Speaker 1: Ah.
Speaker 1: Um... I'm honestly surprised they even made that date.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I remember the other PlayStations coming out.
Speaker 0: There was some other stuff that came out around that time because I remember it was like my brother's birthday and then something would come out and then he would go get it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it was.
Speaker 0: It might have been a PlayStation 2, I don't remember.
Speaker 0: We should look up the PS2 release date.
Speaker 1: Though I do remember that when they had the guy on stage with that controller, just to go back to the controller a bit, and they showed him playing this game, it didn't look like it worked.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it did work, it just...
Speaker 1: No, it just not well.
Speaker 0: I think they were doing a demo, you know, a fake demo.
Speaker 0: Just like all their other demos are fake.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, the thing is, if they faked it, it looked like it was real and just bad.
Speaker 1: Like, it looked like the guy had a hard time making it control the game properly.
Speaker 0: That's something else I want to point out right away.
Speaker 0: At the Sony conference, most of the videos that they showed, because they didn't show all that much real gameplay, were videos of pre-rendered stuff that...
Speaker 1: Oh, God, we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were, uh, bullshots.
Speaker 1: Ah, Penny Arcade.
Speaker 1: A perfectly turbulent world.
Speaker 0: They were just pre-rendered CG videos.
Speaker 0: They weren't videos of what the game is like.
Speaker 0: You know, the Metal Gear Solid thing, it's pretty cool, but that's not what the game looks like.
Speaker 0: That's just a video.
Speaker 1: Nintendo was all, "This is what the gameplay will look
Speaker 1: like.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think Nintendo showed a single video, everything they showed on the screen, the only pre-rendered animation they showed was the little eyes that were dancing around the Wii logo.
Speaker 1: And there's no Wii dancing eye game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everything they showed was either video from a game, or video of models, you know, playing with Wii controllers to show you what it's like to play the game.
Speaker 0: They didn't show anything else.
Speaker 0: Maybe Nintendo logo or two.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and even the games they showed that may not be done yet, where it might have been kind of tweaked, it was definitely at least the level of graphics that'll be in the game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now, Sony, they announced all their games and they showed them.
Speaker 1: Now, Metal Gear Solid 4 is the one game that seems to have been generating a lot of buzz.
Speaker 1: That and Gran Turismo HD.
Speaker 0: Well, Gran Turismo HD is not going to be a game, so I'm going to talk about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was going to get to that, but I want to do MSG first.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: Because I was excited about it.
Speaker 1: MGS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: I want some MSG, I'm kind of hungry.
Speaker 1: But I was kind of excited about it, because I haven't played any of these new Metal Gear games, but I like Metal Gear, I like the franchise, I mostly like the story, and I like the gameplay.
Speaker 1: I like the idea of the games.
Speaker 0: I like the gameplay of Metal Gear Solid-type games, actually.
Speaker 0: You know, the stealth, sneak around, shoot guys games.
Speaker 0: There seem to be a lot more of those now.
Speaker 0: Isn't the Splinter Cells like that, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and some missions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I haven't actually played any of the Splinter Cells.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should get around to that.
Speaker 1: Because, I mean, Metal Gear, when it came out for the NES, was really the first big game that had gameplay like that, where you were a military guy, and your goal was to hide from your enemies at all costs.
Speaker 0: I think it was the Metal Gear Solid for the GameCube.
Speaker 0: I should go pick that up now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't know why we didn't buy it.
Speaker 1: I love those games, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So, Metal Gear Solid 4, and there's been little tiny bits of buzz that this game is going to be like the end-all.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So, then they show the stuff about it at E3.
Speaker 1: They did not show, as far as I can tell, a single second, not even one frame of gameplay.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: What it was, was an awesome trailer for a movie.
Speaker 1: If they were making Metal Gear Solid 4 the movie, that's a badass movie, and I'd go see it immediately.
Speaker 0: Oh, hell yeah.
Speaker 0: Much better than Uwe Boll.
Speaker 1: It looks like an awesome plot and an awesome movie.
Speaker 1: I don't know if there's a game there.
Speaker 0: We haven't seen a game.
Speaker 0: If there is, they're not showing it to us.
Speaker 1: The crowd certainly reacted to the final shot of the trailer, which showed Solid Snake as an old man.
Speaker 1: It's definitely an old man disillusioned with all that he's done in his life in warfare and killing.
Speaker 1: And it ends with him putting a gun in his mouth, and he's about to kill himself.
Speaker 1: And the crowd really reacted to that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But they reacted more to the fact that it was Solid Snake going to kill himself than, "Oh my God, this
Speaker 0: game.".
Speaker 1: Because they didn't show the game.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: They basically said, "Hey, here's the plot of the game we're coming out
Speaker 1: with.".
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's a lot of things that PlayStation games have going for them as plots.
Speaker 0: It's mostly RPGs and games with these heavy sorts of plots on them.
Speaker 0: Things are going to have a freaking Blu-ray drive.
Speaker 0: That's what you put movies on.
Speaker 0: That's what Sony's all about.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The problem is, whenever they have these plots in these games, it seems more and more that the plot is play a game and then watch an FMV that has plot, and then play more game and then watch an FMV.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: You've got to have the games that integrate the plot with the game, like Half-Life did.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about some of the other things that went down.
Speaker 1: Gran Turismo?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Gran Turismo HD.
Speaker 0: Now, I never actually played Gran Turismo 4, so I didn't know what it looked like.
Speaker 0: When I saw Gran Turismo HD, I said, "Wow, I'm actually freaking interested in that.
Speaker 0: That looks like the best racing game
Speaker 0: ever.".
Speaker 1: We've been playing Gran Turismo, what, 2 on our PlayStation 1?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not so good nowadays.
Speaker 0: But I really like racing games, and it seems like the only thing Nintendo is seriously lacking in is real racing games.
Speaker 0: We've got Mario Karts, and we go, "Oh, right, Diddy Kong Racing DS.
Speaker 0: Forgot that
Speaker 0: one.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But that's going to be pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Nintendo doesn't have the realist to racing games, really, at all.
Speaker 0: I mean, there was R Racing Revolution for the GameCube.
Speaker 0: That sucked.
Speaker 0: It wasn't good at all.
Speaker 0: PlayStation's got their Ridge Racers and their Gran Turismos, and Microsoft has their Forzas and their, what's it called, Project Gotham.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but when we get to Microsoft, we'll talk about that.
Speaker 1: I think Microsoft is going to win the Realistic Gaming trophy.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm all about these racing games, so when I saw Gran Turismo HD, I was like, "Ooh, that looks like the best damn racing game
Speaker 0: ever.".
Speaker 0: Apparently, what Gran Turismo HD was is not a game.
Speaker 0: What it was, they took Gran Turismo 4, and they did something to it to make it go 1080i resolution.
Speaker 0: So all it was was a prototype game designed to show you, "Yes, look at this.
Speaker 0: The PlayStation 3 can do a full HD game in real time.
Speaker 0: Look at it go.
Speaker 0: There it
Speaker 0: is.".
Speaker 0: And all it tells me is, "Hey, that looks really good.
Speaker 0: I'm going to get Gran Turismo 4 for the
Speaker 0: PS2.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Because I don't have an HDTV.
Speaker 1: And even if we did, I mean, the HD doesn't really seem to be a good selling point on a console.
Speaker 0: Well, it is something that people there seem to all agree upon, because I wasn't there and I didn't see this, that there were some shots and videos of actual gameplay on the PS3, and they looked really good.
Speaker 0: But people seem to say that they didn't really look that much better or sometimes not as good as what the Xbox 360 looks like.
Speaker 1: Huh.
Speaker 0: I wonder.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't care about the graphics in a game.
Speaker 0: The graphics are not so important.
Speaker 0: It's the game that matters.
Speaker 1: Well, as long as the graphics don't get in the way of the game.
Speaker 0: But when you're Sony and you keep bragging about the graphics so much, and then they're not that super amazing, as you've been saying, or they don't-- It doesn't matter how super amazing they are.
Speaker 0: If people don't go along with what you're saying and they say, "Yeah, I'm not really impressed," well, you've got a problem.
Speaker 1: You know, maybe it's getting to the point where diminishing returns.
Speaker 1: I mean, 720p is really nice, and it is better than what we've got now.
Speaker 1: Our crappy NTSC whatnot.
Speaker 1: But once you get to 1080i and 1080p, the difference isn't quite as noticeable.
Speaker 1: And as you get beyond that, there's no difference as far as human eyes can tell, unless you've got a thousand-foot screen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who knows?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, it looks really nice, but I don't think that it's that super amazing that people are going to say, "Oh my god, the PS3 blows the Xbox 360 out of the water on graphics.
Speaker 0: It's the winner in that
Speaker 0: fight.".
Speaker 1: It really doesn't.
Speaker 0: They're both pretty much tied in that fight.
Speaker 0: And as always, computers are going to win, and I'm going to get to why that's real important when I talk about Microsoft.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So all in all, Sony really didn't impress anyone.
Speaker 0: Well, no, here's the stuff that they had that I thought was good.
Speaker 0: They had a thing with the iToy.
Speaker 0: The iToy, if you don't know, is this camera you can get for your PS2.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah!
Speaker 0: And the iToy had some pretty crummy games.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone actually bought them or used them.
Speaker 0: But they did a demo, which they should have, you know, put a lot more emphasis on.
Speaker 0: It seemed sort of like they did this and said, "Look, we have this,".
Speaker 0: but then they didn't really play it out, you know, and make a big deal out of it.
Speaker 0: What it is, is the iToy looks at this table, and you put cards down on the table, and sort of like
Speaker 0: Yu-Gi-Oh!,
Speaker 0: the iToy sees the cards and it makes monsters.
Speaker 0: And then you can like gesture with your hands, and the iToy will see your gestures, and you can command your monsters on the table to play a cool game in a Yu-Gi-Oh!
Speaker 0: type of style.
Speaker 0: I think that's something really good, that Sony should try more of that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That'd be a whole lot of fun.
Speaker 1: Sony, they're the company who decried Nintendo for being gimmicky, and while this is cool, it is definitely gimmicky.
Speaker 0: No, I think gimmicky means you, at least to me, gimmicky means you have some sort of trick that doesn't actually enhance the thing itself.
Speaker 0: Like, um, if you put, uh, here's in the golf clubs are the most gimmicky things in the world.
Speaker 0: Someone will say, "Check out this golf club, it has this awesomely shaped head with titanium.
Speaker 0: insert
Speaker 0: something.".
Speaker 1: Yep, you know what kills the golf argument right away?
Speaker 1: Have golf scores decreased in a trend as technology of golfing in golf clubs has increased?
Speaker 0: Yes, but the point is, is that you look at the golf club and it has this fancy doodad on it, but the fancy doodad doesn't actually do anything.
Speaker 0: But here, you know, that's why people say that the DS was so gimmicky, because it had all these fancy doodads, like a microphone and a touchscreen, the problem is they do something.
Speaker 0: So they're not gimmicks.
Speaker 1: I guess I wonder if Sony has the support to actually use that in a non-gimmicky way on more than a handful of games.
Speaker 0: See, that's the thing, is they could do it on a handful of games and it wouldn't be gimmicky if they actually used it in this way.
Speaker 0: The problem is, will they do it on enough games to make it a wise economic decision to buy an eye toy and buy these games?
Speaker 0: It could be a Super Scope, but the Super Scope wasn't gimmicky, but it just didn't have enough games to make it worth buying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just don't see the developers getting behind it.
Speaker 1: And plus, I wonder what type of development, because obviously developing for something like this is not the same as developing for the PlayStation itself.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Of course, they also have the problem that the PlayStation is using those IBM cell processors.
Speaker 1: And I could talk at length about the pros and cons of that and what IBM strategy, in my eyes as a former employee, even though I'm still working there, was regarding it.
Speaker 1: But I can say that developing for the PlayStation 3 is not easy, it is not trivial, it is not something people can do without a lot of work.
Speaker 0: Well, the problem is that people are used to programming in a certain way, and the cell processors have a different architecture than most other chips that people are used to, so you have to program for it in an all-new way.
Speaker 0: And to make it easier, Sony could provide a lot of tools, but even they really don't know how to program for it so well.
Speaker 0: So it's like this whole new territory, and it's going to take them a lot of time to develop tools, and then to use those tools to develop better games, and it's...
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, now the people who developed for the PS2 are still making PS2 games, because they've got that down pat.
Speaker 0: I read somewhere today, I can't verify this 100%, that there will be 216 new PlayStation 2 games by the end of the year.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't doubt it.
Speaker 1: I remember I read an article a few weeks ago where some company had two games that were going to be PS3 games, that they just said, "Fuck it," because the PS3 was delayed, and there was trouble with the dev kits, and they made them PS2 games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now here's something to compare this to Nintendo and Microsoft.
Speaker 0: Microsoft, if you want to make a game for the Xbox 360, it's DirectX.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows DirectX.
Speaker 0: It's always been DirectX.
Speaker 1: DirectX is well-documented.
Speaker 0: It's almost exactly like making a game for Windows.
Speaker 0: Everyone knows how to do it.
Speaker 0: You can buy a book on it in the store.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's well-documented, well-understood.
Speaker 1: We could teach anyone out there how to do a trivial game.
Speaker 0: Yep, Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Now, it's not publicly available information how to make Nintendo games for their hardware, but if you are able to get a development kit from them, they give you everything you need.
Speaker 0: In fact, just today at the press conference, they were saying, "Yeah, and no one's going to have to write this code because we wrote the network stack, and we'll just give it to all the
Speaker 0: developers.".
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also, they have said that the Nintendo Wii and the way you write software for it is very similar to the way you write software for the GameCube.
Speaker 0: Oh, the early dev kits for the Wii were all just GameCubes with attachments to hook up the Wii controllers.
Speaker 1: Yep, because the only real difference is that it's more powerful.
Speaker 0: And it has more peripherals.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you have more-- And it has a different disk that holds more storage.
Speaker 1: So you have more options for input, more options for storage, and more power.
Speaker 1: Other than that, the API's the same.
Speaker 1: You still have a, "Alright, hitting a button calls this thing or does this
Speaker 1: thing.".
Speaker 0: The PS3 is a whole new world, and I think that what might see happen is the PS3 isn't going to bomb and kill Sony like the Dreamcast or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it's hard to kill Sony.
Speaker 0: There are enough people out there who really, really want it and want the games that are on it, and they're going to make money, I guess.
Speaker 0: But, eventually, what's going to happen over time is there's a chance that as developers learn how to make PlayStation 3 games, that you'll start to see, like, the second or third round of PS3 games coming out will start to get graphics that are way better than the Microsoft Xbox.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Gameplay that takes advantage of the TILTI controller and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: However, I see that as definitely a situation of, "Too little, too
Speaker 1: late."
Speaker 1: And it won't tank, but I really think the PS3 is going to be the trailing third console in the war.
Speaker 1: Well, quote-unquote
Speaker 1: "war.".
Speaker 0: It'll definitely, I think, the PS3 not do as well as the Xbox 360 overall.
Speaker 0: At least, at the very least, it won't completely demolish the other systems the way it did in the previous generation.
Speaker 0: It'll be on par with the Xbox 360 at most.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and my prediction is that it will be the trailing console.
Speaker 1: It's going to be playing catch-up with Nintendo and Microsoft.
Speaker 0: So, here's some other interesting tidbits that Sony went over.
Speaker 1: Didn't they say they're going to have two million of them right away?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: There'll be two million right away, and then four million a little while later, and then, like, eight million a little while later.
Speaker 1: Now, I saw a few reports that people said, "No, they only have one
Speaker 1: million.".
Speaker 1: But I don't know.
Speaker 1: I didn't chase any of that down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who knows how many they have.
Speaker 0: But that's how many they said they'd have.
Speaker 1: Now, I wonder, because the Xbox sold out right away, and there were supply problems.
Speaker 1: But it was kind of, it wasn't as expensive as the PlayStation 3.
Speaker 0: Actually, Microsoft did a good comparison at their conference of, like, sales per unit time and all that, and how the Xbox 360 actually kind of beat the iPod.
Speaker 0: But the iPod was sort of a slow, gradual build-up to a bigger number than, you know.
Speaker 0: But the rate of sales to the Xbox 360 in its early days was, like, tremendous, more than anything ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Insane.
Speaker 1: However, that was partly because there was a number of them, and there was a number greater than that number of people who would pay any price to have one.
Speaker 1: So pretty much, the sales were instant, and then there were no more.
Speaker 1: But now they're back on the market, and they're not really moving so fast.
Speaker 0: Nope, not so much.
Speaker 0: But I think they will as soon as the next round of Xbox 360 goodies goes out.
Speaker 1: Especially when the new Xbox 360s come out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and in the holiday season, expect a lot of Xbox 360s to start moving for all the people who didn't buy one for their kids yet.
Speaker 1: Of course, the revolution might really put a dent into that, especially as the economy gets the way it's going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, we'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The PSP is going to--they didn't really explain this, but the online service for the PlayStation 3, the equivalent of Xbox Live, is going to have some stuff.
Speaker 0: It's going to have some, you know, cool games you download and video chat with people, and they're going to make the whole big community thing.
Speaker 0: They're going to try to do everything that Xbox Live does, but their main thing is the inclusion of the rest of Sony's business of music and movies and all that shit.
Speaker 0: You know, so some of the stuff they're going to do is, like, download a video and watch it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, they'd better do something like that.
Speaker 1: UMD, as a movie format, is dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, download something to a memory stick and put it in your PSP.
Speaker 1: Oh, the thing we wanted from the start?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, of course, you'd be paying for it through the PlayStation online service, DRMing it to the memory stick and all that, right?
Speaker 0: There's going to be one thing--I didn't read all the details.
Speaker 0: What it sounds like to me is you'll be able to take and pay for a PlayStation 1 game, download it to a memory stick, shove it in your PSP and play it.
Speaker 1: Huh.
Speaker 0: That sounds pretty good to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: A little emulator thing, and they said that there'll be, like, a firmware coming up that supports it.
Speaker 1: Of course, for me, if I had a PSP, I'd just hack it up with the old firmware and just have an NES/SNES emulator in there.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And they said there'll be some sort of micropayment system, so you'll buy these Sony cards.
Speaker 0: Not the Sony credit card that I have, but the regular, like, a little clear card.
Speaker 0: And then you can use that card to buy things on the Sony online service.
Speaker 1: I don't like how Sony really seems to like the idea of just constantly ringing all their customers for money as long as they own a PlayStation 3.
Speaker 0: Well, Microsoft is doing a similar thing with Xbox Live.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't like that anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, one of the examples they showed of, uh, is probably the best example of how this thing is gonna work is the SingStar karaoke.
Speaker 0: Now, what this looked like is they didn't actually have any prices on it, but it's a karaoke game where you would go online to this, you know, site or place interface in the Sony online thing with your PS3, and you can pick songs and karaoke them.
Speaker 0: And the thing was is you would pay to get more songs.
Speaker 0: See, you know, it's like, "Oh, I wanna karaoke that song
Speaker 0: now.".
Speaker 0: You pay, like, 25 cents or whatever.
Speaker 0: They didn't show any prices on it.
Speaker 0: Everything was, like, $1,000.
Speaker 0: And this is, you know, you get the music video, and you get the words, and you get the song.
Speaker 0: And now you've got it, and you can karaoke it and all that.
Speaker 0: So, we'll see how well that works, you know.
Speaker 0: Do people really wanna keep paying for more karaoke songs?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll see, eh.
Speaker 0: But that's the example of how they're combining their music business and their PlayStation business into this one sort of media.
Speaker 0: They're really going more towards the media thing and not so much, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just think they're going in too many directions at once, which they always seem to try to do now.
Speaker 0: Well, here's another thing you gotta remember.
Speaker 0: Remember when the PlayStation 1 came out, and they had the E3 conference for that?
Speaker 0: They said all this stuff, and they only did some of it.
Speaker 0: When the PlayStation 2 came out, they said they were gonna do all this stuff, and they only did some of it.
Speaker 1: Huh.
Speaker 1: Trend.
Speaker 0: I guarantee that not all the stuff Sony said they were gonna do with the PS3 today will be done.
Speaker 0: A lot of it is just never gonna happen.
Speaker 1: It seems like they fish.
Speaker 1: They'll throw out a bunch of stuff, see what people react to, and then react accordingly.
Speaker 0: And they see what everyone else does, and then they do that.
Speaker 0: I don't think they actually have a guiding vision.
Speaker 0: There's no one at Sony who's thinking and planning about what to do.
Speaker 0: They're just doing.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, going through the motions.
Speaker 0: Anyway, let's talk about... I'm not gonna go through all the games on the PS3 and what's gonna come out on it, like we did for the DS.
Speaker 1: We can do the big ones.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy 13.
Speaker 0: Well, hold on.
Speaker 0: I wanna talk about that last.
Speaker 0: Let me just say, here are five of the games coming out for the PS3.
Speaker 0: Metal Gear Solid 4, Tekken 6, Virtua Fighter 5, Virtua Tennis 3, Ridge Racer 7.
Speaker 0: What do those games all have in common?
Speaker 1: Huh.
Speaker 0: Huh.
Speaker 0: Let me... Metal Gear Solid 4, Tekken 6, Virtua Fighter 5, Virtua Tennis 3, Ridge Racer 7.
Speaker 0: See a pattern yet?
Speaker 1: See a pattern?
Speaker 0: Where are the games that are original?
Speaker 0: Now, granted, there were a few original games that were named, but there were plenty of games... Like, Resident Evil Code Veronica isn't a number, but it's a sequel.
Speaker 0: It's that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: So, where are the new franchises, the new games, the new whatnots?
Speaker 1: Sony doesn't make new franchises.
Speaker 0: No, they don't.
Speaker 0: It's all up to the third parties, and the third parties, you know, it's the same old PlayStation 3, the controller looks like the same old thing.
Speaker 0: They're gonna make the same old thing for it and see how long they can just keep making money that way.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And it'll probably work.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much longer it will work.
Speaker 0: If it works for this generation, I don't see it working for yet another generation of games.
Speaker 0: So they've got less than five years to come up with something new.
Speaker 1: Well, consider the Final Fantasy XIII trailer they showed.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about Final Fantasy XIII, and then we're done with Sony.
Speaker 0: It didn't...
Speaker 1: Like, I saw it, and I watched it, and I thought, "That looks like every other Final Fantasy game ever, except for the
Speaker 1: originals.".
Speaker 1: It's just...
Speaker 0: It looks like every Final Fantasy since VIII.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just, "Oh, look, there's an FMV of a girl doing something awesome, and there's a lot of choreography, and, oh, it's all intense and
Speaker 1: futuristic.".
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Now, here's the thing about Final Fantasy XIII, is there's going to be at least three versions of it.
Speaker 0: There's going to be, from what I've heard, this isn't solid, there's going to be the actual game, Final Fantasy XIII.
Speaker 0: There's going to be another game, Final Fantasy XIII Versus, for the PlayStation 3, which I suppose will be some sort of, "You fight your guys against someone else's guys and see who's
Speaker 0: better.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't have any details.
Speaker 0: Maybe a fighting game using the characters?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's going to be some sort of cell phone Final Fantasy XIII game.
Speaker 0: Don't ask me what that's about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really can't imagine, unless maybe it's a mini-game in the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're really, because Final Fantasy, the real Final Fantasy games, quote, are really the big thing that sell PlayStations.
Speaker 0: I mean, the PlayStation 1 would have been another Dreamcast 3DO if it wasn't for Final Fantasy VII, and everybody knows it.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason the PlayStation is so huge today, is because of Final Fantasy VII.
Speaker 1: Just think, if Nintendo and Square had patched up and not been fighting, there's a chance Nintendo would have just continued to be the behemoth that it used to be.
Speaker 0: Yep, it was all Square Enix's fault.
Speaker 0: 100%, everyone knows.
Speaker 0: So, now, since Final Fantasy seems to be the only thing they've got, and it was the thing that they started with, they're trying to make it as big as possible and milk it for everything they got.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean, they got Metal Gear also, but that's really not much.
Speaker 1: We didn't see any gameplay.
Speaker 1: We just saw a woman shoot a bunch of people with an Uzi.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's it?
Speaker 1: Oh, and there was a train going through a futuristic smog-filled city.
Speaker 0: Sounds like Final Fantasy to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, whether Final Fantasy XIII is good or not, I mean, didn't a bunch of people complain about the Final Fantasy XII?
Speaker 0: We still don't have that over here, do we?
Speaker 0: Or do we?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: That was the one that came out in Japan, and the combat was different, right?
Speaker 1: The last Final Fantasy, I played.
Speaker 0: 11 was the MMO, 12 was the one with the weird combat that scored a perfect score in Famitsu.
Speaker 1: 9 was the nod to old school, 8 was the one that was just a movie, 7 was the bridge.
Speaker 0: So, is 12 out in the US?
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: The fact that there isn't a whole lot of crazy talk about Final Fantasy XII since it came out in Japan, at least not that I've heard on any major gaming, you know, general gaming sites.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe this isn't going to, you know, are people less interested in Final Fantasy now?
Speaker 0: Are they still crazy about it?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Now one thing that we noticed, who was it who said the thing about female protagonists?
Speaker 1: Was that Joystick?
Speaker 0: I don't know, with some site.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some people said that, wow, a Final Fantasy game with a female protagonist.
Speaker 0: Obviously you haven't played Final Fantasy VI.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy VI, the two primary protagonists, the two mainest of main characters, are women.
Speaker 0: In fact, the first character you see in the game is a woman, not counting the two nobodies that she's with.
Speaker 1: The first half of the game, you follow one woman around most of the game doing things, and she is definitely the plot mover.
Speaker 1: Then, the game changes up, and now you follow this other woman through the whole game.
Speaker 0: Final Fantasy VI, I guess it's just, in Final Fantasy VI, if you are short-sighted, you can see, uh, what's the guy?
Speaker 0: Locke?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Locke and Edgar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can look at them, because Final Fantasy VI didn't have, no one character really stood out super strongly above the others.
Speaker 0: You're right in that, uh, what's her name, the Esper girl.
Speaker 0: Spoiler!
Speaker 0: Oh no!
Speaker 1: Oh no!
Speaker 1: We have a funny story about that for another day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's for another, well, we should do a day on spoilers.
Speaker 0: We should.
Speaker 0: Okay, so.
Speaker 1: But, Terra was, I mean, she was the main character if you look at it from like a literary work of art way.
Speaker 0: That's correct, but she wasn't so incredibly more main than the other characters.
Speaker 0: Like, if you watch an anime like Trigun, Vash the Stampede is so more main than anyone else in the show.
Speaker 0: But if you watch a show like Gundam Seed Destiny, from what I've heard, so this is probably not the best example, but from what I've heard, in Gundam Seed Destiny, there's a guy who's supposedly the main character, but the characters in the old Gundam Seed come around and they're more main and it's hard to tell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so.
Speaker 1: Of course, in the second half of Final Fantasy VI, there's no doubt one character is the only force in the game at that point.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And everyone else is just side characters until the final movies.
Speaker 0: So, Final Fantasy XIII, however, it seems that there's going to be one female who is as main as Cloud was in Final Fantasy VII.
Speaker 0: Which I guess that's kind of a first if you don't count non-.
Speaker 0: Well, Final Fantasy X2 was all girls, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess, that's what I heard.
Speaker 1: So I guess if you don't count the second half of Final Fantasy VI, then they're kinda right.
Speaker 0: Kinda.
Speaker 0: But yeah, a female protagonist is not a big deal unless you're a perverted fan.
Speaker 1: Now here's the thing, I don't think that they made the distinction like we did.
Speaker 1: I think they just didn't remember or know about Final Fantasy VI.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I think they're just young punks.
Speaker 0: They seem to remember about IV and V.
Speaker 1: Not many people remember V because V was not available until recently.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: In fact, I got a ROM of V a long time ago that I played and it was like this crazy deal.
Speaker 1: Like I went around my school with CD-ROMs with it, giving it to people.
Speaker 1: They were like, "Oh my god, where did you get
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Alright, I think we're done Sony bashing.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about the Wii.
Speaker 1: Alright, we've gone on for about an hour and a half here and we've got at least another hour to talk about E3.
Speaker 0: I really don't mind finishing off and making a crazy long episode, but RIM is wussing out.
Speaker 1: No, it's more than one.
Speaker 1: Our listeners always say they want longer episodes.
Speaker 1: I don't think they would listen to all of it or they would generally be annoyed if we put out a three hour episode.
Speaker 0: I say if they want longer episodes, we should give them what they want and then see whether they like it or not.
Speaker 0: You don't know until you try.
Speaker 1: Nah, it's also a pain in the ass because it's hard to upload things to Libsyn that are that big.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: And it's late and while I wouldn't normally be tired because I'm actually skipping work tomorrow anyway.
Speaker 0: You're skipping work tomorrow?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a dentist appointment and a doctor's appointment and an appointment with my new job.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm going into work for like an hour.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: I might not even go at all.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure yet.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't go at all.
Speaker 1: It's more that I, well, you know, we'll ask you.
Speaker 1: We're going to do the rest of this show on Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So for anyone who subscribes to just the Tuesday podcast, you need to come to frontroadcrew.com on Thursday if you want to hear us talk about the Wii and Microsoft and what they had to say.
Speaker 1: I may put it in a category so that it'll show up in both days, but I'm really leery of doing that and I probably won't end up actually doing that.
Speaker 0: So Thursday you'll hear the rest of this episode and it's not, remember it was all rim.
Speaker 0: So if you wanted a three hour podcast, let us know.
Speaker 0: if you wanted to three hour podcast, put all your blame on rim for not doing it and I'll take it.
Speaker 0: Tell him how, uh, you know, we'll see.
Speaker 0: He is for not doing it.
Speaker 0: If you didn't want the three hour podcast, say, come and tell us that, Hey, rim was right.
Speaker 0: We didn't want a three hour podcast.
Speaker 1: I can't wait till Thursday because basically I just worry that if it's that long, I mean, it either maybe people with small MP3 players love trouble with it or downloading it for people with not the greatest connections love trouble.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are plenty of, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I wonder what the longest podcast ever is.
Speaker 1: I'm going to break the freaking record dude.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: If there is a record, I could easily break it.
Speaker 1: I can generate infinite data.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I could probably make a thing that if you connected to it, it would just constantly stream audio to you forever.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 1: That would be fairly trivial to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but would it count as a podcast?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but actually I will spend some time tomorrow looking into how, how people with really, really, really long podcasts deal with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I haven't really seen any podcasts long.
Speaker 0: I think the longest podcast I've ever seen is like an hour and 40 minutes.
Speaker 1: And we're getting, we're getting, we're getting somewhat close to that already.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of a, I don't want to suddenly foist a giant one on you if it'll cause problems.
Speaker 1: That's my rationale.
Speaker 0: So for everyone so desperate to hear what Rym and Scott have to say about the Wii and the Microsoft and everything Microsoft had to say about Vista and the Xbox 360 and the rest of their games, you're going to have to wait till Thursday because Rym's a wuss.
Speaker 1: Eh, we'll see.
Speaker 1: We'll see what they have to say, whether they think it was a good idea or not.
Speaker 0: We'll see if they're even still listening at this point, but then I guess we know the answer, don't we?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, you know how you want to tell us, you want to send an email to geekknights@frontrowcrew.com or an audio feedback to that email, which we may or may not play.
Speaker 0: Or you want to go to frontrowcrew.com/forum and join our forum, or if you're already joined in it, post stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the forum's rocking and one, I'd like to give a general shout out to all the new people who have joined in the last like week.
Speaker 0: Yay, forums.
Speaker 0: They're having fun and constant discussions.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, once again, Thursday we'll continue with the Wii and at least an hour of talking about that, probably.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, we have a lot to say, but the nice overview will be simply that the Wii is awesome.
Speaker 1: They didn't say all the things we wanted them to say information-wise, but they still said a lot.
Speaker 1: It was very impressive.
Speaker 1: The Xbox was more impressive than you would expect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, considering that my Xbox 360 came out last year and last E3 was their big announce, they managed to add enough to it in this E3 to make me more interested in what they had to say than what Sony had to say.
Speaker 0: And that's pretty good, considering it's Microsoft, who I generally don't like on principle.
Speaker 1: This Shadowrun game, I want to talk a lot about.
Speaker 0: Alright, we'll talk about Shadowrun next week.
Speaker 0: Two days from now.
Speaker 1: Two days from now.
Speaker 0: So, go out and read a bunch of E3 news and that way, when you listen to us on Thursday, it'll all be old news to you and boring.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if nothing else though, watch what Nintendo did, if you can get to it still, because YouTube and everyone is having trouble.
Speaker 1: Since everyone's watching it.
Speaker 1: Watch Nintendo's thing, because we're going to talk about it.
Speaker 0: Go watch all three conferences.
Speaker 0: Watch the Sony conference, the Nintendo conference, and the Microsoft conference.
Speaker 0: Pay attention to the responses of the crowds, the quality of the production on stage, and how excited it makes you, the things that they're showing, and what the things that they're actually showing and saying mean for real.
Speaker 0: That's what you have to pay attention to.
Speaker 0: Don't get wowed over by, you know, CG renderings of demos that aren't actual games.
Speaker 1: I don't think they'll be wowed over by some suits talking about shipping numbers.
Speaker 0: No, they won't.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 1: Yep, and don't forget to let us know about the long episode thing, because I'm actually curious now as to what the feelings of our general listenership are.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't think we're going to have too many opportunities to do a long episode, except maybe a year from now at the next E3.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or maybe an Otacon episode, but...
Speaker 1: Otacon's going to be easy.
Speaker 1: We're just going to have Otacon Week.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Monday will be the video games, or the tech at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Tuesday will be the video games at Otacon.
Speaker 0: You want to do a theme week next week?
Speaker 1: Oh, what theme should we do?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's a robot theme I thought about.
Speaker 1: All right, anyone who's still listening, right now suggest themes to us, and we'll, whatever...
Speaker 0: Next week is going to be a theme week, for sure.
Speaker 1: And it'll be a listener pick.
Speaker 1: We'll pick it, but we'll pick something that you guys suggest.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, if you suggest something on the forums, or by email, we are going to pick a suggested theme for next week.
Speaker 0: Ooh!
Speaker 0: Wee!
Speaker 0: Xbox!
Speaker 1: And that was Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com.
Speaker 0: And if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights airs every weeknight, Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded with absolutely no studio, and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other talk shows, it's actually recorded at night.