Speaker 1: It's Thursday March 2nd, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We nominally talk about bad movies, but we also cover quite a bit of other stuff.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So it snowed today.
Speaker 0: I didn't go to work cuz it snowed.
Speaker 1: I went to work and no one else went to work.
Speaker 1: So all my meetings were canceled, and I left early.
Speaker 0: Yeah, things are going to work tomorrow, but I probably leave early as early as I can.
Speaker 1: yeah The sad thing was driving home.
Speaker 1: I expected you know although probably an accident on the freeway I'll be stuck forever, but no the freeway was fine.
Speaker 1: There was no traffic.
Speaker 1: I made it most of the way home, and I got in a little road that goes to our actual house and I saw this huge traffic backup, and I'm thinking great.
Speaker 1: There's an accident now.
Speaker 1: There was no accident.
Speaker 1: there was literally a little old lady in a little old car Driving as slow as her car would go And it's a lot of this line of traffic is rolling.
Speaker 1: I figure it like you know how you sit in a car an automatic transmission car.
Speaker 1: That's not that good especially older ones And they'll just kind of go if you don't touch the gas pedal or the bro.
Speaker 0: that that's supposed to happen.
Speaker 1: Uh not so much.
Speaker 1: It shouldn't like my laser a problem, and it would go.
Speaker 1: if you just let it it would get to about 25 30 miles an hour.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's too fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean cars.
Speaker 0: I'd let us you know very like thousand something rpm Maybe less than a thousand rpms, and you know if they're in gear They'll roll.
Speaker 0: follow.
Speaker 1: you realize that in gear is a vague term when it comes to automatic transmissions, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's the.
Speaker 0: if you have this if you're driving an automatic transmission And the stick is at the D or the OD that's in gear technically.
Speaker 1: no here's the thing.
Speaker 1: It's not engaged because you know when it's in D Even if you hit the brake the engine is not just pushing against the brakes so much it Moderates itself.
Speaker 0: yes, I know.
Speaker 0: now The point is is if the stick is in D, and you're not stepping on the gas.
Speaker 0: It'll still roll Unless you're going up a hill then it won't.
Speaker 1: a good car won't move so much.
Speaker 0: No, it won't move so much, but it will move.
Speaker 0: Actually not at all it.
Speaker 1: It'll move a tiny tiny bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if it's cold it won't move at all.
Speaker 1: And you know it's not really fully in gear because you can resist the cars forward movement And it'll just make the transmission heat up.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 1: But anyway this lady was probably just driving without touching the gas of the brake and letting her car pull her along.
Speaker 1: She was going less than five miles an hour.
Speaker 0: Okay, well like I don't matter what the conditions are if I'm driving on the rockiest No pavement mountain pass in the middle of the desert, but it's snowing and as a hurricane I will still go five miles an hour.
Speaker 0: I mean yeah, it was terrible.
Speaker 1: I spent more time I spent.
Speaker 1: I was I could see my house But I couldn't get to it because I was behind this little old lady and all these people who runs a little lady And I saw it was a little old lady because she finally turned out of her way.
Speaker 1: We all go on and I Drive and she's gotten.
Speaker 1: she doesn't gotten far at all And I could see the white hair coming up as I drove past.
Speaker 0: her shouldn't be allowed to drive.
Speaker 0: That's all I'm gonna say.
Speaker 0: listen to our driving episode from a week ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, shouldn't be allowed to drive.
Speaker 1: so a while back all the ISPs and media companies have started talking about how they wanted to in some way either provide better Speed to their customers or to people who pay them more money.
Speaker 1: You know that sort of thing like Comcast wanted to say slow down voice over IP traffic But then speed up its own voice over IP or another voice out for IP that wanted to pay Comcast money.
Speaker 1: Yep, and all the companies saw hey, we can make a lot of money with this and they were really going forward with it like it was a good thing and It's actually very bad thing for reasons We don't need to get into.
Speaker 1: we've talked about it.
Speaker 0: basically everyone other than the phone companies said it was a bad thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we not even the phone come it's just the providers like Comcast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the major ISPs of evil who own lots and lots of fiber and such.
Speaker 1: and it looked like AOL.
Speaker 1: Time Warner Thought it was a good thing too.
Speaker 0: Yeah geniuses.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we won't talk about the details because we've talked about it more than once on the show already now.
Speaker 1: senator Ron Witten Democrat from Oregon don't even know who he is.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'd never heard of him before but he's fairly smart and he basically said that this is crap and Congress should pass a law saying that you can't do that.
Speaker 1: and He's they've got a law and We'll see if it goes through Congress or not, but it'll basically prevent the ISPs from doing exactly this.
Speaker 0: Actually, I was watching You know a few videos of like committees, you know of senators doing stuff and a lot of people watch C-SPAN And they say oh Congress doesn't do shit You know, what are they doing?
Speaker 0: If you watch committee meetings like when they meet to talk about stuff all the senators are like actually Smart and doing shit.
Speaker 0: You might not like what they're doing, but they're doing well.
Speaker 1: the Senate and the house are two very different beasts.
Speaker 1: Well, they were intended to be two very different beasts But over time they've merged the.
Speaker 1: the house was intended to be kind of a high turnover, you know local issues advocating for your constituents Whatever.
Speaker 1: now most people don't seem to know this.
Speaker 1: in fact No one at my work knew it Because I talks.
Speaker 1: I said something about it and no one believed me and I just show I know what you're gonna say and I've known It since middle school.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's scary how many Americans don't know this?
Speaker 1: I mean I had to show them in the Constitution in the amendments where it was changed.
Speaker 1: But until recently well not recently but until recently historically at least Senators were not elected.
Speaker 1: senators were appointed by the state legislature.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you would vote for your.
Speaker 0: each state has its own government, you know your state government your governor and your state Congress and whatnot and You would vote for that, you know based on what state you lived in.
Speaker 0: So if you're in New York you vote for whoever.
Speaker 0: and then those people you voted for in, New York Would just pick their own senator whoever they wanted.
Speaker 0: They didn't have to pick who you wanted.
Speaker 0: They could pick, you know, someone you hated.
Speaker 0: That's how it worked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a way to.
Speaker 0: it was a good way to.
Speaker 1: well in some ways I mean part of the reason it was overturned is that there was a lot of corruption in this process.
Speaker 1: there was The millionaires Club because only millionaires became senators.
Speaker 0: Yes, but the solution to Corruption is not to change the system but to just you know justice increase justice.
Speaker 1: You can change the system to to make corruption less feasible or yeah But then you don't want to.
Speaker 0: you know, the point of having this was to have.
Speaker 1: Well, this is a tangent anyway, yeah, but the point is that the Senate 10 they tend to be more long-term people.
Speaker 1: someone would be on the Senate for many terms and Senators specialize.
Speaker 1: so the Senate is broken up in all these committees and each committee You'll have a bunch of senators on it and they won't know much about all the other things the Senate does But they'll be experts on their thing or at least they're supposed to be experts on their thing.
Speaker 1: Some people are some people aren't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty funny because I was watching the commerce technology whatever committee and they were talking about the broadcast flag on radio and The head of the committee didn't know what the hell was going on.
Speaker 0: He just kept asking questions and trying to understand and The smart congressman on the side who was all active on this issue Was you know talking it up and the three experts they had testifying towards before the committee.
Speaker 0: We're all talking it up and the head guy was like, I don't know and he just kept asking dumb questions And so he could try to understand what the hell they were talking about.
Speaker 1: now senator senator Whitten definitely seems to.
Speaker 1: you might not know The technology.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know much about this guy, but there's a quote here from him.
Speaker 1: That seems to tell all.
Speaker 1: the net has always been about Access and equal treatment and giving everyone a fair shake and people who own these fat pipes these cable and telecommunications People who say that they can't keep doing this want to undermine that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what it really comes down to is we're paying them for bandwidth.
Speaker 0: Everyone else is paying them for bandwidth.
Speaker 0: Everyone pays once.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna you can't make anyone pay twice.
Speaker 0: just you know, shut up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see what comes of it.
Speaker 1: I hope the bill passes.
Speaker 1: apparently it's got support from 16 Republican senators So it's definitely not a partisan issue.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone in Congress unless they've been bribed will want to go against this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a feeling it's just gonna go right through.
Speaker 0: I mean, hey, how could you vote against something like this?
Speaker 0: It's just you'd have to be evil.
Speaker 0: That's really If anyone explains it to you and you understand what they explained.
Speaker 0: How could you?
Speaker 0: What are you thinking if you vote?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you don't know that what we're actually talking about in detail read the link It'll tell you everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only reason we're not gonna talk about is we've talked about it multiple times already.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm So ABC, which is the major network owned by Disney that shows, you know, I don't know what they show because I don't watch TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know you're like that guy on FARC who tells everyone he doesn't watch TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let it go.
Speaker 1: We know you don't watch TV.
Speaker 1: We don't care.
Speaker 0: Yep, so Apparently, you know everyone puts their shows on iTunes these days and sells them for like three bucks.
Speaker 0: ABC is gonna try to.
Speaker 0: they're not doing it yet, but they're going to in the future.
Speaker 0: They've said so they're gonna put some shows on iTunes and give them away for free But they're gonna throw some commercials in there and I say woohoo.
Speaker 0: Well, just fast forward through those commercials, baby.
Speaker 0: Yeah Awesome.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I Can't run iTunes.
Speaker 1: Well, I can't easily access iTunes and Linux.
Speaker 0: No, but it does run in wine and a lot of people have it working.
Speaker 0: I couldn't get it to work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I couldn't get it to work.
Speaker 0: other people got it to work.
Speaker 0: But the point is is now you can You'll be able to get the TV shows download them.
Speaker 0: Someone else can you just give you the files or whatever, you know You won't actually have to Have iTunes to you just use a QuickTime player.
Speaker 1: Probably I guess the key is that there any shows I want to watch.
Speaker 0: You know, they didn't actually say which shows you know, at least they didn't say finally which shows that they're gonna show.
Speaker 1: I mean to tie into today's episode a bit.
Speaker 1: I mean, I there are TV shows that are good.
Speaker 1: I mean, I like Arrested Development freaks and geeks was cool all that but I like The Simpsons Yeah, but here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna watch them on TV and I really don't want to download them because honestly Netflix I can just get the whole DVD season whatever and just watch it at my leisure.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing is that you can already torrent all these things, right?
Speaker 0: So what's the reason to get them on iTunes with commercials instead of torrenting them?
Speaker 0: They're gonna have to like put the episodes out faster than the torrents come out or higher quality than the torrents or The torrents are already DVD quality easy to find very fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're gonna free.
Speaker 0: they're gonna have to like put them out before the episodes are on TV or something or else.
Speaker 0: What's what's gonna be the point of this?
Speaker 1: I mean, I mean their entire like all of like all the Family Guy torrents just out there everywhere.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing, you know, we.
Speaker 0: we say this, you know, what's the point this?
Speaker 0: torrents.
Speaker 0: But they're selling the episodes with no commercials for a few dollars and people are buying those.
Speaker 0: You know, not everyone.
Speaker 0: people are still torrenting but people are buying them.
Speaker 0: So and those have no commercials.
Speaker 0: So these have fewer commercials than on TV.
Speaker 0: Someone's gonna be downloading for free.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of people are gonna be downloading for free.
Speaker 0: It's just I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess we'll see what comes of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see but see.
Speaker 0: now Here's the thing is for someone like me who doesn't watch television.
Speaker 1: if there's a show Let me guess you don't watch television.
Speaker 1: Yep, so you don't watch television.
Speaker 0: if they come out, you know I don't go around looking for torrents of shows because you know, that's for anime.
Speaker 0: I do but brother stuff No, not really, but if a show is free on iTunes and I'm bored I'll download the first episode and like skim through it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good point, you know, so I might I mean honestly That's the only way we found out about shows now like Arrested Development, which even you admit it was enjoyable.
Speaker 0: It's all right.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: The thing is I never would have even thought to see this evil evil like.
Speaker 1: the show would have just been completely off my radar, but a friend of ours really liked it and Brought it over.
Speaker 1: me watched on DVD and I discovered that.
Speaker 1: oh, it's actually really funny and cool But I never would have found that out on my own.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now if I could just download random shows for free I think I would watch now that Scott mentions it at least one episode of anything before I knocked it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so plus now when the other thing is because I don't watch TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't watch TV, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know what people talk about.
Speaker 0: like people say stuff and I go what the hell you mean.
Speaker 1: Actually, what's scary is Pete my people at my work.
Speaker 1: They don't even talk about the TV shows but often they'll ask Hey, did you see that ad for blah blah blah?
Speaker 1: Whoa, and then they talk about the funny ad they saw.
Speaker 0: Wow Yep, but yeah Now maybe I can like in my spare time between listening to podcasts I can watch an episode of this or episode of that and at least I won't watch more.
Speaker 0: if I don't like it I won't watch any more episodes, but when someone's talking about something I'll be like, oh I know what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: And then I'll be able to insult them more if it was crap and Nod my head if it was something good you know As Opposed to going huh?
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: Are you talking to talking about?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so fucking steaks on a plane.
Speaker 0: So I think it's it's generally good for them to break their TV shows into the non TV watching people like me.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll see how quickly the advertisers get pissed when they realize that people will just fast-forward through the ads.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think ABC might have a good racket going because it'll be great for us and be great for ABC.
Speaker 0: This would be bad for advertisers.
Speaker 0: They won't know it because they have no way of knowing even now with television How many people buy their stuff because of ads.
Speaker 1: in fact, not only that but see before the internet and the whole I mean there was a time when there weren't pop-up ads on the internet.
Speaker 1: for all you young ins who don't realize this There was a time when if you saw an ad on the internet was like whoa an ad.
Speaker 1: This site must be like professional.
Speaker 1: they've got ads.
Speaker 0: Or this site is some drekkie people trying to make money.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to them, but when the internet came I mean before the internet Advertisers didn't really question that their ads were effective and there was really no real evidence as to how effective ads really were.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of the companies would pull out statistics, but Future recent studies have shown that a lot of those statistics were just made up or not entirely true?
Speaker 0: There is no.
Speaker 0: I mean We're pretty sure that when coke runs a giant ad campaign that it somehow gets people to buy more coke But there is no 100% sure evidence.
Speaker 0: I mean for all we know coke could just stop advertising altogether and close their advertising division entirely and The same amount of coke would still get sold.
Speaker 1: that we don't you know, so when the internet came They had ads.
Speaker 1: the thing is you could click on an ad and they could count how many people clicked on it.
Speaker 1: So the advertisers suddenly said hey Now we can see exactly who how many people are clicking on an ad we'll know exactly how effective that ad is.
Speaker 1: and Then they discovered that almost no one clicked on ads.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then they discovered that Oh People just fast-forward through ads.
Speaker 1: Oh people don't watch it.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Well, except for your co-workers.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so I don't know about that, but at least Younger people not to discriminate.
Speaker 1: but younger people seem to be more ad resistant.
Speaker 1: Here's the other thing though is except little kids who will buy anything that's shown to them on TV, of course.
Speaker 0: But like I remember some funny ads from when I did watch TV Like I remember the the classic one was the the Budweiser wacky waving inflatable arm flailing tube, man Yeah, that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: But I remember those Budweiser frogs were a big deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or remember was?
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of guys going.
Speaker 0: I also think I also remember that the bud ice when but ice was still around and they had that penguin and the penguin would Say do be do be do.
Speaker 1: Oh god that brought back memories of middle school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I remember that but I never drink.
Speaker 0: I don't drink alcohol.
Speaker 0: So I guess there I didn't work.
Speaker 0: I mean they just they gave me something to remember and talk about but they didn't sell me anything.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess the funny part there is that I remember the doobie-doo-doo penguin, but I had no idea.
Speaker 1: I had no idea what product they were selling until you said it was some kind of beer.
Speaker 0: It was but ice.
Speaker 0: it no longer exists.
Speaker 0: Oh good.
Speaker 0: They had you know, they were trying to add a new type of Budweiser.
Speaker 0: That was and I don't know All right.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: you can't ask me cuz I never drank it.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess my feelings on American beer.
Speaker 1: There's no beer in America, but he likes an all beer.
Speaker 0: the same tastes bad makes you drunk.
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh Ladies That's what it's about.
Speaker 1: So we normally don't report on actual real news in the world.
Speaker 0: Well, we have actual real news.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean it came up because it's.
Speaker 1: I saw it online out of the blue because I actually read your real news and if we Wanted we could probably do a real like political news show instead of geek nights and have just as much to talk about because we're Opinionated.
Speaker 0: yeah, I read Google News, but that's about it.
Speaker 0: You know, I try to get the big things But I don't really care about all the other crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well I read Google News But I read it fairly thoroughly and my custom Google News page has like 20 categories in it Just like catching various types of stories.
Speaker 0: I know I just like Eliminated the health category and I added and the and the famous people category and I added like four categories at the bottom.
Speaker 1: Well, I have story.
Speaker 1: I have categories likes and nerdiness like this and this and this or this.
Speaker 1: not this not this not this And usually there's not even a story in there.
Speaker 1: I'm just it's I'm waiting in case there's a story about it.
Speaker 1: So I'll know Wow Okay, but anyway this story I guess it fits into geekery bit partly because of what it's about but to which is something that really Kind of bothered me and I really think this sort of thing needs to get more press.
Speaker 1: but in Kenya And this is very recent and I think it hit Boeing Boeing or something Now Kenya is not like one of those backwater African countries.
Speaker 0: It's sort of you know, it's a pretty good place, you know It's not scary this there's no genocide.
Speaker 0: I know of though
Speaker 1: when I lived in Michigan way back when I was in elementary school and I was a Cub Scout I had a friend who had come from Kenya And I remember him telling me that Kenya was a horrible place and that he never wanted to return.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Well, it's not.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it's fantastic.
Speaker 0: Yeah far from it, but it's not like Rhodesia Darfur and What's the other place Rwanda, you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's like one of those step.
Speaker 0: it's it's a it's It's.
Speaker 0: it's a little bit less than Nigeria where all the scammers come from.
Speaker 1: Now I'm curious as to where you're getting this knowledge as to how nice Kenya is.
Speaker 1: I mean, do you know anything about Kenya?
Speaker 0: No, this is entirely based on the internet.
Speaker 0: So don't believe anything.
Speaker 1: I say Scott Where is Kenya?
Speaker 1: It's in the middle of Africa in the middle a Little bit north a little bit south dead center.
Speaker 0: Okay, anyway, hold on I'm getting so.
Speaker 0: so in Kenya it's on the it's on the right under next to Somalia I think under Ethiopia.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So anyway, what happened was in Kenya the newspapers and the media had been reporting on a lot of government corruption Because the government is fairly corrupt and they've been reporting on it.
Speaker 0: Well, our government that our newspapers don't report when our governments corrupt Well, maybe that's because it would fill the newspaper every day.
Speaker 0: Hahaha.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway, and It looks like some government officials lost an election as a result of this.
Speaker 1: at least they blame the loss of the election on This bad press.
Speaker 1: Ooh So what did the government do?
Speaker 1: they ordered the police to raid all these newspapers?
Speaker 1: Burn all their newspapers destroy their printing presses arrest all the reporters and destroy everything.
Speaker 0: Wow now how?
Speaker 1: Now?
Speaker 1: now here's the scary thing trying to hide it.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, that's the thing I mean, I'm not gonna say I agree with it But this sort of thing happens from time to time in nations and usually it's kind of secret like the government will hire You know a mob to do it or something
Speaker 0: or the company will just go bankrupt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but no no, here's a quote.
Speaker 1: This is from the Interior Security Minister John Michuki.
Speaker 1: He said quote in English if you rattle a snake You must be prepared to be bitten by it.
Speaker 1: and then in Swahili He said that this police raid was necessary to demonstrate state authority.
Speaker 1: It was a show of force.
Speaker 0: Well, they sure showed force.
Speaker 1: Yeah, police officers armed with ak-47 busted in said it was a raid without a warrant and then destroyed everything.
Speaker 0: How can you I mean?
Speaker 0: You you busted up a newspaper Because it was turning the people against you.
Speaker 0: So what do you do?
Speaker 0: you bust up the newspaper and To make more people turn against you and it's it's just like.
Speaker 0: how can you make more bad press?
Speaker 0: What you want to do is you want to?
Speaker 0: you want to lie and say no there is no corruption.
Speaker 0: Don't listen to that crazy lying newspaper.
Speaker 0: That's what you want to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently seven ministers lost Elections were fired or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know all the details.
Speaker 1: I don't know much about Kenyan politics, but this Not only have.
Speaker 1: the reporters that were arrested are probably going to be tried and jailed.
Speaker 1: Wow Now I'd say why aren't the people up in arms about this, but who's gonna report on it?
Speaker 1: How are they gonna know?
Speaker 0: Well, I think there's other newspapers, but those are the newspapers aren't opposed to the government.
Speaker 1: They're you know, I guess they're tool newspapers or in the very least They're not gonna report on it.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: cuz let's see that newspaper reported on it and got burned down.
Speaker 1: I'll let it slide.
Speaker 0: Well, if they were badass real newspapers, they would.
Speaker 1: Newspapers left.
Speaker 0: they get their pirate newspapers out on the street.
Speaker 1: I mean, I it's funny I got to say it but Al Jazeera is one of the few news agencies left in this world that has balls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least according to that movie we watched.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I've read more about him.
Speaker 1: I mean for what?
Speaker 1: they're not any more biased than the Western media are in my opinion.
Speaker 1: They're just biased in a different direction Yep, but at least I mean they'll stand there in the war zone and just take pictures of it.
Speaker 1: Yep Alright, so things of the day.
Speaker 1: my thing was kind of obscure when I found it But it exploded all over the internet before we did the episode tonight.
Speaker 0: I don't even know how that happened.
Speaker 0: usually this is the kind of thing you see on like one website in the back corner like Here's a crazy old video game.
Speaker 0: No one ever got.
Speaker 1: I mean I saw it because someone linked to it from a thread about something else in FARC and Then now it's on Boeing Boeing.
Speaker 1: It's on slash dot is everywhere.
Speaker 1: But I swear to you all it was a unique not easy to find thing of the day when I said something about it When I found it, but anyway,
Speaker 0: I found it this morning and then by the afternoon it was everywhere and I was like, oh wow Yeah, it's kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: But anyway Penn and Teller of the famous, you know Penn and Teller show and bullshit and all that they're awesome magic show and they're also awesome skeptics.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, they have this video game that they made a long time ago.
Speaker 0: For what system?
Speaker 0: the Sega CD and what other system?
Speaker 1: it was for another system.
Speaker 0: I think they said something about the 3do.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that helps.
Speaker 0: Yeah, awesome.
Speaker 1: So systems that no one had anyway and Apparently the game is one of those meta games where it's.
Speaker 1: it's a stupid funny game, but it's not really a game.
Speaker 1: I mean, here's an example of this game.
Speaker 1: I Someone said that apparently if you pause the game it forces you to watch like this two-minute movie That that's just dumb every time you try to unpause it to punish you or something.
Speaker 0: well, that's kind of crazy, but actually the Sega CD was all about that.
Speaker 0: because The Sega CD was you still had a 16-bit Sega Genesis, but you had six hundred and forty megabytes of software.
Speaker 0: So what they did is they filled it up with videos and CD audio.
Speaker 1: I remember playing.
Speaker 1: I think it was called sewer rats.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: that was one of these launch games I think because I remember that it came out.
Speaker 1: I went to funko land because I wanted to try this game and It was probably the worst game I've ever actually played.
Speaker 0: I was our worst game.
Speaker 1: Let me put it this way This is one of those mountain bike.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: I was gonna say it's a lot like that mountain biking.
Speaker 1: Oh my god in that I could not control where I was going and I wasn't sure if any buttons I was hitting at anything to do with my success in the game.
Speaker 1: Wow It's a lot like that, but the Sega CD.
Speaker 0: It's like if they had the space to store videos and had the space to put CD quality audio like actual Full audio like a CD.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it was a CD So one of the one of the game.
Speaker 0: well you can continue yeah, but the games themselves Since they concentrated mostly on the video and the audio Were a lot worse than Sega Genesis games and they really didn't have the ability to be much better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was the Sherlock Holmes game where it was basically just you watch movies Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But anyway this Penn and Teller game It's I guess it's claim to fame is that one part of it is called desert ride or desert bus And it was like part of this very simulator and they talked about how realistic it is.
Speaker 1: and basically it simulates you driving a bus Through the deserts of Nevada for eight hours and then eight hours back.
Speaker 1: All right You do it in real time.
Speaker 1: It literally takes eight hours.
Speaker 0: and then eight hours How does can you save?
Speaker 1: no, I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: all I know is it's a straight road in the Nevada desert and Apparently every now and then you'll see a cactus go by and that's it.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I'll just you know, put something on the a button and walk away.
Speaker 1: Oh So, uh, apparently the bus drifts to the rights and If you don't keep staring it back to the left, it'll crash and you'll lose.
Speaker 0: So if you crash you have to start over again at the beginning of the eight hours, I believe that's the case.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, so who does anyone actually completed this?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Is there anything after this eight-hour bus drive in the game?
Speaker 1: The rumor out there is that if you completed it, you got one point toward completing the game whatever that meant.
Speaker 0: Well, so you could kind of choose things to do and get points.
Speaker 1: I guess I think the game.
Speaker 1: I mean I haven't played it.
Speaker 1: I'm just going off of what I've read in the car.
Speaker 0: I downloaded it, but I have to.
Speaker 0: I need it.
Speaker 0: I either need a Sega CD or I need a Sega CD emulator.
Speaker 1: It seems that it's a lot like The old Monty Python games where you can't just do a whole bunch of random stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh Those that's my best guess.
Speaker 0: I have one of those is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Once we get this game going and we figure out how to play it We're gonna play it and we'll report back.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's crazy.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: a lot of people have a little trouble waking up in the morning.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know I'm guilty of wake up turn off the alarm sleep wake up too late.
Speaker 1: I did that today In fact, I woke up thinking well, first of all, I stayed up to like three and then stay up till three Don't ask.
Speaker 1: so then I I I decide all right, it's supposed to snow tomorrow supposed to snow a hell of a lot.
Speaker 1: I'll wake up at seven.
Speaker 1: I'll see the snow and I'll just go back to bed.
Speaker 1: I wake up at seven I look out the window.
Speaker 1: There's no snow.
Speaker 0: Yeah I always I thought the same thing and I was like there's no snow.
Speaker 0: but I could see the snow was gonna be there soon.
Speaker 0: And I said, you know what?
Speaker 0: I have to drive home.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna delay myself an hour.
Speaker 0: I'll wait an extra hour before I leave the house and Good enough by the Time the hour was over there was some snow and I said yup if I were to go to work I would get there just fine, but getting home would suck ass.
Speaker 0: so I didn't go.
Speaker 1: now me I looked out the window and laid back in bed thinking god damn it.
Speaker 0: God damn it.
Speaker 1: Now I got to go to work and then I fell asleep and I woke up two hours later Awesome, and then I drove to work in the snow because while you know snow whatever I live like ten minutes away from my job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I live ten minutes, I would have gone to work as soon as I woke up.
Speaker 0: Just whoop.
Speaker 0: No question Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I got there to find that no one else came to work and I did a little work and all my meetings were canceled.
Speaker 1: Then I came home.
Speaker 1: Like I said earlier by the time I tried to drive home.
Speaker 0: It had snowed a hell of a lot Yep, so I was correct in my assessment of not going to work.
Speaker 0: But the point is is that if you have this problem where you wake up and your alarm wakes you up but then you turn it off and you fall back to sleep and you're screwed and You can't seem to get into the habit of using the snooze button to you know,
Speaker 1: the snooze button is evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't use it.
Speaker 1: It'll just make your life miserable.
Speaker 0: actually lately I've been using the snooze button because I've never used it before in my life and now I can use it and it works Because I've never used it before but as soon as it stops working, I'm gonna stop using it.
Speaker 0: That way I can keep its effectiveness.
Speaker 1: What effectiveness?
Speaker 1: all I find is I lay bed.
Speaker 1: I wake up and I'm at there.
Speaker 1: either two states either.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess three states.
Speaker 1: I want to get up and I can get up.
Speaker 1: I Don't want to get up, but I can get up.
Speaker 1: I neither want to get up and I don't want to get up and I can't get up.
Speaker 0: Well, you see when I wake up I usually get up enough and then I turn.
Speaker 0: I used to turn the alarm off and Then I would lay back down sometimes if I didn't get up right away and then cuz the alarm wouldn't go off again I was done.
Speaker 0: forget it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I lose.
Speaker 1: see most people use the snooze button as they're laying there and the alarm goes off and they hit it and then they Think all right I can sleep for nine more minutes and then I'll get up and then they hit it and then they sleep for nine more minutes And then they hit it and then they sleep for nine more minutes and then an hour goes by.
Speaker 0: Oh, no See what I do is when I hear when I be alarm goes off my brain says I'm up I'm going but sometimes I'm gonna lay back and if I start to lay back I hit the snooze button and that way You know in ten minutes I get another shot at it and I've never done it more than twice Like by the second try on this news, I'm always up.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the point is people have this problem.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of solutions to this problem.
Speaker 0: There is one person who made something called clockey.
Speaker 1: Oh, is that the clock that jumps off your?
Speaker 0: It's like runs around the clock with carpet and wheels and it and when the alarm goes off it zips around the room and finds A hiding space and it makes a loud noise.
Speaker 0: You have to go and find it and there's another one.
Speaker 0: It's a helicopter.
Speaker 0: So as soon as the alarm goes off this little helicopter takes off and flies around your room when you have to go get it.
Speaker 0: But there is one today that I thought was really good.
Speaker 0: at the top of the clock are for puzzle pieces and One of them is part of the clock, but the other three when the alarm goes off, you know, how perfection goes.
Speaker 0: pop it just pops these puzzle pieces out and they fly around the room and you have to go collect them and Put them back into the slots in the correct, you know fashion in order to get the alarm to shut up.
Speaker 0: So you're guaranteed to get up if the alarm is loud enough because I haven't heard it.
Speaker 0: obviously This thing is guaranteed to get you up because there's no way that you can find those puzzle pieces wherever they went and Put them back correctly in the top of the clock without being awake.
Speaker 1: See I've had friends who would put the alarm clock across the room and they would quite literally get up walk over turn the alarm Off walk back to the bed and fall asleep without even remembering.
Speaker 0: I found the distance doesn't really help so much unless it's a really long distance and I like to have it close because that way I can look at it more easily, you know Yeah, because you can't see very far with your eyes like one half a millimeter open.
Speaker 1: I love that time if you if you wake up in the middle of the night You don't expect to and you're not fully awake, but your eyes are working and you know You kind of stare at the clock, but you can't figure out what those symbols mean.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've had that.
Speaker 0: Or like you see the time and you know the numbers of the time, but you don't know the time You don't know what that means.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not really quite fully Digesting the numbers.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The worst is when you wake up at a time that you didn't expect to wake up.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah figure out what time it really, you know Like you wake up and it says like three something and you're like you're staring at like.
Speaker 1: did I sleep till three?
Speaker 1: Or did I wake up at three?
Speaker 0: Yeah stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah One time I actually woke up at like seven o'clock at night And I thought it was seven in the morning and that I had accidentally slept through the previous day.
Speaker 0: I can always tell the story about how I went to Washington DC for a week on a trip in eighth grade And I came back and I went to sleep and I woke up in the morning and I you know ate breakfast and whatnot and then I went back to sleep because I was so tired.
Speaker 0: then I woke up again and my family was Gone and I thought I thought that I had slept that through the second night into the next day and I ate breakfast again When it was actually just the afternoon of that day.
Speaker 1: So wasn't our friend Greg who stayed up for like 18 hours playing Final Fantasy and thought it was like night?
Speaker 1: Then you thought it was morning.
Speaker 1: It was actually the next night or I forget that story.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It happens all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hopefully the puzzle clock will save you
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least for a month and then your brain your muscle memory You'll figure out how to find the pieces put them together and put you back to sleep,
Speaker 0: dude If you can do that we got to upgrade to like the eight piece puzzle and then eventually we'll have like a 5,000 piece jigsaw puzzle and you'll be just like Put it right back to you.
Speaker 1: If only I could train myself to wake up and do my job.
Speaker 0: for me, dude that would be the best like an alarm clock.
Speaker 0: that like has your job done for you and it undoes your job and then you Have to do it and then you can go back to bed.
Speaker 1: I could do I could technically do that.
Speaker 1: I could just set up a bash script that would break a random thing on my computer and make a noise until I fix it.
Speaker 1: hmm, I Mean my job's IT.
Speaker 1: So that's the closest thing I could do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it might damage your computer though, like delete a file.
Speaker 1: Oops Yeah, I can imagine an alarm blaring at 6 in the morning and I'm trying to recreate like my NTP cough.
Speaker 0: Oh great Yeah, that's not a that's a little going too far All right, so anyway we're likely said wait, I just had thought okay What if a doctor did that?
Speaker 0: it like it like hurts someone and you have to heal them?
Speaker 1: That's uh silly.
Speaker 1: yeah, you're like Gabe With his allergies.
Speaker 0: I thought of a great one.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make this you ready?
Speaker 1: All right, we'll see if you make it.
Speaker 0: Check it out.
Speaker 1: We'll see if you're a shit talker.
Speaker 0: We'll see if I'm probably gonna be a shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that all right, let's hear it.
Speaker 0: So you get a Gameboy or something and the alarm goes off.
Speaker 0: Won't shut up until you beat a level or something.
Speaker 0: Ah Yes has an alarm.
Speaker 1: Maybe we can hook that up, you know, if we get a flash card or a dev kit or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you wake up, you know, the DS is making a shit ton of noise cuz that's thinking it loud.
Speaker 0: You know whose cell phone could do this to?
Speaker 0: actually because they have alarms in video games And then there's like a hard video game thing and until you do it, it won't shut up beat cut man in Mega Man 1.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that that kind of thing are you really good?
Speaker 0: or like beat 1-1 in Mario and then every day you get a different Mario Level or even just a short one like a WarioWare game, dude That would be great cuz freakin.
Speaker 0: you know you could beat a video game like that where if you had to do a level every morning or Like you had to do one level of Tetris every morning and it got harder every single day until you huh?
Speaker 1: Though if the game were Final Fantasy Tactics, I'd kill myself.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll talk about that next.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah Or actually you could train that in with you know, the there's those train your brain games there come over here.
Speaker 0: I think they're coming over real soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I see I mean there's a huge market for that especially for like older people who want you know It's train their brain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually one.
Speaker 0: when you actually see what these puzzles are I don't think we're gonna be too interested in them.
Speaker 1: No, we're not but other people will.
Speaker 1: yeah But I could see games like that for people like us in in the future.
Speaker 1: Like I'd love to see a DS game.
Speaker 1: That was you know learn Japanese Hmm or yeah something like that.
Speaker 1: but imagine if you had to wake up in the morning and like say you're doing the learn Japanese one.
Speaker 1: you wake up and your DS is making noise and you have to like.
Speaker 1: it shows you a word.
Speaker 1: You have to write it in hiragana in order to make it shut up.
Speaker 0: You know we should do.
Speaker 0: we should make a computer program for the PC or whatever called like morning exercises and you can like.
Speaker 0: they will sell different expansions for different kinds of exercises and That way you can force yourself every morning to do certain things and you can program in how many minutes you want to spend doing it Your morning routine.
Speaker 0: so you can be like I want to spend five minutes every morning improving my you know puzzle solving skills in this kind of puzzle.
Speaker 0: and then maybe you're you don't get one of those chess puzzles or a word search or a crossword and It'll you know make you spend five minutes doing crossword every morning and you'll get better and better at it.
Speaker 1: You know it's not a bad idea, and it won't shut.
Speaker 0: and the thing is it won't shut up until you do it because you know That's what gets you up in the morning.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of thing we could actually do in our spare time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we should do it now.
Speaker 1: now all you listeners out there Just heard this.
Speaker 1: now this illustrates a good point about Scott and I about shit talking.
Speaker 1: yeah that we have Conversations like that.
Speaker 1: we probably had four or five of them today, and we forget about them immediately.
Speaker 1: But now because we're in front of these microphones all of you out there Just heard our shit talking.
Speaker 1: so you can call us on it when we don't do this.
Speaker 1: yep But I think we should try to do it.
Speaker 0: Let's.
Speaker 0: I think the DS is or a cell phone is really the bell.
Speaker 1: consider this.
Speaker 1: we can't get a dev kit from Nintendo Just because we're not a company.
Speaker 1: We don't have any established.
Speaker 0: when you get one of those little flash cart DS thing is a lot of people.
Speaker 0: There's already Linux running on the damn things.
Speaker 1: yeah But say we made a demo of this game on the PC.
Speaker 1: then we went to Nintendo and said hey Look at this we could do that for the DS.
Speaker 1: They give us a dev kit and and and will.
Speaker 1: well you can have all the profit whatever.
Speaker 1: we just want to make these games.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm let's go for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: We'll see if we're shit talkers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh wait I think I see something coming out of your mouth.
Speaker 0: Oh It smells like poo.
Speaker 1: Hopefully Sony will send us some Krispy Kremes.
Speaker 1: Alright, so we've gone long on just about everything else, but that's fine because we did that on purpose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, partly because our topic today yesterday.
Speaker 1: We thought oh, it's great.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about terrible movies, then we realized don't have much to say about him.
Speaker 0: well Let's say what we got to say about terrible movies now alright, so uh Speed 2 is a bad movie.
Speaker 0: yet, so the movie industry in America Lately has been making like the percentage of movies that are just no good has been increasing steadily.
Speaker 1: Garfield Catwoman kangaroo jack Snakes on a plane.
Speaker 1: yeah Garfield Deuce Bigelow European gigolo.
Speaker 0: Yeah a sequel.
Speaker 0: I think Bigelow.
Speaker 0: I come on what the hell.
Speaker 1: I think there was a speed three.
Speaker 0: What the hell.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: Disney's making Bambi - what the hell isn't that.
Speaker 0: give me a VHS though?
Speaker 0: They make everything up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know I saw like Aladdin 7 or whatever what I thought they're only three Aladdin's.
Speaker 1: I know there's at least three.
Speaker 1: I think there's a fourth one.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I know they're at least 12 land before times.
Speaker 0: Oh my god See.
Speaker 0: I think what it is is they don't want it.
Speaker 0: movies are more and more expensive to make these days and They want to put less and less risk when they make them so they won't do anything outlandish.
Speaker 0: So they end up doing the same crap over and over again because there are enough stupid people To pretty much pay for the crap like just barely now.
Speaker 1: the reason we decided to talk about this is that now this The thing we're about to talk about has been around on the internet for a long time over a year.
Speaker 1: It's called snakes on a plane.
Speaker 1: and the basic story damn god damn motherfucking.
Speaker 1: snakes on a plane.
Speaker 1: Yeah And it's not a goddamn thing.
Speaker 1: You can do about it Alright, so to sum it up because you this is all over the internet if you haven't seen it by now I hate to say it, but if you don't know about snakes on a plane already I don't care how hip you are.
Speaker 1: You're not with the internet at least not as a Technorati kind of person.
Speaker 1: Now I'm not saying the snakes on a plane is a funny thing or a cool thing.
Speaker 1: it's actually a stupid thing.
Speaker 0: It's real stupid.
Speaker 0: I don't even think it's funny at all, but rim keeps saying it and it's kind of damn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's annoying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically this movie called snakes on a plane.
Speaker 1: apparently that was the working title and they were gonna name it something else later and The plot is basically to sum it up.
Speaker 1: There are snakes on a plane.
Speaker 1: Like really that's all there is to this movie.
Speaker 0: You know when he told me that I was like, oh that sounds like a scene in a movie.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone you know thought up a scene for a movie couldn't find a movie to put it in and just made a whole movie But just the scene.
Speaker 1: so apparently Samuel L. Jackson heard about this movie and was all about it.
Speaker 0: Wow, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what that guy's thinking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe he's having fun Maybe it's just.
Speaker 1: this is all just a scam and it's actually a big internet based promotional viral marketing kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I Hope it's all just a giant joke.
Speaker 0: That'd be hilarious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if the movie doesn't actually come out knowing Hollywood, this is totally plausible.
Speaker 0: It's not even yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, it's in the IMDb and such and there are pictures from it and someone claimed to have seen it and reviewed it.
Speaker 1: Whoa Or saw like a pre advanced copy or something.
Speaker 0: Wow Just just well, you know Who is who are the people behind this stuff?
Speaker 0: thinking this up thinking it's a good idea and doing it?
Speaker 0: Who are these people?
Speaker 1: These are the same people who are making money?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I point out that Garfield made money.
Speaker 1: Wow Garfield God That movie looked painful from the moment.
Speaker 1: I heard it was going to happen.
Speaker 0: I mean Garfield.
Speaker 0: the comic hasn't been funny in like over ten years ever and The the funniest Garfield thing ever was the Halloween cartoon special.
Speaker 0: Yes with the pirates the ghost pirates that tried to frickin kill Garfield and Odie Yep, and the best part was when they went up to houses and they weren't even like trick-or-treat.
Speaker 0: He was just like gimme.
Speaker 1: Yeah I should put that in Netflix and we'll watch it again.
Speaker 0: That's a good one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean basically there.
Speaker 1: I mean there are good movies out there.
Speaker 1: I really want to see jarhead.
Speaker 1: I want to see a scanner darkly.
Speaker 1: I heard the corpse ride was amusing.
Speaker 0: I never heard any of these three.
Speaker 1: Yeah we were talking before the show and Scott was like no good movies come out in like ever and I was thinking back and I could think of a whole bunch of Good movies that I want to see or that I did see.
Speaker 0: I can't think of anything since like Narnia Lord of the Rings I don't want to see that the last Harry Potter movie.
Speaker 0: Don't want to see that either.
Speaker 1: You suck.
Speaker 1: You suck serenity.
Speaker 1: Nope Yeah, anyway, well, I guess you don't watch movies either.
Speaker 1: mister doesn't watch TV.
Speaker 0: I watch movies when they're good or there's something to be excited about.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: I have cautious optimism.
Speaker 1: No, you don't.
Speaker 1: you poo-pooed every movie I mentioned and yeah, I was talking.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about the V for Vendetta movie.
Speaker 0: That's coming real soon.
Speaker 0: I have cautious optimism.
Speaker 0: Okay that one but about all of them.
Speaker 0: all the other movies I even know I'm just like whatever Alright, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So we decided not to talk about that because it's basically Scott doesn't know about any movies coming out and doesn't like any of them.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: The point is is that we're just pissed off that Hollywood makes so many bad movies.
Speaker 0: What are they thinking?
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: more importantly.
Speaker 1: It's more that we don't go to movie theaters anymore And we used to fairly often.
Speaker 1: the thing is the only.
Speaker 1: well Actually, I've been going to movie theaters more often lately, but not to see Hollywood movies but to see either serenity, which was the last movie I really wanted to see in a theater and All these anime movies.
Speaker 1: just cuz we live near New York City and I can go down and actually see Anime movies in the theater.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, like it's so weird The last time I was in a movie theater at all.
Speaker 0: I think was when he went to see episode 3.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: no, we want to see steam boy.
Speaker 0: Was that after we saw episode 3?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure Yeah, and then so I guess he's a house house moving castle after that, right?
Speaker 1: I guess I lost track.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we saw all those in the theater, but we watch mostly anime movies in theaters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like some time around when I got to college, you know early on in college You have to see movies at like Tinseltown Semi-frequently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I note that other than one movie which we went to just because it was dumb most movies We went to were like we were.
Speaker 1: we were we were looking forward to see the movie Yeah, and we were looking forward to seeing it in the theater, which is a separate component.
Speaker 0: It was always like the matrix something or Lord of the Rings something or the Star Wars something.
Speaker 0: That's what we were going to see there.
Speaker 1: Now while there are a lot of movies that come out that I like or that I want to see here that I'm really interested In there hasn't been a movie since Serenity that I wanted to see in a theater or that way.
Speaker 1: I even considered worth the money To go to a theater to see there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like there are plenty of movies and even though I don't find out about them some of them You know They go up high enough on the scale when I do find out about them to be like willing to watch on DVD.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: But there aren't many.
Speaker 0: It's actually they're horrendously few that make me get up out of my chair and go to the movie theater.
Speaker 0: We must go now.
Speaker 1: The problem with that is that the movie industry seems to be blaming the fact that theaters are doing really poorly on Piracy and they blame it also in home theater.
Speaker 0: So like if you wouldn't get the home theater experience at home Why would they go to the theater the real theater?
Speaker 1: Yeah Not only that but the fact that theaters show ads before movies Angers me in a way that that it really shouldn't anger me as much as it does but it does.
Speaker 0: that's like the worst thing Ever like.
Speaker 1: oh, no The worst thing ever was.
Speaker 1: I was at a movie and usually when the ads come on we crack jokes Loudly because you know their ads whatever.
Speaker 1: Someone actually yelled at me to be quiet while I was making a joke about the ads before the movie.
Speaker 1: Wow I laughed so hard.
Speaker 1: I about peed myself.
Speaker 1: I just didn't know it should have peed on them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was really the proper Social thing.
Speaker 0: didn't do anything else to say right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I had to say something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whenever someone angers me in public I'll pee on them.
Speaker 1: That's quite a plan there.
Speaker 0: You know what if I was just so badass that like no one could mess with me?
Speaker 0: That's like to someone who was so terrible like the worst person ever.
Speaker 0: I totally just be on them.
Speaker 1: No No, there's a better thing.
Speaker 0: They'd be like, what are you gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: You go Horatio horn-blower on him you challenge him to a duel They cheat and yet you still beat them and then you've decide not to kill them because it's not worth it And only ruling wasn't illegal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course, then he'll try to kill you again, but captain Pele will shoot him from afar.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just ruined the first episode Horatio horn-blower, but whatever no one cares.
Speaker 1: Here's your horn blowers fantastic.
Speaker 1: And if if you care that that was spoiled for you, you've already seen it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so The thing is is that it's not has nothing to do with me Like it's still very possible to get me excited about going to a movie theater.
Speaker 0: I mean, like I just said I'm like I'm slightly Optimistic about this V for Vendetta movie and if like some people decide to go and I've got nothing better to do I just might.
Speaker 1: yeah I just might go but definitely the movie theater experience has degraded in the last ten years to a point where It's almost impossible to make me want to go to a theater.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Lord of the Rings was like woo.
Speaker 0: I'm going no matter what and if it came out now, I'd still feel the same way.
Speaker 0: I'd be like get up let's go.
Speaker 0: Lord of the Rings in the details goes goes go.
Speaker 0: but Now the movie quality.
Speaker 0: just know the ads.
Speaker 0: so, you know, just know the price.
Speaker 1: Yeah now at least in general I mean in New York City I can see a lot of cool movies in the theater and I'm all about that and I go to the.
Speaker 1: I used to go To the air fairly often.
Speaker 1: I haven't been to the city in a while.
Speaker 1: I've been busy But yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: I remember we went down there once to see Anime movie in the in the little theater there and they had a little sign that was like at midnight We're showing Ghostbusters and I was like dude, if this was a theater the closer to my house I would be there in a second.
Speaker 1: Yep The problem is only the only cool theaters that are left are in the big cities.
Speaker 1: So most people they don't have the option to go to a cool theater like that.
Speaker 1: They either have the crap dollar theater that smells like pee or something like the dollar theater near us smells like pee really.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not like the nice dollar theater in Rochester.
Speaker 1: No, not like that one.
Speaker 0: We saw Powerpuff Girls for 25 cents.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got to say that was probably the best value per unit entertainment I have ever received in my life.
Speaker 0: We should get the DVD for that.
Speaker 0: I want to see it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah Everyone hasn't seen it.
Speaker 1: The Powerpuff's movie is good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all dark and yeah, like it sounds stupid that oh It's dark, but it actually is.
Speaker 1: it's serious, but it's also funny.
Speaker 0: I also like the TV show a lot, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like the TV show.
Speaker 1: I like Dexter's lab a lot.
Speaker 0: Oh, thanks We should.
Speaker 0: I think all that stuff's on DVD like samurai jacks on DVD - you know what.
Speaker 1: I'll put it all in the queue.
Speaker 0: Yeah, go get Netflix the Cartoon Network.
Speaker 1: Yo, yeah, even though our queue is at the point where we're not gonna see anything We put in there for like two years.
Speaker 1: awesome See that's the other thing that's killing theaters.
Speaker 1: in my opinion is that of course It's also I think gonna start hurting the anime industry a lot.
Speaker 1: and then I keep talking about Netflix and I swear they're not paying me.
Speaker 1: but Before if I wanted to see something I either had to go to the theater or I had to buy it.
Speaker 1: I had to go to Blockbuster.
Speaker 1: Blockbuster generally sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah now Netflix.
Speaker 1: I don't buy anything anymore.
Speaker 1: I've bought maybe two DVDs in the last year Not counting the dollar DVDs when media play went out of business.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: only buy DVDs if it's something that I got to own like I bought all of initial D or and I'm proud You know or if it's something so crazy like if
Speaker 1: it's something that I'll watch again and again
Speaker 0: Yeah, or if it's
Speaker 1: something
Speaker 0: if to someone
Speaker 1: yes Give to someone else's key a lot of shows I want to own just cuz I want to lend them to other people
Speaker 0: or something that there won't be a chance to get like.
Speaker 0: I bought that macross box set.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was a good buy.
Speaker 0: now You can't get that shit, even though I paid over $200 for it.
Speaker 0: You can't get that shit now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now you got to buy the re-released one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the ADV re-release that's coming out now Probably for more money with a crummy dub on it.
Speaker 1: What do you care about the dub?
Speaker 0: I don't but that you know, the point is is that I got the real deal and I'm proud of it.
Speaker 0: I'm glad I got it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so.
Speaker 0: But the thing is is I don't think the deep that Netflix really is killing the theater because we stopped going to the theater long Before we got the net.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Netflix is definitely just like one more nail in an already sealed coffin.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: I mean, you know if it wasn't for that I would like if we suddenly got Netflix and stop going to theater I'd be like, oh obviously
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess I I think back outside of anime movies and Just crazy like weird movies like when I saw that nothing lasts forever movie in like a cool indie theater.
Speaker 1: There's maybe two movies a year that I actually want to see in the theater at this point.
Speaker 1: out of how many movies are released Every year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how many movies released every year?
Speaker 1: a lot?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh You know what?
Speaker 0: I think back in the day like I remember even when I was a little kid in the 80s Movies like were different.
Speaker 0: like you would go there and there would be an intermission and it was sort of fancy.
Speaker 1: I only had one intermission at a theater ever and that's when I went to see Kenneth Branagh's Hamlet there And they did the intermission because it's a frickin four-hour movie.
Speaker 0: when I was a little kid We would always go to the movie theater and there was always an intermission like until at some point in time Like intermissions just stopped happening.
Speaker 0: But every movie had one even the 90-minute movies it Wow.
Speaker 0: And there would always be a cartoon at the beginning like a Bugs Bunny or something.
Speaker 1: Wow I never had cartoons at my theaters either.
Speaker 0: really I think if they bring the old style movie stuff back like take all the seats out of the movie theater and put like little tables with chairs around them like in little nightclub places and You know have little.
Speaker 0: you know, you get coffee or whatever little cafe action in there, huh?
Speaker 0: And then You know bring the cartoon back before the movie get rid of the ads throw an intermission in there.
Speaker 0: You know, if you bring it back to the old school, you can still charge the same price that you do now.
Speaker 0: Well, actually a little bit more.
Speaker 1: you may not know this but there's a growing market in adult movie theaters Not adult movie theaters, like you know, what used to be on time square 80s But apparently there's a lot of them in Texas now.
Speaker 1: I think it's a chain because people talk about on FARC all the time But basically they're theaters that one don't allow minors in period so no kids and They actually have ushers.
Speaker 1: So like if someone's a jerk or talking or on their cell phone, they'll just kick them out.
Speaker 1: awesome, like immediately.
Speaker 1: like sir you have to leave and The other thing is they're also a restaurant so you'll sit down you can order like food and beer and some drinks Reasonable prices because there's actual a restaurant there instead of a concession stand like before and during the movie.
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool Yeah And I'd like to see this trend grow because if there was a place like that within driving distance of me I might go to a weekly or like if they had some sort of extra cool.
Speaker 0: you get a place like that Right now.
Speaker 0: the there's still the problem that there aren't really movies They want to see.
Speaker 0: that solves every problem with the theater.
Speaker 0: But there's still the problem of I'm not gonna go If there's some crap movie that kind of ruins it.
Speaker 0: like you're eating a fancy dinner and then this crap comes on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but here's the thing.
Speaker 1: say there's a movie that's worth watching like not crap But just a movie that's worth watching and we were gonna go out to dinner.
Speaker 1: Anyway, cuz you know, whatever Saturday Oh, we totally go there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz it doesn't cost that much more is here's the vision I just had you ready?
Speaker 1: Alright instead
Speaker 0: of waiting for good movies to come from Hollywood cuz I don't bet a lot on that What you do is you instead of selling, you know tickets you sell memberships You become a member and like members come there once a week or so or something like that and they show.
Speaker 0: They don't show new movies.
Speaker 0: They show whatever movie they find or want to show and they only show something good.
Speaker 0: So like we're gonna show this this week and it's a movie you might already know or maybe you know The kind of things that are in our Netflix queue.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know, maybe so, you know just always something good.
Speaker 0: They'll never show a crap.
Speaker 0: movie SARS Wars Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: maybe something that no one knows about.
Speaker 0: maybe something everyone knows about.
Speaker 0: You know loves me, you know just mix it all up and it'll be you know, always fun to go and hang out and Watch all kinds of movies instead of just watching.
Speaker 0: You know wait the movies and for the Hollywood movies only cycle out like every few months, you know.
Speaker 0: So this will be a much faster Cycling if there's a different movie every week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd like to see this trend at least of these types of places grow.
Speaker 0: yeah, for sure.
Speaker 0: cuz I mean I Don't know.
Speaker 0: it is like a recent thing where when I was a little kid or even before I went to college going to Movie theaters people didn't yell in the movie theater.
Speaker 0: Everyone shut up, you know They'd laugh at something was funny and they scream if it was scary, but people were quiet.
Speaker 0: yeah sometime around college like this gradual change where people started to yell shit out and You know cell phones.
Speaker 0: All right, whatever someone forgot to turn it off.
Speaker 0: Maybe you have a real asshole and they answer it actually a lot a lot of times.
Speaker 1: There's the asshole who answers it and then just talks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's something else, you know cell phones technology.
Speaker 0: That would have happened anyway, but more people just yelling like when we went to see episode 2 Long after it was already, you know We saw it well after and some guys in the bag were just yelling shit, you know, and they were yelling funny shit.
Speaker 0: but the point is is like People are more free to be kind of assholes in the theater.
Speaker 0: now, I don't know what it is.
Speaker 1: I Could make a lot of social commentary.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll save that for another day.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know when it's.
Speaker 0: I'd like to try to figure out exactly when it started happening and what the cause was and You know what?
Speaker 0: Maybe when a certain generation became old enough to get to the movie theater on their own.
Speaker 1: I think there's just a a Picture on FARC that I saw a while ago that basically epitomizes exactly what I think is the root cause and it shows a gravestone And the name of the gravestone is personal responsibility And there's a whole bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 1: it was a there was a lot of stuff to this picture, yeah, but yeah I mean a long time ago if someone was a jerk in a movie theater There's a decent chance that someone would just pop him and that would be the end of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that doesn't happen anymore.
Speaker 1: No, if you do that you go to jail now, not that I agree with the popping No, but there it was just not agree with the deserving of the popping.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but not the pop.
Speaker 1: It's like when that that friend of ours got into a fight at Otacon over some stupid crap and the Otacon staff after the fact in the back room were like man You don't start a fight.
Speaker 1: I mean, especially not in the con.
Speaker 1: That's not cool.
Speaker 1: But god damn that kid deserved it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's one thing to say someone deserves violence like that guy deserves to be shot.
Speaker 0: But it's another thing, you know to actually shoot him because it's like, okay, you might deserve it But you don't shoot people because it's wrong no matter if they deserve it or not, you know, yeah Basically, it's hard to explain that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it seems like you know what?
Speaker 1: It's easy to explain.
Speaker 1: you watch try gun.
Speaker 1: Yeah But basically it seems more that in recent years it's become less and less of a social stigma to be an asshole.
Speaker 0: Well is the thing though is like I'm an asshole you're a different kind of asshole and I you know I don't care there's a bracelet is a rudeness.
Speaker 0: But you know, I don't care about what you say only care about what you do.
Speaker 0: But but just making noise when someone's trying to pay attention to a movie.
Speaker 0: Well consider matter of politeness and rudeness.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is.
Speaker 1: It's a night to not be loud.
Speaker 0: Well, it's.
Speaker 0: it's a matter of actually, you know creating a physical disturbance not just upsetting someone's feelings.
Speaker 0: You see the point?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I see your point But the point is that people have gotten this idea that I mean, I believe in a free society.
Speaker 1: I believe that everyone has the right to be an asshole an idiot a jerk whatever the hell they want to be.
Speaker 1: If you want to be an ignorant horrible racist asshole, that's your prerogative and I'm fine with that because I don't have to like you Or talk to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact knowledge.
Speaker 1: I have the right to ridicule you if I want Yeah, if you want to believe in some horrible things, you know would run around jihad, whatever.
Speaker 1: or if you're like oral Robertson Pat, you know just recently said that Jews can't get in heaven.
Speaker 1: Whatever you can say whatever you want.
Speaker 1: But the thing is just because you can't do something doesn't mean you always should.
Speaker 1: I mean I can just start yelling in a movie theater.
Speaker 1: It's the movie theaters right to kick me out and it's everyone else's right to not like me and hate me Mm-hmm, and there you.
Speaker 1: it used to be that people would at least avoid That sort of behavior when they knew it would cause a problem or at least there was a stigma about that sort of behavior.
Speaker 1: I mean if you talked in a movie theater, everyone would look at you like what the hell?
Speaker 1: But now people just do it.
Speaker 1: people just start doing these things all the time.
Speaker 0: I think part of it might be our like detachment from Strangers like you go to the movie theater with your friends and the only people there that you really acknowledge are your friends.
Speaker 0: So if your friends are all about being quiet, you're gonna be all about being quiet.
Speaker 0: But that makes sense.
Speaker 0: if your friends are all about yelling, you'll be all about yelling and strangers.
Speaker 0: You don't give a shit Yeah, and I remember like when I was a kid we would talk to neighbors on the street.
Speaker 0: You would be like, hey, what's up?
Speaker 0: I knew who they were.
Speaker 1: Well, we never did that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we knew.
Speaker 0: you know, it was and people around town We're friendly like you could just walk down the street and say hi to people, you know, you'd even know him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well I'll point out that I grew up in like the other America.
Speaker 1: I grew up in like suburbia suburbia like black hole Sun suburbia.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and All our neighbors like we didn't talk to anyone because we really I hadn't.
Speaker 1: we had nothing in common with any of our neighbors at all.
Speaker 0: We don't really have as much in common with them other than that.
Speaker 0: They were our neighbors.
Speaker 1: Well, our neighbors were all like the homeowners Association types and they'd sit around and the only time they'd ever talked to anyone is like I see you're putting up a fence.
Speaker 1: Yes, I am.
Speaker 1: I Don't think that offense is really a good thing to put up in this neighborhood.
Speaker 1: You know that sort of talk Yeah, or you know, they'd.
Speaker 1: actually we've gone long.
Speaker 1: So I guess I'll end here with a funny anecdote.
Speaker 1: So when I was a kid, I had a cordless headset.
Speaker 0: phone was called Thursday's nostalgia day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that seems to be what we're doing today, but I had this heads.
Speaker 1: I don't think I told this story had this headset phone and it was cordless and it wasn't a cell phone.
Speaker 1: it was just a cordless headset phone that I used all the time because I talked on the phone a lot and I would climb out onto my roof from my window at night and just kind of like hang out up there and talk to my friends on the phone.
Speaker 1: the neighbors Talk to my parents one day and they asked what was wrong with their son with with me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently he.
Speaker 1: they saw me walking around on the roof yelling at people like yelling voice yelling at voices or something.
Speaker 1: They didn't know that I was on the phone.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and they couldn't conceive of the fact that I was on the roof.
Speaker 1: The point I was gonna make before I got way off topic and told an anecdote was that all my life Most of my friends until I got to college were all over the world because my friends were based on like interests and similar culture and I didn't make friends based on geography because most of the people around me weren't interested in anything I was interested in.
Speaker 1: Then I got to college and there were a bunch of people around me who were interested in the same things.
Speaker 1: We formed this tight group.
Speaker 1: Now we've all spread to the wind again.
Speaker 1: And now all my friends are far away.
Speaker 1: I don't know anyone other than I know two people in the entire city that we live in But I know hundreds of people all over the country and almost every city just everywhere and I'm better friends with them than I am with people who Live 20 feet away from me.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I mean, I'm better friends with.
Speaker 1: you know, people like I have nothing to say to these strangers I've.
Speaker 1: I mean every now and then I get I talked to someone but I never really engaged them.
Speaker 1: I don't remember them.
Speaker 0: You don't engage them, but you kind of like acknowledge them and you know, you have a sort of.
Speaker 0: There seems to be like this More detachment from people around you like it used to be people your friends are your friends and your family is your family But at least people who are near you.
Speaker 0: you had you know Something.
Speaker 0: some like loose connection with anyone happened to be near you and it was positive.
Speaker 0: See, I've never had though there seems to be like this like this like if someone's near you and you don't know they are.
Speaker 0: They don't exist.
Speaker 1: See I guess I've never had that.
Speaker 1: I've never had any sort of connection to the people who were close to me Geographically, yeah, I mean I never knew my neighbors.
Speaker 1: as I said when I was a really really little kid living in downtown Detroit I knew all my neighbors, but I never knew neighbors.
Speaker 1: I was growing up as a kid.
Speaker 1: I had all my neighbors.
Speaker 1: now when we lived at RIT Not only did not know my neighbors other than the horrible deaf people upstairs.
Speaker 1: Now none not.
Speaker 1: they're not horrible because they were deaf They're horrible because they were horrible and they happen to be deaf.
Speaker 0: See I would know our neighbors around here.
Speaker 0: We had more of them like I know the old lady next door and the old lady downstairs.
Speaker 0: We don't really have any other name.
Speaker 1: the most I knew about any of our neighbors back We lived in college was that the neighbors next door knocked a hole in their wall once and I saw it through their door.
Speaker 1: Yep Just I didn't even know anyone in my major at RIT.
Speaker 1: I didn't know anyone in my major other than one of my friends who happened to be in the major But I knew him outside of the major.
Speaker 0: I know I knew plenty of people in my major.
Speaker 1: I didn't know anyone.
Speaker 0: quite a few they were.
Speaker 0: they were on the acquaintance level.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: you know who they are.
Speaker 0: You know their name you give them a nod when you see him.
Speaker 0: You know you say hello meet-and-greet small talk, but not like hang out go hang.
Speaker 0: You know do stuff with.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean I guess to me equate.
Speaker 1: I had very few Acquaintances like that.
Speaker 1: most of the acquaintance I had were from other things.
Speaker 1: they weren't from proximity.
Speaker 0: They were yeah, I got a lot of acquaintances.
Speaker 0: like you know I see people all the time.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, I know you from somewhere.
Speaker 0: Hey All right, see you I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't really engage acquaintances unless I'm you know it's like a fan of a show or Like back when I ran the club when it was people who knew me because I ran the club.
Speaker 1: But other than that I just don't engage people.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean, I don't.
Speaker 0: it's it's not about really so much engagement when it comes to the movie theater.
Speaker 0: It's about Like just it's the time.
Speaker 0: They don't the existence of the other people and the fact that they're there.
Speaker 1: I guess I really don't.
Speaker 1: I'm guilty of that.
Speaker 1: well But at the same time I'm generally Quiet in movies, so I don't cause a problem.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'm also the quiet in movies.
Speaker 0: But also what I do in movies is you know I try to like the wish.
Speaker 0: you know because when we watch a movie at Home we always say funny stuff, or you know depending on the movie of course yeah, so when we're in a movie theater I'll always try to like you know whispered to the friends next to me like oh my god.
Speaker 0: You see that.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, scotch that guy.
Speaker 0: yeah, but I don't you know I don't think The people next to me and usually my friends can hear me.
Speaker 0: It's like if I whisper to the friend on the right.
Speaker 0: sometimes the friend on the left gets pissed But usually the people in the front of me and back of me don't seem to get pissed.
Speaker 0: So you know I try to you know keep it quiet.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: anyway, it was a rambly episode, and I think we're about done here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what you get when it snows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not only did it snow, but we've got a crazy weekend planned with all our friends are coming out.
Speaker 0: Yeah Next week, we're gonna start.
Speaker 0: I think our themed weeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not sure what theme we're gonna do next week But we're doing something something awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the theme week will really help us Keep up put up the quality back up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the quality's been up pretty good except.
Speaker 1: I think the penny already the content.
Speaker 1: I mean I think the contents been alright That's alright.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you guys they've been in the past.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've had some good episodes.
Speaker 1: We have some crap episodes.
Speaker 1: That's the problem with doing you know for podcasts a week is that the quality will vary depending on you know?
Speaker 1: Everything in the world.
Speaker 0: yeah, I think that you know that's something we got to accept.
Speaker 0: But I really think the theme weeks will also help us try to figure out what to do.
Speaker 0: and we're like.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to do on Thursday.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Because Tuesday and Wednesday are cake and Monday is cake.
Speaker 1: now because we got a whole list of things we can do.
Speaker 1: Thursday is just up in the air.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but and we all the things we've got planned for Thursday We're still working out.
Speaker 1: You know getting the interviews prepared getting the research and material together.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's all kinds of stuff where it's like.
Speaker 0: Oh, we should do that.
Speaker 0: Oh, we have to research something, and then we never do because our lives are so rushed and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it said, but if we did a one day a week podcast It would be the longest most well researched awesome podcast in the world.
Speaker 0: Probably it would did three days a week.
Speaker 0: It would be so it would like.
Speaker 0: the quality would go up like a zillion.
Speaker 1: yeah We're not gonna cut down anytime soon though because everyone who listens seems to really like the four day a week deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus this will keep it so like anyone new comes along.
Speaker 0: They'll be stuck away in the back archives.
Speaker 0: It'll look really impressive when we have like a hajillion episodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah We've got 68 episodes not counting the secret episodes that none of you were ever going to like their podcast that started in like 2004 and such that don't even have a hundred episodes yet.
Speaker 0: They're still like struggling you know and whatever.
Speaker 0: huh eat my ass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean at least we got through all the hurdles of podcasting very quickly.
Speaker 0: yeah eat the dust.
Speaker 0: that's what I was trying to say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why did you say ass?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like saying ass ass.
Speaker 1: yes, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com, and if you want you can leave us a voicemail.
Speaker 1: at Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.