Speaker 0: It's Wednesday October 25th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We tell you everything you'll need to know about the new upcoming anime pumpkin scissors.
Speaker 0: We're also still lacking our new compressor so expect slightly degraded audio quality.
Speaker 1: Let's do this All right, so since there isn't any anime manga comics news that I could find I'm gonna resort to the super awesome Anime news network.com poll.
Speaker 0: great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right the current poll is.
Speaker 1: of The titles covered in our fall 2006 preview guide which one are you looking forward to the most?
Speaker 1: It is no surprise that the number one most look forward to anime is death note with 568 votes as of right this second that I am recording this.
Speaker 0: that was pretty much guaranteed to be the case.
Speaker 1: that's 46 and a half percent But you know who cares?
Speaker 1: that's obvious that it was gonna be even though it is.
Speaker 1: look at the graph rim.
Speaker 1: Look at this.
Speaker 1: the next anime after death note is nine point two percent Compared to forty six and a half.
Speaker 1: so if I was an anime company bringing anime over to the US Death note is obviously gonna be a profitable license to acquire.
Speaker 1: Nothing else looks like it's worthwhile.
Speaker 0: now everyone might think well Why doesn't some company just license it right away and go with it and start releasing it in the u.s.
Speaker 0: And the answer is that most likely the Japanese company involved.
Speaker 0: if they allow anyone to license it anytime soon Well one charge some crazy amount of money with many millions and two They're most likely going to have a clause in the license saying that they can't actually Release the DVDs in America for like a year or two after the show is shown in Japan.
Speaker 1: Yep You know cuz you know re-importation all that jazz.
Speaker 1: however I think what's more interesting to note than the extreme popularity of death note compared to all the other anime that are coming out in Japan right now is the rest of this list.
Speaker 1: compared to the rest of this list the second most anime which I just mentioned is nine point.
Speaker 1: two percent of the votes is Canon 2006.
Speaker 0: wait wait wait wait wait.
Speaker 0: Canon.
Speaker 0: as in that series of porn games The same the same the same.
Speaker 0: God.
Speaker 0: Canon is not good.
Speaker 0: I don't can.
Speaker 0: is the party one, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's the one that mega Tokyo guy likes.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the most popular anime coming on Japan right now among Americans?
Speaker 1: Well among Americans who go among Americans who were big anime fans who read anime news network Death Note.
Speaker 1: and the second most popular is a perverted game.
Speaker 0: So one turned into an anime a small self-selected statistically insignificant sample.
Speaker 1: It's still scary Whatever.
Speaker 0: I mean kagehime probably did really well Yeah, probably probably made back its money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there I mean there are people still watching bleach and there of course bleach at least and Dragon Ball and all that I understand of course.
Speaker 0: then again, I guess I understand all these horrible porny shows, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well next on the list is negima Which is one of those one of those shows that you look at it and you say that's gonna be popular with the anime fans Even though it's terrible.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean like pumpkin scissors that we're gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: Yeah bit Well, actually that's it's quite surprising.
Speaker 1: pumpkin scissors is one, two, three, four, five six seventh on the list.
Speaker 1: It falls under.
Speaker 1: let's see.
Speaker 1: after negima is Chevalier.
Speaker 0: Hooray Even though I must say Chevalier started out Fantastic as in this show has got everything I want out of any show and he continued as good Yeah, as opposed to continuing is fantastic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the way you said.
Speaker 0: I thought you said you continued just as good.
Speaker 1: No, no, no as good.
Speaker 1: it continued.
Speaker 0: good a little bit of Gonzo there a little bit after Chevalier is that?
Speaker 1: Clamp robot show whatever something else and then pumpkin scissors and then something else and then Oh D gray man Which I thought would be really popular But I guess not.
Speaker 1: and then bartender the show that I want to do well and then crap I don't know.
Speaker 1: and then black blood blood brothers are just crap God.
Speaker 1: and then crap crap crap crap crap.
Speaker 1: So at least the crap is at all at the bottom of the list generally, but Bartender needs more votes that that's and it needs less votes.
Speaker 0: a self-selected Crap sample because most people who download fan subs don't go to that website.
Speaker 0: They just download everything.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I would tend to think there is a strong match between fans of downloading people and anime news network visitors.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: The only way to really know the popularity would be to watch the seeds and see what's getting downloaded when?
Speaker 1: Yeah, as a tough call because a lot of people will download every single episode of something, you know Even if they don't even if it's not their favorite show or if it's not the one show they're looking forward to the most.
Speaker 0: That's also a really weird, I mean a lot of people probably didn't know what all the shows were.
Speaker 0: I was really looking forward to pumpkin scissors until I saw it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is according.
Speaker 1: This is of the titles in the fall 2006 preview guide.
Speaker 0: So but also when is when I mean this polls going on right now?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I voted today looking forward whatever.
Speaker 0: most people have already seen the show They voted for and they obviously watch Death Note first.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was the actually most anticipated one.
Speaker 1: The other thing is this is you're talking about which show are you looking forward to the most?
Speaker 1: a lot of anime fans probably watch A bunch of these shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just had to pick the best one of them.
Speaker 0: There's also the fact pumpkin scissors, which I think is gonna end up doing pretty well Even though I think it's gonna be a really bad show.
Speaker 1: Yeah We'll talk about that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but it really kind of came out of nowhere and no one was looking forward to it.
Speaker 0: It's just gonna come out and everyone's gonna go.
Speaker 1: Ah I really wonder.
Speaker 1: Here anime just sort of jumps out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: It's like here's the new anime is what it's called in Japan.
Speaker 1: Is there some sort of build-up to these shows?
Speaker 0: Well Funny you should.
Speaker 0: I mean, I remember way back in high school.
Speaker 0: I found a video of Some clips from eska flown a a while before it, you know was released in the u.s.
Speaker 0: This is back before you could really get fan subs easily.
Speaker 0: So there was at least for in America for this show and it looked like in Japan too.
Speaker 0: because I ran into a lot of Fansites.
Speaker 0: I couldn't read long before the show seemed to even come out in there talking about this show.
Speaker 0: That's coming.
Speaker 0: the show called eska flown a a collaboration between names.
Speaker 0: I didn't recognize with art by name.
Speaker 0: I don't recognize because I didn't know anything about anime back then.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I at least and my friend group of friends were excited about it for almost a year before it came out in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the problem is that they do that in the u.s.
Speaker 1: All the anime companies make trailers for all their shows, but those trailers come out way after the fan subs come out.
Speaker 1: So they're kind of useless.
Speaker 0: Well, remember when we went to anime next right and they were showing, you know, we've got the Japanese guest.
Speaker 0: Here's what's on TV Right now in Japan and I have the audience was like we've seen all this.
Speaker 0: I'm watching that show right now.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you exactly?
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 0: Oh, well Yeah, we will have to do a whole episode on the state of the industry and fan subs and bootlegging and downloads and all.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's sort of one of those mandatory things that every anime podcast has to talk about and every anime website has to have an article on.
Speaker 1: and You know, you can't everyone's got to say their piece.
Speaker 1: No one can just let it be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though I'll say that in terms of this specific specific issue Most of our opinions pretty much mirror the opinions of anime world orders.
Speaker 0: You can check them out Mostly anyway, at least in terms of the causes of the problem.
Speaker 0: Yes, not in terms of the solution.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's what's your news?
Speaker 0: so So Guitar Hero 2 is coming out is out.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm really interested in Guitar Hero, but I don't have the console that plays it So I haven't played it yet ever.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm gonna pick up a ps2 Awesome when it gets less than a hundred bucks Awesome.
Speaker 0: I might pay up to $100 for a PlayStation 2.
Speaker 0: That's what it's worth to me.
Speaker 0: There are about seven games I want to play on the ps2 and a hundred dollars divided by seven because I can borrow all these games from people Plus the money to buy Guitar Heroes guitar and another guitar.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm buying one guitar.
Speaker 1: I'll buy one of those third-party guitars.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: I don't know what I'll do.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll get the real good.
Speaker 0: I mean you may I buy a controller for your GameCube.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna buy a wiimote for your Wii so you can buy a Guitar Hero for my guitar.
Speaker 1: You'll see we'll see.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah Guitar Heroes 2 is good, you know.
Speaker 0: now that's not the news.
Speaker 0: No one needs to know anything about Guitar Hero 2.
Speaker 0: The news is that one of the bonus songs is none other than trogdor the burninator.
Speaker 0: I'm really liking this trend of Awesome things from the internet being recognized by smart people in companies and being integrated into popular culture.
Speaker 0: You know really I mean it already sucks to be a peasant.
Speaker 0: and then you got trogdor.
Speaker 0: Okay, anyway, it's in the game as a bonus.
Speaker 0: I guess that's a spoiler.
Speaker 0: unlock it probably I don't know with magic Magicals see I like back in the day like DDR.
Speaker 0: You know how you unlock things.
Speaker 0: play DDR more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's all it was songs.
Speaker 1: Just I'm pretty sure that's how Guitar Hero also works.
Speaker 1: It's just you have to play it a lot and then songs unlock.
Speaker 0: Granted I haven't actually watched homestar runner in over a year - yeah me either.
Speaker 1: Like I saw I would watch ever religiously go to the strong bad email every single Yeah,
Speaker 0: pretty much from the sixth or seventh strong bad email until about I don't know the 80th
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then just interest waned and I just stopped visiting and I I know it's still there.
Speaker 1: I still think it's cool I'm still a fan of his a homestar runner.
Speaker 1: I'll still say holy crap.
Speaker 1: and and you know Crazy good night coach.
Speaker 0: He's got money but not much.
Speaker 0: see that's where it is.
Speaker 0: The moment the homestar runner peaked for me is when the CD came out.
Speaker 0: That was like the absolute peak of my fandom of homestar runner and then it fell into sharp decline.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the homestar runner didn't do anything worse or better It just did more of what it was doing and I got tired of the same thing.
Speaker 1: We sort of like we just watched acid ninja.
Speaker 1: someone sent us a link and I realized when I first discovered ask a ninja I was super into it and I was laughing hysterically and every time a new one came out for a few weeks I was laughing hysterically and watching them as soon as they came out.
Speaker 1: But now I didn't really care cuz I've seen that joke before.
Speaker 1: it's just the same joke told differently.
Speaker 0: Well, actually the ask a ninja humor is pretty much the same as the strong bad email humor.
Speaker 0: It's a guy saying something like this and it's all funny.
Speaker 0: You know cuz blood and something relevant to the thing going on.
Speaker 1: and ah, yeah It's pretty much the same humor.
Speaker 1: and I don't know I. there was a new ask a ninja.
Speaker 1: We just watched it and I didn't laugh so much.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: There was one point where I really started laughing.
Speaker 1: I gotta admit but it's not bad.
Speaker 1: It's just you know, it becomes harder for them to make me laugh.
Speaker 1: they have to do more.
Speaker 1: they have to Change it up a little bit more, you know instead of throwing the same fastball.
Speaker 0: So if you happen to be a person who likes guitar hero And if you're not well, you're not a person because everyone likes guitar hero, even though we never played it We know it's good.
Speaker 1: That's how good it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I've only watched other people play it.
Speaker 0: I played it once when I was a little drunk at a convention.
Speaker 0: No, and it's really fun.
Speaker 0: What can I say?
Speaker 0: From what I remember?
Speaker 0: Things of the day which someday I'll be able to say loudly again Possibly tomorrow or the next day.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean we order that new compressor.
Speaker 0: It's it's pretty badass.
Speaker 0: I think it's a double compressor.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: We're all out of the single compressors.
Speaker 1: We are to the double power.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they had a four power, but it wasn't as good as the double power anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so thing of the day it you know Halloween is coming up.
Speaker 0: then next week is Halloween.
Speaker 0: In fact Halloween is also the one-year anniversary of geek nights and it will be the beginning of season two of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Oh noes.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know we might have to push off the luke crane interview to do a special episode But maybe not.
Speaker 0: we're not sure what we're gonna do yet.
Speaker 1: I say we just start doing more geek nights and call season two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: We've got some surprises in store some changes.
Speaker 0: Oh, no Yeah, some things people might like but I might not like.
Speaker 0: I had a thing of the day I was saving for Halloween but since Halloween we might do something else.
Speaker 0: We're not sure.
Speaker 0: I'll use it today because Halloween is coming up and it really fits the season.
Speaker 0: This is a video of Every single death in the entire Friday the 13th series from start to finish in Chronological order showing nothing but the death scene itself quickly.
Speaker 1: Remember, that's not Freddy this Jason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got him confused has been a while.
Speaker 0: Not night.
Speaker 0: Well, actually Yeah, it's not Nightmare on Elm Street.
Speaker 0: It's you know, Friday the 13th.
Speaker 0: Yes Jason kid who drowned Comes back and kills everyone.
Speaker 0: the first movie was actually really good with that twist at the end that Scott doesn't remember.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean what I saw these movies and I was real little barely remember them never saw them again cuz whatever Yeah, that was that the final scene in Friday the 13th when I was a little kid scared the ever-living piss out of me Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Of course, you know movie actually scared me a lot when I was a kid was Halloween.
Speaker 1: this movie I was always scared.
Speaker 1: It was the one with the boogeyman the one where they go boogity boogity.
Speaker 0: Oh, mr.
Speaker 0: Boogity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mr Boogity scared me too, but it was awesome.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: There's like that Cape right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then they beat him in the end with the dry vac.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, there was mr.
Speaker 0: Boogity, too.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 1: yeah, we got to get that shit.
Speaker 1: I've seen it mr Boogity - is really all I remember was this scene where there's a guy floating down the hallway With like he's.
Speaker 1: he just floated out of bed and it was horizontally floating down the hallway and he's like boogity boogity Boogity boogity.
Speaker 1: just kidding.
Speaker 0: See the thing about those movies.
Speaker 0: and it's pretty much the same thing that Project a co did for me when I was a kid and all sorts of other movies that I saw when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I didn't get it.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Boogity is a comedy.
Speaker 0: It is not a scary movie But to a little kid you take that movie at face value.
Speaker 1: You sure do that movie.
Speaker 0: I thought it was horror.
Speaker 0: I was afraid I was worried about what was gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Mr Boogity was this demon thing and the second one was creepy and serious.
Speaker 0: and you know I just I took it straight up and now I'm older and I just realized that it's not a serious movie at all.
Speaker 0: And project a co was not a serious anime.
Speaker 0: There was no plot there.
Speaker 1: No project a co was just a comedy.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know, I'm beginning to see a lot of different ways that kids experience things differently from adults like.
Speaker 1: I just found out that as you get older you lose taste buds and that's why kids like some foods and adults don't like them.
Speaker 1: and it's kind of funny because you always see like my grandpa will eat some like incredibly hot pepper and He'll be like, yeah kid.
Speaker 1: Why don't you eat this?
Speaker 1: It is like and the kids like no way.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, you're a wuss.
Speaker 1: It's like no he has a bajillion more taste buds than you when I have.
Speaker 1: when he's as old as you he can probably eat Pepper just fine.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah physical changes cultural changes.
Speaker 0: But the point is these movies were a lot scarier when I was a kid and we got off on a tangent about you know Other movies.
Speaker 1: Well, there's not much to say about the thing of the day itself other than it's really fucking gory and awesome.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll say one thing one about most of the deaths.
Speaker 0: I'd say three-quarters of them are kind of real like.
Speaker 0: not really realistic in what happens in them But realistic in the way that like the people just kind of die in a kind of realistic sad way Cuz you don't have all the horror movie build-up around it.
Speaker 0: It's just a bunch of people getting stabbed and screaming.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I guess I also realized that a lot of people die in the Friday the third.
Speaker 1: Oh god, there's a lot of freaking kills man.
Speaker 1: A lot of kills shots.
Speaker 1: You'll see more kills in this video than you will in a game of quake.
Speaker 1: Yeah Mortal Kombat or anything?
Speaker 1: All right, my thing of the day is a short short video from Japan And it looks like they're advertising a new product which is only known as the boob Keeney.
Speaker 0: now The funny thing is Scott was sat down in my room with his laptop and we're getting ready to do You know pre-production.
Speaker 0: go over what we're gonna talk about on the show.
Speaker 0: Look at the news.
Speaker 0: do the thing that if you listen to the penny arcade podcast, that's what we do.
Speaker 0: We just don't record it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and while we're sitting here Scott says oh my god, I got a thing of the day and before you can say anything I say it's that boob Keeney, isn't it?
Speaker 1: And then sure enough it was And is anyway the boob Keeney.
Speaker 1: first of all This video is real hot.
Speaker 1: if you have a penis and you are not fond of other penises or maybe you're you know Bye and you swing both ways, but you will enjoy this video.
Speaker 1: It's short, but it is quite enjoyable.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it shows this girl swimming in a pool and she has a normal bikini bottom on but for a top.
Speaker 1: It doesn't look like she's wearing anything because the video resolution is kind of low.
Speaker 1: But when she gets out of the pool, you realize it's no normal bikini top.
Speaker 1: It is a boob Keeney.
Speaker 1: It looks like these two plastic suction cups that just kind of stick to the boobs and don't really Restrict them or hold them in any way.
Speaker 1: They just kind of stick on to them to cover them up and they're flesh colored Outstanding.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this girl seemed to be swimming around feeling pretty good.
Speaker 0: See, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm of the mind that laws against public nudity aside from laws that Specifically are for health reasons.
Speaker 0: Like you shouldn't be allowed to be naked in a restaurant.
Speaker 0: Yeah or walking in the mall But if you're at the beach You should be able to be naked if you want to be naked in the very least.
Speaker 1: why they have nude beaches?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there aren't any nude beaches in South Jersey, yeah, I see I'll be happy with nude beaches.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean if you have a private beach you can make it a nude beach, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So this that's okay.
Speaker 1: First of all, second of all public nude beach, you know The only problem I see with that is I don't want to have to look at some nasty fat guy.
Speaker 0: See whatever?
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: but cuz you should have a nude beach.
Speaker 1: They have to have a non nude beach, you know Doesn't have to be.
Speaker 0: you can do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: There shouldn't be a law just because someone you don't want to see.
Speaker 0: you know, the thing is you see the fat guy Anyway, he's not wearing much to begin with.
Speaker 0: That little bit isn't gonna make a difference.
Speaker 0: And second, I mean imagine this this really puts it as I mean.
Speaker 0: as guys we don't think about it.
Speaker 0: We just go to the beach where in basically nothing but some little shorts and ah.
Speaker 0: But because of the puritanical laws in America all the women whether they want to or not have to wear something on top.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure Imagine if you had to wear something on top every time you went.
Speaker 1: was the other predicament of the nude beach is You know, if you're used to go into nude beaches the problem probably won't happen to you.
Speaker 0: Um, I know where you're getting at and I actually I read a Wikipedia a while ago.
Speaker 1: Okay, what'd it say?
Speaker 0: Apparently nude beaches.
Speaker 0: that happens all the time and even people who go to him a lot.
Speaker 0: It just it happens a lot and Everyone who goes to a nude beach is for the most part adult about it and you know why it's happening.
Speaker 0: It's obvious why it's happening and no one says anything.
Speaker 0: You just don't Bother with it.
Speaker 0: Don't stare at it.
Speaker 0: It's not like everyone's gonna point and laugh.
Speaker 0: Haha.
Speaker 0: He got an erection.
Speaker 1: Lol, what if I start playing with it now that crosses a line?
Speaker 1: See that does indeed cross a line I know but I might want to cross that line if I want to cross some other lines if I find some agreeable females on the nude beach The ones I was looking at.
Speaker 0: Actually nude beaches tend to very much discourage that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Well, that's why it's next to the hotel.
Speaker 0: Aha, then that doesn't cross a line or what?
Speaker 1: if you know, I have my little boat floating in the water near the nude beach or a Little tent.
Speaker 0: well Scott, I'll tell you this if you can make it out to international waters You can do whatever you want hot damn.
Speaker 1: Let's go to some new beaches.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I just want to say it's for talking about nude beaches.
Speaker 1: in the winter It's getting cold out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: while I might feel bad about getting cold We lived in Rochester for a number of years and I've been told by numerous of what one of my friends because I don't get A chance to talk to a lot of people who live there anymore that it is snowed at least multiple times.
Speaker 1: We haven't had snow yet.
Speaker 1: Whoo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it hasn't snowed.
Speaker 0: In fact, it only frosted once and then it got really warm again.
Speaker 1: It's gonna snow I bet within a month and a half.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's a fantastic bet.
Speaker 0: I'll take you right up on that.
Speaker 1: So wait.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So tonight on, you know compressorless geek nights We're gonna talk about pumpkin scissors.
Speaker 1: Like we said we talked about last week How much pumpkin scissors did we watch one episode?
Speaker 0: You know what now first off?
Speaker 0: We've.
Speaker 0: we've mentioned kind of to the side the gonzo syndrome.
Speaker 0: anime world order has talked about this too and They're the ones who really made us fully aware of it because I started thinking back after I heard about Gonzo syndrome and looking at all the shows that exhibited it and then realizing that they were indeed all gonzo shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: Originally the first gonzo show I ever saw was gatekeepers Which is their first full-on show.
Speaker 1: before gatekeepers gonzo did animation work But never a full-on anime TV series.
Speaker 1: and then I looked at the internet at you know The list of shows that they had done And I said, wow Either these are shows that I was really interested in but turned out to not actually be shows for all time Or they were just bad shows at best.
Speaker 1: I think a couple of these shows are a little bit average You know, it's like they have all this fantastic amazing animation.
Speaker 1: They have you know, pretty interesting character designs.
Speaker 1: Everything's all shiny and high-tech and it really impresses you when you see the trailers and the previews for their shows because They seem to be in the right genre.
Speaker 1: They're not.
Speaker 1: you know, you don't usually make harem shows or Stupid shounen fighting shows.
Speaker 1: they make shows that sort of have normal plots in her seem like they're gonna be interesting But in the end you go back, you know 2020 hindsight vision and none of these shows are so great from gonzo.
Speaker 0: Well, the reason seems to be that every one of these shows or at least many of them There's always a great concept when you hear what the show is gonna be about or you hear that.
Speaker 0: It's like ooh That sounds interesting and then you watch know the opener in the first episode of the first ten episodes and it's wow This is great.
Speaker 0: This is going everywhere.
Speaker 0: I was the better however, and then it just kind of Peters out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean and once you realize that Gonzo has this syndrome of doing things like this then every time there's a new gonzo show You have a whole different view on it.
Speaker 1: It totally changes the way you think.
Speaker 0: yeah now I worry about gonkotsuo because I haven't seen it all and the first ten episodes were awesome And the count of Monte Cristo is one of my favorite stories ever.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have the full on a bridge penguin press of it edition.
Speaker 1: Well, I watched not all of it but a vast majority of the episodes I think over 20 of them and towards the end things started to get a little weird and Not the same as earlier and it was still okay.
Speaker 1: But it wasn't as good as it was in the early episodes.
Speaker 1: It was definitely on a downward trend and who knows what the end is like now We're not saying gonzo shows are bad.
Speaker 0: Just notice that when you hear about a gonzo show you start watching it.
Speaker 0: It always seems a lot more awesome early on and a lot less awesome the longer you watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at this list again And I look at the highlights and I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't see a single show on here that I would rank is even like B plus.
Speaker 1: I think the highest share was like B - stuff like Gatekeepers.
Speaker 0: gatekeepers was pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry and full metal panic.
Speaker 0: full metal panic was pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry I didn't like it at all.
Speaker 0: Van Dred Yeah Yeah All those shows showed a lot of promise and didn't seem to go anywhere and I lost interest in every single one of them after The first one to nine episodes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right, so pumpkin scissors is gonzo's new show or one of their new shows?
Speaker 0: Yep, it's directed by Katsu ito Akiyama.
Speaker 1: now I didn't know who Katsu ito Akiyama was because you know gonzo also has this sort of syndrome where you recognize the label But of the studio, but you don't know anyone in the studio.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like Oh clamp You know the word clamp, you know the clamp studio, but I can't name any of people in clamp.
Speaker 1: Can you?
Speaker 0: no No, no, it's like I really can't.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Someone says studio Ghibli and you know me as Aki.
Speaker 1: he works there But and he's the head dude, but can you name anyone else there?
Speaker 1: No it but gonzo I don't know anyone at gonzo not even their head, dude All I know is studio gonzo.
Speaker 1: and then the things that come out of them.
Speaker 0: Well, the guy who did this show pumpkin scissors the director.
Speaker 0: Yes the director the he also was the director for such wonderful things as El Hazzard the Wanderers Not the OAV if you know the OAV.
Speaker 0: No, not the awesome OAV.
Speaker 0: the significantly less awesome Significantly more plotting though actually really funny.
Speaker 0: after you get past the first four episodes TV show The direct.
Speaker 1: he directed bubblegum crisis the original OAV which I like but is hit or miss with a lot of people.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep, the bastard OAV which I think is his metallic on it.
Speaker 0: Yep He was.
Speaker 0: he was an episode director for Legend of Black Heaven, which is terrible.
Speaker 0: Give it a chance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he directed everything that is golf course every OAV And everything that says golf course on it.
Speaker 1: So pumpkin says oh and he also this is this caught me by surprise.
Speaker 1: he directed the Thundercats.
Speaker 0: No, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Whoa Thundercats is awesome.
Speaker 1: Let's find the mega condenser.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that too fast, let's find the mega condenser still going too fast.
Speaker 1: What's wrong lion?
Speaker 0: Oh Fuck it is again Here again that thing that that mega thing.
Speaker 1: Yes, and keep your foot off that blasted summer flange.
Speaker 0: So pumpkin scissors.
Speaker 0: I was excited about this from the moment I heard the name.
Speaker 0: before I knew it was a gonzo or anything because the name sounded like one of those shows.
Speaker 0: That's a little offbeat but actually serious and cool kind of like I don't know.
Speaker 0: I expected something like Batman.
Speaker 0: I don't know why Batman you say like mask of the phantasm Batman Alright, just I don't know.
Speaker 0: Why does this mix of goonie and serious and a cool style?
Speaker 0: That's what the name pumpkin scissors means to me.
Speaker 0: because I didn't know anything about the show except the title.
Speaker 0: I had nothing.
Speaker 0: I absolutely no idea what it was about.
Speaker 0: who did it anything?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had seen the logo which is a pumpkin with a scissor under it.
Speaker 1: That's kind of stylized and cute and definitely the kind of thing you put on a lot of merchandise the pumpkin scissor icon.
Speaker 0: So we finally got the show and I watched it.
Speaker 0: Well, we watch it together.
Speaker 0: The I was hooked in the first 15 seconds.
Speaker 0: in the first 15 seconds of the opener.
Speaker 0: this show Was gonna be an amazing show and about a minute after that.
Speaker 0: I totally lost interest in this show.
Speaker 1: It's surprising how much it changed moods in the first episode from the beginning to the end.
Speaker 0: Not even that but half.
Speaker 0: I mean the opener.
Speaker 0: the opener really says it all.
Speaker 0: if you don't want to watch the show Just watch the opener and you'll get everything you need to get out of this show.
Speaker 0: it starts out with this creepy music coming in and these Stylized kind of tanks coming forward in three to met like it's this weird surreal kind of disturbing imagery these tanks rolling forward and this man is standing in their path and it's creepy.
Speaker 0: and Then he opens this lantern and then crazy stuff happens.
Speaker 0: But then another 30 seconds into the opener the most stereotypical anime girl character in the history of anime appears.
Speaker 1: It's the girl who's the semi main character.
Speaker 1: OMG.
Speaker 0: Yeah mrs.
Speaker 1: Edward Alaric Yeah, the characters in the show it really seems like they've Basically ripped off full metal alchemists.
Speaker 1: They have a whole cast of characters, you know Which are designed to be popular and the main ones are sort of magical and powerful.
Speaker 1: and then there's a whole bunch of military people of varying personalities to fill it in and there's a whole bunch of villains.
Speaker 0: and I Mean it starts out.
Speaker 0: even after the opener.
Speaker 0: other than the fact that the girl looks really generic and stereotypical The show starts out.
Speaker 0: Okay, the opener is pretty good.
Speaker 0: I really want to know what's going on.
Speaker 0: There's a war a truce is announced.
Speaker 0: There's some military function going on.
Speaker 0: Everything's fine.
Speaker 0: And then as soon as we finally meet this main character girl she starts doing very silly like full metal alchemist humor style things like.
Speaker 0: They're taking out something and looking at some bandits and then she rips out the sword and starts yelling We'll see Jim will siege the castle will crush them ha ha ha.
Speaker 0: and the other military guys yell at her like no He'll get us killed.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she's like we can't seize them.
Speaker 1: We're just you know disaster or whatever guys.
Speaker 1: What are they?
Speaker 1: Forget what their job they're the war relief effort.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: We're the war relief effort.
Speaker 1: We don't go see each anyone What's wrong with you, but it turns silly immediately.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's the same kind of like side character interaction from full metal alchemist.
Speaker 0: We have all these secondary funny characters who are really good friends.
Speaker 0: They're in the military they've got a pet dog who does funny things and It's the same thing.
Speaker 0: it's like they're just ripping off the the aesthetic and the idea and the feeling of Those scenes from full metal alchemist to try to make this show popular.
Speaker 1: It could be it very well could be.
Speaker 1: if not, it really seems like it.
Speaker 1: Yeah either way the The show basically continues where they fight these tank guys and you see that everyone has powers that are mysterious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to know the clicheness of this plot?
Speaker 0: So this guy is big and Hawking and scary and he finds out there's a truce.
Speaker 0: Why couldn't this have happened sooner, you know, the typical war is bad thing.
Speaker 0: Then it shifts scenes.
Speaker 0: now they're at this.
Speaker 0: there's this village and these military war relief effort.
Speaker 0: people come in with the girl and the guy is there and they meet and they immediately get to know each other.
Speaker 0: and then you know the party of the anime is formed and then the bad guys come.
Speaker 0: the bad guy is a Growl wolf this member of an elite Secret military unit of which there were what seven or nine?
Speaker 0: Some number of guys some number of special unique military units that were illegal and weren't supposed to exist But they did and they were secret.
Speaker 0: and now that the military order has kind of collapsed Apparently some of these groups have decided to be mercenaries or live as bandits on their own.
Speaker 0: One of these groups is here.
Speaker 0: they're a chemical weapons group and when they say what the group is, we immediately figured out where the show was going because they give a very specific name and That's very specific.
Speaker 0: like this is one of these things one of these X things is out there chemical weapons, whatever and it turns out I'm gonna spoil the first episode that captain main character is Also one of these units and he is the anti of these units.
Speaker 0: His job as a secret special unit was to be able to take out all these other units.
Speaker 1: He's an everyone else seems to have a special thing like a chemical weapon chemical tank.
Speaker 1: This guy is the anti tank trooper with his little magic lantern, which is still unexplained.
Speaker 1: He opens it up and then he can take out tanks on his own.
Speaker 0: Somehow
Speaker 1: somehow with now magic lantern
Speaker 0: I don't I don't always want to rap on something if it's for some reason unrealistic or if I can't suspend my Disbelief, but they shoot this guy full-on straight up with a shell from a tank an Acid carrion exploding shell and it does nothing to him.
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh.
Speaker 0: and they also pull a old Batman style kind of chemical agent that affects everyone Conveniently several hours later for purposes of the plot, but doesn't actually kill anyone because there's a magic antidote.
Speaker 0: Great, this show just goes nowhere.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read spoilers cuz I gotta know what is up with the lantern which probably isn't going to be something cooler interest.
Speaker 1: It's a magic lantern this.
Speaker 1: or there might be the souls of dead people in there or something along those lines.
Speaker 0: I'll bet it's radiation.
Speaker 1: It could be radiation in there.
Speaker 1: It is something evil in there that gives him powers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they keep calling it the will of the wisp.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it could be a will-o-wisp like a demon or something Who knows?
Speaker 1: If it's something good, then what would be the point then?
Speaker 1: Why would bother keeping it a secret?
Speaker 1: It's obviously something bad and that's all you need to know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem with the show is that I figured it out already.
Speaker 0: He's got a bunch of stereotypical characters And it seems like everything the show is designed just to try to get people to keep watching.
Speaker 0: They introduced this lantern.
Speaker 0: It's critical to the plot But they don't say anything about it.
Speaker 0: and even I who know the show is gonna be crap Want to know what's up with the lantern kind of like how in fancy Lala.
Speaker 0: I want to know what's up with the dinosaurs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: And then there's the dog character.
Speaker 1: Oh the closer of the of the show This is dog and They didn't use the dog yet.
Speaker 1: because you gotta understand in the first episode They show scenes from the headquarters the military headquarters where there's a bunch of characters that do very little in the first episode Except you see them doing stuff Talking about the situation in the world.
Speaker 1: and then there's the characters out in the field who are actually the focus of the first episode.
Speaker 1: There's a dog that is at the headquarters.
Speaker 0: The dog is pretty much there.
Speaker 1: It looks like the dog from as among Adil only smaller, but it has a barrel under its neck like yep.
Speaker 1: You know those dogs that are the ski slopes.
Speaker 0: It's really cute.
Speaker 0: But it again it just.
Speaker 0: it feels like I don't know the dogs from FMA.
Speaker 0: This just.
Speaker 0: it's there because it's cute and we can have a cute closer and it provides comic relief.
Speaker 0: all the time It bites the commander's head.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So without being told or with anyone saying this I can tell that the dog's job is to bring messages from the headquarters To the pumpkin scissors people out in the field and in the closer they show the dog doing exactly that.
Speaker 1: This closer is pretty much The main character.
Speaker 1: girl puts a message in the dog's barrel and the dog starts running.
Speaker 0: it's actually really funny.
Speaker 1: cute clothes and there's a cute music playing and The dogs running and the cute music is playing and the credits are rolling and then the dog stops and looks at this poodle Which is pretty funny.
Speaker 1: The dog like pops up in the bottom right of the screen and barks once.
Speaker 0: yes Oh, he goes off with the poodle for a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah He does.
Speaker 1: then he comes back and he eventually makes it to the headquarters and gives the note to the headquarters girl And then he goes away.
Speaker 1: and that's the closer.
Speaker 0: It's all it's like meant to be cute and to sell dog merchandise kind of like the closer to a horror Matic just designed specifically to be cute and make people go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's exactly what is the closer to.
Speaker 1: mohoromatic was?
Speaker 0: Duh-duh-duh-duh-duh-duh-duh-duh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a cute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was these made little tiny Chibi-chibi cartoon maids doing a dance that you could learn and dance that we did in fact learn.
Speaker 1: a dance that we did learn.
Speaker 0: We in fact performed it in front of an audience who will never speak of it.
Speaker 1: That is right.
Speaker 1: That's a terrible terrible show mohoromatic, but it had.
Speaker 1: the cute clothes are going on.
Speaker 1: What other shows had the cute clothes are going on.
Speaker 1: Oh God Did risky safety.
Speaker 1: have a cute closer?
Speaker 0: The cute opener, I don't remember.
Speaker 0: all I remember is when we showed it in club We showed the opener and closer every episode because there was a bunch of short episodes that drove me insane I know but I had no say back then.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway pumpkin scissors It's not the worst show ever.
Speaker 1: It's not a bad show like oh my god.
Speaker 1: It's MB guys.
Speaker 1: It's bad It's bad, but it's not a show you want to watch.
Speaker 1: It's not worth your time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what.
Speaker 0: I'll save you all the trouble.
Speaker 0: pumpkin scissors is the name of the war relief unit.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't seem to be any other significance to that name whatsoever Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: and in fact the icon they show you the logo is just the patch on their shoulders.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if there's more to it like the name came from somewhere.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine it being cool or interesting.
Speaker 1: It's probably just you know made up and corny and force.
Speaker 0: if I find out what's up with the lantern I'll just boil it for all of you if you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, it seems like they just chose to call it pumpkin scissors so they can make a cool logo and sell merchandise.
Speaker 0: So watch the opener Like the first 30 seconds of the opener.
Speaker 0: pretend the show was about that and was like that and just don't actually watch the show.
Speaker 0: Cuz it's not worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you do really have nothing to do for a half-hour you could watch the first episode.
Speaker 1: if you really don't believe us.
Speaker 0: Um, you know what.
Speaker 1: just I wouldn't recommend it, but you could if you.
Speaker 1: there are worse things that you could do.
Speaker 0: if you for whatever reason decide you want to see the first episode of pumpkin scissors and you haven't seen the first episode of You know tari watch that one instead.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: There are many other shows You should watch instead.
Speaker 0: if you haven't seen them like death note or Nana or anything like that yeah, now if you've seen all the other anime in the universe other than MD guys and Or Please save my earth.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I wanted to make fun of some anime.
Speaker 0: That was the first one that came to mind.
Speaker 1: No, it wasn't.
Speaker 1: you thought about that for like a minute.
Speaker 1: It was really bad.
Speaker 1: What can I say?
Speaker 1: I thought that was one of your things you really like place admire.
Speaker 1: Yep So that's what we got to say about pumpkin scissors and gonzo And I think from now on when gonzo comes out with new shows next season.
Speaker 1: I'll be less highly Expecting of them.
Speaker 0: Yes, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't want to.
Speaker 0: I'm never gonna discount gonzo because their animation is usually beautiful.
Speaker 0: It's just they.
Speaker 1: it's like the console would just fire.
Speaker 1: There are some of their writers and get new writers over there.
Speaker 1: I think they would do pretty well.
Speaker 1: You know get like.
Speaker 1: all you really need to do is hire one guy who knows how to write an interesting plot instead of merchandise merchandising crap fest Of course.
Speaker 0: then again, there's the possibility.
Speaker 0: I mean all the cool ideas they come up with might not actually have cool ways to resolve.
Speaker 0: I mean part of the reason a lot of gonzo shows seem so awesome right away Is that when you hear what it's about or you see the beginning you think wow, that's unique.
Speaker 0: Where the hell are they gonna go with this?
Speaker 0: This is gonna be awesome because I've never seen anything like this.
Speaker 0: and then the truth is it really can't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's why all these punk kids in the US like I got an idea for an anime.
Speaker 1: The anime is no good because I mean look at gatekeepers.
Speaker 0: Where did gatekeepers go?
Speaker 1: They fought a bunch.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because I remember it back at RIT.
Speaker 0: Everyone was everyone was going nuts about gatekeepers.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz you could it was really shallow and straightforward, but it wasn't a fighting show.
Speaker 1: It was a fun campy monster the week show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what really shiny animation.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing And it was watching with a group.
Speaker 1: You can have a lot of fun.
Speaker 0: watching the first four episodes with a group was fantastic.
Speaker 0: Cuz you just yell and scream and it's stupid and awesome.
Speaker 0: I mean any anime is enjoyable in a group except possibly Legend of the overfeed gatekeepers is sort of awesome in the Phoenix Wright kind of way.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like a guy stands up at points and it's like go.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 0: My problem with gatekeepers was that it after the first four episodes Everyone kept watching it even though it was the exact same thing.
Speaker 0: Nothing changed it and no one was watching it in groups anymore.
Speaker 0: They were all watching it on their own which wasn't fun at all.
Speaker 0: and then talking about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I did.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch it after club except for when they had a marathon.
Speaker 1: then I went and I saw the whole show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I probably could have better spent my time But I got it's one gonzo show that I actually finished.
Speaker 0: I don't think I have ever finished a gonzo show.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's a reason for that and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.