Speaker 2: It's Monday March 6th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 2: We talk about how not to suck at podcasting.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So we're back after a long weekend of geek a long weekend of not enough sleep.
Speaker 0: Yeah What was originally gonna be two friends driving up from North Carolina to hang out?
Speaker 1: ended up as all of our friends come over our house and trashing it and We didn't even get to do that much stuff because we spent a lot of time in transport and sleep and eat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah the best part was how I lost my cell phone in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: good job, yeah Well, actually I found out later that I lost it on the train to Manhattan and I love technology.
Speaker 0: So I lost my cell phone right and I keep trying to call my cell phone on someone else's cell phone all day And it doesn't answer.
Speaker 0: and then my Scott here gets an email or an instant message, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, is this a message?
Speaker 0: Yeah So and then Scott says oh it's uh this guy aim him here and he aims me and he's like, hey I got your cell phone And I offered to give him some money and he offered to mail it to me and I should have it tomorrow.
Speaker 0: So once again New Yorkers are awesome, and they're not as evil as all you.
Speaker 0: Now New Yorkers seem to think they are.
Speaker 1: of course, you're still pretty crummy for losing that cell phone.
Speaker 0: What do you want?
Speaker 0: I had it on a belt clip under a trench coat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I used to lose shit all the time.
Speaker 1: I can't tell you how many Timex watches I've lost.
Speaker 0: I haven't lost my wallet since middle school.
Speaker 0: I'm proud of that.
Speaker 1: I lost a wallet like freshman year of college sophomore year.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter I haven't lost anything since then.
Speaker 1: so I haven't lost anything like four years before that.
Speaker 0: I used to lose shit all the time, but the dude who found my cell phone when I was offering, you know Hey, I'll give him some money whatever since you know, I do geek nights.
Speaker 0: I offered him Hey, if you have a website or anything you want to promote I'll help you out.
Speaker 0: and his response to that was well, actually Well, what does he want to promote?
Speaker 0: I don't know if any of you out there actually live in Tarrytown, New York It's a one of the burbs kind of of New York City or if you know anyone who does.
Speaker 0: But this EF international language school is looking for host families to host Chinese and I forget what other countries exchange students.
Speaker 1: So if you live in Tarrytown and you have a house and you want to host an exchange student, that's a pretty Specific kind of person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: But I mean you might know someone.
Speaker 0: we've got a lot of eclectic.
Speaker 0: I mean, we got the dudes in Australia.
Speaker 0: We got the guy in the UK.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what.
Speaker 1: If anyone listen to this podcast ends up hosting one of the families for this program in Tarrytown, New York I'll give you five dollars.
Speaker 1: All right, that's how sure I am that none of you are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if you know a guy promised guy I'd plug the site.
Speaker 0: there's gonna be a link there.
Speaker 0: So if this is at all interesting to you, check it out.
Speaker 1: You know, maybe from moving to Tarrytown soon or maybe you want to host an exchange student.
Speaker 1: so much You're gonna move to Tarrytown and get a house there.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: if you do that I'll give you another five dollars.
Speaker 1: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: and and and we'll let you.
Speaker 0: we'll give you a free geek night's t-shirt.
Speaker 1: Oh Good thing they don't exist.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, we don't get a t-shirt that says geek nights.
Speaker 1: on it in some fashion I'll take one of my old dirty t-shirts with a sharpie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the expected joke.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah alright, so I don't know if you realize.
Speaker 1: but Firefox how much does Firefox cost?
Speaker 1: Nothing, how much money does Mozilla make from Firefox?
Speaker 0: I would assume nothing you assume wrong?
Speaker 1: Oh, let's start a guessing game ready.
Speaker 1: make a guess.
Speaker 0: All right, how many dollars?
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 0: All right, it's either gonna be real low or real high.
Speaker 1: Well, this is how much money Mozilla has made from Firefox ever as in as long as Firefox has existed ever.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm a million dollars higher a billion dollars lower.
Speaker 0: a million dollars and a dollar 72 million dollars, that's about 72 million more than I expected, right?
Speaker 1: So You know where this money comes from?
Speaker 1: It's kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: All right in the top right of Firefox.
Speaker 1: You'll notice that little searchy box.
Speaker 0: Do people pay to be there?
Speaker 1: No, no, no, you notice how Google is the default for that searchy box.
Speaker 1: all right, if I make a Google search in that searchy box, and then I get to let's say I search for I don't know fire which is my favorite Google search And I know he's not kidding.
Speaker 0: He searches for it fairly regularly.
Speaker 1: All right, so let's actually do it.
Speaker 1: right now Let's go to the searchy box in Firefox and type in Fire press.
Speaker 1: enter on the right side of this page.
Speaker 1: There's an advertisement for fire Planning a career in firefighting.
Speaker 1: explore the possibilities.
Speaker 1: Www.collegeboard.com.
Speaker 0: Is there anyone selling fire?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's actually a whole bunch of paid for links on the side of this page.
Speaker 1: There's one two, three, four, five six eight eight sponsored links on the side of this page.
Speaker 1: Outstanding if I click one of these links, right?
Speaker 1: That means that the person who paid for that advertisement gives money to Google for that ad.
Speaker 1: For you know, the impression or the click or whatever does Mozilla get a cut.
Speaker 1: if I click on this link Then 80% of the money that that advertiser gives to Google actually goes to Mozilla.
Speaker 0: I did not know that and I never would have guessed that This is only for the paid links on the side, of course.
Speaker 1: However, you know over time that has amounted to 72 million dollars.
Speaker 0: surprisingly when I search for a product I have more than once clicked on one of those links to get what I wanted.
Speaker 1: I click on them.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: You usually happens when I'm looking to buy something like but when I'm looking for information I never click there, but I'm looking to buy a product and what will happen is usually like a specialized online Store will appear over there and that's what I want.
Speaker 1: That's useful.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: if it's an ad it's the link I want you know, and if it saves me going to the 10th page to click where no one gets any money for the same Link, it's just stupid course.
Speaker 0: Sometimes I'll search for mesothelioma and click on all the links to cost evil people money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that works.
Speaker 0: I urge all of you to search for mesothelioma and click on all the links.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should do a show on mesothelioma.
Speaker 1: And what's the other one?
Speaker 1: Uh, What is the other one begins with like a P?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know either.
Speaker 1: I forgot it used to get posted to my site all the time.
Speaker 0: so I'm sure a lot of you have seen that AOL has opened up the AIM instant messaging SDK.
Speaker 1: finally I can freaking get a client besides the aim client and send files reliably to my friends.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, you'd think that now the headline seems great.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Now there's an official SDK.
Speaker 0: I can officially interface with aim.
Speaker 0: It'll be great.
Speaker 0: It won't be a hack.
Speaker 0: It won't be reverse engineered Upon further reading.
Speaker 0: it's bullshit.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: How could it be bullshit?
Speaker 1: They give you software that allows you to interface with aim, right?
Speaker 0: All right, they give you the software.
Speaker 0: However, there are a number of restrictions as to what you can actually do with that software.
Speaker 1: now Are these license on paper restrictions or physical software?
Speaker 0: restrictions are license on paper You'll go to jail as opposed to physical.
Speaker 1: You can just get around so I could just take the SDK and do it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you could but you get in trouble.
Speaker 1: Is there like some sort of key system where they know like Google has with their SDKs?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I didn't look too much into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'd be interesting to know.
Speaker 1: cuz if there is then you really couldn't disobey the license.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the gist of it is that for one you can use this for whatever you want any non-commercial purposes, but you cannot one.
Speaker 0: You create a client or use the SDK with a client that is quote multi-headed Meaning it can connect to more than one type of network.
Speaker 1: What the hell.
Speaker 1: that's all defeats the whole purpose.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna use it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: that's like if GM used it.
Speaker 0: They'd have to drop support for I don't know everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, there goes that - if you're going to use it on any sort of wireless device like a PDA or a cell phone up.
Speaker 0: Nope, you have to get a separate pay license.
Speaker 1: Oh, see that's the freaking scam.
Speaker 1: I hate the worst.
Speaker 1: Oh my that's almost as bad as the first one.
Speaker 1: Oh trying to get aimed to work on anything cuz I have a Blackberry right and there's no reason that this Blackberry piece of hardware Could not be a really really good.
Speaker 1: I am client, right?
Speaker 1: The problem is if all the software that makes it be an I am client costs a lot of money.
Speaker 1: And the only reason that costs a lot of money is because like this crazy vendor lock-in bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah so this won't solve that because you can't use the code if you're gonna do anything like that.
Speaker 0: such bastard number three if You want to make something for any sort of corporate use at all?
Speaker 0: No, you have to pay for that separately, too.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess I aim doesn't want you competing with their aim corporate products.
Speaker 1: that makes corporate products are terrible I know but at least it makes a little more sense than the first two.
Speaker 0: Well the first two look at the first one.
Speaker 0: They don't want people to be able to connect to multiple networks because then why do they need AOL?
Speaker 1: Mmm, because they're still using AOL.
Speaker 1: They're just also using other things.
Speaker 0: Honestly, the only reason I use AOL is because some of my idiot friends won't give it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah use jabber Jabber jabber jabber jabber.
Speaker 1: I'll do a show on jabber one time.
Speaker 0: I'm getting evil looks from our guest who is not.
Speaker 0: her microphone is turned off currently and it'll be turned on the second half of the show And she uses aim.
Speaker 1: I Don't know how old-school all the listeners be but When I had a computer it ran DOS and Windows 3.1.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like DOS as in there's no such thing as networking and there's no such thing as um a gooey.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess you could use das shell 32 bits.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Windows 3 1 1 and Really you only have two mouse buttons that do anything.
Speaker 1: the third one just kind of does nothing unless you're playing a game.
Speaker 0: in Windows 3 1 1 you could minimize your whole computer and then you couldn't do anything and When you exited Windows you went to DOS instead of turning your computer off.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was fantastic.
Speaker 0: Those were awesome days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, um, some people still use Windows 3.1 and I don't blame What.
Speaker 1: oh, well, you don't use it as your primary OS.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, but some people still use it because you got to play those old Windows 3.1 game.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll know to you that OS to warp kick the shit out of Windows 3 1.
Speaker 1: Actually, I had OS to warp and Windows 3.1.
Speaker 0: I still have it.
Speaker 0: In fact, I have the installers for it for the most current version that you guys can't get right now About 15 feet away from me in the closet
Speaker 1: and I work
Speaker 0: for IBM and we still use OS
Speaker 1: 2 and I had DOS All on the same computer and OS 2 war worked pretty well and had some fancy stuff But it didn't have any soft software that was useful.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was very robust.
Speaker 0: It was good for servers.
Speaker 1: So I always ended up dual booting and going back to you know, DOS windows to You know play DOS games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so anyway anyway somebody Awesome made this thing called Cal Myra c a l m i r a. it's Cal Myra XP 4.0.
Speaker 1: Calmyra XP 4.0 is something you can download.
Speaker 1: Put it on your windows 3.1 computer and it makes your windows 3.1 computer Look and function as if it was Windows XP.
Speaker 0: now Scott showed this to me.
Speaker 0: He just showed me a screenshot and asked what's what's up with this picture?
Speaker 0: and I looked at it.
Speaker 0: It was Windows XP with maybe a little skin to it and I couldn't figure it out.
Speaker 1: It looks exactly like Windows XP and there's even a start menu and in everything and it's really scary.
Speaker 1: But this computer is actually Windows 3.1.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: It's an actual old slow computer - you know, they don't say that I have a feeling they're running Windows 3.1 on DOS box or something.
Speaker 0: That would make sense.
Speaker 0: I mean not many people have 486 is kicking around that still work.
Speaker 1: Well Yeah, it's the only explanation I can come up with for it.
Speaker 1: But I Just got to say Windows 3.1 like back in the day.
Speaker 1: It was great But if you try to use it now, you just want to kill yourself.
Speaker 1: I mean They don't even have the X button on the windows.
Speaker 1: you had to double click in that in the top left and the little menu That was like my shape kind of thing Yeah, and like you couldn't really and you had to use the program manager for everything.
Speaker 1: So like the desktop was always hidden behind the program manager, but the icons on the desktop you wanted to use and uh Yeah, yeah, so that's why in Windows 95 the the program manager was still there but it was hidden and they gave you the start menu instead and that's what it was all about, but Yes, and now this makes Windows 3.1 real usable.
Speaker 1: So you can get a computer and load it up with a pile of Windows 3.1 games and you're good to go.
Speaker 0: It's actually if you have a really old slow computer a lot of new Linux's.
Speaker 0: you can do stuff with them But Windows 3.1 actually is pretty robust for how little it is and how weak it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah The difference is if you install an old Linux or a Linux designed to run an old computer like Ubuntu lite or something like that You can run Firefox.
Speaker 1: if you decide you want to run wizards 3.1 on your old computer you have to run Netscape 2 gold.
Speaker 0: Hey, at least you get Netscape 2.
Speaker 1: You're really badass.
Speaker 1: You can get Netscape 3 gold or Netscape 4 point Netscape.
Speaker 0: Whatever Yeah, that one the point at which I switch to IE.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I have a Windows Netscape communicator CD.
Speaker 1: God you want it?
Speaker 0: No sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can run it in wine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, that's really what I want to spend a weekend doing.
Speaker 1: It might be better than running Windows 3.1.
Speaker 0: Alright, so I had one thing of the day, but I saw a new thing just before the show and Since the rule of the thing of the day is that I have to use the coolest thing I've seen on the interwebs since the last time I did a show.
Speaker 0: I have to use this now.
Speaker 0: You're all familiar with fight club and fight clubs.
Speaker 0: Scott here was actually accused of being a member of it's not accused.
Speaker 1: I was you were questioned one level below Suspected.
Speaker 0: so I asked you if an injury you would sustain was due to your participation in a fight club.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 0: They use the words fight club.
Speaker 0: Did they not?
Speaker 1: that is correct?
Speaker 0: I find this hilarious because for any of you who actually know Scott he is weaker than a puppy.
Speaker 1: I'm not weaker than a puppy.
Speaker 1: I could kill a puppy if I wanted to.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think a puppy could just worry you to death.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends.
Speaker 1: I mean if it was a wolf puppy It might bite me and claw me and it wouldn't be happy.
Speaker 1: and then maybe the big wolf would come and eat me.
Speaker 1: but if it was like You know one of those little weird tiny dogs that are all scarily small if it was like a puppy one of those Then it really wouldn't have much to do.
Speaker 0: So anyway, this is a fight club and they have videos of their fights.
Speaker 0: now you might wonder why would rim link to just a fight Club, he's not into fighting.
Speaker 0: Well, uh This is a nerd fight club and you have to see it to believe it.
Speaker 0: Imagine nerds hitting each other with plastic knives.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like two nerds put on little like safety helmets and there's like an officiator and stuff to make sure no one gets hurt And whatnot and they just go at each other with plastic knives.
Speaker 1: It's kind of it's like wow, these nerds don't get out.
Speaker 0: Wow, hey, they're getting out more than some other nerds true, but not enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one foot out of the closet ain't - All right, anyway.
Speaker 0: So today we were debating we were gonna do a themed week this week.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll still do one depending on today, but today's gonna be another one of those how not to suck days how not to suck at Podcasting.
Speaker 1: now at least the technical.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're not gonna talk about you know the like coming up with an idea or learning how to not say um like That's up to you.
Speaker 0: so yeah But just the very basics of one how to make your podcast not sound like an ass To how to use a microphone in a somewhat proper manner, you know all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not like You know the gods of radio or anything.
Speaker 1: No, but our podcast.
Speaker 1: I know from listening to a lot of podcast including ours that like Some podcasts they have some noise in the background and that's sometimes tolerable.
Speaker 1: You know some of them the interview parts or when they have someone on the phone, it's staticky.
Speaker 1: That's tolerable because even real radio stations have that.
Speaker 1: there's nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm talking about like.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about you podcasters who are so amateur.
Speaker 1: I mean it's okay to be amateur But when you like the volume is in audible or when one guy on the show is Incredibly loud and the other guy is so quiet and I have to keep adjusting my volume as you both talk And I can't hear or when I have to turn the volume in my car up so high that when the next Podcast comes on that's made by someone who knows what they're doing It freaking kills my eardrums and I have to turn it all the way back down.
Speaker 0: now We've got two respecters on this because like I said earlier we have a guest.
Speaker 0: now We have here a friend of ours who has been laughing hysterically at how we actually do this podcast off mic.
Speaker 0: But now she's got a mic in our hand.
Speaker 0: So we've got Nuri here.
Speaker 0: So you do a podcast I hear.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I do a podcast about geeky art stuff.
Speaker 0: What's it called?
Speaker 2: Oh, it's called artist alley.
Speaker 2: all one word.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you know, you're getting a link.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I guess so.
Speaker 2: I guess I'll be linked in the show notes.
Speaker 1: Tell people the URL if it cuz if they're schmucks and they don't visit the people who don't visit the website Okay.
Speaker 2: Well the URL is www.candycornstudios.com And the easiest way to get to it is to just click on the podcast link.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, and Andy corn if you don't know what candy corn is.
Speaker 0: Well You can go to hell.
Speaker 2: Yeah, there's a good story behind that.
Speaker 1: Oh, we'll let you know on Halloween.
Speaker 2: Yeah, there is.
Speaker 2: I don't know if you guys ever listen to Lewis black.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we do.
Speaker 0: I know that I know the bit about Your body the yellow part thinking it'll taste like corn, but it doesn't.
Speaker 0: it tastes like ass.
Speaker 1: then you eat another one you fuck.
Speaker 2: Another detailed story.
Speaker 2: you can come talk to me on the website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically we've got her here.
Speaker 0: one because She came up for the weekend from North Carolina to hang out in New York City, which she had never been to.
Speaker 0: We've got two basic perspectives here on how to make your podcast not suck.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have the low-budget version and the no-budget version.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not for any bad reason.
Speaker 0: just she's still in college and we're out of college.
Speaker 1: Now the reason we've left out the high-budget version is because if you have a high budget You don't need to know shit.
Speaker 1: you bought stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you hired a radio guy or who knows.
Speaker 0: any problem You have with audio can be solved by spending money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're gonna talk about how to do it without spending money, which is key because I'm sorry I'd like to listen to podcasts, but most of you out there just don't know how to do this.
Speaker 1: Even it's some like some of you the content is bad, but some of you just despite your content Which I want to listen to I just can't.
Speaker 1: it's just.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were actually watching Nury earlier on her little Mac laptop working on trying to edit one of her previous podcasts.
Speaker 2: Well, it's not actually that easy on a Mac.
Speaker 2: I my my computer does not have a microphone input or anything like that.
Speaker 2: So I had to get all this crap to hook up something in there so we could it would record.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean I bought a bunch of equipment, but I have more money.
Speaker 0: But I guess the the nice perspective here is consider this she spent pretty much no money other than you know Like minimal minimal things.
Speaker 2: Well, I got some stuff for free, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that always helps but you can always get stuff for free.
Speaker 0: if you can't get anything at all for free You might not have and you can't afford to buy anything.
Speaker 1: You might not have the resources to do a podcast just yet You might not have any friends and if you don't have any friends That means no one likes to listen to you, which means you probably shouldn't make a podcast.
Speaker 0: But basically we've spent Scott and I not counting hosting because actually our hosting hosts a lot more than just geek nights.
Speaker 0: We spent less than $200 and that includes everything.
Speaker 0: Yep, Nuria spent.
Speaker 0: how much have you spent?
Speaker 0: Total based on all the podcast stuff that you bought.
Speaker 0: that is for the podcast.
Speaker 2: Okay, I spent $40 on the little adapter thingy to connect things to my computer which you out there and probably won't need.
Speaker 2: Yeah, unless you have a Mac laptop.
Speaker 2: in which case Well, at least if you have a Mac laptop you get the garage band The built-in microphone on the lap Matt the the laptops.
Speaker 2: They sound like ass when you record with them.
Speaker 0: Well, actually that's the first thing we can talk about.
Speaker 0: if your microphone came with your sound card.
Speaker 0: You can't podcast with it It'll sound like ass.
Speaker 0: That's right that that is a universal rule at a minimum.
Speaker 1: It seems to me that the lot like the 20 or 30 dollar logitech headset mics.
Speaker 1: Those are like the minimum.
Speaker 1: They said that's tolerable if you set it up with the right volume and stuff.
Speaker 2: Yeah, the microphones that come with the computers tend to pick up so much ambient sound that you just you hear everything else That's going on in the room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now I'd say what we use.
Speaker 0: we bought like $20.
Speaker 0: unidirectional RadioShack mics come with little like stands and everything and If you're low budget, those are definitely the way to go.
Speaker 0: They're like 20 or 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: If anything if you're not using a headset or especially if there's more than one person in the podcast get a unidirectional Microphone.
Speaker 0: if you don't know what that means.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about it.
Speaker 0: Just get a unidirectional microphone and point it directly at the person who's talking.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I can speak to that because the microphones that I have are not unidirectional.
Speaker 2: there's something called cardioid and they pick up sound not just in one direction, but in multiple directions and unfortunately, that means that it picks up all kinds of machine noise and airplanes and people honking on the highway outside and everything.
Speaker 0: I Basically like there's omni-directional microphones which are they'll get everything.
Speaker 0: They're like the whole room.
Speaker 0: any of you who might have found the lost Episodes of geek nights that are floating out there?
Speaker 0: before we kind of went live We used a lot of omni-directional microphone in the middle of the room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was.
Speaker 1: that was pretty terrible because that was also one that came with the computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, in fact, I'm sitting next to my computer right now and it even looks cheap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's two bucks.
Speaker 1: It's yet.
Speaker 0: Now there's cardioids.
Speaker 0: There's hyper cardioids.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: if you don't know anything about audio, this is really gonna be a low-tech.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna tell you like the base details of how all this equipment works because that'll be another show.
Speaker 0: This is just how to not suck.
Speaker 0: So if you don't know anything about microphones go to RadioShack ask for a cheap unidirectional dynamic microphone And get the RadioShack brand.
Speaker 1: the other brands just cost more.
Speaker 1: They're almost the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like if they have two microphones and they look kind of the same and once $40 and once $20.
Speaker 0: if you don't know the difference You won't notice the difference.
Speaker 2: Oh pick them up.
Speaker 2: first though pick them up and see if it feels comfortable in your hand because if there's one that's $20 And one that's $30 and the one that's $20 is really heavy and hard to hold and the one that's $30 Feels good in your hand.
Speaker 2: It might be worth of 30 bucks
Speaker 0: or by the same token if it feels nice and heavy and solid Yeah,
Speaker 1: yeah, but at the same time they might just put weights in there to confuse you
Speaker 2: What you like.
Speaker 0: actually our old DVD player.
Speaker 0: we bought this crap Crapo DVD player and Inside it the apex.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it felt kind of heavy but inside it was this tiny little like poorly soldered circuit board and Something that I'm pretty sure was just a weight to make it feel more sturdy than it was.
Speaker 0: I Couldn't figure out a use for it.
Speaker 0: It wasn't any sort of electronic device.
Speaker 1: It's like when they sell those little like action figure collectible toys and to make it so you don't know what toy is in Into in each box they put weights.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah the PVCs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hate that.
Speaker 0: Now while we're talking about microphones.
Speaker 0: Consider the difference between me saying Jack Thompson and me saying Jack Thompson.
Speaker 0: Now the latter one probably sounded a lot worse Because if you say P's T's any kind of really hard syllable B and D And yeah air comes out of your mouth and it hits the microphone like so But a pupa pupa pupa pupa pupa pupa.
Speaker 2: Okay, air is always coming out of your mouth But on those particular letters it comes out in a really hard fast manner.
Speaker 2: that makes a really loud spike in the sound volume.
Speaker 0: Now spikes aren't that bad normally if you have equipment in the way, but unless you're like us I mean we have a compressor which we'll talk about in a minute and we don't have to worry about it so much.
Speaker 0: But if you're not gonna spend a lot of money at all You're probably not gonna have a compressor which means you don't want your audio to clip.
Speaker 0: basically the best way to make audio sound good is you want to record so that the average volume is as high as you can make it On the like the game the input meter.
Speaker 0: as you're recording this price in whatever program uses some sort of meter You want to be very close to the top of that all the time?
Speaker 0: But you never want to hit the top.
Speaker 1: So you want the vine to be as loud as you can go without going off the edge.
Speaker 0: now if you're popping all the time Let you know P's and T's into the microphone you're gonna have these big spikes Which means you're gonna have to set the input gain the volume you record at a lot lower which means your actual signal is gonna be a lot lower and You can say your noise floor is gonna be real high.
Speaker 1: Your podcast is gonna sound like ass and that's when you know your podcast is so quiet.
Speaker 1: I have to turn the volume of way up in the car and it pisses me off.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz.
Speaker 0: then you turn it up and you hear all the noise in the background
Speaker 2: or you have to be like me and use a Noise-reduction filter and then turn up the vocals and that doesn't necessarily sound like ass But it doesn't sound as good as you wouldn't use a pop filter
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: actually here I'm the only one who actually has a pop filter in front of me Nurse holding the mic about four inches from her face, which is good Scott pretty much.
Speaker 0: She shoves the mic into his mouth.
Speaker 1: Yep That now because I like to lay down and be lazy and all that.
Speaker 2: I'm laying down and being lazy too, but I know how to not talk directly in you know towards the mic.
Speaker 0: Now luckily Scott actually isn't that bad about popping.
Speaker 0: I'm real bad.
Speaker 0: just the way I talk and the way I form vowels.
Speaker 0: I pop all the time.
Speaker 2: That's cuz you're a northern hick.
Speaker 0: Yeah quiet.
Speaker 0: You're urban, Michigan.
Speaker 0: Hey get me drunk enough and I'll start speaking like a Michigander again.
Speaker 1: I'm the only civilized person here from Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Yeah, New York Yeah, you say you were.
Speaker 0: you lived in New York.
Speaker 0: you were there for what a bum.
Speaker 1: I lived in New York between the ages of zero and one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: It's like I was born in, Georgia Me saying I'm from Georgia, even though I haven't lived there ever.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, but like, you know My immediate family lived in Connecticut almost my whole life But like cousins and grandma and all those other people lived in New York and I went there very frequently to see them.
Speaker 1: So it's like it's.
Speaker 1: you know, I'm no stranger Yeah, but anyway, if you if just record yourself lived in New York for the past six seven years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have And you even worked in New York City for a while Yep But if you have the kind of voice.
Speaker 0: just record yourself and listen.
Speaker 0: The main thing is you always have to record yourself and listen to yourself.
Speaker 0: if you get embarrassed listening to yourself You're probably not the best person to be doing a podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also remember that if you've never listened to a recording of yourself before you don't sound weird.
Speaker 1: You don't sound the way you think you sound because the sound of your voice coming through your skull to your ears is not the way it sounds to other people who have your voice going through the air to their ears.
Speaker 0: your voice sounds a lot deeper and more Awesome in your head than it does in the real world.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get over that fact.
Speaker 1: So when you hear yourself being recorded you hear recording of yourself.
Speaker 1: That's what you sound like to other people whether you know it or not.
Speaker 2: Yeah, there's nothing wrong with your microphone Yep, but you might think it sounds bad But other people are used to your voice and they don't necessarily think it sounds bad.
Speaker 2: Just because you think it sounds different than your normal voice doesn't mean it's bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I still think that my voice is bad when I hear it recorded, but it sounds great coming in my head.
Speaker 0: Yeah now later in the show we can talk more about how to make your voice sound good like really good Because my voice actually sounds quite a bit different in real life than it does in the podcast.
Speaker 0: But I do things to it.
Speaker 0: You got to use your $30 an hour voice But anyway to get to what I was talking about with the popping.
Speaker 0: basically if you if you record yourself and you hear a lot of popping going on You can buy what's called a pop filter.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is a pop filter costs like 30 bucks and That's a giant ripoff.
Speaker 0: because in front of my mouth right now is an embroidery loop With a pair of pantyhose stretched over it if you don't know an embroidery loop.
Speaker 1: Embroidery loop good game.
Speaker 1: Yep is this circle of wood?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a circle of wood.
Speaker 0: I put pantyhose around it and taped it together and I just put it between me and the microphone.
Speaker 1: So my voice it's like a circular cloth shield.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically your voice if you google for pop filters You'll see pictures.
Speaker 0: now my voice and the audio goes through just fine.
Speaker 0: But when I pop the air bounces off of this filter and doesn't hit the microphone directly.
Speaker 1: Well, not as much.
Speaker 1: It's not a hundred percent invincible, but it's it's good enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so listen to yourself.
Speaker 0: And if you need a pop filter, you'll hear it.
Speaker 0: it's pretty obvious because you'll sound like this and People don't like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it sounds really bad.
Speaker 0: All right, so you've got a microphone.
Speaker 0: you got to plug it to your computer somehow.
Speaker 0: Now Nuri versus Oz do it very different ways because we record very different podcasts near a different budget.
Speaker 0: So I'll let you go first.
Speaker 0: How do you connect up?
Speaker 2: All right Well, my microphones don't come with a cable because I got my microphones and my cables from one of my friends for free.
Speaker 2: So I have a microphone and I have a cable that plugs into the bottom of it And then it plugs into either in a mixer or something else on the other end.
Speaker 2: Well, I don't have a mixer because I couldn't find a mixer that could plug into my computer for pretty cheap.
Speaker 2: So I just got this little thing.
Speaker 2: it's called a Griffin i-mic and it's just this little tiny round disc that plugs into the USB port on my laptop and Has a headphone input jack.
Speaker 2: So I got a little converter that lets me plug the quarter inch plug from my microphone cable into the eighth inch plug on the Griffin i-mic and I just connect it straight to my computer just like that.
Speaker 2: No mixer.
Speaker 2: No effects on it beforehand or anything.
Speaker 2: I do all of my editing and mixing digitally.
Speaker 0: Now there are both pros and cons to that.
Speaker 0: the pros I imagine are that it doesn't cost much.
Speaker 2: yeah, it's completely free except for the $40 I spent on the i-mic and the $3 I spent on the converter.
Speaker 0: now I could guess at the cons But I'm sure you could fill us in into all the difficulties you have with the setup.
Speaker 2: Yeah Well, um one of my microphone cables doesn't work so well.
Speaker 2: I think it only inputs on the left channel and it doesn't pick up half the audio.
Speaker 2: So all of my signals are really really low and there's something called a signal-to-noise ratio.
Speaker 2: This is key which means that You have a certain amount of audio signal going through your microphone and a certain amount of background noise picked up.
Speaker 2: if your background noise Is really high then your signal-to-noise ratio is really low and you don't like that.
Speaker 2: You want it to be really high because you want much more signal than noise.
Speaker 2: so you can cut it all up.
Speaker 2: all the noise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the best signal-to-noise ratio is like a hajillion to zero.
Speaker 1: that's the best you can get.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean basically The more distance there is between your all your voice and the noise the easier It is to get rid of the noise.
Speaker 0: because you can do all that in software.
Speaker 0: You can buy equipment that'll do it But we don't even use equipment to do it because you really don't need that equipment for a podcast.
Speaker 1: That's the thing is radio guys as in radio stations that you know broadcast live and such They have all this hardware equipment that you know performs audio operations to the actual Analog signal in real time and we have some of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because that's what they need to happen.
Speaker 1: They need it to happen immediately.
Speaker 1: So that's why they have dials and levers and switches Because you're making a podcast and you're recording it and then distributing it You can record it onto a file on your computer and do all the stuff that the dials and switches usually do You know after the fact using some piece of software like garage band or resound or something like that.
Speaker 0: now as dirty can probably tell You while that works great for most cases.
Speaker 0: It adds a lot of time to post-production.
Speaker 1: Oh god Yeah, does it add time to post-production but it only works almost as well as the actual dials and switches.
Speaker 2: Well, if you listen my podcast, you'll notice it doesn't sound anywhere as good as geek nights and definitely don't listen to it in your Car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually we had a lot of problems before we got a compressor with geek nights and cars as well.
Speaker 0: one of our friends said that it's unlistenable in a car and sure enough it wasn't.
Speaker 1: I Tried to listen to it in the car and it was unlistenable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we've since fixed that.
Speaker 0: now our input chain.
Speaker 0: We spent I'd say a hundred by eighty about a hundred and twenty bucks on the equipment that is sitting in front of me Between my microphone and the computer.
Speaker 2: you also have a very different kind of computer than I do So why don't you tell them what kind of?
Speaker 0: yeah, so if you don't have a Mac laptop and use have a normal computer you've probably got a sound card and the sound card probably has a Core 8th inch little jack going into it.
Speaker 1: It's called the stereo mini.
Speaker 1: That's the normal headphone type plug.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anything at most normal headphones your.
Speaker 0: it's the thing you plug into your iPod, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yep, the iPod hole.
Speaker 0: now if you have that you're all set because you can.
Speaker 0: there you go to Radio Shack or whatever You'll see a million adapters and you'll be able to get from whatever your equipment outputs to that jack.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is you don't really want to plug the microphone directly into that.
Speaker 0: if you can help it Even it no matter what no matter how little money you want to spend unless you want to spend no money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've done.
Speaker 1: there are decent podcasts I listen to that are literally a Logitech headset plugged directly into that hole and as long as you squiddle all your software Meters and all your volume things properly and it'll take you a couple hours It'll sound like the bare minimum of quality.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the main problem with it one is that you can't have guests because you have no way to have them talk.
Speaker 1: Actually, I know a guy who he just gets a Y adapter and plugs in more headsets.
Speaker 1: I could cry and then he brings the volume that it kind of works actually with my podcast.
Speaker 2: We only have one input So we have one microphone and we pass it around between the three of us Which means that we have to do a crapload of post-production because every time we pass the microphone.
Speaker 2: There's a little Sound and that means that we have to go in and cut out every single one of those.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh my god yeah, so our input chain is we have a Eurorack UB 802 mixer.
Speaker 1: we found out about that because the guy who does the Roadhouse podcast, which is awesome blues music Recommended it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's actually very good.
Speaker 0: It was like 60 bucks is fantastic.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's got two now.
Speaker 0: This is the reason why this segment of today's podcast might not sound as good as the previous segment before we had Nury in Because this the mixer we have is great, but it has two Pre-amplified microphone inputs meaning I plug my microphone into slot one and Scott's is plugged into slot two and There's an amplifier there before it even hits the rest of the mixer.
Speaker 0: that amplifies the signal from the microphone to a good level.
Speaker 0: Now the rest of the inputs don't have pre amplifiers So I had to turn everything else down so you could actually hear Nury talk because there's no preamp between her and you.
Speaker 2: That's because your mixer sucks and only has two good slots.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, actually I can buy a little pre amplifier thingy.
Speaker 0: Just we haven't gotten around to that yet because this is the first time we've had a guest on the show since we got the compressor.
Speaker 1: I told you we should have bought the mixer with four holes, but no that mixer was like $40 more and I was cheap.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you guys don't have guests very often.
Speaker 2: So it's not that big of a deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of our guests are going to be with little handheld things at conventions.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm or over the phone.
Speaker 0: But anyway, then I have a headphone monitor coming out of the mixer so I can listen everyone's voices and set levels before we do.
Speaker 0: But that's not in the signal chain.
Speaker 0: that's kind of like a sidechain to my ears.
Speaker 0: I don't wear it all the time when we talk From there the outputs of the mixer go into what's called a dynamic range compressor.
Speaker 0: now I'm not going to talk about the details of exactly how they work or how to pick one But we're gonna do a show on that someday.
Speaker 0: And if you really want to know just email us and I can send you all this information.
Speaker 0: but basically it takes our audio coming out of the mixer that's raw and It keeps the levels the volumes all about the same.
Speaker 0: so above a certain threshold it decreases the Amplification so that the louder I get in real life.
Speaker 0: It doesn't get quite as loud recording to the computer Which means I can set the in the gain or the input level on the computer a lot higher Which means I'm recording with a lot more data Which means I can do a lot more stuff to the audio without making it sound like ass.
Speaker 1: Basically when you get too loud it makes you quiet and when you get too quiet it makes you loud.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically this one doesn't actually make you louder.
Speaker 0: That's that would be a compander.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's that's the general gist of what.
Speaker 0: the yeah, basically if you need It's called a compressor You can do it in software after the fact.
Speaker 0: But compressing is the one thing of all the things you can do after the fact that It really pays to do it before it hits your computer.
Speaker 2: And that's important because when people listen to your show on headphones or in their car Volume jumps are gonna be really They're gonna hurt your ears.
Speaker 2: Even if they're a really small volume jump if you get a little bit louder It's gonna be painful here.
Speaker 0: I I just turned off the compressor.
Speaker 0: So now you're gonna hear the raw audio.
Speaker 2: Yay Yay, whoo.
Speaker 2: No, it's awesome.
Speaker 2: I don't like that.
Speaker 2: I'll turn it back on.
Speaker 0: I turned it back on.
Speaker 0: the difference might not be so bad because actually I didn't calibrate the mixer the compressor.
Speaker 0: so much Mr.
Speaker 1: I had all the dials perfectly set.
Speaker 0: I have all perfectly set when there's the two of us.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: we got this random elephant of Nury who's laying over there.
Speaker 2: Oh, no women messing things up for you again.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: so we realized just now that we could talk about this forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if we kept talking and talking eventually like professional radio guys to start calling us and telling us we're wrong or no You had to do this and God they would just be.
Speaker 0: so I promised all of you We'll do a show someday in the future in detail like the specifics of we use a kid this compressor.
Speaker 0: This is how it works.
Speaker 0: This is how you use it.
Speaker 0: This is why you want it, etc.
Speaker 0: But for now, I mean, this is just like a overview of how to not suck a podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also there's plenty of other podcasts like infinity podcasts about how to podcast.
Speaker 2: Oh, there's a. there's a Podcasting for dummies book that has a companion podcast.
Speaker 2: so if you can't go out and get the book you can go to the for dummies comm website and download the podcast.
Speaker 2: and It's by T Morris and Evo Tara who are both a couple of podcasters and they've got a lot of experience doing it But it's got a lot of good tips in it.
Speaker 2: So go to your local store and check it out.
Speaker 2: Even if you don't buy it.
Speaker 1: Oh, no a shill.
Speaker 1: Haha Yeah, there's also what's the other one podcast for one one?
Speaker 2: I think yeah podcast for one one is good.
Speaker 2: They have interviews with podcasters every show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's how I learned about a gizmo phone.
Speaker 2: No, you learned about that from me, yeah, I listen to podcast for one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so indirectly I learned it from them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know, we're only doing this because we have a lot of you know.
Speaker 1: It seems like every podcast has a pile of listeners who don't know about podcasting and want the one podcast They listen to to tell them, you know instead of going in listening to every other podcast in the world It does the same thing.
Speaker 2: It's surprising how many podcasts there are out there about podcasting.
Speaker 1: Imagine if every TV show had to explain television because it was the only TV show that people watch.
Speaker 0: that was a very apt allegory.
Speaker 1: or like every comic book had to explain to you how to read a comic book and how it Works because a lot of the Tokyo pop manga explain it just in case Read it backwards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's you know, it's a one-page deal.
Speaker 1: That's not like an entire Explanation of like.
Speaker 1: here is you put a grammar book in the front of your war and peace, you know.
Speaker 0: The main reason we're doing this is because I'm sorry But a lot of podcasts just are Unlistenable.
Speaker 2: if you want to start a podcast we want you to know these basic things so that we can listen to it without Killing our yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then we can judge you on your content and not on your inept.
Speaker 0: I don't care how good your content is if I can't listen to it.
Speaker 2: It's not gonna get listened to.
Speaker 0: yep No by the same token if you spend a million dollars have awesome equipment, but you're just a guy going.
Speaker 2: so Yeah You You have to have a solid idea.
Speaker 2: Yeah The better your idea is the more crap audio people are willing to put up with but there is still a level where no one's Gonna listen to it.
Speaker 0: Now I guess we can talk a bit about post-production before we end here and by post-production I mean all the stuff you do after you recorded the episode.
Speaker 0: well,
Speaker 1: the first thing you do is you cut it out when someone says stuff like and And Yeah, yep,
Speaker 2: or when you have like a half hour of just laughing
Speaker 0: Scott and I actually cut out very little from episodes.
Speaker 0: I like maybe maybe a minutes worth of audio from an entire episode.
Speaker 0: we cut out.
Speaker 2: Ah, but how much did you do back when you started?
Speaker 0: when we started we'd cut out like 20 minutes of us Just saying penis at each other.
Speaker 0: Usually the things we cut out are like silence Yeah saying um, or if one of us stopped talking Expecting the other person to chip in but the other person was like not paying attention which doesn't happen so often Except for just now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just but we're a little.
Speaker 0: we've had a long weekend of geek and we're kind of tired right about now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I got a busy day at work actually tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah grown, but that's key.
Speaker 0: So it basically It'll take a long time when you first start podcasting no matter how good you are.
Speaker 0: You'll flub over words.
Speaker 0: You'll screw things up You'll you'll cough into the microphone.
Speaker 0: Everyone's looking at me
Speaker 1: Unless you're like who's
Speaker 2: been sick for two weeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah for all of you.
Speaker 0: the week after katsu khan I don't think you all understand how sick I was doing the podcast.
Speaker 0: Well, I was listening to them and I didn't remember saying any of that stuff was Yeah, but anyway now Nuri you do a lot more editing.
Speaker 2: oh, yeah, well I've only done four.
Speaker 2: I'm editing my fifth show right now.
Speaker 2: So you guys have done so many more shows than me and we're still working on Building our podcasting habits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like we've got actually we're getting better about it.
Speaker 0: But the first time we had a guest on the show the first couple times.
Speaker 0: I don't know what image you have of us doing geek nights but I'm sitting with my back to almost everyone talking into a microphone and a pop filter and Staring at my computer and the show notes.
Speaker 0: Scott is laying on his back.
Speaker 0: You should take a big time with the microphone like in the air over his mouth and Nuri is kind of lounging on my bed.
Speaker 1: We should go take a soft.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's awesome.
Speaker 0: My bed was made in like the 1800s the late 1800s, but still I wasn't lying.
Speaker 2: That's not important.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not at all.
Speaker 0: but and People who we interview or people we have on the show?
Speaker 0: They expect us to be talking to each other because it sounds like we're just two guys standing room talking to each other.
Speaker 0: We're not looking at each other.
Speaker 0: We're not gesturing in any way.
Speaker 0: He's lying.
Speaker 1: Imagine like we're in a TV studio just like yeah, and we have two desks and a whole bunch of couches Between you real fancy microphones and a backdrop that looks like the Hudson River.
Speaker 0: our set looks exactly like The Daily Show.
Speaker 1: In fact, it is The Daily Show.
Speaker 0: Yeah John Stewart.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's here right now.
Speaker 0: He's sitting in the corner.
Speaker 0: He's making this motion.
Speaker 0: Like don't say I'm here.
Speaker 0: I'm supposed to be now.
Speaker 0: he's mad now.
Speaker 0: He's gone.
Speaker 0: He left.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're coming.
Speaker 1: I see a cane coming out from behind the curtain.
Speaker 1: It's around my neck.
Speaker 1: see I Thought that'd be funny.
Speaker 1: I Don't care you do it everyone.
Speaker 0: All right, see now I'm not gonna cut out what just happened But that's the kind of thing that you can cut out like if someone makes a deadpan joke Nobody laughs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or it's just not funny dong See if it were for the fact that it probably annoy you I'm can.
Speaker 0: I was considering just now not editing what we just recorded at All so you can hear the raw like rah rah rah podcast.
Speaker 0: however Most of the cuts are just silence between bits as we collect our thoughts.
Speaker 1: one day Maybe we should.
Speaker 1: when we do a show we should put up like two posts.
Speaker 1: We should be like post the podcast post special unedited version.
Speaker 0: even better.
Speaker 0: We'll post the podcast and then we'll post a stream of all the audio that was cut out.
Speaker 1: They could do that.
Speaker 0: That would be good because it's not that much.
Speaker 0: That would be something trivial that I'm sure at least some of you would like to listen to.
Speaker 0: yeah It's mostly obscenities or silence.
Speaker 2: Yeah back to the whole communicating with each other thing.
Speaker 2: Communication between the podcasters is really important.
Speaker 2: I mean, I know you guys have kind of interrupting cow moo.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you guys have kind of How to talk to each other even when you're not looking at each other, but for my podcast we have one microphone.
Speaker 2: We're in a triangle staring at each other And if we want to say something we have to like stare at the person who's got the mic and hold out our hand.
Speaker 0: That stuff I mean a lot of podcasters is one guy.
Speaker 0: the more people you have the harder it is be ready for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one guy or one girl is the easiest podcast in the universe.
Speaker 0: Yes, two is okay But it took Scott and I about 20 episodes to get down where we don't keep interrupting each other or where one of us will stop talking.
Speaker 0: the other one doesn't pick Up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't even really think about it.
Speaker 0: It's just kind of like, you know I just do the well for anyone doesn't know us when the podcast stops We just keep talking almost exactly the way we're talking now For the next several hours without a microphone in front of our faces.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could pretty much we could do a 24-hour show if you really wanted and it would be mostly interesting.
Speaker 2: It would be mostly Scott playing video games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or so.
Speaker 1: I don't play that many video games.
Speaker 1: usually just because you people are here I can't actually do any work on my computer.
Speaker 1: So instead you play video games exactly because then at least someone will be entertained by watching the video game.
Speaker 1: And you can't tell me you don't like watching video games.
Speaker 0: in addition to editing, you know Like actually cutting things out you have to do some sort of post-production filtering.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you don't have to.
Speaker 0: you should Very simply very briefly a noise gate.
Speaker 0: All it does is you can say any noise below a certain volume Where this this noise or this volume lasts for a certain amount of time will be cut out entirely.
Speaker 0: That can cut out like breathing noises between when anyone's talking or static from your mixer or Anything like that any background noise me bumping into the microphone.
Speaker 0: Oh
Speaker 1: The problem is
Speaker 0: if
Speaker 1: you don't if you turn it up too high or if you have too much noise you'll end up either cutting out all the noise and some of your voice or You know not enough of the noise and it's really tough unless you have really behaved.
Speaker 1: well-behaved noise.
Speaker 0: Yeah now well-behaved.
Speaker 0: There some people get good at like the DJ voice or the radio voice and they can talk at a fairly Constant volume at around a regular at a regular rate and they hold the microphone said distance from their mouth.
Speaker 1: Hey everybody It's Saturday.
Speaker 0: A lot of people can't do that.
Speaker 0: So the other thing you can do is called compression.
Speaker 0: Now I talked about compression already with the hardware.
Speaker 0: You can also do it in software.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend that you do some form of compression on your podcast Software.
Speaker 2: do you use to do software?
Speaker 0: Well, I use resound which I find to be absolutely fantastic.
Speaker 0: But if you're a Linux awesome Yeah It's only for Linux and you might have some trouble getting it to work a hundred percent if you use any sort of Good distro except Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: It just works in Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: Yep, you can use garage band.
Speaker 1: I know garage band has a very nice compression.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you have a bag and your lead Yeah, and you can figure it out.
Speaker 2: cuz I've got garage band and I don't know I don't have the garage band version that supports the make a podcast.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah The real newest garage band has the podcasting stuff in it.
Speaker 1: So that's nice.
Speaker 2: It'll.
Speaker 2: it'll actually do the noise gate while you're recording and it does like pops and stuff.
Speaker 0: That's a real-time audio is a pain in the ass in Linux.
Speaker 0: but the thing is most real-time filters don't help much because you can do them just as easily after the fact.
Speaker 0: and The clipping is the limiting factor in recording and your sound card can't do anything about clipping.
Speaker 0: That all has to be done with hardware before it hits the computer.
Speaker 1: Yep, the most popular podcast software seems to either be audacity Which is for all so all operating which actually we also use.
Speaker 0: we use both resound and audacity for different purposes.
Speaker 2: Audacity is the free provided software online and all the podcast directories like podcast alley linked to it.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's just a multitrack editors.
Speaker 0: You can line up all your tracks and just export and it has compressors and stuff in it.
Speaker 1: The other thing a lot of people use I don't know I don't think it's a hundred percent free is cast blaster.
Speaker 1: cast blaster is like the one-stop shop for podcasting like it does everything from beginning to end from Recording to uploading to your website and making the post and the show notes.
Speaker 0: now, isn't it Windows only?
Speaker 1: it is Windows only Which is why we do not use it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Then we're thinking about using it for like conventions where we won't have all our equipment with us or we won't have like my computer With us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: it has one nice thing about cast blaster Buttons and you can assign like audio files to the buttons.
Speaker 1: So let's say you have a button with a funny jingle on it like rim doesn't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Well while you're recording you just push the rim doesn't give a shit button and it'll play that instead of having to add in rim Doesn't give a shit after you're done recording.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can also do that with compressors.
Speaker 0: It's called auto ducking.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get into that now.
Speaker 0: That's well beyond what you need to know well beyond.
Speaker 2: Yeah, if you want to go the extra step and buy a program that's a little bit higher quality than those there's a program called.
Speaker 2: What is it?
Speaker 2: Adobe Audition.
Speaker 2: Yeah Windows machines.
Speaker 0: now Adobe Audition is actually mostly this other program called cool edit.
Speaker 0: If you can find a copy of cool edit for Windows use it use it use it.
Speaker 0: It's fantastic don't use it does?
Speaker 0: Adobe bought it and raped the shell.
Speaker 0: That was that program.
Speaker 2: Yeah, they probably charge a heck of a lot more for it, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah But whatever Sony also makes a program.
Speaker 2: I think it's called sound Forge, but it's pretty much the equivalent of the Adobe one.
Speaker 0: Oh I've used that in that audio class.
Speaker 0: I took with katsu at RIT wasn't there?
Speaker 1: Pro Tools?
Speaker 0: Is well beyond what you need to do a pod.
Speaker 2: Pro Tools is what professional recording studios use.
Speaker 1: yeah But you can use it and it'll work If you want.
Speaker 0: yeah if you have money Buy a firewire mixer and a Mac and Pro Tools and it'll do.
Speaker 0: is about everything you need.
Speaker 1: Sony also makes some sort of Windows software.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it's called now a noise gate compression and The main thing here is normalization Even if you don't do anything else Normalize.
Speaker 0: if the first half of your podcast is real loud the second half is quiet or every day is a different volume.
Speaker 0: It's just gonna piss me off.
Speaker 1: Yep, normalizing will at least make sure that the volume is Somewhat the same throughout, you know from day to day from minute to minute.
Speaker 2: So what's the difference in your waveform before you normalize and after you normalize?
Speaker 0: Well, it depends on whether or not you do dynamic normalization now basically a normal normalizer.
Speaker 0: That sounded really dumb a normal normalizer.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the standard basic normal.
Speaker 0: all it'll do is it'll find the loudest point in your podcast and Amplify everything in your podcast until that loudest point is as loud as a wave file can make something loud.
Speaker 0: that's all it'll do.
Speaker 0: a Dynamic one will go through your podcast and amplify different parts by different amounts to make everything louder.
Speaker 0: But make things that are already loud stay the current loudness and not get louder.
Speaker 0: to use the word loud a lot of times in one sentence.
Speaker 1: I Can't think of another word for loud right now.
Speaker 0: Loud Painful.
Speaker 0: Now what I do.
Speaker 0: just a lot of podcasts seem to do this lately.
Speaker 0: But basically you want your podcast to be as loud as possible Not as quiet as possible.
Speaker 0: the standard generally in terms of audio on the internet is make it loud.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the thing is is if you make it quiet that means that you know If you want people to be able to hear it They have to make it loud on their end using their stereo their iPod Whatever and if they do that what happens is all the really bad parts of the audio like the hissing and whatnot.
Speaker 0: Get louder also When and it's just bad you want to do as much that you can to the audio before they get to it.
Speaker 0: that way They don't have to do much.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Now in audacity a lot of podcasters seem to use the standard of.
Speaker 0: they'll normalize to negative point two decibels.
Speaker 0: If you don't know what that means, don't worry about it.
Speaker 0: if you normalize or amplified send it to that.
Speaker 0: It's a nice Baseline.
Speaker 2: if you the default in audacity is that normalizes to zero?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do it to negative point two.
Speaker 0: I've seen a lot of people do that there.
Speaker 0: There's almost no difference between the two.
Speaker 2: Well, it's negative point two indeed As opposed to zero which is uh, I'm just saying if you want to use zero If you want to use audacity, you're gonna have to set that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one thing you can do is just Google around online and look at what other podcasters do in terms of their settings.
Speaker 0: But keep in mind that if they say specific numbers They're not gonna help you much in a lot of cases because your levels are probably a lot different from their levels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when people are talking about specific numbers in their settings, that's pretty much like a case-by-case basis eight six, seven five three.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah, that is not rims phone number.
Speaker 1: Do not call that If anyone if anyone doesn't know what that is, you're all.
Speaker 1: you're going on the uncool list along with the rest of the people.
Speaker 0: How about just born after the 80s?
Speaker 0: No, actually if you call it, I'm not gonna give.
Speaker 1: I don't know that it sounded to me like you just said uncool.
Speaker 0: Now I'm not gonna give you my phone number But for all of since you know My phone was lost and that cool guy is sending it to me.
Speaker 0: if you call if someone knows my phone number and calls it Some FedEx guy is gonna have a loud cell phone ringtone going off in his in the back of his truck.
Speaker 0: I Swear to God if my phone gets blown up because they think it's a bomb.
Speaker 1: Dude, I'm totally calling it tomorrow.
Speaker 0: All right, so we're basically done here.
Speaker 0: we've gone long enough.
Speaker 0: If your podcast sucks make it not suck and if you have a question we have for like.
Speaker 0: seriously if you have a question about how to do podcasts email us or post in the forums or Find Nuri's podcast which will link to and I ask her because that we all know a lot about this stuff.
Speaker 0: And if you have a specific question, we can answer it in fairly deep detail Because he sits at work all day and does nothing.
Speaker 1: quite you, you know, who else can answer the question?
Speaker 1: Google Google can answer the question.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll be wary.
Speaker 0: I've seen a lot of podcasters that have a site on how to do a podcast But they don't know what they're talking about and they're just they're making shit up.
Speaker 1: Well, they're not making it up.
Speaker 1: They're just you know, they think they're doing good when they're not doing so good because they're not informed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like that guy who pretends he knows that he's talking about Samir Gupta Rim Samir Show on Samir Gupta someday and Roland pika-pam Roland peak Paley Whatever his name is.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to pronounce it.
Speaker 1: I don't either.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's not that hard though.
Speaker 2: I mean you search on Google for how to make a podcast And you should be able to tell pretty quickly which sites are good which says aren't two sites that say the same thing You're on the right track.
Speaker 1: Yeah As long as one didn't copy from the other.
Speaker 1: another good way to tell is if a guy says something Listen to his podcast and see what it sounds like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if he tells you how to do a podcast and his podcast sounds like to say what I've been saying all night Yeah, what you could also do is go around listening to podcasts and find one.
Speaker 1: find ones that you know look good and seem like they spent the same amount of money you're gonna spend and See if they have an episode about how they do it because a lot of them do.
Speaker 1: I'd say about 75% of podcasts have an episode about how they do it.
Speaker 0: and if you're gonna spend about $100 ask us Because I think our podcast sounds really good.
Speaker 2: Hey, maybe you guys should have a.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, because you know everyone in the frickin world keeps asking us to do a show on it to do a post on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so God doesn't want to do it Because everyone else freaking does it.
Speaker 2: that you know, I know another podcast But your podcast sounds better than most of the other podcasts out there that I listen to and I listen to a shitload of Podcasts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I think we should do a public service to the world.
Speaker 0: All right, all right anyway.
Speaker 0: once again I apologize if the second half of the show doesn't sound as good as you're used to.
Speaker 1: you know The part we talked about how to make it sound good.
Speaker 0: Yeah part Once I'm gonna buy another pre amplifier.
Speaker 0: So when we have guests on the show, we can actually use the mixer the way we're supposed to.
Speaker 2: Yeah, invite me back when that happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah You Roy Jenkins See.
Speaker 0: now this is the part that we cut off at the end of the show or just play the music And That was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.