Speaker 1: It's Monday January 9th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We argue about how to maintain your computer.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So Scott's a little sick today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got some snot in the nose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though he claims that he never gets sick ever and that his immune system is perfect, but I'm not sick.
Speaker 0: It's a cold in my immune system.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 1: You just said I'm not sick Colin.
Speaker 1: It's a cold.
Speaker 1: Yeah, do you know what a cold is?
Speaker 0: It's a little rhinovirus guy, uh, yeah virus, yep, uh Sick, I'm in the process of kicking its ass.
Speaker 1: I don't know considering that you whined until I Accompanied you to CVS last night so you could buy a humidifier for your room.
Speaker 0: You came.
Speaker 1: You tried to buy mine from me.
Speaker 0: I didn't try to buy it from you.
Speaker 0: I didn't take it from you.
Speaker 0: I wasn't gonna pay you money for it.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I just have one funny little bit today.
Speaker 1: I discovered that I am NOT just rim.
Speaker 1: I am the Definite article rim as in the rim, you know, I didn't know any other rims.
Speaker 1: Actually, there's a rim who works for CNN CNN.
Speaker 1: Yeah rim Brahmi is one of their reporters.
Speaker 0: How do they spell his name our YM and it's a woman really?
Speaker 1: Yeah And there's a more and more and finding the word rim on the internet all over the place in things that aren't related to me Republican youth majority.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or a brand of underwear that ran underwear is awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking of buying some.
Speaker 0: get some.
Speaker 1: These designer like men's sexy briefs in other words ghetto bvds.
Speaker 1: Actually my initials cuz my real name is Brandon, but well not my real name kind of my given name.
Speaker 1: I don't really use it.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a long story.
Speaker 1: But uh, my dad when I was born wanted to make my middle name Vincent just so that my initials would be BVD And my mom put the kibosh on that.
Speaker 1: right quick right Lisa but someone mentioned my name apparently at our IT where I used to go and run the anime club and everything and Someone in the room turns and says wait a minute.
Speaker 1: You mean the rim?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a second hand third hand story.
Speaker 0: No, no Resource.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you're still be King exaggerator.
Speaker 1: So hey, hey, do I have to get the primary source on the show to tell you what's up?
Speaker 0: I'll still.
Speaker 0: I'll go and find out what really happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I find it.
Speaker 1: Absolutely hilarious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it was something I'm not saying it was totally You know not happening.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying you are exaggerating the Something.
Speaker 1: someone said blah blah blah rim and some and then someone else said the rim.
Speaker 1: But in less funny news Bush signed in a law today a bill that I had not heard of or been in any way aware of Until slash dot and fart told me about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think anyone knew about it because you know what 99% of laws No one knows anything about.
Speaker 1: but I mean usually when you hear about a like a bad law like the DMCA or something horrible Or that the CDB CBD PA that's these people are watching out for that stuff.
Speaker 1: yeah, but it's always like this menacing thing far off on the horizon that either won't likely get passed or we're gonna worry about it years to come.
Speaker 1: this one didn't appear until it was passed and It's the violence against women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act.
Speaker 0: That's why no one knew about it because the only people looking at it were the people who are like the feminists and they want to be against violence against women and They pushed it through actually.
Speaker 1: No, that's not at all.
Speaker 1: What happened?
Speaker 0: No, this
Speaker 1: was a law that was just kind of cobbled together from a whole bunch of various anti harassment anti Discrimination things all bundled together
Speaker 0: see me as an anti First Amendment law
Speaker 1: No, and then tacked on to another spending law that was gonna get passed no matter what?
Speaker 1: Great had nothing to do with feminists.
Speaker 1: I don't know why I even brought them up.
Speaker 0: Okay Then why did it say violence against women?
Speaker 0: something?
Speaker 1: because that was just one of the names on the law.
Speaker 1: Because part of the law is to protect women who divorce or actually Women and men it just uses women the title of the law who divorce an abusive spouse and want to not be harassed by them.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but basically the law and I'm not exaggerating at all here makes it illegal to in any way annoy someone on The internet or in any way with any piece of technology without providing your full legal name.
Speaker 0: So wait.
Speaker 1: So yeah, if you're a troll on slashdot and you don't say who you are jail two years.
Speaker 0: so who determines When someone's annoying and when someone's not?
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: it's just like any other law.
Speaker 1: it's like any harassment case.
Speaker 0: So I can just say that guy's annoying me and go after him.
Speaker 0: Yeah Sweet next time someone is all like pros something.
Speaker 0: I'm against.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go after him and say they're annoying.
Speaker 1: Okay way to just exploit a stupid law to cause a bad situation.
Speaker 0: That's the easiest way to make it go away.
Speaker 1: Probably not see.
Speaker 1: I worry if the courts are even gonna look at this case because it supposedly protects people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but as soon as someone sees it being abused they're gonna get rid of it.
Speaker 0: or a job.
Speaker 1: MCA has been abused countless times and it's still there.
Speaker 1: the Patriot Act has been abused countless times and it's still there.
Speaker 0: Well, then, you know what worst case.
Speaker 0: a bunch of people.
Speaker 0: I don't like will go to jail Great, and you know what that'll immediately turn them into people I do like as they'll be on my side trying to get rid of the stupid law.
Speaker 0: So Myspace the bastion of crappy websites for crappy little kids god.
Speaker 1: I hate my space so much.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it was bought by evil Fox recently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Murdoch's News Corp and all that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: and They finally started doing evil.
Speaker 0: They blocked links on my space to places like YouTube and Anything that competed with them?
Speaker 0: Yeah, anything that Fox didn't like.
Speaker 0: they basically Myspace blocked it.
Speaker 1: They either deleted the links or they change the text of the links or they deleted entries or filtered them out or you know whatever.
Speaker 0: so Every all little kiddies on myspace said what the hell we're just gonna stop using my space and go use something else.
Speaker 0: And then they caved and they undid it.
Speaker 1: Yeah for now.
Speaker 1: Luckily.
Speaker 1: I think those people realize that they have to get off of myspace.
Speaker 0: Think so
Speaker 1: But at least it made me happy that even in the cesspool that is myspace Which is only about one step up above 4chan in terms of crap Actually had enough smart people to realize that something bad was going on and did everything they could to mitigate that.
Speaker 0: I think any group on the internet period that if you try to you know Do something that harms a group on the internet?
Speaker 0: They'll just come at you, you know, because it's so easy to go after someone on the internet All you do is type a few words and you push buttons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's easy to ignore anyone who does that to you on the internet but not it's not easy to ignore a thousand people.
Speaker 0: who?
Speaker 0: Do that on the internet?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: You just don't read your email anymore.
Speaker 1: You get a new account.
Speaker 0: Yeah And then but if you're like in charge of something or you have power on the internet You'll soon lose all that power when all the people you have power over stop using your software?
Speaker 1: That depends.
Speaker 1: I mean AOL has done a lot of terrible things with aim over the years and most people still use aim.
Speaker 0: We jump ship right just the right time.
Speaker 1: actually we both still use aim so we didn't really jump ship.
Speaker 0: I use aim through a transport so it doesn't.
Speaker 1: so you're still using aim.
Speaker 1: You do you realize that most of your friends use aim?
Speaker 1: a grand total of about ten of us use jabber?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if you look at the messages I said most of the messages I said are to me Specifically to me and me alone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I don't really use aim that much or any.
Speaker 0: I am that much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I am is really my primary means of communication these days.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't really communicate that much.
Speaker 1: Well, you don't communicate with people.
Speaker 1: That's your problem.
Speaker 1: You're always out of the loop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I don't need to be in the loop.
Speaker 0: I communicate when I got something to say when I want to know something specific.
Speaker 1: I just talked to people.
Speaker 0: I don't talk for the sake of talking.
Speaker 0: That's a waste of time.
Speaker 1: I got something to do Podcasting So those of you who know us may know that we're big fans of mr.
Speaker 1: T.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: T. He don't be nobody's fool and Mr.
Speaker 1: T for many of you who might not know had a cartoon show on.
Speaker 1: I think it was the early 90s.
Speaker 0: never saw it.
Speaker 1: it's pretty terrible and In addition to that, I don't know what this is from and I didn't bother looking on the internet to find out but mr T did a music video about uh Mothers, no way Was he singing or was it like his band?
Speaker 0: or as far as I know he's not a musician.
Speaker 1: See it's weird because he's not singing so much as he's talking at you and there's music in the background Uh-huh, and there's backup singers.
Speaker 1: They're singing and dancing.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: T's just standing there pointing his finger at you and talking kind of like Captain Kirk Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Well actually kind of like William Shatner who wasn't playing Kirk when he did that album or how about?
Speaker 0: kind of like mr T who does that, you know looks at you in points and talks at you.
Speaker 1: All I got to say is when you watch my thing of the day after about 30 seconds of it That's all you're gonna get out of it.
Speaker 1: Don't watch the whole thing.
Speaker 1: You'll die.
Speaker 0: I pity the fool who watch the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: So remember the other day we talked about a square one math man math, man.
Speaker 0: I found a nice little website with a bunch of videos from square one one of which is a math, man.
Speaker 1: it's terrible.
Speaker 0: he has to eat every number less than 0.5 and It's just like the olden days when I was a little kid where I'd say yeah eat that one you eat that one.
Speaker 0: Yes Yeah, eat that one.
Speaker 0: Eat that one.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, you idiot if you eat that one.
Speaker 0: I swear to god I'm turning off the TV.
Speaker 0: God damn it.
Speaker 0: God damn it stupid frickin math, man.
Speaker 0: I could beat this game.
Speaker 0: Give me the joystick.
Speaker 0: Yeah Only uh, it looks a lot worse than I remember it.
Speaker 1: It's very obvious that while they're emulating a computer game They did not use a computer to do so.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean sure the bad encoding of the internet video counts for something, but really it's worse than I remember.
Speaker 0: It's bad.
Speaker 0: We should make new math, man.
Speaker 1: So, uh today since it's Monday, which is generally SciTech computer Linux, what's-it-day We're gonna talk about how to maintain your computer.
Speaker 0: A lot of people don't even know they need to maintain their computer.
Speaker 1: I mean most people like they build the computer and there's all this sweat and blood.
Speaker 0: Or they just buy a Dell.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm talking to you know people are at least a little geeky.
Speaker 1: You build a computer and you put a lot of effort into building it and Then it's done and you turn it on and you you know You either install Windows and reboot it 5,000 times or you install Linux and you just do a thousand things to it
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: and then it's done and you leave it and every now and then you install an application Mm-hmm, you can't do that.
Speaker 1: No, I mean it sounds weird and we're not saying that there's bit rot or anything stupid like that.
Speaker 1: But computers need maintenance just like cars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of people are like, ah, the computer shouldn't need any maintenance.
Speaker 0: I want it to have no maintenance.
Speaker 0: if it needs maintenance.
Speaker 0: It sucks.
Speaker 0: Well Everything in the world needs maintenance even like a toaster oven you got to clean the crumbs out.
Speaker 1: No, you don't.
Speaker 1: toaster ovens are three dollars.
Speaker 1: You just buy a new one.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but I'm just you know, I'm saying like even a VCR, you know You can clean it.
Speaker 1: you realize most people don't know you can clean a VCR and they just used to buy new ones or they Take it to a VCR repairman.
Speaker 0: and those are the same people who don't know that when you get spyware You can format your hard drive and reinstall the OS and they just buy a new computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah So you've ever laughed at someone for buying a new something when they could have just fixed it?
Speaker 1: and you don't maintain your computer?
Speaker 1: Well, we're laughing at you.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now if you have a Mac a lot of this doesn't apply because Macs actually really make it easy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just it won't mess up for a very long time and there's not much you can do to mess it up.
Speaker 0: I mean and you can.
Speaker 0: there aren't even screws on those things.
Speaker 0: You can't open them.
Speaker 1: so and you don't need to but PC's you need to.
Speaker 0: yeah Well, you still need to maintain a Mac.
Speaker 0: is eventually, you know You might mess it up and you don't you don't really want to.
Speaker 0: a lot of the things apply across the board no matter what?
Speaker 0: Operating system or kind of computer you have but a Mac you really can't you know get to the point.
Speaker 0: or with Linux You can't get to the point where your computer is.
Speaker 0: just think of it like in your car.
Speaker 0: If you don't change the oil the engine will seize, you know, that's the end of the car.
Speaker 0: But with Windows you can get the engine to seize but not with Linux or Mac or anything unless you go out of your way.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're using Gentoo and you change your global keyword to star and then emerge update new use deep world?
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but that's just that's not.
Speaker 0: that's not forgetting to change the oil and having the engine.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: That is that's replacing the oil with Explosive.
Speaker 0: No, that's driving a hundred miles an hour and then switching into reverse.
Speaker 1: All right, I guess we'll break this up into two broad categories physical and Non-physical.
Speaker 0: the physical is easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 1: it's easy in some ways.
Speaker 1: The hard part is actually doing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm going to do it and knowing that you have to do it Well number one if your computer gets dusty clean it out.
Speaker 1: now you might think oh it doesn't get dusty in there.
Speaker 1: I mean look my desk isn't that dusty?
Speaker 0: open it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you haven't opened your computer before in fact If you've never opened your computer Right after you listen to this open your tape turn your computer off unplug it and just open it and look inside Unless you're allergic to dust or something weird like that.
Speaker 0: You want me to do it outside?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna be real non-technical here.
Speaker 1: So, uh, you know if you have a TV or stereo and For some reason there's always more dust on the TV than there is on anything else in the house There's always more dust on the electronic things than the non-electronic thing.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of reasons for that but electronic things collect dust.
Speaker 1: Your computer is the most electronic thing you own.
Speaker 1: well, unless you own a Various cool Tesla things which we won't talk about.
Speaker 0: little Jacob's ladder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or a little a spark transmitter.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: But I mean the inside of your computer.
Speaker 1: you have the fans on right and they're drawing air through your computer.
Speaker 1: They're drawing dust in and the dust isn't coming back out.
Speaker 0: Well, you know the the dust might come back out but not much.
Speaker 0: and if you have a filter on your intake fan Like I do sure there won't be that much dust in your computer.
Speaker 0: But you still have to clean that filter off or else eventually it'll just start sucking the dust right through it Or even worse.
Speaker 1: It'll just block the intake and then your computer overheat and crash.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's even.
Speaker 1: that's a real bad - so I mean I've seen people like.
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of people who had they bought like an Alienware computer or something and it has a little kind of filter e on it and they thought oh I never have to clean my computer because I got a little filter.
Speaker 1: and Then their computer doesn't work anymore and I look at it and you know what?
Speaker 1: You don't have an intake fan anymore.
Speaker 0: You just have a giant opaque solid mass of dust Yep, and it's real hard depending on like what it to get a replacement for that filter, you know They don't make you know Filters for intake fans that you can just buy in the shape.
Speaker 0: that for your case specifically Especially since cases change every week, you know.
Speaker 1: So the first thing you want to do is if you've never done it before Open your computer and take a can of compressed air and when I say compressed air I mean the compressed air.
Speaker 1: you buy it like staples.
Speaker 0: yeah, I'll just be in there.
Speaker 0: there should be a section in staples that has little cans of air and like LCD monitor wipes and all sorts of computer cleaning equipment's
Speaker 1: use the ones you find at a computer store or an office store because they won't sell the other kinds you go to a hardware store you'll have more choices as to what kind of compressed air you want and Some kinds can break your computer or cause static or get chemicals.
Speaker 1: all these problems.
Speaker 0: Some of those are meant for Not cleaning.
Speaker 0: they're meant for like, you know filling tires or crazy stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Don't use those.
Speaker 0: You don't want that.
Speaker 1: Basically just take the can always hold it upright because if you tip it over Noxious things are gonna come out of it like liquid nitrogen.
Speaker 0: Oh things that will freeze you.
Speaker 0: Yeah and freeze your computer with.
Speaker 1: and basically just first do this outside to and Spray down the entire inside of the computer.
Speaker 1: You'll see caked up dust.
Speaker 1: Just spray it all out Mmm, and then take the little little bit of a straw a bit that you can stick into the end of the can.
Speaker 1: Feel free as long as the computers unplug to poke that into various bits like the power supply The fan around the CPU and just get all the gunk out.
Speaker 0: One of my favorite things to do is point it straight at a fan and pull the trigger and you can make the fans spin Real fast and all the dust comes flying out.
Speaker 0: That's great.
Speaker 1: Now after you've done that and the computers clean you really have two options Either do that every month or so more often if you smoke more often still if you have pets More often still if your computer is in the basement on the floor Or if you live in like Mexico City Or
Speaker 0: like my parents who keeps the freaking computer like on the floor in the kitchen.
Speaker 0: that thing was so freakin dusty.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, man.
Speaker 1: at IBM where I work We have the sintering area which basically are giant furnaces shooting flame into the air Constantly awesome and the air is real sooty Great.
Speaker 1: I maintain like 30 computers in there.
Speaker 0: Well, you just put them in plastic bags or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'll work.
Speaker 0: or just like pipe out the the heat from the computers to somewhere else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and where are they gonna get their intake air from?
Speaker 1: Another pipe, you know what?
Speaker 1: No, I just replaced the computers and they stopped working because they're so cheap and I have so many.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: But anyway, that's really all you have to do to make sure your hardware of your computer stays.
Speaker 0: Good is make sure dust doesn't get all over it.
Speaker 1: But I mean you can either do this every month or you can put a filter on it And then you maybe have to clean the filter every month, which is usually easier.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I should go clean my filter.
Speaker 0: I keep forgetting.
Speaker 1: now I would recommend against buying any sort of filter you see in a store.
Speaker 1: They're overpriced.
Speaker 1: They don't fit Well, they're generally pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: now what I do and Scott kind of says this is a but whatever I use pantyhose for a lot of things.
Speaker 1: I use pantyhose for this pop filter I'm talking through right now and buy a pair of pantyhose and make a filter out of that.
Speaker 0: Oh, see my case came with a filter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most cases don't?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: a lot of cases now They have little filters.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah a lot too, but most don't.
Speaker 0: well if you're buying a case get one with a little intake filter.
Speaker 1: I'd recommend not caring about that because it's much cheaper to just buy a pair of pantyhose Because the case that has an intake filter cost so much more than one without.
Speaker 1: Well a lot of a lot of side.
Speaker 1: They just don't say if it has an intake filter like on Newegg.
Speaker 0: They just say fans whatever you can see you can look at the picture of the case and you're like, oh look There's a filter there.
Speaker 1: You can't always see.
Speaker 1: The presence of an intake filter should not in any way influence for how you buy a case.
Speaker 0: I don't influence how I buy a case.
Speaker 1: You're silly.
Speaker 0: No, you're silly.
Speaker 1: Your case has a glass panel in the side and you have a frickin cold cathode tube that flashes blue light.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: You have a riced out computer and it's better than your computer.
Speaker 1: Rice is not cool on a computer.
Speaker 1: I think it's silly.
Speaker 0: Well, you think it's silly but I think it looks better than your computer.
Speaker 1: Okay, Scott.
Speaker 1: How come it looks good on your computer, but is dumb on your car?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah well Because a computer just like sits there and does nothing, right?
Speaker 0: It's not really You know, they're traditionally like blah and it's not something people look at.
Speaker 0: so turning it into something people look at is like, ah but a car is traditionally something people look at and You know putting lights on it doesn't make it look good.
Speaker 1: How does putting lights on the computer make it look good then?
Speaker 0: Because we're not really much else you can do.
Speaker 1: Um, that was probably the worst argument you've ever made.
Speaker 1: It was real bad.
Speaker 0: What else can you do to make a computer look good?
Speaker 0: It's a box.
Speaker 0: I mean you put a light on it.
Speaker 1: Give it up.
Speaker 1: Just give it up.
Speaker 0: It's like a Christmas tree.
Speaker 0: What can you do to make it look good?
Speaker 1: put a light on it Yeah, so why not put a light on the car?
Speaker 1: Why is the car different?
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: if your car is real crummy a light can help it.
Speaker 1: But if Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: No, no in fact I submit the opposite.
Speaker 1: the better your car is the more likely a light would look good there.
Speaker 1: if you have like a 91 broken tempo putting a blue light on the bottom is not going to make it look better, you know LEDs make everything better including cars Only if they're yeah.
Speaker 1: Don't try to argue when you're sick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's my advice to you Scott.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: How do we maintain a damn computer?
Speaker 1: So anyway, just take some pantyhose and stick them on your intake fans and leave some slack.
Speaker 1: So they'll catch all the dust and then periodically replace them.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's that's the cheapest way to put a filter.
Speaker 1: or like James Coon said in our forums set up your fake your case with positive Pressure meaning have more intake fans than you do.
Speaker 1: exhaust fans.
Speaker 1: That'll keep air from coming in anywhere other than the intakes.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I go with negative pressure because it cools slightly better.
Speaker 1: You just have to clean the inside of the case a lot more often Mm-hmm, so it's kind of a trade-off.
Speaker 1: And you know just there's little things like keep your computer Generally, like don't spell things on it.
Speaker 1: Don't knock it over.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah keyboards.
Speaker 0: Just you can clean keyboards and you should because the dirtiest part of the computer.
Speaker 0: But really you should buy a new one like every year too because they just get mad nasty.
Speaker 1: I use the same keyboard from sixth grade until my junior year and I was freaking mad nasty.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, it had like marker and stickers and key binds from games.
Speaker 1: I played back but like doom two days.
Speaker 0: It was a scary kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah a freaking thing Yeah, and it finally died.
Speaker 1: and then I bought the keyboard I'm using now.
Speaker 0: Thank God I've used four.
Speaker 1: I've used three keyboards in my entire life on my computers mice these days.
Speaker 0: They used to get dirty with the balls.
Speaker 0: But unless you have a ball mouse, which no one has anymore if one has an optical mouse a little light in the bottom You don't need to clean those so much.
Speaker 1: yeah, unless your optical mouse stops working you don't need to buy a new one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though one thing I got to say I see a lot of people who they have an optical mouse.
Speaker 1: So they think oh, I don't need a mouse pad and they just use the mouse on the desk.
Speaker 0: You don't really need a mouse pen.
Speaker 1: There's a good reason why you should have a mouse pad even a little one.
Speaker 1: Because if you just use the mouse on the desk look at look at you take flip your mouse over.
Speaker 1: right now There's probably three or four little ceramic or silicone noblis and they make the mouse flow nicely.
Speaker 1: They're low friction surfaces.
Speaker 1: They get worn down real quick on a lot of old a lot of wooden type desks.
Speaker 0: Well if it depends if your desk is all chafee It'll get worn down like my desk is a shitty piece of wood that I just bought and sanded.
Speaker 0: So you know I need a little pad.
Speaker 0: But if you have like a normal a nice desk with a nice shiny wood that you know is all fan No, even then it wears down the little noblis a lot faster if you have a mouse pad.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: You know is it work at work?
Speaker 0: absolutely no one has a mouse pad and no one's noblis are worn down.
Speaker 1: See at my work everyone who doesn't have a mouse pad their noblis are gone.
Speaker 1: mice are just these scrapey horrible things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are no mouse pads in my work pretty much at all and everyone's just fine of course.
Speaker 0: at the same time actually I saw on the internet just yesterday you can buy little low-friction mouse Stickery bits so if yours wear down you can just replace them for like a buck or two.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, actually they were actually Advertising them as like special gamer ones so they would be even better now.
Speaker 1: That's just a little silly.
Speaker 0: Well, you know that.
Speaker 0: what do you want?
Speaker 1: see that?
Speaker 1: That's just.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a level that's basically audio fileness for gamers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is a mouse pad though the other benefit of a mouse pad that you really don't want to overlook Is that it is a little bit of padding which is good for your wrists?
Speaker 1: Thing is you really don't want the mouse pad that has that giant knob on the end and you rest your wrist on that.
Speaker 0: They're ergonomic.
Speaker 0: studying people who are just gonna argue about that forever and ever get whatever feels good.
Speaker 0: If you feel comfortable you are comfortable, that's what it comes down to.
Speaker 1: yeah My only point is that if you're not using a mouse pad just because you have an optical mouse Looking to get in a mouse pad.
Speaker 1: There are a couple bucks.
Speaker 0: Hey It's all right.
Speaker 0: It's not 100% necessary.
Speaker 0: you get better things to worry about.
Speaker 1: It's a couple bucks.
Speaker 1: I think it's not something you really have to worry about worrying about.
Speaker 0: You know whatever.
Speaker 0: so The non hardware bits ice.
Speaker 1: you can skip monitors and all that.
Speaker 0: Oh clean your monitor if it gets dusty All right.
Speaker 1: Now this isn't a problem on most new CRTs, but if you have an old CRT Don't use alcohol or ammonia on it when it's on.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you'd use ammonia or alcohol in any monitor.
Speaker 1: Well, actually I use alcohol to clean mine.
Speaker 1: Yeah The thing is some older CRTs.
Speaker 1: if you use something harsh like 90% alcohol on the front of it and it's on It'll crack not the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Just the shield on the end and ruin your monitor.
Speaker 1: so if you're ever gonna clean your monitor with a chemical turn it off first, I Always cleaned my CRT with just glass plus.
Speaker 0: the same way clean the TV.
Speaker 1: I you know, it's in glass plus got ammonia Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was just water and blue.
Speaker 1: No, it's water and ammonia and then blue food coloring because it's trying to rip off Windex.
Speaker 0: Wow, the Windex is trying to rip off glass plus.
Speaker 1: now index came first.
Speaker 0: Are you sure?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure about a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 0: Well, whatever it doesn't matter which one came first.
Speaker 1: So like I said before Scott screwed up.
Speaker 1: Yeah ammonia All right.
Speaker 1: Ammonia is a good thing.
Speaker 1: Alcohol is a good thing.
Speaker 1: Just make sure it's off and Don't use a paper towel.
Speaker 0: It could be a nice one.
Speaker 0: those nice soft paper towels Yeah, but generally don't get that.
Speaker 0: don't get the chafee store brand one.
Speaker 1: Well, even generally if you're ever cleaning glass You don't want to use paper towel because paper towel is basically high-grade sandpaper.
Speaker 0: So rim doesn't have LCD so he doesn't know what to do with them.
Speaker 1: But well, I know what to do with them because I have my work.
Speaker 1: I just don't have one right here in front of me.
Speaker 0: No, anyway LCDs, they're not made of glass.
Speaker 0: They have all this glass in the inside somewhere, but you don't worry about that There's.
Speaker 0: it's a piece of plastic in the front and it scratches really freakin easily and it's pretty much irreparable if you damage it in any way and It's gonna be real visible like you're gonna see this hideous mark whenever you turn your monitor on it'll it'll bother you.
Speaker 1: So just follow whatever instructions came with your LCD.
Speaker 0: You got to be real careful.
Speaker 0: You're gonna need to get like these.
Speaker 0: Well, you know most LCDs come with instructions and usually a little pad, yeah, sometimes they come with instructions But I've never seen them come with a cleaning pad ever.
Speaker 1: Ah, the ones we got at work came with them.
Speaker 1: Those Dells come with them.
Speaker 0: Dells might yeah, but if you go to Staples, they have these microfiber cloths and those are pretty much you can just use it like.
Speaker 0: I thought you can get one and use it forever to just clean the dust off the monitor.
Speaker 0: and Maybe once a year once every few months you'll get they have this little kit.
Speaker 0: That's like a wet wipey A dry wipey and then of course another microfiber cloth.
Speaker 0: so what you do is you do the wet one and then a dry one and then you wipe the dust off and That like cleans off any sort of.
Speaker 0: if you get like maybe like a wet sticky thing on your monitor or something like that That's how you get it off.
Speaker 1: Just basically don't ever like.
Speaker 1: if there's grease don't just wipe it off with your shirt ever or paper towel ever or like a washcloth.
Speaker 1: You'll ruin it.
Speaker 0: They really should start making LCD screens that are more resistant.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they don't.
Speaker 1: it's kind of A lot of you a lot of CRTs even newer ones are real easy to damage too because you might think it's glass.
Speaker 1: But usually there's a coating on top of the glass mmm, some sort of reflecto thing or an anti-glare thing and Like it's the same with eyeglasses.
Speaker 1: eyeglasses are real durable until you get anti-fog or anti-glare coatings on them Then they're real fragile.
Speaker 0: Mmm, someone should do something about this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's really no way.
Speaker 1: like my glasses.
Speaker 1: when I got them I had a choice.
Speaker 1: I could either get really durable or Absolutely, no glare at all.
Speaker 1: I chose no glare at all.
Speaker 1: So I don't see a reflection of my eyeball in front of me all the time Mmm, but if I so much as like Nick my glasses, they'll just they're good.
Speaker 1: They're done.
Speaker 0: Wow, you won't just see like a nick of eyeball.
Speaker 0: You'll see like a full eyeball.
Speaker 0: I don't know what.
Speaker 0: I don't know What was that?
Speaker 0: I mean if you only scratch like say the corner of it, then I'll see a scratch.
Speaker 0: well, yeah, but you won't see like your anti-glareness won't be.
Speaker 1: No, no, what did?
Speaker 1: the point is that the anti-glare is a really really really fragile coat and it scratches really easily and the scratches Are very visible.
Speaker 1: So if I scratch my glasses, there's now a giant scratch in my vision forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I didn't get that then I'd have glare instead.
Speaker 1: It was a trade-off.
Speaker 0: It's good not to wear glasses All right.
Speaker 0: Is that all the hardware bits that need maintaining?
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Oh Your wires in the back of your computer keep them neat.
Speaker 1: Actually, you don't really need to bother as long as you can get to all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, it's like if you keep adding things or taking things away, you'll just have a mess.
Speaker 1: I've noticed most people don't plug much into their computer nowadays.
Speaker 1: anything you plug in you plug into the front.
Speaker 1: Yes, little USB.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the best way to do.
Speaker 0: it is you have a really new computer.
Speaker 0: A lot of people just have like, you know A power cable an ethernet cable and a monitor cable and everything else is USBs in the front.
Speaker 0: That's the really good way.
Speaker 1: cable Microphone cable.
Speaker 0: Well, if you have a microphone gotta have a microphone.
Speaker 0: See I realize at work I don't really have so much like.
Speaker 0: I Use like six USB holes and like only like two things go in the power strip But at home I use like eight holes on the power strip.
Speaker 0: It's crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right, so maintaining the software.
Speaker 1: If you're a Mac user other than the file Organize a bit you really don't need to listen to this.
Speaker 1: your Mac just works.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, there are some things you need to maintain like Don't let you know gonna make your serious.
Speaker 0: software is up to date all the time, you know But Mac has a lot of update thing.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: yeah, hence.
Speaker 1: You don't need to worry about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you do have to click on it, you know to update whenever they say you should Windows.
Speaker 1: honestly, just let it auto update.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there might be some Windows updates that are disagreeable But if you don't get them, you'll be sorry later anyway, because while they're disagreeable, there's no alternative.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's not like you can say oh I just won't install that one ever because then you you're open to a vulnerability forever.
Speaker 0: and with Linux depending on your distribution There's some sort of update system in Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: It just kind of says hey update me but in like gen 2 you have to do it manually and I mean just basically just keep Up-to-date maybe once a month.
Speaker 1: just get all your packages get all whatever you need to have updated using whatever automatic thing you have And do it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So especially on Windows there will be software where you don't have an automatic update system And where the software doesn't have its own Automatic update systems you.
Speaker 0: what you want to do is you want to check, you know the website for that software every?
Speaker 0: Month or two to see if there's a new version.
Speaker 1: I mean if that unless it's a some sort of web thing, you don't need to worry unless you need a new feature There's really no reason to upgrade.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a known bug Or it's something that could give you a vulnerability depends on how often you use it.
Speaker 0: I mean if it's something you never ever use and you just have it and you use it like once a year and it does What you need it to do don't even you know bother?
Speaker 1: Well, not even not so much how much you use it.
Speaker 1: It's just if you need it.
Speaker 1: if you need an update I mean I use cool at it 2000 and there were actually a lot of updates for it.
Speaker 1: I never updated it once in the like five years.
Speaker 1: I used it because it worked perfectly.
Speaker 1: I had no reason to update it and none of those updates fixed a vulnerability.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but their updates might add features.
Speaker 0: then you might not realize you don't want them and that you want them until you have them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I need a feature then I go and get it.
Speaker 1: I don't need it.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I mean if I what you went by that logic, you should be using like Firefox 1/2, you know It has all this features that you use.
Speaker 1: you don't use any of the other now because the early Firefox's don't have the primary Feature which is don't crash.
Speaker 0: they didn't crash for me.
Speaker 1: The early Firefox's really didn't like my computer.
Speaker 0: I had some issues with them and it's an issue with your computer.
Speaker 1: But anyway, my computer is an old piece of crap.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 1: Firefox works fine now after the 1.0 days it sure does.
Speaker 0: But you know, I tend to just unless there's like, you know something removed in the newer version.
Speaker 0: like a lot of times What will happen is like you'll get iTunes and then the next version of iTunes will have something worse like a DRM or something.
Speaker 0: then you want to hold back.
Speaker 1: That always doesn't work anymore though, you know because most things just won't accept old versions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like PSP and stuff where you know, you put in a new game and it upgrades your firmware.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we don't really need to talk about this.
Speaker 1: just keep up-to-date.
Speaker 0: Update your software.
Speaker 1: All I keep up-to-date organize your files.
Speaker 1: That's really it.
Speaker 0: Well, you also want to What like if you have Windows you got to keep your registry clean.
Speaker 1: No, you don't.
Speaker 1: that's taken care of.
Speaker 1: now If you use like XP, it keeps it pretty clean.
Speaker 0: No The only things.
Speaker 0: a lot of times if programs if the programs that you install and uninstall Aren't written properly or the uninstallers aren't written properly your registry can become full of crap real quick.
Speaker 1: See the problem with saying that is there's no easy way to clean out the registry.
Speaker 1: So that's really an advanced thing.
Speaker 0: Well, there are.
Speaker 0: there are some registry program.
Speaker 1: every registry cleaner I've ever seen is not worth using.
Speaker 1: they're very dangerous.
Speaker 1: They usually remove keys you need now.
Speaker 0: There is one that is actually made by Microsoft that I use.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait the one that you can get from Windows update No, the one that you can get from the Microsoft website and like a Microsoft developer website, uh-huh I think it's a power tool or something.
Speaker 1: Honestly Scott may disagree.
Speaker 1: I say just ignore your registry.
Speaker 1: if you don't know what your registry does just ignore it.
Speaker 0: You don't even have to go into the register to use it.
Speaker 0: It's just a thing.
Speaker 0: you click on and you say clean my registry and it goes clean.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I say it doesn't even matter because it really won't affect your performance.
Speaker 0: Oh, no See that's the actually not true because the perform and the registry when Windows computers are going slow.
Speaker 0: If you actually like monitor or debug Windows computers to see what they're doing They do hard drive hits to the registry like like every freaking second.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: That's really only an issue if you've been spy word.
Speaker 1: No, it really just you know Unless you've been spy word or you install and uninstall applications on it on an obscene basis You're not gonna have this problem.
Speaker 0: You will have this problem.
Speaker 0: In fact on brand new Windows systems just fresh installed the registry is hit constantly.
Speaker 0: That's the way windows Hit.
Speaker 1: I'm saying you won't have a problem beyond what Windows already has unless you install or uninstall programs Obscenely or you have spyware that made your register huge.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is the registry doesn't just grow.
Speaker 0: unless it does actually just grow.
Speaker 0: watch go.
Speaker 1: No, if you take a Windows computer and boot it and just leave it running the registry is not going to grow magically on its Own.
Speaker 0: it won't grow magically on its own, but we're assuming you're actually using the computer.
Speaker 1: All right, if you're just using it, you don't install anything.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna grow much.
Speaker 0: It actually grows.
Speaker 0: just browsing the web and you know doing things in your control panel The registry gets bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger doesn't get that much bigger.
Speaker 0: unless you go look at it You'll be very surprised.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've looked at it often because I do a lot of wine work with wine in at work.
Speaker 1: yeah wine work it with wine at work and I do.
Speaker 1: I look at my registry on a regular basis because the main thing I do is I get a Windows program to work In wine, but and then I have to go through look at all the register keys and everything and import them into wine and Linux.
Speaker 1: And I see my registry on a regular basis.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: it's been the same size for like six months.
Speaker 0: Oh in wine, it's very different.
Speaker 0: because no no in Windows when I look at it I know the registry on my laptop for work is constantly crazy.
Speaker 1: What do you mean constantly crazy?
Speaker 1: Is it growing?
Speaker 1: How big is it?
Speaker 0: It's pretty scarily big and I ran it because you don't realize it's like 60 or 70 megabytes is not scarily big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know but that's that's about the size.
Speaker 0: Usually this is like hundreds of megabytes.
Speaker 1: It's huge Alright, then you must have installed or uninstalled things or have a profile with a lot of weird things set because the registry doesn't just Do that on its own it does just do that on its own.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't it does.
Speaker 0: I read many things about it back in the day.
Speaker 0: Alright fine.
Speaker 1: I think you're wrong and kind of paranoid about this.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you should still just make sure the registry doesn't get out of control.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what Scott.
Speaker 1: I say ignore your registry if you don't know what it is because you're not really gonna be able to do anything with it.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't have to actually go and mess with it You know, if you don't know you just keep an eye on it.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, if you don't know, how can you keep an eye on it?
Speaker 0: You just look at the size of it Okay, and you see it get bigger.
Speaker 1: What do you do?
Speaker 0: If you don't know anything about it, you run the little handy-dandy cleaning program and you see if it gets any smaller Okay, and say it doesn't.
Speaker 0: well then it is probably nothing bad in it that you know It's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 1: the correct size though is usually if there's something bad in the register.
Speaker 1: It's spyware.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the spyware is the number one thing that gets in there.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much the only thing nowadays unless you install crap old programs.
Speaker 0: Oh crap old bro, that's the other thing you never.
Speaker 0: if you if you can avoid it don't use crap old programs.
Speaker 0: Look for something that's new and does things properly.
Speaker 1: and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 0: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash geek nights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Speaker 0: Also, please visit our website at Www.front row crew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast.
Speaker 0: We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.