Speaker 1: It's Wednesday January 18th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight It's my birthday, and we talk about wings of reen and we have some final thoughts on big O2.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: so it's my birthday even though I Completely forgot and the only reason I realized it was my birthday is because people kept telling me all day.
Speaker 0: I also completely forgot and We just seem to not care about birthdays anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well.
Speaker 1: I don't even know when your birthday is.
Speaker 1: I only know it's a few months after mine April 30th.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: whenever I forget how old I am I just ask you and then I know that I'm at most a year older.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: when you're a little kid you're gonna get a bunch of presents, and you don't have money So you don't usually get stuff so often.
Speaker 0: so you're like oh my god.
Speaker 0: My birthday's in like 10 days.
Speaker 0: Oh my god It's in 9 days.
Speaker 0: You know, but once you're at this age.
Speaker 0: You're just like oh Birthday.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 1: well, I also realize anything because a bunch of people asked me so rim What do you want for your birthday, and I couldn't honestly think of anything.
Speaker 0: you buy me a computer.
Speaker 0: How about a car?
Speaker 0: I could use.
Speaker 1: those things I mean I really want for nothing.
Speaker 1: the only kinds of things I want are things that I wouldn't expect someone to just buy me.
Speaker 1: so I guess the only gifts I like are just like creative or nice gifts or things I wouldn't think of getting that aren't particularly useful that are just cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, seriously if you're gonna give me a present It's like it's got to be something nowadays.
Speaker 0: It's got to be something I can't buy because if I can buy it What do I need you to buy it for me?
Speaker 1: well for me?
Speaker 1: I just have a big heart a very difficult time buying gifts for other people.
Speaker 1: when I like if I feel obligated to Like I'll see a thing.
Speaker 1: I'll give people gifts just randomly when I decide that it's a good gift-giving time.
Speaker 1: But I know I almost never give gifts around Christmas or any other holiday Mmm.
Speaker 0: I just had not to give things because I don't expect things, but if I have a reason to give someone something It's either something like generic like flowers.
Speaker 0: They're nice You know it's in the end.
Speaker 0: They'll.
Speaker 0: you know they'll go away, and that'll be that.
Speaker 0: or You know you make something for someone like.
Speaker 0: that's what you can do.
Speaker 0: That's awesome is you can always make something for someone especially if you have art and/or craft skills because That's not something that anyone could just buy in the store.
Speaker 0: So it's like ah if someone goes and buys something for me.
Speaker 0: It's like oh great if someone makes something.
Speaker 0: It's like oh Especially if it's an awesome thing if you make a crap thing.
Speaker 0: I guess you know whatever.
Speaker 0: I'll just feel bad.
Speaker 1: So in the news today PC game sales I remember way back.
Speaker 1: We had a discussion about whether or not PC gaming was dead.
Speaker 1: Ten million dollars less worth of PC games were sold this year as opposed to last year.
Speaker 0: We're ten million dollars more Xbox game sold.
Speaker 1: I don't know, but I have the list here on game Sutra of what the top ten games in 2005 were.
Speaker 0: and PC games right.
Speaker 1: yeah PC games only all right.
Speaker 1: and the one interesting thing is that Basically one two three four of the top ten are the sims 2 or sims 2 related items Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you add up all the sims 2 that is on this list the sims 2 is far and away the number one PC game in the world for another year.
Speaker 0: now Please repeat to me the minimum system requirements in fact repeat to me the recommended system requirements for playing the sims 2.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: I think it's suffice to say that the sims 2 runs on a computer.
Speaker 0: That's slower than mine And you know what?
Speaker 0: That makes it pretty much Dumb to have a more powerful computer.
Speaker 1: now the list number one.
Speaker 1: if you break them up I'll just read the list.
Speaker 1: number one is World of Warcraft duh.
Speaker 1: Number two is the sims 2 some expansion.
Speaker 1: the number three game is sims 2 which I think came out in 2004 didn't it?
Speaker 0: I don't know when it came out, but definitely not recently.
Speaker 1: Guild Wars is number four.
Speaker 0: Oh really that the game we had like that was the one with no monthly fee, right?
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: there are a few real games on the list in addition to these fluff games.
Speaker 0: Yeah It was.
Speaker 0: that was the MMO that was supposed to have no monthly fee because you would pay 50 bucks and get it in the Store and that would be that.
Speaker 0: and it was supposed to be different like no evil grinding and whatever.
Speaker 0: But it turned out to just be crap like every other MMO.
Speaker 1: Yep Number five is roller coaster tycoon 3, you know?
Speaker 0: You look at those games and you say oh There's just another one of those generic tycoon games because it's probably the most evolved form of that type of game right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah I actually played the original original roller coaster tycoon before any of the other Tycoons existed and it was actually kind of fun for a while.
Speaker 0: It's like it's.
Speaker 0: it's like Sim City 2000 only with a different theme on it Yeah, and you get to design the little roller coasters, which can be fun.
Speaker 1: Number six was battlefield 2 which I here is actually a pretty good game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard it was All right, number seven The Sims 2 another expansion.
Speaker 0: number eight Age of Empires 3 All right, and ever actually played those.
Speaker 1: Yeah I've heard that they're kind of a lot of people try to compare them to civilization games And they're just a completely different kind of game.
Speaker 1: Really.
Speaker 1: Hmm I've never known anyone who actually liked them or at least if they have they never said anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I never actually played one so I can't say Number nine is another Sims thing and number ten is Call of Duty 2 One of those generic World War games.
Speaker 0: Yeah So what it all comes down to is that as I said and people may or may not have believed me PC gaming in terms of gamers gaming on PCs with FPS's and I mean, it's not dead.
Speaker 1: Yes, there are people who play PC games and PC games are big business still but there's no market for PC games that require fast computers.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I Mean, no, I hate to say it but notice how Half-Life 2 and its derivatives aren't even on that list.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Well, I have like two came out last year, but the Sims came out two years, right?
Speaker 0: So, come on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Doom 3 doesn't appear Quake 4 doesn't appear.
Speaker 1: Well, I can see why Doom 3 doesn't appear.
Speaker 1: that game was pretty piss poor.
Speaker 0: Well, Quake 4 was also sort of generic, but those other games that people were hyping up the the fear game didn't appear That even that one what was it called the Indigo prophecy?
Speaker 0: that didn't appear.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah people talk that one up big time.
Speaker 0: Where is it?
Speaker 0: No one bought it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean part of it's that.
Speaker 1: I mean because I saw another report.
Speaker 1: We don't get into the news on this but PC sales are down significantly, too Because honestly other than hardcore gamers and people like us Very few people need new computers anymore and they've realized this and they stopped buying them.
Speaker 0: it's starting to get to the point where the only people buying new computers are dumb people who Have it spy wear it up and they don't know better.
Speaker 0: Yeah And people who are so poor that they couldn't afford one before and now they're getting so cheap They can finally get one or gamers who really know what they need and get it.
Speaker 0: But that's not too much because there aren't PC games coming out and selling big that they need to upgrade for.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so which is also bringing hardware costs down to where fast PCs are getting cheaper daily.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm gonna build a new PC probably this weekend partly because I was looking around online and I was just thinking all right.
Speaker 1: I want to build a three or four hundred dollar computer because that's all I need.
Speaker 1: I don't play the new game so much and that'll play those new games.
Speaker 1: Just fine anyway, and I wanted a little micro ATX motherboard, but I saw that they all kind of suck compared to large full-size motherboards.
Speaker 1: and Then I stumbled upon a motherboard that I looked awesome.
Speaker 1: It was perfect in every way and it was really cheap.
Speaker 1: and I thought it was a normal motherboard ATX.
Speaker 1: and I'm deciding alright I'm gonna buy this motherboard because it does everything I need.
Speaker 1: then I look and I find out that not only is it Micro ATX which I didn't notice yet It still has four dims and two s ATAs and two ID or s ATAs.
Speaker 1: for s ATAs Yep, it has everything.
Speaker 1: it does everything I would possibly need.
Speaker 1: it's micro ATX.
Speaker 1: it has raid 5 built into it.
Speaker 0: on the s ATA there's a raid 5 and The North Bridge has a geforce 6100 built into it with a DVI and a VGA connector on the motherboard and you can use them both simultaneously.
Speaker 1: It's dual head.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and not only that that video card supports DirectX 9.
Speaker 1: It's Basically a top-of-the-line video card.
Speaker 0: So the only thing really wrong with this motherboard is that you need extra RAM because the video card doesn't have its own RAM.
Speaker 0: So you need to give it normal RAM.
Speaker 1: However, it takes standard DDR and Jeep.
Speaker 1: Yep, DDR PC 3200.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I have in my computer and that RAM is fairly dirt-cheap.
Speaker 1: I'm probably gonna get a couple gigs of RAM at least.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would recommend two gigs because the video card doesn't have any.
Speaker 1: Yeah well also because I do you know the podcast and RAM directly Translates to the podcast sounding better because I can do more to it Yep, and you just throw a nice powerful 64-bit AMD processor in there and You're good to go.
Speaker 0: the sound card.
Speaker 0: that's on the motherboards a little crappy, but that can be replaced.
Speaker 1: It's socket what?
Speaker 1: 939?
Speaker 1: so it takes the Athlon FX 64. the Athlon 6 can't afford the FX No and it also takes the sempron.
Speaker 1: so I could put a sempron in there now and then a year from now when an FX is Cheap just buy them top the fastest FX there is and stick it in.
Speaker 0: I would just get a normal AMD 64.
Speaker 1: actually I'm probably gonna go with 64 since I'm gonna do Linux and if I install Windows on it I'll get that 64-bit version of Windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the.
Speaker 0: that's the sure bet to make sure everything's all good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though if I'm cheap I could just throw at the top of the line sempron in there.
Speaker 0: The thing is I've heard some with the semprons.
Speaker 0: There's some weird things where some of them are some way and some of them are another way and it gets weird.
Speaker 0: You need to be real careful buying those.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually suck is there's different with semprons.
Speaker 0: 64 is the normal semprons or something else, but you can't put that in there.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what I'll probably over the next couple weeks be building my computer.
Speaker 1: So I'll have regular updates to all of you who may also be in the market for computers as to exactly what I'm getting And why?
Speaker 0: The one thing though is right now you have a full tower case.
Speaker 0: You're gonna be switching to those little tiny cases like the one that my parents have.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's gonna be so fantastic it's gonna be so tiny and You're not gonna be able to put a bunch of stuff in there.
Speaker 0: It only has room for one hard drive and one.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on what kind of case I get.
Speaker 0: yeah, but you know other cases can hold micro ATX boards But really you can get a normal ATX board.
Speaker 0: that probably is the same exact thing With a good better sound card in it.
Speaker 1: Well, actually I was looking and I saw a two micro ATX cases that they both have space for four hard drives within them Really and they have.
Speaker 1: I'll dig up the link another time, but I saw it at work.
Speaker 0: Okay, because usually I figured the there.
Speaker 1: well, they're a little bigger than the ones we typically see but there's still micro ATX.
Speaker 1: They're still tiny and they have the USB and the firewire and the fronds and that it has one External five and a quarter bay which is all I need because a DVD burner is gonna go there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it And it looks perfect.
Speaker 1: It's a kind of expensive, but it's got the mad quiet cooling Which is what I want more than anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the big giant fans.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, plus my micro ATX is a lot easier to cool and clean just because it's really little and the airflow is usually really simple Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just that all the micro ATX cases I've seen that look really nice are usually really small and cramped and don't have a lot of room to put drives.
Speaker 0: but that's kind of.
Speaker 0: the point is that you get you're only getting a small motherboard because you want this small tiny cute case and You know that you're not gonna put a lot of stuff in it because you want a tiny cute case.
Speaker 0: But if you found one that fits that's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yep, of course I'm still doing my research because the last time I bought a computer I did three months of research before I finally bought one.
Speaker 1: hmm, but of course now I know a lot more about computers because the last time I did this was in the year 2000 and I don't think it'll take me three months this time.
Speaker 1: I don't think so either but it's gonna be a big weekend if I get a computer and Scott gets a car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe I will get the car this weekend or next week.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: I'll have to call those people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I was at work and there's a race car guy in my office.
Speaker 1: He races cars He knows a lot about cars and I mentioned Hey, the Mazda 3 is really the only good car in that class.
Speaker 1: and he said yeah The Mazda 3 is by far the best car in that price range you can ever buy.
Speaker 0: great I just need more reasons to go and get this I know he said.
Speaker 1: and then someone.
Speaker 1: he said like the six is just as good if you want us it in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I drove the six.
Speaker 0: It was a drove like my dad's car.
Speaker 0: So I don't want it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was very sedan e.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm sedan e.
Speaker 1: So we got some more news, right?
Speaker 0: All right, so everyone it might have noticed today There's a big hubbub about this Firefox pinging privacy You know hole in the new version or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah I didn't read much about it because I saw the alarmism and I decided I was just gonna wait and wait for someone who knows better To just tell me about it.
Speaker 0: Well, here's exactly what's going on here.
Speaker 0: There are people who have websites and they want to track when people click on links.
Speaker 0: so what I would they do right now is I would put a link on my website and I would set that link up in such a way with JavaScript or with a redirect or both so that when you click on it, it Actually takes you to a page besides the one that it links says it links to.
Speaker 0: so let's say I had a website and I had a link on my website that said old archives and I wanted to know how Many people were clicking on the archives, right?
Speaker 0: I would set it up so that when you clicked on archives It took you somewhere else and then to the archives or loaded another page and then loaded the archives and that other page.
Speaker 0: There's a whole bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: So I know who you are and I can see.
Speaker 0: oh look how many people visited this page.
Speaker 0: People with it is I can see.
Speaker 0: aha.
Speaker 0: So I know that everyone who visited that page clicked on a link on my site that goes to the archives.
Speaker 1: now That might sound kind of hackish to you and it is kind of hackish and it's prone to problems.
Speaker 1: You can install your server down.
Speaker 1: the redirects might not work.
Speaker 1: people disable things like JavaScript.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that's not really the best thing especially because it low it slows down page loading times because now you have to load this other page and then load the page you actually want to go to.
Speaker 0: so they've added in Firefox when you to a link you can put a ping.
Speaker 0: What this does is when you visit whenever anyone clicks on that link Firefox will send a ping to the URL in the ping Attribute.
Speaker 0: so it takes this whole entire page out of the critical path.
Speaker 0: So you don't actually have to load another page You just go where you're going like nothing happened.
Speaker 0: And then this ping takes place with XML RPC or something that you don't even know or care about So that people running websites can still track people, you know clicking on links without you know making web browsing a shitter experience.
Speaker 1: now a lot of people are saying that this might be a privacy violation or it's just another way to track people and It's really not that big a deal.
Speaker 0: I mean people can do this already.
Speaker 0: So you're not really, you know, you're making a little bit easier for them to do it Because now they don't have to hack together something with you know redirect or whatever.
Speaker 0: But there's a hole in IE that can't be closed.
Speaker 0: that lets people do this.
Speaker 0: You know It just works and people do it all the time and there's not much you can do about people Tracking you visiting, you know, if you access someone's web server They're going to log it and they can get information out of you that is sent to them by your browser.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean browser isn't sending any more information now than it's sending already.
Speaker 1: We know a lot about the people looking at geek nights.
Speaker 1: We can see a lot of times what kind of web browsers people use in.
Speaker 1: I can look at the feed and see exactly what?
Speaker 1: RSS readers you're using out there.
Speaker 1: If I wanted I could track you down specifically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is is you can feel free to disable all those things and there's actually ways to do that.
Speaker 0: you can disable Referrals and you can disable Your user agent strings and you can change all these things so that people can't track you.
Speaker 0: when you visit websites You can go through proxies and hide your IP address.
Speaker 0: You can hide everything if you go through the effort.
Speaker 0: but There's a point at which with disabling things Makes the web a shittier experience for you.
Speaker 0: So and actually giving away that information doesn't really harm harm you.
Speaker 0: I mean someone detecting that using Firefox isn't really an invasion of privacy.
Speaker 1: In fact, it might be.
Speaker 1: you could consider it a good thing because then they might be more inclined to care if Firefox works on Their site properly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this is just one.
Speaker 0: It's just a way to make something easier.
Speaker 0: that is currently kind of making the web shittier.
Speaker 1: now, of course I mean this is new and obviously we're gonna see how people use and abuse it in the coming months.
Speaker 1: So just stay tuned and I don't think anything big is going to come of it.
Speaker 0: The one thing I think is that actually it won't solve the problem.
Speaker 0: It's trying to solve because people will use it in places instead of their redirects and things.
Speaker 0: But only people with Firefox are currently supporting this change So they're still going to use the shitty redirects for to track the IE people and others.
Speaker 0: So until IE7 comes out or whatever.
Speaker 0: This isn't going to solve the problem They're trying to solve but at the same time Webmasters who are savvy.
Speaker 1: this will make it a lot easier for them to notice how many Firefox users they actually have Because it's possible that there are a lot more Firefox users out there than the statistics say.
Speaker 0: I also see people making cool things happen by having using the pinging feature Somehow incorporating web services and links and things so that could be a bonus.
Speaker 0: someone will do something with that.
Speaker 0: I'm not the biggest Toy freak, you know.
Speaker 0: there are those people who will buy every single toy and they'll go to Toys R Us to get Toys R Us exclusive toys and Walmart to get Walmart exclusive toys and whatnot and they won't open the packages.
Speaker 0: They'll just like hang them on their wall and they'll organize like their entire rooms With toys along the walls and poses and organized by what series they're from and what you know universe They're from and whatnot.
Speaker 1: See to me those people have issues.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just crazy collectors But I do like the occasional toy especially when it's extra cool or has some special meaning or something especially if it's fun to play with.
Speaker 0: if it's fun to play with that's like the hugest bonus the toy can have.
Speaker 0: so Today I saw a toy series that combines two really awesome things Star Wars and transformers.
Speaker 0: Yeah So they've got the first toy.
Speaker 0: There are four toys.
Speaker 0: I've only seen three of them.
Speaker 0: The first one is You know those little Jedi fighters from episodes one, two, three.
Speaker 0: They're kind of pointy in the little time millennium Falcons.
Speaker 0: There's one of those that transforms into obi-wan.
Speaker 1: This one's kind of stupid.
Speaker 1: It doesn't transform into obi-wan it transforms into some fat Jedi guy with a lightsaber.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: There's one That is general Grievous Which is a really good toy to begin with and then it transforms to that big circle thing.
Speaker 0: remember in Episode two and Grievous was in that circle thing and he rolled around a bit.
Speaker 0: So that's that's an okay toy.
Speaker 0: It's actually supposedly the highest quality toy in the series.
Speaker 0: The one the third toy which I saw is the one which said, okay I have to buy this even though it looks like a piece of crap, but I don't care It's a Thai fighter advanced that transforms into Darth Vader.
Speaker 0: Wow, the lightsaber becomes little red lasers that the Thai fighter shoots.
Speaker 1: It's pretty badass looking.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of impressed with this toy.
Speaker 0: No, it looks like a piece of shit as far as toys go but not when it's in the time and state.
Speaker 1: It looks really cool.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but I mean in terms like the quality of the toy.
Speaker 0: It's just some crap toy But it's so cool in what it is that it's a Thai fighter that turns to Darth Vader.
Speaker 1: now They don't say what the fourth toy is though?
Speaker 0: That's because they didn't.
Speaker 0: the people who reported this went to Target and just saw the toys and they didn't see a fourth toy.
Speaker 0: Oh, but I know there was one.
Speaker 1: I'll bet it's a Yoda that turns into a yo-yo That would be cool.
Speaker 0: or a Superball or a Luke that turns into an x-wing something.
Speaker 1: a Luke that turns into his father.
Speaker 0: It'd be nice.
Speaker 0: It was like an emperor an emperor that turned into like an electricity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't think of it what it could be but just make him turn into a frickin Death Star, dude That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: I'll go for that.
Speaker 1: so, uh, I have the 1990 Nintendo World catalog and We remembered by when looking at this that back in the 90s Nintendo released more merchandise in this country than you would ever believe.
Speaker 0: I want it this.
Speaker 1: this catalog shows entire rooms furnished in nothing but Nintendo brand merchandise.
Speaker 1: We're talking Nintendo like bean bags Nintendo bedsheets Nintendo husbands things you sit on not husbands.
Speaker 1: Nintendo furniture Nintendo clothing Nintendo clothing that if you wore today, you'd be the coolest kid ever.
Speaker 0: Of course, no one still has this clothing.
Speaker 1: I might have some of it.
Speaker 1: I mean I remember I had because two of the things were these odd knit hats and I remember having a Legend of Zelda and a Mario.
Speaker 0: The closest ever got to owning any of this stuff other than of course the games and such was a Nintendo Mario alarm clock.
Speaker 0: You know the old style with a little hammer that bang book back and forth between two bells.
Speaker 1: I had a Care Bears, uh alarm clock just like that.
Speaker 0: My mom ordered it from the JC penny catalog.
Speaker 0: We went to the JC penny desk to pick it up and it was broken.
Speaker 0: So she gave it back and then we went.
Speaker 0: we got another one for the same place.
Speaker 0: It was also broken.
Speaker 0: So I never got that clock and I got a normal clock instead.
Speaker 1: Ah Actually scary how many things in that catalog I remember owning.
Speaker 0: It's scary that in the catalog I want almost everything that's in there and they no longer sell it.
Speaker 0: There was so little Nintendo merchandise official merchandise available in this country today Compared to there was before and compared to Japan today in Japan.
Speaker 0: You can get all this stuff and more But you can't get you know Anything in this country.
Speaker 0: you can get a few t-shirts a few pins and that's about it.
Speaker 0: You can't get Mario shoes anymore Can't get Mario hats so easily anymore kind Mario racing suits Mario footies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know a Nintendo brand TV stand Beat that.
Speaker 1: So anyway today is anime day and we've got some final thoughts on Big O - since we've seen it all.
Speaker 1: But first we watched episode 1 of wings of Reen And we did.
Speaker 1: we got some things to say about it.
Speaker 0: Well, we didn't know anything about the show and we started watching it other than the name.
Speaker 1: now it starts out really cool.
Speaker 1: it shows like Japan modern Japan normal mundane Japan and there are all these kids and it looks like they're engaged in some sort of like governmental military coup against the American Not occupiers, but the American Defense Forces in Japan And it looks like it's gonna be some sort of political cool thing.
Speaker 0: It seems like they want to You know have a real Japanese military and like they don't want to be drafted.
Speaker 1: I couldn't even tell but they were rebelling and they were cool kids and seriously rebelling like they got a hold of an RPG and Actually fired it at some US troops that were chasing them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were driving this Humvee around and they shot the rocket.
Speaker 1: now all that all this is going on.
Speaker 1: there's one moment where like a little we like feather appears and goes whoosh on the screen and It went by in a second and up until this point there had been no magic in the show and the feather disappeared right away And we weren't sure what it was.
Speaker 1: Not a few minutes later giant giant magical battleships fly up from under the ocean and they're from a mystical land far away and then there's a girl who has wings that come out of her feet and the show gets fucked up and
Speaker 0: Then it's really really hard to understand what's going on.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: for a while I thought that the battle that was like one battleship and I thought it was just coming to fight the earth or it would just Got lost or something.
Speaker 0: But then I finally realized that there were actually two sets of battleships that appeared and they were fighting each other.
Speaker 0: and it the fact That it took me so long to realize that that it wasn't it.
Speaker 1: Oh They introduced a million characters right away and you have no idea who they are or what they're doing or what's going on.
Speaker 0: You don't even know their names and they don't develop them or tell you anything about them.
Speaker 0: It just you just see characters doing stuff and you see the same characters over and over again doing stuff but you don't know about them or why they're doing anything.
Speaker 1: and now too much credit.
Speaker 0: action.
Speaker 1: the main character is gets on one of these battleships, so they think he's the main character almost right away by accident and The first thing he does is find someone and ask them what the hell's going on.
Speaker 1: And he's very like what the hell?
Speaker 1: What is this?
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: But everyone ignores him for several minutes.
Speaker 1: We thought that in fact, they couldn't see him and that this was some sort of plot device.
Speaker 1: But no, they were just ignoring him and then they talked to him later and they still don't explain anything.
Speaker 0: That's terrific like.
Speaker 1: I don't know if the show is gonna go anywhere, but it introduced a Season's worth of plot in one episode as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell there was no plot and it Was just a bunch of action scenes evolved involving some battleships that appear from under the ocean Combined with US military equipment of modern times.
Speaker 0: and then that was it like
Speaker 1: they keep Introducing things like the battleships are here and they start to fight but then there's these dragon golem things on them and then they have these special engines that do something weird and It's just getting more and more out of control and then there's a big explosion and like a nuke and an engine falls out And it's crazy.
Speaker 1: and then a spoiler for the next five seconds and then at the end of the show like there's a big explosion and everyone's dying and then the main character is like, ah And then it was like.
Speaker 1: he says like it's all a dream and then the episode ends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't know if it was actually a dream or what?
Speaker 0: The thing was is I just realized.
Speaker 0: now I went to the anime news network encyclopedia and looked it up.
Speaker 0: This is actually spin-off from or a battler Dunbine, which is an anime I had heard of but never actually have seen.
Speaker 0: it doesn't sound that good I don't know.
Speaker 0: but the point is is that you remember in the show they were talking about like or Engines or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I think that's that it actually is a spin-off of some kind.
Speaker 0: I'm just right.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you have to read the manga to understand this or watch By this show makes no sense on its own whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so maybe if you watch enough episodes, you know what's going on?
Speaker 0: But I'm pretty sure you have to like read either manga or watch some other anime to understand what the hell this is.
Speaker 1: So moving on to better anime that we've actually seen all of big o2, which we've talked about twice before we're done with it.
Speaker 1: we've seen the end and There's actually a lot there.
Speaker 1: the show went in directions.
Speaker 1: I didn't expect at all.
Speaker 0: Well, I expected the direction it went.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but I didn't expect the magnitude of the direction it went in.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: it seemed about right to me.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess the warning I have for anyone who's thinking about watching the show is that it Literally and I know I mean literally in a literal sense pulls an Evangelion.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes very much.
Speaker 0: So the ending is a Very as many many parallels or the ending of the Evangelion TV as in.
Speaker 1: there's action going on And then the show kind of pans back and does the same thing of hey I use big robots to trick you into watching my show now.
Speaker 1: Here's the moral.
Speaker 1: Moral, yeah, and then fade out the end.
Speaker 0: See now the thing is is that I had seen this show maybe four or five years ago I probably would have had a much better opinion of it.
Speaker 0: It's just that I've seen so many shows that like The they you know, they put the moral as the ending instead of after the ending.
Speaker 0: You know and they just all of a sudden turn into this huge like blatantly meta in-your-face metaphorical type of thing That it just.
Speaker 0: it doesn't you know.
Speaker 0: do it for me as much as it used to especially when I it's pretty much like I Seen it all.
Speaker 0: so if you do the same thing again, it doesn't doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Well, at least the thing is.
Speaker 1: the moral is Pretty much present in every single episode of Big O - that is true.
Speaker 1: It just plays out over and over and over again.
Speaker 1: So if you watch the first six or seven episodes and you can't figure out where the show is going You might want to brush up on your plot.
Speaker 1: predicting skills
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you can't figure it out even after the first season of Big O which I guess I can somewhat understand if you don't know what's gonna happen after like The first two episodes of Big O - or just in the first one episode of Big O - you know every.
Speaker 0: you know That's it.
Speaker 1: Just you know, everything that is basically every episode of Big O - does.
Speaker 1: it plays out in a different way?
Speaker 1: It's always the same moral but it plays out sometimes in a funny way Sometimes in a serious way sometimes in a weird way sometimes in a super metaphorical way But every episode has the same kind of thread of who am I?
Speaker 1: Why do I exist?
Speaker 1: metaphysical extant kind of philosophy blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Now I actually really really am satisfied with how the show ended as opposed to Big O one Which I would have killed people if they hadn't continued it.
Speaker 0: I just view the whole thing as one show called Big O. Yeah, but they're just this.
Speaker 0: there's a separation where the second half starts like it Kinda like how I'd be about where this is the first half.
Speaker 0: and then You know, there's the Jupiter jazz, whatever and there's the second half.
Speaker 0: Yeah Only the thing is Callie bebop.
Speaker 0: a lot of the episodes had nothing to do with the overall plot But in Big O all of them did But at the same time at the same kind of separation that Calvary bebop had in the two halves.
Speaker 0: is that what Big O has?
Speaker 0: Yep
Speaker 1: Now if you if you saw Big O one you weren't impressed and you're just not even considering Big O - I Highly recommend just watch the first DVD of Big O - in the very least because the first episode of Big O - which we've mentioned a couple times before is really really well done and Interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think there's one problem with Big O is that it sort of Misrepresents itself in that a lot of people will watch like the first one and be like, oh, this is just Batman You know or it kind of is the first one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're like, oh, this is just steam detectives clone with Batman and It sorta is.
Speaker 0: but that's really just the setting and the.
Speaker 0: you know the the style and the items used in terms of Like the plot and act the characters and what happens.
Speaker 0: it's totally not any of those things.
Speaker 1: I mean the first 13 episodes are kind of just Flynn and they're not.
Speaker 1: there's not really that much to them except if You watch Big O - and then you think back to Big O. one It won there's a lot more meaning there and you see a lot more.
Speaker 1: and two You pull the whole anime logic thing because Utena had the same deal in Utena Which if any of you haven't seen it weird things happen like weird anime things like there's a magic arena where people fight duels and this castle in the sky like falls down on someone but they don't get killed and Most people watch the show and instead of thinking that was fucked up.
Speaker 1: Why did that happen?
Speaker 1: What the hell they think?
Speaker 1: Oh, that's just the way this anime is.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna worry about it.
Speaker 1: when then at the end of Utena They're like they explained like oh There was a reason why didn't I wonder why there's a frickin floating castle in the sky?
Speaker 1: There's actually a perfectly rational explanation for it.
Speaker 0: It's one of those things where they make you suspend disbelief by putting the show on as a fantasy or a sci-fi.
Speaker 0: but in reality, you shouldn't have suspended disbelief, you know, because It was actually real.
Speaker 1: or I mean the big O is a very unrealistic robot.
Speaker 1: It's big and it punches things in ways that you really can't do.
Speaker 1: So think about that.
Speaker 1: How could that actually be?
Speaker 1: Because it is in the show it happens and they explain it very directly in a very heavily handed way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are a lot of things in the show actually that go completely unexp-.
Speaker 0: You know It's.
Speaker 0: it's weird because they'll always look for a rational explanation for things and they'll always talk about things in a strange way.
Speaker 0: And you just you know, you think what the hell are they talking about?
Speaker 0: You know, what are the rules of the universe this show is in when the whole time?
Speaker 0: The show is in the same rules as our universe.
Speaker 0: They're just making you suspend disbelief You know and tricking you into doing it when you shouldn't.
Speaker 1: yeah big O one does it really well.
Speaker 1: But notice even in big O one I mean half the time there's robots fighting and a quarter of the time there's funny stuff.
Speaker 1: But a lot of the whole first season and much of the second season is just Roger talking to himself.
Speaker 1: Now a lot of people just kind of gloss over what he's saying because it's just you know, typical Metaphil- Metaphilosophy blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Oh, but if you really listen to the words he's saying that's what the whole show is about and There's actually a lot there.
Speaker 1: because I'm gonna go off on one of my philosophical things because I got a lot out of big O too And I'd I guess a spoiler warning.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do my best not to ruin the show.
Speaker 1: But if you really are worried about big O too being ruined for you, you could probably stop listening At this point because we're not doing any meta bits after we talk about big O too.
Speaker 1: but Basically consider the premise of big O too.
Speaker 1: The premise is that for and big O 40 years ago.
Speaker 1: Everyone lost their memories and no one knows what happened in the world before that time.
Speaker 1: There's no clue yet.
Speaker 1: everyone just got on long with their lives and lived and played whatever roles they decided to play in the new world and The people who lived the best were the ones who didn't worry about what happened before or what came before Because there was really no way to know.
Speaker 1: now That seems kind of weird.
Speaker 1: You know, you don't know what happened 40 years ago And it's a very direct problem to these people and some people can't handle it.
Speaker 1: But look at our world the real world the world.
Speaker 1: We're in right now meet space We.
Speaker 1: we have the same issue except it just it's much further into our history.
Speaker 1: We don't know the history of humanity and we have a lot of theories but we really don't know what civilizations were and what happened to them and where people came from and what they did and why we're here now.
Speaker 1: and But a lot of people don't think about it because it's so long ago that the only people who worry about it are Philosophers because most people they just think back and they don't really consider the fact that we have no clue where we came from.
Speaker 0: Historians think about it too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they thought they actually figured out a lot.
Speaker 1: but yes Yes, but like I mean there I mean we know like.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying Oh magic creation Whatever any of that BS But definitely there are civilizations that we know almost nothing about other than that they may have existed like the mice and I civilization cyclopeans.
Speaker 1: yes, we but big o but big o did.
Speaker 1: and I really like this is they took that idea that we don't know where we came from and They made it a present issue Instead of the point before which we don't know anything is millions and millions of years ago.
Speaker 1: that point is within the lifespan of people who are alive in this world and It forces.
Speaker 1: the whole show is just showing characters dealing with the fact that they can never know where they came from and as Roger concludes Realizing that it doesn't matter because you can choose to be whoever you are or whatever you are and the world around you is the world Around you and you can take it as you will.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, at least that's what I got out of it.
Speaker 1: And I really like that because it's an.
Speaker 1: it's an idea I actually hadn't considered before until I saw a big O.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I probably would have gotten more out of.
Speaker 0: it is just that I've been turned off by seeing the same.
Speaker 0: It's something you know, it's like seen it before.
Speaker 0: if it wasn't something I'd seen before Yeah, not specifically big O. But you know the same kind of thing, you know, it would have been like ooh They did something really cool there, but I've seen the same kind of thing like 20 times.
Speaker 1: Yeah I've seen similar things and that they they have this kind of philosophical agenda and they use a robot to show it to you.
Speaker 1: or It's a very, you know intellectual show like this.
Speaker 1: But I've never seen a show that addressed the specific philosophical idea that big O addressed before.
Speaker 1: Alright, I guess it's just just the idea of Take the the fact that we don't know where we came from and make it urgent make it recent make it something that you can't Just ignore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then take characters and see how they react to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess I'm not really, you know, the it doesn't really matter which specific idea it could have been any philosophical idea.
Speaker 0: I'm just generally turned off by you know philosophical ideas.
Speaker 1: I definitely see where you're coming from and if big O hadn't been the specific idea that it was if it had been the same Idea Ava had or the same idea eska flown a head or if it had been any sort of rehash of an idea.
Speaker 1: That's just been an anime over and over.
Speaker 1: I probably would have hated big O - It's just that it happened to be about an issue that I hadn't really considered philosophically before.
Speaker 1: that really made me like the show.
Speaker 1: Hmm now if you were mad about the original ending to Evangelion don't watch big O - you're going to hate the end.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing except no one's gonna make a movie to explain what happened.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm They don't show you what happens physically because it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: just like the end of Ava The robots fighting didn't matter.
Speaker 1: all that mattered is what went on in Shinji's head.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see I used to be like all into this stuff Like I'd watch Ava and I'd be like, oh it was the best thing ever.
Speaker 0: or like Akira where you know You don't really know what happens at the end.
Speaker 0: just kind of you know This vague metaphorical thing and I'd be like, oh I get it or I don't get it But and I would always be like who.
Speaker 0: it was awesome Anyway, or you know something like that and it would be the greatest thing in the world and shows that were just kind of like You know normal where you see what physically happens and that's that we're kind of like.
Speaker 0: these aren't as smart as these other shows.
Speaker 0: They don't do anything for me.
Speaker 0: But now it's like I've seen.
Speaker 0: I must have seen a hundred shows just like this where Instead of instead of having an ending and then a moral or An ending with a moral they have a moral in place of an ending, you know, like they make the ending all for fun, you know.
Speaker 0: and If you go and look at the IMDb top movies list I don't know if it's still number one but for the longest freaking time number one was The Godfather and I would be like, all right, that was a really good movie.
Speaker 0: But why is it, you know number one and why is it still there at number one?
Speaker 0: it doesn't really you know, is it really that much better than every other movie?
Speaker 0: and Then I started that thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've never finished it.
Speaker 0: I should go back to it where I was watching every single movie in the top 250 of IMDb and I saw a lot of freaking movies that were either like way out there in artsy and some that were just way normal.
Speaker 0: and I realized the reason The Godfather is number one is because it's both at the same time.
Speaker 0: It's not all.
Speaker 0: you can watch it and it would just be a perfectly normal see everything that happens, you know mundane Unmeaningful plot movie but at this other at the exact same time It's the most meaningful movie with all kinds of symbolism and things all over the place.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't make one instead of the other.
Speaker 0: you the end of The Godfather.
Speaker 0: It doesn't just turn into like metaphorical stuff.
Speaker 0: You still see what's happening.
Speaker 0: You look at it and it's at the end.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: he's in the church, you know saying I do You know get rid of the devil.
Speaker 0: I won't do bad things whatever they do in church I don't remember exactly and they keep.
Speaker 0: they keep going back and forth between him and the church.
Speaker 0: You know for that and the hitman that he told to kill people killing people and It's an action scene.
Speaker 1: but at the same time it's as metaphorical and meaningful as you can get yep as opposed to say Evangelion where the original ending was literally they don't show you anything that happens and it's just Shinji in his head contemplating the meaning of existence.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm so I guess you know if you still Haven't seen enough crazy metaphorical endings to you know, turn you off to that sort of thing Then you'll probably still like big o2.
Speaker 1: Yeah No See I can.
Speaker 1: I never tire of a show that does that because that's all I'm there for at least for shows like this.
Speaker 1: The only thing that tires me really as opposed to you.
Speaker 1: or shows that try to do this But either do it about a philosophical con philosophical construct that's boring useless or Already done to death or a show that just does it poorly
Speaker 0: Doing it poor doing anything poorly whether it's you know metaphorical or not is just poor to begin with.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess big o2 to me did this really well and you might you don't realize what it's doing right away But it.
Speaker 1: I was extremely pleased with the ending and I'm extremely pleased with the ideas I've been churning about since I saw it.
Speaker 0: I mean don't get me wrong I you know, I did like the show a whole lot and it did do what it did a lot better than other people have done.
Speaker 1: You're coming from it.
Speaker 1: just a lot of shows do this and but it's like.
Speaker 0: You know, okay, you taught me something new.
Speaker 0: I learned a new philosophy.
Speaker 0: Whoo You know, well, it's not like you enlighten me to some great amazingness.
Speaker 1: well, see this comes down to the argument Scott and I always have because I'm very philosophical and he's very pragmatic and Whenever we argue we always tend to go into exact opposite directions to the point that we're a hundred percent Diametrically opposed on every issue.
Speaker 0: Hmm because philosophy is just bullshit.
Speaker 1: see to me philosophy is the only thing that matters, but it's just talking and words.
Speaker 0: It's not a physical thing.
Speaker 0: It's not real.
Speaker 0: What does it matter?
Speaker 1: See I stay up at night wondering about the mysteries of the universe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Just tell you not to.
Speaker 1: yeah, exactly That's why I really like big O because well, it didn't say not to.
Speaker 1: it said to not worry, but to still seek the truth.
Speaker 1: Of course it got complicated because uh, what's-his-name?
Speaker 0: didn't you notice that anyone who was seeking out memories got fucked?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I'm telling you not to seek out the truth But angel found the full truth and she was fine with it because that she realized what it was and it didn't destroy her What's-his-name?
Speaker 1: What was that guy's name?
Speaker 1: the guy in the bandages?
Speaker 0: Schwartz Oswald.
Speaker 1: Schwartzwald found the truth and couldn't handle it and died.
Speaker 1: Rosewater found the truth and freaked out and that was the end of him.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Angel found the truth and almost freaked out but then dealt with it.
Speaker 0: Well didn't Gordon Rosewater make the truth and made himself forget or something?
Speaker 1: See there's a super spoilers from this point on like if you haven't seen the show to stop listening right now Seriously, but Rosewater it like I get the feeling that They the one of the points they made is that at least in this show because at the end of Big O Like you like all of you saw it it pans back and you discover that the whole world was just a stage like literally stage lights in the sky and machinery outside.
Speaker 1: may it Manning the stage and it seems to hint at the idea that an Omniscient being like God couldn't exist because he would.
Speaker 1: there's nothing to live for being Omnipotent and he would create a world in which people could exist and the deny himself memory of doing so Thus allowing people to exist with free will.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm, and That's at least one way to interpret it and it seems to me that Rosewater is a God who's forgotten that he's God willingly And that his son.
Speaker 1: Well, his son was just dumb.
Speaker 1: I don't know what I was up with that.
Speaker 0: He started out in Big O one is like the mysterious big evil guy.
Speaker 0: and then towards the end of Big O one You actually saw him a couple times and he talked and he was there and it was just like hey, how you doing?
Speaker 0: It wasn't like whoa, you're the big bad guy.
Speaker 0: It was like hey, what's up?
Speaker 0: And then in Big O - he was just dumb dumb as a brick and out there doing all kinds of crazy stuff Yeah unbefitting of a big evil character like the Emperor someone.
Speaker 1: but I realized I like how they did that in the sense that in Big O one you don't see a lot of Gordon Rosewater.
Speaker 1: and when you see him or Alex Rosewater Alex Alex Rose Yeah, Gordon's the father.
Speaker 1: But when he's there he like you see him for a second and he says something and he seems very intelligent.
Speaker 1: superficially and even in Big O - Superficially, he's very intelligent and very wise.
Speaker 1: like he sits there eating fine meals with that pretentious music playing in the background Constantly telling himself that he's doing the right thing constantly just spouting philosophy that he doesn't seem to understand himself and Big O - as you get to know this character more and more you realize that he's full of shit and he doesn't know anything and He's just an idiot who happens to be in a place of power.
Speaker 1: and I kind of like how they did that How there was no villain.
Speaker 1: there was just one idiot One senile God and then a bunch of people trying to figure out what was going on.
Speaker 0: Well, no, what's-his-name was the villain?
Speaker 1: Oh Alan Gabriel.
Speaker 0: Alan Gabriel is was a villain.
Speaker 0: He was a bad guy.
Speaker 1: See, I think the reason he was a villain because I know Alan you made a good point.
Speaker 1: I didn't think of that Alan Gabriel is really the only villain in all of Big O. Yeah, no one else is a villain.
Speaker 1: They may do bad things, but they know.
Speaker 0: Beck started out as a villain But he unvillain, but he wasn't.
Speaker 1: I don't consider him a villain.
Speaker 1: He was just an antagonist.
Speaker 0: No, I think he was actually a villain in the first like episode or two when he first did bad And then we broke out of jail on his own.
Speaker 0: in that other episode He was still a villain But then after that second time he appeared and he was done.
Speaker 0: for then he unvillain.
Speaker 1: see now Here's where I disagree with you because to me Beck wasn't a villain He was just playing this role just like Roger Smith was playing his role.
Speaker 1: because notice that while Beck did whore tried to do horrible things he always had the sense of style and the sense of morals and he never stepped over the line.
Speaker 1: and Alan Gabriel is the only character in the show that has no morals whatsoever.
Speaker 1: he has absolutely no compunction against doing anything and he forces back to step over the line and Beck can't deal with that.
Speaker 1: and even in the beginning when Beck does is evil.
Speaker 1: He's not a villain He's not the villain of the show.
Speaker 1: He's just an antagonist and a plot point.
Speaker 0: No, if you've never.
Speaker 0: when I first saw the show ever and like the first two episodes I was like, all right back that bastard go get him, you know, he was a bad.
Speaker 1: Definitely Beck that bastard go get him, but I wouldn't use the word villain.
Speaker 0: I would at least if you only watch the first two episodes of the big O one.
Speaker 1: Well, if you watch big O one and that yeah, but if you watch all the big O one you'd think Alex is the villain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: if I watched one and two again You wouldn't be viewed as a villain because I've already seen the whole thing.
Speaker 0: But when I remember that when I watched it fresh, he seemed like a villain right away.
Speaker 1: So yes to me because having seen the whole show the only character I can justify calling a villain is Alan Gabriel Because he everyone does what they do for a reason and everyone who do whatever they do They believe that they're in the right or at least they know they're in the wrong and they've dealt with that.
Speaker 1: Alan Gabriel doesn't care right or wrong anything.
Speaker 1: He has absolutely no direction.
Speaker 1: He's just doing whatever the hell he wants for fun and Whatever the hell he wants tends to involve hurting people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's not even after the truth.
Speaker 1: He's not after anything I don't know.
Speaker 0: You know, it's just you never know.
Speaker 0: what he's thinking is the thing He might be thinking that you know He might have some crazy whack job plan where if he does this and this and this then he'll somehow get something But he doesn't ever get anything.
Speaker 0: So either his whack job plan isn't working or At some point he like his whack job plan fails and he gives up on it and goes crazy.
Speaker 0: But you don't realize it because you didn't know his whack job plan to begin with, you know, but I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think I mean cuz Roger Smith was kind of obsessed with memory and that's what was keeping him down and preventing him from Realizing what he was.
Speaker 1: and once he realized what he was he didn't like get rid of the idea of memory.
Speaker 1: He still cherishes the memories.
Speaker 1: He has.
Speaker 1: he cherishes the past looks forward to the future But he lives in the present as opposed to living in the past.
Speaker 1: Alan Gabriel lives in the present, but he ignores the past completely Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: He acts.
Speaker 1: one moment is completely separate from any other moment in his life.
Speaker 0: But notice how is Roger like gets better and better and understands what's going on more and more He.
Speaker 0: it's like when he stops trying to worry about memories.
Speaker 0: He gets more memories of how to do awesome things with the robot.
Speaker 1: Yes, the robot is definitely a metaphorical Device through the entire see.
Speaker 0: that's the good kind of thing.
Speaker 0: is where you have, you know, the completely mundane action But you also have the meaning and it's together in the same thing because at first they did that perfectly.
Speaker 1: Remember when I angel discovered the studio where she'd grown up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was very much the metaphor and mundane plot going on at the same time And I think if they'd had more episodes and more money they could have constructed an ending for the whole show.
Speaker 1: That was similar.
Speaker 0: You know what it is.
Speaker 1: It's like they took the easy way out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: You know when you read a book and you read in between the lines, it's not.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: They don't actually write down what their meaning is.
Speaker 0: You're just reading a perfectly normal story But there's a meaning there and you have to extract it by thinking about what you just read.
Speaker 0: But it seems that a lot of these animes that try to or you know Especially animes but also TV shows and movies that try to be meaningful What they do is they might make you read between the lines the whole way but at the end They just take what is written in between the lines and put it in bold text at the end.
Speaker 0: And that's what I kind of don't like.
Speaker 0: I wish I could just read between the lines the whole time and that stupid people would you know?
Speaker 0: Maintain the thing where they didn't see anything between the lines.
Speaker 1: Well, look at the end of trygun.
Speaker 1: Alright, I'm gonna spoil the end of trygun.
Speaker 1: So if anyone who is afraid of spoilers, but is still listening I'm swelling trygun now, too but I think that did it very well because the the moral, you know, no killing whatever because he doesn't kill knives at the end is There and if you read these on lines You can see all the conflict and the fact that he decided he's going to kill knives throughout the entire final fight And it's not until the very end when he decides not to.
Speaker 1: but then he doesn't.
Speaker 1: and they don't do a crazy metaphor Whatever.
Speaker 1: they just show him carrying knives back to town and that's the end.
Speaker 0: Yep That's a.
Speaker 1: and if you watch the fight and you watch the expressions on his face I mean if you don't notice any of that You just see an awesome fight and then the show ends.
Speaker 1: and if you watch his face and you pay attention to what's going on You get all that other meaning as well.
Speaker 1: But the show isn't ruined for the people who don't get the metaphor nor is it ruined for the people who don't care about the action Mm-hmm, and we've gone on really long about that.
Speaker 1: So I think that's a good stopping point.
Speaker 1: All right, sure, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.