Speaker 1: It's Monday February 6th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about instant messaging messaging messaging.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So we were in good old Rochester this past weekend Great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had a quite a fun weekend lined up and kind of got pissed on a little bit a Lot.
Speaker 0: Well, let's see.
Speaker 0: It started out great.
Speaker 0: You know, we're driving back to Rochester.
Speaker 0: We're going with two of our friends in Scott's brand-new Mazda 3 gonna be a good time.
Speaker 0: Scott gets a little pulled over along the way.
Speaker 0: Great gets a little 80 and a 65 speeding ticket that he may or may not fight in court.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: And then we get to Rochester to discover that the main event that we had driven to Rochester for Had been canceled suddenly that morning by the board of the club that was running it.
Speaker 1: another very sarcastic single word Great Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wasn't a total loss though because we ended up just going to millennium games Which is the best freaking gaming store in the eastern seaboard as far as we're concerned.
Speaker 1: Well, as far as we know, I haven't heard of a better one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we haven't heard ever found a better gaming store than this place.
Speaker 0: We bought between all of us over three hundred dollars worth of board games Woot which amounted to what like five games?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, no, we got five games and then between our friends They got I think two more games.
Speaker 1: What did they get?
Speaker 0: Pete one of them bought Illuminati.
Speaker 1: Oh, right, right, right.
Speaker 1: Yeah That was it.
Speaker 0: No, I don't remember.
Speaker 1: Oh, we got else bunny.
Speaker 0: We got Attica Citadel's through the desert and deck are and Stratego.
Speaker 0: Whoo Yeah, Stratego is a farm, but we'll talk about all that on a gaming day Tomorrow and probably the next week on Tuesday and the next week on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but luckily we ran into all our friends and we pretty much salvaged the weekend as best we could.
Speaker 1: We salvaged a little bit man.
Speaker 1: It feels like mech warrior mercenaries and you blow up all the enemies and you pick up like a laser.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess I had a better time than you since one.
Speaker 0: I didn't fall asleep early Saturday night So I actually got to hang out with everyone.
Speaker 0: Mmm, yeah I mean there are about ten of us in a tiny apartment yelling and screaming and arguing philosophy and solipsism all that crap.
Speaker 0: Scott's asleep in the middle of the floor just kind of curled up with his coat over him like a blanket.
Speaker 1: That was cold and tired.
Speaker 0: We woke you up to give you wanton soup that you had ordered but forgotten about.
Speaker 1: I didn't forget about it.
Speaker 0: You seem to have forgotten about it.
Speaker 0: You didn't seem to know why we were waking you up.
Speaker 1: No, I I was.
Speaker 1: uh, I was semi awake like I was hearing some things here and there but you know Never put enough effort in to get up and then I knew food arrived.
Speaker 0: So You know, I was just sleeping Whatever yeah, but at least anyway in the news Google did something that it's generated a lot of grousing from both sides and I think it was a good thing though But they delisted a spammer.
Speaker 1: essentially They did this all the time, but this is the first time they've done it Visibly because they've done it to other big companies but invisibly.
Speaker 1: But now they did it visibly to a large important company.
Speaker 0: Not only that but they stood up and said yes, we did this We'll do it again.
Speaker 1: Well, it was a guy On his official Google worker on his blog said it It wasn't like a Google press.
Speaker 0: what happened was the German BMW site was doing something kind of shady.
Speaker 0: I Mean, yeah, everyone knows that Google uses page rank which is a complex trade secret Algorithm for determining how useful a website is based on what you're searching for
Speaker 1: and people try to reverse engineer and figure out how page rank Works so that they can make pages all around the internet to raise the page ranks of other pages So that they will show up on Google very high up when someone searches for something.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of the basics are that linking to a page Will boost its page rank as long as the link comes from a useful page.
Speaker 0: Like there was a problem not too long ago where blogs were ruining Google because blogs all linked to each other in this kind of incestuous link pile of links.
Speaker 0: So what they did is they just decided that links between blogs don't count and that solved that.
Speaker 0: and they've done various things like that Over the years to tweak their page.
Speaker 1: sure if that's exactly what they did That's that's what they did.
Speaker 0: to a point links from blogs are not weighted as highly as other links anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: they also had a problem where people would go around to different blogs posting in the comments section where then you know, I would go to a hundred blogs and Comment on those in stories on those blogs and in those comments put links to my site and that would make my rank go up.
Speaker 1: But now this is the thing where you in the link you say rel equals no follow And that basically means Google completely ignores that link in terms of page ranking or anything.
Speaker 0: Thus removing the incentive to spam blog.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so now all blogs automatic all good blogs automatically put in the little no follow thing.
Speaker 1: So there's no point in spamming the comments to raise your raise your page rank anymore.
Speaker 0: now We don't know exactly who did the BMW site but either they did it themselves Internally either knowingly or unknowingly or they hired what is called an SEO or a search engine optimizer.
Speaker 0: Now you might see spam from these people occasionally.
Speaker 0: you probably find them when you search on various search engines.
Speaker 0: SEOs are about a micrometer above spammers in terms of ethics and morals.
Speaker 1: now as far as I'm concerned They're on the same level.
Speaker 1: They're just internet scum people who are using the internet to scam the internet itself and make money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll charge you money and they'll Optimize in quotes your site to make it appear higher in Google
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and they'll do things to other sites like spam them to make your rank higher in Google
Speaker 0: or they'll run massive Networks of fake sites that all link to each other to have their own high page rank and then they'll link to you from that Network.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm all sorts of things and looks like BMW dot-com.
Speaker 0: dot-de did something like that because they were doing a lot of shady things on their site.
Speaker 1: Specifically the one thing that you're really not allowed to do is you have a web page and the web page is a bunch of Text.
Speaker 1: but then you have some JavaScript that edits all the content on the page.
Speaker 1: So when you visit it, it looks like a normal web page.
Speaker 1: But if you actually look at the source code of the page There's a whole bunch of words in there like used car used car used car used car.
Speaker 1: that shouldn't be there.
Speaker 0: So when Google noticed this on the BMW German site instead of just quietly adjusting or ignoring it they De-listed them.
Speaker 0: they dropped their page rank to zero remove the cache and basically unless you search for the URL itself all of the BMW Germany site you can't find it in Google anymore period.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean you can get it by.
Speaker 1: I'm sure if you went to the thousandth thousandth thousandth page It might be there, but I wasn't about to click that far.
Speaker 1: I tried I got to like a few hundred pages down and I couldn't find it.
Speaker 0: so Page rank zero really sucks Yeah, so I guess the moral out here is don't use SEO's don't be a spamming jackass and follow the rules.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just if you're gonna make a web page for a reason just make it for that reason and don't try to grow up in The Google ranks, it's just who cares.
Speaker 0: now I saw on slash dot a lot of people especially web designers who are complaining about this and their main complaint Was that Google is quote dictating to me how to design my website.
Speaker 0: Because if you don't know Google one of the page rank things is it looks at the content of your site.
Speaker 0: It looks at your HTML that looks at your CSS It looks at all sorts of things and it has various weightings based on how often the contents updated how it's arranged etc.
Speaker 0: Now if you have a site that's made entirely in flash say There's no information for the Google spider to get so your page ranks going to be crap.
Speaker 0: no to how good your site is.
Speaker 0: Well if a lot of people link to it you're all right Yep But they won't find it based on the content and it'll be kind of weighed.
Speaker 0: how they will.
Speaker 1: it depends on the content of the Links linking to you like if I post a comment in my blog that says check out this awesome flash site Then and that adds it so that if someone searches for awesome flash site you you might show up true.
Speaker 0: But if someone's searching for content on your site that might not be linked to directly But would appear on the site and would otherwise be found by Google spiders and waited It'll be weighted less because as far as ghouls concerned your site doesn't have as much content as it wants to see.
Speaker 0: yeah, maybe And I really knows for your HTML your site will be ranked more poorly even if your content looks identical.
Speaker 1: Oh well Yeah, if you use poor HTML, and that's that's just what happens because it's harder for the the spider to read it the way It's written.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also harder for my web browser to read it so knock it off.
Speaker 1: Yeah Make web pages well.
Speaker 0: But basically all the people I saw complaining about this decision by Google We're doing so for really kind of spurious reasons.
Speaker 0: They really didn't have any good arguments there.
Speaker 1: No I mean So wait Google is dictating to you how to make your website well number one.
Speaker 1: You're still free to make whatever website you want.
Speaker 1: yeah What are you?
Speaker 1: you're trying to dictate to Google to rank you higher.
Speaker 0: Google isn't an ISP.
Speaker 0: Google isn't anything.
Speaker 0: Google is just a company That says we are going to present the internet to you in this way.
Speaker 0: if you like to see it in this way Please see it in this way.
Speaker 0: If not then please don't come to our website.
Speaker 0: We don't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you know you don't have to do what Google says.
Speaker 1: what do you know?
Speaker 1: and if you want to give it if you?
Speaker 1: Want to go up in their page ranks well, then you know you have to be good and be good.
Speaker 1: anyway I mean what do you?
Speaker 1: I mean?
Speaker 1: this isn't like some computer system that is going around delisting people randomly.
Speaker 1: You know if you want to make a website that has different content, and then renders it all differently with JavaScript You can do that, and they probably won't do list you.
Speaker 1: This is like a very a person looking at it and saying whoa that's a spammer And they don't do it often.
Speaker 1: yep, so I wouldn't worry about it.
Speaker 0: I'm hoping in fact that this ushers in a new era of Google cracking down on shit websites that pretend to be real websites.
Speaker 1: I also think what it can do is if Google starts pushing people to obey certain web standards.
Speaker 1: Then perhaps like ie will become more useless in Firefox more useful because an ie won't render sites that are properly written to show up high in Google and Such and such.
Speaker 0: you know what?
Speaker 0: maybe the stupid experts exchange will finally disappear from Google.
Speaker 1: god damn you.
Speaker 1: X.
Speaker 0: I hate these so much.
Speaker 1: you know who beats experts exchange?
Speaker 0: How about those fake sites that just rip content from Wikipedia and put it in an HTML?
Speaker 0: So you'll find it, and then it's just a spam site when you go there.
Speaker 1: You know who beats experts exchange.
Speaker 1: bug me not.
Speaker 0: ah Bug me not yeah, but yeah bug me not.
Speaker 1: okay so This is guy who is an ice cream man an ice cream man.
Speaker 0: Eh as in he sells ice cream in a truck that goes ding ding ding ding ding.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: I remember when I was a kid the ice cream man would come down the street every day in the summer And we'd all run out to buy ice cream.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my parents always yell at me and tell me that it was a ripoff, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: it wasn't a ripoff.
Speaker 1: It was like a cone for a buck 25 cone.
Speaker 1: We don't?
Speaker 1: I always bought the WWF wrestler bar for it If I was gonna buy one of those I would get like the Mario with the bubblegum nose or something.
Speaker 0: No, it was all about either the Cookie Witch the WWF bar or Just a regular old cookie which the Cookie Witch is awesome.
Speaker 1: He had the greatest vanilla.
Speaker 1: I always got his vanilla on a cone and the cone was really good, too.
Speaker 1: Or I got the thing that was red white and blue on a stick, but of course the white tasted bad.
Speaker 1: There's only the red and the blue.
Speaker 1: that tasted good.
Speaker 1: So it was like red.
Speaker 1: you just cut the white off and hit the blue.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it was an ice cream man.
Speaker 1: Who is a pretty genius ice cream man?
Speaker 1: according to me what he did is he's Pirated a whole bunch of PlayStation games a whole mess of them like wow That's a lot of PlayStation games, and he kept him in the back of his truck And he sold.
Speaker 1: so he was selling him and he sold him to kids.
Speaker 1: just burn CDs of games.
Speaker 1: They caught him.
Speaker 1: He had a whole bunch of games in the back of his truck, and now he's busted.
Speaker 0: now I wonder how they caught him.
Speaker 0: what kid would complain I?
Speaker 0: Don't know, but who could possibly have found out something?
Speaker 0: you know what someone didn't follow the rules of the playground Must not have been.
Speaker 1: maybe a parent maybe a Cops just saw him because they look out it for ice cream.
Speaker 1: Maybe like it.
Speaker 1: I know ice cream and go to like Little League games and stuff all the time.
Speaker 1: Maybe there was like a cop coach or something who knows.
Speaker 0: well I grew up in Detroit and more than once an ice cream man was busted for actually just selling drugs.
Speaker 0: Wow they drive around and they sell ice cream to kids.
Speaker 0: just fine, but if you gave the right code word They'd sell you drugs, but they accidentally sell drugs to.
Speaker 1: somebody said the code word by accident and then got busted.
Speaker 0: No, I think the cops were just onto it anyway, and we're kind of keeping eyes out for him, okay?
Speaker 0: But it's just when a when an ice cream truck goes through a kiddie neighborhood and sells can't.
Speaker 1: oh well this guy Oh, he was in Britain.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's something to do with yeah You know goes to a kiddie neighborhood and sells ice cream and then goes to a ghetto And it's just like crazy looking middle-aged men standing around giving large sums of money to an ice cream man.
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway he had 4,000 DVDs CDs and games that were seized during a raid on On his business premises, so he didn't have all those in the truck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so don't do that.
Speaker 0: But I think you just said he was cool.
Speaker 1: He is cool, but why not do it?
Speaker 0: just don't get caught I guess.
Speaker 1: But I mean seriously don't buy from the guy cuz you can totally download this stuff.
Speaker 0: There you go All right, so my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: This is a little old, but that's just because we had the weekend lag here.
Speaker 0: But this here is a Super Mario Brothers one soundboard.
Speaker 0: It seems to have every single sound from the game, and it is quite fun amusing useful and interesting.
Speaker 1: I like it a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We if we ever set up some more complex audio here Maybe we'll have it handy whenever we're doing the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that would be cool.
Speaker 1: be like Dude, I made some mad money today Or Something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's all I got about that.
Speaker 0: It's cool.
Speaker 0: Check it out.
Speaker 1: hmm Well my thing we got.
Speaker 1: you might remember a while ago that some people made like Trailers for old movies, but they changed the themes.
Speaker 1: so you like it was The Shining But it was a romantic comedy shining well.
Speaker 1: No that that's a feel-good movie But all the same whatever movies that we don't like.
Speaker 0: they turn West Side Story into a zombie thriller.
Speaker 1: Yeah, instead of a you know gang dancing singing thing.
Speaker 1: so some people decided to keep on keeping on with this little trend bit here and Usually when someone tries to copy something that's already done.
Speaker 1: They mess up, and it's not so good.
Speaker 1: But these people seem to have Kept the same level of quality and they've taken fight club and made a fight club trailer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a romantic comedy, and it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: All right, I liked it.
Speaker 1: You should watch it if you've seen fight club.
Speaker 1: Don't watch it if you haven't seen fight club because you'd be like what the fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fight clubs fight club.
Speaker 0: for the any of you out there who haven't seen it is not really about fighting Although the fighting parts are kind of entertaining.
Speaker 0: yeah But it's one of those movies like the matrix where you get in to see it, and it's not at all what you expect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's exactly what it's.
Speaker 1: it came out around the same time.
Speaker 0: I think - yeah, I did.
Speaker 0: I actually didn't see it for a while.
Speaker 1: I didn't see fight club for a long.
Speaker 1: I saw matrix in the theaters.
Speaker 1: I didn't see fight club until way later.
Speaker 1: I Think not to like 2,000 huh, though.
Speaker 0: I never saw the second matrix movie at all.
Speaker 1: You're not missing much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know if you cut the 20-minute Rave see now.
Speaker 1: It's not so bad.
Speaker 0: You know if you cut the key rape out of kagihime.
Speaker 1: It's not so bad Yeah, then it'll just be normal magic girl girl show which is pretty bad.
Speaker 0: So anyway, we decided since being science and technology day that we talk about instant messaging Especially since I just changed.
Speaker 0: I am clients today, so you're going with sigh all the way.
Speaker 0: well looking at version point one definitely 0.93 definitely not But basically instant messengers, you know AOL instant messenger ICQ MSN messenger jabber QQ Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: yeah, none of you have ever heard of QQ.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: So let's start at the beginning here back in the ancient days when there was no real internet.
Speaker 1: It was dial up into Existing computer networks that were providing services.
Speaker 1: You know to anyone dialed up into them such as the old prodigy BBS's CompuServe the original AOL that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: There really wasn't instant messaging.
Speaker 0: Yeah In fact the closest you got was on some BBS's.
Speaker 0: you could like message someone if they were online Like by sending them a short text string.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and on the old days and like Unix lands you could use like the chat program.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I talk you talk and whatever The Message windows had what's it called the message box check in the box guy, right?
Speaker 0: I never even knew what he was or ever used him in any way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he was.
Speaker 1: basically.
Speaker 1: you could pop up messages and other people's computers if you had an old-school Windows for workgroup style LAN or like a novell whatever type whatever it was called.
Speaker 0: Now Scott and I both had very different early.
Speaker 0: I am experiences because we're not gonna cover the old old history.
Speaker 0: We're pretty much talking about the rise of AOL instant messenger and ICQ into what we have today.
Speaker 0: Yep That's when it really started anyway, and Scott was much more in the AOL instant messenger camp.
Speaker 0: I had ICQ though Yeah, but you seem to use AOL and like it more.
Speaker 0: Yeah And I started with ICQ and I actually never even touched AOL instant messenger other than trying it once and hating it Until I got to college and no one I knew at RIT used ICQ.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Well, it all started because we used AOL the program, you know, the when AOL was.
Speaker 1: I think it was still is a program.
Speaker 1: I don't know why people still use it though, but I've never used or had AOL.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well AOL was like the only ISP we could get for a long time.
Speaker 1: Really the only ISP That was really like that would work.
Speaker 0: See I was on prodigy classic.
Speaker 1: We didn't we didn't have ISPs in the in that day.
Speaker 0: and then I switched from that to Wow Which money?
Speaker 0: it was the first one the first ISP.
Speaker 0: that was a flat rate monthly fee all you can access.
Speaker 0: It was like 20 bucks a month.
Speaker 0: It was fantastic and you know what?
Speaker 0: It was too good to be true.
Speaker 0: It went out of business about a year after it opened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had AOL with just 20 bucks a month for unlimited, but it Had some other ways of making money off of you, you know, cuz it was AOL.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess I was real.
Speaker 0: lucky me and my friend Ken we lived in.
Speaker 0: where we lived in sterling Michigan was actually way way back like 1996.
Speaker 0: They deployed cable modems as a test.
Speaker 0: So I've pretty much had broadband for most of my internet using life.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, we had dial-up pretty much until I went to college.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: We had I had a 56 game modem.
Speaker 1: It worked well enough, but I didn't play 3d games online.
Speaker 1: but everything else was just fine.
Speaker 0: see before I got to college I remember thinking that a ping higher than 50 was terrible.
Speaker 0: Then I got to RIT and I remember thinking a ping higher than five was terrible.
Speaker 1: Actually, the 56 game modem was able to play like tribes to online pretty well because tribes to network code was written real Well, but yeah, that wasn't until I got back from college and we had DSL.
Speaker 0: Yeah back then games weren't so tolerant of latency.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean quake one and quake to quake one.
Speaker 0: literally What your lag time was was how long it took between when you clicked and when a rocket came out of the front of you?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was terrible.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: Instant messaging.
Speaker 1: So AOL the program you chat rooms are the big thing because you know when I was a little kid high school middle school Whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah going to chat rooms.
Speaker 1: Talk to people.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah My first moniker on the internet for anyone who cares because you won't be able to find anything about me was origins.
Speaker 0: I was origins on prodigy classic a fuck long time ago.
Speaker 1: I was taser 3-1-4-6-0 on AOL.
Speaker 0: Wow, you suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so so wait a minute.
Speaker 0: I'm curious.
Speaker 0: Where did you get that name?
Speaker 1: So there was his old DOS game, which I don't remember the name of the game But basically the way the game worked was.
Speaker 1: you were in this car hover car thing that that also shot lasers or whatever And you would.
Speaker 1: you could go up down forward backward and rotate turn left and right.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of like a first-person driving game, but you didn't race.
Speaker 1: Imagine it was like an FPS but you could move up and down and But it was like but you're in a car You weren't shooting with your hand and you went around shooting other cars and it was an old DOS pixely thing.
Speaker 1: You couldn't type in a name in this game.
Speaker 1: We had to click on an existing nickname So I always click taser.
Speaker 0: Did you know what a taser was back then?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes, they did.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh But it was it afraid that's a cool name and then it was already name.
Speaker 1: also if you pick taser you also got to be green.
Speaker 1: That was key.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we often have fights over who is going to be green in various German board games here, right?
Speaker 1: So Taser was my AOL name.
Speaker 1: now in AOL chat rooms If you double clicked on someone's name You would say you could like open up a little tiny chat with them and I never really thought of his instant messaging.
Speaker 1: It just thought as tiny chat with that person.
Speaker 1: But then they eventually made it so you could keep people on a buddy list.
Speaker 1: It wasn't really I am.
Speaker 1: it was a buddy list first and you would put people on your buddy list And then he clicked on them.
Speaker 1: you would you know do a little messaging with them And then eventually they said you know what there are a lot of people who don't have AOL.
Speaker 1: they want to talk to AOL people and they made AOL instant messenger a separate program and It did all the things that aim inside of AOL did.
Speaker 0: Now I started in 1996 was the first time I ever used.
Speaker 0: real instant messaging.
Speaker 0: was ICQ when it was founded or it was built by Mirabilis company in Tel Aviv.
Speaker 1: Israelis made it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it was basically a standalone.
Speaker 0: I am thing but it was very.
Speaker 0: it was extremely fully featured and very light and generally very awesome.
Speaker 1: It was full of a ton of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep It was very much not geared at people who didn't know a lot about the internet like you could check your email.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can
Speaker 1: send SMS messages which I never figured out how to use
Speaker 0: and the biggest thing about it was that it had it had the Stateful away messages where there are different types of away messages and you could program it to say if I'm in this kind of away Messages give me a message like give me a message without making a noise But if I'm in this away state don't give me anything and whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, AOL didn't have any.
Speaker 1: AOL still only has a way and not a way.
Speaker 1: it also didn't even have a way for a long Time.
Speaker 0: it had two of my favorite features and these two alone are the reason that I used ICQ for most of my life until I got to college.
Speaker 0: one AOL instant messenger.
Speaker 0: you could only send a message to someone if you were both online.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm ICQ if you were off it would just save your message in the server and give it to the person as soon as they got Online.
Speaker 1: well the logic of AOL was that if someone wasn't online You were that you were going to use aim to like talk to the person in a conversation just like a chat room.
Speaker 1: Yeah So that if you were gonna send them a message that you wanted them to get and they weren't available for a discussion You would send them an email because that's how it worked, you know in AOL the program.
Speaker 1: yeah, that was a logic in the instant messenger.
Speaker 0: ICQ's logic was that it is a standalone communication medium and thus if you send a Message it would all you would always get there is guaranteed that the message would get there.
Speaker 0: So it was more like fast email instead of chatting.
Speaker 0: It was like it was instantaneous so you could just chat in the window.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you often chatted in the window, but it was a lot more like fast email and it was slightly geared away from.
Speaker 1: you know Conversing unless you use the chat feature, which was a chat making a chat room.
Speaker 0: There was much easier to have a conversation though I got to say I had straight-up hour-long conversations with people just in the normal message.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I did too because I did have ICQ.
Speaker 1: once I figured out you could run other Programs and minimize AOL and I ran ICQ when I talked to a whole bunch of people that you know people mostly people I didn't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah That was the one thing that talked to internet people.
Speaker 0: with it all of you out there today really miss.
Speaker 0: is that back?
Speaker 0: I don't want to sound like an old man, but back in our day when I am was a new thing Honestly, there were very few asshats on it because asshats couldn't figure out how to use it.
Speaker 0: So especially more so ICQ than aim because every AOL user could use aim
Speaker 1: every AOL user was using aim and every non AOL user was using ICQ which included most of the world other than the u.s Yep
Speaker 0: Even so is basically
Speaker 1: most
Speaker 0: of the world uses ICQ or MSN.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's basically on ICQ.
Speaker 1: in those early days was all the early internet adopters Worldwide.
Speaker 1: so most often your your odds of talking to like a British guy or an Israeli guy were pretty high.
Speaker 0: I mean, it was great because I honestly in high school I had no I mean I had friends in high school and whatever but I Really wasn't interested in most of the people that were near me physically in proximity.
Speaker 0: I however made a lot of interesting friends online.
Speaker 0: some of them I talked to.
Speaker 1: still to this day I didn't make friends online, but I did talk to random people about random stuff.
Speaker 0: Well, I did that and I kept talking to some of the same people over and over again.
Speaker 0: And like I have a friend in South Africa now just because I talked to him back in the day And I still talk to him occasionally Yeah, I never actually talked to anyone online.
Speaker 1: that much to be a friend with them.
Speaker 0: Well ICQ also made it really easy to find people to talk to.
Speaker 0: You could.
Speaker 0: they'd had a whole directory service built into it where you could put in information about yourself And you could say if you wanted to be searchable or not and people could just search for you.
Speaker 0: It was like a giant LDAP.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember you could be online Or you could be free for chat and free for chat was like hey random people come talk to me And I did that you would just wait around and people would just come talk to you.
Speaker 1: and sometimes I would sit there just searching for like high school girls and People who like computers and people who are playing the same video game I was playing right now, and then trying to talk to them about it, and it worked a lot of the time
Speaker 0: Yeah, but
Speaker 1: sometimes I also remember sitting there for like 20 minutes not doing anything Just searching.
Speaker 0: see I always just had it on while I was doing other things.
Speaker 0: then someone would pop up.
Speaker 1: Hey, but like you I would add a whole bunch of buddies and then delete him because I never talked to him again.
Speaker 0: And yep, but think about what a different world is today.
Speaker 0: back in the day I was hoping for strangers to just say hi to me today.
Speaker 0: If I don't know immediately who you are when you talk to me you get deleted banned blocked within about three seconds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I just don't want to deal with you.
Speaker 1: That was back in the day.
Speaker 0: Now the other feature of ICQ that I loved was invisible mode.
Speaker 0: You could put yourself in invisible mode and be online But no one could see that you were online unless you talk to them mm-hmm Or you could make a list of.
Speaker 0: you could flag your some people in your buddy list as like ultra friends or whatever I forget Exactly, and they had the ability to see you when you were invisible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you could have like your inner circle of friends, then your outer circle of friends.
Speaker 1: That was good for when someone was annoying you But like right now or like you didn't want to talk to someone right now But you need to talk to someone else.
Speaker 1: yep, then but you knew someone else is gonna bother you so you could be invisible and talk to the someone else and Then get a really online to get the other person to jump on and annoy you.
Speaker 0: yeah And aim never really implemented any of those things.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, but I think aim really tried to keep it simple because most people who use it were a wellers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'll admit ICQ was not simple Yeah, and actually the interface of the normal ICQ program was never high quality.
Speaker 1: It was always blocky and There's even right-click and you get this gigantic context menu.
Speaker 0: you could edit that but you had to go edit it.
Speaker 1: It was a giant context menu with 90% of the options were just useless or crazy And they didn't make sense a lot of the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you could customize it all but it took time.
Speaker 1: it took a lot.
Speaker 0: It was very much a Windows 3 1 style application.
Speaker 1: It was it still is the Windows 3 1 style.
Speaker 1: I think I haven't yet.
Speaker 0: well the thing is like most people in the world used ICQ and a lot of Americans use aim and then AOL bought ICQ.
Speaker 1: that was a lot.
Speaker 1: I was a while later though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did that.
Speaker 1: by then there were a lot more competitors in the market.
Speaker 0: the only big competitors ever to really come out were yahoo messenger which not many people use to this day.
Speaker 1: a lot of people are actually using yahoo messenger because it had these features like The webcam ness and the ability to do like the drawing chat where you can draw pictures on a shared canvas.
Speaker 0: Oh true.
Speaker 0: I forgot about that.
Speaker 1: yeah, yahoo added a bunch of those like happy little yahoo type things with like Java and whatever and A lot of people were using yahoo, you know when it came out to do those sorts of things with each other.
Speaker 1: Like I know people who would like they be AOL aim people, but they would have yahoo to do those other features.
Speaker 1: but MSN.
Speaker 1: Somehow MSN seems to have slowly built from no one uses that to.
Speaker 1: a bunch of people use it.
Speaker 1: It's kind of scary.
Speaker 0: scarily enough India is where MSN is king.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone uses MSN there.
Speaker 1: It seems like more and more people using MSN here too.
Speaker 1: It's like the people use aim Seem to be the people who were AOL errs and then now that AOL is kind of dead The people who got internet for the first time after the age of AOL like since the age of cable modems.
Speaker 1: Those people are all MSN errs.
Speaker 1: Cuz what did they do?
Speaker 1: They turn on a computer and they have IE and MSN.
Speaker 1: They don't have aim.
Speaker 1: That's not on there.
Speaker 0: Now the thing about instant messaging networks and why it matters is that you can't talk to people on a different network Mm-hmm, so especially back in the day for us when there weren't these multi like trillion or GA You had to run the client of every network you connected to yep,
Speaker 1: and no one really wanted to run more clients.
Speaker 0: That was like yeah, especially back when RAM was scarce.
Speaker 1: Yeah running a wall and ICQ at the same time was about my limit.
Speaker 0: You would end up having to use whatever all your friends used.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: and when you move to college they're always the bitter wars where half the people used aim and half the people used ICQ and Eventually one half caved in and everyone used the same one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or you just didn't make friends with people who used other.
Speaker 1: I am clients.
Speaker 1: I remember a couple times people like here's my MSN and then I never talked to them because they had an MSN and That was it and never met him again because I never talked to him.
Speaker 0: Of course There was that fanboy in line for the TMR concert at Otacon that we just gave made-up aim names to so we'd go away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't ask me for my aim I'm not going to talk to you after I met you for five seconds at a con and you were annoying.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I joined the dance dance revolution DDR maniacs forums a long time ago when I was trying to build a hard pad for DDR and Not even thinking I put my aim name in my profile.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: to this day.
Speaker 0: I Periodically get messages from punk kids asking me for help on making a DDR pad.
Speaker 1: There's a point at which I had to set my a my g aim So that it would not accept messages from people not on my buddy list, but now that doesn't happen anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now luckily Fairly recently as in within the last many years Multi protocol clients have come out and despite their best efforts.
Speaker 0: They can't keep them out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically people who don't know a lot about computers use one Instant messaging network and that's it because they just don't know how to use more.
Speaker 0: But the real the geeks out there connect to whatever I am networks they want.
Speaker 0: I have accounts on several of them and I just route them all through my gene.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't use my ICQ anymore But for a while I had a jabber and ICQ and aim and IRC all running at the same time inside of gene.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is AOL and ICQ are the same now and ICQ number is the same as an AOL screen name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kind of you you can route to one through the other with some with some black magics and things.
Speaker 0: It's not really black magic.
Speaker 0: if you have an AOL client and you add a number that happens to be an ICQ number It just adds the person.
Speaker 0: does it really work?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Wow and vice versa.
Speaker 1: I guess that's when they develop the Oscar which goes between right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, that was also the big thing.
Speaker 0: that AOL was screen name based.
Speaker 0: your screen name was unique.
Speaker 0: No matter what.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm ICQ.
Speaker 0: you had a serial number and Your.
Speaker 0: you could pick whatever name you wanted.
Speaker 0: So there could be a million rims out there.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Each rim had a different serial number and different user information.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I remember I had a. we had a five digit ICQ number that me and my brother shared.
Speaker 0: and the sad story is That later I got my own one and he got my own one and mine was one five.
Speaker 0: Oh three six one one, too Which is significantly longer than that awesome five digit number as was his.
Speaker 0: and then one day we saw on eBay The people were selling five and six digit numbers for a decent sum of money.
Speaker 0: And we remembered that we did not in fact know the password anymore and that the email account it had been pegged to was long Since gone sorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the account is dead.
Speaker 0: It's still out there.
Speaker 0: It's under the name.
Speaker 0: God I remember I could cry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my old ICQ number was nine three five seven two seven seven six.
Speaker 0: Wow, it's funny how we still remember him.
Speaker 1: Well, actually the that wasn't my old ICQ number.
Speaker 1: That was the one that I got because you do you freeze to use aim for a while?
Speaker 1: But yeah what I had before that as long as I could the one I had before that was was the same length and digits But it began with one and that was like years earlier.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, but now it doesn't matter just connect everything.
Speaker 0: yeah and Basically for us at least the wave of the future is Jabber.
Speaker 1: Well Jabber has been around for a long time but now because aim seems to be crumbling a little bit and You know this big flux and I am networks everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, basically aims crumbling and there's no good alternative.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like what can you use?
Speaker 1: MSN is poop Yahoo is boo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't like the Yahoo clients and the Yahoo Network's kind of funky.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everything is kind of poop and You know if you want I am to stick around and not fill up with all this kind of junk that happens on it.
Speaker 1: Jabber seems to be the way to go and Google's semi supporting it.
Speaker 0: So Now I best to describe Jabber because if you're technical at all You probably know how Jabber works at least on some level.
Speaker 0: but to describe it in an entirely non-technical way with Jabber It's like email in that anyone can run a Jabber server anywhere.
Speaker 0: We're running one on the front row crew comm servers right now for us.
Speaker 1: No, don't tell them then Why not?
Speaker 1: They'll try to sign up to it then restrict it.
Speaker 0: I did great But basically we're running run now and anyone can run one.
Speaker 0: You can run run on your PC if you want tunnel the ports to the router whatever and Your name in Jabber is just whatever you want at like an email address Your server's address
Speaker 1: and if you don't want to set up a server I think Jabber org has a free server that anyone can
Speaker 0: use.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's dozens of free Jabber servers out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you get Google Talk, it's basically just Jabber except it's whatever you want at gtalk Comm?
Speaker 0: I think yep, and there's a good chance that eventually gtalk Jabber for Google is going to open up.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure, but I think I read something where they opened it up.
Speaker 1: But even if they didn't it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: But the key thing is that everyone runs their own servers and the servers all talk to each other.
Speaker 0: So there's no big bad company with its crazy EULA's in the way to bring things down or censor you or log Whatever you're saying or whatever evil they could do.
Speaker 1: and it's also free completely free.
Speaker 0: free as in speech and as in beer.
Speaker 1: yep, and The way it works is so wide open in turn.
Speaker 1: You know like if you want to write a program that does something to aim You have to do all sorts of reverse engineering to figure out how aim works and all sorts of BS and Jabber It's just XML.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all it does is send plain XML over a standard TCP IP connection.
Speaker 0: So if you want to write programs that do awesome things with Jabber It's real easy like you could set it up where you could make your computer run a Jabber user And you could like ask it questions that would Google and get answers for you.
Speaker 1: Oh, you can make all kinds of crazy, or you could set it up.
Speaker 0: So if you taught you send a certain thing to it your Jabber guy It'll call someone's cell phone and leave a voicemail on it.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm almost anything Anything a computer can do.
Speaker 1: you basically can make it so that computer programs can talk to you via Jabber Or talk to each other via Jabber or that you can talk to computer programs via Jabber and tell them what to do.
Speaker 0: I always wanted to make a bot that would look through all.
Speaker 0: I think someone else has this idea too and they were talking to me about it.
Speaker 0: that would look through all my logs of conversations I've had with people and Basically be a non interested rim bot.
Speaker 0: so I could set that on people.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk to it them.
Speaker 1: I think someone already made that.
Speaker 0: yeah, I should get it and see if it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Jabber Also has other features like priority setting.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: So say like a lot of people will have either one AOL account And they log into it all over the place which causes all sorts of hell Mm-hmm or they'll have a bunch of AOL like I have my name.
Speaker 0: then I have my secret name name that only a few people know and I use that one at work or when I'm on the road and It's kind of a pain in the ass to have two different names.
Speaker 0: Jabber you just had a priority so Messages will always go to the highest priority client.
Speaker 0: That's all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can do whatever you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you set a resource and a priority.
Speaker 1: so let's say I log in on my desktop I call the resource desktop, and I set a priority of I don't know zero.
Speaker 1: then I go To my laptop and I sign in and I set the resource to laptop and I said the priority to five.
Speaker 1: Now if someone sends a message to me at me calm whatever I am It'll go to the laptop because it has a higher priority.
Speaker 0: But if the laptop logs off it'll go to his main one instead.
Speaker 1: yep now Let's say someone sends a message to me at me calm slash desktop.
Speaker 1: They can specifically say they want it to go to my desktop computer and not to my laptop where I am now.
Speaker 1: And they can say different status messages for different places.
Speaker 1: I could be like I'm away at my laptop, but I'm do not disturb on my desktop, and I'm here on my telephone.
Speaker 0: Also handy-dandy many ways of encrypting things and It is really great jabber is like zombocom.
Speaker 1: It can do anything.
Speaker 1: you can do anything Anything anything is possible, but the problem with jabber is That the only way to make things in jabber work is to use a proper jabber client.
Speaker 0: gee aim I love you, but why don't you support the freaking priorities in jabber?
Speaker 0: It's an integer.
Speaker 1: It doesn't support any of the features of jabber except talking to people.
Speaker 1: jabber has this mountain.
Speaker 0: You can set your resource name.
Speaker 1: You can set your resource name.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: It doesn't support any of the other important jabber features.
Speaker 0: takes me off because other than that gee aim is beautiful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look GM supports more features in the closed and secret AOL than in the wide open public jabber protocol.
Speaker 1: come on.
Speaker 1: But anyway if you use psi or Exodus or any of the other real jabber clients You can do all the things that jabber does But you don't need to.
Speaker 0: I mean if you aren't a power user And you're just using your regular AOL name and you just have one and you just kind of use it.
Speaker 0: however if you just use Gee aim or a trillion to connect to jabber you'll be just fine.
Speaker 0: You don't worry about all that.
Speaker 1: you just message people back and forth.
Speaker 1: It's like normal.
Speaker 0: Yep I also like the fact that my name is now exactly what I want.
Speaker 0: I'm rim at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm all me as opposed to shazar 105 Or one five oh three six one one two.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that that's really cool.
Speaker 1: So a lot of people don't realize there's this.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you want to call it controversy.
Speaker 0: Yeah disconnect schism, right?
Speaker 1: basically, what it is is every nerd in the world is intelligent.
Speaker 1: that's what makes the nerds.
Speaker 1: and When they type a message into their instant messenger, they want to send the message.
Speaker 1: They don't push enter.
Speaker 1: enter goes to the next line.
Speaker 1: You know if they want to send the message they push control and enter at the same time.
Speaker 0: Well, basically where this started was ICQ.
Speaker 0: by default was a text box and a send button and you typed your text and you had enter just made a new line.
Speaker 0: And when you were done typing your message, you either clicked on send or the shortcut control enter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now because that was ICQ wasn't really supposed to be a conversation.
Speaker 1: You were actually sort of typing a semi email.
Speaker 1: So pushing enter to go to a new line made a lot more sense because they thought you're gonna write something big.
Speaker 0: So when I first switched to aim, I'd freaking send half messages to people left and right.
Speaker 0: It's me off to no end Yep.
Speaker 1: Now the thing is when you want to send a message Control enter is the only way that makes sense.
Speaker 1: Because how else can you make a new line if you said enter to send the message?
Speaker 1: How do you send a message that is multiple lines long?
Speaker 0: You can set it so control enter.
Speaker 1: it makes a carriage return but that makes no sense either.
Speaker 1: How can you type like that?
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of a good typing.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say.
Speaker 0: there's definitely a post hoc Proctor Hawk situation here.
Speaker 0: But in AOL enter sent the message and the way AOL was.
Speaker 0: it seems that people sent very short messages.
Speaker 0: people would type a single sentence a single sentence and the single sentences would fly back and forth.
Speaker 0: and I've noticed that in AOL back in the day.
Speaker 0: and now people would type.
Speaker 0: if they wanted to type a multi sentence message They type each sentence and send them one at a time.
Speaker 0: So you'll send someone three or four messages before they respond to you in ICQ.
Speaker 0: I remember very specifically.
Speaker 0: I would send like a paragraph to someone and then a minute later.
Speaker 0: They'd send a paragraph back to me.
Speaker 1: well, I think the reason I usually I usually send one sentence at a time when I'm gonna say a bunch of stuff is because Aim only has a certain limit of characters.
Speaker 1: You can send in one message.
Speaker 0: Yes ICQ is message limit was much greater.
Speaker 1: I don't think jabber has a limit.
Speaker 1: I had to go check.
Speaker 0: I found that it does at least through GA because when I send you a large message it automatically splits it into two or three.
Speaker 1: That might be GM.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or it might be our jabber server.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's the jabbers.
Speaker 1: I'll go check it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because sending large messages, you know, especially Sometimes you're having a conversation, but sometimes you're you're sending someone something That's not quite an email and not quite an.
Speaker 1: I am like you're sending them a link and a description of it.
Speaker 0: You're giving someone driving directions to somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like go left go right go left go right, you know, you type that, you know, whatever I mean I guess that the interesting thing I've noticed is that it used to be that instant messaging was definite was a lossy kind of.
Speaker 0: you know, you just talk to people whenever an email was like the the communication of record.
Speaker 0: Now to me email is lossy and I don't trust email to get anywhere and I don't trust that anyone gets an email I send.
Speaker 1: Well, I trust that they'll get the email.
Speaker 1: the thing is I don't trust if they'll actually go and read it and email is sort Of like sending a letter.
Speaker 1: It's like this old-fashioned thing and I am is what used to communicate with people.
Speaker 0: I mean, honestly, I leave my computer on 24/7 all the time.
Speaker 0: my I am is always on and it's always been on since 1996 when I first got ICQ and I would just use it like email and like instant messaging all rolled into one.
Speaker 1: Yep, I be I'm logged into aim or jabber most of the time during the day and night, you know sometimes it goes off a little bit maybe when I'm on my way to work or something, but Eventually, I'll have a cell phone that can log into jabber in some way and I'll be all set.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can log into aim on my cell phone.
Speaker 0: It's just not worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean well the blackberry can do it But it really sucks because what it does is convert every message into an email which is terrible on the blackberry interface, right?
Speaker 1: You know, I'm think I can pay money for a real client Which I might do someday in the future if the client is quality enough, but we'll see.
Speaker 0: Well at any rate, I think we've talked enough about that for now since we've got a good half-hour just on this Mm-hmm, but I think we're gonna do another show on this sometime.
Speaker 0: I think we'd like to cover the kind of culture of instant messaging.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the smile all the smiley faces and crap you see today and where they came from and honestly There are different dialects of smiley and it's kind of interesting to see.
Speaker 0: like like to the types of smiley is the different types Of people tend to use.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that'll be another show.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.