Speaker 1: It's Tuesday October 3rd, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about Capcom classics mini-mix and Def Con.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So today I did something that I haven't done for a long time.
Speaker 0: Maybe if you're real good about myself.
Speaker 0: I'm a big man.
Speaker 0: now I killed Hitler again.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Hitler was dead before you were born.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: and kept.
Speaker 0: commander kilft brought him back and then He killed the guy after busting out of some lightning and then I shot him in the face after he said damn you So you didn't go to work?
Speaker 1: You went to Germany instead.
Speaker 0: see well I beat a game that I love.
Speaker 0: I beat bionic commando again.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh now unlike other times.
Speaker 0: I've beaten it.
Speaker 0: I beat it in a straight shot on a non emulated fully legitimate.
Speaker 1: No possible way to cheat medium, but so wait when you were a kid you never beat it on the NES.
Speaker 0: Oh, I did, but I didn't beat it that quickly.
Speaker 0: Aha, I mean usually I'd save up.
Speaker 0: my nine continues And then I'd spend like six of them on the last two stages.
Speaker 0: Falling in the fire over and over and over and over again.
Speaker 1: That's a good strategy.
Speaker 1: Falling in the fire sure way to win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if I keep stacking up the bodies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if I had Megaman 2 on a on a cartridge for the GBA or the DS I would beat it just as easily.
Speaker 1: so yeah, there's some games.
Speaker 1: You just you know you never fail to beat him.
Speaker 0: once you know once you're the master I wonder we had to look up how long those games are cuz.
Speaker 0: that's something stupid.
Speaker 0: we could do with a con Megaman 2 vs.
Speaker 0: Bionic commando.
Speaker 0: who beats it first?
Speaker 1: yeah races, and you know single-player platformers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially if you're playing two different games that happen to have similar lengths or something crazy like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this actually reminds me of something.
Speaker 1: is that a long time ago?
Speaker 1: You may not know.
Speaker 1: But the Megaman games for the NES and the SNES and whatever are different from the Megaman games of the Gameboy.
Speaker 0: You don't say.
Speaker 1: yeah, Megaman 2 and 3 for the Gameboy and other.
Speaker 1: there are other Gameboy Megaman's are not.
Speaker 1: it's the same as Megaman 2 and Megaman 3 for the NES.
Speaker 1: They're different games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not they have some of the same bosses, but they're different games mostly.
Speaker 0: yeah It's not just different like oh, they're in olive and brown instead of color.
Speaker 0: They're actually different games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Capcom you know they released Megaman mix which is you know Megaman anniversary edition Which all the Megaman's then they had a Megaman X which had all the Megaman X's But they haven't released the supposedly going to be released Megaman Gameboy mix.
Speaker 0: well Scott Why haven't they released this wonderful gem that we've been waiting for for all these years?
Speaker 1: well a long time ago Some talking about you know they lost code or something like that.
Speaker 1: and yeah Whatever the thing is is hey couldn't they just get the cartridge?
Speaker 1: cuz I mean I've seen cartridges around.
Speaker 1: They're not you know super common, but they exist.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure there's one at the GameStop or the EB or whatever across the river Yeah, and just rip the ROM out of it and put it on a Gameboy advanced cartridge with an emulator.
Speaker 0: You know what I'll bet.
Speaker 0: the answer to that is simply that that's probably the most rational Intelligent and expedient way to solve this problem, so of course no one would do it.
Speaker 1: I just want to point out the Capcom released Capcom classics mini mix for the GVA.
Speaker 1: that has three games in it, and they haven't released the Megaman mix Games three games.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is how many games not five Five is right out.
Speaker 0: But before we move on to the you know news the video game news.
Speaker 0: since it is video game day I would like to say do the thing I've been doing for the last two weeks And it'll end at the end of this week.
Speaker 0: We are going to be this weekend October 6th 7th and 8th in Utica, New York for Citacon S I T a con.
Speaker 0: it is an anime and gaming convention that mostly anime mostly anime But there's gonna be pretty much 24/7 gaming video gaming mostly, but some also a little bit of role-playing gaming Yeah, also the fact that we're going to be bringing some German gaming.
Speaker 0: We are definitely going to be breaking out some gaming of the geek night's fashion, so if you live anywhere within about 400 miles of Utica, New York I highly recommend you come because regardless of this convention Which is a first-run convention it could be hit or miss.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm not gonna pretend that is it's automatically gonna be awesome because I don't know I'm optimistic.
Speaker 0: I think it'll be a good con, but I can guarantee 100% you got the front row crew backing this up.
Speaker 0: there will be awesome to be had At this con.
Speaker 1: wait a minute.
Speaker 1: how much of the front row crew is backing this up?
Speaker 1: you and me and that's it.
Speaker 1: well We're pretty much everyone else copped out and they want to go.
Speaker 0: the whole crew bailed on us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what the hell guys?
Speaker 1: What the hell to their convention right there?
Speaker 1: And you all bailed to their credit.
Speaker 0: one of the people who is not coming is not coming because a relative died.
Speaker 0: Another one is getting some rather horrible dental surgery.
Speaker 0: No one else could get off work and some people live in, Texas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but I'm just saying that you know They could have come on Saturday for free.
Speaker 1: What it is.
Speaker 0: Well, they'd have to drive there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's relatively free.
Speaker 1: Come.
Speaker 1: a compared compared to what you're gonna get out of this convention, you know as to what it cost to get there.
Speaker 1: Come on, come on.
Speaker 0: I mean that I don't think you guys understand just how much we're gonna be pulling at this con.
Speaker 0: I mean if you have never been around us and seen the kind of hijinks we pull whenever social order breaks down I think that we are besides the con chair himself.
Speaker 1: We are doing more at this convention than anyone else.
Speaker 0: I mean in addition to the events, we're running sanctioned.
Speaker 0: You will not understand the magnitude of the unsanctioned events We're gonna be running at this car.
Speaker 1: I mean at the bare minimum We're gonna be in the artists alley making an evil ruckus at bare minimum.
Speaker 1: But as soon as got artists alley closes watch us bust out crazy games.
Speaker 1: Watch us bust into the gaming room and set up impromptu video game tournaments.
Speaker 1: Watch us run around yelling and screaming and grabbing people and making mischief.
Speaker 0: Yep Plus while the front row crew is gonna be there We're gonna have Dave and Joel from fast karate for the gentlemen, my favorite rust hurricane related podcast.
Speaker 0: I gotta stop making these rust hurricane jokes.
Speaker 1: I know but they can't.
Speaker 0: Turcane what's?
Speaker 0: uh, what's Megaman week against?
Speaker 0: Ross hurricane Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah No, he's kind of equally weak.
Speaker 0: you can't defend against ten Ross hurricanes, okay, there we go Though also as a total aside before we get into the actual video game stuff.
Speaker 0: to all the people out there kind of question You know, hey if you guys ever seen homestar runner, the answer is yes We are well aware of home star runner.
Speaker 0: great chair up there We uh slice we were watching them home star runners back when there were only ten strong bad emails.
Speaker 0: home style Home star.
Speaker 1: my favorite character home star is by far the best character cuz he is indeed.
Speaker 0: All I'd like to say is that while home star is awesome It played itself out for us.
Speaker 0: I'll pretty much four years ago.
Speaker 1: Oh the crap All right, let's get crazy good nuts.
Speaker 0: Okay with the video game news.
Speaker 0: We'll start with Scott cuz.
Speaker 0: my name isn't actually video game related at all.
Speaker 0: You suck.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so last year Activision made a study about video game advertising and everyone said hey Activision sponsored that study.
Speaker 1: We can't trust it.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: You might remember Activision from such classic hits as pitfall river raid mech warrior 2 Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so two decades ago.
Speaker 0: They were a great game company.
Speaker 1: Well, they're a game publisher and they publish some good games and they publish some bad games.
Speaker 1: and what do you want?
Speaker 1: I can't recall the fact that they've stuck around since the Atari days and they're still here is pretty impressed.
Speaker 1: You know why?
Speaker 0: because there are people who buy games like BMX xxx.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess that is the reason people like activists can continue to exist.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fine You know.
Speaker 1: at least you got to respect the fact that you know.
Speaker 1: A company like Atari is now just like a part of another company that gets bought and sold and traded around Activism Spanish hall Activision is still its own company owned by no one at least.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure they are.
Speaker 0: So yeah, our listeners will probably correct us.
Speaker 1: if Scott is wrong I'm pretty sure that they're just their own game publisher owned by no one.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, they put out a study about game advertising and no one trusted it.
Speaker 1: So now com score media metrics Confirms the earlier findings.
Speaker 0: I still think that you study That's a really funny name for a for a place that does study.
Speaker 1: all the companies that do studies have names like that.
Speaker 0: here's the thing is a lot of the ones that have the really long names like that are more or less study for hire and I'm real dubious.
Speaker 0: If anything they do.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the study says and this is the reason I believe it is because the numbers make sense Is that heavy gamers people who play at least 16 hours of video games a week?
Speaker 0: There's probably a joke about heavy gamers and fat game.
Speaker 1: Yeah something they were the most receptive to in-game advertising.
Speaker 1: By most receptive they mean that 37% only 37% of heavy gamers agreed that the inclusion of ads makes games more realistic and in terms of light and medium gamers only 27% of them agreed that advertising makes games more realistic which means that 63% of hardcore gamers and 73% of hardcore gamers do not agree that Realistic, you know ads make games more realistic.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 0: I got a question about this up.
Speaker 0: Why did they need a study?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's Common fucking sense.
Speaker 1: Well, you know when they first.
Speaker 1: the topic of in-game Advertising has been pretty hot in the past six months to a year or so and when it first came up I thought you know ads in games aren't necessarily bad when they match the real world.
Speaker 1: I mean it makes a lot.
Speaker 1: it really takes you out of a game.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you need to drive down a highway in a game and the billboard says like, you know bake Oh something something and make up some phony product name.
Speaker 1: That's so phony.
Speaker 1: you just sticks out like a sore thumb and kind of ruins the you know, the atmosphere Yeah, and I gotta say even in movies.
Speaker 0: I always hated it when someone was drinking, you know Unlabeled soda because Pepsi and Coke wouldn't let him use the logo, but at the same time, you know all that BS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly what I'm talking about, you know, I mean sometimes a guy drinks a dr.
Speaker 1: Pepper let him pick his dr.
Speaker 1: Pepper.
Speaker 1: Yeah and there have been a lot of games in the past that have had in-game advertising like Ninja Turtles 2 had all those Pizza Hot ads.
Speaker 1: but those Pizza Hot ads made sense because well the Ninja Turtles ate pizza and They were just billboards on the wall in the game.
Speaker 1: They didn't stick out like sore thumbs.
Speaker 1: They didn't ruin the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if I'm playing Grand Theft Auto and there's real billboards, I'd have no problem with that.
Speaker 1: In fact, I just uncovered the Ninja Turtles 2 arcade version for the NES.
Speaker 1: Oh Instruction book recently.
Speaker 1: on the back of it is a coupon for a free personal pan pizza that expired in 1991 1991.
Speaker 1: I think in 2011 20 years after that coupon expired I'm gonna go to a Pizza Hut and try to use the coupon with some sort of hidden HD camera And if YouTube still exists, we're gonna YouTube that at business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we should just use it now while we still can.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah now the problem I have with the study is that they really.
Speaker 0: I mean It seems like they just asked if you let like ads in games or not.
Speaker 0: But I mean it.
Speaker 0: the context of the ad and the way the ad is used matters a lot more Than any other issue at stake here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also the article goes on to talk about how Actually, this advertising generates a grand total of one to two dollars of profit per title sold Mmm, now they also make the point.
Speaker 1: if you compare that to the number of people who aren't gonna buy the game because of ads You're probably gonna end up losing money not making money.
Speaker 0: Well, they also point out if that's all it makes why not have an advertising version and then a non advertising version for a dollar fifty more?
Speaker 0: Hey, see which one people buying up.
Speaker 0: Maybe it didn't need the advertising one at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I think that you know.
Speaker 1: The problem here is that if people put ads in games that were tasteful and correct No one would even notice or complain.
Speaker 1: Maybe some you know blog would notice and write a thing about it and most people would go and like if you went into a Bar in a game and the neon signs said bud Coors and Miller.
Speaker 1: No one would you know it?
Speaker 1: that's how bars look.
Speaker 1: That's how every bar in the country is like that.
Speaker 1: You know, that's just fine.
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 0: All right counterpoint.
Speaker 0: not not that I agree with this, but here's why One all these companies and in general, this is a big problem with IP law that I think should be rectified.
Speaker 0: I am of the mind that if you create an advertisement That is shown publicly and published that it should be able to be used in any medium by anyone for any purpose.
Speaker 0: Because now you have a situation where a company has you know, they're advertising copy out there billboard something.
Speaker 0: But if you're filming a movie and that billboard is in that movie the or that guy's drinking that kind of soda.
Speaker 0: You can't do that.
Speaker 0: The company usually won't let you do it without permission.
Speaker 0: So instead in whenever you're gonna have a product placement, you know They say drink a can of soda instead of just having it be whatever kind of soda they had in the fridge.
Speaker 0: They have to go and you know say Pepsi Will you pay us to let your product be featured and it ends up being a product placement instead of just a product that happened To be used.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but regardless of what's going on behind the scenes, you know It's all about when you're playing a video game.
Speaker 1: You want to stay immersed.
Speaker 1: You don't want to be taken out of the game Just like when you're watching a movie.
Speaker 1: you want to be taken into the movie, you know We're like.
Speaker 1: you don't even see the people sitting in front of you like, you know the.
Speaker 1: the movie takes up your whole brain, you know, your full attention is in it.
Speaker 1: and that's where you are.
Speaker 1: and You know a fake product can sometimes take you out of that.
Speaker 1: but so can you know the obtrusive placement of a real product?
Speaker 1: It has to be toned down.
Speaker 1: Realistic placements of real products or you know, usually tone down places are to keep you immersed, you know, yeah I mean good.
Speaker 0: I'm playing counter-strike.
Speaker 0: There's a sprite machine bad.
Speaker 0: There's an ad for World of Warcraft and blazoned on the wall in the middle of the.
Speaker 1: that's exactly what I was gonna say.
Speaker 1: Is that you know?
Speaker 1: If there was proper in-game advertising, I wouldn't give a shit because I wouldn't even notice it.
Speaker 1: But there's a lot of all the in-game advertising that's going on now seems to be bullshit.
Speaker 1: For example, I was playing planetside a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Remember I complained about it and whatever.
Speaker 1: in the ready rooms in planetside I think probably because I was playing for free and not paying any money There were these giant castrol GTX ads on the walls.
Speaker 0: That's just silly.
Speaker 1: It is just silly has no place in that world where they probably don't even need oil and definitely don't need castrol GTX.
Speaker 1: And why would they pull me?
Speaker 0: a gamer could make that argument?
Speaker 1: I know but Why are there giant ads for the product when you can't even choose products in the game?
Speaker 1: The ads are in the teleportation rooms.
Speaker 1: I mean, come on.
Speaker 0: I think part of the reason should
Speaker 1: they at least be in the vehicle Bay
Speaker 0: when it comes to realistic games Would be simply that if the ads in a generally realistic game are in
Speaker 1: the same
Speaker 0: manner and placement of ads in the real World people would ignore them because people ignore ads in the real world.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because a lot of the ads in video games are scooby-doo-ified where they stick out, you know You'll have all these really high-resolution textures and then you'll have this JPEG That's really just slapped on on a wall somewhere.
Speaker 0: I mean worse is like a bright color.
Speaker 1: the lighting doesn't affect it.
Speaker 1: You know your bullet marks don't appear on it.
Speaker 0: It's you know, of course if the bullet marks appeared I would be drawing penises in bullet on every ad I saw.
Speaker 1: You know your flamethrower doesn't burn it.
Speaker 1: It has to act like everything else in the game.
Speaker 1: It can't be scooby-doo or else it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: However, the advertisers usually won't go for that because they don't want their you know logo to be defiled in any way.
Speaker 1: They want full total control and they're only making one $2 per copy of the game.
Speaker 0: So so why is it even an issue?
Speaker 0: why even bother?
Speaker 1: why I have this study?
Speaker 0: Because they were trying to sell the viability of advertising in their games to advertisers that they could make money.
Speaker 0: Yeah See, everyone always forgets that the advertiser.
Speaker 0: It's not the kind of industry you think You are the product being sold by the person who makes the thing to the advertisers.
Speaker 0: You're selling your eyes to the advertisers.
Speaker 0: You're the commodity.
Speaker 0: They are the customer.
Speaker 0: so they're not trying to please you in this sense.
Speaker 0: They're trying to please the advertiser Regardless of what you actually do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they've already got your eyeballs, you know that they're trying to collect your eyeballs.
Speaker 1: They got ice cream scoops.
Speaker 1: They pluck them out of your head and then they sell them to somebody.
Speaker 0: You know, I saw a movie once where someone did that.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, they took someone's eye out with a teaspoon and then they took their other eye out with the teaspoon.
Speaker 0: and it happened in Russia.
Speaker 0: No idea they already dead.
Speaker 1: no Okay, enough of that.
Speaker 1: I was in my news.
Speaker 1: What's your news my news?
Speaker 0: I was in like fifth grade.
Speaker 0: I don't remember anything about the news.
Speaker 0: If any remembers a movie in Russia where a guy gets his eyeballs scooped out with a teaspoon.
Speaker 1: What's rooms news?
Speaker 0: Why you don't like the eyeball scooping?
Speaker 1: Not really?
Speaker 0: No All right, my news will be quick because I don't want to get into too much depth about this.
Speaker 0: But New Jersey has had some problems lately, you know, they're in debt because the government is.
Speaker 1: when does New Jersey not have problems?
Speaker 0: Actually, you know people you have Jersey a bad rap.
Speaker 0: But once you get past, you know The Newark Jersey City like the area right next to New York.
Speaker 0: the rest of Jersey's not like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know the problem.
Speaker 1: The only good thing I can say about New Jersey is that it has boardwalks It has a six flags and it has more comic book stores per square foot than any other state.
Speaker 0: No, no, they got cheap gas - all right cheap gas.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it's full serve only so that kind of balances out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I still don't get full serve.
Speaker 0: I mean I see why Jersey does it but I don't like other people pumping my gas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, me either I mean I just kind of.
Speaker 0: in fact, I accidentally today I went to get gas down in the Bronx, right?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I pull into the gas station and the gas is like 235 a gallon.
Speaker 0: All right I'm like hot dams.
Speaker 0: I pull in and I start to get out and the guy points up and it says full and I look Around and I realize the whole thing is full service.
Speaker 0: Huh and it was weird because it was not New Jersey, yeah, you could.
Speaker 1: there there are full services outside of New Jersey.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: That's the first one I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: I've never had full service outside of New Jersey in my life usually in Connecticut at least You know, most of the gas pumps are like you go to a gas station and one of them will say full and the rest Say so.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you know those old people will go up to the full.
Speaker 0: see where I grew up.
Speaker 0: You know in sterling heights in Detroit.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know in Rochester in RIT right next to RIT at that coastal.
Speaker 1: That was all also the mechanic.
Speaker 1: You know that place?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was a full service only gas station.
Speaker 0: I never went there.
Speaker 1: I know I never went there for gas.
Speaker 1: I went there for my kids.
Speaker 0: It was more expensive I know.
Speaker 0: well, no, it's actually cheaper usually but it wasn't cheaper than the place up Scottsville Road a bit.
Speaker 0: Anyway, no one cares about that No one cares, but where I grew up every service station had the full service sign But no one actually had full service.
Speaker 0: those signs were just legacy.
Speaker 0: if you pulled up and sat there No one would do anything.
Speaker 0: They just stare at you Yeah, which every now and then would happen when some out of stator was driving around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway now New Jersey has decided that the best way to get rid of their four point five billion dollar debt Not spend four point five billion dollars on crap.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is they've already spent it.
Speaker 0: They can't undo it.
Speaker 0: It's not a deficit.
Speaker 0: It's a debt.
Speaker 1: get taxes from people.
Speaker 1: All right, New Jersey has very high property taxes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's some of the highest in the country and as a result, they have some of the best schools in the country.
Speaker 1: Yeah and take the money that you don't have to spend on crap and pay off your debt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then the government shuts down.
Speaker 0: Now here's the thing.
Speaker 0: They're the way they're handling this aside from writing a billion parking and speeding tickets everywhere.
Speaker 0: So watch out if you're traveling in Jersey.
Speaker 0: But they've decided to one raise the sales tax to seven percent and more importantly Expand the things that sales tax covers.
Speaker 0: now you have to pay sales tax on health club memberships security alarms tanning storage space and iTunes music store downloads.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: all those other things I can understand perfectly And I don't know why people weren't paying sales tax on those things before.
Speaker 1: but iTunes music store downloads now one Apple Probably.
Speaker 0: I don't know the deal but they I'll bet they want nothing to do with this.
Speaker 1: No, they got nothing to do with
Speaker 0: it, which means that the way Jersey is going to have to enforce this is that you'll have to declare your iTunes music downloads on your tax forms as like a use tax or something and They'll get you if you don't pay it.
Speaker 1: Nah, I just pay the minimum because I'm a wuss.
Speaker 0: now Yeah, I pay them.
Speaker 0: Of course the minimum for my income is like a couple bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Plus I didn't buy so much online last year.
Speaker 1: It's really so.
Speaker 1: eventually someone's gonna have to fix this problem.
Speaker 1: Perhaps I think with a federal law because there's a lot of state border crossings going on here with the Internet's That you know finally seals the deal on how we pay sales tax on things online.
Speaker 0: You know if I buy a bunch of stuff on you realize that if you go to a different County and buy something.
Speaker 0: Technically you have to pay a use tax because you would have paid the piddly point whatever percent sales tax from the county you lived In.
Speaker 0: yeah, but because you left the county you lived in and went to another county to buy something You're somehow ripping off your County.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're not gonna talk about tax law.
Speaker 1: No, we're not.
Speaker 1: but I'm just saying someone has to fix it.
Speaker 1: Sometimes is a problem that's going to eventually jump up and bite everyone in the ass when we're thinking about these more important things.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like after we saw this terrorism bullshit and this DRM and freedom bullshit and Those days are behind us and it's that and it's good times again.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be the problem that comes up next.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean just generally tax sales tax law and use tax enforcement in general because use tax was never enforced Until state started running out of money and then suddenly they started trying to enforce it, but it's impossible to enforce.
Speaker 0: So instead of enforcing it, right and having you actually pay it They make you pay a minimum penalty and that way you're basically paying the extortions.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's a penalty.
Speaker 0: It's basically you pay an amount of money in order to be protected from having to pay what you actually owe Even though you probably owe less than that minimum.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just too much effort to figure it out.
Speaker 0: Here's my other issue about this because we could do a whole show about this stupid thing.
Speaker 0: Now you buy something from iTunes, right?
Speaker 0: It's a DRM file.
Speaker 0: Now do you really own it?
Speaker 0: What did you just purchase?
Speaker 0: Are you purchasing a license to listen to that music?
Speaker 0: Are you purchasing the music itself?
Speaker 0: Are you purchasing the file?
Speaker 0: How is this going to be taxed?
Speaker 0: What if I give it to someone else?
Speaker 0: do I what if I sell it to someone else?
Speaker 0: What if I trade it with someone else?
Speaker 0: if you start taxing this shit?
Speaker 0: There are so many ramifications that I'm sure John Corzine has never even heard of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean he's probably trying to jam his envelope into a tube speaking of which I was gonna use it as news But it's not much to say about it.
Speaker 1: But today is day against DRM.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah DRM bad Yep so Fire.
Speaker 1: but I guess since you know today is already over because most people listen to this the day after as opposed to at night Like they should be listening to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz everyone, you know is gonna listen to our podcast at 11 o'clock at night.
Speaker 1: Hey in some parts of the world.
Speaker 1: It is 11 o'clock a.m.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Hey to all of our overseas listeners, especially Australia You are probably the most represented overseas place.
Speaker 0: We have yep.
Speaker 0: So and I urge all of you to fly out here and hang out with us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you think that your country is has more people listening to us than Australia does then go to frapper Our frapper map and put your stuff there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to see a battle.
Speaker 0: I want to see if the Australians are really on top or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yes, if it's true if Australians are the biggest non-us listener base we have I'll buy a bottle of Foster's and break it for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, yeah today's anti DRM day day against DRM.
Speaker 1: do something against DRM.
Speaker 0: I pirated some music.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you go to defective by design dot org You'll see all the things people have done today or yesterday depending on what day you listen.
Speaker 0: things of the day things of the day.
Speaker 0: Okay Yeah, I've been fiddling around with music as you could tell from the last several episodes.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm thinking of changing up a lot Of the music in season two of geek nights If you have an opinion on that?
Speaker 0: hit the forums, let us know.
Speaker 1: if you are good at making music Try to make music but we want something jazzy kind of like the same kind of music we got now only different Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway, my thing of the day actually lets me tell a story from way back.
Speaker 0: This was either 19 like maybe seven or 58.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was 1998.
Speaker 0: Might have been early 1999, but I think it was late.
Speaker 0: 1998 was in high school had my car.
Speaker 0: Me Ken and Dan, you know the core of our D&D group went to my first LAN party in Southfield, Michigan.
Speaker 0: We crammed my Pentium 200 and their computers into my car.
Speaker 0: The car is so small.
Speaker 0: Dan had to sit with a 17 inch CRT on his lap for an hour while we drove.
Speaker 0: No I had a cell phone with me because my parents were worried something would happen because I'd never driven somewhere like that before.
Speaker 0: I mean I barely had my license.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I had this brick of a cell phone that had to be plugged into the car to use.
Speaker 0: and we go to this LAN party and It was the first time.
Speaker 0: I mean I had a ping of like one and I was playing action quake on a LAN.
Speaker 0: It was crazy.
Speaker 0: Like that was.
Speaker 0: that was amazing.
Speaker 0: I couldn't believe how awesome it was to play LAN games on a LAN Like I couldn't.
Speaker 0: also we pirated everything.
Speaker 0: everyone copied every program they had every music file they had and we all swapped.
Speaker 0: It's what LAN parties were except this one guy who didn't have a big enough hard drive and couldn't get it all.
Speaker 1: See if I was going to a LAN party today like that giant ones they have in Sweden Norway and shit.
Speaker 1: You know where this like giant giant convention halls.
Speaker 1: It's full of computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, were you like stake out a spot and live there for a few days?
Speaker 1: You can go online and look at pictures of these things.
Speaker 1: if I was going to one of those places I would buy a 300 gigabyte hard drive and bring it with me.
Speaker 1: hell I might buy a NAS and bring it with me and it's perfectly empty.
Speaker 1: I would format it with it like an XFS partition and fill it up as the week as you know the LAN party could progressed.
Speaker 0: so my first LAN party and Towards the end of it, you know, it's winding down.
Speaker 0: It's about four in the morning and I'm pretty much totally knocked up on jolt Cola after playing a whole bunch of action quake and weapons factory and Then they decide all right is movie time because one guy had this projector and he was playing quake on the projector Which also blew my mind back then because projectors are common now.
Speaker 0: They were not common in the late 90s.
Speaker 0: a Projector you could plug into your computer was this crazy expensive amazing thing.
Speaker 1: It was the guys probably a rich He was.
Speaker 0: he funded the LAN party.
Speaker 0: We had to pay some pittance to get in And also while we played the big games the projector showed the score the whole time.
Speaker 1: But HLTV is the awesome.
Speaker 1: A lot of people don't know about HLTV.
Speaker 1: That wasn't HLTV I know but I'm not gonna talk about it now.
Speaker 0: Okay, but that wasn't HLTV.
Speaker 0: I know I know that was quick, too.
Speaker 1: I was just reminded of the existence of HLTV, which is awesome.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right, so we're there and it's movie time So they're all talking.
Speaker 0: What should we watch?
Speaker 0: Let's watch father Frank's best.
Speaker 0: Whoo And none of us have any idea what the hell this guy's talking about.
Speaker 0: Then he starts up quick too and he loads a mod and the mod Wasn't a game mod.
Speaker 0: It was a mod that basically played out a sitcom called father frags best within quake 2. it was the first encounter I ever had with machinima.
Speaker 1: machinima.
Speaker 0: machinima is the idea of taking games and Doing and using the games to create content like using quake 2 the engine of quake 2 to film a movie.
Speaker 0: hmm, and Don't bother reading the Wikipedia on this if you are more interested in it because the Wikipedia article is kind of dubious and full of crap.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll rewrite it someday, but this is one of the earliest Well-known machinimas out there.
Speaker 0: So you remember Scott's thing of the day yesterday the urinal thing that was machinima - what the Sims?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Sims in Sim City and whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or like there's a very very popular one - uh, you know Avenue Q The internet is for porn - World of Warcraft and is red versus blue with halo and whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep Yep, that is all machinima.
Speaker 0: And this is one of the earliest earliest Items of this.
Speaker 1: Yeah is one of the first machinimas.
Speaker 0: I'll warn you it's funny if you're a hardcore gamer and even then not so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: it was back in the day.
Speaker 1: It was hilarious because things like this didn't exist.
Speaker 1: So You shouldn't watch this expecting to be laughing hysterically because unless you're super old-school, yeah, it's like that Hiyama, Kaga juichi thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not that good.
Speaker 1: It's more that it's like all your base are belong to us.
Speaker 1: It's not funny anymore history lesson.
Speaker 0: It's a museum exhibit exact watching.
Speaker 0: This is seeing a piece of internet history.
Speaker 0: Yep, however, if you need Quake 2 to play it because I looked and I didn't see any video mirrors of it.
Speaker 0: So you basically have to install Quake 2 which is free And then install this mod and then run the mod And then this thing will play out including outtakes at the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is worth watching it is.
Speaker 1: All right, so College humor calm has this new awesome video called Street Fighter the later years.
Speaker 1: now It's actually really well done and awesome.
Speaker 1: Like you think it's just gonna be corny, but it looks like you know.
Speaker 1: If it was any better, it could be put in a real movie theater.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Scott says oh there's a Street Fighter 2 thing on College humor and I think what whatever?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it starts out with these two kids playing Street Fighter in an arcade.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like Chun Li versus I know it's Zangief versus Dalsin.
Speaker 0: Oh Dalsin.
Speaker 0: Was it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it was.
Speaker 0: I think at that fight It might have been Chun Li.
Speaker 1: No, anyway, so one guy's Zangief and he's like man.
Speaker 1: if this are real I could totally kick your ass.
Speaker 1: He's like what if you were you or if you were a Zangief?
Speaker 1: He's like no if I was Zangief right in the background.
Speaker 1: now you see this janitor with a kind of looks like Zangief.
Speaker 1: He starts crying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially when the one kids like Zangief's a bitch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know, I'm not gonna tell you where it goes from there because what's the point of watching this?
Speaker 1: But it's really well done.
Speaker 1: It's really hilarious and there's gonna be more parts, which I can't wait for.
Speaker 0: This is what the Street Fighter movies should have been.
Speaker 1: I think about this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was a Street Fighter movie a live-action one in the United States With Van Damme and it was ass.
Speaker 1: It's famous for being ass.
Speaker 1: I saw it in the theater.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Yeah, fuck's wrong with you.
Speaker 1: Oh, what do I know?
Speaker 0: It was such a movie.
Speaker 1: I knew everyone knew it was ass.
Speaker 1: It was ass.
Speaker 0: as you like Jean-Claude Van Damme you watch fucking Bloodsport and that's it kickboxer.
Speaker 1: But no Bloodsport, whatever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, some fucking kids on College Humor have made a better movie and it's only they only did five minutes.
Speaker 0: If the rest of its like this though hot damn now, we're not saying better than Street Fighter 2 the anime.
Speaker 1: No, no, we're saying better than Street Fighter 2 the American live-action movie.
Speaker 0: If this was a trailer for an actual movie, I would see it on opening night.
Speaker 1: I would bootleg it and watch it before opening night.
Speaker 1: And then oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah wait lines.
Speaker 0: I believe that part is unstated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so go and watch this.
Speaker 1: if you know anything about Street Fighter at all This will be funny.
Speaker 1: If you don't know anything about Street Fighter, it's not gonna be as funny But you'll still see how well done it is.
Speaker 0: So on to the main bit.
Speaker 0: we're gonna go back to the original format of gaming day.
Speaker 0: Meaning.
Speaker 0: Scott and I are each going to review a separate game kind of anime world order style.
Speaker 0: Holy crap I don't know.
Speaker 1: This is some kind of crazy trend Mmm, or maybe because we both just got into new games or maybe it's because we just have so much stuff to cover that we can't possibly cover it at the rate of one thing per Week.
Speaker 0: or maybe the fact that I'm not gonna talk much about my thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that could be it too Alright, so I've been waiting for this pretty much since I heard it was coming out and I bought it as soon as was reasonably possible the Capcom classics mini-mix.
Speaker 0: It's a Game Boy Advance cartridge that has three Awesome classic games from the NES days, but rim only cares about one of those games.
Speaker 0: Yes effectively I paid $20 which is less than I paid when the fucking game came out for bionic commando aka Hitler no Fukkatsu.
Speaker 1: Hitler no Fukkatsu.
Speaker 0: now this game is Famous for one being one of the most innovative platformers in the history of early gaming.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I mean this is it looks like a normal platformer guy gun gun shoots But here's the.
Speaker 0: here's the gimmick guy can't jump at all.
Speaker 1: He's a white man in.
Speaker 0: Instead you've got this bionic arm and you can grab things and swing around and the game is mostly Acrobatics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much it's all about shooting the bionic arm in the correct direction with the correct timing.
Speaker 1: And that is how you move around in this game and the levels are complex And if you can't manipulate that bionic arm properly, you're not gonna make it very far.
Speaker 1: Did I give enough innuendo with a bionic arm, I think you did okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was gonna make a joke about in the right direction.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right timing Yeah Manipulating the bionic arm.
Speaker 0: Okay Now if you've never played this game.
Speaker 0: find an M or ROM or something and play or no.
Speaker 1: go buy Capcom classics mini mix.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll get to that.
Speaker 0: Okay, but this game is Absolutely fantastic as in it's one of my favorite games ever.
Speaker 0: Not gonna talk.
Speaker 0: I'll do a separate show about bionic commando Because we can talk all about Hitler.
Speaker 0: No, that's not the point here because it also comes with Strider an equally Classic Nintendo game.
Speaker 1: Strider is classic.
Speaker 1: however it is the opinion of me and most other people that I have encountered that the Sega Genesis version of Strider is the real Strider and the NES version is kind of a.
Speaker 0: I have not really played either To an extent to where I could make a judgment.
Speaker 0: Yes, the game is pretty typically early NES game Strider.
Speaker 1: the character is Strider here you who's a very famous character because of these games but you know He you'll often see him in like all the voting for like best video game characters and so and he has.
Speaker 1: he's basically like a super pretty shonen boy who?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the plot is something like there's lots of fancy swords and our friend Kane has been kidnapped.
Speaker 1: Kill him, yeah Lots of fancy jumps and sword slashes while killing robots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it probably make a better anime than a game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a pretty good platformer.
Speaker 1: Basically just as good as bionic commando except for the lack of innovative bionic arm manipulation.
Speaker 0: I would say no because the controls in Strider are a lot looser than bionic commando.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they are loose But I mean bionic commando is one of the tightest games out there.
Speaker 1: But in terms of being a platforming game where you whack stuff and it blows up It's it's kind of it's in the same vein.
Speaker 1: They weren't wrong to put it on the same cartridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course the third game on here is mighty final fight now, which is one of the greatest final fights.
Speaker 0: I want to say right now in case any of you aren't really up on Japanese sensibilities.
Speaker 0: But final fight were some fairly violent walk down the street and beat people up game.
Speaker 1: Yes They're pretty much in those days.
Speaker 1: There were two series of walk down the street beat people up games.
Speaker 1: There was Final fight and Streets of Rage.
Speaker 1: streets of rage is for the Genesis and stuff and final fight was for the NES and SNES.
Speaker 0: Yep, I played final fight in the arcade a lot and I only ever played as Haggar.
Speaker 1: Yeah streets of rage.
Speaker 1: I actually think the series overall was better.
Speaker 1: But any if you're talking about an individual game of walk down the street beat people up River City Ransom.
Speaker 0: But besides that final fight 3 I think for the SNES that had the really hot anyway anyway to not get off track Adding mighty do final fight does not make them larger or stronger.
Speaker 0: It makes them super deformed and funny.
Speaker 1: That's what mighty final fight is all about.
Speaker 0: mighty Final final fight is a romp.
Speaker 0: you walk to the right Jump kicking people in the face until they die and you repeat it until you've killed everyone.
Speaker 1: That's what that game is.
Speaker 0: now I'm not gonna review the three games because they're classic games.
Speaker 0: I mean, what am I gonna say?
Speaker 0: I could review them all separately in other shows years from now.
Speaker 0: But the actual GBA cartridge is very high quality as in it is 100% faithful to the three games.
Speaker 0: you can't save your game, which is the only thing I actually would complain about.
Speaker 0: You can't glitch you can't cheat.
Speaker 0: You can't do anything.
Speaker 0: Basically, you start the ROM.
Speaker 0: it is identical to how it was on the Nintendo right down to the slowdowns and the glitches Except for the aspect ratio because you're on a GBA screen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yes screen the aspect ratio has changed slightly.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Nothing else has changed.
Speaker 0: all the same cheat codes work all the same glitches work.
Speaker 0: The games are 100% faithful to the originals Which is a little annoying in the fact that you can't save your game or suspend or anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they can be a little annoying.
Speaker 1: you expect those sorts of nice tees and you know remakes or re-releases of very old games.
Speaker 0: Of course, it's only 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: GBA game brand new three games.
Speaker 0: I'd especially recommend it.
Speaker 0: if you've never played bionic commando I mean that game god damn.
Speaker 0: Now I wanted to get through that real quick because the more interesting game to talk about today is the game Scott's been playing.
Speaker 0: That I will be playing as soon as I have the ability to do so.
Speaker 1: Yes now I don't know.
Speaker 1: I hope you've seen the movie war games.
Speaker 1: if you haven't seen the movie war games What?
Speaker 1: what the fuck's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: What kind of what kind of geek are you?
Speaker 1: You know what everyone's seen this movie and you have to see.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like to play a game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of like a requirement.
Speaker 1: How about a nice game of chess?
Speaker 1: It's a really classic movie and in the movie.
Speaker 1: There's a computer whatever and At the end the computer is playing this game.
Speaker 1: What's the name of the game?
Speaker 1: It's like global Nuclear war nuclear war.
Speaker 0: now aside from the fact that the game the movie war games Made hacker culture known to the masses.
Speaker 0: that was the the Inspiration for almost all of the computer geeks out there currently.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much I mean the movie showed war dialing right away.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the game thermonuclear war global thermonuclear war show it was basically a map of the world That was like an outline of a map of the world and it had little pictures of missiles with lines behind them showing the trajectories of the ICB M's and the event of a global thermonuclear war.
Speaker 1: And it would show up US would get totally blowed up in Russia would get totally blowed up, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean this is you know in movies like I don't know.
Speaker 0: It was in the Cold War era like Doctor Strange Love one of those the big board where you see, you know Here's what the people actually doing all the big decisions are seeing and the nuclear war blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: This is made by introversion software the people who brought you uplink and Darwinian I believe in uplink.
Speaker 0: There's an easter egg where you can play global thermonuclear war.
Speaker 1: Is there?
Speaker 1: I don't know if there is.
Speaker 0: I read that in multiple places.
Speaker 0: Okay, I didn't play uplink enough to find it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was never.
Speaker 1: I wasn't good enough at uplink to get anywhere.
Speaker 1: really I could do a few missions and then I was stuck.
Speaker 1: But the point is that this company is pretty much my hope for PC gaming.
Speaker 1: They are the only people making innovative new PC games and they seem to specialize in taking The way things appear in movies and making them real.
Speaker 1: like uplink is Basically a game where you hack.
Speaker 1: you hack the same way that people in movies hack not the way people hack in real life.
Speaker 0: Yeah you know images of people flying by while you're looking for the file and you see like the red line of the tracer program that's Tracking you down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's also a very good game uplink, but Def Con is their new game, which is super cheap.
Speaker 1: I mean this thing is $15 on Steam for the full version $15.
Speaker 1: in November, there's gonna be a Linux version.
Speaker 1: You can get like you could just download the game.
Speaker 1: you can download the demo.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's 1750 to download it from the Def Con site.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's 1750 for the non steam version.
Speaker 1: So get if you if you have steam.
Speaker 1: if you got a steam account, I recommend you use the steam one.
Speaker 1: Yep, but This is essentially what you know.
Speaker 1: The big war map in the war room is like in a movie only a game.
Speaker 0: I just picture, you know But I deny them my essence.
Speaker 0: Yeah The game's creepy as fuck.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty creepy game I gotta say because you know while the strategy and the play of the game is pretty typical for what you know A very clever RTS that you know doesn't have the same problems every other RTS.
Speaker 1: It has this eerie kind of music and you are Nuking the hell out of the whole world and you're getting nuked and it's you know, you hear sometimes it's like really faint screaming I think and but
Speaker 0: it's so understated like it's because it's all just kind of this like not really.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like what the president of the United States at Least in the movies would be watching as this war went down and the DC got nuked.
Speaker 0: Well, he's obviously in like looking glass or something Obviously, but you know be like you.
Speaker 0: you click like you click on Tokyo and you just you know Launch ICBM and then you'd like you'll see later like in Russia like launch detected launch detected meaning that they're launching ICBMs and you don't know what's going on.
Speaker 0: and then you know You see your little trajectory and it hits Tokyo and it just there's a white flash not even a flash.
Speaker 0: Just a white thing appears and it just says, you know Four million dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it says like in big square letters like Tokyo 4.1 million dead.
Speaker 0: and that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually I love how the game is scarred.
Speaker 0: You were scarred in the number of people you kill.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you kill people you get points and you get killed you lose points.
Speaker 0: Default scoring as other scoring methods unit score is effectively mega deaths.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but The game is labeled the world's first.
Speaker 1: genocide them up, which is pretty hilarious.
Speaker 0: I say But well, isn't the website I like?
Speaker 0: kill them all?
Speaker 0: dot-com?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the interesting thing about everybody dies everybody - dies.
Speaker 1: calm.
Speaker 1: The reason that this game is so awesome to play is because it's an RTS that doesn't have problems of other RTS.
Speaker 1: Is you know how?
Speaker 1: if you play Warcraft 3 it's essentially a game of who knows what order to build the units in.
Speaker 1: you know who can click the fastest to build the units the fastest and You know who can build a whole bunch of one unit and send them off to destroy the other guys base.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's who figured out the click sequence that makes one more tank than the other guy to win the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah now in DEFCON is not how it works.
Speaker 1: Everyone gets pretty much the same amount of stuff depending on which territory you pick and all that.
Speaker 1: but you start with stuff And that's what you get.
Speaker 1: You don't get any more than that.
Speaker 1: You're never gonna get more nukes or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You get what you get.
Speaker 1: you deploy it and you spend it the rest of the game Utilizing it and then it's over now.
Speaker 1: The game starts at DEFCON one.
Speaker 1: You then have a few minutes before DEFCON 2, DEFCON 3, DEFCON etc.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, you start game start DEFCON 5 and counts down to one.
Speaker 1: So in DEFCON 5 that's when you're deploying stuff.
Speaker 1: now You can set the speed of the game.
Speaker 1: The lowest speed is real time where one second in the game is one second in real life.
Speaker 0: Now the Wikipedia claims that people play it in full real time and they spend most of the time diplomacying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if they do that they're crazy because it takes three hours to play that game if you do it in real time.
Speaker 0: Well, it says here they can take up to eight hours.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: That's even crazy Yeah, but the point is is that I most people don't play the game in real time.
Speaker 1: At least I haven't ever played in real time all the way through.
Speaker 1: you generally play at a sped up level.
Speaker 1: Now the way the speed works is you choose a speed one, two, three or four and in a multiplayer game It goes at the lowest speed voted.
Speaker 1: So let's say everyone wants to go at max speed but rim wants to go at real time.
Speaker 1: it goes at real time.
Speaker 1: So rim puts it in a real time does whatever he wants to do and then speeds it up again when he's done Managing whatever he wanted to manage, you know, and I think that's a pretty good system.
Speaker 1: actually You know, but so the game goes in DEFCON 5 to 1 and in the early DEFCON's you're building stuff And then there's a boat fight and then does the nuke fight?
Speaker 0: Yep, like pretty much DEFCON 5 and 4 are essentially the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah only it doesn't matter It's just DEFCON 4 is sort of like DEFCON 3 is coming up and DEFCON 3 is when the boats fight.
Speaker 0: Yep, conventional warfare is authorized.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the The boat fight is pretty much where the game is decided.
Speaker 1: I've noticed because if your boats survive to the to the later levels They will be able to prevent a lot of nukes from hitting you and they will also be able to deliver a lot of nukes.
Speaker 1: So if you put all your boats in an ocean and win that ocean You can now have a serious advantage In terms of nukes going over that ocean, you know.
Speaker 1: And then the game goes on some more and then the ICBMs go and woo.
Speaker 1: There's just nukes everywhere and it's all about defending from the nukes and sending the nukes so that they destroy the other guy.
Speaker 0: I really want to stress how eerie it is.
Speaker 0: I mean even watching this game is a very eerie experience.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's just the theme the music generally and how it looks and it's it's really.
Speaker 0: They get the point across and yet at the same time there seems to be enough strategic depth and fun to make the game Incredibly interesting.
Speaker 1: there is.
Speaker 1: so it's really strategic.
Speaker 1: like this stuff I couldn't even begin to think about like you have these the missile silos.
Speaker 1: Here's an example the missile silos.
Speaker 1: when they're not shooting missiles.
Speaker 1: They are defending from missiles.
Speaker 1: so and if you decide to fire a Missile everyone now knows that there's a silo there because they can detect launches.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like giving up your position when you fire but you're also giving up your position at when you put your defenses down and There's all sorts of other stuff like that.
Speaker 1: It just in this radar and there's submarines and there's airplanes and it's that it's out of control But it's actually.
Speaker 1: there's not too many things to manage in the game.
Speaker 1: I mean you only have three kinds of buildings and three kinds of boats and that's it It's.
Speaker 1: it is barely anything to manage and if you do the tutorial and you pay attention You'll pretty much be the master of doing everything in the game, but you won't have a strategy that wins at all.
Speaker 1: You know, and let's see.
Speaker 1: I played this game against the CPU a bunch of times and I played online Four times and the fourth time was a game with a lot of people and I did Okay, but when I played the one-on-one games, I won all three of them.
Speaker 1: You know the one complaint I have about the game is it's hard to get a game together Like you'll go online to join a server and the guy will drop out.
Speaker 0: This isn't a complaint against the game just the complaint against people playing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you'll join you'll play against a guy.
Speaker 1: He won't know what he's doing.
Speaker 1: He'll quit you'll see a server You'll try to connect to it and it won't work.
Speaker 1: You have to quit and try another server.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's generally just sort of a pain to get a game going.
Speaker 1: once the game is going with a reliable players You're okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seems like you really got to play with reliable people who are dedicated to at least one full game.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think what the ideal a situation is to find your friends and play against them and screw the people on the internet because you Can't realize playing against your friends.
Speaker 0: one aspect of the game is that you can form alliances which are even in the game.
Speaker 0: It lets you share rate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can play with anywhere from two to six people.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I played a game that was three on three.
Speaker 1: It was three people versus three people, you know, and the Alliance is set up for the beginning and unchanged.
Speaker 1: But you know, that's that's not the point.
Speaker 1: but it could play a game of six, you know six individual players and You make alliances and break alliances in the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's an actual game mechanic.
Speaker 0: But the thing is while you can do all the alliances you want There is no such thing as an allied victory.
Speaker 0: So in the end the Alliance will end in a traitor because it has to yep It's it.
Speaker 1: only one person wins and that's whoever gets the most kills.
Speaker 0: so I could see spending like four hours Playing this game with all your friends with the full-on Negotiating with each other like Scott we could.
Speaker 0: we have to gang up and take out cops.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because he's a he's a renegade and that that East Asian co prosperity sphere can't stand to be there any longer.
Speaker 1: There are lots and lots of advanced play options But I haven't even begun to explore them yet because I'm still not done with the regular play option yet.
Speaker 0: so I guess in closing check this game out and Probably in a month or two once more people have played it and we've played it a lot.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about it again.
Speaker 0: Maybe a sort of final thoughts once we figured it out.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a demo of the game that I urge everyone to get even if you're not gonna.
Speaker 1: I mean this thing runs at a Pentium 600 megahertz processor.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It doesn't run it with a GeForce to Linux.
Speaker 1: It will in November in November.
Speaker 1: There's a Linux version They'll be.
Speaker 1: so don't worry about that.
Speaker 1: It's another introversion.
Speaker 1: software is very good about supporting Linux But the demo version.
Speaker 1: the biggest caveat of the demo version is that in a multiplayer game?
Speaker 1: Only one player can be a demo player.
Speaker 1: So if you get the demo and your friend gets to the demo You can't play against each other.
Speaker 1: It doesn't work But you can play against me because I bought the game Just two of your friends who have the demo and me couldn't play together because there's more than one demo player.
Speaker 1: Did I get that across?
Speaker 0: I think you got it across.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's.
Speaker 1: I think that's a pretty clever way to Differentiate the demo from the full version.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, sorry Def Con is an awesome game.
Speaker 1: If you haven't seen war games, you need to go see that movie ASAP and And Download this game.
Speaker 0: and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at two oh six three three three one five three seven Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.