Speaker 1: It's Tuesday December 5th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight having finally rejoined the ranks of regular role players with the new D&D campaign We talked a bit about our experiences.
Speaker 1: coming back to the old game Let's do this Hot damn, I actually kind of did some work today.
Speaker 1: That's unbelievable as in work That wasn't just paperwork or BS or whatever.
Speaker 1: I put I set up about a hundred thousand dollars worth of 48 port switches.
Speaker 0: I read a book today, but not the whole book about half the book.
Speaker 1: and what book?
Speaker 0: the second lensman book.
Speaker 1: Now you're still reading those.
Speaker 0: I see I only read the first one.
Speaker 0: before that I you know read comics and now I'm back to reading the second one.
Speaker 0: So anyway tomorrow I might actually do work cuz someone's coming to the office.
Speaker 1: Holy crap What are they gonna be doing there?
Speaker 1: They there for you or they just there?
Speaker 1: they're just there permanently No, so what are they there for?
Speaker 0: it's like the CEO and you know since it's holiday season He doesn't go into the city or whatever.
Speaker 0: So he's just gonna be coming.
Speaker 0: Yes to make like a conference call She's gonna come in and use the phone.
Speaker 1: Well, you should be dressed really nice and look like no not really now.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: because it's not necessary.
Speaker 1: Maybe you should schmooze a little bit.
Speaker 0: You realize the last time this guy showed up at the office.
Speaker 1: He was in his pajamas All right, then forget that we still schmooze.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I make nice.
Speaker 0: Make sure I don't go.
Speaker 0: Hey fuck quad go away.
Speaker 1: Make sure the DDR pad is invisible.
Speaker 0: Yeah It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: No one.
Speaker 0: People have been there before while it's been sitting out.
Speaker 1: They don't ask They're like the fuck is this?
Speaker 0: Well, it's leaning up against the wall when I'm not using it.
Speaker 0: So they don't really notice it.
Speaker 1: They probably don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: I don't know whatever.
Speaker 1: I remember trying when I worked at IBM trying to explain to people what DDR was.
Speaker 0: Well, it's funny.
Speaker 0: you should say that because my thing of the day is DDR related.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, really Well, we'll have to get to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we will but first we haven't done this in a while.
Speaker 1: But I'd like to do a geek back.
Speaker 1: We got some.
Speaker 1: oh shit I mean we get a lot of email.
Speaker 1: and to all of you who email us.
Speaker 1: Yes, we read your emails.
Speaker 1: We don't read them on the show because I'm sorry, but most of them are uninteresting or just saying something like hey You guys are awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm reading this one for a particular reason that may become apparent in short order.
Speaker 1: All right Hey guys I recently downloaded all the episodes of your podcast geek nights and I wanted to tell you that it is awesome.
Speaker 1: Exclamation point.
Speaker 0: you're correct.
Speaker 1: You guys are hilarious and take away the boredom of my classes in my high school.
Speaker 0: Maybe you shouldn't be listening during class.
Speaker 1: I was about to say good job listening to stuff in class.
Speaker 1: You probably wouldn't be learning anything there anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know how well is the punctuation and spelling and grammar of the email?
Speaker 1: It's mostly impeccable other than in the post script Which I just noticed.
Speaker 1: the post script is an all lowercase, but everything else is pretty good.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: Well, don't listen in English class, maybe a few times.
Speaker 1: Yeah You see at least you know.
Speaker 1: back when we were in high school There really weren't mp3 players or portable gaming devices that weren't gigantic.
Speaker 0: Well, there was a Discman.
Speaker 0: was the best you could do?
Speaker 0: Yeah But they were still kind of big and you couldn't be too surreptitious man or a Gameboy color I think and that was like senior year of high school.
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh Gameboy Pocket actually was you could do.
Speaker 0: that was the best you could possibly get.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but now I could sit there with a Gameboy micro and an iPod Nano.
Speaker 0: Hell.
Speaker 0: you can sit there with an iPod shuffle and some wireless like in-ear earbuds Right Bluetooth or some shit or you could have like a cell phone set on vibrate with a2dp Bluetooth stereo earbuds and yeah, yeah damn anyway you continue.
Speaker 1: so whenever I'm bored I just pop in earbud up.
Speaker 1: There we go Should have said an earbud from my iPod and turn on geek nights.
Speaker 1: Keep up the great work guys.
Speaker 1: Cheers.
Speaker 1: Oh, by the way, just for the fun of it Can you spelled with a lowercase.
Speaker 1: you guys mentioned my name on the upcoming podcast?
Speaker 1: I don't know about what but maybe just say hey this guy wanted to be mentioned on the podcast.
Speaker 1: So here you go.
Speaker 1: I would appreciate it.
Speaker 1: It would be really cool.
Speaker 1: exclamation point.
Speaker 1: Thanks.
Speaker 0: Oh, all right now You see why we don't do geek back so much.
Speaker 0: but Seriously, we like to get lots of emails and we like to get odios and all those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: You know, it seems like a lot of other podcasts even ones that have fewer listeners than we do get a lot more feedback.
Speaker 0: That doesn't?
Speaker 0: that's not really true.
Speaker 0: What's true is they just read the feedback on the air and thus Provoke more feedback.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I mean when we did geek backs every day, we got probably double the email Yeah, and I'll basically tell you this most of the email we get if you don't ask a question or something.
Speaker 1: We read it.
Speaker 1: we appreciate it, but we're not gonna respond cuz what do you say to a declaratory statement?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you send us an email and go you're awesome.
Speaker 0: What am I gonna?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Thanks, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah And most of the people who ask us questions we tend to just email them back because it's usually something that really wouldn't be Appropriate on the show.
Speaker 1: I mean no one cares where.
Speaker 0: if we tell some guy what anime they should watch some night Yeah, but we like to get more emails So don't hesitate to communicate with us or send us voicemails or whatever just because it won't be heard on the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, however, if you want to be heard on the show your best bet is to send us an audio Yep, which we get none of.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean we got audio feedback a long time ago but we haven't in a while and I wonder why cuz I've seen that a Lot of podcasts don't get so much audio feedback and I wonder if people are just nervous about doing it or don't know how.
Speaker 0: I think it's the once we if we play It's like we had to get a few and then we have to play them and then that provokes more P. It's sort of like this, you know tidal wave kind of thing.
Speaker 0: So we just need a few that we can play and then once you play some everyone else will go.
Speaker 1: Ooh, I got it in their own will start asking for things like we'll ask a question some Monday and then the next Monday We'll play a relevant way.
Speaker 1: We could do this.
Speaker 0: This sounds like a good idea.
Speaker 0: We could start some sort of new segment, right?
Speaker 0: Where we Put up like a question or a topic and you have to send in like a voicemail with a very short response.
Speaker 0: Relatively we don't want like 20-minute diatribes here, right?
Speaker 0: This is not your show.
Speaker 0: And then we'll play like you can't do 10 diatribe.
Speaker 0: We'll play the good ones and maybe we'll respond.
Speaker 0: a little pun them if they're stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I guess I'll ask right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, you got a question.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a question.
Speaker 0: I didn't even start thinking one yet.
Speaker 1: Why don't you guys send us audio feedback?
Speaker 1: All right, I'll simplify it.
Speaker 1: whoever sends us it has to be less than 10 seconds, I'll put a constraint on here 30 seconds 30 seconds, whoever sends us the funniest bit of audio that you created on your own It'll be played on the show.
Speaker 0: We'll give you mad props and we won't bleep out your name Alright, so for those of you who don't know how the wiimote works it uses Bluetooth.
Speaker 0: so that means that any and all data that goes between the wiimote and the we is Bluetooth.
Speaker 1: yeah now a lot of people think that the sensor bar does something and we talked about this before but it's really just a Dumb piece of equipment with LEDs in it.
Speaker 0: Yep So all that really matters is the wiimote and well a lot of other things besides the.
Speaker 0: we use Bluetooth.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not like the wave bird that uses some proprietary wireless protocol or the DS where it uses Wi-Fi But it's all encrypted.
Speaker 0: so you can't do anything about it.
Speaker 0: You know, this is hey, there's a potential.
Speaker 0: we can use this with a computer.
Speaker 1: So since we have or even like a Palm Pilot since we have the we sitting there right next to our Mac The first thing we thought about a day after we got the we was huh?
Speaker 1: These are Bluetooth, right and we tried to use them with the Mac and it showed up.
Speaker 0: The Mac said I see a Bluetooth device there and Scott went.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is gonna be great.
Speaker 0: But then what I didn't think I was gonna get much further and I was right when I actually tried to use it I was unsuccessful, you know the.
Speaker 0: even though the Mac recognized it as a Bluetooth device It did not a handle it at all.
Speaker 0: But however people have figured out how it works mostly and they've written drivers for Windows and Mac and You can now use your remotes with your Windows and Macintosh computers.
Speaker 0: Probably Linux computers real soon.
Speaker 1: now Don't think that this is super awesome yet.
Speaker 0: It's not super awesome yet because they have learned how to get data from the accelerometers So they can tell when you tilt your remote in any direction and they have learned how to get data from the button so you can push the different buttons except for the power button, of course and The computer will know when you push the buttons.
Speaker 0: the computer is not yet.
Speaker 0: they have not yet figured out how to get the driver to understand the Sensor bar pointing device functionality.
Speaker 0: So without that I mean, it's not really a good mouse Which is what you want to use it for?
Speaker 0: is a mouse for a TV computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's I mean it.
Speaker 1: once they get this working I'm sure someone will though.
Speaker 1: frankly I think it would be an interesting idea if after this remote and nunchuck shortage is over, you know sometime next year if Nintendo got some developers and released official drivers for their remotes to be used on computers as generic peripherals.
Speaker 0: See, I don't know if it's really necessary though for them to do that because oh no no No, it would just generate a lot of good press.
Speaker 0: I mean it it's it takes a lot of effort for them to do something like that You know and Nintendo hates to do stuff for computers because computers are not a homogeneous platform.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: Well, I see the one reason they might not want to is that if people start pirating Wii games And they can use the remote on the computer
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean of that if people already have their own homemade drivers to use the remote on a computer that covers 99% of the market for that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Well, then you know what you do.
Speaker 1: you uh Make the people who are currently developing these on their own Call them like official and give them the data to do it But don't pay them anything and then when they finish it release it under your name.
Speaker 0: Yeah, considering it's it's already gotten so far.
Speaker 0: It's not really necessary Yeah, but I'm sure the people that rather have them work more on getting out more Wii channels and virtual console games.
Speaker 1: Well, you've seen all the the rumors and various grumblings on the internet that everything we care about is gonna be live by Christmas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, supposedly.
Speaker 0: I also.
Speaker 0: there was a magazine that had a blurb that was like OMG something is coming to the virtual console That's gonna change everything.
Speaker 0: Holy crap.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine what that would be.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I got ideas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you read the actual blurb, you know, you could get a hint that it's probably Earthbound or something like that, but who knows?
Speaker 0: anyway I've linked to the page with the Macintosh Darwin Darwin remote Driver and program for you to use.
Speaker 0: if you have a Mac and if you have a Windows you can find it on your own.
Speaker 0: Eventually, this will hopefully support pointing and then it will be awesome.
Speaker 1: So natural selection a mod for half-life has got to be one of the Most innovative and greatest first-person shooters of the modern era.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably I mean, it's a little old hat.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Technology is old.
Speaker 1: the mod is old.
Speaker 1: It doesn't look very shiny compared to anything new coming out doesn't have a lot of players anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though the people still plan are very dedicated.
Speaker 0: They're awesome.
Speaker 1: I mean in its heyday It was one of the big greats of gaming.
Speaker 1: it still very few games have come to even close in my eyes To replicating or even matching the sheer level of fun and amazingness That was.
Speaker 0: natural selection and natural selection is a half-life 1 mod that didn't come out until like right before Half-life 2 came out.
Speaker 0: It was like half-life 1 was almost dead half-life 2 was coming soon and here comes a brand new Half-life 1 mod that knocks your socks off.
Speaker 0: It's like what the hell?
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean once it came out and was stable it exploded in popularity.
Speaker 1: Now natural selection 2 for the half-life 2, you know source engine has been in the works for a long time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've had some issues with that.
Speaker 0: They keep changing what their plans are and you know all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: They even made a sudoku game and they sold it in order to make money to develop natural selection - but they are working On it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the good news is that not only they're still working on it But they seem to have kept sight of the true vision of what NS is.
Speaker 1: a lot of times when people make a mod like action quake was a really good thing and then they tried to make action quake like the next version for Quake 3 and it just kind of was crap.
Speaker 1: weapons factory at the same thing weapons factory for quake 2 was awesome.
Speaker 1: They tried to make a new version.
Speaker 1: They got all the right things wrong.
Speaker 1: No, they got all the wrong things right and the right things wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah That kind of makes sense.
Speaker 1: Natural selection the team behind it unknown worlds entertainment really seemed to know what made natural selection good.
Speaker 0: What's that guy's name?
Speaker 0: Flaira, isn't that the head guy?
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: He's one of them.
Speaker 1: He's awesome Yeah But they really like.
Speaker 1: they the things they would change and the things they would work on.
Speaker 1: They knew what the people playing natural selection wanted and more importantly They knew what they really wanted because a lot of times fan communities will ask for things that they think they want but they don't really and if the developer listens to them you get the tribes to Situation where they take one of the best games ever made and run it straight into the fucking ground.
Speaker 0: Here's a good example, right in in tribes two people wanted.
Speaker 0: they wanted like to automatically get in the vehicles and other crap like that and They wanted what was that other stupid thing?
Speaker 1: Oh god I forget.
Speaker 0: they wanted to like Change some weapon or something and they did and it totally ruined the game and changed everything, you know Meanwhile in natural selection, what are those little guys that you had in the early versions?
Speaker 0: that you the know?
Speaker 0: the creatures the babblers The babblers in the early versions of natural selection.
Speaker 0: One of the alien abilities is these babblers and they were hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yes, they were one of my favorite things in NS.
Speaker 1: basically you could spawn little tiny aliens that were kind of like skulks that would run off and attack Marines but They weren't that bright and they were kind of buggy.
Speaker 1: and there were situations where you'd send off a babbler It would get stuck in you and then kill you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or it would attack your own hive until it killed it.
Speaker 0: Yep, you know and everybody took the babblers out of the game and everyone said oh man bring back the babblers.
Speaker 0: Babblers and people today's probably still talk about the babblers that used to be a natural selection.
Speaker 0: But they even though a lot of people say they want them back These guys know that they really don't make a good game and they've kept them out.
Speaker 1: Yep Now recently that they've really have opened their kimono in their own core their own words to release one of the cool things They're working on as part of natural selection - they call it dynamic Infestation.
Speaker 1: now in natural selection you know areas of the map that were near hive locations or areas where the aliens tended to start or be powerful through.
Speaker 1: much of a game had a very Alien esque vibe to them.
Speaker 1: there was organic shit growing all over the walls and weird sounds and weird plants and like throbbing pulsing Geiger looking kind of things all over the place and that kind of tapered off as you got to the more civilized areas where the Marines would start.
Speaker 1: Now this was entirely static.
Speaker 1: no matter who was winning no matter what was going on nothing changed other than you know A hive appearing or a gorge building an offense tower somewhere.
Speaker 1: in natural selection - they've come up with a method of having this infestation kind of grow organically and naturally procedurally in real time While the game is progressing based on how well the aliens are doing how widespread they are What areas they occupy and possibly what buildings they have built?
Speaker 0: Wow, so if the Marines take over the whole map and the game's over there isn't gonna be any yellow alien gunk around?
Speaker 0: most likely Yeah.
Speaker 0: And if the aliens like start encroaching on like a new area of the map like yellow shit will start growing everywhere and go blurbity blurbity Blurbity blurbity.
Speaker 1: now they haven't figured out.
Speaker 1: I mean they figured out how to do it and It's if you've read the article is really kind of cool.
Speaker 1: They talk a lot about it But they haven't figured out exactly how to use it yet because one it adds a lot of nice ambience to the game And I think it'd be really cool on its own.
Speaker 1: But I can also see this having significant gameplay factors.
Speaker 1: They haven't said anything but I imagine maybe like skulks or lurks are a little camouflaged in alien infested areas Or maybe the more infested an area is the more resistant aliens are to damage.
Speaker 0: Well, they did say.
Speaker 0: one gameplay factor was that you know Let's say you have a room with some computers in it or something right and the infestation Room then like the computers that get all infested and stop working and like the lights will go out in that room and then if The Marines come and clean it up then you know The computers will start working again and the lights will turn back on and shit like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the possibilities are endless and I am all about this.
Speaker 1: and one astute person on dig made a quote.
Speaker 1: I'll paraphrase if Dynamic infestation can somehow be fought with flamethrowers.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going to wet myself.
Speaker 0: That sounds good to me.
Speaker 1: I want to see a flamethrower.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: and as doesn't really have a flamethrower yet The flamethrower is a key weapon in alien aliens alien three, etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 1: Well, I could see them.
Speaker 1: using it like a flamethrower would probably be good against infestation and gorgeous and structures and be absolutely useless against anything else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think oh no Fade is gonna be phased by flame.
Speaker 1: You can't kill 10 fade.
Speaker 1: Oh Man I'm having natural selection flashbacks because Scott and I would always play in the same room next to each other sometimes on the same team sometimes not.
Speaker 1: it didn't matter because we never really cheated or anything, but I Remember there would be times where I'd be walking around my little machine gun and Scott be walking around somewhere else and suddenly he yells Fade fuck and then he dies and then I go oh then I die.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, Oh knows Things of the day.
Speaker 1: You can't have think 10 10 things of the day.
Speaker 0: we've had like 200 400 something things of the dance.
Speaker 1: We can't have 10.
Speaker 1: All right, then more than 10 is just as not 10 is less than 10 is I suppose that's technically correct?
Speaker 1: Anyway, my thing of the day now when I was a kid, but play video games.
Speaker 1: I would often be Fascinated by glitches or bonus areas or strange things or busted stuff in video games like in Castlevania.
Speaker 1: one time Castlevania 2 my favorite Castlevania game with the possible exception of Castlevania DS I was wandering around.
Speaker 1: I ended up glitching the game.
Speaker 0: Yes - comes out this week.
Speaker 1: I'm well aware All right.
Speaker 1: So much for my money situation in my free time situation.
Speaker 1: But anyway and I would I discovered an area that I shouldn't have been able to get to near the top of one of the Manners and in this area there was nothing but dead bodies hanging from the ceiling and a really creepy lake that you really couldn't get Past.
Speaker 0: if it's on top of a manor, how can a dead body hang from the ceiling if it's a sky?
Speaker 1: Well, no like the top level of the manor okay in a place that you shouldn't have been able to get to and it went on forever and There were all sorts of things where you could holy water in the wrong place and fall into a spot.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't have gotten to where there's creepy shit down there.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of games have this stuff and when I was a kid, it used to be kind of this Mr.
Speaker 0: Don't seem to have it anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now games have things like Princess Peach's mysterious third eye.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it pretty much stopped with the the SNES.
Speaker 0: I mean The SNES really didn't have any glitchy action like that on the GameCube.
Speaker 0: There was a little bit of glitchy.
Speaker 0: I mean not the GameCube the N64.
Speaker 0: there was a little bit of glitchy action going on in some games, but Nowadays, no, it just doesn't really happen anymore.
Speaker 1: well if you ever wondered why the glitches in old NES games are Often so much more interesting or strange or inexplicable than the glitches you get now Which generally seem to be resigned to deleting your save data or preventing you from beating the game?
Speaker 1: back in the day games were designed very differently for a number of reasons and My thing of the day is a cool little bit written by snow, bro explaining exactly how Metroid works how the level data was saved how it was accessed and why all the different kinds of glitches you could run into and Strange areas you could gain access to existed.
Speaker 0: It's actually really interesting because it shows you you know nowadays if you want to program something your computer is is so powerful that you Just write an object-oriented program And you don't have to really think about a lot of things that used to cause programmers trouble.
Speaker 0: But back in the day you had very few resources.
Speaker 0: You had to do all sorts of tricks and think really hard about how to get the most out of very little.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like oh, I want to make a car.
Speaker 0: well good thing I have this car factory with robots in it you know.
Speaker 0: but back in the day was I want to make a car.
Speaker 0: Oh great.
Speaker 0: I've got ten popsicle sticks and somehow you managed to make a car.
Speaker 0: This is a good.
Speaker 0: This is a good thing to show you just how kind of thinking that they use to make that happen.
Speaker 1: and it's non technical enough To where you could easily even if you don't know much about programming or computers Understand where they're going with this at least grasp the basics.
Speaker 1: It's a really good read.
Speaker 0: So is a combination.
Speaker 0: my thing of the day is it's sort of like a news actually But one thing I hate and one thing I love have combined and therefore I must inform the world.
Speaker 0: What do I hate?
Speaker 1: Ninjas?
Speaker 0: well, no yeah, I don't hate ninja.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: I'm just I'm just a pirate fan.
Speaker 0: I'm not really anti ninja Yeah, but I really really don't like Burger King or any other fast food for that matter.
Speaker 0: I eat it as not often as possible for many reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were forced at sitcom to eat some Wendy's one night because there was nothing else open Anywhere.
Speaker 0: yeah before that the time I ate fast food was like months and months and months.
Speaker 0: before that I did an Arby's once and That they you know.
Speaker 0: before then I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: see I frequently eat at White Castle But I consider that to be a whole different brand of food.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 0: You're crazy anyway.
Speaker 0: Burger King I don't know if it's right now or real soon.
Speaker 0: It's gonna have dance dance revolution toys.
Speaker 0: Yes, you heard right if you go to Burger King you can get DDR toys.
Speaker 0: Some of them look pretty stupid But some of them look pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: if I were a betting man I would bet that the primary reason Burger King is doing this is to stave off any Question of lawsuits by fat people against them in the future because they will be able to look point back at things like this and say Look we promoted health at every opportunity.
Speaker 1: It's not our fault.
Speaker 1: You didn't read the menu with all the caloric information that we put on the wall.
Speaker 1: He ate a thousand french fries.
Speaker 1: We told people to play DDR.
Speaker 0: if they don't It could be something like that.
Speaker 0: I mean if you go to the website for the official website of the DDR Burger King You know one of the links is fitness And you know they tell you hey DDR helps you stay fit play it blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Drink water before after before during and after playing DDR.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: But one of the toys I think the best toy is a little is Baldo or Whatever.
Speaker 0: you want to call him the afro guy and you can like push buttons to make him dance a little bit.
Speaker 1: Maybe you might have to go to Burger King just to get one of these.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only other toy that seems to be worth getting is not really a toy, but a CD full of DDR screen savers wallpapers and Stickers and such stickers.
Speaker 0: you say yes stickers of arrows, huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I might actually go to a Burger King walk in and just say I want the toy.
Speaker 1: So this weekend this past weekend.
Speaker 1: We did something that we haven't done in a long time.
Speaker 1: We played Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 1: See we used to play it on a very regular basis in college and before then at least I used to play it on an even More regular basis in high school and even before then in middle school.
Speaker 1: I didn't play it that early, but I've been playing it Yeah, and we hadn't ever since we moved out of our IT and pretty much when I graduated and left.
Speaker 1: I Really miss D&D a lot and I missed it pretty much non-stop until due to sheer force of will we have convinced most of our friends for one reason or another to move into our general vicinity and Now we can get together on a regular basis and play Dungeons and Dragons again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, D&D is one of those things where you really want to do it and when you actually do it It's kind of special just because it takes preparation.
Speaker 0: Like if you have four people together, you can just whip out a board game and play.
Speaker 0: But if you have four people and you want to play D&D, oh, well, you have to have characters prepared.
Speaker 0: the DM has to prepare.
Speaker 0: It's like this big.
Speaker 0: it's a whole lot of trouble to do but it's like this huge reward.
Speaker 0: So it you don't do it often and when you do, it's awesome
Speaker 1: except in college when you play constantly yeah, yeah, but pretty much being in the real world with jobs and such and Especially early on when our friends were still in college or moved all over the place and didn't live near us right away It was hard to play.
Speaker 1: So now I mean everyone lives close enough to hang out on weekends and like Alex actually lives right here Like right down the street a bit.
Speaker 1: But playing D&D now serves two purposes.
Speaker 1: before we played D&D just as a thing to do we all lived in the same place.
Speaker 1: We just would go over to mine and Scott's apartment to play D&D every weekend.
Speaker 1: Now we play D&D and it's also in addition to playing D&D.
Speaker 1: It's a gathering of friends and a party all rolled into one.
Speaker 1: It's like triple threat.
Speaker 0: It's like if you're gonna do this big old D&D game Well, everyone's gonna come over and give it everything they've got, you know, you can't let it go to waste or else What's the point?
Speaker 1: Yep I mean I think our eventual plan will be and most people will show up Friday night and we'll start partying and hanging out Saturday all day we'll play D&D and then Sunday we'll muck about for the rest of the day.
Speaker 1: Oh, right Though I gotta say it was really interesting to be playing D&D again I mean after having not played for so long.
Speaker 1: a few people expressed that they wondered if they were out of touch or if they Remembered how it went or if they would still enjoy it and I think the overwhelming consensus was that yes It is equally awesome to all the D&D we've ever played before if not better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is I didn't really prepare as much as everyone else did we noticed.
Speaker 1: Yeah Scott made a con man partly because I told him to make a con man.
Speaker 1: He didn't have anything better to do.
Speaker 0: It was a good idea.
Speaker 1: It was a good idea.
Speaker 1: But then right away he tries to con some people and the con starts out pretty good And then he totally bollocks it up and almost got executed.
Speaker 0: you know, I think that one of the problem twice one of the fundamental problems the Dungeons & Dragons and and any RPG in which you have Very powerful characters or anything like that.
Speaker 0: You know is your character knows more than you usually is Stronger than you has more powers than you and some of that you can handle and some of it you can't.
Speaker 0: usually the knowing.
Speaker 1: See now that's easily mitigated because what you do in that situation, especially if you have a profession or craft or knowledge Skill related or if you have a reason to say my character would know this.
Speaker 1: I just don't like say, you know Your character would know the name of the capital city of the nation you're in but you don't personally know it because you didn't bother reading the wiki or the Manual before you started playing.
Speaker 1: it's perfectly within the realm just as the DM.
Speaker 1: What's the name of the blah?
Speaker 1: I should know this.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah or with a knowledge skill It's well you make a knowledge roll and you'll find out whether or not you knew that or not.
Speaker 1: And if you knew it then you get all the information out of character and you can use it as you wish in character.
Speaker 0: Yep, however, it does disrupt the game a little bit when you're like me and you didn't read any of it.
Speaker 0: You're just constantly asking and confirming the DM like every two seconds.
Speaker 0: It's much better if you study it and actually know it and then can roleplay it much better.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, that's all.
Speaker 1: my philosophy has always been to learn the entirety of whatever campaign setting I'm working in at least insofar as my character would know and to pointedly not read about things I don't know about or wouldn't know about to make it easier to roleplay.
Speaker 1: I mean I played mostly most of the D&D I've ever played in the Forgotten Realms setting just because Everyone knew it well to the point that people could just name off geography or they knew who major people were.
Speaker 1: they understood the gods and the pantheon in the world and the political situation and The DM and the players both did not have to bother with no fleshing any of that out because it was already there.
Speaker 1: We didn't have to focus on learning, you know, what this nation is like or what these things are like.
Speaker 1: We just played our characters in the world as though it was a world our characters lived in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's kind of scary to see that you know more about this fantasy world than the real world except I don't I know a lot more about the real world.
Speaker 1: No, there are people.
Speaker 1: there are people got that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just like I don't want to be one of those people.
Speaker 0: So I end up like not knowing anything about fantasy world, but you don't know anything about the real world either.
Speaker 0: I know plenty of stuff.
Speaker 1: I Got some old examples.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, but I mean your con was ludicrous.
Speaker 1: He basically shang.
Speaker 0: I don't think the thing I really messed up was two numbers.
Speaker 0: if I would have changed the number 200 silver to some other number I mean, oh and if I would have changed the number free to some other number my con would have worked great.
Speaker 1: well, the problem was when you said 200 silver and Everyone in the room 11 people go.
Speaker 1: what the fuck's wrong with you Scott.
Speaker 1: out of character I think it would have been acceptable to say should I have picked a different number?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, you know hindsight is 20 20.
Speaker 1: remember now that because one thing that's really influenced our style of D&D play.
Speaker 1: well two things have influenced our style of play now but the most important thing is that Many of us have played burning wheel or at least know about burning wheel and we have integrated Many of the concepts and ideas both of burning wheel and of Luke Crane himself and just his opinions on how gaming should be done Into D&D and it seems very easy in Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 1: One of the things along with this is to have the in character conversation and the out of character metagaming Simultaneous in order to make the actual scenario the characters are playing out work.
Speaker 1: It's well, I think it's perfectly okay to step out of character and confirm details as you go.
Speaker 1: So the plot just makes sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah Because playing it out is one thing but once the moment is done and you've moved on to something else People don't think back and remember the metagame stuff.
Speaker 1: They think back and remember what actually happened in game and all the meta stuff kind of fades away And all you're left with is the memory of the story.
Speaker 0: I think what I learned in the most recent D&D playing is that to have awesome role-playing see at first I was trying to take the advice of make a guy who screws up Yeah, I was trying to like not do well like at one point like I could have tried to do something to get out of a situation but I just said I screw it let it go.
Speaker 0: Let's go down the shitter You know and it worked out.
Speaker 1: Okay, I guess I'm still alive But yeah due to a deus ex machina.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but eventually like not succeeding at anything.
Speaker 0: It kind of got me in a rut and I'm like, okay, this really isn't going well.
Speaker 0: So then, you know Alex, I think he learned one thing from Luke Crane is at one point he was like I was just like and he He must have remembered what Luke Crane said and he said what do you want?
Speaker 0: and I'm like, oh shit Oh, it was.
Speaker 1: there was a situation where Scott's character and Scojo's and Jess's characters were arguing about something and Scojo and Jess had a very clear goal.
Speaker 1: they intended to talk to Scott this con man in order to get in on the black market in this area and Scott was role-playing very well, but for what he was doing.
Speaker 1: but you didn't.
Speaker 1: you didn't really have a Motivation like there was no specific goal and as a result the conversation was continuing and the characters were talking in character But it wasn't going anywhere and resolution was nowhere in sight.
Speaker 1: So Alex implemented the alright state.
Speaker 1: what you're after.
Speaker 1: What is your goal?
Speaker 1: do things to achieve that goal?
Speaker 1: And if everyone does that the situation will resolve itself quickly.
Speaker 0: Yep I think what I'm gonna do for now on is just whenever I'm playing first of all I'm gonna prepare some for next time and second of all when I'm playing I'm just gonna constantly think what do I want?
Speaker 0: What do I want?
Speaker 0: What do I whenever I have a turn whenever it's my turn to act or say something Whatever it is that I want.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go for a hundred percent and see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yep That's something I really got to try to do better too since it's been a while since I've role-played and I'm playing a character That I think is somewhat different from what I usually play.
Speaker 0: No kidding.
Speaker 0: Let's see not elf Not a fob Not aloof, yeah Not whimsical.
Speaker 1: Yep, kind of nice not feminine In fact, he's the epitome of Roman masculinity.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except I wrote his history But I didn't really flesh out his motivation very much and I still am not sure about his beliefs.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about beliefs in a minute.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So now that we've played one session I think everyone is going to kind of rework their characters subtly in order to make the game more cohesive.
Speaker 1: I mean everyone realize well this part of my character works and this part doesn't but if I make this Aspect this way then it'll fit better with this party and then things will progress better and all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I see no problem with.
Speaker 0: I mean it's our game.
Speaker 0: We're playing.
Speaker 0: we could do whatever we want.
Speaker 0: So who's to say I can't change this and that and the other thing if it makes the game better?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean a lot of thing people are hesitant to do is to like do certain things because you know It is a. it's like it.
Speaker 0: it's weird because like if you're in Puerto Rico you play in Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: You can't just be like, oh, I'll change this.
Speaker 0: everyone agrees.
Speaker 0: It makes the game better.
Speaker 0: Well, though you can't really do that because the game has rules and you don't want to go against them.
Speaker 0: put in D&D.
Speaker 0: It's not a game of winning and losing so, you know or any other RPG.
Speaker 0: So do whatever the hell you want as long as you know It's not just you saying my fireball should do 10 deep 12s of damage not 46 and everyone else going.
Speaker 0: no You go for it.
Speaker 0: change whatever you want.
Speaker 1: Now we considered using burning wheel to play this game and we're beginning to feel like we could.
Speaker 1: well Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: burning wheel is great and I really like it and I want to use it But not everyone is intimately aware of the details of it yet.
Speaker 1: And if we use burning wheel for the this specific game We would spend at least because we're only playing once a month here in order to ensure that everyone can travel to make every game.
Speaker 1: Yeah we would at least for the first several months be bogged down a lot by not everyone knowing all the rules and Confusion and all sorts of things that are going to be fun.
Speaker 1: and we're going to do this with burning wheel anyway.
Speaker 1: But I don't want that to detract from the purity of the the actual campaign.
Speaker 1: because I want to play D&D I want to roleplay a lot.
Speaker 1: I don't want anything to get in my way of that right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we should do is like slowly transition from one to the other.
Speaker 1: well see the reason I would say we shouldn't is that to Burning wheel.
Speaker 1: the one thing it doesn't do very well is the D&D style of high magic Super-powerful people wandering about creating mischief.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: It doesn't do that because there's basically no high magic.
Speaker 1: It's much more a. I think it's a better system.
Speaker 1: It just doesn't suit Straight up D&D in a magical world.
Speaker 1: So I think D&D especially since everyone knows D&D and more importantly because Alex has implemented several reforms both from some from Internal sources and from burning wheel that I think are making our D&D experience a lot better than it are otherwise would be.
Speaker 1: I Think D&D is a good fit for this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: It's working out.
Speaker 0: Okay, I mean we started off with a doing really good stuff and then everyone sort of faded.
Speaker 0: after a few hours You know the the steam really kind of died down.
Speaker 1: Yeah Part of it was that it was Sunday and that everyone kind of realized that they needed to tweak their characters a little bit Mm-hmm, and it was the first time playing in a while and some people weren't.
Speaker 1: I mean some people haven't played a lot of D&D In the group and they're still kind of getting the hang of it.
Speaker 0: It's weird like back in the day used to just be able to play D&D Non-stop forever as long as I kept getting food now.
Speaker 0: It's like I can't play it that long.
Speaker 1: I think we'll be able to once the game gets going once everyone really is in character and really knows exactly What their characters about and once everyone knows everyone else's characters on a first name basis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was where it's like.
Speaker 0: What's his name again?
Speaker 0: What's that guy's name again?
Speaker 1: That's always what happens in a in a D&D campaign.
Speaker 1: for the first several sessions.
Speaker 1: until everything kind of clicks Everyone gets used to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also really there's a lot of players in this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's the largest long-term D&D game I've ever been in.
Speaker 0: We'll see if everyone sticks with it.
Speaker 1: so far No one seems disinterested and everyone is very excited about.
Speaker 0: yeah, that was not my prediction.
Speaker 0: My prediction is you know, everyone would show up early on and then people would kind of fade away.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even though people faded away near the end of the session One of the first things off everyone's lips was that was great.
Speaker 1: Let's schedule the next one.
Speaker 1: I want to do this next time.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I guess what we should do before we close cuz.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go super long in this episode by any stretch and Actually, we've already gone fairly long.
Speaker 1: We can go longer.
Speaker 1: Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 1: we've complained a lot about how third edition is kind of an annoying system.
Speaker 1: We have mitigated this significantly and I think we should go over the things we have Implemented in this game that seemed that at least seemed to be or hopefully will make D&D a better role-playing experience.
Speaker 1: All right, I mean first.
Speaker 1: Alex implemented burning wheel style beliefs, which is key.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not like you know.
Speaker 0: Your beliefs are actually a game element with rules about them like it isn't burning wheel.
Speaker 0: but he had.
Speaker 0: he just told everyone write down what your beliefs are and You know, we'll take them into consideration for like XP's and all that.
Speaker 1: Well, no more so than that.
Speaker 1: He did the loot crane thing.
Speaker 1: one you have beliefs - there is an in-game reward Either for following them or for changing them or for going against them in dramatic fashion - there are in-game mechanics - in.
Speaker 1: additionally additionally encourage you to follow or break beliefs in dramatic ways.
Speaker 1: in that Alex will give you Magic.
Speaker 1: d6 is kind of like Arthur in rare occasions when you pull off something cool.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I think those two things together are really gonna make the game a lot more focused.
Speaker 1: It's like you said when you didn't have any motivation for the character.
Speaker 1: It gives us motivation.
Speaker 1: It reminds us why we're playing.
Speaker 1: what does my character want?
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I'm gonna try to get that or that's something stupid.
Speaker 1: I don't want that anymore.
Speaker 1: I want something else.
Speaker 0: Yeah It seems like D&D without like saying what your characters beliefs are and all that is sort of like everyone's beliefs are.
Speaker 0: Get this show on the road Let's go to where the DM is pointing us and let's hop on the choo-choo train to beat the bad guy.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that's the kind of D&D that I really dislike.
Speaker 1: I really like.
Speaker 0: I used to like it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I like it as a one-off, you know, here's the plot.
Speaker 1: follow it, but I'm much more of the in a campaign.
Speaker 0: I'm much more like the idea of let's go here because my character would want to La yeah, the problem I have though is when my character wants to do something that is It's nothing to do with the other players and would basically take me out of the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then again reform number two if a character Concludes either by achieving whatever they were after to where it would no longer be Useful or relevant or make sense for them to stay in the game or if they complete as in they die You can just make a new character with all the experience that the previous one had Introduce them into the plot as a new character and keep going.
Speaker 1: so you won't be forced to keep playing a character Whose motivation is gone who has completed what he wanted to do or had a very good reason to leave.
Speaker 0: I Like that a lot cuz.
Speaker 0: then when you look at the game, you know as you know Just the story with characters in it and take away the ties to real people out there.
Speaker 0: It makes a lot more sense because a lot of times you play D&D and it's like, alright every character Every player has to go from the beginning to the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even Scott Johnson played in a game way back where that same thing happened.
Speaker 1: his character won Saved everything rescued the artifact saved the girl.
Speaker 1: It was over.
Speaker 1: He was ready to go home But the game kept going.
Speaker 1: so he kept playing the character, but it was just a hollow Unfulfilling experience from that point forward because the character was done.
Speaker 1: There was nothing left.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And actually I remember in high school one of the games we played.
Speaker 1: that was very much how we play the first game and you know everyone had their character and it went on and The game completed.
Speaker 1: it ended a character won a character died everything was done and then we decided we picked one of the characters and that kept.
Speaker 1: the player kept playing that character and None of the other characters would have any reason to stick around because it ended up being a fight between members of the party.
Speaker 1: Everyone else made new characters and the game just continued and we basically decided that the campaign the world the story would just follow This one character and every time, you know a plot arc ended or a character ended all the other players would just make a new character or bring back a Character who had a reason to be back and play that and we had a story instead of a hack-and-slash Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I really like that and I think Alex is making that an official game mechanic is going to be huge.
Speaker 0: I won't that's good because I don't know how long of my character is gonna last.
Speaker 0: Yeah Plus I will probably have a better idea of a good character once the game is going along.
Speaker 1: and now if you have a character Who's willing to die for something?
Speaker 1: You're actually willing to die for that in dramatic fashion because you don't lose anything and D&D usually like oh shit I don't want to die.
Speaker 0: then I had to be raised dead for five thousand golds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course he also has the nice thing if he kind of got rid of raising dead pretty much It's almost impossible to bring someone back from the dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well when you're level three, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah it is Yeah, but in general he said that the characters die they die.
Speaker 1: That's good, too I like that but but I like it because we've implemented these other things.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And one thing he's added We haven't had gotten to try it in a large scale but we tried it in the small scale was an idea of making combat go quickly by Counting down the initiative numbers from the top to the bottom and when the number of your initiative comes up you immediately have to act And you can't really talk to other players out of character or in character during combat.
Speaker 1: Combat is quick brutal decisive and deadly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think that counting is really necessary in third ed because your initiative doesn't change around around.
Speaker 0: however forcing people to hurry up if there is a combat and just do something do something do something is much better because Here's obvious reasons.
Speaker 1: well I just realized this.
Speaker 1: here's why you keep the counting in One as a just as hearing that count go in the background Even when you're not acting.
Speaker 1: it adds a sense of urgency to the characters who aren't playing and it keeps you focused.
Speaker 1: But more importantly and you can actually you can skip the count whenever this isn't happening but whenever someone say delays action or Readies an action or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Then you count down and then the person just chimes in at the number and says I do my thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if they if someone says they're gonna delay or ready then you can do that.
Speaker 0: But if no one's delaying or readying you might as well just go to the next person.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, Alex actually figured that out on his own when he did the demo where he started he'd be 20 19 18 and then after the game started going he realized and he started going like he knew.
Speaker 1: when people's numbers worse He was like 20 negative 1.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz they the whole goal is to make the combat take less time and be more exciting and less of a tactical analysis paralysis board game Analysis paralysis.
Speaker 0: so, you know counting down more quickly with skipping all the useless numbers just only helps that goal.
Speaker 1: Yes, and we have once again, we haven't tried this in the full game yet.
Speaker 1: It's actually something that we used religiously when I played D&D in middle school in high school and I just kind of forgot about it and combat took forever in college.
Speaker 1: And once I showed everyone this it seemed to work really well.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should mention it to the Dragons landing and see if they have any Insight into initiative and counting and all that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I gotta email them about something else.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Yeah, I don't think we should go on much longer.
Speaker 1: I all I can say is that we will have multiple Episodes on Dungeons & Dragons and role-playing in the coming months as we play D&D again on a regular basis.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution Non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.