Speaker 1: It's Tuesday November 21st.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We we Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You go down to the Nintendo store.
Speaker 0: So what?
Speaker 0: Sunday I woke up I was sick.
Speaker 0: I went down to the city on the train listening to my iPod and some podcasts on the way there.
Speaker 0: Get off the train go to Nintendo store.
Speaker 0: I got a pre-order.
Speaker 0: I'm guaranteed to walk away with a Wii.
Speaker 1: meanwhile I am in bed completely asleep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they got thousands of Wiis there.
Speaker 0: There's no chance They're not gonna have one for me.
Speaker 0: The line went from the Nintendo store and almost around the block.
Speaker 0: I was on the exact opposite side of the block.
Speaker 0: So it was three sides of a block away and this guy from the Nintendo store is standing at the end of the line And he says, you know, you might be in line here till after 5 p.m When we'll close.
Speaker 0: he's like.
Speaker 0: he said that we don't think we can actually process all these people it before we close.
Speaker 0: It'll take too long.
Speaker 0: We only have six registers seat now.
Speaker 1: I gotta say if I were in charge of the Nintendo store if I were the general manager there I would have taken a page out of the playbook for a lot of conventions a lot of other events.
Speaker 1: I would have set up Temporary Extra cash registers.
Speaker 1: you can rent them for very little money.
Speaker 0: That's what I would say.
Speaker 0: They had employees that were owned that were just managing the line And not only that had excess employees there.
Speaker 1: those registers often come with people to man them.
Speaker 1: you can for very little money rent Cashiers who are very good at what they do for and it cost almost nothing.
Speaker 1: They could have just set him up outside even and just process people as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: Yep, instead they kind of process people slowly.
Speaker 0: I think the problem was is it was sort of inefficient.
Speaker 0: everyone wanted something different, you know And some people had pre-orders and some people didn't and it was kind of.
Speaker 0: it was a little bit tricky.
Speaker 0: You know some people wanted different games and they also wanted to make sure nothing got stolen and all that jazz.
Speaker 1: See I would have done something else too.
Speaker 1: I would have said pre-orders from this time this time or pre-orders only day one day two free-for-all.
Speaker 0: I actually think before I got there from six to eight I heard I don't know if this is fact that they did pre-orders only for two hours.
Speaker 1: Oh two hours great Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway what they did.
Speaker 0: there was one big line going around the store and I was in this line and it actually moved a lot Faster than I said it would.
Speaker 0: I was in the store like noon.
Speaker 1: They were probably trying to trick people into not standing there But what they did it was really.
Speaker 0: essentially there was a line for pre-order people and a line for non pre-order people Even though there wasn't physically two separate lines.
Speaker 0: So what this guy did is he would go down the line and he would say he was a pre-order and he would take the people who at the front who had pre-orders and you know Say go to the head of the class and you would go into the store and as that when the store after people left the Store, he would go down the line and pick out more pre-order people and get them into the store.
Speaker 0: So at you know, eventually I was led into the store way ahead of the people I was standing there.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, I'm still asleep Yep noon, I Might have gotten up around 11.
Speaker 0: Anyway, maybe I don't remember about the line.
Speaker 0: The only thing really I have to say about the line is it wasn't an exciting line is you know?
Speaker 0: Say the Miyamoto line or anything.
Speaker 0: There weren't lots of fanboys with all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean one guy had a link costume.
Speaker 0: some people had Nintendo shirts.
Speaker 0: Not actually that many DS is really and but the line primarily consisted of people who are at least 20 years old.
Speaker 0: There were some parents with kids, you know There were some teenage punk kids But mostly it was 20 plus year old people who all were going to buy the Wii and play it as opposed to homeless people hired by greedy capitalists to Exploit the masses.
Speaker 0: so actually like everyone near me, you know They weren't the kind of people I would make friends with and hang out with all the time But they were cool people and they had entertaining and intelligent conversation for a few hours You know talking about mostly video games and such like.
Speaker 0: oh what games you're gonna buy?
Speaker 0: Oh what games you've been playing lately?
Speaker 0: Yeah, do you like this kind of game?
Speaker 0: Etc, etc.
Speaker 1: Any DS is in the line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were.
Speaker 0: I already said there were some but not as many as lines previous.
Speaker 1: Did you have yours?
Speaker 0: Nope what?
Speaker 0: I left there home.
Speaker 0: I was I didn't want to carry anything cuz I knew I was gonna have to carry a bunch of shit back.
Speaker 1: You mean one bag?
Speaker 0: I didn't want to carry extra shit.
Speaker 0: Plus I wasn't feeling well.
Speaker 0: that true true and it was cold.
Speaker 0: I wanted to keep my hands in my pockets.
Speaker 1: So you could have worn gloves and played your DS.
Speaker 0: You can't play as a glove.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can in fact today.
Speaker 1: I was playing my DS with gloves on Nothing.
Speaker 0: I don't have like tight leather gloves.
Speaker 1: See I got all the gloves I own.
Speaker 1: I have one pair of gigantic ski gloves and everything else are tight leather gloves.
Speaker 1: I got for four dollars or less in Chinatown.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna get new gloves and hat this season totally bootleg.
Speaker 0: one of them You know, it's kind of annoying is the only thing I wanted to buy besides a Wii is I wanted a new wool hat And I saw these people walking around with these white We will hats and I was like, oh I want one.
Speaker 0: they gave him away at the Toys R Us midnight launch.
Speaker 0: I couldn't get one.
Speaker 0: I was so pissed.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll find one on eBay for like 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: That's about what I'm willing to pay 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So eventually got inside waited in line in the store for an hour got to the front bought my Wii The only thing they had.
Speaker 0: they didn't have trauma center.
Speaker 0: They didn't have that Marvel game, whatever.
Speaker 0: They didn't have every game at the Nintendo World Store but the games they did have.
Speaker 0: they had an essentially infinite supply that it essentially infinite supply of Wii and They had an essentially infinite supply of wiimotes and nunchucks.
Speaker 0: But they weren't letting people buy more than one extra wiimote and one extra nunchuck.
Speaker 1: So we can only play two-player games right now Which is kind of annoying because we had four people over all the five feet.
Speaker 1: We really wanted to play Wii games with a lot of people and we couldn't.
Speaker 0: I'm sure in a few weeks that we will be Able to buy emotes and nunchucks and we'll be all good.
Speaker 0: but right now every store is Almost completely sold out and reports around the country are pretty much agreeing that not only is the Wii sold out But the nunchucks and the wiimotes are sold out as well, but games are not sold out.
Speaker 0: You can get games aplenty.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Some people said oh doesn't matter because in some areas you could get wiimotes but not nunchucks and in some areas You could get nunchucks, but not wiimotes.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: This is one annoying thing Is that the wiimote is $40 retail and the nunchuck is $20 now.
Speaker 0: This is good in the long run.
Speaker 0: because let's say my nunchuck breaks.
Speaker 0: I can go buy a new one for 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 0: Instead of having to buy a wiimote nunchuck combination for say 50 bucks or 60 bucks.
Speaker 0: However in the short run this kind of sucks because you know, what if you basically have to send every store You know like three wiimotes and three nunchucks for every single Wii the store gets to make sure there are enough out there and it doesn't balance out apparently.
Speaker 0: and Some game a lot some multiplayer games.
Speaker 0: You only need the wiimote and some multiplayer games.
Speaker 0: You need both.
Speaker 0: So it's got.
Speaker 0: you know, I'd like to only buy like two wiimotes to none or four wiimotes and two nunchucks.
Speaker 0: But monkey ball, there's some things where you need four remotes and four nunchucks.
Speaker 1: See, I think the way it'll work out is that I would expect Everyone I know to own their own wiimote and just bring it wherever they go.
Speaker 0: That's what I would expect also, but at the steep price of $40.
Speaker 0: It's a little tough, you know what?
Speaker 1: No, it isn't not for our friends.
Speaker 1: I guess some of them are really poor though I wasn't really pointing out other people just us.
Speaker 0: Oh So in the end, I got the Wii I got on the train I came home and then it was we tap.
Speaker 1: now we'll get to all that after the news.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna do the news.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the news that we came out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got it.
Speaker 1: Actually We'll probably talk about this next week but the news media has generally had the consensus and there have been a lot of reports to the effect that There were a lot of problems in the ps3 launch lines A lot of crime a lot of robberies a lot of injuries a lot of trouble.
Speaker 1: There were no as far as I saw reported incidents in any we line anywhere Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and considering that more people lined up for the Wii because there were more wheeze and there were still people who didn't get wheeze I think that a different kind of crowd was trying to get the Wii as opposed to trying to get the PlayStation 3.
Speaker 0: Yes, the obvious.
Speaker 1: So in the interest of going to bed since we are still a little sick more so Scott than me with his seppical or Sepical or however, we've decided to pronounce it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's a tough call in the pronunciation of seppical.
Speaker 0: I've always said seppical but I look at the box now and there's a line over the E and if I remember correctly that Means long vowel sound and if you know the long vowel sound of easy, so it could be seppical.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I see.
Speaker 1: I've never actually used that.
Speaker 1: I usually use halls or chloroceptic.
Speaker 0: Sepical basically started out as a chloroceptic spray like the first one and it was wicked powerful because he uses benzocaine and Also menthol or halls is just menthol if I remember right.
Speaker 0: and so eventually, you know, it did so well on the market they made the throat lozenge and it's basically the most powerful mouth and Throat numbing thing.
Speaker 0: you can get over the counter.
Speaker 0: So if you have a sore throat and you just need to go away seppical way to go.
Speaker 1: product placement.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, but I'll endorse a product that works.
Speaker 1: we decided to skip the news and go right to the things of the day and we're gonna be real to the point about our Things of the day because they're more to the point than we were about seppical.
Speaker 1: They're very simple things of the day.
Speaker 1: I just like saying that okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Actually, it's two yuko things of the day in a row mostly because I'm lazy and I haven't seen anything funny on the internet And I don't really want to talk about the kid getting tasered or Kramer being a racist.
Speaker 0: So we'll save that for next week.
Speaker 1: Enjoy this video of a bunch of Siamese kittens versus a bunch of bananas hanging from strings.
Speaker 0: Oh, man It's really freaking cute All right Mine is a little animation video thing made by some obviously punk kids possibly college kids.
Speaker 0: They put post-it notes on a glass pane and they made stop-motion animation by moving the post-it notes around and taking pictures, right?
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I like the way it dances.
Speaker 0: So without further ado Though we so after the long ordeal at the Nintendo store I received the Wii that I rightfully pre-ordered and I brought it home on the choo-choo train and was not mugged.
Speaker 0: and The first thing I knew about the Wii but in before opening it was god damn is it motherfucking small?
Speaker 1: It's a really little box compared to what you might expect.
Speaker 0: Like people were walking out of the Nintendo store with these pretty small bags and I was like what did that guy not buy a Wii?
Speaker 0: But and I was like no wait the Wii fits in that bag.
Speaker 0: Oh Shit, and you get in the store and you see these boxes and they're so small.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's bigger than a GameCube box, but that's because it comes with a bunch of extra manuals.
Speaker 0: I mean they're putting everything in English Spanish and French where before you know The other languages they didn't concentrate on so much and they got to stick a wiimote in there and the sensor bar and all That other stuff, but if they didn't do that The wiimote itself is so small.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I should.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna take a picture while you're editing the podcast of the wiimote next to a Mac Mini So everyone can see.
Speaker 1: yeah and compared to the Wii Yeah I gotta say we.
Speaker 1: next I gotta say I wish and I hope that Apple and Nintendo Would do some fun things together.
Speaker 1: make a little incestuous love child because I got to say the Wii Looks real slick next to that Mac Mini and I feel like the two of them should do something together.
Speaker 1: I feel like my wiimote should work with Bluetooth on the Mac.
Speaker 0: We tried to get it to work.
Speaker 0: We just we tried to make the wiimote Bluetooth work as a pointing device of the Mac Mini And it didn't work.
Speaker 1: We tried the minimal amount of.
Speaker 0: We said does this work right away with no modifications?
Speaker 0: No, no, it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it almost did until we had to type the passkey into the wiimote.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, so Unboxing the Wii was really very different in experience from the unboxing of any other Console I've ever had.
Speaker 0: well basically it had like these numbers on parts of the box So that idiots and people who don't know how to set up computer audio visual electronics equipment could follow.
Speaker 1: well No, actually, there's a trend lately in a lot of things because I didn't talk about this yet but I'd install some printers at work giant expensive HP printers.
Speaker 1: and The cool thing was it came in this special package with all this fancy Cardboard folded in fancy ways so that you open it and Each part of the package like comes out in a special way and it makes it really easy to unpack and protects the thing really well.
Speaker 1: packaging science has come a long way.
Speaker 0: Yeah the Wii box scene you open it up and it says one two obviously pull out number one first do it number one says then Pull out number two and do it.
Speaker 0: number two says and etcetera etcetera.
Speaker 0: But we just took the Wii out.
Speaker 0: we plugged in the sensor bar put on top of the TV plugged it into the wall with the Incredibly relatively small power cable Maybe plugged in what else.
Speaker 0: Oh the AV cables right into the back of the TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we still got to get the component cable.
Speaker 0: Yep, we pushed the power button and we were good to go.
Speaker 1: We were we in here we now.
Speaker 1: the first thing we noticed His Scott experienced at first he's holding the Wiimote.
Speaker 1: We didn't even put the sensor bar up really, right?
Speaker 1: We just got to toss it on top of the TV.
Speaker 1: We just went as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: get it going get it going turn it on.
Speaker 1: It was pretty much perfect the Wiimote with.
Speaker 0: no matter how poorly you set your room up the Wiimote pretty much just works as appointing device in the menus of the Wii Channels area and all the Wii the bait that the Wii operating system interface.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much like a mouse, but you hold it in your hand.
Speaker 0: I mean it works with optical mouse technology.
Speaker 0: We basically learned this over time.
Speaker 0: is that the sensor bar?
Speaker 0: all it really does?
Speaker 0: is it has some infrared LEDs in it that blink And the Wiimote has a camera that looks for.
Speaker 0: these LEDs sort of like your optical mouse is a camera that looks at the table.
Speaker 0: So when you move the Wiimote around, you know trying to use it as a pointing device not as its other functions but it can tell if it's moving left or if it's moving right or up or down and then the arrow on the screen moves accordingly and As a pointing device to pick different items on the screen.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much perfect unless you have infrared interference.
Speaker 1: Yep, now there are a lot of cool people trying to figure out exactly how this works because basically your remote is kind of like A camera, so people are trying to figure out now how high resolution is it?
Speaker 1: How sensitive is it?
Speaker 1: If you want to really see this well take a digital camera especially an older one or one.
Speaker 1: you can remove the IR filter from and take a picture or look at Your.
Speaker 1: we can your bar the sensor bar and you'll see a whole bunch of lights coming out of it.
Speaker 0: Yep, if you if you run monkey ball calibration mode, you can actually see what the camera in the Wiimote sees.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it gives you a semi rod dump straight up.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's basically two blinking dots and that's what's in the sensor bar.
Speaker 0: So it's pretty.
Speaker 0: that's how it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now the Wiimote also does other things.
Speaker 0: You can rotate it in pretty much every different direction and flick it in different directions and these accelerometers in the Wiimote Which are pretty much Average run-of-the-mill accelerometers from electronic shop they detect when you rotate it or move it.
Speaker 0: So for example in the Wii menu your cursor isn't an arrow like on every computer.
Speaker 0: It's a hand with a finger pointing up and it has a number in the middle of it.
Speaker 0: so player one has a blue hand with the number one and Player two has a red hand with the number two.
Speaker 0: We don't know what.
Speaker 0: players three and four.
Speaker 0: I imagine it's green and some other color probably probably totally guessing But you move the Wiimote around like you're trying to point at the screen and The hand moves around if you just rotate.
Speaker 1: this was one of the shining moments.
Speaker 0: I you've Scott rotated his hand his wrists just a little bit I flipped it over so it was all gangsta style and the hand on the screen Flipped over and now instead of the finger pointing up the finger was pointing down.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Now in general, I mean in terms of unboxing the thing and plugging it in.
Speaker 1: aside from all that This was the first console where after we plugged it in We went for almost two hours before we put even a single game into this thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean when I put the game when I set up the GameCube, which is the last console we got.
Speaker 0: You know it took me a few minutes to set the time and date and it took me a Committed or two to check the memory card thing to see how it worked and then popped in Luigi's Mansion Which is the only game that day and we were off.
Speaker 0: But the Wii.
Speaker 0: First I had to set up the internet connection.
Speaker 0: Then I had to install.
Speaker 0: I had to put my Wii points that I bought two thousand Wii points on a card.
Speaker 0: I had to install them into the Wii store.
Speaker 0: Then we had to make me now and we had to try everything else before we even played a game.
Speaker 0: We'll get to the Mies Mm-hmm be that we will.
Speaker 1: there was.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of stuff to do.
Speaker 1: the Wii by itself is Barely entertaining and has potential for great amounts of entertainment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was disappointed However that the opera browser the news channel and the weather channel are not yet available.
Speaker 0: I'm still waiting for those because I was really looking forward to that.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I got a couple guesses.
Speaker 1: the weather one I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's not ready yet.
Speaker 1: Maybe they want to wait until the wheeze are already on.
Speaker 1: they have an idea of how many are out there online Before they put these servers live.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know though opera about browser.
Speaker 1: My guess is that the reason it is not working yet and not available yet is that they are trying to make sure There is some sort of don't let children see Pornography or run into child predators option and they want to make sure it works because Nintendo is so paranoid about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was a thing when I turned the Wii on for the first time.
Speaker 0: it asked me Do you want to set parental controls?
Speaker 0: Do you want to do this and that?
Speaker 0: and I just said no to all of it.
Speaker 0: Of course because we don't need parental controls in our house But there it is if you're a parent and you care about that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: I imagine it works via the ESRB system because I can't imagine what other system it worked by actually In America, it works by the ESRB In Japan, it works by another system that you know this for sure.
Speaker 1: I read an article about this this morning.
Speaker 1: Okay, so apparently I don't have the article in front of me So take my five-minute readings word on it, but at least in America it goes by the ESRB.
Speaker 1: Obviously, this doesn't work for GameCube games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: So for Wii games.
Speaker 0: you can just set it, you know only play games that are tier less and you need a parental unlock I guess to play any other game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there's a code.
Speaker 1: you can like you set a code.
Speaker 1: Then you can enter the code to override it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: We didn't really actually play with that Obviously.
Speaker 0: All right, so let's talk about the the console a little bit.
Speaker 0: when you put discs into it It grabs the disc the way the Mac Mini does only better like right away.
Speaker 1: It feels really good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you put a GameCube disc.
Speaker 0: like the hole is big.
Speaker 0: It's a hole big enough for a Wii game, which is about the size of a DVD Maybe slightly different from the size of a DVD.
Speaker 0: I haven't actually put them next to each other to find out.
Speaker 1: so one of those little GameCube discs is really be sidewalling if you Try to stick it in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah You could put the GameCube disc in the middle You could put it in the side You could put it in the other side and it'll suck it right in and work just fine No matter where you put it in that big old slot.
Speaker 0: It's really cool.
Speaker 0: I mean you could just sit there putting GameCube discs in and taking them out all day And also while you can stick a disc in upside down, it doesn't hurt anything.
Speaker 1: It doesn't scratch the disc.
Speaker 1: It just says up.
Speaker 1: I can't read this disc and spits it back out.
Speaker 0: Yep The other thing is the Wii is really small and you notice the people always in the pictures online or have it on its side In the little stand.
Speaker 0: I opted to just put it lying, you know face up like a little player way to be different Horizontally, I just rested it right there.
Speaker 0: You'll see it in the picture.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: maybe we'll put it on top of the Mac Mini.
Speaker 1: We'll make a Nintendo come back.
Speaker 0: I don't know what we want to do.
Speaker 0: that little heat issues.
Speaker 0: Plus the Wii is a little longer than the Mac Mini, but it's shorter and less wide.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that wouldn't balance.
Speaker 1: I want to make room for the Atari 7800 that's bigger than both of them combined.
Speaker 1: Wow, think about that.
Speaker 1: The Atari 7800 is half air inside Yeah, and also it has really big resistors.
Speaker 1: Like if you look inside an old Atari system It's the kind of board that I would solder on my own.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Parts from Radio Shack Yeah, a lot of electronics parts like back in the day like a capacitor for like with a set number of amount of storage Of capacitance.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was great.
Speaker 0: Back in the 80s was a big thing physically and today you can get that same electronic part But really really small, you know miniaturization, which is probably one of the best advances in Civ 2.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it probably is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it leads to all sorts of fun.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah So let's talk about the Wii interface.
Speaker 0: is you move this arrow around?
Speaker 0: and the Coolest thing that I thought was when you move it around from item to item it Vibrates.
Speaker 0: when you move it between items You can.
Speaker 0: actually it actually feels like all the buttons on the screen are physical buttons and you're bumping over from one to the next.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can't stress how absolutely intuitive this is.
Speaker 1: I could hand this to my grandma.
Speaker 1: Well, not like I could end this to my grandpa and he would just immediately be able to use it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's only cuz your grandma has problems.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, she has Alzheimer's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my grandma doesn't have Alzheimer's and she probably couldn't but my grandpa could after a few minutes wait But he has a pacemaker so he can't use it.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what do you mean?
Speaker 1: He gets a pacemaker?
Speaker 1: He can't use a sensor.
Speaker 0: Apparently it says on the Wii if you have a pacemaker don't play.
Speaker 1: that's ridiculous.
Speaker 0: That's what it says.
Speaker 1: That's absolutely ridiculous.
Speaker 0: There might be some kind of interference.
Speaker 0: Maybe perhaps the blue There's no interference.
Speaker 1: if that was true then people with pacemakers couldn't go near computers which give off far more Interference than the we know.
Speaker 0: that's what it says.
Speaker 0: That's what the internet says.
Speaker 0: I've seen the pic.
Speaker 0: it's in the manual that the health and Sort of BS, you know this.
Speaker 1: it's like the epilepsy thing is double.
Speaker 0: get my grandpa.
Speaker 0: We'll try to get him to play we golf and we bowling cuz he loves golf and bowling like and we'll see if he falls Over.
Speaker 1: well like fun fact, you know a long time ago used to be like microwaves had warnings.
Speaker 1: No, don't be around with a pacemaker, but modern microwaves are for the most part shielded enough to where it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Your pacemaker is not gonna have trouble with your microwave.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll find out when my grandpa tries to play we bowling.
Speaker 1: of course He's gonna play we bowling.
Speaker 1: we bowling is one of the best games and even though we solved it And it's all I saw that you didn't I saw what you did.
Speaker 1: It didn't look too tough to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see if you get to all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so horse feedback is awesome.
Speaker 1: The fact that the PlayStation 3 doesn't have rumble really isn't cool, especially feeling how well the Wii is using rumble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like I didn't care about when rumble came out for the n64.
Speaker 0: I was like whatever.
Speaker 0: who gives you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the n64 rumble was really ham-fisted.
Speaker 1: It was really this.
Speaker 1: the controller would either be sitting there normal or shaking wildly at semi random times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they had forced feedback for joysticks on the PC a long time ago.
Speaker 0: And while I thought it was cool and semi useful for a few games especially space flying games There was so many different Standards for it and so many different joysticks.
Speaker 0: It just didn't pan out.
Speaker 0: and now it's like a few people have all the patents for it.
Speaker 0: So that real force feedback for joysticks is dead.
Speaker 0: And so we're flying games.
Speaker 0: Yep, so forget that.
Speaker 1: and you know rumble really started getting good with the GameCube where it was mostly the PlayStation 1 And the PlayStation when the dual shock came out.
Speaker 0: that's when rumble was used properly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but a lot of games for those systems even though they could have used it Well used it poorly.
Speaker 0: a lot of games for every sit pretty much any game for the play.
Speaker 0: Once the dual shock was came out and as the GameCube and every other system that had rumble As soon as those systems existed every game that came out was using rumble.
Speaker 0: some games used rumble properly and some games Didn't use rumble prop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the most games didn't use rumble.
Speaker 1: proper games that used it well were the ones with very subtle You don't like that.
Speaker 1: your engine start and there's this very very faint rumbling in the controller And then as you accelerate the rumble increases.
Speaker 1: things like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah little little things.
Speaker 0: I mean there were some games where it's like you die.
Speaker 0: it rumbles a whole bunch other than that.
Speaker 0: It doesn't rumble at all.
Speaker 0: It's like good rumbling games.
Speaker 0: You'll know use the rumble often and they use it appropriately.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, but the wiimote make sound.
Speaker 0: you probably know this.
Speaker 0: you barely even notice it when you're playing because it's just so natural.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if you took it.
Speaker 0: it's one of those things where you don't notice when it's there unless you're looking for it.
Speaker 0: But if someone took it away you'd go where to go and you'd be pissed off.
Speaker 1: There's little things like in Wii sports when it's your turn your controller goes ping.
Speaker 0: Yeah in bowling and Wii bowling, you know, you sit there while someone else is bowling.
Speaker 0: You're just sitting there holding your wiimote and you know picking your nose or whatever.
Speaker 0: Then when the other person is done bowling your Wii shakes a little bit and makes a noise like doo Go bowl.
Speaker 1: or when you're boxing and you hit someone well, it makes a hitting noise Out of the wiimote.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: or and in terms of rumble actually the Madden game This is really cool.
Speaker 1: If you're choosing plays you can hover over like, you know You point out what play you want and you hover over whatever play.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: So yeah, because in Madden the problem is you'll pick a play and everyone sees what play you picked.
Speaker 0: Oh now they're gonna pick the perfect defense or the perfect offense to counteract the play you chose.
Speaker 0: if you hold the B button Which is the trigger on the bottom of the wiimote and pick a play with that It won't actually look on the screen like that.
Speaker 0: you pick that play.
Speaker 0: It'll look like you just passed over that play.
Speaker 0: Then you pick another play with the a button and it looks like you picked that other play.
Speaker 0: But in reality you picked the first play.
Speaker 1: now it tells your partner your teammate if it's multiplayer How does it happen?
Speaker 1: by making their wiimote vibrate a little bit in their hand when you're pointing at the right play?
Speaker 0: Yep So if you have people on your team and you're the one who picks the plays you pick a play Everyone knows on your team knows because their wiimotes vibrate and then you pick some other play to confuse the opponents.
Speaker 1: now that to me Is hot shit.
Speaker 1: that demonstrates one of the small but very awesome things you can do with this sort of technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Wii is really all about really small stuff lots and lots of incredibly small perfections.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like World of Warcraft in a way in that they took the standard MMO Which basically I have I'm against the standard MMO, which is the reason I don't like World of Warcraft But I got to give it to him and that they took all the little things that were wrong with every other standard MMO And they fixed all of them and polished all of them.
Speaker 0: The Wii is a game console which I have no problem with and they polished all the little things.
Speaker 0: So it was great.
Speaker 1: Now in terms of the wiimotes themselves, I mean way back when they first announced it.
Speaker 1: it was a little bigger.
Speaker 1: they you know made it smaller and such and now it's Really small.
Speaker 0: it looks really small.
Speaker 0: you go.
Speaker 0: No way, but then you hold it and you're like, ah, oh it kind of fits my hand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it feels absolutely perfect.
Speaker 0: I imagine someone with huge Frickin incredible Hulk hands is gonna have a problem and someone with little tiny hands is gonna have a problem also.
Speaker 0: But everyone that was over our house ranging from small people to big people Yeah was doing just fine and in terms I mean you hold it sideways.
Speaker 1: So it's a normal controller and it fits really well.
Speaker 1: It really feels good.
Speaker 0: It's an excite truck.
Speaker 0: You don't hold it like a remote.
Speaker 0: you hold it like an old NES Controller with the arrows on the left and one and two on the right and it works.
Speaker 0: Well, like I'm really good at excite truck.
Speaker 1: now Wow excite truck.
Speaker 1: I got to say that would that really proved to me how intuitive this is.
Speaker 1: We sat down.
Speaker 1: Scott has played it a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: I finally sit down to race against him and I hope I sit there and the game starts.
Speaker 1: I just kind of hold my wiimote naturally.
Speaker 1: I had no idea how to play the game.
Speaker 1: I'd never even seen the game before.
Speaker 1: and you know It's one two three go and I start going and it.
Speaker 1: after about a minute of racing I realized that I was using the wiimote and that I wasn't touching buttons other than you know The gas button and I was just staring with my hands and I kind of expected the way to feel weird.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm moving the controller I'm not hitting the d-pad or moving an analog stick But I totally didn't notice that I was playing a Wii for a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you expect it to be all fascinating like whoa Like, you know, you play virtual reality.
Speaker 0: I'll think the calibration of everything is always seems to be off like you move the gun in a VR game And then the camera angle moves crazily and you can kind of feel it and it's very noticeable in the Wii Totally subtle.
Speaker 0: You don't even realize you're doing it.
Speaker 1: That's probably the Wii's biggest strength is just that absolute intuitiveness.
Speaker 0: so we set up the Wii's internet connection and It did its internet thing and updated with no problems.
Speaker 0: apparently some people are having problems updating the firmware and I don't know what their problem is.
Speaker 1: Yeah Luckily, it seems to be a very small minority and Nintendo is right on that if you actually have a problem Yeah, the Wii does have a warranty and you can get it.
Speaker 0: But I mean every console that has come out in the past 10 years has had problems at launch.
Speaker 1: No, but think it is expected.
Speaker 1: if your PlayStation 3 doesn't work.
Speaker 1: When do you think somebody's gonna give you another PlayStation 3?
Speaker 1: Nintendo right now.
Speaker 1: they sold out but they have more Wiis because if you have a problem they ship you a Wii Immediately, well, they ship you a Wii when you send them your Wii.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna go a few days without a Wii.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but other than that you'll get a new one.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling.
Speaker 1: well I'm not gonna bash the PlayStation 3 but I don't think you'll get a PlayStation 3 real quick if your PlayStation 3 doesn't work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: So what comes next?
Speaker 0: we got the Wii modes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right, so let's talk about the Wii channels.
Speaker 0: the first channel I'll talk about is this photo channel.
Speaker 1: This is really really completely unnecessary and yet at the same time really really nice.
Speaker 0: So the photo channel the front of the Wii has a little flat and you open it up and you can put it in an SD Card.
Speaker 0: I took the SD card out of my digital camera.
Speaker 0: It contains some pictures that we took and one video that I took.
Speaker 0: I don't know when I took the video though I know when you took it.
Speaker 1: you were driving and for some reason you accidentally took a video.
Speaker 0: I must have anyway.
Speaker 0: I put it in the Wii and The Wii didn't say anything and we went to the photo channel and there were all the pictures and we could look at all Of them.
Speaker 0: we could zoom in all of them.
Speaker 0: We could draw on all of them.
Speaker 0: We could turn any picture into a puzzle, you know, like a sliding piece puzzle to you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: most importantly it had a slideshow and yeah had a slideshow that had epic sort of music and It could.
Speaker 0: what was the?
Speaker 0: oh it can apply certain filters to any of the photos make them brighter or Negative or anything like black and white.
Speaker 1: that that parts kind of silly.
Speaker 1: They're for they're completely useless.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's kind of dumb.
Speaker 1: It's just fun.
Speaker 0: You can save the modified photos to your.
Speaker 0: the Wii has some internal memory so if you don't have an SD card You can just save things to the memory in your Wii.
Speaker 0: an SD card is sort of like a memory Expansion and also a way to you know, take things in and out of your Wii and to bring them with you But you don't have to buy any memory cards for the Wii really you can just save everything in the Wii.
Speaker 0: Your virtual console games you can save in the Wii or on an SD card, you know, whatever you want.
Speaker 1: now aside from that I mean, that's really cool.
Speaker 1: There was the store channel.
Speaker 0: Oh, well first of all, I gotta mention one thing though Is that the video on my that my digital camera took also worked on the Wii.
Speaker 0: We could make a puzzle out of the video, which is oh, yeah That hurt my brain trying to watch that.
Speaker 1: that don't do it.
Speaker 0: everything you can do to photos You can do videos, but it only works with JPEGs standard JPEG avi Movies and mp3s.
Speaker 0: nothing else works in the Wii.
Speaker 0: So if you take an SD card out of a digital camera You're just using it's probably gonna work just fine.
Speaker 0: If you try to take photos off the internet and put them on an SD card put in your Wii Unless they're all JPEGs This isn't gonna.
Speaker 0: you know, you can't take Divx movies or x-vid movies and put them on an SD card.
Speaker 1: Sorry, this isn't for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: maybe they'll fix that in a firmware update cuz I can understand why they wouldn't include some Formats like I don't know AAC and WMA, but there's no reason not to include a hug, which is free other.
Speaker 0: No one cares about it.
Speaker 1: I think that's the primary reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but doesn't hurt to have it.
Speaker 1: It takes development effort to put it in.
Speaker 1: it does low priority, but anyway, yeah, but the store Don't mind Scott coughing.
Speaker 1: He's still a bit sick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so in the store you can buy.
Speaker 0: We chant you could buy more Wii channels and virtual console game.
Speaker 1: There aren't any more Wii channels to buy yet.
Speaker 1: There will be.
Speaker 1: I imagine there's going to be a lot of fun things.
Speaker 0: Yes, so the two ways to get first any Wii points now.
Speaker 0: Usually I'm wary of point systems because they're usually a scam.
Speaker 0: the reason people have point systems Is because they want you to convert your money into points that can ever be converted back into money.
Speaker 0: Then they hold on to your money and they make they basically made money off you before you actually bought anything.
Speaker 0: It's like giving a store like $20 and saying I'll buy something from you someday, but not right now.
Speaker 0: You just hold on to that money and make interest on it until you know Get a hundred percent profit until I actually decide to come and take something from you.
Speaker 0: It's a great deal.
Speaker 0: The other reason they have point systems is because what they do is they make everything available Worth some weird number of points so that it's impossible to get your account down to zero points and Thus not give them any more money.
Speaker 1: Well, except actually with the Wii.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I was gonna get to that.
Speaker 0: You know, usually you'll run down to like a hundred points and the cheapest thing in the store is 200 points.
Speaker 0: So you're like, uh, I don't want to let them have that hundred points worth of money forever.
Speaker 0: I want to get something, you know for what I paid already, but I can't get anything.
Speaker 0: So now I got to put in more money to get something and then get my.
Speaker 0: you know It's very difficult to get your balance to zero on the Wii not so in Japan.
Speaker 0: one yen is one point.
Speaker 0: in the u.s.
Speaker 0: One yen at one point is one cent.
Speaker 0: So one dollar gets you like a hundred points.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you can just buy points.
Speaker 0: You can just buy points.
Speaker 0: You can go to the store and buy a card.
Speaker 0: That's two thousand points for twenty dollars and you scratch it off and there's a number on it.
Speaker 0: You type the number into the Wii and You're good to go.
Speaker 0: or you can type your credit card number into the Wii and buy points directly from Nintendo.
Speaker 0: then when you want to buy something is go into the store click on what you buy and click buy and it takes points away and Gives you whatever you bought.
Speaker 0: and that's all there is to it.
Speaker 1: Yep, though another reason and I can see why they would do this The reason they'd like to use point systems like this is that you've already paid for it.
Speaker 1: So now it doesn't feel like real money.
Speaker 1: I mean if you tell someone, you know, they're looking five bucks for Mario Brothers screw that.
Speaker 1: but Five hundred points for Mario Brothers.
Speaker 1: I have two thousand points.
Speaker 1: That's almost nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've been.
Speaker 0: every time I go and look at the virtual console I keep it in mind that a hundred points is a dollar and I look and I see pinball for the NES which is a game I kind of want to play because it's I have some history with that game and Has that fun little minigame with with Mario and what's-her-name?
Speaker 0: Not the princess, but that other girl where you the ball bounces and Mario metal thing back and forth But it's like five dollars.
Speaker 0: I'm like five dollars for pinball.
Speaker 0: I get that like at five for a dollar at the local store on an NES cartridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll pay you 50 points for that not 500 for free.
Speaker 1: on to internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like I go to venus.com with the Opera browser once it's available and play it there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there are some games I imagine will buy and I imagine that the prices on older games will eventually come down or something.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm counting on.
Speaker 0: I'm hoping that as games like the first games that came out in the virtual console or like pinball Zelda Donkey Kong etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 0: in a gear those games are gonna still be sitting in the virtual console now.
Speaker 0: either What they're gonna do is take old games out and put in new games and thus, you know, you'll be like, oh I missed out.
Speaker 0: or The old games will sit in there and they'll decrease them in price and number of points they cost so that more people will get.
Speaker 0: And I hope they do the second thing now.
Speaker 1: Here's what I foresee.
Speaker 1: I imagine that eventually what they'll do is they'll take a lot of old games Put them into packages that you can then buy like for a thousand points.
Speaker 1: get these 15 games from last year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the virtual console the only real problem with it beside it works Great, is that it really does cost a bit too much for the games.
Speaker 0: I mean when ice hockey comes out I'll pay five bucks for ice hockey But most of the games.
Speaker 0: while I want them and I really I kind of want them to play on my Wii I'm not gonna pay that money for them but I think a lot of people will.
Speaker 0: a lot of people will.
Speaker 0: I mean I Felt the urge just to buy something for the sake of seeing how it worked and I wasn't gonna do it.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people.
Speaker 0: they bought Wii points.
Speaker 0: when they bought their Wii.
Speaker 0: they go home.
Speaker 0: They want to spend those Wii points right away.
Speaker 0: See how it works.
Speaker 0: They're gonna buy a game even if they wouldn't have bought it in the store for the same amount of money.
Speaker 0: It's a psychological thing.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 0: I've seen it work on people Yep.
Speaker 0: But all that aside perhaps the most entertaining thing not even counting the games yet on the Wii is the me Mii, yep, the me is actually I but soon as I found out about it, I knew it was gonna be cool But it's it's pretty damn cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically in Wii Sports This is the first game that uses this but in the Wii itself built in one of the channels Go to your me area and you make an avatar a it's set up to where you make it a human like avatar.
Speaker 1: They took out anything weird or fanciful So you're very much encouraged to make it look exactly like you look and so far We've been able to make a me that looks pretty much like everyone.
Speaker 1: we know Yeah I mean Brian and Yuko and Emily and everyone all made pretty perfect spot-on me's.
Speaker 1: my me looks almost exactly like me.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's kind of scary.
Speaker 2: Yeah Anyway, so we all made me's and it was we had a lot of fun Just sitting around making me's and telling other people how to make their me's look more like them, you know And you it's.
Speaker 2: it's a pretty simple thing.
Speaker 2: Like you choose the hair style you choose the color you choose the eyebrows style You move it around you rotate the eye.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just love stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I don't know why but creating characters and games is really really fun for me.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's like what was that?
Speaker 2: That he City of Heroes game.
Speaker 2: It was only fun for the character creation part All those Korean like build-a-princess games, yeah His Korean build-a-princess anyway Uh-huh.
Speaker 2: So it's a lot of fun to make a lot of me's.
Speaker 2: now in addition to making me's there are a few things you can Do with them.
Speaker 2: first you can.
Speaker 2: What was it?
Speaker 1: You didn't know where you're going with that.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 1: I first off.
Speaker 1: you can use them as your avatar in games that support it.
Speaker 1: It's you.
Speaker 1: so you can bring it around with you.
Speaker 1: you can save your me on your remote Yep, or just send.
Speaker 2: yeah You can save your me on your remote that like a one we moat the actual controller can hold I think like 10 plus me's in it.
Speaker 2: So it's pretty if you got to bring just your me to your friend's house You can put it in your remote.
Speaker 2: Bring your remote to your friend's house and then unload your me and play.
Speaker 1: so what you do in Wii Sports At least as you start the game and in any different any game you want to play within it You pick your me and then it's actually you playing the game.
Speaker 1: It's just the avatar in the game is the me you made.
Speaker 1: Yep So when we're boxing it's a thing that looks exactly like me fighting a thing that looks exactly like Scott.
Speaker 2: Yep It's also fun because let's say you're doing bowling and let's say I'm bowling and rims bowling.
Speaker 2: So those the avatars that do the bowling but sitting around the bowling alley are all the other me's that we made and a bunch Random me's.
Speaker 2: yeah, if you don't have enough me's in your me area created It just has random system means that it uses like we'd be bowling.
Speaker 1: I see Emily talking to Harry Sada in the background.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we made a me for Harris.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you don't know who Harris is you didn't watch Gog manga.
Speaker 2: be already like.
Speaker 2: we told you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably one of the greatest anime ever made.
Speaker 2: Oh now it's one of the greatest anime ever made.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd say so.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Now in addition that's all really cool.
Speaker 1: now remember how the Wii is on the internet.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I have a Wii.
Speaker 1: my friend James has a Wii.
Speaker 1: We share our Wii numbers, which are a lot like DS friend.
Speaker 1: Yes
Speaker 2: You have to go into the message board which I'm gonna talk about pretty soon and there's an address book and in the address book You can add
Speaker 0: people by
Speaker 2: their email addresses Which doesn't do anything yet because it doesn't let you send email or you can add people by their Wii number and to get your Wii number you just look at the front page of your address book and it tells you your Wii number.
Speaker 2: So if I add James's Wii number to my address book and he adds my Wii number to his address book We are now connected.
Speaker 1: now among other things my Miis Might just wander over to his Wii.
Speaker 2: Well, they won't just wander over.
Speaker 2: first You have to enable me traveling in the me parade section.
Speaker 2: Then for any Miis that you want to travel you have to set those Miis to mingle mode So you can have you know private me like Harris is a geek nights geek house exclusive.
Speaker 1: He's not allowed to go to other people's Wiis.
Speaker 2: Yep, but all the other Miis, you know that represent our.
Speaker 2: You know ourselves.
Speaker 2: go to all our friends, you know in their me parades so that if we go to their house There's a good chance that they'll just have our Miis already there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You can also straight-up send someone a me.
Speaker 2: Yeah, well, yeah if you go to the message board and send someone a message you can attach a me to the message Which is like here check out this me or you know.
Speaker 2: You put a picture just you know.
Speaker 2: So they can see at a glance who's sending the message by looking at the me.
Speaker 2: that's on the message.
Speaker 2: So that way even though we only have one we it's mine because I paid for it Rim can send James a message with rims me attached.
Speaker 2: So James knows it's a message from rim.
Speaker 2: Yep And yeah the message board area it does a few pretty cool things.
Speaker 2: The first thing it does is it gives you every day if you play your boot your Wii There will be a message telling you exactly what you did and when
Speaker 1: played Wii Sports for one hour from this time to this time
Speaker 2: Played with me's for 10 minutes played virtual console Mario Brothers for 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: now I see a lot of ramifications for this one.
Speaker 1: It's really fun to look back and laugh about how much time you spent playing with your Wii.
Speaker 1: to Parents can go and say alright Billy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Wii for eight hours today.
Speaker 2: This is a non editable thing.
Speaker 2: This is I haven't found a way to remove it.
Speaker 2: I'm There might be a way to just erase messages, but I this is a permanent thing.
Speaker 2: There it is for all to see.
Speaker 2: it can be disheartening when you realize how much time you spent.
Speaker 2: It can be surprising if you spent less time than you thought.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's just pretty cool all around.
Speaker 2: The other thing it does is you can send messages to people.
Speaker 2: now You can send a message to yourself and just like leave messages up there like using the calendar.
Speaker 2: So let's say instead of having a whiteboard on the fridge You can use this system in the me in the way To do the same thing as a refrigerator whiteboard calendar type of thing for the people in your house.
Speaker 2: You can also just send messages to other people.
Speaker 2: my guys send a message to James like hey, how you doing?
Speaker 2: He sent me a message back like hey, what's up?
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's like little.
Speaker 2: we email.
Speaker 2: Not too not too useful right now, but maybe as more people start to make friends with each other It'll become pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Not only that but just I mean in general There's a lot of potential in the Wii that is going to be unlocked over time.
Speaker 1: as more channels appear more services become available.
Speaker 1: The Wii is very extensible and has a lot of opportunity.
Speaker 2: Here's an example of in create interesting use of the Message board area.
Speaker 2: I went into Wii Sports and I did the fitness workout training mode and I got like a I think my Wii Sports age was 60 and I think the best is 20.
Speaker 2: So I did terribly.
Speaker 2: it was I hadn't been good at Wii Sports yet Anyway, and it put a log of my Wii Sports performance in the message board.
Speaker 2: so I guess for games like DDR with diet mode might put something in there.
Speaker 2: or You know any sort of game where you're building skill over time or Games or you might want to remember how well you played it in the future or how well you did in the future.
Speaker 2: if they Come out with brain age.
Speaker 2: We it'll totally do something like this.
Speaker 2: I can guarantee it, you know.
Speaker 2: Maybe if you beat a game, it'll put something on the calendar so you can remember what day you beat it stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I can imagine a lot of things.
Speaker 1: I could imagine a trophy room channel.
Speaker 1: I can imagine God we don't even get into that.
Speaker 1: I can imagine like a house area so they could set up where your me can live in.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow, maybe you get Pokemon and you put them in your little little me house.
Speaker 2: Pokemon channel is dangerous.
Speaker 1: This game can do a lot.
Speaker 1: this system can do a lot.
Speaker 1: We haven't even touched the games yet and we're not going to.
Speaker 1: we're gonna review the game separately in another episode.
Speaker 1: But before we end tonight, I think we'll each say one sentence about each of the game.
Speaker 2: I just want to talk about one other thing.
Speaker 2: one other thing the mp3 playing.
Speaker 1: All right, right Yeah, totally forgot about that.
Speaker 2: the.
Speaker 2: if you have mp3s on your SD card It is possible for the Wii to play them.
Speaker 2: The most interesting use of this is currently excite truck.
Speaker 2: No other game does this.
Speaker 2: that I know yet.
Speaker 1: I haven't tried though I wish Madden did it god damn.
Speaker 2: Yeah, EA Sports games with their MTV crap music.
Speaker 2: But if you play excite truck, it has this standard rock music in it.
Speaker 2: It's okay.
Speaker 2: You can tell excite truck to instead of playing that standard rock music to play mp3s from your SD card instead and That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: So you can play excite truck to geek nights if you really want.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you could totally take geek nights.
Speaker 2: put it in your SD card.
Speaker 1: You know what I would play to a loop of that laughing insanity test from way back.
Speaker 1: Happen happen happen.
Speaker 1: Okay Yeah, but alright let's go through the games and then we'll call it a night so I can go to bed and hopefully sleep off this minor sickness that Has been ailing me and Scott who has been coughing constantly throughout.
Speaker 2: Actually, I was feeling sick before now.
Speaker 2: I'm not feeling sick.
Speaker 2: But because I'm talking so much for this episode It's starting to bother my throat and it gets scratchy and then I cough and there's a lot of mucus moving around.
Speaker 2: That's all that's really wrong with me right now is I got a lot of mucus in motion?
Speaker 2: Yeah, I got to get the mucus out.
Speaker 1: I sympathize.
Speaker 1: I only bring it up because that means I have to sit here editing out as many coughs as I can.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's alright.
Speaker 2: It's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it won't be so bad.
Speaker 1: But yeah, uh, Okay, we sports.
Speaker 1: We'll do a sentence each per game.
Speaker 1: Okay We sports is really really intuitive and really really fun.
Speaker 2: We sports makes better use of the wiimote than any other game that I played.
Speaker 2: yet Monkey ball Hey, I haven't played the single-player.
Speaker 2: The multiplayer is half really awesome minigames and half absolutely terrible minigames.
Speaker 1: exactly what Scott said.
Speaker 1: It was worth purchasing though.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we're in bought that one.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 2: So not a fan of monkey ball.
Speaker 1: excite truck is Very very fun with lots of crashing.
Speaker 2: Excite truck is a very good formulaic truck driving game yet somehow it's really fun.
Speaker 1: All right, you got trauma center didn't you?
Speaker 1: I didn't play it yet.
Speaker 2: trauma center is DS trauma center exactly ported to the Wii Plus another trauma center game.
Speaker 2: It's like getting the DS episodes and plus a whole bunch of new episodes.
Speaker 1: I have not played trauma center awesome Zelda Twilight Princess looks like it's going to cause minor orgasms for me.
Speaker 2: I've barely.
Speaker 2: I played it for 10 seconds just because I don't have time.
Speaker 2: I got to really sit down with that one for an extended period of time and part of the Wii philosophy is short game playing.
Speaker 2: It's that I really haven't had time.
Speaker 2: Yeah this weekend for sure is all the action.
Speaker 1: Definitely.
Speaker 1: Well for you, I'll be out of town.
Speaker 1: Yeah crying.
Speaker 1: Yeah now they have any good food.
Speaker 1: It's all good Alright.
Speaker 1: Madden is a typical but probably well-executed football game that I need to play more of before I can pass judgment.
Speaker 2: if you like Football and you understand football then Madden will be fun.
Speaker 2: It makes use of the wiimote But it doesn't make use of the wiimote in a way in a good way.
Speaker 2: It makes use of the wiimote in an average No-brain kind of way.
Speaker 1: Wow, there were a lot of semi-colons and such what you just said.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's alright.
Speaker 2: It could make better use of the wiimote than it does.
Speaker 1: Yeah It uses the wiimote more like mouse gestures in black and white then a wiimote where you throw the football and depending on how You throw it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly, which is probably fine.
Speaker 2: It is fine.
Speaker 2: It just it could be better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it could be better.
Speaker 1: But there were a lot of DS games that didn't use the touchscreen to its full capacity.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we're still really good games.
Speaker 1: They were I mean in some.
Speaker 1: the Wii is frickin awesome.
Speaker 1: I am so incredibly pleased with this.
Speaker 1: I think it is going to be.
Speaker 1: I think it has a decent chance of in terms of this Console war that may or may not be actually happening.
Speaker 1: I think the Wii has a chance to come out on top not just in second place.
Speaker 2: No, I think that pretty much anyone who plays the Wii is gonna go As long as this because there's a game out there for everyone.
Speaker 2: I mean you got everything.
Speaker 2: they got the Call of Duty game They got a bunch of kids games based on some recent cartoon properties and such.
Speaker 2: You know, they got excite truck They got Wii Sports They got Madden.
Speaker 2: They got all the bases covered depending on what your gaming taste is and these are the launch titles.
Speaker 2: You know, they've been Metroid and Mario when all that other stuff is coming out soon.
Speaker 2: They got Zelda Yeah, so as you play the Wii game that is right for you.
Speaker 2: I can't imagine that you wouldn't go.
Speaker 2: I mean, it's gonna be hard to find someone out there who isn't like, you know a blind Nintendo hating Sony fanboy or something who's gonna go.
Speaker 2: man the Wii sucks.
Speaker 2: anyone who's played it and has played the game That is made for them.
Speaker 2: I can't imagine you saying eh, whatever, you know who wouldn't enjoy the Wii?
Speaker 1: a man with no hands?
Speaker 2: Someone with no hands would not like the Wii?
Speaker 2: not at all No, but you know would like the Wii.
Speaker 2: a man with no legs a Man with no legs would love the Wii.
Speaker 2: the Wii would be the best thing ever Right.
Speaker 1: We're off for the holidays.
Speaker 1: We will see you next Monday when we will well Yeah, the coming Monday Monday after this weekend where we will continue our series on hard drives and file systems because you all really seem to like that a lot Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and well Tuesday will probably actually review some of these Wii games as we've Finally probably been able to have a chance to play them for more than a few minutes.
Speaker 2: Oh, hey, if you're gonna be all sad about not playing the Wii this weekend Why don't you go buy Final Fantasy 3ds and it's $40.
Speaker 2: I know 35.
Speaker 1: I'd buy it in a second.
Speaker 1: The problem is that's the upper limit.
Speaker 1: I want the game But I know I could just borrow it from Alex a month from now for not buying it.
Speaker 2: cuz I was planning to borrow it From you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 1: We'll lend Alex Phoenix right and then we'll get three and then we'll pass it around.
Speaker 2: Yeah, yeah, I was just figuring.
Speaker 2: if you got it you can talk about that.
Speaker 1: Maybe I will.
Speaker 1: I'll be in Rochester, which means I'm coming back with some board games.
Speaker 2: Yeah, call me when you're at millennium and I'll look up on the board game.
Speaker 2: geek, whatever you see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we'll play those board games after.
Speaker 2: there are a couple games that came out at Essen that I know we're hot stuff And I want to check them out.
Speaker 1: All right, so everyone out there have a good Thanksgiving.
Speaker 2: Um, I don't think if you're not for the United States Thanksgiving is a holiday.
Speaker 2: That's not really bad meaningful historically, but we celebrate it and we eat lots of good foods.
Speaker 2: We don't care.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I'm not going used to eat food.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to be around on the forums.
Speaker 1: I don't watch football.
Speaker 1: I don't know if mr.
Speaker 1: Period is going to be around.
Speaker 1: I swear to God.
Speaker 1: if we come back and the forums are full of shit cocking and bad grammar There will be hell to pay.
Speaker 2: I'll be on the forums on Saturday at the latest.
Speaker 1: so Yeah, yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: It might be you having to correct people's grammar, which I imagine is not as fun as it sounds.
Speaker 2: No, not really.
Speaker 2: We still need like a mr.
Speaker 2: Comma or a mrs.
Speaker 2: Comma.
Speaker 1: We need some more moderate or a Joe semi-colon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah now starting next week I think we're going to talk about exactly how we may or may not choose to have another moderator because mr Period's hands are full and while I and Scott also have the power to edit your posts.
Speaker 1: I don't have time for that shit.
Speaker 2: It's really and you people are making such long posts so many mistakes.
Speaker 2: It's really nice.
Speaker 2: Not easy.
Speaker 1: No, I would say that 99% of the mistakes rest in 1% of the people in the forums.
Speaker 1: Yes, true.
Speaker 2: If you have free time and you hang around our forums and you have good grammar and spelling Send us an email.
Speaker 1: Yeah We'll come up with some sort of death match to figure out who is going to be the next moderator.
Speaker 2: geek nights at front Recruiting and such.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 2: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 2: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 2: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.