Speaker 1: It's Tuesday January 24th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about the Milton Bradley game master series.
Speaker 0: Let's do this All right, so you may or may not know that I'm in the market to buy a nice new car.
Speaker 1: Any because he drives a beat-up tempo that barely runs.
Speaker 0: it barely runs for sure.
Speaker 0: it makes all kinds of noises But it goes.
Speaker 0: so it's gonna last me until I get this new car in a few weeks, so Anyway we I'm looking for a hatchback kind of car.
Speaker 0: You know two or four doors, but there's no trunk.
Speaker 0: the back just kind of opens.
Speaker 1: there aren't so many hatchbacks anymore.
Speaker 1: It's like Americans.
Speaker 1: Just don't desire them.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is that you know.
Speaker 0: you'd figure that for every variety of vehicle There would be one per brand you know.
Speaker 0: so for an SUV you can get the Mazda SUV the Ford SUV The Chevy SUV the Tonda SUV.
Speaker 0: right everyone makes an SUV But not everyone makes a hatchback.
Speaker 0: They're only really good ones to choose from considering the fact that the Honda Civic hatchback is not made now because they're gonna make the Honda fit next year and The Acura hatchback won't be out till next year either.
Speaker 0: My only choices are pretty much the Volkswagen GTI and the Mazda 3.
Speaker 1: now the Mazda 3 seems to be a clear winner here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we went.
Speaker 1: we went with our friend Pete I want the scientists from the other day and we were test driving the cars and Pete and I just played Mario Kart DS while Scott was test driving.
Speaker 1: and All I have to say about Volkswagen is that the salespeople are kind of creepy at least the one that we went to.
Speaker 0: I mean Let's look at the dealers who went to.
Speaker 0: he went to the Mazda dealer where the guy was just kind of cool.
Speaker 0: You know a little bit of salesman action, but you know he wasn't pushing it on me And I you know it's like.
Speaker 0: you know he knew he wasn't a doofus.
Speaker 1: Went to the Chevy dealer where the guy was just like here's the keys.
Speaker 1: see you back whenever.
Speaker 0: yep That guy was very hands-off But I think that's because we went in the middle of the rain when it was dark out and late And he didn't care.
Speaker 1: yeah, plus word.
Speaker 1: He's like where do you live?
Speaker 1: and we're like we pointed at our house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see it from the dealership.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then The Volkswagen dealer.
Speaker 0: they were actually like.
Speaker 0: you know I was like.
Speaker 0: can I drive it because I expected it to be like the other Dealers.
Speaker 0: they just gave me the keys and I went.
Speaker 0: but no there She was like well come into my little box.
Speaker 0: And I went into this little box, and she gave me like this psychological talk German engineered blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: German engineer.
Speaker 0: She's like she's like try it when you're in the car try to you know think about how great it is, and I'm like yeah Nice try professor X Cuz.
Speaker 0: now I'm just gonna be thinking about how annoying you were instead of The car.
Speaker 1: well the one thing we noticed that and Scott pointed it out And I kind of laughed at him, but then we looked online and verified that it's in fact true.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it's also a service center It's not just a dealer and there were a large number of cars of the type.
Speaker 1: He was looking to buy being serviced Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: now I wrote that office.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is probably the regional service center, and they send them all here.
Speaker 0: I think it is the regional service center, and they send them all here.
Speaker 1: however there are serious problems with the Volkswagen GTI's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I went around the internet looking at various websites comparing the two cars And you know all kinds of user reviews which are about as reliable as shit You know.
Speaker 0: but a couple time I tried to remember things that I saw more than once because you would and I tried to ignore Anything said by someone who sounded like a ricer Because there were people who were like the Mazda 3 sucks.
Speaker 0: You can't modify it.
Speaker 0: It's hard to get parts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the funniest one is.
Speaker 1: someone said they didn't like a car because the subwoofer that came with it wasn't powerful enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, you need you need to get out of here.
Speaker 0: But I saw at least two times on the internet that there were rely.
Speaker 0: It's all it said were reliability issues with the Volkswagen GTI.
Speaker 0: So then I was like who knows that's not from anything official.
Speaker 0: then it was in the supermarket standing around and I picked up this car magazine that had every single car from 2005 and 2006 with stats in a summary.
Speaker 1: meanwhile I'm standing outside the supermarket with all my groceries wondering where the hell Scott went.
Speaker 0: I didn't know where you went Cuz.
Speaker 0: I had finished shopping and you were still getting milk or some juice or something.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: and So I was just reading this magazine waiting for you to get in line And then you were already finished getting in line while I was reading.
Speaker 0: but anyway, it they'd said right in there Volkswagen GTI reliability issues.
Speaker 0: and Another thing is I don't know how many times this lady was like feel those doors.
Speaker 0: And I got to admit when you close the doors on this car It's like it feels really solid.
Speaker 0: It's like they do it on purpose with like super hinges or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know why the car is so solid because it weighs like twice as much as any other car that size.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't needs a giant supercharged engine to actually push it.
Speaker 0: They like double steel reinforced the doors.
Speaker 0: That's why they're like that which makes it real heavy.
Speaker 0: So it's a supercharged engine and it might I'm not a hundred percent sure but the Volkswagen website said it, you know Should use premium gas and not regular gas which I could see.
Speaker 1: that because basically I used to drive a car that had a turbo.
Speaker 1: it was a real fast car and Turbo or super in either case generally means high compression and not to get into a long technical discussion of cars But high compression basically the more you compress gasoline the more likely it is to spontaneously Ignite before your spark plug goes.
Speaker 1: that's bad.
Speaker 1: That causes knocking and if you have knocking basically your engine is one second away from shitting itself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not gonna go into all the other details about the difference between this car and the Mazda 3 But I'm probably gonna get the Mazda 3.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna call the guy.
Speaker 1: probably tomorrow We're gonna try to start a dealer war because there's two Mazda dealers around.
Speaker 1: I told Scott he should call one get a price quote call the other one say he's got this price quote ask him if they'll Beat it.
Speaker 0: I do realize I just found a disadvantage in the dealer war though because one dealers in New York I just noticed in the little Mazda book, you know the brochure thing Yeah, that the Mazda 3 is sold in New York are somehow different from the one sold in Connecticut.
Speaker 0: They have seven less horsepower.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it said 153 horsepower in California, New York Massachusetts Maine and somewhere else.
Speaker 0: so I kind of want to get it in Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Well, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: There's probably more to it than that I know.
Speaker 0: that's why I'm gonna ask the guy when I call him It might be an emissions thing.
Speaker 1: It might be a thing.
Speaker 1: It might just be that's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to find out exactly what that is because who knows maybe if I buy in Connecticut bring it to New York I'll have to pay to have something done to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I mean Dutchess County where we live There aren't emissions tests.
Speaker 1: I mean we have car inspections, which honestly I used to live in, Michigan.
Speaker 0: So the idea of the fact that I had to get my car inspected was an alien thing to me as long as it passed Inspection which I think it's kind of hard for a brand new car to fail inspection.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I'm alright.
Speaker 1: So the thing is we don't have emissions testing here yet.
Speaker 1: Nope, and every year the legislature is like we're gonna do it.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do it We're gonna do it and everyone's kind of all the car people around here always yelling about it Yeah, but I could see you get in the car in Connecticut and then we have emissions testing and it doesn't pass some silly New York rule we don't know about.
Speaker 0: well, Connecticut had emissions testing for as long as I can remember.
Speaker 0: You know probably in my lifetime it started but I don't remember it because I wasn't paying attention.
Speaker 0: I was a little kid but Then there was an issue when I left for college that the emissions testing people which was a private company Which is contracted by the state government Was all corrupt and the emissions testing was just this big sham.
Speaker 1: Haha.
Speaker 1: I'm scamming your emissions.
Speaker 0: Yes, so they closed emissions and you didn't need emissions for in Connecticut for a few years and then it started up again.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it started up again now or it's sooner.
Speaker 0: Who knows.
Speaker 0: It's a big mess.
Speaker 0: Yeah governor went to jail.
Speaker 0: God, who knows he went over to jail over something else though that shows you how great he was.
Speaker 1: See it was weird in Michigan because they had an emissions laws that your car couldn't emit certain things But there were no inspections or anything.
Speaker 1: So basically the only way you get caught is if a state trooper saw smoke coming out of your car and pulled you over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if someone can see smoke coming out of your car It's usually because you're burning oil not because your emissions are too high.
Speaker 0: if your emissions are too high It'll just smell real bad driving behind you.
Speaker 1: You won't actually see anything Yeah, and actually that bad smell usually just means you're running too rich and you get there.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna get into that.
Speaker 0: Cars nevermind, we're done with the cars.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So What's in the news today?
Speaker 0: Oh the MPAA?
Speaker 1: Yeah the MPAA and you know, we all love them.
Speaker 1: They're just bastions of honor and righteousness and they're really fighting for the little guy.
Speaker 0: Well, I got to say one thing though in the MPAA's favor.
Speaker 0: They're not as bad as the RIAA That's you know what.
Speaker 1: yeah Mussolini was an ass, but he wasn't quite Hitler.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not quite.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not quite, you know now Wasn't quite Stalin?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the MPAA Basically a bunt.
Speaker 1: someone did a documentary film about them and about their business practices called.
Speaker 1: this film is not yet rated.
Speaker 0: Well it talks mostly about the rating system and how the ten the group of people who do the ratings don't have to reveal themselves and how they're like biased against.
Speaker 0: you know certain movies as opposed to others and they give certain movies a worse rating when they don't really deserve it and It's not objective and it's all bullshit.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: It's a good movie and it's worth watching especially if you don't like the MPAA.
Speaker 1: This is just more fuel on the fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah And if you do like the MPAA or you think the rating system is good This will either piss you off or work to change.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait now if you if you like the MPAA I'm not saying if you don't know they're bad, but if you actively like what they're doing.
Speaker 1: stop listening to my show.
Speaker 1: Yeah But basically They got a copy of the film.
Speaker 1: this film is not yet rated to rate among other things.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and They made copies of it to distribute to a bunch of their employees.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now, I don't know about you but as far as I know it's illegal to do that without the permission of the copyright owner.
Speaker 1: and This copyright isn't owned by the MPAA.
Speaker 1: It's owned by the people who did the documentary who in fact told the MPAA specifically, please don't copy this Mm-hmm, even better and no one's sure yet, but they might have actually given it to him on a DVD.
Speaker 1: Mmm, if that's the case, not only did the MPAA break copyright law and break a contract But they violated the DMCA the law they got.
Speaker 1: they got passed on their own that the law They're trying to use to fuck all of us.
Speaker 0: now at least the MPAA kind of admitted it.
Speaker 0: they said yeah Okay, we we pirated the movie.
Speaker 0: We're gonna destroy and give you back all the copies and we'll make it right.
Speaker 0: But if I was the people who made this movie I Would stick them to the wall with very large pointy bits.
Speaker 1: now, you know, what's great?
Speaker 1: No one's sure exactly how this is gonna play out yet But there's been a lot of talk that the people who made the movie are going to take them to court.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: I will will if that actually happens.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about it more see now.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing though.
Speaker 0: It's like if they win then that gives grounds for the MPAA to do things to other people the same way and they'll win.
Speaker 0: But if they lose then it means, you know, they lost which sucks But at the same time it means the MPAA can't win if they try it on someone else.
Speaker 1: Yep, because if the MPAA gets you you could just say hey, hey, hey Fine, I'll get rid of all the copies I have.
Speaker 1: and yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: so someone finally had the Testicular fortitude to make us some audio feedback.
Speaker 0: Holy crap Yeah, so of course you send it to us in a WMA file Yeah, which don't worry.
Speaker 1: We discovered a way to turn that into a wave file in Linux.
Speaker 1: But just the heads up to all you out there.
Speaker 1: We don't run windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah waves MP3s and odds that's that's pretty much what we deal with in terms of audio.
Speaker 1: Actually, I've been running a file of WMA a lot because we're looking for a little solid-state device to record for.
Speaker 1: When we go to conventions when they're interviewing people We don't want to lug a PC around or fiddle with resound while we're recording a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: We just want a little recording thing and all the ones that are nice and cheap Record natively to crappy crappy crappy WMA files.
Speaker 1: and although I know why all the ones that record nicely are Much more money than I'm willing to spend on a solid-state recorder I think we should just get use this laptop or maybe get an external hard drive for this laptop.
Speaker 1: I get a new laptop or I'm trolling around eBay for an old DAT recorder Because DAT for that's really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, DAT is basically get tapes though.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's fine I can get them.
Speaker 1: basically for anyone who doesn't know about digital audio and everything DAT is the original Useful digital audio format.
Speaker 1: it came out a long time ago, and it's pretty much been the industry standard in terms of you know recording something authoritatively and definitively and pretty
Speaker 0: much tons of radio stations used it instead of vinyl and Japanese radio stations I think still use it and I'm Japanese people used to use it instead of cassette tapes because it's like a thousand times better.
Speaker 0: But now the American Record industry didn't want us having perfect digital copies of music.
Speaker 1: So we didn't get that yeah, in fact DAT unless you.
Speaker 1: basically they segregated that into two classes of players and recorders in the US and They made the ones that could record more than some piddly amount Outrageously expensive.
Speaker 1: to make sure that no normal people could get their hands on good digital audio.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just artificially inflated the prices so that you know Real music.
Speaker 0: people had to pay a lot and normal people didn't have access.
Speaker 0: That's kind of why they're screwed now is because now everyone has access to perfect digital recording with the computer.
Speaker 0: Hence this show.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we'll see if I can find a little DAT device.
Speaker 1: So anyway, Eric for those of you who might not remember is the person who's listening to the podcast on Sony PSP and he sent us nice little audio on how he did it.
Speaker 1: now you can do it.
Speaker 0: Let's listen.
Speaker 2: Hey Raymond Scott, this is Eric glimpse and tonight.
Speaker 2: I'm going to tell you how to set up your PSP.
Speaker 2: So it's an RSS reader.
Speaker 2: now first of all you need to make sure you have a PSP and not a Nintendo DS because obviously those things can't do what the PSP can do.
Speaker 2: and next I'd like you to check if you have a wireless connection and It needs to be hooked up to the internet so you can do this.
Speaker 2: so you can update your PSP to 2.6 firmware if you haven't already.
Speaker 2: Now first of all, you need to go to Download the PSP firmware.
Speaker 2: You first need to go to your settings icon on the left side of the screen.
Speaker 2: then you need to move up and click network update and then you can just follow the on-screen on-screen instructions and those will tell you how to do everything and You can just download that and it won't take very long.
Speaker 2: and As soon as you're done with that you need to go in and install your PSP 2.6 firmware on your PSP and If you don't have enough battery when it's done downloading It'll tell you to charge your battery and the reason it does that.
Speaker 2: first of all because it's like, you know your PC when you update your BIOS is Like.
Speaker 2: if you don't do that, then you're you know, your your BIOS chip will go out.
Speaker 2: So it just applies the same way to PSP and you can go in and update that.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 2: first you need to charge your battery and Then you go to the game icon on the right side of the screen and then you move down and you go to memory stick click that and then choose PSP firmware 2.6 and then once again go with the on-screen instructions and Install that on your PSP and after that your PSP will reset and then you can go in to the left side of the screen or the right side of the screen again and go to the network icon once again and then go up to internet browser and then on that choose the button file and then you can type in the address like if you want to go to.
Speaker 2: Lets you do this.
Speaker 2: For example, go to podcast.yahoo.com then click enter and Then that page will open and this is specifically to get geek nights on your PSP And then go to
Speaker 1: That
Speaker 2: text box with tagline beside it and then right in there type in geek nights and I think I've tried geek before.
Speaker 2: maybe it came up, but just try geek nights just to make sure and Then geek nights will show up as number one and you can go besides that and click the name And there's a link right there and then it'll send you to this page and it'll have like these two big buttons when you get there for Subscribe or download the podcast.
Speaker 2: but don't go to that whatever you do But on the like the right side of the page right besides the words RSS colon you'll have a link.
Speaker 2: It'll be in like XML or whatever and just click that and that will tell you to Subscribe to the download or subscribe to the podcast and you can do that.
Speaker 2: and so then when you want to leave the web browser just press circle and then select yes from that message box and now you're ready to go in and Listen to the podcast.
Speaker 2: so now that you're on the main menu again go to the network icon once again, then go to RSS channel and There you can select the podcast you want to listen to and you can stream it from the internet.
Speaker 2: so that's basically how to do that and You can just prove how smart you are.
Speaker 2: And also I heard that with the new updates you can actually listen to Or watch streaming video.
Speaker 2: So see that's gonna be a new update pretty soon and that's gonna be really cool.
Speaker 2: I can't wait for that and maybe we can get all like a game spot video streams from there.
Speaker 2: So that'll be pretty cool.
Speaker 2: Now.
Speaker 2: I also have another question for you guys.
Speaker 2: You guys remember the fear game that came out?
Speaker 2: I know you talked about that like when you were talking about how PC games were dying.
Speaker 2: So maybe you guys could talk to us about that.
Speaker 2: That'd be pretty cool because that was a really awesome game and I don't think it got enough credit for all the innovation it had.
Speaker 2: So thanks guys.
Speaker 2: Talk to you later.
Speaker 1: Well and first I just like to say that Eric did put some nice music at the beginning and end of that and no offense We only.
Speaker 1: it was real done.
Speaker 1: We only took it out because one we were very mindful of copyright here.
Speaker 1: Yeah nights and two.
Speaker 1: Now there's.
Speaker 0: no I don't really want to get sued by a CDC.
Speaker 0: So the first thing The DS.
Speaker 0: I don't see any Technological reason why the DS can't listen to podcasts other than not having any place to store them While you're listening, but you know if someone made like a little flash cart for the GBA slot or something You know it.
Speaker 0: it can go on the internet.
Speaker 0: We just need someone to write the software to do it.
Speaker 0: People have already written DS software to go war driving.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean and honestly I think within some amount of time there's gonna be an official sort of web browser Something for the DS.
Speaker 0: yeah Reggie someone asked Reggie about it once and he was kind of like it could happen.
Speaker 0: He didn't say he was gonna do it or Nintendo was gonna do it, but he said there's no reason why not.
Speaker 1: Yep, because I mean the PSP seems to do this really well like from.
Speaker 1: from what you said It looks like it's really simple to update it and get online and all that.
Speaker 1: But I just got to point out that the DS has a freaking stylus Which is like plus 10 in my book for browsing the interwebs.
Speaker 0: Yeah when you were talking about like hitting circle Oh god that brought back flashbacks.
Speaker 1: Yes, we've actually we.
Speaker 1: I bought a Sony PlayStation a ps1 for a hundred dollars Solely to play dance dance revolution.
Speaker 0: playing dance dance revolution doesn't teach you circle square triangle X.
Speaker 1: so a bunch of our friends got the Naruto fighting game and Those are ps2 game.
Speaker 1: I think yeah It was ps2 and we went over there to play it.
Speaker 1: and one of the things in the game is whenever a combo starts It'll show you a sequence of like Triangle XX circle real fast and you have to hit him and We freaking didn't know which button was where and we couldn't do it fast enough, and we just got creamed.
Speaker 0: yeah I guess that sucks for us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were definitely only fluent in Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a B C like Sesame Street.
Speaker 1: Yo well a B X Y C was definitely Sega Genesis.
Speaker 0: Well C is also on the n64 gamecube.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I didn't really play the n64 much.
Speaker 1: I kind of skipped a generation of consoles there.
Speaker 0: hmm Anyway, but it seems like the PSP firmware is pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm really updating.
Speaker 0: it is pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: I really like the fact that it has a nice little idiot proof.
Speaker 1: Hey the battery is low.
Speaker 1: plug me in or something.
Speaker 1: Otherwise you're boned.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because if you try to update my firmware my battery runs out I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: you're basically gonna brick me.
Speaker 1: cuz I mean computers I. I can see that if you're gonna flash your BIOS you know about that anyway.
Speaker 1: But I really don't expect everyone who owns a PSP to Understand the concept of a BIOS or a CMOS because that is kind of esoteric knowledge.
Speaker 0: I'll admit that and you know what I got to admit.
Speaker 0: It sounds like the firmware in the PSP is actually a lot more awesome than what's in the D The iPod now the DS.
Speaker 0: yeah the iPod cuz pretty much the iPod.
Speaker 0: it all this stuff is in iTunes.
Speaker 0: You need to plug the iPod in to get it to sync up.
Speaker 0: the PSP seems like it has iTunes equivalent in it Which is really what I think the iPod should be because it's really annoying to have it tethered to my computer.
Speaker 0: I wish I could just you know Subscribe and unsubscribe from podcasts on the iPod and it would just download them wirelessly.
Speaker 0: That's what I really want and it sounds like the PSP can do that.
Speaker 0: But I'd get it except for the fact that it's really expensive and really big and the battery life isn't long.
Speaker 0: and yeah I have a nano so you can see it's quite a size upgrade there.
Speaker 0: No, and the the last thing is you wanted us to talk about the fear game.
Speaker 0: Actually, I know about the game and I've heard people talk about it and they know of its existence and what type of game it Is but I never played it.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna download the single-player demo and I'll get back to you Yep, and I was actually poking around just looking at it and it actually looks like it's probably a pretty cool game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it looks like some combination of like a Resident Evil Silent Hill type of scariness with some FPS action.
Speaker 1: Because I mean, I guess when it comes to PC games I don't think we're not really trying to say that it's dead as in there's nothing good out there.
Speaker 1: I think it's more of a. it's dead and that it's lost the hearts and minds of gamers and That there aren't many gamers out there who seem to delve into the PC realm to find the gems anymore
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: and I got to admit gems are increasingly hard to find but this game might be a gem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: but it is basically because the Xbox taking away a lot of Genres that used to not be playable on the console and MMO is basically dominating the entire platform of PC.
Speaker 0: There just aren't that many PC games worth playing anymore, so it becomes less and less intelligent to buy a crazy gaming PC Of course.
Speaker 1: luckily it seems that as time goes on all you can play almost every good game on a crap.
Speaker 1: OPC Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I was playing Civ 2 today and loving it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, honestly I'm kind of thinking upgrade my computer just because I do want to play Civ 4 and half-life 2 and I don't need to play them perfectly.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to play Civ 4 but I don't really want to pay for it without playing.
Speaker 0: maybe there's a demo of that Too.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, check it out.
Speaker 0: I should go for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah So at MIT, they got this crazy crazy awesome digital painting machine thing.
Speaker 0: you know you've seen stuff like this before where someone takes a camera and they pointed at something and the camera figures out what color It is and then maybe like lights up a light in the same color or something like that.
Speaker 0: well, what they got is they have this paintbrush for the camera in it and you pointed at something and then you go over to this special screen and you paint on it with the brush and It paints using whatever the camera took a picture of.
Speaker 0: so if I pointed it at I don't know a piece of green construction paper I could basically paint on the screen with the texture and color of green construction paper.
Speaker 1: now It's much more than that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the cool.
Speaker 0: This is the now see.
Speaker 0: that was just a normal leap of logic Like something like oh I could have figured, you know, I could have thought of that But that's that's a pretty interesting use of existing understood technologies, you know, and it's cool.
Speaker 0: They made it video.
Speaker 0: So This means you could but the example they use is they pointed at someone's eyeball and the person blinks, right?
Speaker 0: And then they paint on the screen and you get a bunch of eyeballs.
Speaker 0: blinking eyeballs.
Speaker 0: It's really cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah Just just watch the video and you will comprehend and be amazed.
Speaker 1: Yep, so a lot of you probably remember those magic eyes that were really popular in the mid 90s.
Speaker 1: Well, you stand there and you unfocus your eyes and then a three-dimensional image appears.
Speaker 0: I always used to put my face up next to it and then pull away from it like the instruction said.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the technique I saw.
Speaker 1: but basically I learned early on that there's two ways to do them And for the longest time I always saw those things backwards because I cross my eyes instead of unfocusing them.
Speaker 1: Basically either move the eyes together move the eyes apart But luckily my thing of the day caters to both types of people and if you can do both well kudos to you.
Speaker 1: But basically they use the same concept and they made an entire Stereoscopic animation of a little girl in Japan trying to take pictures of cats with herself.
Speaker 1: I am cell phone cam We and it's just really cute cool.
Speaker 1: Just cross your eyes or unfocus them or do whatever you need to do to see the 3d image.
Speaker 1: If you're not familiar with how to do it, just google around for stereoscopic images and you'll find instructions.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna go into detail about that here.
Speaker 0: It actually been a while since I'd done it so it's kind of hard for me.
Speaker 0: But basically what I did is I crossed my.
Speaker 0: there are two pictures.
Speaker 0: So I crossed my eyes until of course then there would be four pictures and I lined up two of them on top of each Other to make three but it was all blurry.
Speaker 0: So what I had to do is I had to line it up so that there were three and then like I don't know How to explain it, but I did something to my eyes to hold the crossings that remain three images while also focusing.
Speaker 1: He had a lot of trouble with this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he just eventually got it.
Speaker 0: It was a two-step thing cross Lock focus.
Speaker 1: now the cool thing is back in the day and I should see if I can find it again.
Speaker 1: I remember someone made a mod or a thing for quake one Where you could quake one would display on two little windows and you could do the same thing and play quake one in real 3d Mmm, it was really cool.
Speaker 1: But you couldn't play it for more than about 15 minutes without getting a headache.
Speaker 0: Yeah I noticed I had a real problem with it because I had to.
Speaker 0: I had to keep my eyes open Basically to do it and then eventually to blink and half the time when I blinked I totally lost it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus if you do it too often, you might get your eyes a little bit out of sync.
Speaker 0: Yeah Maybe that's why I had a hard time doing it because my eyes are so good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure I'm sure.
Speaker 1: And in fact, uh, some video cards have drivers in them where they'll do stereoscopic things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if Windows Vista locks out drivers, oh You won't be able to use your cause.
Speaker 0: some stereoscopic driver mods.
Speaker 1: So today since over the weekend we played an old game that we really hadn't touched since we were in school We Decided that we're gonna talk about the Milton Bradley Game Master series and all the games in it since the game we played obviously is in that series.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was in fact the last and as many would argue the greatest of this series.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Now the game is called Shogun though It hasn't been marketed under the name Shogun for quite some time and you might hear it as samurai swords.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you see you might see in a store somewhere.
Speaker 0: if you're lucky, I don't know if they still make it.
Speaker 0: I don't think so, but it'll say samurai swords Previously named Shogun.
Speaker 1: Yep, but basically the four games in the series and you might have heard of some of these or five games axis and allies conquest of the Empire broadsides and boarding parties fortress America and of course Shogun Shogun.
Speaker 0: basically what this was is When we were little kids, we didn't have awesome German games like are available today.
Speaker 0: And these are the most strategic Games that you could buy in Toys R Us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these aren't life.
Speaker 1: You don't just roll a spinner and see who wins.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know, it's They're.
Speaker 0: they're very American games, but they're also very good games and they're pretty much they well.
Speaker 0: until Recently, they were the only really good American board games that were available to American children.
Speaker 1: The one thing they all have in common is that the rules are horridly written.
Speaker 1: I could cry And I mean, I remember when I was a kid always having trouble with the rules nexus and allies.
Speaker 1: We never really played it the same way twice Yeah, and it wasn't until this weekend that we actually learned the proper rules of Shogun.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And they were actually.
Speaker 0: we messed up one thing.
Speaker 1: Well Scott messed up.
Speaker 0: Yeah But messing up one thing.
Speaker 1: I consider that to be great that we got everything right except one thing because a German game They they write the rules in this way where you know that if they say the word may it means may.
Speaker 1: if they say the word Well, it means will.
Speaker 1: it's very specific exact logical phrasing and if something's omitted it means you can't do it Yep, and even when it's translated to English, it's still perfect.
Speaker 0: I think that might also be partially because the translators do such a good job.
Speaker 1: Yep, but these games are written in the American style.
Speaker 1: so the the rules are just kind of meandering and they touch on all the points back and forth and they Assume that you'll just assume things and a lot of.
Speaker 0: sometimes the rules are like only really Explained by reading the examples and I just skip the examples.
Speaker 0: cuz I don't need them Cuz I expect everything to be in just the rules.
Speaker 0: It's kind of annoying Yeah, but another thing these games have in common Which is why they were so popular and we liked them so much.
Speaker 0: is they come in real big boxes?
Speaker 0: Like, you know the size were pretty much a normal monopoly box and there's a deluxe monopoly box three times as thick wider and longer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, imagine a deluxe monopoly box with like on top of itself.
Speaker 0: So it's double.
Speaker 0: That's what this is like.
Speaker 1: and they come with lots of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, lots of fun little pieces and stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean you think risk comes a lot of guys freaking X's and allies comes with like little tank little tanks little airplane Bombers aircraft carriers shogun comes with a ninja.
Speaker 1: the aircraft carriers are big enough that you can put the planes on them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's just really cool to play with all little pieces and you know It's not like a crazy war game with the hexes and the little cardboard bits.
Speaker 0: But it's a lot more fun, especially when you're little and you're not a super hardcore guy.
Speaker 1: now We've only actually played three of these games.
Speaker 1: So we're just gonna talk about all of them as best we can.
Speaker 1: So the first one to be released and perhaps the most popular is axis and allies Which I used to play a lot when I was a kid with my dad my little brother And we had a lot of fun.
Speaker 1: But now then I got older and I played it once with a bunch of friends at college and I learned that the game is Fundamentally broken.
Speaker 0: It's not quite perfect.
Speaker 0: It can be fun, but it's not something you can play very.
Speaker 1: the Allies can't lose unless they're retarded.
Speaker 1: Basically, unless they're functionally retarded and illiterate the Allies cannot lose.
Speaker 1: America just builds up a giant army and then marches its way over to Europe.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It just takes a while, you know, if if they're dumb, they don't get that army across the Atlantic Ocean fast enough.
Speaker 0: You know, there's a lot of America's troops and troop building capacities in America.
Speaker 0: yeah, so it all depends on if the person being America and controlling America is knowledgeable enough about how the game works to move those guys across the ocean to get them to Germany as quick as possible.
Speaker 0: because Germany does start out with a big pile of guys.
Speaker 0: and You know and I'm sure on board game geek if we looked it up There are people who have modified these starting positions and such of the game to make it more even.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, people have made rules mods that make the game a fairly good game.
Speaker 0: Basically, the way it works is it's well axis and allies.
Speaker 0: It's what Britain Russia and US versus Germany and Japan Japan and you have this nice little European map and everyone has a. there's a default starting position and you put all your little units out on the board and you can develop technologies and You can buy units and you can move units and fight them and all kinds of fun stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no diplomacy.
Speaker 1: Germany can't surrender or ally with Russia to take over the world on their own or anything like that.
Speaker 0: That would be wicked cool.
Speaker 0: Of course, then people just do that every time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean basically the game is real fun Unless you're playing with people who all know the game fairly well because then everyone knows exactly what to do And the game is just deterministic and the Allies win in the end.
Speaker 0: Yep but you know, it's fun to play with little pieces and You know, especially if you know, not everyone knows how to play then, you know, it feels like you're playing something.
Speaker 1: Of course, it is hard to follow the rules because they're written kind of weirdly and to this day I'm not a hundred percent clear on the movement rules for ships.
Speaker 1: Yeah They're very ambiguous to say the least.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and not to mention, you know all the the things of the technology can sometimes get confusing.
Speaker 0: You know when they affect how you shoot and move and all that business.
Speaker 1: See, I mean once the strategy I always use is I usually agreed to play Russia or something Just because no one would.
Speaker 1: my little brother wouldn't play with me if I was Germany.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm So I'd always be Russia, you know They're basically the crap in this game and my strategy was to do nothing but build infantry every round no matter what?
Speaker 1: Good straight never attack anyone.
Speaker 1: I just sit there and build infantry and if he didn't wipe me out Just march its way across Europe.
Speaker 0: sweet Yes, that's how good this game can be.
Speaker 0: fun as you can do stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if everyone knows what they're doing that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: and then I have to use the actual Russia strategy Which is attack on the first round attack constantly no matter how many troops you lose from the very beginning of the game.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: One of the modifications is Russia can't attack on the first round.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you pretty much have to implement that to give the axis any chance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because if you know what you're doing with Russia, you just attack immediately.
Speaker 1: You lose almost your whole army, but Germany spends so much effort stopping you that Britain just jumps over and that's the end Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: The next game is Conquest of the Empire which we've never played.
Speaker 0: we've never played at all.
Speaker 0: I've seen it, but I've never played it.
Speaker 0: It comes in the same size box and it seems to have a lot more fun pieces than the other games Catapults and roads and little hellas like Greek Roman guys little legionnaires.
Speaker 0: They're Romans.
Speaker 0: I think the legionnaires They're Greco Romans It seemed as I think there's some road building and some ooh, there's a little What's it called a Roman building with little pillars in the front?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it looks pretty fun But according to this the rules are kind of also shady.
Speaker 1: The game is pretty much completely broken and it's all that matters is whoever has the most catapults wins.
Speaker 0: It seems though like there's some sort of Mechanic of generals leading armies and you can do cool stuff like try to extort generals or kid Someone else's general.
Speaker 1: you can just say like give me something or I'll execute your general or I'll exile him or I'll Jump them into my army or something.
Speaker 1: It looks like they can do a lot of cool stuff.
Speaker 0: Yes So if you can I'm sure there's a way to fix the catapult brokenness and then this could be a really cool game.
Speaker 1: But I also saw that you have generals and then you have your Caesar Which is you personally and you can personally lead your army into battle, but like the game says you'd better not lose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think generally that's a strategy for when your generals are fucked and you you think you know Oh this I can definitely go save him if the Caesar goes out with an army that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: But I'm sure as soon as anyone takes their Caesar out of a safe place Everyone else in the game tries to go kill it.
Speaker 0: It's like up there.
Speaker 0: He is.
Speaker 0: Let's go get him.
Speaker 0: and anyway The next game is one that I kind of want to like even though I never played.
Speaker 0: it called broadsides and boarding parties.
Speaker 1: Everything I've read says that it's terrible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like terrible terrible terrible not worth playing.
Speaker 0: I want to like it cuz it's pirates and I like pirates.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we seem to like pirates a lot around the here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are plenty of pirate games and one day I'm gonna find a pirate game worth playing but this isn't one of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically, we don't know much about the mechanics But everyone says that it's just kind of chance who wins and it's two-player.
Speaker 1: It's just a duel.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's essentially a duel between two ships like a Spanish ship and a pirate ship and They fight each other and the pirates might win in the Spanish guy might win.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's just kind of random and there's barely any strategy to it.
Speaker 1: Well, we've seen that generally it's very difficult to make good two-player board games because a lot of the randomness in games Ruins them if there's too much of it because then the randomness matters more than your skill.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you might.
Speaker 0: you're basically just putting a big fancy theme on tossing a coin If it's randomness.
Speaker 1: if you have a game that doesn't have randomness the game is very deterministic and it'll play out the exact same way every time.
Speaker 1: So many games that are good.
Speaker 1: They don't have much randomness in terms of what you get but you play with three other people and then the randomness That gets interjected is just how those people do because you can't predict them And they can do whatever they want.
Speaker 0: but in a two-player game, there's just two people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you you know, even if the game has some sort of thing where you can play it once you play it again There's only so many thing ways you can play it where the two people won't do the exact same thing every same time.
Speaker 1: Yep, and This game does not solve that problem.
Speaker 0: Yep Surprisingly this guy says they sell well on eBay, but I don't know how true that is.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah So this next one we played once.
Speaker 0: We kind of we didn't finish it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we stopped playing.
Speaker 1: I don't think we really understood how to play.
Speaker 0: I don't understand how to play.
Speaker 1: Fortress America looks like a cool concept.
Speaker 0: It does seem really cool.
Speaker 0: basically, you have this big map of the United of the continental United States and One person is the US and everyone else is not.
Speaker 1: The plot is that the entire world hates the US and has decided to get rid of us once and for all and we're being Invaded on three fronts.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: Now what's interesting is that this is the one game in the series based on Future and not history.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like a theoretical future plot.
Speaker 0: It's not real and obviously it still isn't real though.
Speaker 1: It's slightly predictive.
Speaker 1: I mean most of the world hates us now.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but the all the other games are based on some sort of history axis analysis.
Speaker 0: World War two Shogun is ancient Japan.
Speaker 1: Feudal Japan not a little Japan, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know the difference.
Speaker 0: Well, I do know the difference but I always get them confused.
Speaker 0: And The other one's based on Romans or pirates and this one is based on made-up crap.
Speaker 0: But it's still cool because there's a map of the US and on the sides and the oceans There's basically these columns and the bad and whoever is not America The bad guys is basically cramming units into these columns to jam them into the United States.
Speaker 1: now independent of all that Not only are there three large conglomerate armies trying to invade the United States luckily Canada stays out of it But there are partisans within the United States who have taken this opportunity in the chaos to revolt against the federal government.
Speaker 0: so basically the whole game is one person is the u.s.
Speaker 0: Trying to hold on and Everyone else is trying to screw the u.s.
Speaker 0: So it's pretty much a one guy against everyone.
Speaker 1: game Yeah, and the one guy starts out at a huge disadvantage.
Speaker 1: but the longer the game goes on the more and more troops he gets as America mobilizes for war.
Speaker 1: and Basically, if they don't capture America and defeat it completely quick enough they lose and America pushes them all out one by one.
Speaker 0: Basically what this game comes down to is if the person playing America knows what they're doing versus The other people know what they're doing, you know, because I gain.
Speaker 0: that could be fun once maybe twice Yeah, and as soon as everyone figures out exactly what to do for each side.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure that the same side will win every time although I'm not sure which side it is.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling it's not America.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah America knows what it's doing.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think if America knows what it's doing But the other guys also know what they're doing then they can just attack and destroy America before it even has a chance.
Speaker 1: There's one cool game mechanic though, and that's supply lines.
Speaker 1: So all these invading armies are coming in.
Speaker 1: but there's this rule that any unit that's in America That's not American has to have a complete line of supply all the way back to their landing point at all times.
Speaker 1: So if the Americans disrupt your supply chain all the units upstream of that die They run out of fuel and they just can't function anymore.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm It's kind of a neat mechanic and I wish the game were better.
Speaker 0: so I think that's America's only real chance.
Speaker 0: You see is to win is to disrupt those supply lines and I'm my guess is that the people who are attacking if They know what they're doing can defend those supply lines against everything except, you know Some randomness and if they do that then America has no chance because America's only chance is to start the supply lines.
Speaker 1: well, I was reading that apparently the game always seems to plateau where the three allies are gaining ground and gaining ground and kicking America's ass and Then the game plateaus and there's a small core of America left.
Speaker 1: But at this point America just starts pushing back out And then almost every time America gets to the brink of losing and then comes back strong and kicks everyone's asses.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's just supposed to play out that way every single time for fun.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's a jingo is game?
Speaker 0: I think it is partially a jingo is game Definitely, but I wouldn't say I would recommend buying it, but it might be fun to play it once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's definitely a part of board game history.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm as little fun little tanks and things in it.
Speaker 1: Now the last one is the one that is near and dear to us Shogun which was renamed to samurai swords because the owners of the estate of the book Shogun were giant cocks.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it does say on the bore on the game box previously sold as Shogun in case you were wondering and it's a.
Speaker 1: it's a actually Decent war game the only griver.
Speaker 1: really have it that other than the ambiguous poorly written rules Is that it takes fucking long to play?
Speaker 0: Yeah, imagine if you had a game that was really fun and if the game lasted in like an hour long.
Speaker 0: It would be like the best game ever, but the game is like three hours or four hours long.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of like your fun is spread thin.
Speaker 0: We it's not spread too thin that it's unfun.
Speaker 0: But the game would be like perfect and amazing if it was two or three hours.
Speaker 0: But it now it's just kind of really good.
Speaker 1: instead Yep, myself Scott and Pete played one complete game of it over the weekend almost a complete game.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I won.
Speaker 0: Yeah as complete as it can be.
Speaker 1: Yeah we played.
Speaker 1: it took about three a little over three hours to play not counting the time we spent figuring out the rules and The game came to.
Speaker 1: it was funny.
Speaker 1: It came down to because basically the mechanics of the game or that you have units that you can put out in the various provinces You've captured but you also have three armies and the army has a marker on the board.
Speaker 1: That's a unit holding the flag of that army And then you have the units that are in the army sitting on a little board next to you separate.
Speaker 1: So there are little provincial forces whatever guarding territories.
Speaker 1: But the real game are the actual conquering armies marching around and posturing.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of like risk only less random and Instead of risk where you have, you know, just your armies are just normal and they're in every country all over the place.
Speaker 0: It's every province you have is basically weak as hell and has a few defending units just to you know.
Speaker 0: Hold the enemies at bay a little bit and you have three really big Armies that are like giant globs of units that are super dangerous and they walk around the board individually.
Speaker 1: You know conquering and defending and the whole game is them clashing because you start with three and they all have names and there's actually A lot of color in the game.
Speaker 1: every player color has three real generals from that era that were allied in some way or members Of the same faction or what have you?
Speaker 0: and each general has like a different colored flag and a different shape so that it in those often those flags actually somehow match the Historic flags of those generals or show guns and stuff and all the pieces in the game are really nice.
Speaker 0: You have these really brightly colored guys and little spearmen bowmen swordsmen Ronan Gunners gunners the Daimyo.
Speaker 0: the Daimyo is really cool.
Speaker 0: The castles and the fortresses are really cool.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean, there's a lot to this game and really our only gameplay gripe with it is that it takes too freakin long to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like the money in the game of this little Goku.
Speaker 0: They're red and with a little hole in them look like real old money and it has a lot of strategic elements.
Speaker 1: There's no one way like one way to I'm going to win.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of posturing and yelling at people and diplomacy and then you have money based on how many territory you have and then you bid that money secretly like you allocate where you're going to spend your money on secretly and then everyone reveals simultaneously and In addition to that some things that you allocate money to our bids like you bid on the ninja.
Speaker 1: so say I'm sitting there and I need the ninja because I want to assassinate Pete's Daimyo before he Marches into my fortress and kills my last guy.
Speaker 1: but then Scott seems to want the Daimyo.
Speaker 1: I know that Scott wants the ninja because he doesn't want me to do that because he wants to go march in and take it.
Speaker 1: So I got to figure out.
Speaker 1: how much do I bid on the ninja?
Speaker 1: I don't want to over bid because I need that money to spend on troops and such.
Speaker 1: But if I underbid he'll get the ninja and I'm boned.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: Oh the ninja might fail and you might get revenge Who knows?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the ninja has some randomness associated with it, but you paid for that ninja and you chose to use it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you don't use it You can always use it to look at someone else's bidding in the next round which can be really useful and turn order.
Speaker 1: There's no.
Speaker 1: a lot of games have a right left problem where the boot depending on who sits to your right or left You'll have a. it'll affect the game a lot Like Puerto Rico is nefarious in this.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and so is st.
Speaker 1: Petersburg to a degree.
Speaker 1: But uh this game it doesn't do it that way.
Speaker 1: instead you have these swords with numbers on them and you draw them randomly And then you go in the order of the swords one, two, three, four five.
Speaker 0: But if you want you can spend money to choose which sword you get.
Speaker 0: if you want You know the one two, three fourth or fifth sword.
Speaker 0: If you want to go usually want to go first you want to go last depending on what your situation is.
Speaker 1: There's just.
Speaker 1: there's so many strategic elements to this game.
Speaker 1: It's fantastic Mm-hmm and a lot of color like we played it out quite a bit in college and we have Scott here You know rim and Scott geek nights.
Speaker 1: We have another friend named Scott and in two separate games Individually independent of each other one of them tried to hold on to this one area of the board That's pretty much impossible to hold on to.
Speaker 0: yeah It's like right in the middle Like and in between these two separate islands and it's you just basically surround it if you're stuck.
Speaker 1: It feels like Asia in risk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we dubbed it Scotland Not Scotland, but Scotland.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the last game we played it was going on pretty well.
Speaker 1: Eventually, like all the armies are marching around kind of getting closer each other and backing off getting close and backing off everyone's kind of solidifying their position.
Speaker 1: and then the army started fighting and in the end I had two powerful freaking armies marching around Uncontested while Scott's last time yo and Pete's last time yo or each hold up in giant well-defended Fortresses hiding from me.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then we decided that it would take too many hours to finish the game and we just stopped playing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty good, but I think my problem was is that I tried to be the the offensive guy.
Speaker 0: I was trying to kill other people's Daimyo's and as a result I killed one of yours and then mine.
Speaker 0: the guy who did the killing died.
Speaker 0: and then I tried to kill one of Pete's and The guy who did the killing died.
Speaker 0: So I think the strategy in the game is to you know not go in for the kill until the guy is weak.
Speaker 0: You know if you try to go in for the kill when the guy is not ultra weak, you know You're asking for it, but someone has to go in for the kill and if no one does then they're all grabbing territory.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot.
Speaker 1: it's mostly posturing as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: it's another good.
Speaker 0: Another good strategy is to gang up two of your Daimyo's against one of his if you catch him in a bad position.
Speaker 0: You know that that's key.
Speaker 0: That's why when you level them up You can move them real far to get him into positions like that.
Speaker 1: Yep Like I played a nice bit where Pete's Daimyo was was kind of dangerous because one of them I'd been Neglecting one of my armies and it wasn't that well equipped and it's just kind of moving around gathering territory along my borders.
Speaker 1: and Pete's army is coming for me and Instead of coming straight at me He jumped to take an island from me because islands are actually very defensible positions because attacking over the water You're at a huge disadvantage if you're the attacker and the island was poorly defended.
Speaker 1: I know army.
Speaker 1: They're just some troops.
Speaker 1: So he took my island.
Speaker 1: So I jumped my Daimyo like I bid so I could go first and I put an army at The at the territory that he just jumped from so he couldn't jump back without fighting my army at that disadvantage.
Speaker 1: And then he tried to take other island territories to get around and I put another army there and I basically trapped him in the ocean.
Speaker 0: Yep It's just really cool and and I like the theme and I like everything about it Except for the fact that it takes freaking forever though I think now that we know how to play we'll be able to play it faster.
Speaker 0: We will be able to play it faster.
Speaker 0: But this isn't a game you can play too often without it getting really painful.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah like Illuminati.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually I could stand to play Illuminati more often than I could play this.
Speaker 1: I don't know because I always think that but then I play Illuminati again.
Speaker 1: I remember how much it pisses me off.
Speaker 0: Hmm, maybe I haven't played it in a while.
Speaker 0: I think it's just because it's time to play Illuminati again, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we don't own it anymore.
Speaker 1: our friend who we haven't actually heard from in a long time owns it.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll buy it this Saturday or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or maybe when I'm in Rochester, I'll buy that Mafia one.
Speaker 1: that's almost the same game.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, when you go to Rochester you buy a bunch of new German games for us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I got to say that millennium in Rochester is really the only gaming store in the world that we know of.
Speaker 1: that's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can't find them around here.
Speaker 0: I mean there is one around here but it doesn't have nearly the selection of German games and they have too much of the store devoted to stuff like video games paintball yugioh Airsoft.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah makes yeah, but Millennium just sells role-playing games board games miniatures games and card games really And a small section for stuff like, you know, fancy mahjong sets and such.
Speaker 1: Yep It definitely catered to the euro gamer and all of us.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah And that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at Www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.