Speaker 0: It's Thursday October 5th, and this is a Geek Nights special.
Speaker 0: Tonight we bring you the final final lost coverage from Otacon 2006 which includes, among other things, the famed assassination attempt by Anime World Order on myself and Scott.
Speaker 0: Now before I begin I would like to point out that this is a Geek Nights special.
Speaker 0: For any of our newer listeners this is not a canon episode.
Speaker 0: This is not a normal episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: If you want to hear what Geek Nights is really about and this is the first episode you've ever heard, I suggest you check out any other of the approximately 190 episodes we've got up on the website and in the feed that do not contain the word "special" in the title.
Speaker 0: Now to provide a little background, this is a recording that we did shortly after the Webcomics roundtable that we recorded at Otacon with the Anime World Order guys and Fast Karate for the Gentlemen Ninja Consultants, a few other people were around.
Speaker 0: It was about two in the morning.
Speaker 0: I was both drunk and exhausted.
Speaker 0: My throat was so scratchy I could barely talk.
Speaker 0: Scott was doing equally miserably and we were attempting to have some sort of panel discussion.
Speaker 0: This discussion, for anyone who is not fully aware, ended in myself being shot in the face with a clown pistol, shortly followed by Scott being shot in the face with a clown pistol.
Speaker 0: Now you might be wondering what is a clown pistol?
Speaker 0: Well, I think you're just going to have to listen to the following.
Speaker 0: I apologize for the audio quality and that I'm not going to even bother trying to clean this up.
Speaker 0: Now there are a lot of conspiracy theories as to why this content was not provided immediately after Otacon, ranging from the fact that we actually died as a result of injury sustained and we've been covering up ever since with clever robot voices, to some sort of conspiracy to cover up any sort of discontent among the masses or assassination attempts thereby.
Speaker 0: The sad, sad truth is simply that GarageBand made a weird file and I didn't want to bother trying to get it out and do the things necessary to make it able to be put into an episode of Geek Nights, let alone to clean it up and deal with all of the artifacts from the fact that there were a bunch of drunken people at two in the morning trying to record a podcast.
Speaker 0: But because we are going to Sitacon this weekend and we are not doing a normal show today, I had plenty of time to finally slap something together.
Speaker 0: So at last, at long last, what the moment you have all been waiting for, the first of I assume to be many assassination attempts on Rim and Scott of Geek Nights, as well as some commentary about Otacon, you know that con we were all at at the time.
Speaker 0: So we're here at Otacon 2006 with the Geek Nights crew and the Anime World Order crew and this is going to be a very free-form, somewhat alcohol-filled romp through, at least from my part, alcohol-filled, romp through Otacon.
Speaker 2: Well, the first two days is currently Saturday night, pre-Geek Nights panel.
Speaker 0: So of course first, let's have everyone introduce themselves so voices are actually understood as who they are.
Speaker 3: Yeah, it's not actually just the Anime World Order crew, but I guess since you mentioned the Anime World Order crew, we may as well introduce ourselves.
Speaker 3: I'm Daryl Surratt from Anime World Order.
Speaker 3: I've got Tom, a podcast about World Order and anime.
Speaker 1: And I'm Gerald Rathgeld, the other one-third of that.
Speaker 2: The Muppets Eagle Rathgeld.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Muppets Eagle Stephen Hawking's butthead.
Speaker 2: I was with the Muppets Eagle thing, but when he said like the butthead, I was like,
Speaker 2: "What?".
Speaker 0: And of course, the rest of our panelists here, I apologize for their audio quality, but they were using the cheapest microphone we have through no fault of their own.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I apologize for my audio quality too, but that just comes with the territory being me.
Speaker 2: I'm Noah Fulmore of the Ninja Consultant podcast.
Speaker 4: Joel and I apologize for no such audio quality.
Speaker 4: I'm Dave Riley of Fast Karate for the Gentlemen.
Speaker 1: And I am Joel White, the other half of Fast Karate for the Gentlemen at JoelandDave.com.
Speaker 1: That wasn't my decision.
Speaker 0: And of course, in case this footage ever appears anywhere, it's not really footage, I'm Rym.
Speaker 2: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 2: Great.
Speaker 2: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I guess I'll let... Do we want to try to coordinate this?
Speaker 2: Here's a secret.
Speaker 2: We don't really say, "Let's do
Speaker 2: this.".
Speaker 2: We've said it maybe twice.
Speaker 0: We recorded it raw every time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got it right once, and we were like, "Let's use that in every episode forever and see if anyone
Speaker 0: notices.".
Speaker 2: You want to say it?
Speaker 0: Let's try it.
Speaker 0: One, two, three.
Speaker 2: Let's do this.
Speaker 2: That was pretty good.
Speaker 2: Good enough.
Speaker 0: I guess we'll let Gerald and Scott lead the discussion, because you have the schedules in front of you.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I think we should just go through Otakon chronologically speaking.
Speaker 2: So when did we get here?
Speaker 2: We got here Thursday morning.
Speaker 2: What did you guys get?
Speaker 1: I got here Thursday, around Thursday noon.
Speaker 2: Thursday noon?
Speaker 2: Yeah, that was about when we got here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, give or take.
Speaker 3: I was supposed to get here Thursday, 8.15.
Speaker 3: The flight was delayed for roughly an hour and a half, because there were just total ineptitude on the ground people and the air traffic controllers.
Speaker 3: Then I get here, and then I have to carry an extensive amount of obscenely heavy flyers, which we have printed up several thousand.
Speaker 3: The box of flyers weighs 50 pounds.
Speaker 3: I weigh roughly 110.
Speaker 0: Also, I would like to note that he is an Otakon virgin.
Speaker 2: Yeah, how many Otakons has everyone here been to?
Speaker 2: Me and Rem, this is our fifth Otakon.
Speaker 3: Yeah, so the story continues.
Speaker 1: For those of you who don't know, it's exceedingly hot this weekend.
Speaker 3: On Thursday, it was something that feels like 112 degrees Fahrenheit, and so I had to carry this box.
Speaker 3: I got on the train, the light rail, at a mere $1.60, and on the way to the con, the train stopped in the middle of the tracks.
Speaker 3: No lights, not at a stop or anything.
Speaker 3: Total blackness.
Speaker 3: I was expecting judgment night to happen, and then the train starts going backwards.
Speaker 3: It stops for about 20 minutes, and then eventually I got here.
Speaker 1: I got a phone call from him as well, and I'm about to wish him goodbye.
Speaker 3: Not even good luck.
Speaker 2: Tell him about the hobos.
Speaker 2: There's a lot of hobos in Baltimore.
Speaker 0: Baltimore is the home of the hobo.
Speaker 2: Well, they're not technically hobos, they're bums.
Speaker 2: A hobo is someone who actually works and just doesn't have a home and kind of does things that are homeless.
Speaker 4: You guys clearly do not inhabit populated areas.
Speaker 4: Joel and I, being from the wonderful metropolitan area of Philadelphia, are acclimated to spending no less than $2 for a public transit fare, not actually getting to the intended destination, and being harassed by hobos or bums, should you prefer.
Speaker 3: Fortunately, I've played Condemned Criminal Origins and know exactly how to deal with hobos with a wood stick.
Speaker 1: Door of a locker, man.
Speaker 2: All right, so after everyone did or did not get here peacefully or quickly, there was a pre-reg line.
Speaker 2: What did you think of the pre-reg line?
Speaker 0: Are you going to go through every single thing?
Speaker 2: No, no I'm not.
Speaker 2: I'm going to go through the major things.
Speaker 2: I think the pre-reg line is pretty major.
Speaker 2: Is that the only thing that happened on Thursday at all?
Speaker 0: We ran into three cosplayers.
Speaker 0: I asked them what the fuck they thought they were doing, and that was it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I stood next to a really fat man with an Evangelion tattoo, and I got a photograph of it too.
Speaker 0: A really fat man at an anime con.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 4: I've seen that same fat man in years past.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 4: Unit one on what, the left?
Speaker 1: On the right shoulder.
Speaker 4: Oh, there you go.
Speaker 3: You have to be the guy.
Speaker 2: Wow.
Speaker 2: Oh, scary.
Speaker 2: Yeah, the people at the front of the line said they were there since, like, stupid early in the morning, but then we just went out there at, like, six, and it only took ten, fifteen minutes to get through the line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they let us in early just to sit inside there because they were sure that people were going to die from the heat stroke.
Speaker 2: Yeah, yeah, pretty stupid people.
Speaker 2: They had umbrellas though, which is smarter than we were.
Speaker 2: We were not smart enough to bring the umbrella to block out the sun.
Speaker 2: That was an idea we never would have had.
Speaker 2: All right, so fast forward to Friday morning.
Speaker 0: How about two things we did at the con?
Speaker 2: Yeah, what did you do Friday morning?
Speaker 2: Anyone remember?
Speaker 2: You went to work, really?
Speaker 3: We shut up.
Speaker 3: I didn't get here until 9.50 on Friday.
Speaker 2: And you still had to pay the, you know, the three day fare to get in.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I did.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: I spent, I got in and I spent the two hours at the artist's table.
Speaker 4: But we didn't have to wait in the pre-regs line.
Speaker 2: Oh.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 2: Pund.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Did you guys go to any panels?
Speaker 2: We went to...
Speaker 0: Well, fantastically, many of us went to a certain panel just a little while ago.
Speaker 2: Oh, that was...
Speaker 1: On Friday?
Speaker 1: On Friday morning?
Speaker 2: On Friday morning we went to the OC remix panel.
Speaker 2: Oh yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2: Where we finally got permission from DJ Fredzel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, our opening song, we never actually got permission, technically.
Speaker 0: We just asked him for it and he didn't answer and that was good enough.
Speaker 2: Yep.
Speaker 2: So, and we figure he gives the MP3 away for free, he doesn't mind.
Speaker 2: And he didn't mind, he was totally cool, but yeah.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually stay at the panel, so I can't talk about it.
Speaker 2: It was actually, as panels go, it was pretty good because they had live performances and stuff.
Speaker 2: They played music and they sang stuff.
Speaker 2: It was much more than I expected.
Speaker 2: And then some people actually asked some moderately intelligent questions.
Speaker 1: I went to the Sentai panel.
Speaker 1: I don't have anything funny to say about it, but they played a 16 minute clip of every single opening to every single Super Sentai show that's ever been created.
Speaker 3: I think lots and lots of running away from explosions and rock quarries.
Speaker 2: Did they seriously do every- Are you sure it was every single one ever?
Speaker 1: Every single Super Sentai.
Speaker 1: Ah.
Speaker 3: Which is totally different from Battle Heroes and Kamen Rider.
Speaker 4: We've done the research and they're all pretty much the same.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, were they?
Speaker 0: Well, was the panel well done at least?
Speaker 1: It was very well done.
Speaker 1: These people seemed to know what they were doing.
Speaker 1: Well, that makes one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Then again, I only stood there for the video, so whoever did that video was really good.
Speaker 1: I walked out after it.
Speaker 3: Yeah, I was thinking of going to History of Gainax, but it was just two dudes I'd never heard of with no visual aids whatsoever talking about how Gainax existed there.
Speaker 0: Seems a lot of panels were like that this year.
Speaker 0: There's someone talking about something.
Speaker 0: Like, I'm going to talk about something I know nothing about.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's kind of weird.
Speaker 2: When I go to a panel, I expect to be informed about something I do not know.
Speaker 2: If I went to the Super Sentai panel, I would want someone to teach me the difference between Super Sentai and non-Super Sentai.
Speaker 0: Ultra Sentai.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 3: I believe they did go into that to their credit.
Speaker 2: Because then that's a good panel, but the Science in Anime panel, as the contrary, which I spent about less than a minute in, was just nerds going nerd, nerd, nerd, nerd, nerd, and they really didn't have anything intelligent or informative to say at all.
Speaker 2: Totally uninspiring and a waste of time.
Speaker 3: Yeah, on the subject of that, I went to Anime Name That Tune.
Speaker 3: It was run by a girl, and she had decided she'd cut out 300 of these little paper egg-shaped things, and whoever had the most of them at the end would win.
Speaker 3: And she got through about 40 songs because the thing was an hour long, and half the songs were from the same shows, and she's like, "Well, this is probably the second oldest thing I've got, and I've lost at life and have to commit ritual suicide because someone else beat me to Fist of the North Star.
Speaker 2: Part
Speaker 2: two.".
Speaker 2: Part two?
Speaker 3: No, no, tough boy.
Speaker 0: Tough boy.
Speaker 1: And yeah, I gave up on going to see Nobuteru Yuki, the character designer, because I wanted to check out older Otaku, and every year before they had these real old guys there, these guys that were watching Astro Boy and 8-Man when it came on TV.
Speaker 1: This year, they had guys that were my age.
Speaker 0: Isn't that a scary feeling?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then they were talking about, oh, back in the day of Streamline and trading tapes.
Speaker 1: I wanted people back in the day of Super 8, back in the day before Color TV.
Speaker 2: Well, there are some of those guys that were at the Club Summit, actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are those guys who ... I don't know their names or anything.
Speaker 2: I don't know what their club is.
Speaker 2: What's the name of their club again?
Speaker 0: I don't even remember.
Speaker 2: But there are these three guys who've been coming to the Club Summit every year, as long as we've been here, because they run this anime club of old guys.
Speaker 2: It's like this community club, and they watch the oldest stuff you've ever heard of.
Speaker 2: It's way cool when they talk about it.
Speaker 3: That's why it's called Oldurotaku, but not Oldist.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Oldotaku.
Speaker 2: I mean, it's like they're talking about 8th Man, and 8th Man is new stuff to them.
Speaker 3: Tobor the 8th Man, the brand new prehistoric monster.
Speaker 3: I don't even remember the lyrics to that stupid song.
Speaker 3: Something about how the FBI is helpless back in the days when the FBI was capable of repelling alien invasion.
Speaker 1: I should mention it took about 45 minutes to get into the dealer's room after the line got moving, an hour after the line got moving.
Speaker 0: I don't know what was up with that, because usually people don't line up in that quantity for the dealer's room in Otakon.
Speaker 0: That was a surprise.
Speaker 1: What was interesting was that the line got longer as it started moving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why was that?
Speaker 0: I mean, there was nothing else to do with Otakon?
Speaker 2: I think that had something to do with just not pushing people into the room fast enough.
Speaker 2: I mean, usually on Friday, the line builds up, and then as soon as the room opens, the line disappears in less than an hour, less than a half hour.
Speaker 2: But this year, it just stuck around for a long, long time, and they couldn't get people into the room fast enough.
Speaker 2: And yet they close it at 8 on Friday, and at 6 on Saturday.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: Why?
Speaker 0: A lot of cons have been closing dealer's rooms earlier and earlier these years.
Speaker 2: I think it's possibly to encourage, because when the dealer's room is open, that pretty much takes away a giant pile of people from any event that's going on.
Speaker 2: So if they want to encourage people to go to certain events, they'll close the dealer's room earlier, open it later.
Speaker 3: And that's what Otakon needs, more people at the events, because there just aren't enough people at Otakon to go around.
Speaker 2: Once they close the dealer's room, they can't seat everybody anywhere.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it is true.
Speaker 0: Though at least Otakon has mitigated that now.
Speaker 0: I mean, the Masquerade can seat like 15,000 people now.
Speaker 0: If you want to see the Masquerade, you can see it.
Speaker 0: There's no longer a question of getting into that room.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that did used to be a problem where people would line up for the cosplay, and only some of them would get in, and the rest would go, "Ah,
Speaker 2: dammit.".
Speaker 2: Now, the number one biggest event at the entire con, anyone who wants to see it can see it, and they just have to walk down the street.
Speaker 2: The thing is, I didn't really notice when... When that was going on, the con would be empty, but I never really noticed the con being empty.
Speaker 0: Because a lot of people are like us, and we'd never go to masquerades ever, for various reasons ranging from dislike of cosplay to dislike of cosplay.
Speaker 2: To the fact that, you know...
Speaker 0: Well, cosplay skits at least.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I mean, the cosplay is traditionally, there are three awesome skits that are entertaining as hell, and then the rest of them are painful, painful, painful.
Speaker 3: Three?
Speaker 3: That's generous.
Speaker 2: That is generous.
Speaker 2: It is Otakon, so there would be three at Otakon, and there would be one or fewer at any other?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that Muppet-Utena one a few years ago.
Speaker 2: That was just amazing.
Speaker 2: That was amazing, but it's really just not worth it to sit through 30 terrible ones to see the three.
Speaker 3: I, for one, am quite glad that I don't even know where that cosplay was held.
Speaker 3: It was in some magic building.
Speaker 0: There's the Baltimore, what's it called?
Speaker 0: The First Mariner Arena, which is a hockey arena.
Speaker 2: It was where the Larkins Yale concert was.
Speaker 3: Oh, okay, that.
Speaker 3: Yeah, full-on arena.
Speaker 3: At the convention I've never been to before.
Speaker 2: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: But, yeah, at night, you think all the stuff at night's 18+, you know, all the kids would go home, and they did, but, you know, everything still filled up like crazy.
Speaker 2: I mean, even frickin', what was that movie we just went to?
Speaker 2: I forget what it's called.
Speaker 2: Sex and Fury?
Speaker 2: Oh, boy.
Speaker 2: It just filled up with people, and then halfway through the movie, all the people left.
Speaker 2: It's like, why did you get in line in the first place?
Speaker 0: Yeah, did you guys hit any of that?
Speaker 4: Because the name of the movie is Sex and Fury.
Speaker 2: I know.
Speaker 0: 18+ content?
Speaker 3: And they must have all realized there's far too much sex and not nearly enough fury.
Speaker 2: That was, I was going personally for the Fury, and I was dealt with too much sex, and...
Speaker 3: There was no man in a space suit with a flamethrower blasting off into the cosmonaut.
Speaker 3: The Fury, yeah.
Speaker 3: And Lethal Weapon 4, that's right.
Speaker 3: Opening scene where Danny Glover has to dance like a chicken.
Speaker 1: Okay, so, back to what we were doing.
Speaker 2: Yeah, did anyone go to any of those other 18+ nighttime things that we didn't go to?
Speaker 1: Confidentially, yes.
Speaker 2: Well, I meant...
Speaker 0: Well, in the interest of journalism.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, what did I see?
Speaker 2: Let's see, what was there?
Speaker 2: Did anyone actually go to the...
Speaker 0: I mean, actually, at Gerald's recommendation, I went and watched a good movie.
Speaker 0: 15 minutes of...
Speaker 2: We've been trying to figure it out.
Speaker 3: It was drawing hentai, is my understanding.
Speaker 2: That's what our understanding was too, but we're not sure.
Speaker 4: That's totally weak that you would name your panel that.
Speaker 2: I think they named it that to attract people, and it worked because they're...
Speaker 3: And then the con guide, when you look at it, it just says hentai drawing.
Speaker 3: Like, they wussed out on it.
Speaker 3: It says do-it-yourself bukake on this.
Speaker 2: Read the, uh, read it from the book.
Speaker 2: Read it from the book.
Speaker 3: It's written there, but it's changed on, like, the revised schedule.
Speaker 3: Yeah.
Speaker 3: Like, if it's do-it-yourself... Well, don't make the girl wait.
Speaker 3: No, listen.
Speaker 3: That is not the terrifying panel.
Speaker 3: That's the panel with the most terrifying name.
Speaker 3: The terrifying panel was the hookups panel.
Speaker 3: Oh my god, yes.
Speaker 3: Let's get social.
Speaker 2: Oh, Scott Johnson went to that, didn't he?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there wasn't the ratio of men to women, like, three to one, and that only increased as the night went on.
Speaker 4: Did you say only three to one?
Speaker 3: I don't know.
Speaker 3: There were a lot of things.
Speaker 3: I just walked in and was terrified by.
Speaker 3: The anime parliament.
Speaker 3: I walked in.
Speaker 2: Oh, god.
Speaker 3: Have you ever been to one of those before?
Speaker 3: No, no, I never heard of it.
Speaker 2: It's like, what is this?
Speaker 0: Did you know what it was walking into it?
Speaker 3: No, I was like, anime parliament.
Speaker 3: What are they gonna do?
Speaker 3: And then it's like, huh?
Speaker 2: They have those at a lot of Northeast cons, and it's quite frightening.
Speaker 3: Note to self, never attend Northeast cons.
Speaker 2: No, just never attend anime parliament.
Speaker 1: Wait, what is anime parliament?
Speaker 3: Yeah, what is anime parliament?
Speaker 3: Anime parliament is... Free bonus gear!
Speaker 0: I mean, you just saw, you experienced it for the first time.
Speaker 3: I walked in and walked out instantly just because it was like, oh, well, the archangel has been sentenced to being a ripoff of...
Speaker 0: The way it was explained to me, because I have never stayed in one of these for more than about 15.5 seconds, is that people who have a grievance with an anime will come in and say, like, my favorite character shouldn't have died in this show.
Speaker 0: And then the panel will pass judgment, like, yeah, they shouldn't have.
Speaker 0: They're hereby alive.
Speaker 1: So that's not even really parliament.
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: All right, allow me to read...
Speaker 2: Sit down, sit down, sit down.
Speaker 2: Allow me to read the description from the con book here.
Speaker 0: Ava didn't end like that.
Speaker 2: At anime parliament, you, as your chosen character, can strive, so there's role-playing involved, can strive to clear your name, get justice, or argue for admission into another anime universe.
Speaker 2: Bring witnesses to provide counter defenses and increase your chances of swaying the pose.
Speaker 0: All right, the looks on everyone's faces were priceless, as that was read.
Speaker 1: Just the black hole of...
Speaker 0: This is just, I expect a guy to walk in in a football jersey and scream,
Speaker 0: "Nerds!"
Speaker 0: That would be so great.
Speaker 4: You could be like Gendo Akari and be like, "No, rape and incest is totally
Speaker 4: cool.".
Speaker 1: That's pretty lame that they couldn't even get the name right, because they're not actually legislating.
Speaker 1: They're adjudicated.
Speaker 3: No, it's anime supreme court.
Speaker 3: Where's James Caan when you need him?
Speaker 3: He's an expert in the aforementioned art of adjudication.
Speaker 1: Part of it isn't exactly a foreign concept in the Western world.
Speaker 1: You can look up the rules to parliament anywhere, in a local library, the internet.
Speaker 3: Nobody else likes the way of the gun.
Speaker 3: Robert's Rules of Order comes second nature to otaku.
Speaker 2: They do indeed.
Speaker 0: That is in fact the second time in this con that Robert's Rules of Order have come up, because I talked about it extensively in our panel.
Speaker 3: At the Anime Club Summit, whether or not Robert's Rules of Order need to be invoked.
Speaker 2: Occasionally they do.
Speaker 2: They are very important.
Speaker 3: In terms of other things that were very important, we went to I Can't Believe You Haven't Seen That, which is a panel that we had just ripped off ourselves.
Speaker 1: One week ago.
Speaker 3: About one week ago, and we wanted to see how the real pros would do it.
Speaker 3: It turns out you were the pros.
Speaker 3: Yeah, well...
Speaker 1: They didn't do a bad job.
Speaker 1: They were good guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's no humor in there.
Speaker 2: What did they not believe?
Speaker 2: I haven't seen?
Speaker 3: They had things like Future Boy Conan and Bobby's Girl, which is this really obscure madhouse OAV.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I never heard of that.
Speaker 3: That Gerald and this guy are the only people on the planet to own.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 3: And then they also had perennial classics such as Riding Bean.
Speaker 2: Riding Bean!
Speaker 2: I saw Riding Bean at the Anime Club Library.
Speaker 1: And the special How to Teach Your Children Absolutely Useless English through Doraemon.
Speaker 1: Singing things like.
Speaker 1: I've Been Working on the Railroad.
Speaker 1: I saw that!
Speaker 3: I recently saw that!
Speaker 3: Did you see it with the ridiculous warning subtitles?
Speaker 3: Like, warning, hobos will take your money in.
Speaker 3: Well, you don't actually work on the railroads.
Speaker 3: Yeah, and then they closed things off by showing The Wizard of Speed and Time.
Speaker 2: I don't know what that is, but it sounds awesome.
Speaker 3: I can't believe you haven't seen that!
Speaker 3: And then the other panel.
Speaker 3: I was sort of let down by... Actually, let me back up.
Speaker 3: Digital Fan Subbing.
Speaker 3: That was like Live Evil.
Speaker 3: The panel.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 3: What did they say?
Speaker 3: They talked about how much better they are than professional subtitlers.
Speaker 3: Because they put a billion liner notes on the screen as someone talks.
Speaker 2: And they use fancy... It's all about karaoke opening theme songs.
Speaker 2: Yeah!
Speaker 2: It's all about fancy fonts that sometimes are hard to read.
Speaker 0: I mean, that makes it.
Speaker 0: Fullmetal Alchemist crap without that karaoke.
Speaker 1: Also, failing to interpret context.
Speaker 1: Very important in any fan sub operation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, being very liberal with use of obscenities.
Speaker 3: Then the next panel.
Speaker 3: I went to... I'd gone to this because of the recommendation of Aaron from the Weekly Anime Review podcast who's forgettably not here because it's like three in the morning.
Speaker 3: It's Your Favorite Anime Sucks, the panel.
Speaker 0: I had high hopes for that.
Speaker 3: I had really high hopes for it because on other internet message boards I have as my avatar Your Favorite Anime Sucks.
Speaker 3: And I do panels at conventions entitled Anime That Sucks.
Speaker 3: But my approach is that I show clips of anime that sucks and their approach is, "Well, we're three guys on stage and the audience, we're gonna call people from the audience and they're just gonna say an anime name and we're just gonna fire back why it
Speaker 3: sucks.".
Speaker 3: Which, I guess if you're really fast on your feet, and to these guys' credit, they were all really fast on their feet, it could work.
Speaker 3: But I just didn't think it was funny.
Speaker 3: I don't know.
Speaker 4: Could you give an example of what was said?
Speaker 3: Alright.
Speaker 3: Someone said something like... They had a few things worked out in advance, you could tell.
Speaker 3: Someone said, "Oh, Bleach is the obvious
Speaker 3: one.".
Speaker 3: And then they said,
Speaker 3: "Alright.".
Speaker 3: And then they all put their mics down and said, "Alright, let's do a trust
Speaker 3: check.".
Speaker 3: And then one guy got behind him and he's like, "Alright, trust
Speaker 3: And he fell back and caught the guy.
Speaker 3: And he's like, "Alright, now, Bleach, do that with
Speaker 3: swords.".
Speaker 3: That's the joke.
Speaker 2: I was gonna make the cricket noise.
Speaker 3: And then things like, "Space Runaway
Speaker 3: Idion.".
Speaker 3: The guy who was running the panel happened to have an Idion shirt on.
Speaker 3: And he said, "This is a show where a five-year-old girl, you get to see her head burned to a crisp, and then everyone in the universe
Speaker 3: dies.".
Speaker 3: And I said, "Wait a second, I thought you said explain why the anime sucks, not why it's totally freaking
Speaker 3: awesome.".
Speaker 1: They put you on the stage.
Speaker 3: They didn't call on me.
Speaker 3: I had my hand up for a good hour straight.
Speaker 3: 'cause they must have sensed...
Speaker 2: What anime were you gonna say if they called on you?
Speaker 3: I was gonna say Madbolt 34.
Speaker 3: And any reason they could have possibly given me for why the anime was bad would in fact have been...
Speaker 2: I think that would be the trick, is to name an anime.
Speaker 2: they never heard of that way.
Speaker 2: What did they say about it?
Speaker 3: Well, they took great pride in the fact that it's impossible to stump us 'cause we know every single anime that you could possibly name.
Speaker 1: Don't ever say that around us.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 3: They were smart to not call on me.
Speaker 2: Also, they got one wrong.
Speaker 2: Someone called out High School Rumble and they confused it, I think, with Combustible Campus Guardress.
Speaker 1: And while Daryl was at this panel, I was witnessing Art in Motion.
Speaker 1: I was at the movie Belladonna.
Speaker 1: And this is a... It's supposed to be a porno movie that Osamu Tezuka did.
Speaker 1: I don't know what was going on in that movie.
Speaker 1: What are you doing, Daryl?
Speaker 3: I'm seizing the microphone from you so I can mention how.
Speaker 3: if you thought the experimental shorts that Geek Notes reviewed by Tezuka a few weeks back were weird, Belladonna...
Speaker 1: Yeah, we ran into... Belladonna, holy shit.
Speaker 1: There was a scene in there of a woman whooping fish that flew into the air and then she ripped herself open and balls fell out of her.
Speaker 2: That reminds me of that thing we saw at the sex museum.
Speaker 2: Oh, God.
Speaker 2: Remember that?
Speaker 0: Because Adam and I ran into Daryl after he'd come out of that, obviously, and he mentioned it and I was like, "Tezuka porn.
Speaker 0: There's no
Speaker 0: way.".
Speaker 0: So I went and it's a woman talking to this demon who turns into a giant penis and then there's this yellow submarine kind of sex scene and I have no idea what was going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I saw that scene where she was supposedly having sex and she got fatter and fatter and fatter and exploded.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, the camera's zooming in more and more and more.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 3: You can buy this movie on DVD.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a three-pack along with Cleopatra, the queen of sex, and A Thousand and One Nights, and Cleopatra has Mark Anthony fighting in a gladiatorial combat and he gets thrown a handgun.
Speaker 2: We gotta get that.
Speaker 0: Yes, we have to review that.
Speaker 2: Is that not how it happened?
Speaker 1: And Julius Caesar as Syphilis.
Speaker 2: Yeah, when they...
Speaker 1: There's a ninja as well and there's Gamelons, I swear to God.
Speaker 2: What's the limit on that?
Speaker 0: We're good, we're good.
Speaker 2: I like my history better with Gamelons.
Speaker 1: So everyone out there, find Belladonna.
Speaker 1: You will never be the same again.
Speaker 2: God.
Speaker 1: Wait, you're recommending it on those grounds?
Speaker 1: Holy shit, yes.
Speaker 3: He was shaking, he was sweating, his eye, his pupils were fully dilated.
Speaker 2: The man was jittering.
Speaker 2: We have it on tape.
Speaker 4: Now that was something else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's one thing.
Speaker 0: listeners of all of our shows here, if any of us say don't watch something, we're not saying don't watch it as in oh my god it's hilarious.
Speaker 0: watch it because it's bad.
Speaker 0: We're like don't watch it.
Speaker 2: Just don't fucking watch it.
Speaker 2: You're wasting precious moments in your life.
Speaker 0: Empty geist.
Speaker 2: You're only going to live for probably around 60 to 80 years, you know, why spend a whole hour of it watching something completely terrible and that will only bring you pain.
Speaker 2: Unless you're into that sort of thing.
Speaker 2: Because it makes really awesome podcasts.
Speaker 1: That's the entire purpose of our podcast really.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Meanwhile, speaking of terrible.
Speaker 3: To trick people into watching horrible things.
Speaker 2: Speaking of terrible things, while they were watching Belladonna and whatnot, I watched Lady Terminator followed by Art of the Devil 2.
Speaker 2: Lady Terminator was.
Speaker 2: it was so stupid.
Speaker 2: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: So why did you watch it?
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: We walked into it and like in the middle of it.
Speaker 0: I was out experiencing art.
Speaker 0: You know, giant penis demons.
Speaker 2: This was, well there were penises I guess.
Speaker 2: It was a woman acting much in the same way.
Speaker 0: Could you be a little more specific?
Speaker 2: Alright well, the Lady Terminator most of the people she killed blows them down with an Uzi that has infinite ammo somehow.
Speaker 2: But occasionally she would like take her shirt off you know, use her moderate breasts to attract some men.
Speaker 2: Then she, you know, they would Of course.
Speaker 2: Wait, was this a live action movie?
Speaker 2: Yes it was.
Speaker 1: I've seen this movie before.
Speaker 2: She would have sex with them and then they would die of like bloody face pukake somehow.
Speaker 0: Someone just explained to us that there was some sort of snake in her that was biting them.
Speaker 2: I think that's what someone did say but I wasn't sure.
Speaker 2: Looks like a ninja scroll.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 2: Later on in the movie she inexplicably acquired a third means of dealing out death which were eye lasers.
Speaker 2: that could, well, when fired at a helicopter caused it to explode.
Speaker 2: when fired at a man, they caused him to fall down and die, but when fired at the main character they just didn't do anything at all.
Speaker 2: Awesome.
Speaker 2: The eye lasers are completely unexplained.
Speaker 1: Eye lasers from who's eyes?
Speaker 1: Her eyes?
Speaker 2: From the Lady Terminator's eyes.
Speaker 1: So she shot them into a mirror and they bounced back?
Speaker 2: No, she shot them at a helicopter which exploded.
Speaker 2: Oh, the main character.
Speaker 2: The main character was some white blonde guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: I thought she was the main character.
Speaker 2: No, no, no, she was like, you know, it was more like the John Connor couldn't be killed with the eye lasers.
Speaker 2: She was the title character but not... Exactly.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess we should probably move this along a bit mostly to the fact that I'm going to pass out due to tiredness.
Speaker 2: And we have a panel tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: General impressions of the con.
Speaker 0: The dealer's room.
Speaker 0: How was it?
Speaker 0: What do you think?
Speaker 1: I spent $120 there on Monday buying cool stuff so I was kind of happy.
Speaker 0: The front row crew combined bought, I think, five box sets of giant robo.
Speaker 2: And like four Zeta Gundam boxes because they were $40.
Speaker 1: I got all of Master Keaton that I didn't already have.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 2: Yes, we got that.
Speaker 4: Whoever bought all Master Keaton and all Big O box sets, man, F you.
Speaker 2: But there were none left.
Speaker 2: Isn't that what you're saying?
Speaker 4: There weren't any left like last night.
Speaker 2: Oh, man.
Speaker 2: That's rough.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Screw that guy, though, for having Crying Freemen.
Speaker 2: volume one and three and not two.
Speaker 2: Making three unbuyable and two not being there also unbuyable.
Speaker 0: Honestly, though, the dealer's room was generally not... I'm just jaded, I think.
Speaker 0: It wasn't impressive anymore because it's mostly bleach and Naruto and like the same Gundam seed things every year now.
Speaker 1: Well, it's kind of hard to be impressed by a dealer's room.
Speaker 1: True.
Speaker 1: Which is why I spent $120 buying really freaking obscure weird stuff.
Speaker 1: That wasn't porn related.
Speaker 1: I better make that clear.
Speaker 2: The thing is like a lot of the weird stuff we see is either just weird old crap.
Speaker 2: You don't want it or it's like I saw this great Galaxy Express poster from back in the day and it was like 30 bucks and I'm like, oh, I like that but I'm not paying 30 bucks for a movie poster.
Speaker 3: Yeah, there was another poster from the same dealer that I was considering getting a $25 theatrical poster for Odin.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 2: I would pay $25 for that.
Speaker 2: That is totally worth it.
Speaker 2: But yet, I notice a lot of things are missing from the dealer's room this year.
Speaker 2: Like, uh, Viz wasn't there.
Speaker 2: Anyone see Viz?
Speaker 2: No.
Speaker 2: Viz, they usually give out those awesome bags.
Speaker 2: They weren't here last year, though, either, were they?
Speaker 2: I think they were.
Speaker 2: They gave out all the free bags again.
Speaker 2: Somebody missed it last year.
Speaker 2: Yeah, and Bandai totally dropped the ball this year.
Speaker 2: They usually sell all kinds of awesome robot shit.
Speaker 0: Bandai didn't even try to muscle their way into our panel like all the other companies.
Speaker 2: Bandai was nowhere to be seen.
Speaker 2: I was like, where'd they go?
Speaker 3: They were somewhere to be seen.
Speaker 3: They were there in the $5 DVD section.
Speaker 3: It's all Bandai stuff.
Speaker 2: Yeah, if you can't make it to a convention, I think, what's the website of the $5 DVD guy?
Speaker 2: They're awesome.
Speaker 2: Buy right?
Speaker 3: Buy right DVDs.
Speaker 3: We get to buy 15 of each thing before you can get the prices.
Speaker 1: Or sailors if you buy it off the website, really.
Speaker 2: Not cool.
Speaker 0: Do you guys hang out in the artist alley much?
Speaker 0: Check out all the art at the art show.
Speaker 1: Only fags are in the artist alley.
Speaker 1: Easy.
Speaker 2: Only fags and only cool booze.
Speaker 2: I guess it might be more evidence to our listeners that we're gay.
Speaker 1: By fag, you mean awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the art room was all right.
Speaker 0: I saw a lot of it.
Speaker 0: Do you guys check out the art show?
Speaker 0: It's been my experience.
Speaker 0: I like big cons and I like small cons, but small con art shows have just been really bad this year.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's like you go to a con that's maybe a quarter the size of Otacon, but the art show is 1/100th the size.
Speaker 0: It's all the same tracings of the same scenes from Naruto.
Speaker 2: It'll be like four pictures on a bulletin board.
Speaker 1: You don't have the art show personalities that we have in Florida, or at least we had in Florida.
Speaker 3: That are exceedingly hairy people.
Speaker 3: No offense to anyone who is present right now.
Speaker 3: Instead of setting up in the artist alley, they just set up a random table somewhere in a high traffic area and blare really loud obnoxious music.
Speaker 3: He's been banned from every Florida convention that I know of.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I thought the art show was pretty good this year compared to past years.
Speaker 0: I bid on things.
Speaker 0: It's rare for me to bid on things.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I don't think I've ever bid on anything before, but there was this cool Phoenix Wright and the minimum bid was like five bucks, so I was like hells.
Speaker 2: yeah.
Speaker 2: Comes in a frame.
Speaker 2: The frames are usually five bucks at the freaking store.
Speaker 2: Five bucks for a frame with a picture in it.
Speaker 0: Chris, we didn't delve into the porn room.
Speaker 2: No, no we did not.
Speaker 2: Did anyone else go in the porn part of the art show?
Speaker 1: There was a porn part?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was hidden off and you had to be 18.
Speaker 2: Yeah, usually in past I noticed that this year they've done a lot more of the 18+ checking than in past years.
Speaker 2: I mean, it used to be you could have gone to see each of the killer three years ago without an ID check.
Speaker 2: In the artist's alley the porn was separated by a divider, but you could just walk back there.
Speaker 2: If you were a little kid and someone saw you, they might be like "Hey, what are you
Speaker 2: doing?".
Speaker 2: This year they were checking I18+ to go into the hidden area, which is more hidden than ever before.
Speaker 4: Man, not being able to just walk down the aisle and see a picture of say, Lena inverse getting a free limb It's like totally a different convention, man.
Speaker 1: Is that like roots getting root?
Speaker 1: I think I've got that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not going to complain about that at all because if anything it means I just don't get exposed to it either.
Speaker 2: I'm not complaining about it.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I'm not complaining.
Speaker 2: I'm actually also glad that I don't accidentally see nasty hentais.
Speaker 4: It's just, you know, I noticed You do still have to deal with the fairy eyes yourself for 275.
Speaker 2: I can't believe that guy has such a specific skill.
Speaker 2: I mean, talk about a one trick pony.
Speaker 2: I mean, he could have said "I paint you into something".
Speaker 2: No, only fairies.
Speaker 0: I would have gone with centaur but not fairy Of course, like three people independently Like, "Rim, you should do that.
Speaker 0: It'll be
Speaker 0: awesome.".
Speaker 2: We
Speaker 4: wanted to get one for
Speaker 3: one of our buddies
Speaker 1: Less than 270 dollars.
Speaker 1: That guy would have had like five commissions.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like he's right over there, here's his picture as gay as possible.
Speaker 0: So I actually have a question for Daryl while you're here about.
Speaker 0: You've been to the two prime days of Otacon.
Speaker 0: What do you think of this con?
Speaker 3: I mean, it's freaking huge I don't know, I think something's Something's kind of missing from this whole thing.
Speaker 3: It's like All the elements are there Sort of, it's like Oh, you look at the list You see, like, oh, well We've got our art show We've got our cosplay We've got our AMVs We've got our panels We've got our dealer's room.
Speaker 3: What is missing?
Speaker 3: What is the?
Speaker 3: I don't know, there's something about it that is just not there to make it an anime con for me and it's like I went an excessive distance and I think I can sum it up in about three words.
Speaker 3: uh seek semper tyrannis.
Speaker 0: Now, the sound you just heard was that of a clown pistol, which is a small explosive device being detonated directly in my face followed by my death screen.
Speaker 0: If you ever run into me in the street and blow something up in my face, you will probably hear a similar scream.
Speaker 0: Now at that moment, the room went into silence for a second, and then everyone wondered well, does he have any more of these clown pistols?
Speaker 0: Scott specifically was wondering this and then, he shot Scott in the face with a clown pistol.
Speaker 0: I've got two.
Speaker 0: that should be enough for all of you.
Speaker 1: I inadvertently left these in my bag.
Speaker 3: I'm very glad I wasn't arrested by airport security.
Speaker 0: I think you realize how often we've spoken of fucking clown pistols ever since you brought them up and we didn't know what they were and then we googled for them and you guys show up as the number one link.
Speaker 3: clown pistols are not an official term (laughter) and I just throw them down like I'm 47 and steal off into the night.
Speaker 3: now coming here was worth it.
Speaker 3: it was always worth it.
Speaker 2: stupid clown pistols are not acquireable in our northeastern states.
Speaker 0: yeah, you realize fireworks are totally bad, like we have to drive to Tennessee to get anything Pennsylvania has just bottle rockets sweet snake action.
Speaker 3: listen, I had to sign a legal document stating that I was going to use these in compliance with a very specific Florida law stating that the detonation of fireworks is permitted only if you're using them to frighten away birds (laughter).
Speaker 2: is that true?
Speaker 3: listen, it's shaped like a gun (laughter).
Speaker 3: you don't shape something like this like a gun if it's not meant to be pointed at another human being.
Speaker 0: and that was Geek Nights with Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 2: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 2: if you like our podcasts you'll love our forums, make sure you visit them.
Speaker 2: you can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com and if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 2: Geek Nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience but unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.