Speaker 0: It's Tuesday April 11th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talked about Tetris DS But you're gonna have to wade through a whole bunch of other stuff We talked about until you get to it, so if you only want to hear about Tetris fast forward now Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well before we actually get into the news and the show and all that as we usually do we have some meta type things to Say, but they're somewhat unorthodox today.
Speaker 0: Unorthodox you say.
Speaker 0: could they possibly be conservative or reform?
Speaker 0: Or maybe they're more than Orthodox.
Speaker 0: They're Hasidic.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: That was not funny which is?
Speaker 0: You don't know who the bubbishes are?
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 0: I'll explain it to you sometime.
Speaker 0: Okay, they're like the craziest of Jews.
Speaker 0: the love of it is okay, all right All right, so as I said yesterday, and I'm gonna say every day this week of course I'm gonna explain it a lot less than I explained it yesterday.
Speaker 0: The forum sends you an email when we approve your membership to the forum unlike other forums.
Speaker 0: So you're immediately automatically approved.
Speaker 0: However some people have spam filters and those spam filters are blocking the email and as a result There are many people who have applied for membership to our forums who have been accepted and they've never come back.
Speaker 0: If you never come back because you're not listening anymore well You're not listening anymore if you haven't come back because you didn't get an email saying you were approved.
Speaker 0: guess what you got approved.
Speaker 0: Come and sign into the forums and have fun.
Speaker 1: We've never turned anyone away.
Speaker 1: yet.
Speaker 0: not yet however One person who he did this call yesterday the flaming geek or the flaming geek or now.
Speaker 1: I'll warn you right now This is not something we're going to do often now.
Speaker 1: those of you who've been listening long enough know that we're very intolerant of certain things Namely a pseudoscience Scientologists lying Stupidity in general bad grammar yeah All those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: well We're opinionated for this and background information.
Speaker 0: someone applied to the forums a long time ago named like the flaming geek or whatever And I approved them, and they never showed up.
Speaker 0: Of course I'm pretty sure it was due to the email problem because they applied again a few weeks later and I approved their second account and Okay They still didn't show up.
Speaker 0: then I discovered the email problem and yesterday.
Speaker 0: I made the announcement on the show and today The flaming geek signed into his account and started posting.
Speaker 1: now at first we thought all right.
Speaker 1: a new member to the forum.
Speaker 1: the forums Are growing very quickly.
Speaker 1: yep awesome now I hate to directly call someone out, but I'm very much a fan of calling people out, so I actually don't hate this at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and After examining all the evidence there is only a point zero zero one percent doubt on our part.
Speaker 1: So I guess I'll say this right now to the flaming geek if you can prove us wrong You will not only be interviewed on the show for being awesome But we'll probably give you some money and maybe some prizes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the flaming geek you do not live in Japan.
Speaker 0: it is painfully obvious.
Speaker 1: We are fairly certain that you live in or about Miami, Florida.
Speaker 0: your name is Juan.
Speaker 0: We're pretty sure you are Hispanic, and you can't be old.
Speaker 0: you you're either You.
Speaker 0: you either grew up speaking Spanish and are very poor at English You or you are so young that you have not received sufficient education as to speak English pro.
Speaker 1: or or there is the sophisticated answer that You're pretending to speak English poorly in order to bolster the image that you were living in Japan.
Speaker 0: Or you just are the kind of kid who goes through school getting terrible grades, and you're not smart you don't study and yeah Yeah, Scott will really lay India.
Speaker 1: I'll do it slightly more civilly, but that's fine.
Speaker 0: We could do a lot worse.
Speaker 1: The fact remains that I was mostly tipped off when you didn't seem to understand Japanese when it was written in Romaji.
Speaker 1: Yet you claim to be able to read it or type it in the actual Kanna But you can't speak it or know what it sounds like which is really odd to me because Japanese is Really syllable based and the sounds and yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: now Here's a hint for people who want to lie about something.
Speaker 0: don't be Samira Gupta.
Speaker 1: We will tell Samira Oh my god, Samira Gupta is like my favorite guy ever.
Speaker 0: We will tell the story of Samira Gupta in a future episode of geek night.
Speaker 1: suffice to say he has for at least Seven or eight years then living a charade a lie on the internet of epic proportions.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say it in one sentence.
Speaker 0: He goes on slash dot and pretends that he worked for every video game company ever When he of course has never worked for a video and game company ever.
Speaker 1: now the scary thing isn't that people believe this dude Cuz.
Speaker 1: no one believes this dude, they'll be a lot of people do.
Speaker 0: well No people don't believe him.
Speaker 0: over time people believe like they see one post and like and it one post looks good But over every soon as you point out this guy is a history of lying.
Speaker 0: people like oh He's now.
Speaker 1: the scary thing is that if you search on usenet you find a guy posting like in the early 90s Under the same name making the same kinds of claims either.
Speaker 0: It's a conspiracy or it's one, dude We don't know.
Speaker 0: but that's for another episode.
Speaker 1: I think it's like Zorro.
Speaker 1: He just passes the mantle on.
Speaker 0: it could be.
Speaker 0: The point is is that if you're going to lie about something like let's say I wanted to lie about being from Japan on a forum somewhere right number one I would learn a lot about Japan.
Speaker 0: before I said anything about Japan I would look it up and make sure I was saying accurate stuff and that if anyone tried to challenge me by saying You know name all the prefectures of Japan or name the adjacent prefectures, or what street do you live on?
Speaker 0: I would be I would have that shit down.
Speaker 0: You know don't you watch enough movies with this like Hannibal and stuff, and he gets everything perfect You know.
Speaker 0: yeah, well Hannibal was a transhumanist, so yeah - don't keep mentioning it.
Speaker 0: I mean he posted on the frapper map that he was in Tokyo.
Speaker 0: all right He posted in his profile.
Speaker 0: He's in Tokyo or Japan?
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 0: He said in his post you know about himself that he was from Japan.
Speaker 0: Then it seems like half his posts are like yeah, I'm in Japan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm having trouble with Japanese keyboard.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, isn't so crazy that it's so late here yet.
Speaker 0: I'm still posting.
Speaker 0: He said that like two or three times.
Speaker 0: Then he doesn't know what someone means and they say kawaii doesn't a.
Speaker 1: yeah that really got me there.
Speaker 1: Yeah You're gonna lie.
Speaker 0: you gotta be on top of your shit.
Speaker 1: Yep number three if you're going to lie about something and for whatever internet reason you know fake online persona You've really gotta not make too many extraordinary claims all at once.
Speaker 1: I mean born in London moved to Miami then moved to Tokyo.
Speaker 1: all right tiny-ass little apartment in Tokyo.
Speaker 1: all right Terrible English grammar.
Speaker 1: yet you and you use a Japanese OS and yet you don't know spoken Japanese.
Speaker 1: Alright a short dude buys you groceries every week, and you don't understand him.
Speaker 0: You don't leave your apartment And you have some contract with some job that you can't talk about.
Speaker 0: That requires you to stay in this little apartment.
Speaker 1: But yet you can say that you have the job with the contract that you're not allowed to talk about But you can't talk about it, and then you bring up the fact that you can't talk about it.
Speaker 0: It's obviously a poorly not so well thought through made-up story by a little kid.
Speaker 1: Also, I would point out that if you're gonna lie about something like this Someone's gonna trace your IP address at some point, and I traced your IP address to the area of Miami, Florida.
Speaker 0: Now you might make up some story like oh my roommate did something or whatever.
Speaker 0: But first of all you said you live in a little tiny box and second of all There is no way you could have a Miami IP address in Japan.
Speaker 0: no none.
Speaker 1: well There's.
Speaker 1: there's one way.
Speaker 1: if he had someone in the u.s.. Who is on Bell South DSL because like my grandma my grandma's on Bell South the run an HTTP proxy for you, and then you connect to that and then from there connect to the rest of the internet.
Speaker 0: That is possible.
Speaker 0: that is possible however ludicrous.
Speaker 0: It is so ludicrous that if anyone actually were to set that up.
Speaker 0: I would pay you a dollar.
Speaker 1: Really really all right, I'll set one up tonight for Emily who's currently in Japan.
Speaker 0: You have to set it up on Bell South in Florida for someone in Japan.
Speaker 1: Bell South in Florida.
Speaker 1: Why not Comcast up here in Beacon?
Speaker 0: We don't have Comcast.
Speaker 1: We have oh yeah, whatever we have we have C star Online.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah All right, so Fleming geek Either you have to post on the forum with Sufficient evidence to convince two people who are much smarter than you that you are actually in Japan as well as many many people Who know a lot more about Japan than you seem to know.
Speaker 1: yes?
Speaker 0: I mean including people we know in person that are Japanese people that speak Japanese.
Speaker 1: Or how about the fact that Emily is currently living in Japan right now?
Speaker 1: in fact I talked to her over Skype last night right Emily who's been on the show before.
Speaker 0: so Unless you can prove to us with some sort of forum post that you all your claims of Japan are actually correct Um You're going to be ridiculed a great deal, so if you're a mature intelligent person you will come clean.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you come clean, that's fine.
Speaker 1: I mean we're not gonna ban you or anything.
Speaker 1: We want you to listen.
Speaker 1: just uh don't lie to us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because um and this is a note to everyone else out there listening to geek nights.
Speaker 0: We're the last people on earth that you can fool Like we don't want to sound like we're can.
Speaker 0: well no no we're not the last people on earth that you can fool.
Speaker 0: It would be it would be harder to fool.
Speaker 0: perhaps James Randi possibly you could.
Speaker 1: there could be a fooling a con That could get us, but Randi would point out that we've gotten to the point when we'll Disbelieve something that is true longer than most people would have disbelieved it.
Speaker 1: yes We disbelieve just about anything and everything we see and any claim anyone makes.
Speaker 0: that is not completely mundane But you know what we seem to be always right.
Speaker 0: What's up with that?
Speaker 1: Not always 90%.
Speaker 0: I wasn't right about a frickin Boulder Hill Boulder Mountain yeah, but that's a stupid thing.
Speaker 1: I Am proud that I was right about the Korea thing even though I see the thing is is you?
Speaker 0: I was I was in the Right on that one.
Speaker 0: you guys are arguing about it.
Speaker 0: So I said I'm gonna fucking look it up, and I found a picture of the thing and I'm like well There's the answer yeah,
Speaker 1: I was gonna, and then you beat me to it, and I saw it was like oh,
Speaker 0: yeah Oh,
Speaker 1: you know what came out of it.
Speaker 1: I've discovered that my mask toys are worth well over a thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: Well, it's time to convert some useless pieces of plastic.
Speaker 1: They're awesome I want to keep.
Speaker 1: well the thing is you want to keep useless pieces of plastic instead of converting them into useful gadgets.
Speaker 1: Um I point out one that you have a lot of useless pieces of plastic.
Speaker 0: those useless pieces of plastic cannot be converted into useful Gadgets.
Speaker 1: - more importantly I have two of every mask toy with a few exceptions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well older hills.
Speaker 0: and yet you still thought they were called Boulder Mountain.
Speaker 1: Uh yeah, actually someone posted that that in the German dub It was called Boulder Mountain, but and the thing is I found out that one Wikipedia said Boulder Mountain.
Speaker 1: So did half the internet.
Speaker 0: I edited Wikipedia to be correct But anyway my stance on the issue is that when they were making this show and they said huh?
Speaker 0: What do we call this base?
Speaker 0: Well?
Speaker 0: It's a mountain hill thing, but what should we call it?
Speaker 0: I know we'll call it Boulder Hill.
Speaker 0: Do we call it Boulder Mountain, maybe no Boulder Hill sounds better.
Speaker 0: Boulder Mountain sounds a billion times better than Boulder Hill Any other human on earth would have but given a choice between Boulder Hill and Boulder Mountain We would have chosen Boulder Mountain immediately.
Speaker 0: What is wrong with these stupid mask show?
Speaker 0: make a guy.
Speaker 1: You know what was awesome about mask?
Speaker 1: it had some of the best toys ever And hence the fact that they go for a lot of money to the transform.
Speaker 0: Yes, you need to transfer.
Speaker 0: Do they combine?
Speaker 1: some of them do all right.
Speaker 0: you need transformation and kind of Most important aspects of any toe.
Speaker 1: every one of them comes with dudes.
Speaker 1: the dudes have big Masks with powers that go on and off very well.
Speaker 1: the dudes are articulated And they're all perfectly interchangeable.
Speaker 1: like everything interacts with everything.
Speaker 0: All right like Lego.
Speaker 1: also I'll point out that if you had the Ninja Turtles technodrome It is the best base for masked men ever far and far and above Boulder Hill.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't have a technodrome.
Speaker 0: I had Thundercat.
Speaker 1: my masked man lived in my Technodrome.
Speaker 0: I had a late siege to Boulder Hill.
Speaker 0: yeah, the Thundercats lair is awesome.
Speaker 0: I had a little the headlights in the head.
Speaker 1: Oh, I always wanted that.
Speaker 0: I have it.
Speaker 0: It's in my attic.
Speaker 0: you want to go get it.
Speaker 1: We should get all our toys and play with them.
Speaker 0: I could bring it here.
Speaker 0: I think I'm going home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you get a picture of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, have you awesome alright?
Speaker 0: It's in the attic though alright.
Speaker 1: That's enough meta bits.
Speaker 1: We have some actual news now.
Speaker 1: Scott's news is a little old But we've been talking about it the two of us pretty much quite a bit for the last week.
Speaker 1: So we have to talk about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is sort of a rant I've got about Star Wars kid.
Speaker 1: yeah now if you remember Scott's rant about Singapore It'll probably be similar.
Speaker 0: it might be a little longer and less yelling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to do mine.
Speaker 1: first my news because it's kind of sensational and it's actually kind of current.
Speaker 0: all right all right.
Speaker 1: So dig had an article.
Speaker 1: What was it yesterday?
Speaker 1: That the PlayStation 3. the headline of the article was that the PlayStation 3 is not going to be playable at e3.
Speaker 1: I?
Speaker 1: Read that headline and thought wow Sony's fucked.
Speaker 1: That's the end of that company It's over mm-hmm, and then I laughed hysterically for like 10 minutes mm-hmm, then we clicked on the article and I discovered that dig is perhaps the most sensationalistic news outlet in the world.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's wrong with.
Speaker 0: it used to be that Occasionally some article on dig would have a crazy headline And it would get a bunch of digs and show up on the front page.
Speaker 0: now It seems that any article about anything of import the headline I mean sure when you were trying to summarize an entire article of information into a single sentence or just a few words It's easy.
Speaker 0: It's quite difficult to include all the details.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's also easy to imply things Unintentionally.
Speaker 0: it is easy to imply things unintentionally, but the magnitude to which the headlines on dig Part doesn't even come close.
Speaker 0: Yeah completely falsify and Mislead people as to what the articles actually contain.
Speaker 0: and then even the paragraphs of Description under the headline or even worse they don't help you at all.
Speaker 1: Scott.
Speaker 1: We're either one saying that dig is a better than slash.
Speaker 0: It gets that if you actually just read the stories and only use the headlines to figure out generally Gonna do that.
Speaker 1: you might as well use FARC because it has everything on digging more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't have everything.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: a lot of times people dig other stuff like.
Speaker 1: I've never seen something that was on dig that Didn't also hit FARC in a within a reasonable span of time and honestly the FARC headlines are usually much more accurate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, and also humorous.
Speaker 1: I think the problem with dig is that they people see that headline They go holy shit, and they dig it and then you know the next day They read the article.
Speaker 1: if they even look at the article uh-huh I think a lot.
Speaker 0: I think I don't think people seem to read articles at all like RTF a. yeah We should do some sort of study like we find the people who actually read articles and then we get those people together and all the people don't actually read articles and we see like we watch their link farm just Like continue to grow.
Speaker 0: if you were just linking to things without looking at them all over the place Crazy,
Speaker 1: but anyway there was a tiny tiny grain of truth in the middle of the sea of lie and the truth Is that the ps3 is not really gonna have a big show at e3.
Speaker 1: most likely.
Speaker 0: Do you remember the show for the revolution at the last e3 where they had it behind?
Speaker 1: Like a curtain and you couldn't go in there and only a few people got invited to play with some cheap demos or like the PSP At the last one when there was like one and they'd let like people come back and look at it.
Speaker 0: Yep That's what the ps3 is gonna be like at e3 in a month or so.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if all of this is be to believed which honestly I believe it because once again I work for the frickin company making the chips.
Speaker 0: However, the revolution will have you know booths everywhere.
Speaker 0: The Nintendo booth will be full of revolution stuff crazy crazy go nuts.
Speaker 0: People are gonna be playing it.
Speaker 0: There's probably just gonna be huge lines around the hall of e3 waiting to play with revolutions.
Speaker 1: Yep, I don't want to sound like a fanboy and I don't I. I really have no like Nintendo fanboy leanings behind my following statement But I really believe that Nintendo is going to regain the top position in consoles in this generation.
Speaker 0: The DS is the new SNES.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I mean seriously the DS alone right now.
Speaker 0: Oh my god It just came to me metal Marines DS.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah We'll talk about that another day.
Speaker 1: If you remember the game metal Marines post in the forum that game is awesome and we want to try to remake it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a vision metal Marines DS.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a good vision.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm with you on that vision.
Speaker 1: I see it I see it.
Speaker 0: Yep, but But you should talk about the vision inside.
Speaker 1: actually someone noticed the vision inside.
Speaker 1: joke and post.
Speaker 0: I think that was actually the flaming game.
Speaker 0: I don't know I don't know who it was It might have been.
Speaker 0: the story of the vision is simply this we used to play Mario Party hardcore Like as in we had the World Championship belts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't have them.
Speaker 1: But the people of course, we didn't have a loss.
Speaker 0: Well our friends they we what we played Mario Party hardcore and they had you know, the the toy wrestling bells from Toys R Us and whoever won would get the belts.
Speaker 0: now The one guy we played with and I forget his name.
Speaker 0: I remember it but not gonna say it What he would do is he would get the poison mushrooms and create the row of death and he would just make a row of Poison mushrooms so that if you ever got around the board to this port to this point You pretty much had to land on.
Speaker 0: a poison mushroom is basically the poison mushroom.
Speaker 1: If you don't know this game makes it so you really can't move very far.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if there's a whole bunch of them you keep hitting them and you just get stuck here.
Speaker 0: Yep, so whenever anyone got a poison mushroom, he was like my vision.
Speaker 0: you must make my vision become reality.
Speaker 1: The vision became a thing.
Speaker 0: Yes The vision became a thing and we had rows and rows of poison mushrooms in every Mario Party.
Speaker 1: now We have another Mario Party story that I'm saving for another day.
Speaker 1: Hooray the bamboo.
Speaker 0: Oh the bamboo.
Speaker 1: We we are fairly invulnerable to many forces in this world But the one force that took us down as a unit as in we were routed was a tiny Three inch tall piece of bamboo.
Speaker 0: So Star Wars kid.
Speaker 1: All right Star Wars kid.
Speaker 1: This is Scott's rant.
Speaker 0: I will interject periodically Alright, so for those of you don't know Star Wars kid is that kid who made a video of himself swinging a broomstick around Pretending to be all Jedi and then he left it in the equipment.
Speaker 1: He recorded it which happened to be in school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he recorded it on some like a V Club video camera.
Speaker 0: some other kids found it and put it on the net.
Speaker 0: It became an overnight sensation like Numa Numa sized crazy.
Speaker 0: so The kid who did the Star Wars kid, you know the the Star Wars kid He wasn't so happy because he was uh, you know Nerd a fat dopey kid who didn't have any friends and no life and got picked on.
Speaker 0: and all that Of course after he became Star Wars kid.
Speaker 0: what started happening is kids Bothered him about it.
Speaker 0: It's it's only natural.
Speaker 0: He goes into school and kids are like hey Star Wars kid.
Speaker 0: Whoo I think one of the stories is that in one class they took the overhead projector and they were writing stuff on it.
Speaker 0: So they started sliding the piece of plastic with the writing on it up the overhead projector and go and the whole class is like Now
Speaker 1: I just like to say at this point that if that were me and I had that level of fame suddenly Like that does the level of fame to the point that everyone on the internet everyone on Fark at least know who I was.
Speaker 1: I would be all over that shit like a fanboy on something.
Speaker 0: fanboys like some nudie Sculptures, I don't know life-size naked anime chicks, whatever fanboys disgust me anyway.
Speaker 0: So what happened recent?
Speaker 1: Well, we're just kind of mean-spirited today.
Speaker 0: We are.
Speaker 0: it's it's mean day here on geek night.
Speaker 1: Yes Well, we won't like it.
Speaker 1: So we're all surly and physical today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, watch out.
Speaker 0: You don't want to get near us geeks.
Speaker 0: I guess that's what daily podcast is, you know, the mood changes from day to day.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Star Wars kid what happened was recently.
Speaker 0: he sued the three kids who put the video on the internet.
Speaker 0: Now if he would have sued them for say copyright infringement, you know I made that video and you distributed it without my permission.
Speaker 0: I would have been like, all right I don't like copyright law, but at least that's legitimate.
Speaker 0: I can live with that.
Speaker 0: No, he sued them for making him upset and picking on him.
Speaker 0: now I gotta say if someone picks on you by say beating you up or stealing your lunch money or like harassing you in a real dangerous threatening or like damaging way or you know sexually harassing you or You know that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah racial things anything that's like like there's.
Speaker 1: there's an obvious line and people might debate about the exact position of the line but everyone agrees That there's a line between good-natured bullying and dangerous bullying.
Speaker 0: The line for me is when you infringe upon the rights of another human being people have rights and if you infringe upon the rights Of someone else then that's not okay.
Speaker 1: So I guess seeing Star Wars kid in the street and going a Star Wars kid.
Speaker 1: Haha That's okay Go into his house and like egging it or you know yelling at through his window Star Wars kid.
Speaker 1: Whoo, not okay Exactly.
Speaker 0: So According to all the evidence that I've read and all the stories I've read these three kids all they really did was Put this video on the internet.
Speaker 0: That doesn't cross the line for me.
Speaker 0: That's you know, first of all, I'm against copyrights.
Speaker 0: That's freedom of speech.
Speaker 0: You're taking art and you're distributing it, you know.
Speaker 0: And even if they had you know sung the Star Wars song in school or been like hey Star Wars kid And like, you know, you know said things to him that's freedom of speech.
Speaker 0: you're saying things.
Speaker 0: They're not saying fire in a crowded theater, you know the classic example You're.
Speaker 0: I'm perfectly within my rights to say rim you suck cocks in hell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know it.
Speaker 0: so the difference here is that Star Wars kid is upset not because of anything anyone else did because that's what people always try to do with bullies is they try to say the Bully's the bad guy and the Star Wars kid is the victim.
Speaker 0: Well, sometimes that's true.
Speaker 0: if the guy's beating him up or crossing the line as we generally say that probably more than half the time That's true.
Speaker 1: Just because of the nature of the bullying.
Speaker 1: I've seen kids and under cake these days, but yeah, that's a whole different show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you want to argue, you know, it's it's.
Speaker 0: I'd agree with you that most bullies seem to cross the line a lot.
Speaker 0: However, we have no evidence that these guys cross the line and whether they did or not.
Speaker 0: That's not my point.
Speaker 0: my point is in general if you don't cross that line and Some kid is being all upset because he's picked on but the bullies never crossed the line and they all they did was say stuff to him That's not the bully's fault.
Speaker 0: the bullies are doing things that they're perfectly allowed to do and in some cases should be encouraged to do.
Speaker 0: and If you're Star Wars kidding you're upset because other people are doing things that they're allowed to do.
Speaker 0: That's your fault.
Speaker 0: It's your attitude that is causing you to be upset not some other kids putting a video on the internet.
Speaker 0: if he had the attitude of being proud of being Star Wars kid instead of an attitude of being Ashamed of being Star Wars kid his life would be terrific.
Speaker 1: or let's say he really couldn't deal with it.
Speaker 1: And like that, maybe it wasn't over the line But it was close to the line or just it was.
Speaker 1: it was getting to the point where is really affecting his life.
Speaker 1: there are many steps between doing nothing and sucking it up and being miserable and Filing a lawsuit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean they're standing up to the bullies.
Speaker 1: if you can't do that, you know going to your parents and Talk, I think he did go to the parents The parents are the ones who did the lawsuit or going to the school I mean the school will usually.
Speaker 1: well actually no I could have a whole rant about the way schools the schools don't deal with it Properly.
Speaker 0: schools
Speaker 1: deal with bullying and basically to sum this up schools nowadays, and I didn't really believe this But I've read so many articles lately where this happens schools will basically blame the victims of bullying now because the victims are more of a liability because when they get hurt or when something Happens the school is liable.
Speaker 1: So they don't want to kick the bully out because then the bullies parents tend to also be That way and they'll sue the school.
Speaker 1: They kick the victim out because the victim can't do anything and that way the school has no liability because no one's gonna get hurt.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's all bullshit.
Speaker 1: But that well again, that's a whole nother show.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that Because of Star Wars kids attitude about being Star Wars kid He sort of brought it upon himself if he had had an attitude of being proud of being Star Wars kid.
Speaker 0: Eventually people would have just gotten used to it and forgotten about it.
Speaker 0: See I learned this lesson.
Speaker 0: See people it seems to me like it started.
Speaker 0: on slash dot people seem to be against me and on other websites people seem to Be with me.
Speaker 1: Yeah FARC was mostly with you.
Speaker 0: I must say yeah and slash that was against me.
Speaker 0: and it seemed to me that the people on slash that were against me or People who have been bullied as a kid and they felt they sympathized and empathized with Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Yep, though I'll say right now.
Speaker 1: I was bullied when I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I was bullied when I was a little kid too.
Speaker 0: And you know what.
Speaker 0: around this time around some time Some kids started calling me mr.
Speaker 0: Bean because I look kind of like mr.
Speaker 0: Bean.
Speaker 0: Do I look like mr.
Speaker 0: Bean?
Speaker 1: I don't look like Rowan Atkinson a little bit.
Speaker 0: All right, I didn't even know who mr.
Speaker 0: Bean was.
Speaker 0: and these kids started going mr Bean and they were trying to make fun of me and I realized that that, you know, I didn't.
Speaker 0: it didn't bother me I was like whatever.
Speaker 0: and then it started, you know when they started calling me mr.
Speaker 0: Bean.
Speaker 0: I was like, what up?
Speaker 0: That was that they called me mr.
Speaker 0: Bean, but I didn't care I didn't get upset and They're trying to pick on me failed and that was that they didn't.
Speaker 0: they never crossed the line.
Speaker 0: All they did was call me Mr.
Speaker 1: Bean, well, I guess what I'd like to say to kind of direct this toward not just a rant but actual useful advice or Something.
Speaker 1: if you're bullied if people bully you in general I we have a number of bits of advice on how to deal with this.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Now the first thing is regardless of what you feel you have to be really objective about yourself and wonder why?
Speaker 1: Are people picking on me?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: You have to be kind of brutally honest with yourself.
Speaker 1: I mean It's one thing.
Speaker 1: if people are picking on you because I don't know you're gay or black or some religious thing There's nothing you can do about that.
Speaker 0: They have a right to be racist, but if they cross the line you get some police action or something.
Speaker 1: Yep Plus, you know, they have a right to be racist, but they also have a right to be assholes, right?
Speaker 0: So let's say if I was black and there's a KKK guy walking down the street, you know But I had the same attitude that I do right now as being a not black person You know, I'd be like, that's fine.
Speaker 0: He can be in the KKK if he starts to burn crosses on my lawn that cross the line you call the police.
Speaker 1: Yep, but you have to be brutally honest with yourself because if they're picking on you because you're fat and you're fat You should do something about that because it's not good to be fat anyway, and they might not be good for them to pick on you, but at the same time it's not good to be fat.
Speaker 0: and Un-fatting will solve all of your problems exactly any at the very least if you can't un-fat because you have such low willpower Help get help or at the at the absolute minimum be proud of being fat.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't like people who are proud of being fat because it causes other problems in society.
Speaker 0: But at least you won't be unhappy or be a jolly fat guy.
Speaker 0: Who's cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and not a slovenly disgusting fat guy You know or girl?
Speaker 0: They're jolly fat people, you know, like those real happy fat people who are like, hey, what's up like fat Albert?
Speaker 0: You know, it's all cool.
Speaker 1: Now a lot of kids seem to think oh, they're just jealous of me now.
Speaker 1: That may be true because I mean that happens but it does happen.
Speaker 1: really think about yourself objectively and think all right.
Speaker 1: Is that really true?
Speaker 1: or am I just trying to make myself feel better about the fact that I'm actually Napoleon Dynamite?
Speaker 0: Yeah, think about this.
Speaker 0: You know, you have yours.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're a smart kid and stupid kids pick on you, right?
Speaker 0: Are they picking on the other smart kids?
Speaker 0: Why have they singled out you?
Speaker 0: I mean Sure, they're bullies.
Speaker 0: They got to find someone but why was it you?
Speaker 0: they didn't pick you randomly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not the Simpsons.
Speaker 0: They were.
Speaker 0: they give off some odor bullies.
Speaker 0: There's a reason that they picked you.
Speaker 0: you have some sort of personality Something about your personality that makes you a magnet to people picking on you.
Speaker 0: You have to change it and if you change it you will live be much much happier and You won't need to go jump through hoops to make the bully stop.
Speaker 0: They're bad.
Speaker 0: make them stop or stop and you know provoking them.
Speaker 0: It's your fault too.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: The next step is Once you've realized why they're picking on you and you've decided whether or not you can do something about it.
Speaker 1: You have to decide what you're going to do.
Speaker 1: I mean if they're picking if it's people who are picking on you for no reason at all Like you really can't find a reason and they single you out exclusively and there's nothing else you can do.
Speaker 1: I don't want to advocate violence, but if someone starts something finish it.
Speaker 0: Here's another thing a piece of advice.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're in a classroom, right?
Speaker 0: Not every single person in the classroom is bullying you.
Speaker 0: that's a rare situation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that means something either you're in a bad environment and you need to get out of there anyway, or something's wrong.
Speaker 0: Yes, something very wrong.
Speaker 1: So usually what would happen is like how.
Speaker 1: this is video game day.
Speaker 0: I know right?
Speaker 0: We'll get to the video games.
Speaker 0: Don't worry.
Speaker 0: We're coming.
Speaker 0: There are kids in the class we bullying you.
Speaker 0: Well people getting bullied and they'll be normal kids in the class.
Speaker 0: if you're being bullied right ask the normal kids Like, you know, seriously like hey, man, listen You're not bullied and I am and I really kind of want to know like Does anything?
Speaker 0: I do annoy you or You know because I can bet you there's at least one normal kid who wants to bully you but is a smart Intelligent mature kid and restrains himself But there is something about you that he doesn't like and they can probably tell you why you're bullied.
Speaker 1: Ask them and I'll tell you this not from personal experience but from anecdotes and stories.
Speaker 1: I've heard that that works and There are a lot of people out there who will.
Speaker 1: if you ask they'll be honest and they won't like.
Speaker 1: they won't try to hurt Your feelings but they'll tell you like man is because you smell like.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry But you smell or some whatever it is.
Speaker 0: We are those people.
Speaker 0: yeah, if you want to know why you're bullied just ask us.
Speaker 0: and Flaming geek if you start getting bullied it's because you lied about being from Japan.
Speaker 1: though if you come clean, we can guarantee you some form of No, I really can't I don't know.
Speaker 0: yeah, you won't end up like Star Wars game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Star Wars kid could make a lot of money or could have made a lot of money in my opinion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of you will slash there like what?
Speaker 0: if he doesn't want to make money what he doesn't want to be famous?
Speaker 0: Well, he doesn't have to be.
Speaker 1: but if your trouble in life is that you have to avoid fame and fortune.
Speaker 0: Well Yeah, you're not getting my sympathy.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you that because it's not difficult to avoid fame and fortune and still maintain happiness.
Speaker 1: In fact, I would submit quite the opposite.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right, we're done with Star Wars kid.
Speaker 0: All right, let's get some video.
Speaker 0: things of the day.
Speaker 1: So anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: we talked about video games.
Speaker 0: All the other stuff is over.
Speaker 1: Yep, now my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: the video I'm linking to is old.
Speaker 1: it is fairly well known.
Speaker 1: It is this guy.
Speaker 1: He's a cop and he's in a classroom giving a demonstration.
Speaker 0: Does he work for the DEA?
Speaker 1: Yeah, he used to be a cop used to be a football player all sorts of things prison guard and He's doing a thing on gun safety and such.
Speaker 1: and he pulls out his Glock 40 and he's holding it.
Speaker 1: They're saying this is unloaded weapon.
Speaker 1: It's a Glock 40 and he's talking it up all big and bad.
Speaker 0: I'm the only one professional enough to use this weapon.
Speaker 1: This is the.
Speaker 1: it's probably one of the most classic and ironic videos in the history of the Internet Because at the end of this long speech he basically says like Scott said I am probably I am the only person in this room Was professional enough to handle this gun and then he immediately immediately shoots himself in the fucking foot
Speaker 0: not Pulls the trigger goes
Speaker 1: BAM and he goes like
Speaker 0: bullet comes out and goes into his foot.
Speaker 1: It's it's freaking hilarious and he's trying to pretend he's not hurt.
Speaker 1: But he's limping all around the room and like he doesn't know what to do it.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: So the news is.
Speaker 1: the news is that this guy's back and I mean this happened quite some time ago.
Speaker 1: the guy is back in the news because he is filing a lawsuit against the government for Basically allowing this video to be spread thus defaming his good character and limiting his career options.
Speaker 0: Hello Star Wars kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so a guy shot himself in the foot and with a loaded gun that he said was unloaded in front of a bunch Of kids he could have easily shot one of the kids.
Speaker 1: He's real lucky He didn't shoot one of the kids or something.
Speaker 0: he then he'd be in jail and being guarded by someone like himself.
Speaker 1: and he's mad that because of this gross act of Negligence and incompetence.
Speaker 1: He is now branded as a negligent and incompetent person.
Speaker 0: Gasp
Speaker 1: now, it's obvious to me that the lawyer he hired Knows that this is bullshit or is stupid and one of his friends because I read part of the actual legal filing and they introduced the guy as a Respected football player and then they list all of his credentials, you know work blah blah blah work blah blah.
Speaker 1: commended blah blah blah but the primary one they listed that he was a respected football player.
Speaker 0: a Judge doesn't care about your resume.
Speaker 0: a good judge doesn't care about your resume.
Speaker 1: All I have to say is I am gonna follow this because if there's any way I can see a video of the trial I will get it.
Speaker 1: or if I can find a transcript of what the judge says I will get it because when they show the video of him shooting himself in the foot in court I would bet money that the judge will laugh.
Speaker 1: That's the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all are equal under the law.
Speaker 0: be you president be you Bill Gates be you homeless bum be you President's.
Speaker 1: not equal should be not while he's sitting because he the president can only be tried for high crimes and misdemeanors And he can only be tried by the house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's BS, but should be yeah.
Speaker 0: Everyone should be equal under the law.
Speaker 0: Anyway, my thing today this got to the top of delicious popular today So I immediately tagged it with the flimflam tag.
Speaker 0: just a note to everyone out there if you ever see something on the internet.
Speaker 0: That's complete bullshit.
Speaker 0: Put it on delicious with a tag of flimflam.
Speaker 1: It's starting to spread some things we see that are flimflam.
Speaker 1: get tagged by it before we get to them.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: So This video is on YouTube is supposedly a video of a guy with super acupuncture key powers.
Speaker 1: now I'm we as we talked greatly earlier in this episode.
Speaker 1: We are very skeptical of I don't know everything Basically, you're just reeks of bullshit.
Speaker 0: This guy is just a crock.
Speaker 0: The British guy who's there completely falls for it.
Speaker 0: the slightly skeptical camera girl also falls for it.
Speaker 0: The guy claims that he has some sort of like electrical body power.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: he zaps people and stuff now in the video.
Speaker 0: You see people touch him and then go.
Speaker 0: Ooh Yeah, well, there's that dim mock guy who Can make his students pretend that they like pass out when he just touches them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yet.
Speaker 1: He couldn't make the reporter pass out despite all of his efforts.
Speaker 0: Yep so there's a huge psychology thing going on there and also there's a whole bunch of stage magic going on with his.
Speaker 0: You know probably got a battery in there somewhere Maybe like a little shocking finger.
Speaker 1: the best is when he claims to set that piece of paper on fire with you know The cigarette that you can't really see.
Speaker 0: so yeah He squishes a lump of paper to of newspaper together like real tightly.
Speaker 0: obviously There's some sort of fire mechanism down there.
Speaker 0: Then he puts it to the side and kind of points his hands at it and then gets real close and it starts on fire.
Speaker 1: All I gotta say is it doesn't bother me that this guy is some sort of charlatan.
Speaker 1: because I see so many charlatans I just yeah, if you're gonna be a charlatan go nuts The fact that the reporters who are investigating him are such goddamn tools.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not only that but how many people on Delicious and stuff believe this?
Speaker 0: and that's why they linked to it and that's why it showed up on delicious popular.
Speaker 0: Not everyone tagged it with flim-flam Very few people did in fact.
Speaker 0: and on YouTube there tend to be three types of comments.
Speaker 0: one This the people saying it's real and those people no one likes.
Speaker 0: To the people saying it's fake like us and those people that everyone likes except for the third type of person who Seems to be bothersome is that there's people who think that you should be fair and such and such and such.
Speaker 0: They're like.
Speaker 0: this could be true.
Speaker 0: It might not be true.
Speaker 0: We have to investigate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's all well and good being fair and reasonable and open-minded But at the same time you don't want to take that so far you become stupid.
Speaker 1: I mean the extraordinary claims require Extraordinary evidence.
Speaker 1: the key word there is extraordinary.
Speaker 1: if I claim that I can burp No one is gonna not believe me.
Speaker 0: You don't need any evidence.
Speaker 0: And there you have sufficient evidence because it is not an extraordinary claim.
Speaker 0: It only requires normal evidence.
Speaker 1: now if I claim that by burping I can create a sonic boom nobody should believe you.
Speaker 0: and if someone was going to believe you we would have to have a whole lot of demonstrations to prove that your burps are actually causing sonic booms and such and such and such and such and such and scientific studies and God.
Speaker 0: and without that we all can only assume that Your burps cannot cause sonic booms because that is common-sense.
Speaker 1: boom sonic boom sonic boom Yes.
Speaker 0: So the next time someone comes in your house and says your toaster can do perform in a musical If you want to be open-minded, you know, you can say it might be true The toaster might be able to get up and sing and dance
Speaker 1: the flaming geek might be in Japan
Speaker 0: and this acupuncture guy The acupuncture guy might really be able to zap you with electricity.
Speaker 1: I just like to say right now that During the episode because we took a short break between the first half and the second half - I went to got a drink of water and Scott was picking at his face, but We got a message from our friend Katsu in the forums who was basically telling us that yeah I've pretty much determined that this guy isn't in Japan and we've already Talked about it.
Speaker 1: So Katsu.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we beat you to it, but props.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean apparently when he was posting like oh my god, it's X o'clock in Japan.
Speaker 0: You know the forum sees what time you post things in Eastern Time.
Speaker 0: So if you compare the times they're they're wrong.
Speaker 0: So then he said, oh my god, my watch battery is dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have a computer in front of you You're not.
Speaker 0: you're done.
Speaker 0: Give it up.
Speaker 1: It's over.
Speaker 0: It's over.
Speaker 1: wonder what it'll do when he hears this.
Speaker 1: You know what flaming geek if you give us some audio feedback, that'd be awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, flaming geek record an mp3 of Yourself saying something or perhaps, you know the sounds of the street in Japan where they're.
Speaker 1: I guarantee if you send us something We'll probably play it.
Speaker 0: It'll be hilarious Okay.
Speaker 0: Oh And one last way, you know, the acupuncture guy is fake.
Speaker 0: If this is real he supposedly says that anyone can do this.
Speaker 0: if anyone could do it How come more people aren't doing it?
Speaker 1: How come the military isn't all over this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, if this is real wouldn't the US military be training every single soldier to have electrical set things on fire powers?
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of people point to the fact that during the Cold War the US and the Russian governments both research psychic powers as a means of espionage or combat or whatever.
Speaker 1: and it's true.
Speaker 1: they both did and They didn't find anything.
Speaker 1: and that's why there are no psychic military units.
Speaker 1: They investigated it because they figured hey it won't cost that much and we might as well see well anything that gives us an edge.
Speaker 1: And they discovered that no it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it doesn't do anything.
Speaker 1: It's stupid and they quit.
Speaker 1: Just because someone studied something does not mean it's valid.
Speaker 0: now It means it's valid when someone studies something and then continues to study it and finds uses for it And then it becomes an ology that's not made up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's very unlikely that something as Amazing as the claims many of these people make would not be widespread in use by someone.
Speaker 1: Even if there was some massive conspiracy by like the pharmaceuticals to keep the magic onion that cures cancer away from the world Some doctors somewhere would say hey this onion cures cancer and then you can't hide stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh my god, and the fat I mean Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it comes down to is if there really was an onion that cured cancer More people than just a bunch of hippies and health food stores would be saying it.
Speaker 0: Everyone would be like holy crap and to be on the news and it'd be like pharmaceutical companies exposed hiding the magic onion Wouldn't?
Speaker 0: just?
Speaker 1: my hippies we're done we've.
Speaker 1: we barely talked about.
Speaker 1: you know, we're talking about video games starting now video game time.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about Tetris DS Which in my opinion is probably the current crowning achievement of Tetris.
Speaker 0: Tetris DS is the greatest incarnation of the game of Tetris Currently conceived by man.
Speaker 1: It is perhaps Tetris perfection to be rivaled only by future greater releases of the same game.
Speaker 0: If you want to know a lot about Tetris It's actually this really really good article interview with one of the Tetris dudes on planet GameCube Which usually doesn't have the greatest article.
Speaker 0: So go read that and you'll learn a lot of shit about how they decide Who can make a Tetris game and what they can put in it and all kinds of stuff?
Speaker 1: It's actually really interesting really interesting.
Speaker 1: but before we talk about Tetris in detail the one thing I want to say the glow at the most glowing recommendation I can make About it and the greatest evidence I have for its awesomeness is the fact that I am perfectly willing and in fact happy to spend $35 to buy Tetris in the year 2006.
Speaker 0: again I paid $50 for Tetris for the NES in like 1980 whatnot?
Speaker 0: and other people paid like 30 bucks for it on the Gameboy.
Speaker 1: Yep, and a little note I think Tetris is still the number one selling Gameboy original game ever.
Speaker 0: I think it is.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: even without Tetris the original Gameboy would have hit the pooper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the Gamegear was well exactly like the PSP.
Speaker 0: if the Gamegear had Tetris they would have scored.
Speaker 0: That's what it was all about.
Speaker 1: It had a bunch of cool puzzle games.
Speaker 0: Not Tetris.
Speaker 0: It had lousy.
Speaker 0: what was it?
Speaker 0: crystals or columns?
Speaker 1: Well that and the Gameboy lasted You know forever.
Speaker 1: on those double-a batteries the Gamegear lasted about six minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I owned a Gamegear So I I'm not I'm ragging on something I love Tetris.
Speaker 0: oh my god, so Tetris DS first off.
Speaker 0: Everything in Tetris DS has an old-school retro Nintendo theme.
Speaker 0: You've got Mario's you've got Zelda's you've got metroids You've got balloon fighters a doctor from gyro my.
Speaker 0: you got gyro mites.
Speaker 0: You got all the cool retro stuff.
Speaker 0: So if you're a Nintendo fan a Donkey Kong's Donkey Kong is actually the best one in this game.
Speaker 1: The music is Fantastic.
Speaker 0: like they take the old-school beats and they spruce them up a little bit and consider that the sound chips.
Speaker 1: The way sound is done in the DS is actually very very advanced and good.
Speaker 1: This music in this game is the kind of music I wouldn't mind listening to on an iPod.
Speaker 0: The best part is as you find songs in the game It unlocks them in a little like sound mode so you can go listen to the songs whenever you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, someone is probably going to rip them all to some sort of torrent collection.
Speaker 1: I will then download and listen to Awesome.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So the single player of this has like six modes.
Speaker 0: I think the modes are normal Tetris Push mode, which is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll get to that touch mode, which is alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll mode.
Speaker 0: I forget the other modes because I don't really.
Speaker 0: Oh mission mode, which is link.
Speaker 1: yeah, mission mode is cool because basically they give you a mission like get two lines at the same time with a line between them.
Speaker 1: that isn't gotten.
Speaker 0: or Make a Tetris or get three Tetris in a row make a line using the yellow piece.
Speaker 1: Yeah stuff like that.
Speaker 1: And while that may sound dumb when you play it one, it's really fun - it really Teaches you how to be good at Tetris really quickly.
Speaker 0: I think that was what the guy said.
Speaker 0: is that Mission mode is there to teach you techniques of Tetris that you may not have known Or that you may not realize.
Speaker 0: in playing the normal game where you're just trying to make Tetris's, you know Sometimes you're playing Tetris and you get caught in a difficult situation and you don't know what to do And you can't really figure out a way to out a way to save yourself and you die.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean I play my Personal Tetris style is that I drop pieces as fast as I can.
Speaker 1: as soon as I see a place where a piece could go Where it will not directly harm me or make an open hole somewhere that I can't fill I immediately drop it Which is very effective.
Speaker 1: until I get a piece that doesn't fit my little scheme then I'm fucked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so mission mode Because it forces you to do things besides just get as many lines as quickly as possible.
Speaker 0: Often what will happen is you'll learn to do things in a non-obvious way.
Speaker 0: That will create better Tetris situations for you And I can attest to the fact that my Tetris skills have improved greatly due to playing mission mode.
Speaker 1: I will attest to this as well because playing against Scott and Tetris while I do not get completely and totally owned by him at all Fronts he fairly thoroughly schooled me for a while until I finally started catching up a little Two days ago.
Speaker 0: I schooled this guy, but last night.
Speaker 0: I was just getting hosed by these guys.
Speaker 0: I was playing.
Speaker 0: damn they get the shit out of me all right.
Speaker 1: now the main thing about Tetris is all right.
Speaker 1: I'm good at Tetris whatever I can play Tetris on my cell phone.
Speaker 1: Why is this a big deal?
Speaker 1: the answer to that is multiplayer.
Speaker 0: the multiplayer is insane.
Speaker 0: if you play?
Speaker 0: With people in the same within 30 feet of you you know a bunch of DS's and a bunch of friends You can play what 10 player Tetris yep, and we did this at uber con with a bunch of people and it's crazy.
Speaker 1: I mean yelling and screaming and Tetris is flying everywhere people throwing items at each other.
Speaker 0: the best is you can make teams Which could be even more fun?
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 1: We didn't even try that.
Speaker 0: yeah and everyone to choose teams.
Speaker 0: you like you have team link and team Mario and team balloon fighter and Team ice climber, and oh it's good.
Speaker 0: It's good stuff All right, so the the Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: you can only.
Speaker 0: oh, that's the other thing.
Speaker 0: in wireless mode I think you can play all the a lot of different modes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've only really really play Touch.
Speaker 0: more push mode yeah, but online on Wi-Fi You can play a lot fewer modes than you can with normal wireless.
Speaker 0: You can only play two-player Tetris with no items four-player Tetris with items and push which is a two-player game no matter what.
Speaker 1: now Push push is a is a revolution in gaming.
Speaker 0: as far as I'm concerned push is perhaps the greatest two-player Tetris Game ever created.
Speaker 0: the way this works is you have one column one full column and one player.
Speaker 0: Both players look to themselves like they're on top of the column, but really one guy sees it flipped vertically.
Speaker 0: So your top is your bottom is the other guy's top.
Speaker 0: So it looks to you like they're pieces that are out of your control coming from below Cramming into the bottom of your Tetris j-game going on
Speaker 1: and there are two Tiny one by one blocks at the bottom of each of about the bottom middle area of the screen and that's
Speaker 0: at the start.
Speaker 0: yeah, and basically what happens is You drop pieces and if your piece lands on another piece Then it stops and you start to make Tetris's.
Speaker 1: if you don't land a piece on something it flies off into the ether and you Get a new piece.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you you can drop pieces right through the board out the other side and nothing happens and you get a new piece.
Speaker 0: So if there's a big hole in the board and you get pieces you don't like you can just throw them down the hole Until you get something you want.
Speaker 0: Here's the catch.
Speaker 0: if you make more than one line at a time you get a double the triple the Tetris.
Speaker 0: It moves the whole board every single Tetris piece down.
Speaker 0: so if you get a Tetris it moves every single piece on the board down four spaces in The background.
Speaker 0: it's all Donkey Kong.
Speaker 0: So there's a little level markers.
Speaker 0: It's like zero one two, and then you know minus one minus two, then there's a danger zone.
Speaker 0: so you're making a board of Tetris and you're putting pieces on top and the other guy is putting pieces on the bottom and You move the whole board down which gives you a bigger amount of room to work with to make Tetris's and it shrinks the other guys room to work with to make Tetris's and That that gets really cool because that's how you kill him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically when you push the other guy into his top completely you're done you went you in it's over.
Speaker 0: However, there's a certain amount of strategy and push.
Speaker 0: you see it is still one board.
Speaker 0: The other guy can use your pieces against you.
Speaker 0: Let's say I stack up and I'm ready for a Tetris and I got to put the long piece on the side and I get A Tetris and I've also done the same thing.
Speaker 1: So we basically got a whole solid board with one row completely empty all the way through on the far left side.
Speaker 0: Well, if anyone drops a long piece down this hole it's gonna fly right out the other side and no Tetris's are gonna happen.
Speaker 0: So, what do you do?
Speaker 0: Well, you're gonna have to block it up.
Speaker 0: Now here's the thing.
Speaker 0: Let's say I just put a piece on top of that hole.
Speaker 0: The other guy drops two long pieces down to it and I built up that big block to make Tetris's and he got the Tetris Using those pieces I set up and it moves the whole board up and I'm in trouble.
Speaker 0: You have to use the L pieces to make triple lines while also making the L piece completely disappear and Thus leaving the hole.
Speaker 0: so the other guy can't get a Tetris, but you get a triple and you move the board down.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much the only strategy I found for beating the situation in which there is a vertical column that is empty but there's more strategy to it than that and Push is a really exciting game of two-player Tetris.
Speaker 1: Now there are a few little kinks to this Tetris game that I don't think any of them detract from the game at all But they're definitely there and they make Tetris a little bit different.
Speaker 1: The one thing people have been calling it infinite spin.
Speaker 1: Basically, you are almost entirely free to keep moving a piece around once it hits the bottom in any configuration you want before it sets Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Now that might sound stupid until you realize that in classic Tetris the game starts out really really ass-slow like It did it and it slowly speeds up.
Speaker 1: this game starts right away going pretty fast.
Speaker 1: So that way and some Nintendo people even said this this way you can jump right into the action and the games quick immediately But you're not completely hosed.
Speaker 1: if you just happen to put a piece in the wrong spot Mm-hmm, and two you have a sideboard.
Speaker 1: you can hit R to pop a piece into it and then any time you hit R again it'll pop that piece out and pop whatever piece you had out into it.
Speaker 1: and There are many possibilities for this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically if you get a long piece, but it's not ready for Tetris time Yeah, you can hold on to it.
Speaker 0: And then when it's time for Tetris you pull that out and way.
Speaker 1: Or you get a green piece and it doesn't fit anywhere and you don't want to put it down pop it in and then drop It out later when you made a hole for it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So usually what happens is I'll get a piece I don't want I'll put it in I'll get another piece I'll put that on the board.
Speaker 0: then all of a sudden the other piece fits I take it out.
Speaker 1: It adds a little dimension to the game that I really enjoy.
Speaker 0: The final thing about this Tetris is that you can see six pieces into the future unless there's a boo.
Speaker 0: But don't worry about boo.
Speaker 0: Yep, boo boo sauce.
Speaker 1: I don't take too much advantage of that.
Speaker 1: yet in that usually all I do is I Out of the corner my eye keep an eye on it and I see when a long piece is coming up.
Speaker 0: That's what's the.
Speaker 0: it's the beginning strategy of see of the six piece future.
Speaker 0: But the real strategy to use is you look at those six pieces that are coming up.
Speaker 0: You want to set up the board.
Speaker 0: if you see a piece that's over there that will basically ruin you.
Speaker 0: if it gets onto the Board use the pieces before it because you know what they're gonna be To create a situation to where every piece is always a good piece and no piece will ever fuck you.
Speaker 1: Like let's say you've got a rampart.
Speaker 1: basically You've gotten.
Speaker 1: you've got no like a whole bunch of little jaggies and no like flat area of land at the top And you see the square coming now.
Speaker 1: There's nowhere to put that square on your current board.
Speaker 1: that won't fuck you.
Speaker 1: So use all the other pieces to make some flat land for it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Now if you don't see a square coming, you know, I mean if there's a square.
Speaker 0: if there's no square in the next area You know that it's more than six pieces away.
Speaker 0: Feel free to not make any area for a square to go.
Speaker 0: You can you know make a not as good Tetris and you'll be just fine because it's no squares coming.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can read more in that article that I talked about which will link to.
Speaker 0: you can read out.
Speaker 0: the guy talks all about This stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep, and why?
Speaker 0: they decided that it's not actually Nintendo.
Speaker 0: It's a feature of all Tetris's.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like a standards committee or consortium only it's for a game instead of something real.
Speaker 0: It is something real.
Speaker 0: at least it should be.
Speaker 1: yeah, I Don't really know what else we can say about Tetris.
Speaker 1: It's a very simple game that for some reason.
Speaker 1: Well, I can think of a lot of reasons is just immensely awesome.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are a million similar type games, but Tetris really is one of the best.
Speaker 0: the best You know, it pretty much comes down to this if you have a Nintendo DS and you don't have Tetris You should go get Tetris even at $35 and you should probably get it for 30 somewhere.
Speaker 0: It's totally worth it.
Speaker 0: If you don't have a Nintendo DS, you should buy a Nintendo DS and then buy Tetris or else You're dumb.
Speaker 1: and That was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.