Speaker 0: It's Monday, May 21st.
Speaker 0: I am Scott.
Speaker 0: I am rim and this is the geek nights Tonight we tell you how to get into Linux If you are outside of it.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So rim I see this piece of a computer still sitting on the floor here.
Speaker 1: Yes, my computer is still in fact not built.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 0: Why is that?
Speaker 1: well?
Speaker 1: The RMA actually just went through today.
Speaker 1: so tomorrow They're going to ship back a new identical motherboard to the one that I shipped them But hopefully it's not exactly identical because that means it's non-functioning.
Speaker 1: Well, it's probably going to be the identical model number.
Speaker 0: I would assume you could assume But then you might get in trouble.
Speaker 0: I don't know what.
Speaker 0: yeah It's just so funny that you spent so many so long you needed a new computer And then you finally break down to get one and then it doesn't go.
Speaker 1: honestly I was in the city today And I just stopped by an internet cafe to get online and take care of some business And I saw that they also sell computer components, so I thought I'd edit internet cafe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well it was an internet cafe slash computer store.
Speaker 0: That's pretty cool and weird at the same time.
Speaker 1: plus It was two bucks for like an hour and the receipt lasts for I don't know a month or two.
Speaker 0: so oh That's a good deal because usually those places are like 25 cents five minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no this is a pretty happening place up in the Bronx near 210th Street.
Speaker 1: I forget the name or I'd give them a total plug because they're really cool, but I was looking around.
Speaker 1: I saw they had power supplies, and I saw they had some motherboards.
Speaker 1: But they didn't have the AB 9 Pro because if they had there's a good chance I would have just bought one right then and just told Newegg to keep the one I sent back and pay the difference.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'd have to pay the restocking fee and such.
Speaker 1: It would have been worth it just to get the computer working.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess
Speaker 1: because a lot of the things that I want to do with the show are Waiting on the new computer because the new computer includes a lot of hard drive space is the thing that
Speaker 0: I find funny though Right now that you paid so much for the computer you got it, and it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: You're willing to pay more money just to make it work.
Speaker 0: if you would have bought the Dell It would have just worked.
Speaker 1: But the Dell has been also spent more money.
Speaker 1: The Dell would have cost a lot more money than any of the money.
Speaker 1: I would have spent on upgrading.
Speaker 1: I know cuz I looked the Dell that costs about $400 more than what I paid for.
Speaker 1: this thing is a lot slower and doesn't have a good video card But it just also also is a lot less RAM, but it just works.
Speaker 1: not worth it.
Speaker 1: It's a piece of crap.
Speaker 1: I'd have to replace half of it.
Speaker 0: It'd be fast enough for you.
Speaker 0: You don't really need the whatever extra speed you get and you need it.
Speaker 0: something that works is better than nothing.
Speaker 1: now considering all the video I'm probably gonna have to be cross trans coding for challenger on fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe plus the show which considering that I'm setting up a straight-on filter macro That's gonna pretty much automatically do most of my editing.
Speaker 1: for me that all told will take a while unless the computer's really fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually kind of want your computer to just got freaking work already.
Speaker 0: So I want to see like how that Ubuntu studio works, and I want to see just how fast it is and all that.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm really looking forward to it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have at least four on what I have at work is stupid fast, so this has to be stupider.
Speaker 1: fast I'm gonna have an Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have an Ubuntu studio.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have a Gentoo, and I'm probably ever windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh yeah, so get this speaking of Ubuntu's and Gentoo's right.
Speaker 0: so yes if you use some Linux distribution such as Gentoo right when a new version of the Linux kernel comes out Let's say to 621 comes out.
Speaker 0: then if you're currently using to 620 you have the opportunity to upgrade to 2621. that's how Gentoo works.
Speaker 0: You just constantly upgrading everything all the time including the kernel.
Speaker 1: It's really easy to do contrary to popular belief, but it's not easy to know how to do it.
Speaker 0: Yes It's once you know learn how it's done.
Speaker 0: Then you can do it many times.
Speaker 1: basically just make a couple files put them in the right places make sure they're pointed at By other things make sure the configuring is the part That's actually that's tricky that you have to learn.
Speaker 0: the rest of it is just a simple.
Speaker 1: If you have trouble with that when in doubt turn it on.
Speaker 0: Not really no, but basically, uh Ubuntu doesn't do it like that.
Speaker 0: the way Ubuntu works is if you are using say Edgy F. All right, you will always have kernel 2617.
Speaker 0: You will never get 2618 or 2619 or 2620 you'll always have 2617. furthermore You'll have the 2617 that they made yes, and they might upgrade the 2617 to a better 2617.
Speaker 0: You know if there's a bug in it or something they'll patch that bug But they will never give you the new features in 2618 or 19 or anything else And they will never upgrade you to the newer kernel.
Speaker 1: now there are plenty of good reasons for this.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of good reasons.
Speaker 0: They do it that way.
Speaker 0: It's not just.
Speaker 0: they're not stupid or anything.
Speaker 0: there's reasons, but in feisty you get 2620. all right.
Speaker 0: the newest kernel is 2621 so that's not too bad.
Speaker 0: give you using 2620.
Speaker 1: no no not at all.
Speaker 0: It's not is really nothing to worry about.
Speaker 0: unless you have a laptop That's somewhat modern because in 2621 they have added two important new features to the kernel.
Speaker 0: No, HZ and some IRQ balance something.
Speaker 0: basically if you use kernel 2621 configured properly on a laptop That is modern you can save a lot of electricity and increase your battery life many fold.
Speaker 0: Probably I could probably get another hour out of this thing with a newer kernel.
Speaker 0: That's how big a deal it is, but because I'm using Ubuntu feisty phone I can't get 2621 unless I do it by myself Say Scott wouldn't it be great if there were an easier way to do that in Ubuntu?
Speaker 0: gee you know there would be and you Know what.
Speaker 0: well there was an easier way.
Speaker 0: at least it was relatively easy Mostly because I know how to do that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: so I went and I got the source code to 2621 And I built it and I put it in there and it worked.
Speaker 0: then I realized something hey this kernel It doesn't have my wireless stuff in it.
Speaker 1: this kind of is making me thirsty.
Speaker 0: So I was saving all this battery power But my wireless network card wasn't working because apparently I was using the default kernel sources from kernel.org.
Speaker 0: And of course the Ubuntu kernel is not just this kernel source from kernel.org.
Speaker 0: The Ubuntu people put a bunch of patches and stuff in there including the stuff that makes my wireless card work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean even in Gentoo you get some patches because there are patches that aren't really part of the bare kernel that yeah are really Important or very good.
Speaker 0: That's basically how you add stuff to the kernel that isn't already in there.
Speaker 0: by default is you take other source code And you kind of patch it in and then you can enable more options and whatever.
Speaker 0: so the default Linux kernel from kernel.org that Linus Torvalds and those people released does not have the stuff to make my wireless card work and the Ubuntu people are So nice they put it in there for me.
Speaker 0: But if I want a newer kernel the Ubuntu people aren't going to do that for me And I have to go get that wireless stuff myself.
Speaker 0: now I know how to do it, but it's a huge pain in the ass a huge pain it's not even worth it, so I'm basically going to suffer with shittier battery life and Working wireless until gutsy gibbon comes out because my other option is to switch distributions.
Speaker 0: Well, it's either stay where I am suffer a pain in the ass switch distributions to something like Gentoo which is also a pain in the ass or I don't know what God the thing is I really like Gentoo.
Speaker 1: when Scott convinced me to try it way back I really liked it, and I learned a lot in a real big hurry about how Linux works.
Speaker 1: I also like I didn't learn as much as Scott partly because we started doing the show and I had other things going on and my Computer was slow and it took four days to recompile X. Yeah, so after a while I stopped playing with things and remaking my Gentoo But even so I really like Gentoo because I've optimized it with the little that I knew to the point that my one gigahertz Thunderbird here is Stupidly faster than the much much actually faster hardware in the other computer.
Speaker 1: I have sitting next.
Speaker 0: Yes, however it took a great deal of time, which we don't have and it also not just time to build.
Speaker 1: I mean no OS to take four days to compile.
Speaker 1: that wasn't really that bad.
Speaker 1: the problem is Every time you update Gentoo something breaks.
Speaker 1: you might not notice right away, but something breaks you have to find it You have to fix it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Also you you didn't actually go through the trouble of like the by default.
Speaker 0: if you install Ubuntu There's a whole bunch of things they do for you like if you plug in a USB thumb drive It'll just work and mount automatically and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now you have to.
Speaker 0: you have to set that kind of automatic functionality up yourself.
Speaker 0: It's not just done for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I did.
Speaker 0: you didn't bother to do any of that shit.
Speaker 1: Well, I did get that working until my USB stopped working physically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there are a lot of other things you didn't get working all the way.
Speaker 1: I didn't bother with you dev.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you didn't bother like setting up special like also configurations.
Speaker 0: Well, I didn't really need to because you just use you know one stereo output normal.
Speaker 0: Yes, cuz I don't want stereo input.
Speaker 1: I've always I really haven't jumped on to the whole.
Speaker 0: You didn't enable like like the d mix type of stuff that allows different programs to all play sound at the same time with OSS.
Speaker 1: Also, yeah, the only reason I didn't do that is that think about that.
Speaker 0: That's that's the perfect thing for people to understand here in gen 2. right by default if you don't do anything You cannot have two programs play sound out of the same sound card at the same time.
Speaker 0: You have to set that up.
Speaker 0: That's the level of setting up.
Speaker 0: We're talking about.
Speaker 1: the worst part is with also.
Speaker 1: at least that was easy and it worked right away.
Speaker 1: I set my also pretty damn well.
Speaker 1: Yep with the OSS which the old flash was using I had a few issues Yeah a few and I gave up because it wasn't worth it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the point is Ubuntu does a lot of those things for you.
Speaker 1: Yep, actually That's why I'm really really excited about this Ubuntu studio and I really want to play with it because even if I don't use it the kernel that they make for it is Generally in Ubuntu kernel except that it has low latency patches Which I don't really want to bother Applying myself and I don't really want to make my own kernel.
Speaker 1: and if they've made it already Then I'm although I'm on board I think.
Speaker 0: other than that it appears to me that the only difference between a bunch of studio and Ubuntu besides the low latency kernel Is that by default it comes with a bunch of?
Speaker 0: Multimedia production applications already installed like, you know the game and the our door and the center Lara.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looks like they also make it real easy to make Jack work and a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: I still have to look into it.
Speaker 1: I haven't really.
Speaker 0: they also change the theme.
Speaker 0: Actually that I want to steal the theme from it because it looks really nice.
Speaker 0: It's a dark theme that doesn't screw up your computer, which is rare for GTK Basically because the Firefox if it is pretty much just Ubuntu with a few changes I'm probably gonna run it instead of Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: That's probably a good idea for you And if it's not or if there's anything fishy I'm probably going to steal its kernel and then run Ubuntu with it.
Speaker 0: You can do that.
Speaker 1: if that works That'll probably be a lot easier than making my own.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Absolutely.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I was reading some news is on the internet and usually I ignore.
Speaker 0: most of the science news is because the science news is Tend to be medical study blabbity-blah outer space blabbity-blah.
Speaker 1: There's been a lot of very interesting quantum mechanics news lately Yeah, or stuff like that.
Speaker 0: I don't understand this at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically when I read those articles half the time, it's Wow I'm sure that what I'm reading is very relevant to the modern world and very interesting to other people.
Speaker 0: Yes, but here's the science news that I understand And is very awesome.
Speaker 0: Basically, they invented a new kind of plastic that both attracts and repels water.
Speaker 0: It is hydrophobic and hydrophilic but not just hydrophobic and hydrophilic super hydrophobic and super Hydrophilic.
Speaker 0: now this has a lot of applications but what I thought was really cool is the number one application they seem to talk about the most in the article is Collecting water for people in the desert in Africa and other such places and I'm like, huh?
Speaker 0: Collecting water.
Speaker 0: apparently there's a lot of places in the desert in Africa and other deserts I think where there are desert fogs and they collect water from the desert fogs was sort of like these meshes and the water.
Speaker 1: I actually had a survival guide From when I was a Cub Scout and it described in the desert how to make one of those meshes and then drain water out Into a bucket at the bottom.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah well Apparently if using this plastic what you could do is you can make a strip of the plastic Where the top part of it was hydrophobic hydrophilic and the bottom was hydrophobic.
Speaker 0: So the top part would attract all the water from the fog Right.
Speaker 0: and then as that water like, you know as it got became fully saturated and the water dripped down to the bottom Where the hydrophobic strip was it would fall off immediately a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: if it would fall off I wouldn't have any water sticking to the plastic and you could collect that water in it, whatever and drink it.
Speaker 0: and Basically, you could get many many many more waters out of the fog than you could using the current method.
Speaker 0: and there are many other applications of this thing for example like chemistry labs and things and medical tests and Medical equipments and all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: Those are probably the vaguest possible ideas.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I could even imagine it though.
Speaker 0: Like I'm in a chemistry lab, right?
Speaker 0: You know you deal like a test tube and you clean it and then there's always like some water still in there.
Speaker 0: Or like you you put in exactly X milliliters of water and then X milliliters of a chemical and you stir it up and you heat it or something in a chemistry Lab and then you pour it out of the test tube into something else and then there's always some left in there.
Speaker 0: So now you're like how much is left in there?
Speaker 0: Maybe like two drops?
Speaker 0: How much is that?
Speaker 0: Is that gonna throw my measurement off?
Speaker 0: and it always throws your measurement off by some decimals, whatever.
Speaker 0: What if your little test tube was made of this super hydrophobic plastic, right?
Speaker 0: Look all of it came out 100%.
Speaker 0: see luckily do a lot more accurate Chemistry lab things even in just like lame-ass high school chemistry lab.
Speaker 1: That was never a concern for me mostly because I got in trouble in chemistry for getting bored one day and silvering all of my glass wear.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: It took me about two hours Awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this these new inventions of cool hydrophobic and hydrophilic plastics are pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh think about a fog free windshield.
Speaker 1: Ah Free eyeglasses, I'm thinking mostly about ski goggles because there you go.
Speaker 1: even back when I skied no matter how fancy women goggles.
Speaker 1: Forget that.
Speaker 1: swimming goggles are for losers and professionals.
Speaker 0: That's right for the professionals.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you were thinking for you astronaut helmets.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they have a problem with song with diving helmets.
Speaker 1: See, I remember skiing as a kid and no matter how expensive they were whatever I got to put on my face it would either immediately scratch up and you couldn't see through it because The thing that made the fog not appear also made it really scratch.
Speaker 1: non proof to go about to say that in a very far Way, yep, or it would fog up and I couldn't see LCD screen.
Speaker 0: Maybe like wouldn't that keep all the water off?
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know what water I don't know.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't be getting water on your LCD I know nothing's.
Speaker 0: maybe you could make though a waterproof laptop because it would basically just expel all water.
Speaker 1: If only I could make a finger proof LCD, that would be awesome.
Speaker 0: Alright, so yeah Plastic, you should read about it.
Speaker 1: I guess it just proves once again our theory not our theory but our our basic idea that Science is always making the world better and most problems can be solved by the direct application of science.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure all the problems can be solved by so.
Speaker 0: well, there is one possibly have to have a broad broad definition of science.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying there's one possible exception.
Speaker 0: Maybe Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is we might not be able to solve the problem.
Speaker 0: But you know if it's a problem that is solvable then Science is the way to solve it.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: so with all these computers We've been using and building and all this technology for the past 20 years or so Every now and then you see articles they come and go always in clusters about the issues of dealing with all the waste from computer products and it's really not a trivial issue despite the fact that It's not often in the media.
Speaker 1: and when it is in the media It's only there for a flash and then California passes some sort of law and then it disappears again.
Speaker 0: Yeah people always talk about how like You know motherboards is like so much poison gas and dispose of it because it basically is just a board made of poison gas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, computer components are incredibly toxic, especially when you collect them in mass.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's a lot of places that will basically collect old computers and take all the pieces and to make new computers Not new but functioning computers and then give them out install Linux on them and give them out to people who don't have computers and well stuff like that.
Speaker 1: according to foreign policy currently there is 17 times more gold in computer waste per unit weight.
Speaker 1: then in gold or And there there's 40 times more copper than in copper.
Speaker 0: or well, maybe we should Get the gold and the copper out and not let the poison gas get out.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: It just so happens that that exact is exactly what has been going on in the world for a long time Which is good.
Speaker 1: It is going on in China, which is bad.
Speaker 0: Why China's collecting gold?
Speaker 0: What's wrong with that?
Speaker 1: No, because what's happening is they're collecting.
Speaker 1: it's not just China It's a lot of third third world or developing or basically non Western industrialized nations That are taking all of this waste in mass Gigantic amounts of it paying people practically nothing to sort it and deal with it and run the machines poisoning Horribly the atmosphere
Speaker 0: and gas get
Speaker 1: out.
Speaker 1: They're letting the poison gas get out particularly there don't they know?
Speaker 0: It's like the first rule of computers.
Speaker 0: You don't let the magic smoke get out.
Speaker 0: What do you think?
Speaker 0: the magic smoke is people it's poison.
Speaker 1: See the thing is in China.
Speaker 0: That's what makes computers work poison gas.
Speaker 1: They don't?
Speaker 1: they just don't have to care about that.
Speaker 1: There aren't as many environmental regulations.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: You know, it doesn't really bother me but they're gonna be pretty sorry if you're sitting there taking gold out of a computer.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like Indiana Jones He takes a statue and then a rock rolls him over.
Speaker 0: these people they're gonna take gold out of this old computer and then a poison Gas will kill them.
Speaker 1: well The worst part is they deserve.
Speaker 1: because of the way these industries Run the people actually doing the work and being poisoned and living near the factory are not the ones profiting.
Speaker 1: They're being paid practically nothing.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're problem.
Speaker 1: I Remains that the amount of computer waste and technology waste that the United States alone is producing is growing at a startling rate.
Speaker 1: And yet the only solution we have so far is to ship it to China.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't see.
Speaker 0: I think what we should do is we should scrape all the gold off and then send to China.
Speaker 1: Uh, the process of scraping the gold off to do it Well is very expensive and you don't scrape it off using solvents.
Speaker 0: Does it cost more than the gold?
Speaker 0: it slightly.
Speaker 0: But then why?
Speaker 0: how is China profiting?
Speaker 1: because they don't have to worry about safety or regulation or people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe we should Should what find a way to make it profitable?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, even if it is profitable It's always more profitable to do it in China.
Speaker 1: And if anyone does it here, they can't compete with the people in China.
Speaker 0: I guess if you had a machine that did it with no people.
Speaker 1: But even then it still generates horrible waste you can make.
Speaker 0: well You just put the horrible waste in a barrel and put it with the nuclear waste.
Speaker 1: But we don't even store the nuclear waste anywhere.
Speaker 1: It's all still sitting at the nuclear power plant about that another day.
Speaker 0: Why that is?
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact, I believe there's a forum thread about that right now.
Speaker 1: There might be Suffice to say it's an interesting and complex issue that we would probably have to spend at least a whole show to actually cover in Any depth.
Speaker 0: someone should sell a home kit where you can collect the gold out of your old computer.
Speaker 1: It's not that easy.
Speaker 1: it's Having worked at IBM in a factory where we kind of did the reverse and put the gold on.
Speaker 1: I can say that it is Not easy to put the gold on let alone to take the gold off.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'll leave the gold on us.
Speaker 0: Take the platinum back.
Speaker 1: There's not so much platinum.
Speaker 0: That sucks that wants it.
Speaker 1: then things of the day.
Speaker 1: Now I wasn't so much a fan of the show at least not as much as Scott But the Jetsons at least has to be respected for being popular.
Speaker 0: at when it was on TV Yeah, I mean, I didn't really think about the Jetsons that much.
Speaker 0: but when I was a kid I watched it and I liked it.
Speaker 0: and now that rim found it a bit of it.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, yeah I remember that I like that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Let me as a kid.
Speaker 1: I always preferred the Flintstones And above that I always preferred my Nintendo, but oh, yeah, of course, of course, but yeah, I don't know Flintstones or Jetsons.
Speaker 0: It's tough.
Speaker 1: What about the movie?
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: the movie was done.
Speaker 0: them sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah when they meet it wasn't so bad.
Speaker 0: It sucked wasn't any worse than any of the shows I think I like like Dino and Barney Rubble better than I like any Jetsons characters.
Speaker 0: But the plots of the Jetsons episodes, I think I like better.
Speaker 1: Yeah I like Cogswell.
Speaker 1: I like Cogswell was my man.
Speaker 0: Well, the only problem was basically he was awesome Except when his wife pundit he needed if he stood up to the wife.
Speaker 0: you've been in the best ever.
Speaker 1: He was a dick though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if anything he should have fired George cuz.
Speaker 1: George was a terrible worker Should have but didn't.
Speaker 1: what really bothered me was that George's job was just to push that button Which he couldn't even manage to do that half the time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Just use a drinking bird.
Speaker 1: Homer Simpson figured that out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this is a little Family Guy spoof and Normally, I don't go for this sort of thing as a thing of the day But it's just the opener to the Jetsons until the last second.
Speaker 0: Yeah, totally caught me by surprise.
Speaker 0: I thought it was something someone on YouTube put together and not something that was actually put together by Family Guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wasn't sure what was going on.
Speaker 1: The joke was kind of worth it kind of like that other one where they made fun Of Amadeus.
Speaker 0: Yeah suddenly at the end All right, I got this thing of the day here and I kind of like the thing.
Speaker 0: but I looked at the website.
Speaker 0: It's on and I don't like this website cuz it's really yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway the thing I'll only talk about the thing the thing is 15 useless or even dangerous eyesight myths.
Speaker 0: and I'm just gonna go off the myths real quick because I think some of these are pretty interesting because some of These I believe some of these I knew I know a lot of people believe these and I checked up on these seem to be Actually mythical.
Speaker 0: so all the information here seems to be correct as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: Number one sitting too close to the television will damage your vision.
Speaker 0: Okay, all of these are false by the way, so sitting close to the TV does not damage your vision.
Speaker 0: Reading in the dark does not damage your eyesight.
Speaker 0: Some eye exercises can improve your vision.
Speaker 0: That is also false.
Speaker 0: You cannot wear your eyes out by using them too much.
Speaker 0: Ah Vision does not improve in older people as they gain second sight.
Speaker 1: what that actually is apparently is I know all about that You tend to become farsighted as you get older.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's that there's something with cataracts.
Speaker 0: We're at a certain stage.
Speaker 0: It actually changes your vision in a way where you can see better and then it's actually the cataract advancing.
Speaker 1: Ah, well, there's also a thing where if you're near-sighted you tend to be farsighted when you get older.
Speaker 1: So as you become farsighted, it slowly corrects your near-sightedness.
Speaker 0: Yeah, too much sex, especially magic masturbation cannot make you go blind.
Speaker 0: Wearing poorly fit glasses will not damage your eyes.
Speaker 1: It just hurts Yep, and makes you nauseous.
Speaker 0: blind people do not have a sixth sense or extraordinary talent.
Speaker 1: Actually, there is a lot of evidence that blind people have exceptional hearing.
Speaker 0: Well, what it is apparently is that you know, if you didn't if you actually you know Closed your eyes all the time and you were using only your hearing you would practice it a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you would.
Speaker 0: it's not that they have innately, you know, DNA better hearing or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Well, no one argued that.
Speaker 0: I know it's that's.
Speaker 0: all they're saying here is that they don't have Intrinsically better hearing.
Speaker 0: is that they use their hearing more.
Speaker 0: thus They're better at hearing than you.
Speaker 0: But there's no reason you couldn't hear as well as a blind person if you practiced it just as much as they do.
Speaker 1: Well, I did read somewhere that a lot of the parts of the brain that work for vision end up being co-opted by Hearing and other things.
Speaker 1: Yes, so You'd have to permanently blind yourself to get that level of ability.
Speaker 0: Yes, but you could get pretty close especially if you close your eyes a lot and listen to a lot of things very carefully.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I guess we'll have to do a double blind study.
Speaker 0: Oh There is a need to have your vision checked before you turn 40.
Speaker 0: Everyone should go to the eye doctor.
Speaker 1: Even if your eyes are fine you might have glaucoma might have it because glaucoma is pretty much symptomless until ah Shit, I'm lying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've all popped.
Speaker 0: glaucoma is basically nothing.
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: eyes explode and We're I think we're relatively higher risk for that than other people looking at screens all day.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep, plus I actually used to get tested for that a lot and I still continue to get tested for it every couple years.
Speaker 1: Also for any of you who hate the glaucoma test because it basically they put a Gun in front of your eyeball and you have to hold your eye open.
Speaker 1: Well, they shoot a blast of air into it And if you blink they do it again and again and again and again.
Speaker 0: They'd hold your eyelid open with a little thing cuz.
Speaker 1: that's kind of hard to set up.
Speaker 1: Okay Well, apparently they don't test for it that way anymore.
Speaker 1: Ah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I haven't been tested since the new way was used around here, but I hear there's a new way.
Speaker 0: Alright doctors cannot transplant eyes Not yet.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's correct.
Speaker 0: Scientists have not created a bionic eye.
Speaker 0: Well, they kind of have.
Speaker 0: yes, they but it's like you can see some dots of light.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I can't freakin see see.
Speaker 1: well not yet.
Speaker 1: But the thing is someday we are going to have that because already Prototypes and ways of doing that sort of thing kind of work and it's getting better every day.
Speaker 0: It is harmful to look at the Sun.
Speaker 0: even if you squint or use sunglasses Do not look at the Sun.
Speaker 0: if you look at the Sun you can blind yourself in like less than a minute.
Speaker 0: Yep, I don't know who even if it's an eclipse.
Speaker 0: It's it don't look at the Sun god damn it.
Speaker 0: There is something you can do to prevent vision loss.
Speaker 0: go to the eye doctor.
Speaker 0: do what they say.
Speaker 1: Actually, there's a cool study about how apparently putting atropine drops in kids eyes if the kids are starting to get myopia Will prevent the myopia from progressing.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's interesting.
Speaker 1: yeah, really interesting and I really want to see more follow-up on.
Speaker 0: that won't help me but Yep, and the last two myths.
Speaker 0: although glasses make you see better.
Speaker 0: They do not make vision get worse over time.
Speaker 1: There was a friend of our family when I was a kid who for many years after they realized that one of their children had Vision problems didn't get this child glasses because they were afraid that it would make the vision worse over time.
Speaker 1: So the kid had to suffer with not being able to see crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically what happens is before you get glasses you see this blurry world And that's what you're used to and then you put glasses on and now the world is correct again When you take the glasses off and you see that shit same shitty blurry world from before.
Speaker 0: It's so much worse because you're now comparing it to be correct world.
Speaker 1: Well, not only that but once you start wearing glasses your vision usually continues to degrade.
Speaker 1: so you keep needing stronger and stronger glass.
Speaker 0: Yes, but your vision is not degrading because of the glasses.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like how a lot of parents of autistic children Well, I guess not a lot because these are just the wacko minority nut jobs They think that vaccines cause the autism When it just so happens that the symptoms of autism tend to come about right around the age that kids get all their vaccines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the final myth post hoc non ergo, dr Hawk eating carrots will improve your vision and okay Basically, it is true that carrots are high in vitamin A which is an essential vitamin for seeing.
Speaker 0: however You don't need that much like a carrot every day or two is enough Vitamin A to see properly out that if you eat too much vitamin A like a vitamin A tablet that could be harmful I believe.
Speaker 1: correct me if I'm wrong.
Speaker 1: Not that you know, but I don't know either.
Speaker 1: I think vitamin A is the most toxic vitamin for humans.
Speaker 1: It might be because I have read of a lot of cases of vitamin A poisoning.
Speaker 1: Yep You just need like what is one of those fat soluble ones?
Speaker 0: You just need some vitamin A and then you can see just fine.
Speaker 0: eating like a vitamin A tablet isn't suddenly gonna give you like X-ray visions or let you see like a mile away.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's.
Speaker 0: you only need like a carrot once in a while.
Speaker 0: You know, you feed salad with carrot.
Speaker 0: You're all right.
Speaker 0: It's cool.
Speaker 1: so we haven't done this for a while partly because honestly the only reason we had theme weeks Was to force ourselves to have some show ideas or to otherwise get us out of some sort of slump.
Speaker 1: We never really used them proactively.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well here comes a theme week watch out.
Speaker 1: And we actually planned this one.
Speaker 1: We actually are kind of excited about it because
Speaker 0: it's one of those theme weeks We came up with a long time ago and somehow never did even though we probably should have a long time
Speaker 1: Yep, and then it came up in the forums again about one of the geekeries and how to get into it.
Speaker 1: So we decided alright, it's time.
Speaker 0: Especially I think is something we waited because this is sort of an important theme week And I think now we can do it justice.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So to this week's theme.
Speaker 1: every night this week We're going to talk about how to get into it how to get into some sort of geekery or hobby or whatever thing We're interested.
Speaker 1: Yes,
Speaker 0: for example If you are not a member of the anime geekery and you may want to become or try it out We will tell you that probably on Wednesday, you know, if you are not a member if you're not a technology person You don't know shit about computers.
Speaker 0: All you know how to do is listen man This kid don't know shit about Pokemon.
Speaker 0: All you know how to do is listen to Podcasts and visit websites.
Speaker 0: We're gonna tell you how to become a computer nerd.
Speaker 0: We're gonna tell you all that stuff.
Speaker 1: now I would like to clarify that the intended audience for this week's set of shows though Anyone can enjoy them and keep this in mind because the second one I think is very important for one Any of you out there who have an interest in these things, but just aren't sure how to go about it.
Speaker 1: Maybe you might like anime, but your friend brought over la blue girl and you think all anime is like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or you just don't know.
Speaker 1: you don't know what to watch.
Speaker 1: There's a million things out there.
Speaker 1: You like this German board game business, but you don't know the difference between Puerto Rico and Hellas Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I think that this week has two main purposes in my mind.
Speaker 0: one purpose is I know a lot of people listen to geek nights Who are really mainly into like one of the geekeries like.
Speaker 0: there are a lot of anime fans to listen to geek nights.
Speaker 0: They listen to all the days and they email us and they tell us yeah Listen to all the days even though I don't really care about video games or hey I listen to all the days, but I really only care about Monday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so for those people we're gonna help you out Understanding the other days quite a bit.
Speaker 0: and also if you have people that you know see friends out there.
Speaker 0: See, this is the second part and let's say you're an anime fan and your other friends.
Speaker 0: They're not so much the anime fans.
Speaker 0: Well, you can apply the episode to your friends to make them get into it.
Speaker 1: Now this is important and don't forget this idea because
Speaker 0: While
Speaker 1: it might seem easy to get someone else to be interested in something that you yourself enjoy You have kind of a selective bias in how you present because you are already immersed in the fan culture or in the hobby Or whatever.
Speaker 1: So a lot of times anime is a good example because someone in our forums asked Hey, I kind of am interested in anime.
Speaker 1: What anime should I watch?
Speaker 1: How do I get into this business?
Speaker 1: and I've noticed there wasn't just our forum.
Speaker 1: I see this everywhere.
Speaker 1: a lot of the people who give advice to people who aren't in their hobby will give them in my opinion Absurdly useless advice that if anything is going to keep them away from your hobby.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you go into some IRC chatroom You're like, hey, I'm thinking about using this Linux.
Speaker 0: What do I do?
Speaker 0: and some guys like OMG and build your own computer and install Gen 2?
Speaker 0: It's like well, that's something you do when you're already into it.
Speaker 0: That's not gonna get you into it That's just gonna make you pissed off and tired.
Speaker 1: Yep, or if someone wants to get into German board games We're not gonna throw Twilight struggle.
Speaker 0: hell is and Puerto Rico Struggles a German game but regardless.
Speaker 0: Yes, you don't start out with that stuff.
Speaker 0: You start with the settlers of Catan.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows yeah that or possibly Carcassonne.
Speaker 0: Yeah Carcassonne is the other one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and thus we realized that over the course of our years the front row crew We had a lot of common interests But we also had a lot of disparate interests and over time all of us got all of the rest of us Into many of our hobbies and we became a semi homogeneous culture of interests.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean in the most recent one I think is Pete has gotten us more and more into metal.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I think a lot of it is that when you're getting someone into something or getting into something yourself Someone pushing something on you rarely works.
Speaker 0: You have to discover it on your own.
Speaker 0: But sometimes you know, you can try to discover it on your own and that'll work.
Speaker 0: But yet if you try to discover it on your own the wrong way You could have like this tainted first impression and most people won't go back once they have that tainted first impression.
Speaker 1: I think about people who play D&D.
Speaker 1: How many of you out there who play Dungeons & Dragons and enjoy it have a friend who says something like oh I thought D&D would be really cool, but then I played it and it was just a bunch of scary nerds blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: It was stupid and horrible and the DM was an idiot and they just made stuff up and it wasn't fun and crap.
Speaker 1: and a Lot of those times they just happen to play with a group of people who in my opinion were playing at least I want I don't want to say objectively bad Dungeons & Dragons or anything like that because you can enjoy a game ever you want.
Speaker 1: But they were not playing it in the way that I enjoy it But because I enjoy it one way and this person would probably and also enjoy it that way.
Speaker 1: But they were tainted by another group of people who play it a different way.
Speaker 1: They have now written off the entire hobby.
Speaker 0: All right, let's not spend the whole episode talking about the week itself.
Speaker 0: Let's get into it Alright.
Speaker 1: so tonight being Monday science and tech day.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about how to get into quantum physics.
Speaker 0: awesome.
Speaker 0: Step one be smart.
Speaker 0: step two take a lot of calculus.
Speaker 0: step three go to really fancy college a straight A's.
Speaker 0: step four lots of internships and a hard life of much graduate school with lots of work and no fun and Lots of math and no money.
Speaker 0: and then one day Nobel Prize.
Speaker 1: Right that was easy.
Speaker 1: so how do you get into Linux?
Speaker 0: ah much more difficult.
Speaker 0: Honestly it depends how you want to get into Linux.
Speaker 0: like you could get into Linux like hey I don't want to be the random fool on the internet who doesn't know about Linux.
Speaker 0: So I want to figure out what the deal is.
Speaker 0: you could get into it like I want to use Linux as my desktop computer.
Speaker 0: Or you know what I. yeah, I don't want to use Linux as my desktop computer But I do.
Speaker 0: I have websites and I host them And I want to you know know enough about Linux that I can do my hosting better.
Speaker 0: or hey I want to actually learn about Linux and make Linux stuff and learn to code and all sorts of whatever.
Speaker 1: now see here's the thing I generally get the impression when it comes to Linux or anything like that that the people who are of the most success getting into it are the people who Decided to get into it or even if they didn't decide because they didn't know about it Someone who has identified a problem with the current way they do things and is looking for a solution.
Speaker 1: even if they don't know that Linux is possibly the solution or OS X or whatever they recognize a problem and are looking for some way to get around it.
Speaker 1: because without Some form of focus some sort of goal some sort of success condition.
Speaker 1: It is very hard unless you have Ultra high dedication or just a lot of free time and a great motivation in and of itself to get into something like this Because you have no way to succeed you have nothing to keep you going no goal to strive for No reason other than for the fuck of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I find that with anything I do with computers in general is that if I don't have Some sort of actual goal like if it's just do something if I like if I want to learn a new programming language But I don't have an actual meaningful project to do with it.
Speaker 0: I won't actually learn it.
Speaker 0: I'll just look at the tutorial and then forget what I read.
Speaker 1: yep That happened to me with I think Python was a good example.
Speaker 1: when I was an RIT I thought alright I should learn Python because I hate Java and I hate coding.
Speaker 1: But bash isn't really enough for the kind of scripts I need to write and pythons really easy and really good and awesome and I sat down.
Speaker 1: I started learning Python, and I got bored with it immediately and quit.
Speaker 1: then when I was working at IBM I needed to write a script for something I Couldn't really do it in bash.
Speaker 1: you probably could have oh yeah, but it would have sucked.
Speaker 1: It would have really sucked.
Speaker 1: you just said no I would have sucked.
Speaker 0: you could have done an awk.
Speaker 1: well part of it was that there were a bunch of Python functions that I Had from other coders and IBM that did things.
Speaker 1: so I had to interface with these things.
Speaker 1: So I just wrote the whole thing in Python instead of there you go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I had this goal.
Speaker 1: I learned a bunch of Python really quick and finished the job almost immediately.
Speaker 1: I learned more in that week of having a goal With using Python then I did in two months of looking at books and trying to teach it to myself with nothing no reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you're thinking about doing something with Linux What's your goal?
Speaker 0: is your goal to have a desktop that is?
Speaker 0: Free of spyware and doesn't crash because that's a good reason to go to Linux?
Speaker 0: is your goal to have a computer That's easier to use?
Speaker 0: Maybe your goal is to give your parents a computer that won't have so many problems that you have to keep fixing.
Speaker 1: Maybe your goal is to buy a new computer and not have to pay for or pirate windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe your goal is like I said before to have some sort of you know Web server that you host and manage on your own instead of letting someone else do it for you.
Speaker 1: So I guess even if your goal your real goal is just I want to know what this Linux business is about.
Speaker 1: I want to get into it come up with something come up with some reason other than that to get into it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you'll just poke it and be bored And it'll just be like a time-waster.
Speaker 1: because I think part of that problem is that Linux particularly Ubuntu has come far enough to where it mostly just works.
Speaker 1: So if you just turn on an Ubuntu CD, it's a lot like Windows.
Speaker 1: you can word process You can get on the internet you can play a couple of little games, and then what are you gonna?
Speaker 0: Do you're gonna be like oh I can browse the web?
Speaker 0: I was doing that before with Windows or OS X whatever.
Speaker 0: you're using a big deal.
Speaker 1: So I guess my advice here is if you have no purpose no goal other than getting into it like we said Then I think your best goal your artificial goal is to try to go an entire week without rebooting back into Windows.
Speaker 1: Force your shell yourself to use Linux as much as possible Because then when you want to use your computer for something And it's not immediately obvious how to do it or make it work You'll be forced to interact with the Linux, and you'll learn a lot really quickly.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean for all your basic stuff your instant messaging your web browsing and music listening Linux is kind of gonna just work for you pretty much especially Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: so yes But that's pretty much what you most people do with their computer is 90% of the time But everyone does something weird with their computer once in a while.
Speaker 0: You know maybe you like to encode videos or maybe you like to I don't know organize photos or something like that.
Speaker 0: And when that time comes you know the thing that you don't do with your computer that often.
Speaker 0: But you do do it, and you're using Linux, and you decided you're not gonna reboot.
Speaker 0: you're gonna end up learning something.
Speaker 1: yep I mean it might be as simple as say you've got some more stripped down Linux And you need to open up a word file.
Speaker 1: well now you realize you can't and you'll go around you'll find open office You'll install it.
Speaker 1: It'll start working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe you'll run into a Java problem.
Speaker 1: You have to fix that.
Speaker 1: the forums help you.
Speaker 1: you get on your way.
Speaker 0: So the first thing you should do if you're thinking about getting into Linux is of course probably get an Ubuntu CD.
Speaker 0: Go to the Ubuntu website.
Speaker 0: There's an ISO file.
Speaker 0: you download it.
Speaker 0: you burn it to a CD.
Speaker 0: There's instructions on their website to help you out.
Speaker 0: You need a CD burner by the way you put the CD in your computer.
Speaker 0: you boot off of the CD Which they are also instructions on the website.
Speaker 0: pretty much That's the first thing to know about Linux unlike Windows where if you have a problem searching on Google won't always help you that much.
Speaker 0: Linux Google always has the answer.
Speaker 0: you go to the website for whatever you're trying to figure out the Ubuntu forums the Gentoo forums Google Any Ubuntu wiki all sorts of places Debian website?
Speaker 0: There are people.
Speaker 0: all the answers are on the internet.
Speaker 0: at the very worst you can go to the IRC Channel and someone will answer you.
Speaker 1: it is not a far cry to say that if you can't find the solution to your problem with Linux on Google you are probably well beyond the stage of getting into Linux.
Speaker 0: Yes, that it's like.
Speaker 0: a problem like that is such a difficult problem.
Speaker 0: it probably yes.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's at the point where well this experimental kernel won't work with this blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: And I ran these extra patches and March blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: any normal problem like my wireless card won't work.
Speaker 0: You know why does?
Speaker 0: why does my?
Speaker 0: how do I get this screensaver to turn on granted occasionally?
Speaker 1: sadly the answer is still?
Speaker 1: Oh, it just doesn't work, but you'll find that out pretty definitively pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And that's only if you have some weird or new hardware or something like that and
Speaker 1: even
Speaker 0: that too common
Speaker 1: like apparently the motherboard I bought the a b9 had a lot of problems with Linux early on and Most of those problems have been fixed some of them in the interim between when I are made it and when it's coming back.
Speaker 0: Yep, Lynn, that's unlike windows.
Speaker 0: You know where people work on something on Windows and they work on a work on it And then you don't get it until five years later when Vista comes out or seven years later when Vista 2 comes out Linux.
Speaker 0: they constantly fix stuff and make new stuff and it comes out within a couple days.
Speaker 0: You're constantly updating things all over the place.
Speaker 0: So you get the CD you boot the CD you have a working Linux.
Speaker 0: I don't like we said.
Speaker 0: the next thing you want to do is force yourself to use it.
Speaker 1: Yep, maybe install it accomplish your goal, whatever you decide to set out to do try to do it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Now once you've gotten to that point, you're pretty much there.
Speaker 0: I mean you've got Linux.
Speaker 0: you probably installed it Which is not difficult.
Speaker 0: you click on an icon and you answer the questions and bam it's installed.
Speaker 0: You can run it off your hard drive.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 1: Yeah at that point It's really no different than using windows.
Speaker 1: You just have to navigate around and use it and eventually every now and then you'll run into something that you might not understand And you'll probably find an answer pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So what do you do now?
Speaker 0: well, the thing is Ubuntu sort of makes things easy for you and While using Ubuntu you will learn how to use a slightly different Desktop environment to accomplish your daily tasks and you will learn how to not play 3d games all day and waste your time.
Speaker 1: Ah, I think there's another important thing that you learn from using Ubuntu even straight up.
Speaker 0: What is that you realize?
Speaker 1: or at least you'll start interacting with the open source paradigm of getting software?
Speaker 1: No more share where no more going to sites to get programs.
Speaker 1: You'll download things from repositories everything signed and verified.
Speaker 1: you'll learn about repositories and how they work.
Speaker 1: You'll realize that when you install a program, there's no such thing as where did it install to?
Speaker 0: yep, there is no such thing as where did it install to.
Speaker 0: it's either installed or not.
Speaker 1: and Basically, these things don't matter a lot unless you really want to use Linux instead of just using Linux.
Speaker 1: but at the same time I think this is an important part of learning about Linux is using Ubuntu or whatever easy distro and Interacting with these things easily throughout your normal days.
Speaker 1: use of a computer
Speaker 0: but basically all you're gonna do by using Ubuntu is learn the stuff that you do and Learn as much as you need to do whatever you're doing, you know, if you're only gonna do so much you're eventually gonna learn Everything about the stuff you do and nothing else because Ubuntu is really easy.
Speaker 0: They did all that stuff for you And they don't force you to learn anything that you don't have to learn in order to get done what you want to get done.
Speaker 0: So if you want to learn more than what Ubuntu provides You actually can without.
Speaker 0: you don't actually have to leave Ubuntu right away because there are.
Speaker 0: while Ubuntu makes things easy for you You can still get under the hood You can open up the command line you go digging around and you know, there are websites like I think it's like command line.
Speaker 0: calm I think.
Speaker 0: Oh Linux command org is the website.
Speaker 0: It is a really great website that just tells you how to use the Linux command line and all the basic Really simple commands and how all that stuff works.
Speaker 1: Yep granted much like Linux itself Don't decide I am going to learn the Linux command line that come up with a task that you need to accomplish on your computer That you can't do easily any other way and then do it in the command line Where if you read you'll discover that usually it's a lot easier than it would have been to do it in the GUI.
Speaker 0: Here's another hint that this is how I learned a lot of the things I know about Linux, right?
Speaker 0: What you're gonna end up doing whenever you have a problem is you're gonna go to a forum You're gonna go to Google and you're gonna say hey, this doesn't work.
Speaker 0: What do I do?
Speaker 0: and someone might send you some instructions like click here do this type in this command now do this And you'll do all those things exactly as it says right there and nine times out of ten It'll work and you'll forget about it.
Speaker 0: Don't do that what you should do when anyone gives you a how to do this in Linux or you know Here's the fix to your problem in five easy steps.
Speaker 0: Make sure that when you do each of those steps that before you do it you 100% understand exactly what you are doing in each step.
Speaker 1: in the very least Look at what the commands are and try to figure out what they're doing just easily even if it's not the exact detail just Kind of what it's doing.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I'm copying this file here.
Speaker 1: I wonder what that file is.
Speaker 0: Yep, cuz basically that's how I learned everything.
Speaker 0: I know is someone to give me a how-to and I would say alright I could just type these things in and they'll work.
Speaker 0: sort of like You know if someone gave you instructions on how to fix your TV and they said You know kick it and you kicked it and it worked.
Speaker 0: Well, why did that work?
Speaker 0: and you kind of if you know why it worked suddenly?
Speaker 0: A lot of other things will start to make sense and you'll get pieces and they'll put together and you'll it's really that's how it Goes man.
Speaker 0: That's the way to learn.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now if you want to move beyond that, I Think it's Gentoo time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see Ubuntu makes everything easy for you And it's sort of a lot of things are unnecessary to tweak.
Speaker 0: like you can go and tweak them But you wouldn't ever think to because they're already correct.
Speaker 0: And this is why Gen 2 Linux exists.
Speaker 0: Gen 2 Linux is Still Linux but the design of the distribution is a completely different principle from Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to explain it but regardless to say needless to say Gentoo makes you learn.
Speaker 0: it basically Makes you make it.
Speaker 1: but yet don't think that you'll be in over your head.
Speaker 1: even if you don't know a lot about Linux.
Speaker 1: you could use Gentoo or at least get it working because their documentation is Wonderful.
Speaker 1: and if you follow their how to make a Gentoo step by step where it shows you what to type and then it Explains what you just typed why you typed it and what it did and if you follow it step by step by the end You'll have a mostly working Gentoo.
Speaker 1: And as long as you actually read all that text and didn't just type the things that said but actually learned what those things were Doing you'll suddenly realize so that's what a kernel is.
Speaker 1: So that's where it is, huh?
Speaker 0: Oh, that's how that thing works, that's what that piece does see because Linux is all pieces unlike Windows.
Speaker 0: It's just one blob.
Speaker 0: That's all Windows.
Speaker 0: Well, I believe you mean GNU Linux, whatever Windows is one big blob.
Speaker 0: Linux is a bunch of tiny pieces and many of the pieces are interchangeable.
Speaker 0: or perhaps you can choose between pieces have them all simultaneously and use whichever one you want or have multiple pieces all working together and each part of the Whole system can be switched out.
Speaker 0: You could have grub or lilo as your bootloader.
Speaker 0: You can have GDM KDM or some other ones as your you know, login manager.
Speaker 0: You can have KDE XFCE gnome as your window manager.
Speaker 0: You can have so many different choices all over the place and using Ubuntu Those choices are mostly made for you.
Speaker 0: You can change the choices, but they've already decided for you in Gentoo.
Speaker 0: They don't decide anything for you.
Speaker 0: They basically give you nothing and you have to pick the pieces for yourself one at a time.
Speaker 1: They do.
Speaker 1: however don't leave you completely in the cold.
Speaker 1: They often give suggestions like I think one good example was how to deal with logs on the computer And they give you like four different options and they explain in very brief Just well this one's kind of like this and this one's kind of like this and this one's kind of like this.
Speaker 0: And this is everyone you probably use the most people use Yep.
Speaker 1: And then for cron your cron jobs and all that they give you examples of.
Speaker 1: we could use this one or this one or this One.
Speaker 1: we recommend this one because it's easy but blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile in Ubuntu, you probably didn't even know what cron was.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now suddenly you're forced to install cron configure cron and learn how to use cron all at once Basically, you can.
Speaker 0: then you go back to your Ubuntu and you see hey cron is there.
Speaker 0: it just never forced me to nope Pay attention to it at all.
Speaker 0: It was already set up and nice working.
Speaker 1: Gentoo will force you anytime you want something new to work.
Speaker 1: It'll force you to learn at least on a base level how that thing works.
Speaker 0: Yep, like an Ubuntu you want to make the Apache web server work.
Speaker 0: you do app get install Apache install it It works.
Speaker 0: end of story.
Speaker 0: It just happens in Gentoo.
Speaker 0: You want the Apache web server work?
Speaker 0: Well you install it which is is easy enough.
Speaker 0: you emerge Apache.
Speaker 0: Now you have to configure it and you'll pretty much be forced to learn how to configure Apache Whereas Ubuntu comes with a default configuration.
Speaker 0: That is nice.
Speaker 0: Gentoo comes with a default Configuration that is not as nice and is will not just work the way you want it to by default.
Speaker 1: But at the same time because it doesn't just do stuff for you There's no chance that your computer did something that you didn't make it do somehow.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So whenever there's a problem I'm not I mean, it doesn't mean you're stupid because God by Gentoo I it's alright.
Speaker 0: for anyone out there who's like Oh Gentoo sounds too hard You know what?
Speaker 1: I first time I built a Gentoo I was all excited and I built it over three days.
Speaker 1: it was ready to go and then I rebooted into it and my network card wouldn't work and I couldn't figure out how to Make it work.
Speaker 1: and I freaked out and eventually reinstalled it.
Speaker 1: And then the second time through the install I get to the networking part and I'm like, oh I get it I'm just a dumbass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I did like five or six of those before I finally figured out everything I need.
Speaker 1: the only reason I only did one was because Scott actually gave me a lot of advice Particularly with the kernel.
Speaker 1: he's like, all right, don't enable that.
Speaker 1: All right, don't enable that.
Speaker 1: enable that.
Speaker 1: you need that.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is either but that kind of crap the Linux kernel basically is is one program.
Speaker 0: when you're when Linux starts it loads the kernel into memory and the kernel is This one thing down at the bottom of the heap that every other program talks to it.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's the thing that goes in between your hardware the physical chips and everything else on your computer.
Speaker 0: So the way it works is you configure the kernel there are many pieces of it is completely modular in every way and Every piece of the kernel.
Speaker 0: you can either choose to not have it have it in the kernel itself or have it as a module Which means it'll be there, but it'll only actually get loaded if you're gonna use it now.
Speaker 1: Distributions like Red Hat and Ubuntu Tend to just throw a lot of stuff into the kernel to make it more likely to work.
Speaker 0: the Ubuntu kernel Basically is the full almost the full kernel.
Speaker 0: They have so many extra stuff in there and they have everything turned on and it's a really big kernel.
Speaker 0: But because it's so big no matter what computer you try to use it on It'll probably work because it'll have whatever you need in there.
Speaker 1: Gentoo Meanwhile gives you pretty much nothing and you got to go through and pick.
Speaker 0: Yes individual thing Gentoo gives you the kernel the way it was meant to be given and You go through the kernel configuration every single menu probably every single menu.
Speaker 0: You probably should reading what each bit does and deciding whether you need that bit or not.
Speaker 0: You know what most of the bits you don't need.
Speaker 1: it took me Over an hour to sit there and go through the kernel looking at everything and wondering what it was Looking in the documentation to see what it was trying to figure out.
Speaker 1: if I needed it Some stuff I had to figure out.
Speaker 1: Oh, well because you're booting with blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: You can't have that be in module because you won't be able to load the module before you need it So you'll have to file it into the kernel.
Speaker 0: Doing this will not only familiarize you with your Linux system and Linux kernel It will also make you very familiar with the hardware in your computer because if you don't know what hardware is in your computer Specifically you will have a very difficult time configuring the kernel.
Speaker 0: Yes with the hardware if it's a mystery box and it's not just.
Speaker 1: oh I have X brand network card All right, I have X chipset on X network card, yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: do I have the silicon image Serial ATA controller or do I have the 3215?
Speaker 0: Serial ATA controller?
Speaker 0: and people don't even know what a serial ATA controller is.
Speaker 0: so you can see already how?
Speaker 0: Installing gen 2 Linux forces you to learn so many things about your computer and Linux and everything.
Speaker 1: Yep, like in that case it also teaches you like oh you need to know all this hardware.
Speaker 1: It teaches you how to get that information from your hardware.
Speaker 0: Yep, a lot of the reason I know so much I know is because I forced myself to learn all that stuff and I use gen 2 for many years And I don't know as much as Scott But I learned more in the year or so.
Speaker 1: I actively kept my gen 2 up to date before I just stopped.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then I did in the rest of my time using Linux.
Speaker 0: So if you want to get into Linux get an Ubuntu CD and get to work and make sure you have a Reason to be doing this don't just do it for the sake of it because you're not gonna get anywhere.
Speaker 0: You're gonna lose interest and quit.
Speaker 1: if you're serious about it, or you want to use it for a job or career or whatever I would say that any Linux professional or any computer professional should build at least one gen 2. or If you're hardcore Completely Linux from scratch.
Speaker 0: Yes gen 2 is bait is really a system that makes doing Linux from scratch easier.
Speaker 0: It's basically Linux from scratch only with some stuff to help you do it.
Speaker 0: You can actually do it.
Speaker 0: go to Linux from.
Speaker 0: I think it's LFS is the website I think I don't remember Linux from scratch org and that will tell you how to build this.
Speaker 0: There's like a document there that you can read.
Speaker 0: that will tell you how to make Linux from scratch by hand Completely 100% and it takes a long time a real long time.
Speaker 0: But you'll probably learn even more than you learn doing like three Gentoos because there's nothing helping you out except this book.
Speaker 1: But I mean if you're a professional or you want to be a professional Doing this once and dealing with it for even a short amount of time will give you a very valuable foundation.
Speaker 1: Yes, how many were?
Speaker 0: suddenly you'll go from that nub in the Ubuntu forums going?
Speaker 0: How does my wireless work?
Speaker 0: What's this ndis rapper business to the guy in the Gentoo forums going?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't want that kernel module.
Speaker 0: It takes up a lot of memory and slows you down.
Speaker 1: and don't be afraid to ask for help.
Speaker 1: while there are scary Linux nerds Out there who will make fun of you and berate you there are many more people who will just answer your question.
Speaker 0: In fact, if anything for every guy for image even in the Gentoo forums or even on IRCs for every one guy Who's like our TFM nub there's like three guys who are like.
Speaker 0: here's a link to the how-to.
Speaker 0: Read this yeah,
Speaker 1: well in fact Scott as an example not only does he like to help us all of us in the front row crew with our Linux trouble But he
Speaker 0: will
Speaker 1: out of the blue go out of his way to impart new Linux knowledge unto us rather or not we want it.
Speaker 0: Yep, I also go out of my way to force people to try to do things the more efficient way like hey use the keyboard Shortcut bitch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'd have my ass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do respect the superiority of you dev.
Speaker 0: However Yeah, you realize that Dev FS is basically dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know isn't?
Speaker 1: you'd have default now in Gentoo.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's the default period in all Linux.
Speaker 1: Yeah good cuz this Gentoo is not.
Speaker 0: Wow, that's old.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I have an update.
Speaker 1: God You should see what happens if I type the word emerge in my current Gentoo My Gentoo.
Speaker 1: the way it functions is no longer supported by anyone.
Speaker 1: awesome This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.