Speaker 1: It's Wednesday December 12th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nines.
Speaker 1: tonight the New York anime festival.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well for a lot of you new listeners.
Speaker 1: I know tonight's the night You've been waiting for.
Speaker 1: we're actually gonna talk about that their New York anime festival.
Speaker 0: And if you're a new listener you were there.
Speaker 0: So I don't know.
Speaker 0: was it entertaining to hear people talk about a thing that you experienced yourself?
Speaker 1: see I've always found it that way Listen to look before.
Speaker 1: I you know did this.
Speaker 1: when I listen to other people do like con reports There's always like wow I didn't see that at the con or man I miss that see I think also.
Speaker 0: in addition if you you know you you saw us at the con in some way And you thought we were entertaining.
Speaker 0: maybe you're not quite sure that.
Speaker 0: maybe you want to become a. you know Spend four hours of your life every week listening to this if you were at the con And you listen to us talk about it And you go mmm and nodding your head in agreement at the things we say.
Speaker 0: Maybe listening is a good idea and Maybe if you listen and you go what the fuck you guys are full of shit at all the things.
Speaker 0: we say maybe listening is A good idea, maybe you're you're better off listening to anime pulse.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: No I said, maybe listening is a good idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, listen what I said.
Speaker 0: Anyway, all right, so you remember how I had trouble sorting all my musics.
Speaker 1: I do and I remember my advice was always well Shouldn't have gotten into this situation.
Speaker 1: keep your music in.
Speaker 0: we offered no useful solution.
Speaker 1: Well I offered one solution which was delete everything and then torrent.
Speaker 0: yeah great well I have a new solution delete everything in torrent.
Speaker 0: No the new solution is every day do a few albums.
Speaker 0: It's every day.
Speaker 0: It's gonna.
Speaker 0: Do a little bit like in the morning like so baby steps.
Speaker 0: yeah, and as long and as long as I don't acquire new music or Acquire music at a rate less than the rate at which I sort music eventually it all be done.
Speaker 0: Basically my strategy is for example on the first day right which was today I guess you know I took I went in and I said all right what I want.
Speaker 0: I said I want some Daft Punk's.
Speaker 0: I looked in the Daft Punk folder which kind of you know cuz it's still semi sorted.
Speaker 0: You know so and there wasn't much in there.
Speaker 0: I mean there was Daft Punk songs But not every Daft Punk song and you know I knew there was more.
Speaker 0: So I went and I got a bunch of Daft Punk torrents, and I down torrented every album.
Speaker 0: I checked Wikipedia for the discography and then I Sorted them with the music brains thingy, which I had.
Speaker 0: there's a newer better one that works better, and there I had it.
Speaker 0: I had a few albums, and I deleted my old stuff, so I'm doing this sort of slow replace But also we'll see how long this keeps up, but also in addition to these slow replace There are also some things I have that are sort of Unreplaceable.
Speaker 0: so those I'm.
Speaker 0: what I'm thinking is I'll do the slow replace of all the replaceables And then all the non replaceables will be left over and there won't be all these Replaceables in the way and it'll be much easier to handle those.
Speaker 0: well then those you can put in the rare directory Maybe but rare usually means like opener to a single anime.
Speaker 1: now I got some weird stuff like.
Speaker 1: I got that random recording of like a yokokano playing the eska flown a theme on a piano.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like that.
Speaker 0: What is that?
Speaker 0: It's just like a bootleg mp3.
Speaker 0: There's no album or anything to sort.
Speaker 1: it goes it for me.
Speaker 1: It goes in the yokokano directory I guess I guess.
Speaker 0: but In addition to that I'll probably be You know finding all sorts of amazing new old musics that I've had lying around on my mp3 folders.
Speaker 0: Ah, we'll see if any of those make it anywhere in the show or anything.
Speaker 1: But anyway because no one wants to hear about that before we get to the you know I think some people want to hear coverage of the con.
Speaker 1: you know all you new listeners We do news.
Speaker 1: at the beginning we talk a little bit about what's going on in the anime world.
Speaker 1: so Scott What is going on in the anime world?
Speaker 0: What is indeed going on in the animal world?
Speaker 0: many many awesome things, but perhaps the most awesome thing well I don't know if it's the most awesome is There was quite an announcement at the the New York anime festival an announcement that was anticipated because well I don't know you couldn't see it a mile away, but when you look to the con schedule there were many panels.
Speaker 0: There was a. there was you know a Tokyo pop panel Vertical panel of his panel whatever.
Speaker 0: there was also a Del Rey panel And then there was a Del Rey and Marvel panel.
Speaker 0: and well if that doesn't give everything away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean what.
Speaker 1: they were just gonna have some Del Rey guys and some Marvel guys talk about something together.
Speaker 1: Just you know nothing special.
Speaker 0: It's like they Just announcing the scheduling of the panel.
Speaker 0: they sort of gave away.
Speaker 0: You couldn't really keep the secret of some sort of Del Rey Marvel partnership.
Speaker 1: now the panel was Sunday And as many of you went to the con might have known Sunday was not our best day.
Speaker 0: The Sunday was not the best day.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about that soon enough.
Speaker 1: We did not make it to the panel to do our sort of coverage of it.
Speaker 0: No, but that's not necessary because anime news network covered everything.
Speaker 0: So we're not really gonna talk about much other news from the con unless you have something to add you know to the story.
Speaker 1: I have one very important piece of news from the con.
Speaker 1: Peter Fernandez has a sexy voice.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah good God he is like professional radio voice better than us ever.
Speaker 0: but anyway What they did specifically announce is that they're gonna make some?
Speaker 0: Mangas with some x-men's in it.
Speaker 0: Aha, but you know manga is in quotes because it's you know not made in Japan for a Japanese audience in a Japanese magazine.
Speaker 0: It's just gonna be you know published in you know digest format in the US as you know.
Speaker 1: Is it just that it's gonna be published in trades, or is it gonna be in the?
Speaker 1: I hate to say something like this But the quote-unquote marketing speak manga style.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be in the manga style the oels of the world mangas or whatever you want to call them and basically They're gonna make a shoujo a shoujo x-men right where it.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it'll be just like the movies.
Speaker 0: well It's gonna be like kitty pride is the only girl in the all boys Pride is like the best.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 0: the kitty pride is the only girl in the all boys Xavier school for gifted youngsters.
Speaker 1: wait wait wait wait wait.
Speaker 1: what about rogue?
Speaker 0: What about Jubilee?
Speaker 0: not gonna be there Jean Grey?
Speaker 0: not gonna be there I can understand, but or at least not gonna be in the school.
Speaker 0: Maybe they'll be outside the school somewhere.
Speaker 0: ah But yeah, and the other one is gonna be shown in Wolverine where Wolverines badass cutting people up.
Speaker 1: So won't it just be lone wolf and Cobb man.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: that's Lone wolf and Cobb then Wolverine then lone wolf and come again.
Speaker 1: who knows it's just gonna be lone wolf and Cobb only without the Cub.
Speaker 0: who knows it'll probably more like a Naruto style.
Speaker 0: Wolverine is using the special techniques.
Speaker 0: You know like.
Speaker 0: oh, no, so I can't beat you saber-tooth I'll have to use my spinny slashy.
Speaker 0: Oh, no is to use the spinny slashy.
Speaker 0: oh You cannot defeat my healing powers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: I guess I know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what?
Speaker 0: In the past Marvel has tried this manga thing before manga thing before with their Marvel manga verse.
Speaker 0: You know where they made in American comic style format, but also Marvel digest for.
Speaker 1: well I think they've realized one thing that regardless of the reasons behind it the fact remains that Even average manga outsell pretty much any comic in the u.s.. A billion to one.
Speaker 0: well That's true, but I think the problem here, and it clearly shows the problem Is that these companies even the manga companies?
Speaker 0: I guess vertical understands, but the other companies like Viz and I guess Del Rey especially Del Rey and Marvel especially at least They know that manga is popular But they still don't understand why.
Speaker 0: and it's like they.
Speaker 0: they see what makes it different.
Speaker 0: right because it's sort of obvious Why it's different, but they're not.
Speaker 0: they can't fake.
Speaker 0: They don't truly know the exact things the reason why it sells more.
Speaker 0: They're just like.
Speaker 0: well It's different in these ways and it sells more.
Speaker 0: so let's make something in those ways now.
Speaker 1: granted this can cause some good effects.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not just because they're in trades that they tend to do better.
Speaker 1: however I would be a much happier man if I never saw a single issue of any comic ever released ever again.
Speaker 0: But they seem to think still that it's the artistic style that would makes these things sell or the fact that they're right to left That makes them sell.
Speaker 0: you know it's people don't buy manga because it's right to left.
Speaker 0: You know people would buy manga if it was left to right.
Speaker 0: It's but they it's.
Speaker 0: the thing is because it was originally right to left.
Speaker 0: They like it to be the original way.
Speaker 0: it has nothing to do with you know as people aren't going.
Speaker 0: oh, man I'm buying this manga because it's cool.
Speaker 0: It's backwards.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm buying it.
Speaker 0: That's not how it is.
Speaker 0: They're also not saying check it out as a stereotypical anime styling.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm gonna buy it.
Speaker 0: That's not granted.
Speaker 1: at the same time I think the fact that a lot of at least the manga that's brought out commonly in the u.s.
Speaker 1: I mean there is manga that looks very different, but we don't see a lot of that over here sadly, but People who see it saw that in the store especially.
Speaker 1: you know in the early days of manga being brought over shoujo manga Especially it was just a breath of fresh air compared to big muscly men to hit another big muscly man.
Speaker 1: I'll hit you you little guy.
Speaker 0: the only reason why Manga and anime are popular and what made them popular in the first place is you had people who grew up on animation and comics right and They still liked animation in comics And they wanted more.
Speaker 0: But the only supply of animation in comics was designed to appeal to a very young audience and people grew out of that.
Speaker 0: You know I mean Rugrats is only funny.
Speaker 0: you know Nick tunes could only entertain you until you were such an age until which they stopped being entertaining.
Speaker 1: I mean as to counter that Doug is always entertaining.
Speaker 1: That's your original.
Speaker 0: I didn't say Doug.
Speaker 1: I said rugrats Yeah, they're the same kind Right.
Speaker 0: so things like the Simpsons and the family guy and the MTV.
Speaker 0: you know animations and whatever.
Speaker 0: you know they.
Speaker 0: they were working But not they didn't.
Speaker 0: you know beavis of a head, but they didn't fulfill the desire And they didn't you know they weren't didn't have the mass appeal you know.
Speaker 0: so the animes came on the sci-fi channel and people who?
Speaker 0: Animation.
Speaker 0: but grew out of Nick tunes and whatever said wow look at that It's an animation that appeals to an older audience to me that is made for me.
Speaker 0: That's so awesome.
Speaker 1: now granted older audience I was in fourth grade, and I saw vampire hunter D.
Speaker 0: That's all that's about the right.
Speaker 1: and my fourth grade brain was was saying to myself Wow that guy just got cut in half.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: This is awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm what is this called anime?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna watch every anime.
Speaker 0: I find all they have to do is take a lot of people in half that just take an intelligent mature Cut.
Speaker 0: you know storyline.
Speaker 1: yes because vampire hunter D was such a deep But she was with a big it you know compared to any other cartoon kids were watching back then.
Speaker 0: I mean yeah Yeah, exactly have a beginning a middle and an end with no crossover bullshit and publish it in a format that is Financially feasible for someone in the target audience to buy.
Speaker 0: that's all you have to do.
Speaker 0: all this other stuff that you're doing Like let's make it in this kind of artistic style make it in this kind.
Speaker 0: That's not necessary.
Speaker 0: That's not the reason this stuff is popular in the first place, but you don't seem to understand that And I don't know if you ever will.
Speaker 1: I mean at the same time I did hear that those Manga II looking spider-man comics sold a lot better than a lot of other spider-man comics.
Speaker 0: That's quite possible, but that's also.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of those are published in the digest format.
Speaker 1: see I don't.
Speaker 1: I think that there might also be.
Speaker 1: just in the culture of people are reading manga.
Speaker 1: They I mean and I'll say when I see it of spandex wearing muscle man.
Speaker 1: I really have very much difficulty in seeing any sort of meaningful or interesting plot behind that Spandex covered muscly man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is harder.
Speaker 0: There is no doubt especially if it's drawn in the old style.
Speaker 1: I mean there is the exception and I say exception cuz it's pretty well.
Speaker 1: There's a couple I guess.
Speaker 1: there's Watchmen and there's Frank Miller's Batman the Dark Knight Returns, which you finally read.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should talk about the next week.
Speaker 1: That was the best Superman comic ever.
Speaker 0: Let's read it Let's just talk about next week.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 1: God.
Speaker 1: We haven't talked about anime.
Speaker 0: How long let's do?
Speaker 0: we watched anime.
Speaker 1: Let's do an anime next week, and then the week after that we're gonna talk about Frank Miller.
Speaker 0: All right right?
Speaker 1: so real quick my news because you know we live in New York City or around, New York City.
Speaker 1: Takashi Murakami who is known for these super flat style.
Speaker 1: if you want to know what super flat is don't fucking ask us.
Speaker 0: We have no clue.
Speaker 0: It's a word that talks about a kind of style of art.
Speaker 1: I know anything I've seen that people called super flat was generally pretty cool and Takashi Murakami seems to be the man who started it all.
Speaker 0: yeah What is up with lately?
Speaker 0: people coming up with terms, but the terms not being clearly like defined.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, we have this word.
Speaker 0: super flat refers to this artistic style.
Speaker 0: well Can you categorize it?
Speaker 0: no we really can't.
Speaker 0: it's like back in the olden days?
Speaker 0: They were like rock and roll, and it was clear.
Speaker 0: What was rockin was?
Speaker 1: it wasn't really not.
Speaker 0: yes It was there were.
Speaker 1: you know rock and roll evolved from one point to another point And there's a points where a lot of people would have said that stuff isn't rock and roll and this stuff is but then people Were born later would say that's all rock and roll, but this new stuff is.
Speaker 1: at what point is it no longer rock and roll to Me.
Speaker 1: yeah, whatever Murakami is awesome.
Speaker 1: You should check out.
Speaker 1: you know any of this stuff, but he has an exhibit a rather large exhibit And it is coming to the Brooklyn Museum in New York City in April through July of 2008.
Speaker 0: Well, let's go.
Speaker 1: We're definitely gonna be there.
Speaker 1: We'll tell you when we're gonna be there.
Speaker 1: We should arrange.
Speaker 0: we should arrange like a date and time for all those people's to go.
Speaker 0: I think we'll do something like maybe we'll go to the opening.
Speaker 0: ha Yeah, how about that?
Speaker 1: But seriously check out any like clips or anything you can find and if you're in New York City check this out I think right now.
Speaker 1: It's at the Museum of Contemporary Art in LA.
Speaker 0: if you're in LA you should go see it.
Speaker 1: Yes, you should.
Speaker 0: I'd.
Speaker 0: also.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that Tezuka thing is still in San Francisco.
Speaker 0: My parents saw it.
Speaker 0: you should go to that.
Speaker 1: did they see it in San Francisco.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right There's also the woodblock thing there, which is ten times better than the Tezuka thing, but you know it's not comics Things of the day.
Speaker 1: So uh I was going through my papers a while ago and I just found something that was kind of amazing and I feel like it's my duty as a Human being in an anime fan to fill this out and send it in all right now.
Speaker 1: I'll let you all guess what year it's from but I found a Central Park Media Survey that came with some sort of anime that I bought at some point in my life Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: now this survey asks a lot of important questions.
Speaker 1: for example What is my age?
Speaker 1: and I like how they break down these demographics?
Speaker 1: It's like under 17 18 to 35 35 to 50 or over 50?
Speaker 1: Wow Yeah, they really because I think they're forgetting that there's like this 18 to 25 year old like college kid demographic.
Speaker 1: that information is basically useless I know or out annual household income.
Speaker 1: it maxes out.
Speaker 1: It's like over 50,000 much less than 50,000 Alrighty, but here's where it gets really fun.
Speaker 1: It's like what equipment.
Speaker 1: Do you have and it gives me six checkboxes now?
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: We'll do this live on the show.
Speaker 1: VHS.
Speaker 1: I guess we still have a VCR though.
Speaker 1: I haven't plugged it in yep eight millimeter.
Speaker 1: We don't have that nope video disc.
Speaker 1: No, we don't have that.
Speaker 0: I guess we technically do.
Speaker 0: it's VCD.
Speaker 0: They're talking about right.
Speaker 1: Uh I think they're - I don't know.
Speaker 0: Where's the laser?
Speaker 1: They're probably talking about laser disc.
Speaker 0: We don't have laser disc.
Speaker 1: satellite dish.
Speaker 1: nope nope compact disc.
Speaker 1: I have a compact disc player.
Speaker 1: yep projection TV.
Speaker 0: no no no no.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Do we get our anime?
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess this is only asking about video cassettes.
Speaker 1: I mean how many video cassettes do I purchase in a month?
Speaker 1: how often do I rent video cassettes?
Speaker 1: Zero zero and I think my favorite good how many videos do you purchase an average year?
Speaker 1: and it's pretty much zero more than ten.
Speaker 1: All right, I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean this.
Speaker 1: this is like a piece of history.
Speaker 1: I mean CPM is almost out of business.
Speaker 1: They're like a bacteria that turned into a spore, and it's just desperately waiting for the water to come back.
Speaker 0: They confirmed that their panel at the New York anime festival that they're sort of in like low-cost mode like they're not doing anything.
Speaker 0: They're just chilling out and you know building back up.
Speaker 0: You know they're basically it's sort of like when you put the set it you put the tat in civilization, too.
Speaker 0: You know you you don't make any war you stop building anything.
Speaker 0: You just capitalism and and tax and just chill until you get to.
Speaker 0: you know you get stable So you can go at it again, and that's sort of what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not a bad plan at least.
Speaker 0: We're not just going out of business.
Speaker 0: You know horribly or whatever you know, but Also, they did a funny thing after their panel on Sunday because it was a late Sunday panel.
Speaker 0: They said anyone with a red bag can go to our booth and take whatever they want.
Speaker 1: now That's dangerous.
Speaker 1: That was a trap.
Speaker 1: I mean especially since you don't want any that stuff I do that my favorite thing was CPM.
Speaker 1: You know cuz they have a lot of licenses to let or DVD stocks of some old awful anime.
Speaker 1: I mean they're awesome in one sense because they're not so bad that they're just not watchable like Odeon, but They're kind of awesome and that they're the kind of thing you can watch with all your friends and enjoy immensely especially if you're drinking
Speaker 0: Mmm,
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: I have some a few good shows too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but they were selling.
Speaker 1: It looked like they basically bundled together like 12 of the worst anime they had and they were selling it as a box set for Like 40 bucks is the CPM collection.
Speaker 1: and the scary thing was.
Speaker 1: at first I thought oh, man I'm totally gonna buy that and then I realized that I already own more than half of those DVDs.
Speaker 0: No, actually that box at 12.
Speaker 0: I think we owned actually none of those.
Speaker 1: No, cuz it had silent service in there, which is all right.
Speaker 0: We own one of them.
Speaker 1: I think we own a couple more - you forget that I have Graffler Baki and a bunch of that wasn't in there though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: no I wasn't in that box that I saw.
Speaker 1: they might have had more than one box.
Speaker 0: then maybe they just had boxes of 12 But I saw one box.
Speaker 1: You know, they have so few employees so it was someone's job to sit there and decide what DVDs to put in these bundles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well CPM.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the cool thing about this survey is you know in Japan when you get say shot and jump There's always a survey in the back You know or any anthology and it always asks you which manga did you like which one?
Speaker 0: didn't you like whatever and you send it?
Speaker 0: In you could win prizes and get free stuff and whatever.
Speaker 0: But that's how they know which ones are popular and which ones aren't is based on those surveys and they give the high return rate On those surveys like a ludicrously high return rate.
Speaker 0: So the early anime industry I don't know if they copied that from the Japanese manga, you know companies the survey thing But they were doing the survey thing and now they're not doing the survey thing.
Speaker 0: I think they should do the survey thing some more and right.
Speaker 1: if this survey reeks of like late 80s early 90s Absolutely incompetent at making a survey.
Speaker 0: that'll be used to be a modern Competence because I remember I used to use these all and also give me something free for mailing it in.
Speaker 1: you know back in the day when I'd spend my 35 or 40 bucks on a single VHS tape with three or four subtitled episodes of a show One of these would always be in it and I always fill it out and send it back.
Speaker 1: I don't know why I didn't send this one back.
Speaker 0: All right All right, so we are not the fans of the moe so much.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess this you know, you can argue about what's moe and what's not, you know Cuz we like you it suppose and I was among adios and I guess there might be some things you might be able to legitimately Call like moe saying in that we would also like.
Speaker 1: but I think the line just has to be.
Speaker 1: there are things that I like and things that I don't like in labels that can apply to either.
Speaker 1: because you know, I like I was among Adio, but I don't like creepy whatever that I saw at the con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean generally we use the word moe to apply to.
Speaker 0: you know the anime that you know things in anime that are there and the only way you could enjoy them is If you're a pervert who got jollies by looking at cute underage things Right, and but I thought moe was pure.
Speaker 1: It's not a sexual attraction It's just this intimate understanding of the helplessness of this cute thing and you just want to protect it.
Speaker 0: It is but that's just the excuse to cover up the pedophile isms.
Speaker 1: I'll bet there's at least a couple of people who actually do just feel that way.
Speaker 0: there might be but that's also kind of scary.
Speaker 1: Regardless, I think found Scott an example of when moe can be awesome, right?
Speaker 0: So so here is an example of when moe can be not so bad or at least I don't know if it's moe or not.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter, you know, they have like those moe tans which are like moe representations of like computer things OS time Yeah, and then they have those other ones that are like representations of like military vehicles.
Speaker 1: I'm a consumer.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, here's one where They did every pokemons.
Speaker 0: This is so adorable every pokemons in the moe style and but not just in the moe style and also in the pokémon style.
Speaker 0: And then there's a little song and they go through.
Speaker 0: they say all the names of all the pokémon.
Speaker 1: so far My favorite one is Diglett.
Speaker 0: I don't know that Gengar was pretty good.
Speaker 1: It was yeah.
Speaker 0: So if you like pokémon And you like cute this is where it's at people.
Speaker 1: But enough of all that because of course you're here to hear about the New York Anime Festival 2007 the first New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 1: we were guests there.
Speaker 0: We were there all three days and do you want to cover this the chronological way or a different way?
Speaker 1: I think we should start on well.
Speaker 1: first, you know shout outs and highlights and then you know.
Speaker 1: Well, let's talk about the good parts of the con and then the bad parts of the con.
Speaker 1: I've noticed that we tend to be very critical about conventions even ones We love like Otakon and Katsucon my favorite two cons.
Speaker 0: I think that's because when you go to something like a convention, it's right, right it no matter how many good things happen.
Speaker 0: What can you really say about the good things?
Speaker 0: Like for example, let's pretend that I go to Convention Y. Convention Y is an amazing game room and amazing showings.
Speaker 0: What am I gonna say?
Speaker 0: There was an amazing game room.
Speaker 0: There were amazing showings.
Speaker 1: Chirp chirp chirp not necessarily you could go into detail.
Speaker 1: I think the real problem is that I mean I think back to my first Otakon and I cannot think of a single bad thing that happened at it.
Speaker 1: Everything was awesome.
Speaker 0: I can think of some bad things.
Speaker 1: No because anything bad that happened ended up being an awesome story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, kind of.
Speaker 1: but now I've been to.
Speaker 1: you know A bunch of Otakons like five or six or seven of them by six.
Speaker 1: I forget it doesn't matter old man I can't remember and They kind of all blur together and I can't remember what like.
Speaker 1: I have to think Alright, that was the Otakon with Laraku right?
Speaker 1: So who was there?
Speaker 1: was this guy there?
Speaker 1: Did we go what hotel?
Speaker 1: I just can't remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're totally a blur to me.
Speaker 0: I don't remember which one was which I can't imagine.
Speaker 1: what that guy who wears his armor made out of con badges feels like.
Speaker 0: no God that guy with a beard.
Speaker 1: I know that guy's kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: We should talk to that guy.
Speaker 1: We should interview him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So highlights of the con number one.
Speaker 1: We ran, you know four panels at this con three of which were absolutely awesome and I think The best moment of this con for me hands down was you know We ran our anime match game like we run at every con and it pretty much always plays out.
Speaker 1: run
Speaker 0: at every con recently
Speaker 1: Yeah to a standing room only crowd and you know yelling and screaming and cheering and yeah
Speaker 0: I'm always surprised because it seemed I get the feeling right that people, you know Anyone who goes the anime match game will love it if they're at an anime con.
Speaker 0: That's a guarantee, but I get the feeling that a lot of people don't really understand the anime match game until they've gone to it.
Speaker 0: So I'm always amazed that people show up to it right off the bat.
Speaker 0: Like they know beforehand.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be good.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, you know when most people don't even know how the match game works I have noticed that pretty much throughout con history.
Speaker 1: if you see of Any sort of game show especially where there's any hint that the audience might be able to participate It's gonna be standing room only at a big con because people just they love that stuff
Speaker 0: Yep, especially if it's not competing with anything,
Speaker 1: but uh, you know, we always get celebrity guests.
Speaker 1: I think the best guest we've ever had until recently and I think I'll always be Steve Bennett because the Stevie B Is like the match game king.
Speaker 0: Well the best he's the best guest at match game.
Speaker 0: Well, hence the match game king Yes, I'm not gonna say is the best guess period.
Speaker 1: the guests we had were in no particular order except I'm saving the best for last Jamie McGonigal who's pretty damn awesome.
Speaker 0: I didn't know who he was at all And he was like the first guest that we saw there and he was pretty cool and he was very good at playing the match Game.
Speaker 0: Rachel Lillis equally awesome also excellent at playing the match game.
Speaker 1: Lisa Ortiz Who was a personal hero of mine for a long time.
Speaker 0: also excellent at playing the match game.
Speaker 0: She was hilarious and yeah I think she was the best at on the panel at playing the match game.
Speaker 1: Well also just the fact that she was she voice actually acted in a lot of anime that have a lot of very big dub Nostalgia for me.
Speaker 1: I mean slayers.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yep and Veronica Taylor also awesome.
Speaker 1: She was pretty much right up there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she was okay at the match game, but Corinne or and Peter Fernandez I know they were gonna be at the con Right, and I think they were on our.
Speaker 0: they we were.
Speaker 0: they were on a list that was emailed to us, right?
Speaker 0: Yes And I was kind of worried before the con because if you don't know these are like the original American voices of like speed racer and tricks.
Speaker 1: you see Corinne or also voice acted in star blazers galaxy Rangers Ultraman.
Speaker 0: these are these are awesome old people from way back and Like all man's.
Speaker 0: but I was worried because while these people are awesome and the triple awesome and I knew that beforehand On a match game.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: It's like Peter Fernandez amazing, dude What does he know?
Speaker 0: he's not watching name the hottest boy in anime.
Speaker 0: if you ask him to he'll be like.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is what first I mean I still I. it's like oh you're gonna be on my match game.
Speaker 1: Wow I kind of just want to shake your hand and get your autograph.
Speaker 1: yeah, I could do that the autographs but They were both awesome Corinne or was just hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Peter Fernandez has one of the sexiest voices I have ever heard a human being give out in person like Riley on the radio is kind of sexy, but Peter Fernandez in person god damn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like you hear these radio guys and they sound like radio guys You know on the microphone or whatever.
Speaker 0: But Peter Fernandez like I saw this old man kind of walk in and I'm like, oh man, it's the old man Oh man's the awesome old man, and I didn't hear him say anything.
Speaker 0: And then when he finally said something I was like, holy shit cuz.
Speaker 0: he sounded like an amazing radio guy But he was just sitting right there and it was kind of crazy.
Speaker 0: It was like a voice coming out of a thing.
Speaker 0: You didn't expect I expected like an old voice, but it wasn't.
Speaker 0: it was like a. Who's that guy who does the rockin New Year's Eve Dick Clark?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah kind of like that.
Speaker 0: It was like whoa Plus wonder.
Speaker 0: he was voice acting and such.
Speaker 1: I wasn't sure how he would like being on the match game, but he seemed to love it and the crowd just loved it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though you know him and Corinne were weren't so good at match game mostly because they didn't know about anime.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is they didn't know about modern animus Say like the name a character in Naruto who's better than Naruto.
Speaker 1: but at the same time they were able fairly consistently to wow the crowd with various answers that They did a pretty awesome job.
Speaker 0: They did the best job they could with their knowledge and it was still quite awesome.
Speaker 0: And yeah, it was a good match game.
Speaker 0: What can I say?
Speaker 1: I think we're pretty much gonna run the match game at any con.
Speaker 0: we go to keep running the match game until stops working.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is right about when it stops working.
Speaker 1: we have challenger on fire coming up.
Speaker 1: now we've rework.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that's gonna work.
Speaker 1: I think it's gonna work great, especially with what we've got lined up for katsu con.
Speaker 1: Yeah we'll see we were gonna have.
Speaker 1: we're going to have guests who are fully aware of exactly what it takes to be a challenger on fire.
Speaker 0: that can help a lot.
Speaker 1: and Also, we've got fanboy feud still in the works.
Speaker 1: We have a bounty about that.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that next week.
Speaker 1: Okay, but another highlight.
Speaker 1: we write, you know, that was the anime match game.
Speaker 1: Now we ran the video game match game on Sunday.
Speaker 1: I would consider that probably The second or third lamest panel we've ever run.
Speaker 0: Well, I think I realized my mistake too late in running the video game.
Speaker 1: and you see Saturday I pretty much ran the anime match game and wrecked my voice as a result because there were two microphones between like a people Gaga, everybody was gaga.
Speaker 1: We didn't even give the Contestants microphones.
Speaker 1: they had to yell, but I had to yell a lot and I was shot.
Speaker 1: so I'm like Scott.
Speaker 1: Do you think you can run the video game match game without written material?
Speaker 1: and he says immortal words?
Speaker 1: Yeah rim I can make up stuff for a video game match game.
Speaker 1: How hard could it be in advance?
Speaker 0: I actually did make up a bunch of stuff in my head But then when it actually came time to use it, it was all gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was kind of late.
Speaker 0: You know how that happens.
Speaker 0: Everyone's had that experience.
Speaker 0: We didn't line up really should have written some of it down.
Speaker 1: We didn't really line up guests for it.
Speaker 1: So and and a bunch of our friends decided not to come to the con on Sunday.
Speaker 0: And honestly, I almost didn't - I can't blame them They made a wise choice and we'll get to that.
Speaker 1: but as a result, it was pretty much Scott myself Darryl Surratt and Dave Riley and Darryl Surratt and Dave Riley.
Speaker 0: We had to like pester them on Saturday in order to get them to come on Sunday.
Speaker 1: I had to bribe them with badges to katsu-kan.
Speaker 1: It was like all you have to do is be in this room Relatively sober around 11 a.m And I will give you a free badge to katsu-kan.
Speaker 0: and no matter what else we may say about them in the show or in The future they came through for us because the video game match game I mean, it was pretty bad, but if they didn't show up, it would have been non-existent.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: It was was much better because they were there.
Speaker 1: what it was was something.
Speaker 0: Uh Okay, basically this how it went down right?
Speaker 0: First of all, there wasn't so much attendance Which is understandable considering it was Sunday and the attendance was low in general, which we'll talk about again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is weird.
Speaker 1: I mean you know Saturday all our panels were like two of our panels were standing room only just about and One of them was like mostly a full room in this game.
Speaker 1: There was nothing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It was all our friends and fans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, bored people.
Speaker 0: So very few people showed up understandably and Which really doesn't work for a game show.
Speaker 0: then only four people wanted to be contestants.
Speaker 0: So we got two of them up there and because there were only four of us I had to host the show and be on the panel at the same time or else it wouldn't have really worked at all.
Speaker 1: Now, uh, how'd you come up with flavor text on the fly?
Speaker 0: I had flavor text made up in advance for like three questions.
Speaker 0: Then it flew out of my mind and I never wrote it down because I was moron.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I think my mistake in running the video game match game and the reason it didn't go I mean it could have gone better given our circumstances.
Speaker 0: It also could have gone worse very very easily.
Speaker 0: But I think the reason it didn't go as well as it I mean it couldn't real given the circumstances.
Speaker 0: It could have gone better than it did but it couldn't have gone great.
Speaker 0: That was pretty much out of the realm of possibility.
Speaker 0: But I think it could have been better.
Speaker 0: and the one mistake I made was this When I came up with questions and I guess since I just sort of came up with them Naturally and not really thinking too hard about them because I was pressed for time Was that I came up with questions in wit or or things to match where my answer had some sort of agenda attached to it as Opposed to coming up with matches.
Speaker 0: That would be humorous or entertaining.
Speaker 1: There's a reason Scott why when I wrote the match game originally way back.
Speaker 1: I I spent days and days and days like thinking about what could match what the da?
Speaker 1: Could I coach the guests for this?
Speaker 1: Well people know that anime And I and today I've refined it and refined it and refined it and now I have a database that I'm working on of all The possible match game questions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I still think the problem is a lot of our match game questions.
Speaker 0: Don't have these sort of like, you know it blank in the middle of the sentence innuendo that the original TV match game head.
Speaker 1: Well at the same time you you have the instead the anime con innuendo, which yeah I mean, you know my favorite question to ask in any match game is always who is the sexiest man in anime because There's always the creepy answer.
Speaker 1: I mean Someone who shall not be named gave Oh Tori Akio as the answer to that question.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, that was bad.
Speaker 1: But also someone gave the answer Peter Fernandez.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is kind of true.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, yeah, I think that the key is if we ever do another video game match game I'm definitely I can come up with a lot of questions because I came up with a bunch in it.
Speaker 0: You're gonna write them down and none of them are gonna have agendas.
Speaker 0: they're all gonna be entertaining answers Like I thought of one today while I realized the mistake, you know, you could do something like, you know Which video game character you're most attracted to and my aunt?
Speaker 0: Well, my answer would have been either What would your answer be?
Speaker 0: I don't know what video game character you're most attracted to.
Speaker 0: Luigi I think it's a tie for me between a Goombella and Scott with the goombas and what's-her-name?
Speaker 0: who vomit?
Speaker 1: Right, I have a feeling.
Speaker 1: what'll happen is you'll read the game the questions that I'm going to generate from my database and give to You before the show.
Speaker 0: we'll see.
Speaker 1: Regardless while it was kind of mad and we're up there and the crowd was the crowd went with it But I forget what question it was, but Dave Riley was sitting next to me and he'd always like we'd show each other answers.
Speaker 1: So, uh One question came up and Dave didn't show me what his answer was.
Speaker 1: So I'm sitting there and you know I give my answer and goes to him and he kind of pauses for a minute and he holds his thing up and the crowd Looks at it and they're like, huh?
Speaker 1: And he says sick Semper and before you can say tyrannous my brain is thinking I've never heard of that.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute and right about that is when the clown pistol went off.
Speaker 0: I don't know where the hell Dave Riley a resident of now I guess New York got a clown pistol from.
Speaker 0: he must have bought it in Pennsylvania and drove it up with him or something.
Speaker 1: maybe the ninja consultants because I heard they had a stockpile.
Speaker 0: Oh, did they get a stockpile when they were down in the Atlanta or something?
Speaker 0: Cuz we knew that Daryl Surratt didn't have one because they're all primed us all.
Speaker 1: Friday and Saturday.
Speaker 1: He talked about how the clown pistol thing is dead.
Speaker 1: cuz you got to be subtle and no one can expect it.
Speaker 0: Well, everything he was saying was true.
Speaker 0: Is that?
Speaker 0: I think it anime we can Atlanta, right?
Speaker 0: I think the ninja consultants and some other people Attempted to clown pistol him and they did it in a non surprising and unsubtle way.
Speaker 0: Daryl basically said when I open this door something crazy is gonna happen.
Speaker 0: He opened it up and there was like a submachine.
Speaker 1: That's the brilliance.
Speaker 1: by telling that story to us and then referencing it again later He planted in our mind the the subtle unconscious idea that there's no danger of clown.
Speaker 0: No, that was his story did not in any way Change my expectation of clown pistol II at all.
Speaker 0: my expectation of clown pistol ing was at zero because I Thought that the only way a clown pistol could be transported to this to this Convention would be by Daryl Surratt who lives in Florida.
Speaker 0: were available Surratt and that the TSA would prevent him from actually Successfully transporting one of these things.
Speaker 1: see but I knew that there were stockpiles of clown pistols in the area.
Speaker 0: I did not know.
Speaker 0: I was under the assumption There's no way to get a clown pistol up here short of driving from Florida.
Speaker 1: However, Daryl very either ingeniously or by accident basically put me completely at ease.
Speaker 1: I was like a deer and I finally decided it was safe to drink and then 6-cent for Toronto's and Dave Riley shot me with a clown pistol in the face at the New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I Don't know what's gonna come of this clown pistol ing.
Speaker 0: I feel there has to be some sort of Grand finale of clown pistol ing at some point.
Speaker 0: But I'm not exactly sure how it can go down because it's it's you know Pete.
Speaker 0: now everyone is always looking out for it.
Speaker 0: I mean from now on I'm never going to assume that.
Speaker 0: pretty much I'm going to assume that if there is a convention and Either Dave Joel Daryl Gerald anyone any one of our anime podcast people is there even one of them?
Speaker 0: Even if it's me alone at the convention, I'm going to assume I have a clown pistol Myself.
Speaker 0: right that is how it's gonna be and I'm gonna be on the lookout for it at all times and I'm pretty much Locked in and impossible to surprise.
Speaker 0: So I'm really wondering how are we gonna top this?
Speaker 0: We got it.
Speaker 0: How's it gonna go down?
Speaker 0: and I have one idea, but I don't know how the idea will play out in the long run.
Speaker 0: It's going to be.
Speaker 0: it'll take such.
Speaker 0: it's such a high production value.
Speaker 0: I think it's in the realm of impossibility anyway.
Speaker 1: Other highlights from the con.
Speaker 1: I got to give some shout outs here because out of the blue like at the last second a non from Apple geeks and I'd open fallen and Conrad from c-squared Just decided hey, we're driving out to beacon and coming to the New York Anime Festival
Speaker 0: And that was good because without them there have been a much more boring.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: They just randomly came out.
Speaker 1: So we got to totally hang out with them.
Speaker 1: They spent time at our table chillin.
Speaker 1: We made fun of things.
Speaker 1: we forced someone to get their Portfolio reviewed by Tokyo pop and good times are had by all.
Speaker 0: it was quite the good times had by all.
Speaker 1: also We met a lot of our listeners at the con.
Speaker 1: I mean it was kind of surprising when he went our geek nights live podcast and First we asked how many people in the room know what a podcast is and everyone raises their hand just about.
Speaker 1: So then, you know I asked well, how many of you are geek nights listeners?
Speaker 1: and half the room raises their hand.
Speaker 0: Wow, yeah, it was pretty crazy stuff right there.
Speaker 0: But yeah that that was a weird panel that we just kind of rambled on for an hour and then we were done.
Speaker 1: I think it was really good.
Speaker 1: I mean the crowd loved it did they cuz?
Speaker 0: I wasn't really looking at them.
Speaker 0: I was sort of just looking around like I do when I'm podcasting.
Speaker 1: see I cuz.
Speaker 1: I guess I do the same thing.
Speaker 1: I always did an anime club where you know I watched the crowd and all I'm doing is just the body language is the crowd and they're like during the gecky a panel.
Speaker 0: I was all watching the crowd because I was in my panel mode But when I was doing that panel I was in my podcast mode.
Speaker 1: see we're all laid-back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was cool.
Speaker 1: Very different modes, but also Particularly among the people we hung out with because you were all awesome.
Speaker 1: I can say with pretty good certainty that to date I have not met in person a listener of our show who was creepy.
Speaker 1: You guys are all cool.
Speaker 1: I think part of what our show does is it turns away the creepy people, you know, but There's a bunch of people from the SUNY purchase anime club and the generally SUNY purchase people out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, check this story out, right?
Speaker 0: So the Corbin who's the the con chair of sitcom right which he invited us to?
Speaker 1: that was the first con that ever paid us To be guests, right?
Speaker 0: so he I think was on a bus back from Otacon or something like that and he meets this girl and She's apparently like the co-president of the SUNY purchase anime club.
Speaker 0: What a coincidence, you know two anime club presidents sitting next to each other.
Speaker 0: I'm like a greyhound leaving the biggest anime convention on the East Coast, right?
Speaker 0: And he starts telling her all about the geek nights and she starts listening to the geek nights And then she loves the geek nights and she's crazy about it.
Speaker 0: And then she tells all her SUNY purchase anime club friends about the night's and then it also just so happens The SUNY purchase anime club from what I can tell from what these people have said is an awesome anime club Reminiscent of the RIT anime club only smaller in number and They do.
Speaker 0: they want us to go there to like, you know run some events.
Speaker 0: I'm totally all about that plus the only thing I the only reason I'm not just doing it right away is time and such.
Speaker 1: Well, we should just go out there for like a weekend.
Speaker 0: I don't know what we'll do.
Speaker 0: We'll do something cuz.
Speaker 1: on one hand we have to work it out Yeah, but pretty much it seems like SUNY purchase has this very intense den of geekery much like RIT.
Speaker 1: So, uh, if you're looking for a geeky school and you can't afford to go to RIT or you just don't live near Rochester You can just be on the other end of New York.
Speaker 1: totally check out SUNY purchase because everyone we have met from that school so Far has been awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah And it sounds like they've got the comics and the video games and the board games the tabletop games and the anime and the whole Thing going on, but seriously, you guys are pretty damn cool.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We even invited them to our New Year's party.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: So let's see what what's going down to the convention that didn't involve us.
Speaker 0: All right, so I get there on Friday, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz it's.
Speaker 0: it's Friday Saturday Sunday and I'm hanging out before the con opens and I'm talking to the people's, you know, hey, what's up?
Speaker 0: What's up?
Speaker 0: I meet my Peter Rios and Charleto from I guess respectively the comic geek speak podcast.
Speaker 0: Yep indie spinner act podcast.
Speaker 1: when I told them that Finally finally after all this time.
Speaker 1: I read Frank Miller's Batman the Dark Knight Returns One of them shook my hands like about freaking time.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, so, you know, I'm talking to them.
Speaker 0: I'm showing them around cuz they're mostly comic guys You know and they came to this sort of like a one-day deal on a whim.
Speaker 0: So I'm showing them around.
Speaker 0: all the cool stuff like yeah this I told I explained the plot of DNA angel the Charleto and how it was.
Speaker 0: you know twin girls a and B and a dude who transforms into an evil art thief at night and He likes girl a but girl a likes the evil art thief He transforms into but the evil art thief Trent likes girl B who likes the kid before he transforms and he was like
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't explain to him Ranma.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't explain to them Ranma that would have been scary Yeah, but yeah, I showed them around, you know taught them about animes and stuff and about Kiyohiko Azumon whatever.
Speaker 0: and Then I'm talking to Luke our dealer friend because I always like my thing.
Speaker 0: now at conventions This right is like if you're a fan going to a convention, right?
Speaker 0: You only really see things from one angle, but when you go to a convention, especially a big thing like this There's so many perspectives and so many different experiences.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's the experience of the staff the experience of the volunteer the experience of the chair the experience of the fan The experience of the artists alley the dealer The professional like a TV guy running panels or promoting his company or whatever.
Speaker 0: this you know the the AV guys who run the panel rooms the the Teamsters and the janitors and the people work in the hotels and the people doing out the badges.
Speaker 0: There's so many different people at a convention who have a totally different experience.
Speaker 0: So I try to go around and talk to all these people to see what it's like for all of them.
Speaker 0: So the situate the dealer situation at this con basically was this First he was complaining to me that hey, there's no one at this con and I'm like the con didn't open.
Speaker 0: yet He's like, oh and then he's like, you know because of the labor union at this the convention center Which is true for every convention center in order for him to get his stuff into the convention center through the loading dock He would have had to pay these guys to haul it in and we had to pay by the
Speaker 1: pound.
Speaker 1: It would have cost twice as much as his dealer table.
Speaker 0: His dealer table booth cost seven hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: to have those guys haul it in would have cost him $1,500 for the hauling.
Speaker 1: now the best part is an unnamed friend of ours works with you know A bunch of other dealers at the con and they were like, yeah It's gonna cost you X dollars to get all this stuff in.
Speaker 1: So then he immediately turns the people he works for and says I'll do it for why and why was still a lot of money But it was a lot less than what they wanted from the Javits.
Speaker 1: Yep, so he made a whole bunch of money and all he had to do was get some friends with cars and haul some stuff To the Javits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't go in the loading dock, but you can pull stuff.
Speaker 0: You can go park across the street from the Javits and bring it in the front door.
Speaker 0: They can't.
Speaker 0: you know, that's the way those guys did it.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: I'm sure someone must have paid the delivery, you know pride people with more stuff, but whatever.
Speaker 0: So that was that's the dealer perspective.
Speaker 0: also, you know the con.
Speaker 0: I realized this, you know before the con I had all sorts of speculation about what was gonna go down and I knew that the con was gonna be different from Other cons because the situation but didn't know exactly how this is.
Speaker 0: how it was different Because the con was in New York City in the Javits in December when it's cold when people are in school, etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 0: And because New York is very expensive, especially during the holiday season.
Speaker 0: this is how it went down on Friday not so many people.
Speaker 0: on Saturday a crazy number of people and on Sunday not so many people.
Speaker 0: you see The reason for this is no one was gonna stay in the expensive hotels But because it was in New York in an incredibly central location with a lot of fans around and it was a big con with Lots of promotion and the world cosplay some and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: You did get a shit ton of Saturday only badges a shit ton and I think I heard numbers like 15,000 plus peoples But I know it's between 10,000 and 15,000. something is more accurate.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a lot of people and it was actually mighty crowded.
Speaker 0: Yep, especially on Saturday was mighty crowded.
Speaker 0: Friday and Sunday kind of crowded.
Speaker 0: the other thing with this con I noticed that I didn't realize until well into the convention is the con.
Speaker 0: hours were Friday 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: To like 5 7 p.m Saturday 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: To 7 p.m.
Speaker 0: And Sunday like 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: To 5 p.m.
Speaker 0: Now 5 p.m.
Speaker 0: Is usually later than most cons go on Sunday.
Speaker 0: Most cons end at like 3 p.m.
Speaker 0: Or 2 2 p.m.
Speaker 0: On Sunday, but this con was starting at 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: And ending at 7.
Speaker 0: I mean most cons are like at least anime cons like Friday crack ass of dawn till 2 a.m.
Speaker 0: Saturday crack ass of dawn till 2 a.m Well, the thing is I took on is 24/7 crack as a dawn because it's a hotel con I know totally different kind of con I know can't even compare them but I'm talking about like the hours were so short, right?
Speaker 0: That was another contributing factor to the one day passes rather than the you know, full weekend action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean the thing is it was run more like a trade show exhibition comic-con than it was a standard anime con.
Speaker 0: There was definitely I mean there was plenty for fans But there was definitely a lot more industry stuff there than there was at the usual.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about that a little bit because I have to say one thing.
Speaker 1: I Realize now the exact difference between a for-profit professional con and a fan-run con.
Speaker 1: the staff as in like.
Speaker 1: if I need some AV stuff or I'm gonna run a panel and I got to hook up my Marantz to the equipment or I got to record something or I have to do a PowerPoint or I need any sort of service or Support or I have a question.
Speaker 1: The staff were better than any convention.
Speaker 1: I've ever been to in my life.
Speaker 1: Good God if I needed anything.
Speaker 0: Well those AV people at least.
Speaker 1: well everyone else too.
Speaker 1: The only problem that in the entire con with the staff seemed to be that it was a little top-heavy and that the staff were Great, unless you needed a high-level decision to be made in which case there were there was a very small number of people who?
Speaker 1: Could make that decision.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, I'm not sure if the because those AV guys they were quality They kept talking to us every time we ran something always checking in being Like 10 minutes and 5 minutes before the panel ended and signaled 10 minutes left 5 minutes left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they hooked me up with everything I could have possibly asked for.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: that could just be that you know company or whichever.
Speaker 0: You know the the union of AV guys of the Javits are just high quality.
Speaker 0: I think you know cuz you know who can say that if you hired a different company to do some of the other cons We've been to that there would be just as helpful, you know, but everyone else too.
Speaker 1: I mean I went to get my badge and it was professional.
Speaker 1: everything worked it.
Speaker 1: it just worked so differently from a fan convention.
Speaker 1: I mean there was no Ambiguity about what was gonna happen when?
Speaker 0: well that there is one thing though.
Speaker 0: The only thing that I personally had a problem with was you know while the staff were super helpful I often had a hard time finding a staff member and also it seemed like at least for us We were sort of left to our own means a lot, you know, it's like we showed up at the con.
Speaker 0: I got my badge right and I don't know if we were supposed to have guest badges, but we got a professional badge Which I guess which was like solid gold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just as good.
Speaker 0: I guess I didn't really care but I saw people with guest badges and I'm like I'm supposed to be a guest.
Speaker 0: Where did you get that?
Speaker 0: But regardless?
Speaker 0: Like no one told us anything.
Speaker 0: like I went down and there was an artist alley table with our name on it.
Speaker 0: So I sat at it and there was no check-in.
Speaker 0: No one told us.
Speaker 0: Hey your panels at X your panels at Y. We just looked at the schedule.
Speaker 0: that again to our panels on our own.
Speaker 1: But then again, I have to say the con kind of self-organized and it just worked like everyone showed up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they found their artist alley table.
Speaker 0: It did self-organize but there was very there was.
Speaker 0: no it was like I didn't need direction from the staff But occasionally I was like looking for it, you know sort of like for a confirmation Like am I doing it right?
Speaker 0: and it wasn't there.
Speaker 1: I didn't even feel that.
Speaker 1: I just thought wow Everyone seems to know what they're doing.
Speaker 1: I didn't see any problems and while I didn't see staffers wandering around at the same time There was almost never a point where I thought there should be a staffer.
Speaker 1: I mean the crowd kept moving.
Speaker 1: there were never problems anywhere.
Speaker 1: You didn't?
Speaker 1: it's like if the con had happened with zero staff other than security at the front.
Speaker 1: I don't think anything would have been different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: it was very strange.
Speaker 0: I just everything seemed to sort of go on its own and like.
Speaker 0: I was looking for like Facilitators and they weren't there but it didn't really matter things.
Speaker 1: just I thought that was kind of cool.
Speaker 1: Also in terms of panels there was none of that BS rescheduling that happens at a lot of fan conventions.
Speaker 0: well, I heard that some things were canceled, but there was no rescheduling.
Speaker 0: at least we had four panels one Friday two Saturday one Sunday and Everything just kind of worked out.
Speaker 0: They were happened at the right times.
Speaker 0: Nothing rescheduled.
Speaker 0: Nothing canceled.
Speaker 0: Nothing got in the way.
Speaker 0: People got out of the room when we told them to whose it just kind of worked.
Speaker 0: Alright, what else are you guys saying?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean we had our artist alley table.
Speaker 1: That was fun.
Speaker 1: We met a lot of awesome people.
Speaker 1: I'm sure a lot of you're listening now, but one person in particular We met this young girl who was cosplaying as a perfect Yotsuba.
Speaker 0: Perfect as he can be it was perfect.
Speaker 1: now now not just cuz you know, she dressed up like yo.
Speaker 0: head was less around I think.
Speaker 1: well, yeah When I say a perfect Yotsuba, I mean she effectively was Yotsuba.
Speaker 1: She acted like Yotsuba.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I may be a little bit older than Yotsuba like Yotsuba when she's grown up and her dad Was one of those awesome geeky dads.
Speaker 1: and you know I'm asking her cuz she's really cute and she's showing us like.
Speaker 1: these are all the Sketches I've gotten from artists and you know, she's like.
Speaker 1: she really wants to show it to us.
Speaker 1: I'm flipping through it and she got some pretty high caliber artists to draw sketches for.
Speaker 0: I mean if your dad's taking these comic cons That's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's kind of hard to avoid.
Speaker 0: She's talking about the last San Diego comic-con She went to and they've been to every mocha talking about how she got her friends into Yotsuba and how her friends got her into something else.
Speaker 0: and It's like a little girl who's living the geek lifestyle starts admonishing her dad for being a closet geek.
Speaker 1: And then he's explaining to us cuz cuz you know, she has this tough dragon with her and it's also green.
Speaker 1: I think she likes green things and dragon things
Speaker 0: perhaps
Speaker 1: but you know She's really smart and really she's talking to us and I I had to talk down less to her that I've had to talk to Let's say a lot of people I've worked with in the course of my life.
Speaker 1: Oh but The coolest thing was that her dad was like, yeah, I'm trying to get her to Dungeons & Dragons and I'm halfway there.
Speaker 1: I just got to work on those dungeons.
Speaker 0: You gotta get some Bezum action going on.
Speaker 1: But then you go in enough kind of wander back over and we see them from a distance and We know that they have seen this cute girl dressed up as goats about because they stop and they're like, wow Oh my god, she's so cute.
Speaker 0: So I can't really just could not contain herself.
Speaker 0: So I point out to this girl and then I facilitated that inability to contain as much as I could sort of point out like You know overloading the containment unit if you will, you know, you've.
Speaker 1: you've got that great book of sketches.
Speaker 1: Well, there's two pretty famous artists right over there walking toward the table.
Speaker 1: It's now.
Speaker 1: they couldn't escape the spotlight and she ended up drawing a sketch of Yotsuba in her book and it was very high quality.
Speaker 0: Oh super high quality.
Speaker 1: The girl is even like you don't have to ink it.
Speaker 1: She's like, it's too late.
Speaker 1: I already started.
Speaker 0: Oh god What else cool happened at this convention.
Speaker 0: it was basically it wasn't some amazing life-changing convention.
Speaker 0: in all honesty I wish we would have gone just Saturday and not Friday or Sunday.
Speaker 1: Well part of that was just cuz I didn't know.
Speaker 1: if I had a hotel room in the city I would have been much happier staying the whole weekend.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: But since we didn't I would have been much happier doing just Saturday and I think most people Realized that and did Saturday only.
Speaker 0: and if this is a one-day con it might have been.
Speaker 0: it would have been a super amazing Double triple awesome con.
Speaker 0: but it was.
Speaker 0: it was just a normal con.
Speaker 0: Nothing incredibly bad happened.
Speaker 1: That was like I would say that the con was overall if you got every con is overall positive experience.
Speaker 1: I'd say it was above average even it was.
Speaker 1: it was like solid con.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean also I point out there were a lot of people there just from who we talked to and asking and it for those People.
Speaker 1: it was their first anime con ever and I guess totally just making up this number, but I would guess that a good Third to half of the people there.
Speaker 1: It was their first anime con.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, definitely I mean being in New York, you know being what it was Having a lot of marketing, you know outside outside of the internet.
Speaker 0: I know this is the kind of con that would attract a lot of people who had never been to a con before and It totally worked and there were plenty of people there just never been to a con.
Speaker 1: I mean if anything I would say that the only Problems the con had at all and I find this inter one There was no water.
Speaker 1: every fan con ever has pretty much infinite free water everywhere And they every panel room has a water cooler.
Speaker 0: There's water coolers just around as water coolers in all the special rooms.
Speaker 1: I was dying a thirst at this con.
Speaker 0: Yep, I had to keep going to the water fountain filling my Nalgene.
Speaker 0: I gotta bring my Nalgene back to work tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I keep forgetting but yeah, and the only other thing and it's not really a problem I just find it interesting, but I guess it's kind of obvious in the end, but no con feedback session panel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were a lot of things that are just sort of like staples.
Speaker 0: no dance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were things that are staples of the typical fan convention.
Speaker 0: that just didn't happen at this.
Speaker 0: Maybe you know.
Speaker 1: no dance because it ends at 7 p.m Granted I'll admit that I didn't miss the dance because Katsucon is the only con I've ever enjoyed.
Speaker 0: at least in the last several years I've enjoyed a con dance at yeah, but regardless, you know There were things that sort of be our default like you expect them to happen at a con.
Speaker 0: They didn't happen here and I don't know if that's just a result of it being you know An industry con pro con or what?
Speaker 0: It's it's hard to tell like what differences were because of what.
Speaker 0: or maybe they were just differences Because they felt like it or they didn't think about it or who knows No way to know because they're not that far on the inside of this thing.
Speaker 0: But that that's how it was and I guess it didn't.
Speaker 0: it's hard to tell how it would have affected it If it was different, but I guess didn't matter.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I think it was a success.
Speaker 1: I imagine they'll have it next year.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we'll find out, you know statistics and press stuff.
Speaker 1: I didn't bother to try and find it out ahead of time.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they'll just release a press release and we'll talk about it.
Speaker 1: But if it happens again, I can say that we'll definitely do shows there if they'll have us back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm definitely thinking we'll do a Saturday.
Speaker 0: only though Yeah if it happens at least the same time of year because I definitely think the time of year really contributed is I could do a Friday Saturday because Friday started out slow, but I really picked up by the end.
Speaker 0: I could do a Friday Saturday possibly.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is I couldn't do Sunday.
Speaker 1: That was just too much.
Speaker 0: yeah, the Sunday was I was wrecked and the only reason we went Sunday was because we had an event to do and Because well the thing is off sitting there that we had to get.
Speaker 1: very simply we gave Dave Riley shit all weekend about the fact That we never ran into him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: I check this out right here.
Speaker 0: We're gonna.
Speaker 0: we got to call them out Right.
Speaker 0: we freakin get free badges for Dave and Joel because they coming from far away and we want them to come to this Con because everyone's gonna be there, you know.
Speaker 1: and Daryl Surratt's coming from Florida What I think I talked to them to all of them combined total no more than three consecutive minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we can get free badges for people and they what they talked to us for like three minutes.
Speaker 0: They come to our table zero times, you know, we see him.
Speaker 0: We get him to come and help us with our you know video game match game, which was you know, okay?
Speaker 0: You know good for that.
Speaker 0: Well, like, you know, like we got we told them to.
Speaker 0: As soon as that game show is over poof disappears.
Speaker 0: where the hell he go.
Speaker 1: The ninja consultants are all awesome giving us golf manga which was fantastic to read the Kazuo Koike golf manga Recommended.
Speaker 0: all I can say is you know The the people that are training to be golf masters are using golf clubs and they're playing golf Against the champion shot putter who is shot putting the golf ball.
Speaker 0: But anyway, yes, that is not a joke.
Speaker 1: So we gave Dave Riley shit all weekend about the fact that he kept disappearing.
Speaker 1: So then Saturday, we're like Saturday ever like.
Speaker 1: alright Dave You have to be at the video game match game on Sunday for the love of God.
Speaker 1: and then we're home you know Saturday night for Sunday morning and we're saying wow want to just bail and we realized that the amount of shit we would Have gotten in return like it would have been like everything we had said was nullified and then reflected.
Speaker 0: Yep, so we show up and he shows up and there also shows up and then as soon as it's over they're gone.
Speaker 0: They go You know, it's like we can't.
Speaker 0: it's weird.
Speaker 0: It's like online.
Speaker 0: We can talk to these people a whole bunch and we're all friendly with them and having conversations.
Speaker 0: But then whenever we see him at a con, it's like we see him for like five minutes like at Otacon, right?
Speaker 0: We saw him was it Friday night when we were doing that panel?
Speaker 1: Well, see they're not the kind of people who got you know Show up to Otacon Thursday through Sunday and then go on vacation.
Speaker 0: They show up like Friday night and leave like Sunday morning I know but it's like they can't even like we didn't even see them after that.
Speaker 0: They were there Saturday and we just didn't see them.
Speaker 0: They don't I don't know what the hell are they just hiding in somewhere secret that we don't know about.
Speaker 0: That's like the secret.
Speaker 0: I mean Dave and Joel anime convention hiding spot.
Speaker 1: I think they just have a short attention span and they can't sit still.
Speaker 0: it might be Apparently they they cuz their latest podcast or two.
Speaker 0: It was recorded like at the ATV booth with their you know, ATV friend there You know and that was on Saturday apparently, but I didn't see them behind the ATV booth Saturday.
Speaker 0: Was that just like when I was sitting at my table not paying attention like what was going on there?
Speaker 1: Well, you said at the table not paying attention for most of the time I did sit at the ball.
Speaker 0: that you know, there wasn't really that much to do.
Speaker 0: You know at least for me as a con.
Speaker 0: goer, you know Cuz I guess if you're it was your first time anime con.
Speaker 0: there was plenty for you to do there.
Speaker 0: But for me, you know, what was I gonna do there?
Speaker 0: I was not really interested in any of the events so much.
Speaker 0: I had already perused the entire room of dealers and artists alleys and everything like and we walked around the artist alley and all that.
Speaker 1: But other than that, I think that's it.
Speaker 1: I spent most of the con just kind of chilling with all our new friends and a bunch of our listeners and people from the Forums.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that frame for us.
Speaker 0: That was what there was to do there.
Speaker 0: run our events Talk to people try to talk to as many people as I could.
Speaker 0: they were cool artists sitting next to us.
Speaker 0: I made friends with people like the people at the vertical booth and such.
Speaker 0: and Was that?
Speaker 0: so yeah, New York anime festival Recommended at least to go one day at least in the future if it happens again.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.