Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, June 12th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we review the crazy war game Twilight struggle.
Speaker 0: Let's do this man, you know we've talked about this before but we were in Rochester over the weekend for a wedding which was awesome, but Millennium games in Rochester is still far and away the best gaming store I've ever seen or heard of in my entire life.
Speaker 1: is it technically in Henrietta?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's in Henrietta.
Speaker 0: I guess but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It doesn't it's Rochester.
Speaker 1: It's it's suburb of Rochester.
Speaker 1: is Rochester?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like anime central was actually in Rosemont, but it's in Chicago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and penguin Khan is in Detroit even though it's in no.
Speaker 0: well No penguin Khan advertised itself as no vi.
Speaker 0: no vi is pretty separate from Detroit.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it counts as Detroit.
Speaker 1: Anyway, not really point is.
Speaker 1: millennium is an awesome story.
Speaker 1: Millennium games and hobbies is a store that it only sells games.
Speaker 1: I'm like a lot of other gaming stores which tend to be general nerdiness stores, you know They sell, you know all sorts of nerdy stuff including, you know, baseball cards comic books, you know toys.
Speaker 1: millennium sells board games RPGs miniatures games and CCG's.
Speaker 0: well They used to have back in the day a small Modeling and rocket section that looks like it disappeared.
Speaker 1: Yeah that pretty much disappeared.
Speaker 1: now They still have like, you know the paints and that sort of stuff for miniatures, but not so much the modeling action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, millennium is just the awesomest store.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I guess I went to that Complete strategist in New York City and they might have had a slightly better selection of the board games You know just because it was stacked from floor to ceiling with multiple copies of everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they also had a lot of the old stuff.
Speaker 0: I guess Yeah compared to what pretty much any gaming store has.
Speaker 1: but millennium is just a better store in every way Mostly because it has room to walk around and look at things.
Speaker 0: plus it is Incredibly rare that I've ever walked into a millennium game Well the millennium games and not seen at least the game I wanted or if not the actual game.
Speaker 0: I wanted another game worth buying.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, I just I went into that store and since I'd been out of that store for so long I was.
Speaker 1: it was like just like goddamn and I wanted to buy like six or seven games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, make up my mind.
Speaker 0: So in the end, you know I was gonna buy one game and Scott had this one game and I got I guess he's the owner.
Speaker 0: now I don't know what the guy's not the owner.
Speaker 1: He's probably just like the you know, one of the managers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's deaf because I see him there every time I go and this time Yeah I guess he recognized that we kind of brought this whole crew in with us and he ends up offering us the discount.
Speaker 0: Yep Which meant we just bought a bunch more games and then he happened to have La Cita's that we've been looking for forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's like.
Speaker 1: he's like, yeah Like we were.
Speaker 1: just we were about to check out and he's like, yeah If there's any out of print games you want and I'm like, oh I remember an out of print game I want La Cita and he's like, you know, I got one in the back.
Speaker 1: I got one in the back We opened it we were gonna play it, but we didn't play it.
Speaker 1: So this is opened but effectively new.
Speaker 0: So then he's like so, uh, how much should I sell it to you for?
Speaker 0: and we're like, uh, I don't know We only see it on eBay.
Speaker 0: So he looked on eBay and he saw that the going price was like $90.
Speaker 0: so he offered us 45 bucks for it and I was opened and it's not gonna.
Speaker 1: it's only $90 because it's Currently out of print and it's gonna be in print again soon.
Speaker 1: So the $90 price is going to evaporate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, we'll see when soon is - yeah, I heard it's gonna be pretty soon, but who knows with these things We'll see doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: from what I know about La Cita It's good.
Speaker 1: It's an awesome game, but I can't say that yet until I've played it even better.
Speaker 0: He started to realize cuz he's going around the store showing us like oh this game's good.
Speaker 0: This game's good and every game He said.
Speaker 0: our response was own it played it done with it or it sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah And eventually started realizing what our tastes were.
Speaker 0: So finally we you know, we asked him about one game.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: that game will probably give you about 12 plays before you figure it out.
Speaker 0: That game will probably give you about one play before you figure it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, what do we buy?
Speaker 1: We bought La Cita.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we bought.
Speaker 1: We bought the the goth game which we talked about in our gaming for hope episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm really looking forward to playing that.
Speaker 1: give a full review of that.
Speaker 0: Once we solve it Scott got a jumbo.
Speaker 1: I got jumbo jumbo jumbo.
Speaker 1: I think like one of the only two player games in the world.
Speaker 1: That's gonna be good.
Speaker 1: and I also got power grid which is a very very popular game and after reading the rules I can see why it is a very good game, but it is also not a game without its problems
Speaker 0: like most games
Speaker 1: yes,
Speaker 0: and Scott got a little expansion that might make battle or slightly less painful and stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got it's basically another board for battle or so that you can double the size of the game.
Speaker 1: I think that might help a lot.
Speaker 0: I think it'll help a lot because now there's room to maneuver other than Because the strategy in battle or that works best is pretty much line your guys up defensively and wait.
Speaker 0: The other guy is either going to be forced to attack you and your strong position or also wait And then it's just a question of who has the most patience.
Speaker 1: Well, you can just you can what you can do.
Speaker 1: if you instead of waiting you can just keep manipulating your guys and rearranging them Until you're in an advantageous attack position, you know, oh Anyway, Oh Alex got tempest which is a game that I had seen and known about but I don't remember playing.
Speaker 0: He is convinced that one of us played it with him, but I don't remember playing it.
Speaker 1: I think I was playing another game while he played it.
Speaker 0: I have definitely never played it and I'm pretty sure you and him did when I was out of town for something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I recognize what the game looks like and I remember maybe being told the rules But I don't remember any of the rules.
Speaker 0: Maybe this is like that time when for a long time It's not just Scott but much of the crew were Absolutely convinced that I had seen some of the second matrix movie with them.
Speaker 1: You still haven't seen it.
Speaker 0: Not only have I not seen the movie miss the 10-minute rave orgy at all But I think the reason people thought I'd seen it is that I could still make jokes about the rave orgy because I don't know I read the internet.
Speaker 0: So I knew all about it and I knew not to see the movie.
Speaker 1: and It's just sort of like for me going to see movies at the Tinseltown and Rochester just you know all through college.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you idiots all went to see the Dungeons & Dragons movie and I was the only one who said you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna pass.
Speaker 1: I'm not going while that movie was ass.
Speaker 1: I think that was a worthwhile experience.
Speaker 0: I just remember when you guys came back and I was like, so, uh, how was the movie?
Speaker 1: and Pete said it was ass It was terrible.
Speaker 0: I was like, so you guys drove a half hour.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a half hour.
Speaker 0: It takes at least 20 minutes to get there.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, I forget how to get there.
Speaker 0: now I remember I remember the back way go all the way around the left of the airport.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember that part but I don't remember like the ending bit.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the ending bit you see it's like a shining Miles into the distance because there's nothing else there.
Speaker 0: It's literally like you take the highways through the open wilderness around an airport and there's no lights or anything.
Speaker 0: And then in the distance, there's the shining beacon and it's the only lit up thing.
Speaker 0: It's just this big movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if we had a tinsel town, I'd probably go to the movies still but because all our movie theaters suck I'm not going.
Speaker 1: well, we have some good movie theaters, but they're down in Manhattan Yep, and I'm not going because I need to get home and do this show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well anytime I'm there on a weekend, I tend to just if there's a good movie.
Speaker 0: I'll go see it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we saw paprika down there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was movie worth seeing right?
Speaker 0: So in the news the Smash Brothers game coming out on the Wii because we need a new game for the Wii.
Speaker 0: the best game on the Wii right now Is crap.
Speaker 0: I haven't even played any games in a while.
Speaker 1: I haven't used the Wii in probably over a month at all.
Speaker 1: I mean like maybe I'll beat that Super Paper Mario this week or the next week, but I Joke, I haven't really been playing video games at all.
Speaker 1: I even stopped playing Pokemons for like since I turned it on the other day because you know Everyone was at the dim sum had Pokemon But I turned it on and the last journal entry was May 22nd.
Speaker 1: Wow That's the last time I actually really played the Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Actually, I was playing some Phoenix right on the train and I can now beat bionic commando in like 24 minutes without dying.
Speaker 0: you should go for the world record might be a little more than that, but Under a half hour I can beat the game.
Speaker 0: It's kind of scary because I play that game more than I play.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: that's the best game on the Wii.
Speaker 0: right now It's not on the way because my I can't do the joke.
Speaker 0: the last time I made the joke I said Soulcalibur 2 because that was the thing I played on the Wii the most and that's still the thing I played on the Wii the most.
Speaker 1: in fact I think that everybody votes channel is still the best game by the way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I haven't even played that in a while.
Speaker 0: I I I guess two or three weeks ago I looked and there are like ten new things.
Speaker 0: I hadn't voted on any of them.
Speaker 0: And yeah, I just gave up.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it to boot the Wii in the time It takes to boot the Wii.
Speaker 0: the Mac is already booted and I'm already watching someone get hit in the nuts on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yep So what's your news?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, this game's coming out, you know a game for the Wii and a lot of people have been wondering How it is going to be controlled because the Wii has you know, the innovative controller with the motion sensing but also as the classic controller, it also has the GameCube.
Speaker 0: you can just plug a GameCube controller in.
Speaker 0: and A lot of people really wondered how was this game gonna use the Wii stuff.
Speaker 0: was the game gonna be GameCube classic?
Speaker 0: because when they first announced the game before Wii's even existed before anyone even seen a Wii People were debating and there was a rumor that the Smash Brothers game on the Wii was just gonna use the GameCube controller And that the GameCube controller was going to be like the standard controller for any game on the Wii that didn't use the special stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well Smash Brothers is one of those games where if they've changed like you think huh?
Speaker 1: Well, how could you make a Smash Brothers game using the Wiimote intuitively?
Speaker 1: Well, if you kept with the current Smash Brothers idiom, you know of a side view Platforming fighting knock the other guy off the edge game the Wiimote It's like you.
Speaker 1: just you could use some gestures for some of the moves But that's really it.
Speaker 1: you would have to change the game into some sort of Maybe first person or third quarter kind of you know still knock the guy off the edge fighting game But it wouldn't be like the previous Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: I mean I can picture ways of controlling a game like Smash Brothers with the Wiimote straight up And I think it could be interesting But it really wouldn't be Smash Brothers anymore, and I think a lot of people would just I mean look They.
Speaker 0: if they did something weird like that it'd be the same thing that happened with Wario.
Speaker 0: people freaking loved WarioWare for the GameCube because it was just amazing multiplayer awesome and When they put it on the Wii they tried to use the Wii stuff And they didn't seem to understand what made WarioWare good and popular and as a result They made it really shit game.
Speaker 0: if they did that with Smash Brothers people would try to play it go What the hell is this and they'd go back to playing the original Smash Brothers?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well it seems that they definitely.
Speaker 1: This the new Smash Brothers brawl is if you look at all these screenshots And there are some is still the same old side view.
Speaker 1: you know Platforming fighting knock the guy off the edge game.
Speaker 0: and as far as the internet as reported there are four Possible control schemes all of which should theoretically be equal.
Speaker 0: you can either hold your Wiimote sideways Hold the Wiimote up with the little nunchuck use the classic controller or use the GameCube controller.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is I'm wondering what are people gonna do in tournaments?
Speaker 1: because Even if the like the Wiimote nunchuck method is you know a good method?
Speaker 1: It's not moving the Wiimote around with the motion sensor.
Speaker 0: I don't know how you move.
Speaker 1: well I know I'm not saying not how you move But you know moving the Wiimote physically with your hand to control anything is Not as precise as pushing a button and in a game like Smash Brothers Winning is all about having lots of precision.
Speaker 1: you want to have the exact right move at the exact nanosecond You know.
Speaker 1: so having very precise moves and timing with the sort of you know loose imprecise control of this motion sensing Wiimote won't You're gonna.
Speaker 1: I think you're gonna be at a disadvantage.
Speaker 0: Well you see this is where I'm thinking.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 0: even if you use the setup where you hold the nunchuck in the Wiimote I don't think the motion sensing is gonna be a part of it.
Speaker 0: or if it is it's gonna be incredibly minor like just activate shield if it's moving or something because My bet is that they just want it that way because you can use all the buttons on your one hand to make attacks And then use the other buttons and the control stick in the other hand to move.
Speaker 1: Oh, we'll see.
Speaker 0: I really don't think the motion sensing will be used in any mode except possibly the just holding it sideways because in that mode There's not enough buttons as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: I think they're definitely Gonna use it in some way And I definitely think most people are just gonna use the GameCube controller at least hardcore people are gonna use the GameCube controller So that they can have the the precision that they desire.
Speaker 0: also the heavy rumble.
Speaker 1: yes the rumble.
Speaker 1: I hope it better rumble.
Speaker 0: get the GameCube controller to this day just has the best rumble of any controller I've ever used.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's rumble isn't me.
Speaker 0: I mean ever the PlayStation DualShock.
Speaker 0: It's like buzz.
Speaker 0: Buzz.
Speaker 0: it was always kind of the same buzz But yet the GameCube was just.
Speaker 0: it had such control that a lot of games like you're idling your engine and the controller.
Speaker 0: We're just kind of idle a little bit.
Speaker 0: Just this very subtle, but that might also just been the way the developers chose to use rumble.
Speaker 1: Yeah I have no idea, but I'm also I don't know how well the Xbox 360 controller rumbles.
Speaker 0: cuz I don't know.
Speaker 1: If it doesn't rumble.
Speaker 1: people would have said something.
Speaker 1: it definitely rumble.
Speaker 0: Maybe they did.
Speaker 0: we don't really pay attention even though if I had free time.
Speaker 1: I don't an Xbox 360 already yeah, but All right, so Smash Brothers brawl gonna have multiple control screams.
Speaker 1: who knows which one will win out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all this really says to me is Nintendo has given up one more opportunity to fuck this up.
Speaker 0: Yep, there aren't many opportunities left.
Speaker 1: See yesterday.
Speaker 1: I talked about Safari being for Windows which was announced at the worldwide apples worldwide developer conference.
Speaker 1: I Couldn't really express how little I cared say yes me either But something else was announced at the worldwide developer conference.
Speaker 1: ooh John Carmack was there.
Speaker 0: I don't know how I feel about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Remember he showed off doom 3 on the Mac at a similar thing many moons ago like when the geforce 3 came out.
Speaker 1: Yes, doom 3 geforce 3 and doom 3 were both shown for the first time at the same time on a Mac at I think a worldwide developers conference though.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure by John Carmack.
Speaker 0: so yeah, well I'm glad doom 3 was such a great game.
Speaker 1: I was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it was so much.
Speaker 1: the world would be totally different without doom 3 so much better than you know.
Speaker 0: those other doom Games that I guess some people said might have been a little revolutionary in terms of yeah In those half-life games which completely dominated all FPS is forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah now I mean I really wanted to stumble around in the dark with a flashlight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well anyway John Carmack showed off his new technology, which is called id tech 5. basically They've been making an engine in secret, and he showed off like something They threw together in like 10 days on this new engine, and it looked pretty good.
Speaker 1: basically the thing that he's promoting about this new game engine is that You no longer have the problem of you know All that without I guess having bajillions and gigabytes of memory Specific.
Speaker 0: does it not use textures?
Speaker 0: does it store textures different.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Okay, just give a little marketing bit.
Speaker 1: but anyway The thing that he's really going after is that our people who are creating content like levels and maps and models and things Can change things on the pixel level with great ease.
Speaker 1: so in theory with this new engine of his artists will be able to make Incredibly awesome game content with greater ease than ever before.
Speaker 0: If that is actually true I'm kind of excited because I got to say I used to fiddle around a lot with doom and I made a lot of doom Levels and do modifications and all sorts of like weapon packs and whatever just for fun.
Speaker 0: And I mean I really enjoyed it, and it wasn't that hard and obviously I was limited by the doom engine Which wasn't really the greatest most stellar thing out there?
Speaker 0: But it was very easy to understand it and to manipulate it to the fullest that it could be used.
Speaker 0: I Decided when you know half-life and quake and all those things were coming out that I wanted to continue my hobby and I realized that my hobby had become exponentially more difficult and Tedious and terrible and I gave up and I never bothered making levels for anything ever again.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's like if I've AutoCAD or like even 3d studio max or any of those kinds of programs.
Speaker 1: I actually kind of know how to use those and while I'm not the greatest at 3d art I can actually make or blender.
Speaker 1: even I can make 3d models of things with the relative ease.
Speaker 1: You know I don't make something that looks really pretty But I can make something.
Speaker 1: the programs that you use to make say half-life levels God awful nightmarishly difficult to use nightmare difficult yes for Absolutely no reason.
Speaker 1: why can't I just use AutoCAD to make a half-life 2 level it could make?
Speaker 1: I could make one in like a day Just cuz.
Speaker 1: AutoCAD is actually easy to use once you learn how the hell it works.
Speaker 0: Well the main reason is like in half-life 1 at least how maps are actually constructed.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna talk about it, but So you make a thing that converts a sensible reasonable 3d model created by a human being Into your whacked-up crazy level format, that's not I wasn't.
Speaker 0: that's not so trivial or so easy Especially back then when computers were slow.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: But regardless it sucks to make levels and things for game.
Speaker 0: also the fact that much of it is scripting and not actually Designing the 3d part yeah, and John Carmack thinks he's gonna solve that with his new engine which looks pretty good.
Speaker 0: Well John Carmack tends to oscillate between genius and idiot, so I'm not sure which side of the scale is on right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this engine is gonna be on the PC the 360 the ps3 and I guess the Mac also.
Speaker 1: Why isn't it on the Wii?
Speaker 1: Cry cuz the.
Speaker 0: we can't do it, but man as much as I love Nintendo I feel like Dave and Joel here just ragging on the Wii at every opportunity.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna keep ragging on it until it has a game which I know well one day.
Speaker 1: But we're gonna have to wait like six to twelve months Yeah, and then we will be like oh alright now the Wii is on the DS level.
Speaker 1: It's just a matter of time.
Speaker 1: I'm not you know too worried about.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean I guess the only reason the DS didn't feel that way to me when I had it is that I never actually Played Mario 64. so I ended up playing Mario 64 and by the time I beat Mario 64 Wii games came out.
Speaker 0: or God not.
Speaker 0: Wii games DS games yep.
Speaker 0: But I'm not that bad.
Speaker 1: and the only thing that I'm weirded out about about this engine here Right is that pretty much any time anyone's ever made a game engine like.
Speaker 1: I've read multiple interviews of the game engine makers And they say that when they make a new game engine they always Simultaneously make a game because how else would you know how good the engine is if you weren't trying to make a game on it?
Speaker 1: And when the act of making the game for the engine Whether it's a good game or not the act of doing that you know reveals all the problems in your engine as you go through and actually try to make a game on it.
Speaker 1: and Is Carmack making a game on this or not?
Speaker 1: He didn't say he was.
Speaker 0: maybe he's making not really a game But just a test case internally to test the engine?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean it's not like unless you make a full game You're not really gonna get the full effect, but at the same time.
Speaker 0: I mean depending on your development cycle I wonder how important that is in the grand scheme compared to spending the money to make a game considering how well doom 3 did.
Speaker 0: Yes, yet the doom 3 engine was fairly robust, but who's using the doom 3 engine?
Speaker 1: how many people bought it?
Speaker 0: a lot of people?
Speaker 0: Said they were going to and I don't know what came of that.
Speaker 1: yeah See that's.
Speaker 1: the other thing is that in let if your game you need a game to come out on the engine that blows everyone away so that Gamers will buy that game because you need in order to sell mods for a game you have to get gamers to buy the original game in the first place.
Speaker 1: and even if your engine is the most amazing and easiest to create mods and content for in the whole world if Gamers don't have the engine on their computers They're not gonna go out and buy Your game just to get the mod.
Speaker 1: You know it's like the game that had the game first and then once they have the game.
Speaker 1: then they'll get all sorts of mods for it and right now half-life 2 and steam is the winner and They're gonna have to come out with some pretty fucking badass game for this engine or to push it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess we just don't know enough information So there's not really much we can say.
Speaker 1: no I can say though one small bit is.
Speaker 1: I heard a rumor Which is probably true that Capcom is gonna be putting stuff out on Steam.
Speaker 1: That's the high quality things of the day.
Speaker 0: So in the trend of having friends give us things the day because otherwise we just do whatever is on the top of dig Our dear friend I do showed me this a while ago, and it's finally a Tuesday where I can talk about it.
Speaker 0: Monkeys at least bonobos, which are some of my favorite kinds of monkeys are Smarter than a lot of people seem to give them credit for.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I knew they were smart one of the smartest types.
Speaker 0: well Would you have expected that they'd be smart enough to be pretty good at miss pac-man?
Speaker 1: you just got to move a sticker ad they?
Speaker 1: Could definitely do that.
Speaker 1: they move their banana and their own sticks around plenty.
Speaker 0: But at the same time would you think they'd be smart enough to not only play miss pac-man reasonably well But to figure out to avoid the ghosts and then to figure out that the power pellets turn the ghost blue And then to figure out that you can eat the blue ghost, but not the non blue ghost.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, I mean if you have any sort of cognition You could definitely tell right away that your stick is controlling the pac-man and then from there the other stuff sort of follows.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty intuitive game and the colors are very Contrasting so you don't need like ultra awesome vision to sort of figure it out.
Speaker 1: I mean at the same time did they figure out like how to get higher score?
Speaker 1: And you know like did they wait for all the ghosts and then eat them all?
Speaker 1: or Are they you know trying to eat all the pellets?
Speaker 1: are they using the warps on the left and the right?
Speaker 0: Strategically that um I don't.
Speaker 0: I think the point is more that a non-human is able to figure out the generic general endgame or goal of a video game.
Speaker 1: You know most humans can barely even play pac-man.
Speaker 0: that well, so well actually it wasn't.
Speaker 0: pac-man is miss pac-man.
Speaker 0: I much prefer it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do as well, but I must say these bonobos You it's.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's fair to say they play pac-man as well as a human.
Speaker 1: I think they play pac-man better than most humans.
Speaker 1: most humans can't play pac-man for crap.
Speaker 1: They just they don't know what the hell to do.
Speaker 1: I just watch the video.
Speaker 0: It's really interesting to watch this monkey.
Speaker 0: Get really into this game and get very frustrated when he gets eaten.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: it's pretty frustrating when you get eaten.
Speaker 1: Pac-man says no, I got pac-man's especially the first pac-man.
Speaker 1: I hate it when I get eaten than at the most man I still have a burning desire.
Speaker 0: That's the best game on the Wii.
Speaker 0: I really think yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: So rim knows from trying to eat lot He's trying.
Speaker 1: there was a time when rim was trying to eat many proteins like more.
Speaker 0: I'm still trying to.
Speaker 0: I forced myself to eat protein constantly more protein than I would otherwise want to eat and One way to do this to eat those nasty protein bars.
Speaker 0: Yes For some reason some reason any thing that ever claims to be a protein supplement that isn't just meat in and of itself or possibly Nuts tastes like the inside of an asshole.
Speaker 1: Protein is not tasty.
Speaker 1: only fat and sugar are tasty.
Speaker 0: protein is tasty.
Speaker 0: Well meat is tasty and meat has a lot of protein in it.
Speaker 1: Yes, but for me Meat is not tasty because of the protein.
Speaker 1: meat is tasty because of the but.
Speaker 0: yet the meat does not taste like ass.
Speaker 0: Well, the meat the protein bar tastes like ass.
Speaker 0: Why can't I have a meat candy bar?
Speaker 0: I know you're gonna say jerky, but I can't eat that much jerky in one day or I start to feel a little ill.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, and I learned this when I ate a bunch of jerky that I found a few days ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also rim and other people tend to really be like in the Red Bull these days.
Speaker 1: you like the Red Bull.
Speaker 1: Uh, I drink about one Red Bull a day on average Too many but my boss also drinks a Red Bull a day, uh, you know or more it's almost.
Speaker 0: it's kind of bad because Red Bull does have a very noticeable effect on my alertness and awakeness and ability to concentrate and all those things.
Speaker 0: and I Get that like I start feeling like if I'm playing counter-strike that I should drink a Red Bull right before.
Speaker 1: Well funny you should say that because this company here has come out with a new product called Headshot as in the gamer energy bar Huh?
Speaker 1: It is a candy bar called headshot with a picture of a sniper crosshair on it and It is a guarana infused energy bar.
Speaker 1: It's a candy bar, but it's got the Red Bull stuff in it.
Speaker 0: Well, which red does it have?
Speaker 0: glucose in it?
Speaker 1: I don't know as opposed to full ingredients, but it has guarana.
Speaker 0: That's that's just kind of like caffeine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Suppose they say it tastes good.
Speaker 0: Well, I point out that the guy who invented that cocaine drink also said that it tasted good.
Speaker 1: That is why I'm saying they said it.
Speaker 0: However, I also point out that when that guy was on TV, I might have been on The Daily Show or something I remember and he goes to like he drinks his own drink.
Speaker 0: He winches a little bit.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, so if Anyone out there goes like a LAN party or some sort of game center and you see the headshot candy energy bar Try one out and tell us how it goes.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm interested But at the same time I'd rather just drink a Red Bull that need any sort of energy bar because I don't trust that at All.
Speaker 1: yeah, but this might be good because if we start heavy, you know It seems like every energy thing is always a beverage like this big action going on in the beverages and there's not so much action Going on in the food, you know what?
Speaker 0: I bet the main reason is it is very easy to mix a Red Bull with vodka.
Speaker 0: It is not so easy to make an energy bar with vodka.
Speaker 1: You just put whipped cream on it.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be good.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's the end of things of the day, all right.
Speaker 0: So we're kind of probably be a little bit brief about this just because we haven't played the game a lot.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I don't see us playing it much anytime soon And I really want to at least talk about our experiences thus far before we forget.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So Last time I was in Rochester of many moons ago.
Speaker 0: I picked up Twilight Struggle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically, this is a game.
Speaker 1: That is a two-player Cold War war Strategy simulation game and I had seen the old guys at Moz play it a lot and it was like one of their most favorite Games.
Speaker 1: and it was you know the sort of game that a crazy old war gamer would like.
Speaker 1: I could tell from looking at it.
Speaker 1: But because it was the sort of game a crazy old war gamer would like I was sort of turned off to it But it began over time.
Speaker 1: I sort of warmed up to it thinking.
Speaker 1: Hey, maybe that is the two-player game.
Speaker 1: That's actually good because we really need to play our game.
Speaker 0: Well when I was in Rochester, I happen to see it there and I've been 50/50 on buying it if I ever saw it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, so I see it and I think from the side of thing.
Speaker 0: All right Time to make this 50/50 arbitrary decision as to whether or not I'm going to spend $65.
Speaker 0: what the?
Speaker 1: It is an expensive game.
Speaker 0: It cost the same as Zelda 2 when it came out.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's actually.
Speaker 0: I think I paid 70 for Zelda 2 so it's not that bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these I've noticed that the war games and the sort of serious historical games cost a lot more money like German games cost like 40 bucks and Like American games cost like 10 bucks, but the super war games that always cost a lot of money.
Speaker 1: They're super expensive mostly because they come with big maps and all sorts of like Detailed text and giant rule books with lots of words and lots of cards and lots of bits and you know stuff that we're a German Game, you know, it comes with a lot of wooden cubes but they're just colored cubes and this comes with like Little chits with text on them and different text on each and every one and that's kind of complicated printing going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but so then I pull the box out and I see the cover art and the cover art is really nice.
Speaker 0: I really like the cover art to this game.
Speaker 1: It is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I don't think they could have had better art at all It's just it's perfect.
Speaker 0: It is definitely a gestalt of what this game is.
Speaker 0: So pretty much that sold me on it and I bought it.
Speaker 1: it's also rated very highly on board game geek.
Speaker 1: It's eight point three out of ten, which on board game geek is huge.
Speaker 1: That's like people.
Speaker 1: that means that people love this game Yep.
Speaker 0: Now, uh, I like the game quite a bit more than Scott and Alex do.
Speaker 1: yeah But I think Alex actually likes it a little bit less than me.
Speaker 1: Like I don't like the game so much as a game but sort of at playing.
Speaker 1: it is fun for a while.
Speaker 0: The continuum is I'm slightly positive on it.
Speaker 0: Scott is neutral and Alex is slightly sour on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I don't think he's gonna sweeten.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's gonna sweeten either.
Speaker 0: now the game is ostensibly a simulation of the Cold War given the idea that all of the ideologies and all of the theories and all of the political ideas from the Cold War are actually true meaning Domino theory is real and the world really did work that way.
Speaker 0: all that stuff Yeah.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of like taking the Cold War at face value Being in that time period believing these things to be true.
Speaker 0: It tries to simulate not so much the historical reality of the Cold War but the kinds of decision-making and the kinds of Feelings and the tension and the brinksmanship of the Cold War and it also tries to be an asymmetric Good two-player game and I'm not sure if it succeeded.
Speaker 0: I really am not sure how I feel about this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically the way the game works is.
Speaker 1: you have these cards and there's you know, three part.
Speaker 1: There's the early cards which are sort of the cards that represent events that happened early in the Cold War the middle cards that represent events that happened in middle of the Cold War and the late cards that happen represent events that happen late in the Cold War and You deal out these cards to both players and some cards are for the Soviets and some cards are for the US and some cards Are for both and every card is a number on it and every card also has a historical event.
Speaker 1: now Basically, you might get the other guys card.
Speaker 1: So if I'm the US I might have a fistful of Russia cards.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: The second game of this I play.
Speaker 0: Well, like yeah the third game whatever the one game I played with Alex I drew all Russia cards and you were the US and Alex drew all Russia cards.
Speaker 0: not so good for the US and it was awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah So but on your turn what you do is you take a certain number of at.
Speaker 1: you take turns playing cards and when you play A card you can either play it for the event that's on it or you can play it to just.
Speaker 1: you know Do stuff on the board based on the numbers.
Speaker 1: So it has a number like four.
Speaker 1: you can do four things on the move guys around the boards.
Speaker 0: yeah, the cards are numbered one through four and Generally the higher the number the better the event.
Speaker 0: So it's definitely a trade-off and the number is just how much you get to influence the board.
Speaker 0: We're not really gonna talk about the details this game.
Speaker 0: Yes It's really complicated.
Speaker 1: basically want to move numbers around the board to take over more countries in different areas Like aha, I have the majority of the spots in Europe.
Speaker 1: That's more points for me and aha I have more places in.
Speaker 0: you know Asia kind of conquered and you're just increasing influence and on different countries and things Yeah, and inciting coups in places and bringing DEFCON down engaging in military actions and all sorts of stuff all sorts of cold war stuff.
Speaker 1: But basically what you're doing is you're playing cards either to make historical events happen which the what happens is written on the card or To just do standard moves and let.
Speaker 1: I can even use the other guys cards.
Speaker 1: Of course, you're gonna have to.
Speaker 1: you know If you draw Soviet cars near the US you would play say a Soviet card and I would use the number two to do two.
Speaker 1: But because I played the Soviets card and I'm the US the event still happens.
Speaker 0: Well see to actually explain what Scott like how that actually works is if you play a card that has your own event on it So I'm the US I play a card with the US.
Speaker 0: I have to choose to either do the number or the event.
Speaker 0: I don't get both.
Speaker 0: But if I play my opponent's card for the number on it, I guess I could play it for the event But you wouldn't want to because they're always bad Always for you and always good for the other person.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Then you play it you get the number but the event happens no matter what and it happens immediately.
Speaker 0: So you kind of get this game where you have a set of cards and events?
Speaker 0: So, you know to what extent you can influence the game and what things are on the horizon as far as you can plan for.
Speaker 0: but at the same time so like maybe you'll have to play a card with the number three because you really need to do those three actions somewhere and You can take the calculated risk of allowing your opponent's action to happen Like you can plan for that event and act accordingly.
Speaker 0: but at the same time There's also the other player who has their own hand of cards and you have to kind of predict what they're going to do And try to figure out what cards they might be holding based on the actions They're taking.
Speaker 0: based on the actions you're taking which cup is poisoned.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah a lot of the game is it seems like In advanced play a lot to in order to win if someone the other guy knows what the cards are in the deck.
Speaker 1: Like he's studied all the cards or he's played it so many times that he knows what most of the important cards are or what?
Speaker 1: All the cards are.
Speaker 1: they're gonna be at a significant advantage Regardless of their strategy because they'll be like, aha.
Speaker 1: I see what he just did there.
Speaker 1: he's probably got this card, so I'll do this to foil him.
Speaker 1: and That's a big part of the game.
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: I mean I think part of the reason that it's hard to say if we like this game or not is that I Get the sense that the majority of the good part of the game can only be had between two experienced players of the game because it's kind of like if you're playing chess with an idiot.
Speaker 0: where say you set up some sort of Complicated.
Speaker 0: I'll put this piece out But it's actually a faint.
Speaker 0: and what didn't you have?
Speaker 0: this whole layered plan of you know?
Speaker 0: A smart player wouldn't do this because plus you plan on the other person being smart.
Speaker 0: But if someone's never played the game before you might bluff or do something interesting and they won't even see it.
Speaker 0: I'll just kind of blunder through the game and As a result all the strategic planning just kind of goes to hell and the game's not fun anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and between two novice players you haven't played the game enough So you can't really formulate a real good strategy.
Speaker 0: You can't really bluff effectively because you can't know if your opponent would even recognize what you were doing at all.
Speaker 0: bluffing or not bluffing and It's just the game doesn't flow too.
Speaker 0: Well, it also didn't help that Scott didn't look at the list of cards so we often didn't know what cards were coming up when.
Speaker 0: Well, you know it's just that You're putting all your influence in Africa, and then eventually I point out that Africa can't be scored until the mid game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah stuff like that, but you're like yeah, I took over Egypt, and I'm like yeah, good luck with that.
Speaker 0: You can have it.
Speaker 1: I think Egypt's actually Middle East in that game.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure about it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter either.
Speaker 1: My basically the main problem I have with the game is that at least for us who are people who don't know all the cards and haven't studied the Game extensively and such it seems like Whether you do well or poorly Depends almost entirely on who who gets what cards if I am the US and I draw a fistful of US cards.
Speaker 1: I'm going to get way ahead Even if I try to fuck up.
Speaker 0: see now you like no matter what I do while I thought that the game is a very interesting mechanic where The score is zero and the score can go toward the US or toward Russia.
Speaker 0: I think this is really cool.
Speaker 0: so if I score five points it moves five toward Russian victory and if Scott scores three moves three toward US victory and At the end of the game whoever has the most points on theirs well, which whoever has the marker on their side anywhere wins.
Speaker 0: Also, there's a fun mechanic where if you get the marker all the way to the end of your side the game ends immediately And you immediately win no matter what.
Speaker 1: yep,
Speaker 0: and the first game we played That's how the US won, but and in the second game when I played with Alex We had this horrible situation where every single card benefited him and screwed me And he had like 15 points after the first couple rounds, and I had almost nothing on the board.
Speaker 0: I was totally fucked.
Speaker 0: it seems like they chose the number of points to absolute victory very well Because since it's an asymmetric game, and there's a limited number of cards, and it's a known quantity of cards.
Speaker 0: the game tends to even itself out and Scott Alex did really well and did like started controlling everything and got all these points.
Speaker 0: but Then the tide turned because now there's only good cards for me left in the deck for a while.
Speaker 0: And it's more a matter of you have to manage your cards to make the most out of what you've got.
Speaker 0: and No matter how good a run of luck you have I don't think there are many runs of luck that will just win you the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it does seem like you know it depends.
Speaker 1: You're doing well Depends a great deal on more on the cards rather than See anything else like I just said.
Speaker 0: I really don't think so.
Speaker 0: I think the game is set to where it Balances out in the end almost no matter what and it's more a matter of how you use the cards you get and how you Plan like say I have the crap hand.
Speaker 0: my game now is not you know Win or do it.
Speaker 0: my game now until I get better cards is how do I control this situation?
Speaker 0: How do I put this bad situation to be as little harm to me as possible like how do I mitigate the damage and hold?
Speaker 0: Until my string of luck come?
Speaker 1: yes, well, I think what it is also Is that you know certain events on certain cards are more or less powerful depending on the current situation in the game?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you have a card where right now this card doesn't do much for you.
Speaker 1: but if you had the card say a turn ago, you could have kicked some ass with it.
Speaker 1: and You know it's not really up to you whether you get this card last turn or this turn.
Speaker 1: so it's sort of obvious that Okay, you know this turn this card doesn't do much for me.
Speaker 1: so I'll use it for the number and you know because it's not the event isn't so useful for me.
Speaker 1: or Aha this card would be really good for rim if it happened now, so I'll space race this one.
Speaker 1: and You know this card is usually good for rim, but right now.
Speaker 1: It's not so good.
Speaker 1: You know it doesn't help him as much as it normally could.
Speaker 1: so I'll let him use this one right now So it doesn't get used later when it's more dangerous.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: while the game is not the greatest game I really think you're underestimating the tactical depth.
Speaker 1: That's in there see but most of that tactical depth is You and the other guy have to know what all the freaking cards are.
Speaker 0: yeah Well the other interesting thing is that if you know about the cold war The game is pretty intuitive because you kind of know like what parts the world were unstable generally when and what kinds of things happen when and you can really plan ahead a lot better.
Speaker 0: and Scott really didn't know much about the cold war so he didn't really Like.
Speaker 0: he didn't take advantage of the fact that France could very easily sway toward communism in the early game and things like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's because I I know a lot of people out there.
Speaker 1: They really like those games that have real history.
Speaker 1: like you're playing rare or tycoon.
Speaker 1: We had maws and this one guy was actually just.
Speaker 1: he was more interested in like what kind of train was drawn on the level Up card, and you know the history of that kind of train engine than the actual game That was going on.
Speaker 1: and I'm not that kind of person like.
Speaker 1: I'm perfectly happy playing a game if it's historically inaccurate.
Speaker 1: It just like aliens and space monsters I really don't care like.
Speaker 1: the theme is nice to look at and nice to maybe like add some role-playing type fun like yar The cold war.
Speaker 1: you're evil Russian something something blah, but I don't really don't care about the history.
Speaker 1: I care about the strategy of the game itself.
Speaker 0: Here's the other thing.
Speaker 0: you even the card list was there and even without the card list you didn't plan ahead.
Speaker 0: When we played the game you pretty much played each turn as though it were an independent thing in and of itself and there was Absolutely, no forward planning at all.
Speaker 0: well
Speaker 1: That's also because like it seems like when I play the game even if I'm trying to think of forward planning it's like I look at my hand and I look at the board and It seems like the best plan long-term or short-term is to use the cards in my hand in the best way possible.
Speaker 0: Well, there's no best way possible because you like the ops you can put influence somewhere on the board.
Speaker 0: You can put the influences just about anywhere.
Speaker 0: Where are you going to put them?
Speaker 0: You got a plan ahead and the two times I played the game I planned like where I was going to expand to a good like two turns in advance And I only altered that if the situation absolutely forced me to because I'd made a mistake And while Alex completely dominated me for the early part of the game with that run of luck But by the end of that while he had a lot of victory points I controlled every single part of the board and if the game had continued, I really think I was going to win.
Speaker 0: However, I conceded defeat because here's my real gripe about the game.
Speaker 0: I mean, I really think you underestimate the tactics and I think you give the game less credit than is due though I'm not saying that the game deserves Great amounts of credit because the real problem is quite simply that this game should be a video game as a board game.
Speaker 0: It's crap because as a result a lot of the game mechanics that could be interesting are really dumbed down and simplified to be able to be done with counters and markers and dice and You spend so much time just manipulating physically all these pieces all over and keeping track of all these numbers.
Speaker 0: If the game were a PC game, I probably played a lot but the fact that I have to do all this Constantly on my own and if I make any mistake the game's fucked and there's no way to fix it.
Speaker 1: You have to quit because of all these cards like there are cards that come out and sort of have lasting effects on the game and like you have to remember those effects and Like doing one thing like makes like three different like exceptions to the rules count.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like like and if you look at the instruction book It's it's.
Speaker 1: it's labeled like five dot one five dot one dot one five dot one dot two.
Speaker 1: Each rule is a separate numbered item in this book and it goes on for like.
Speaker 1: it's a big book with lots and lots of these rules in it and each one is important.
Speaker 1: and if you forget just one You've ruined the entire game and it's very difficult unless you play very slowly and methodically To make sure that you do everything perfectly and manipulate every piece without messing up.
Speaker 0: I just want to point out that of all the times we've played this game Rim screwed the game up zero time.
Speaker 1: you screwed the game a little bit.
Speaker 0: No, yeah, and because you see the thing that you accused me of screwing up How come the exact same thing happened to you when you played against a different thing?
Speaker 1: that happened?
Speaker 0: You not drawing enough cards the only times the game screwed up for games that Scott was involved in.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but the point is the real problem with the game aside from that is that it's tries to sit like the one cool Thing is that nuclear war is not the goal.
Speaker 0: nuclear war immediately ends the game.
Speaker 0: Whoever caused the nuclear war to happen loses, but the game doesn't have any brinksmanship.
Speaker 0: There's almost no reason to go toward nuclear war.
Speaker 0: There's no tension in the game.
Speaker 0: It's so like methodical and calculating the way you play that you never really get the sense that you're actually anywhere close to a nuclear war.
Speaker 0: and in fact You can only really have a nuclear war if you are stupid and you just stupidly make a mistake.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems like I like when games have many different avenues to victory like, you know civilization You can if you play Civ 3 or Civ 4. you can win by war by a space shuttle by Culture by all sorts of things right in this game.
Speaker 1: You can win by making the other guy nuclear war.
Speaker 1: victory points all sorts of conquering all of Europe many different ways to win but Most of those ways to win are sort of these flukes that don't really happen unless someone really screws up.
Speaker 0: Actually, I think they can all happen pretty readily except for the nuclear war.
Speaker 0: one Nuclear war is the only one that can really happen by accident.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it seems like most of the game is concentrated on the victory points and the rest is sort of like these side Like, you know special case.
Speaker 1: Well, like
Speaker 0: I was saying the game should be this kind of brinksmanship game But there's no real brinksmanship in the game because the only stakes involved in brinksmanship at all because coups kind of suck are simply Oh, no, I have to engage in a military action because Scott engaged in a military action.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I'll lose a point or two.
Speaker 0: and oh no is the DEFCON went down to three?
Speaker 0: whoopty shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just gonna go back up again next.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it got down to two a couple times and there was no fear.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 0: no Are you gonna head it?
Speaker 0: Because you can't screw that up unless you're really dumb or not paying attention.
Speaker 0: and in the end I like the game more than Scott and Alex But I don't have time to play it and I don't think I'm ever gonna really pick it up again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean not only is the game not so amazing, but you play it with two people.
Speaker 1: It takes forever to set it up.
Speaker 1: It's like read this book like you have to put exactly this number of pieces in these places and then you have to The board is really flimsy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the board like I know it the Moz guys They have this big piece of clear plastic They put on top of the board and that helps out a lot.
Speaker 1: because the board It kind of bends and it punch and you're only putting these little tiny pieces of cardboard on it So they don't hold they don't weigh the board down.
Speaker 1: So it never gets flat.
Speaker 0: Also, that's the easiest way to screw up the game.
Speaker 0: If you just sneeze it's over.
Speaker 0: You can't fix that.
Speaker 1: Yep, and There's just so many that's like I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it really needs.
Speaker 0: The game has to be a video game or else it's just not worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know when you play Civilization 2 and you double-click on a city, right?
Speaker 1: and you see like all the different meters with different numbers on them like you making this many grain this many this and All these things the game sort of calculates for you and you just look at to get the.
Speaker 1: you know This this visual aid to show you what's going on in this game All that that sort of level of complexity is there but you're managing it with your hands and math in your head And it's not visually there for you all the time.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: I mean the game takes a long time to play But if I didn't have to manipulate like I looked at all the time I spend manipulating Versus the time I spend taking my turn You could knock off a game of this in less than an hour if it was a video game.
Speaker 1: Oh, absolutely.
Speaker 0: But no, it takes several hours to actually play the game with the pieces.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's like deciding what to do takes like two seconds.
Speaker 1: The part that takes a long time is okay.
Speaker 1: I decided what I'm gonna do now.
Speaker 1: I gotta roll this dice now.
Speaker 0: I got I now.
Speaker 1: now I got.
Speaker 1: no sometimes you roll dice.
Speaker 0: You said well, you only roll die in that game.
Speaker 0: You roll one die, whatever.
Speaker 0: and then I said roll this dice.
Speaker 1: Anyway, then you got.
Speaker 0: if you what is you should have said these dice.
Speaker 1: then you got to do some master period.
Speaker 0: it'd be kind of.
Speaker 1: Then you got it.
Speaker 1: then you got to do some math.
Speaker 1: then you got to.
Speaker 1: you know Take a piece of cardboard off the board put a piece of cardboard on the board then flip those pieces of cardboard over and then Look at neighboring pieces of cardboard that all look the same and have little tiny numbers that are different and then it it takes forever.
Speaker 1: All I want to do when I play a game is spend all my time making decisions and that's all I should have to do.
Speaker 1: I shouldn't have to do much more than that now granted.
Speaker 0: The game is still Easily two or three times better than battle are.
Speaker 0: so as a two-player game if you need Kind of like battle or I can't stand battle or it's just it's so it's drivel.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry You suck.
Speaker 0: The game is just.
Speaker 0: there's no substance to it whatsoever.
Speaker 1: This game just like pretends to have substance.
Speaker 0: No, I this game has a lot of.
Speaker 0: this game has a lot more tactical depth than you give it credit for.
Speaker 1: no I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I think all the tactical depth is just.
Speaker 1: you know, what the cards are.
Speaker 0: No a lot of it's still knowing what the cards are.
Speaker 0: It's a game of knowledge more than it's a game of no because once you know the cards and your opponent knows the cards it Becomes a game of bluffing and second-guessing and planning ahead and it's still a strategic game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think so.
Speaker 0: In fact, if the game were easier and quicker to play I'd play it a lot more because I do enjoy it.
Speaker 0: Like I said, I have a somewhat positive view of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you do I disagree.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if you want to play a really simple crappy entirely non skill based game Is for you.
Speaker 1: battle or I think is is skill based and you it's just the level of skill is low.
Speaker 0: Yes, low.
Speaker 0: so low to be effectively meaningless.
Speaker 0: No, no battle or is not a game of Be better at it.
Speaker 0: It's a game of.
Speaker 0: don't screw it up.
Speaker 1: Hey, it's just an easy game.
Speaker 1: It's not a no skill game.
Speaker 0: It doesn't take much skill.
Speaker 1: I gotta say It's a no skill game.
Speaker 1: is like Candyland.
Speaker 1: There is no skill battle or if someone had no skill they would lose every time.
Speaker 1: It's just the required level of skill.
Speaker 1: to be the master is not much.
Speaker 0: if all you've got left Is that it doesn't have no skill then?
Speaker 0: I think I've won that today.
Speaker 1: It's not a no skill game.
Speaker 1: It is a game of skill line.
Speaker 0: It is a minimal skill game.
Speaker 0: It is a mostly die-rolling luck based game.
Speaker 1: Now the luck isn't that big?
Speaker 0: Yes, it is.
Speaker 1: Like it's also There's other luck in Twilight struggle besides just what cards you get.
Speaker 1: that is bitten me multiple times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well part of it is that you tended to take risks that weren't worth it.
Speaker 1: Well, that was in like one time I played and your next time I played I would have like a huge advantage And it would still ruin me.
Speaker 1: Yeah stupid dice.
Speaker 0: Well, that's just.
Speaker 0: any game that has dice is fundamentally in most cases pretty broken.
Speaker 1: I'd say yeah, but I just kind of hate how You know it rolling the 1d6 and then even though you had a huge advantage you still got beat back.
Speaker 0: But at the same time you still get all the military points for it.
Speaker 0: So it still works out.
Speaker 0: It's not like it's a wasted turn.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, Twilight struggle is the sixth most popular game on board game.
Speaker 1: geek.
Speaker 0: Where's a battle or on that list now?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: I think it's been dropping.
Speaker 0: It used to be pretty high and then people actually played it.
Speaker 1: It's number Number.
Speaker 0: what seven?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: It's got some time to fall still.
Speaker 1: Oh, there you go.
Speaker 1: Yeah We got game six and seven, but yeah, so number six.
Speaker 1: I'm working each wild struggle.
Speaker 1: I'm not the biggest fan.
Speaker 1: rim likes a little bit, but he doesn't like to play it.
Speaker 0: But just if I wanted to be a video game.
Speaker 0: if I had free time I'd say we make it into a video game just so I could play it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh well Definitely.
Speaker 1: I don't think I think it'd be worth it to buy this game and play it if it was cheaper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I might be willing to sell it to anyone out there for like 45 or 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's in like almost perfect condition.
Speaker 1: We barely played it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much in perfect condition.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the pieces are punched out and that's it.
Speaker 0: I think the Castro card has a little bit of a nick on it.
Speaker 0: Oh, no This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.