Speaker 0: It's Monday November 12th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight.
Speaker 0: I teach you about surround sound because you don't know shit about it.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, we finally did it.
Speaker 1: This has been a long time coming Scott and I have been debating this for many years even back before it was an option.
Speaker 0: We probably should have done it earlier.
Speaker 1: I wish I'd done it earlier, but I guess the stars were in line.
Speaker 1: We kind of randomly decided.
Speaker 1: All right, let's uh, actually go there and do it.
Speaker 1: But we weren't sure if we were gonna do it.
Speaker 1: We went there and we were just thinking all right, we'll look We'll uh, we'll touch.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we'll actually go all the way.
Speaker 1: I had looked and touched.
Speaker 0: I had looked and touched previously.
Speaker 0: I did not to look.
Speaker 0: I did not need to look and touch again.
Speaker 0: I had already been there.
Speaker 0: It was not a new experience.
Speaker 1: I touched one of these before but the other one I'd never actually experienced it.
Speaker 1: once I actually felt it against my back.
Speaker 1: It was it was fantastic.
Speaker 0: Well, there was one that I experienced for a short time But there was another one that I experienced for a very very long stint, you know, perhaps over a year.
Speaker 1: I think it's a good idea that you got that extender at the top.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the extension at the top definitely helped out.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't laugh if it wasn't contagious.
Speaker 1: I'll have you okay?
Speaker 1: so Scott and I Finally went and bought real office chairs.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't even use the word chair.
Speaker 1: I think at this point throne is appropriate.
Speaker 0: I think throne is appropriate.
Speaker 0: I mean until I can't get my business hammock from Scorpio, so this is I guess second best.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll just we started laughing because Emily is our studio audience and she lost it.
Speaker 0: She definitely lost it.
Speaker 1: But Seriously, so I bought not the old Aeron chair, but the new Aeron chair like the newest fanciest Aeron.
Speaker 0: I didn't even realize that the Aeron chair was updated like when I worked at that.
Speaker 0: You know middle of nowhere office that I quit.
Speaker 0: they had a bunch of Aeron chairs there and I could.
Speaker 0: they were like more Aeron chairs than people, you know, there's one person and like 20 chairs, but they were.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize at the time like I sent him they weren't so great, you know I mean they were great best chair.
Speaker 0: I had sat in up till then but not amazing great.
Speaker 1: I mean I'd sat in him before too and I remember always thinking it's real good, but it's not a thousand dollars good, right?
Speaker 0: Well, actually those at the time I think they were $800.
Speaker 0: But the point is is that I didn't realize that that chair that I had was the lowest end oldest version Aeron chair and nowadays they have Posture fit.
Speaker 0: they have a much updated much newer version much higher end Aeron chair with more features.
Speaker 0: So we
Speaker 1: went to Sam flax
Speaker 0: and flax if you don't know is basically staples, but fancy
Speaker 1: Let me put it to you this way, you know when you go to staples you find some like pimply 18 year old And you're like, hey, I want that office chair that $80 office chair.
Speaker 1: Bring me a box and then an hour later they stumble out with it here.
Speaker 1: It was like we had a basically a personal salesman.
Speaker 1: It was a lot like buying a car.
Speaker 0: He's definitely making a big Commission.
Speaker 0: I think that helped his enthusiasm But he just.
Speaker 1: it was very interesting to be serviced with that level of just what I mean.
Speaker 1: would sir like to try this?
Speaker 0: And if I could do a whole Thursday episode about the the degradation of customer service in the retail industry?
Speaker 0: But I'll just keep it at this when I was a kid a kid like three years old My mom would take me to the mall right the same mall.
Speaker 0: But now is just a crap hole crap mall.
Speaker 0: and there was a shoe store there I think was Buster Brown and I would go there and this old man who was the cool old shoe, man he would measure my foot and he would pick a shoe that he said thought would be good for my foot and he would put it on my foot and then I'd walk Around and he'd be like, huh?
Speaker 0: and he would actually try to sell us the shoe and he'd be real nice and he'd put it in a box and he'd take My old shoes and take care of them and he'd see put the laces in and it was his level of service.
Speaker 1: I mean go you'd go to the Disney Store in the mall.
Speaker 1: There'd be animatronics.
Speaker 1: Yeah people would be dressed up at the mall and all the stores would have very helpful people standing at the door welcoming you selling you Things.
Speaker 1: if I went to the gap or whatever place you buy clothes from nowadays punk kids There'd be a salesperson who would recommend things.
Speaker 0: Yep, then one day I went to buy shoes and there were just boxes of shoes sitting there and I was like what the fuck is this?
Speaker 0: is someone gonna come and measure my foot?
Speaker 0: and That was the end.
Speaker 0: and from then on I just had to get used to the fact that.
Speaker 0: well and I did eventually get used To the fact that I look at the shoe is on this display.
Speaker 0: I have to find a box in my size instead of saying hey Do you have this in my size?
Speaker 0: go in the back and find it for me, you know?
Speaker 0: And I find it in my size and to try them on myself figure it out myself some place.
Speaker 0: mostly don't even have the frickin measuring things out there right and it sucks.
Speaker 0: and Then in New York City, I went to buy shoes, you know Like three years ago because I had to you know dress up for that job.
Speaker 0: I quit when I when I did work in the city and said the middle of no Did you dress up just for the day?
Speaker 1: you quit like you come in in a suit and tie?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I quit yeah, but I Went to floor chime I think which is you know in a shoe store a men's shoe store.
Speaker 0: Well, mostly a men's shoe store.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, that's the handbag Yeah and the old man Measured my foot and he went in the back and he got the size and he did the whole thing and he was talking it.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, wow this level of service still exists in New York City in the city where things are priced higher and People demand a higher level of service.
Speaker 0: and I'm saying, huh?
Speaker 0: it's sort of worth it to pay more to get the service that I demand.
Speaker 0: that I Became unused to that.
Speaker 0: now realized that I miss and I want plus.
Speaker 1: I mean I sat down in one of the normal Aeron chairs.
Speaker 1: I'm like, alright This is I don't know if I want to spend $900 on a chair.
Speaker 1: This is nice.
Speaker 1: I like the mesh because my butt won't sweat when I'm doing the show.
Speaker 1: But at the same time it wasn't like this revelation It wasn't some sort of transcendent experience.
Speaker 1: and then it's pointed out to me that the Aeron chair next to that one is the new Model the newest model the fanciest one that exists and I sat in it and it was like a completely different chair.
Speaker 1: It was
Speaker 0: totally different like I had sat in an Aeron chair for months and months and months like every day and I sat in That new one and I was like, whoa This one is totally different
Speaker 1: and the guy was showing me how to work it and the different angles and the way it floats And the way it works and it.
Speaker 0: there was very One thing that really turned me away from that chair.
Speaker 0: that was how complicated it was.
Speaker 0: You keep manipulating all the levers.
Speaker 1: that's fine though because there's two position two basic states that are easy to switch between the sitting and typing and the front five degrees elevated.
Speaker 1: that apparently will like it'll.
Speaker 1: It's great for podcasting.
Speaker 1: What can I say?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, you're Herman Miller.
Speaker 0: Aeron chair might have two states but my human scale freedom chair has infinity state.
Speaker 1: now Scott way back and always talked about this freedom chair and You know the head of there.
Speaker 1: and the thing is there's the normal freedom chair and then there's the one With the headrest and the headrest adds like a hundred to two hundred dollars to the price It has like 150 dollars, but you can't add the headrest later.
Speaker 0: So you have to decide when you buy it if it's headrest or no head rest.
Speaker 0: I'd always thought other things like the gel seat and the gel armrest.
Speaker 0: you can change later, but not I was like $150 for a headrest.
Speaker 1: what the balls but I sat down in it before Scott did and Let me tell you that headrest.
Speaker 1: I I don't know how we did it But like I leaned back and it would move Differently from the rest of the chair and I was always comfortable no matter what position I was in.
Speaker 0: It was I think the reason I like the freedom chair the most over the Aeron chair is that basically I like to sit You know in in weird ways my posture sucks, but I like it.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: I'm very comfortable when something is pressing against my back called lumbar support, right?
Speaker 0: Well, no, I mean like my entire back all the because the lumbar is key for me, right?
Speaker 0: So it is key.
Speaker 0: everyone's all the chairs have that if they're worth a shit.
Speaker 0: But you know what I would do a previous jobs is I would put the armrest of the chair up on the desk Right to sort of keep the chair in a reclined position.
Speaker 0: That I was always.
Speaker 0: gravity was always pulling me into the back of the seat to us to put pressure on my back.
Speaker 0: the freedom chair has very few levers.
Speaker 0: that has an up-down lever and you can move these the Pad of you know the seat pad forward and back, right?
Speaker 0: I'll probably put it all the way back Other than that.
Speaker 0: Oh, you can also move the armrests around but other than those three things There are no other levers on the chair but it just moves.
Speaker 1: you just move.
Speaker 0: you just move the way you want to move to get in the position you want to be.
Speaker 0: And the whole chair moves with you and is applying constant pressure to my entire back.
Speaker 0: and there's a non headrest version Which I sat in and was amazing and if I really needed to save that hundred and fifty dollars I would have gotten it.
Speaker 0: but the headrest one is just more $150 more and I wasn't originally gonna go for it, but I did and it is awesome.
Speaker 0: So yeah for it to show up It'll arrive probably the day after tomorrow.
Speaker 0: It'll arrive this week.
Speaker 0: definitely there's no doubt about that.
Speaker 0: for the amount of money we're paying They're gonna give us the high-class service.
Speaker 1: Um, I just The fact that we just drop more money on office chairs than we've spent on the entirety of geek nights to date.
Speaker 0: Well you think about I sit in the chair a lot and the chair I have now I had since like 1998 the worst thing I'm
Speaker 1: the guy pointed out, you know It's only 40 bucks to ship one within Manhattan and I realized
Speaker 0: could have had it sent to your office.
Speaker 1: Now I'm thinking this is bad, but I feel like I should have to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because between sitting in the chair I'm sitting in now, which is a nice chair.
Speaker 1: I spent like 400 bucks for this I don't know eight years ago, and it's a nice chair, but it's starting to fall apart.
Speaker 1: It's old and I Sit in this chair most of my time and I sit in my chair at work the rest of my time.
Speaker 1: There are very few chairs.
Speaker 1: I sit in more than those two chairs combined.
Speaker 1: I feel like I should spend the money to have the absolute best thing to put my ass on that I can get.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do sit in the office chair a bit more, but I figure I'm.
Speaker 0: you know I'm not gonna work at the job forever Even though I have no problems with it now and there's a good chance that you know one day I mean, you know the building that we're running out of room So we might move and then there might be a chance for the company to buy me a good chair a better.
Speaker 0: I mean the chair I work at have is not so bad now Plus if I buy one for work and then I stop working there I might work somewhere else.
Speaker 0: that gives me a chair and I'll have a redundant chair.
Speaker 0: You know, it's
Speaker 1: I gotta say the primary reason I didn't just buy another one was very simply that I just started my new job and I wondered how it would look if in my second week of work I just roll an errand chair in one day and stick it in my little space.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it might not be too good.
Speaker 1: I imagine would have been hilarious.
Speaker 0: No, but yeah People say these chairs, you know that the he's right.
Speaker 0: The price does keep going up and I tried to get a deal on eBay because I didn't want to pay the ludicrous price.
Speaker 0: But it's just impossible to try to get a deal.
Speaker 1: So not worth it.
Speaker 1: it the chairs are great and they're worth the money.
Speaker 1: I'm serious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus it's gonna last me, you know, probably I mean this chair lasted me.
Speaker 0: how many years?
Speaker 0: Six seven eight.
Speaker 0: I assume that this chair will last me like 20 to 25 years Hopefully if not more plus I can replace the you know, the seats and the cushions if they get screwed up.
Speaker 0: yep, I like my current chair where the cushions is screwed up and that's the end of it.
Speaker 1: just really goes in with our whole philosophy of Instead of buying a bunch of crap like a lot of people do I'm willing to spend money for quality.
Speaker 1: so I guess if I want if I'm gonna get something I Yeah, and like I'll spend a lot of money on a few very good things than a lot of money on a bunch of crap.
Speaker 1: I don't need a thousand DVDs, but I'd really like to have one really good DVD.
Speaker 0: Yep, and a chair that I sit in at my computer is something I use a lot and is very important and will make a big Difference, you know, where is something else that I might use?
Speaker 0: very rarely?
Speaker 0: I like, you know my toaster oven.
Speaker 0: I can afford to get a $20 toaster.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually currently we will we have the toaster oven.
Speaker 0: the actual toaster we own cost $4 and 98 cents and target and for the amount that we use it and the difference it makes in our lives the $20 toaster the $30 toaster wouldn't really improve our lives.
Speaker 0: It's an awful toaster.
Speaker 0: It's garbage, but it does what we need barely it overheats.
Speaker 1: It can't do a bagel for crap.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not a bagel toaster the worst hosting anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so should buy a thousand dollar toaster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz we toast.
Speaker 0: if I toast it every day I would but I don't right.
Speaker 0: so news I guess This is an old news from last week, but I want to talk about it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, cuz I didn't talk about it last week.
Speaker 0: There are some guys and I'm not even gonna go into any details on this because I don't really care.
Speaker 0: The point is is that they are coding the basically what amounts to a stupidity filter for the Internet's.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're gonna talk about this.
Speaker 0: Yes, they you know, I I don't know what software, you know Principle it works on.
Speaker 0: it could work, you know, similarly to a spam filter I imagine but I guess it could work in other ways as well.
Speaker 0: That doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: the point is they're gonna make some sort of filter that will detect Stupid posts so or stupid typing so for example read somewhere that it was kind of like a Bayesian thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's similar to a spam filter.
Speaker 0: the way this would work I guess in theory as I've heard it described is let's say you try to post on a blog and you say something like Well, I think that's jolly good and you should blabbity blah and it would say Congratulations, you're British.
Speaker 0: Yes, and then you go.
Speaker 0: let's say you go to that blog again later and you say man It would say and you click post.
Speaker 0: it would say sorry your post is too stupid.
Speaker 0: try writing something more intelligent.
Speaker 1: You know, it's kind of like warning cat-like typing detected.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I imagine this also could be used for email.
Speaker 0: You could be like, you know, it would like highlight the emails which are stupid.
Speaker 0: You could just not read those ones and then read well more and more because our forums are getting to the point where?
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Perry doesn't around so often and he doesn't get you guys as much as he should and Waters poison does what he can but he can't get all of you and I don't have time to look at the stupid farm.
Speaker 0: I'm too lazy.
Speaker 1: So, uh Once something like this is in a workable state you can bet your collective asses that stupid types Typing will just be blocked outright on our forums.
Speaker 0: Yep, pretty much.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna use this on pretty much everywhere I can get.
Speaker 0: I Hope I imagine that it could have some sort of algorithm like detect spelling mistakes detect grammatical errors Some sort of percentage wise.
Speaker 0: definitely well I could see what I look at like the the amount of typing and then look for like standalone use and or if you just Train it.
Speaker 1: I mean you say this is a stupid.
Speaker 1: put rate every post on a scale of one stupid to five stupids Yep, and then five stupids being the most of the least stupid, uh Either way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it would just work just fine.
Speaker 0: being stupid or not stupid as opposed to rating on a scale of stupids I mean I could see it being very elegant.
Speaker 1: in the end These sorts of things tend to turn out that way where it wouldn't.
Speaker 1: I mean if someone makes a typo that happens.
Speaker 0: everyone makes mistakes, but if someone consistently ends sentences and poorly placed prepositions It would definitely, you know have some sort of leniency wouldn't be like oh you made a spelling mistake You're stupid.
Speaker 0: It would probably, you know be like, okay your post is like 10% stupid.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like how the Supreme Court decided what pornography was, you know, I'll know it when I see it.
Speaker 1: I Know a stupid post.
Speaker 1: when I see a stupid post I can pick them out.
Speaker 1: if I can get a computer to Within 80% do the same thing.
Speaker 1: for me The Internet's gonna be a much better place to be.
Speaker 0: I think this is great And I think that I will mostly only go to websites that use this sort of thing At least websites with user comments and forms and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So Speaking I'm not even gonna try that sort of segue.
Speaker 1: New York State has had some issues with Facebook lately.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna get into all of them But one of the big issues is that they seem to and this isn't just with Facebook or New York State.
Speaker 1: This is kind of a broad American problem.
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 1: Any sort of social networking or internet thing will be used by people of all ages and there's no way to verify Anyone's identity easily.
Speaker 1: as a result a lot of people Possibly say things they maybe shouldn't have said a lot of people who say they're 18 or obviously 11 and occasionally there are sexual predators and other problems and More and more.
Speaker 1: it seems like parents and lawmakers are doing everything they can to punish The people who provide these contents and these services and prevent them from giving us good stuff Instead of just forcing parents and or schools to teach kids how to not Give their social security number to strangers on the internet
Speaker 0: or you know parents watching the hell what your kids are doing.
Speaker 1: I mean remember butters never get into a car with a stranger unless it's a limousine.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I guess the rationale there is that Facebook is kind of I mean parents don't get it.
Speaker 1: They look at Facebook or myspace or any of these places and to them.
Speaker 1: It's a limousine.
Speaker 1: It's just a place that it's run by a corporation.
Speaker 1: It must be safe, and that's obviously not true, but I think this problem just comes out of the fact that the Generational gap in terms of understanding of technology by and large is just widening.
Speaker 1: there are exceptions But you can't pretend that isn't the general.
Speaker 0: the question I have here right is that basically Facebook is doing something right and New York State has a problem with it, but where is Facebook like, California, right?
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 0: Don't know.
Speaker 0: so so why should anything New York State matter to Facebook like I?
Speaker 0: Guess they you know wouldn't they'd have to sue them under like a federal law because they're doing business across state borders, right?
Speaker 0: So I that's.
Speaker 0: the thing that I'm struggling to understand is how and one individual state has a problem with a national Or an international company, and how what they say even matters.
Speaker 0: shouldn't it be require federal action to do anything?
Speaker 1: well It's more.
Speaker 1: It wasn't really lawsuits or anything It was just them.
Speaker 1: a lot of this was just tongue-lashing and garbage just saying well You should do this and you should do this.
Speaker 1: They're trying to force them to do.
Speaker 0: they could do that all you want, but Facebook.
Speaker 0: I shouldn't be obligated unless right.
Speaker 0: see I'm not a lawyer I don't know either, but that's it's sort of weird to me that like you have these companies You know like internet companies like Google and stuff.
Speaker 0: You know we know the problems like Google in China, and that's an issue of.
Speaker 0: you know international stuff Which which makes sense, but where certain states have different laws and these companies you know that are you know basically?
Speaker 0: Worldwide are forced to change their ways because one state has a problem And it changes the ways for everyone because you can't change it for just one state.
Speaker 0: that well as basically impossible.
Speaker 1: the issue I'm more interested in is just the idea that People are always saying oh Facebook should do something about this.
Speaker 1: What pray tell do these people expect Facebook to do?
Speaker 0: These people don't expect.
Speaker 0: they don't understand that so they can't.
Speaker 1: People in Congress and parents just don't understand the technology so they make demands of the technology that are infeasible.
Speaker 1: I mean what ban anyone under 18?
Speaker 1: how you gonna tell credit card doesn't count.
Speaker 1: I had a credit card when I was 16. you can use your parents credit card You can generate a card number.
Speaker 1: nobody.
Speaker 0: you cannot expect someone to make a real a realistic Expectation if they don't understand the thing that they're complaining about.
Speaker 1: and I wonder when this idea I mean the very vague broad idea behind this of parents and lawmakers Making demands of technology that are infeasible.
Speaker 1: at what point is that going to explode one way or the other?
Speaker 1: at what point our laws Gonna ruin the internet?
Speaker 1: or at what point our old people going to die of old age?
Speaker 1: I know that it's never going to become feasible So I don't know that stupidity filter will probably prevent the majority of 14 year olds from posting on the internet for at least Another 12 years.
Speaker 0: that might help.
Speaker 0: Yes
Speaker 1: So things of the day While I don't think we ever used it as a thing of the day But there hasn't been nearly as much Team Fortress 2 machinima as I've hoped for now
Speaker 0: I think I think the problem with that is that you know with something like quake, right?
Speaker 0: There's very little done for you.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much you got the quake guy and you got some bad guys and that's it.
Speaker 0: and because there's so little done for you But you still have to work within these huge constraints that you get really creative machinima going on Whereas with Team Fortress 2 it's sort of like all the work is done for you already.
Speaker 0: So what machinima can you really do?
Speaker 0: the game is machinima?
Speaker 1: I think the other problem is just that.
Speaker 1: for me at least the real appeal of machinima was that it wasn't easy to do and It wasn't done.
Speaker 1: and seeing it like when I saw father's frags father frags best at a LAN party in Southfield I'd never seen anything like that.
Speaker 1: That was amazing.
Speaker 1: who would even think to do that?
Speaker 1: now It's kind of easy to make machinima and I don't care about it a lot anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I care about machinima the same way I care about other short funny videos or perhaps long funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have to be good or not even funny.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's basically just someone made a movie in some Length and they distribute it in some way and they happen to use a game engine to make the movie.
Speaker 0: Yep That's that's all it is.
Speaker 1: It's machinima.
Speaker 1: It's not Doesn't mean anything useful to me because it's just it's a video on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Is it funny or not?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: I don't really.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: prejudice between live-action or animation and machinima is just a different animation tool But we talked about a briefly.
Speaker 1: Ignis sold us which the first half of it is actually I think an extremely well done work And the second half goes nowhere.
Speaker 1: Yep, but This is probably the funniest team fortress to machinima to date.
Speaker 1: If you don't count the actual official animations from the team fortress to do the machinima is made by valve.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's funny Mostly voice acting.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: The voice acting is just dude it muscles coming out lips.
Speaker 0: It's mostly a work of voice acting that happens to use machinima's but it's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now it's on the start of that pure pointed show that I haven't really watched and I don't know much about.
Speaker 1: so that is Not my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day is just the machinima at the beginning.
Speaker 0: No, as long as at the beginning you can just stop at the mckinmas over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is what I did.
Speaker 0: All right, my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure how old this is, but I discovered it recently and that's well screw everybody.
Speaker 0: It's cicada calm calm and it's.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure exactly what there is to know about it.
Speaker 0: There's music on this website and I assume there are people at this website who made this music and the music is very video gamey.
Speaker 0: I mean, they've got like some Metroid tracks here, but Basically, they've got two album.
Speaker 0: They got a bunch of albums on this site and most of the I haven't listened to nearly even most to all of them.
Speaker 0: But there are two there is technology crisis and technology crisis - and these are basically full albums You can just download and listen to.
Speaker 0: but I think they are fully copyrighted.
Speaker 0: So I'm we might have to ask to get permission to use them in another way.
Speaker 0: but you can download the mp3s for free and It's an album of music that sounds like it should be music from a video game.
Speaker 0: Like you're like man.
Speaker 0: This is an awesome video game soundtrack.
Speaker 0: What game is it from?
Speaker 0: It's not from a game.
Speaker 1: That's kind of like pirate baby cabana battle whatever where man.
Speaker 1: what video game is that?
Speaker 1: It's not a video game It's just a movie that looks like one sort of like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this website has a whole lot of music that's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Geeky rockin music a varying quality and If you're looking for something to listen to here is a treasure trove that will provide you with many hours of listening pleasure for no money.
Speaker 1: so it came up in the forums recently partly because also on the whole internet.
Speaker 1: because well partly because we talked about it and I Made an offhand comment that I will defend at the end of all this but the idea of Dolby Pro logic and the problems with guitar hero and all that business and It made us realize that one.
Speaker 1: that's something we could talk about.
Speaker 1: because while I have been writing a Podcasting guide for some time and I'll finish it someday and publish it somehow Scott did something similar.
Speaker 1: that isn't done, but he's worked a lot on it.
Speaker 1: about computer audio right and consumer audio.
Speaker 0: basically, you know a lot of people seem to understand, you know parts of audio that are like You know, okay the CD the audio comes off the CD with the laser and they understand near the speakers Like okay, the electricity comes into the speaker and the magnet goes back and forth and it makes sound.
Speaker 1: but you know How few people know there's a magnet there.
Speaker 1: Okay, but okay a few people even.
Speaker 0: Speaker works.
Speaker 0: an analog electric signal comes into the speaker.
Speaker 0: There is a magnet in the speaker.
Speaker 0: The electrical signal is a wave.
Speaker 0: It's analog.
Speaker 0: the air right moves according to the wave sound comes out.
Speaker 0: Learn something today.
Speaker 1: I could make a digital speaker with servo motors that vibrated cones.
Speaker 0: This is how heart people turn all sorts of random electronic devices into speakers.
Speaker 0: They just send electrical anything with a moving part.
Speaker 0: You just send an analog electrical signal into it that can power it at the right voltage and it'll make it move According to the analog wave.
Speaker 0: and if things move in a wave they make sound.
Speaker 1: Well, the one interesting thing people should know is just that there's no difference between a microphone and a speaker.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yep Okay.
Speaker 0: So today I'm going to teach you and rim will help about surround sound.
Speaker 1: mostly I'll let Scott talk but I'm go.
Speaker 1: I'll jump in with all the relevant audio engineering bits.
Speaker 0: Yes, the first thing you need to know before you know about surround sound is about mono sound.
Speaker 0: Mono sound is just mono.
Speaker 0: It's one one one track.
Speaker 0: So if you have one speaker just one that vibrates one magnet and you take a mono track You can hear the whole thing with one speaker, right?
Speaker 0: There's all.
Speaker 0: the noise comes out of one speaker.
Speaker 0: That's a mono is stereo sound.
Speaker 0: you have two Speakers, it's 2.0 two speakers and no subwoofers.
Speaker 0: That's when people say 5.1.
Speaker 0: They mean five speakers and one subwoofer, right?
Speaker 0: 6.2 is six speakers and two subwoofers, which is stupid.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: There were those I believe they were called quadraphonic records a long time.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna talk about quadraphonic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that went nowhere that my dad had one, but so did my dad.
Speaker 0: He had a quadraphonic receiver, but only two speakers.
Speaker 0: But anyway stereo sound 2.0 you have two speakers and you can actually send different audio to the left and different audio to the right.
Speaker 0: and it's basically The way they do this is they have two monos.
Speaker 0: You just have twice as much sound and it takes up twice as much data and you don't lose any data because you have just Two different mono tracks.
Speaker 0: you said one out one wire and one out of different wire.
Speaker 0: and you sort of you know You create your music in such a way where you decide when you're making the music or audio Which sounds are gonna come out of left in which you come to come out of the right and it sounds really good.
Speaker 0: You can do cool stuff with it.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, you'll you'll be playing you listen to some music and like, you know The guitar will be rocking on the left of the bass be rocking on the right and it sounds totally awesome.
Speaker 0: That's the stereo sound is now.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess I because stereo sound is just the way it doesn't always have to sound stereo.
Speaker 1: It's just yep.
Speaker 1: That is when you have two streams of audio going to two speakers.
Speaker 1: Now you can with trickery use those two speakers to make surround sound that sounds totally real to people.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the math of that is complicated.
Speaker 1: But basically all you have to do is you can.
Speaker 1: the reason we hear in stereo and the way that works is one.
Speaker 0: We have two ears.
Speaker 1: not only do we have two ears, but our ears are not both identical.
Speaker 1: Usually someone want someone's right or left ear is a little bit higher lower shapes a little bit different.
Speaker 0: Everyone's ear is crazy different.
Speaker 0: You got bones in the ear that make a difference.
Speaker 0: You got the shape of your ear.
Speaker 0: that makes a difference the position.
Speaker 1: You notice how a lot of animals or humans too if they hear a sound or they wander instinctually You'll kind of cock your head a little bit and you'll move your head around a little bit.
Speaker 1: and there's all these ways that animals Can define where sound is coming from.
Speaker 1: and here in stereo, but the way we actually tell basically Essentially boils down.
Speaker 1: the brain figures it out to the difference the delay Between when one ear hears it and when the other ear hears it.
Speaker 1: And because our ears are shaped we have other Mechanisms to determine if something is in front of us or behind us.
Speaker 1: because theoretically if our ears were identical We would not be able to tell between the sound that was exactly in front of us and exactly behind us.
Speaker 1: Mmm, but we can tell and there are a lot of reasons for that.
Speaker 1: But the shape of the head and everything have an effect.
Speaker 1: But basically if you mess with sound like say I say, all right I'll take this frequency range and I'll phase shift it or something or I'll delay it out of the left speaker but not the right speaker a Tiny fraction of a second, but then this frequency range I'll delay even more and this frequency range.
Speaker 1: I'll delay even less.
Speaker 1: Each one of those bands will sound Physically like it's in a different part of the room because your brain says well I calculated this delay.
Speaker 1: Therefore the object is right there.
Speaker 0: Hmm and a lot of Computer games have used this to great effect a lot in the day before, you know The the current, you know right now if you want to play a game and surround sound a lot of them just use.
Speaker 0: You know DTS or whatever.
Speaker 0: But you know some of them use creative EAX kind of sound blaster stuff.
Speaker 0: back in the day There was what a C3.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a C3 was um, I'll take no what the hell a track?
Speaker 0: No, what the fuck was it called?
Speaker 0: forget it.
Speaker 0: It began with an a because he ate all that like sound blaster stuff.
Speaker 0: you pretty all those words I said were things that have other things to do with audio.
Speaker 1: No, that was just reverb the creative thing.
Speaker 1: They they acted like it was fancy.
Speaker 1: You know, this is like the.
Speaker 1: it's just reverb.
Speaker 0: Yep But yeah, there was another competitor that began with an a that got killed by a 3d.
Speaker 0: Yes a 3d goddamn.
Speaker 0: And that was basically this what rim is talking about?
Speaker 0: using stereo sound to sound like surround sound?
Speaker 1: Specifically I'm talking about doing it myself because I've done it all I do it.
Speaker 1: It's fun.
Speaker 1: I used to take music that I had and do that to it and I'd bring like I could bring the trumpet part.
Speaker 1: So it sounded like the trumpet part was next to me and everything else was far away and all this fun stuff.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so in stereo sound is pretty good And that's why most things you listen to today are in stereo sound.
Speaker 0: FM is you know FM radio is stereo am radio as well.
Speaker 1: It helps that we have two ears.
Speaker 1: I mean binaural recording.
Speaker 1: you can record things perfectly.
Speaker 0: Yep You can you know, this is why headphones, you know, you have two speakers in them.
Speaker 0: Stereo is great.
Speaker 0: It's that's all there is to say.
Speaker 0: So then we some guy came up with quadraphonic.
Speaker 0: I cannot can talk about this much but quadraphonic was.
Speaker 0: it came and it went with good reason.
Speaker 1: It was more.
Speaker 0: Four speakers was basically four speakers with four full audio tracks and you had to get special records Because this is that old right.
Speaker 0: and you had a special receiver and you had to have four speakers.
Speaker 0: and it was ludicrous.
Speaker 0: and you Know it's something that rich fancy people bought and there weren't too many quadraphonic records.
Speaker 0: and that was it.
Speaker 0: This was like.
Speaker 0: then it went away early.
Speaker 0: audio files If anything tells you my dad had a receiver capable of quadraphonic But he only had two speakers and he had stereo records on his stereo turntable.
Speaker 0: So, okay, so Later on eventually people decided hey Surround sound we can do cool stuff.
Speaker 0: Like what have you had?
Speaker 0: a whole bunch of speakers in the movie theater?
Speaker 0: We could make it sound like stuff is coming all over the place and in the movie theater.
Speaker 0: It is pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: You can get wicked Star Wars action going on and it.
Speaker 0: you know things in like, you know The what's it called the Omni max or theaters and stuff you can.
Speaker 0: I'm X I'm X. Well, Omni max is better than I'm X but what it's?
Speaker 0: all the same You can get really cool special effects If you have lots of speakers lots of powerful speakers and you determine in production time which audio comes out of which speakers.
Speaker 0: and that's pretty cool stuff.
Speaker 0: and People eventually said hey, I can afford to get a lot of speakers speakers achieve.
Speaker 0: Why can't I have that awesome cinematic experience in my house?
Speaker 0: Well, you can you can.
Speaker 0: you can get surround sound in your house.
Speaker 1: The problem is it's not quite that simple.
Speaker 1: I mean how many old movies are recorded in?
Speaker 1: Surround sound almost has a. Blanca doesn't have 5.1 audio tracks.
Speaker 0: Here's another thing, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, you want in surround sound right five point one audio tracks with no loss of data.
Speaker 0: Well, you know how big a wave file is of like say, you know a three-minute song, right?
Speaker 0: No, even a flack.
Speaker 0: Okay, so you compress losslessly a Five minute song.
Speaker 0: right that is stereo sound.
Speaker 0: that's a lot of data that can be like 40 megs.
Speaker 0: this podcast right compressed An hour in mp3 heavily compressed can be like 40 megs.
Speaker 0: Take a 90 minute movie now take six tracks of audio.
Speaker 0: So three times stereo and Make it lossless.
Speaker 0: That is still have room for the movie and still have room for the movie on a four gigabyte DVD.
Speaker 0: It's not happening.
Speaker 1: Plus the movie is gonna be HD.
Speaker 1: and then what?
Speaker 0: and then what?
Speaker 0: Okay, so you put it on a gigantic blu-ray.
Speaker 0: So you fit the HD movie on the gigantic blu-ray.
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: There's no room for the six channels of lossless audio.
Speaker 0: Also six channels of lossless audio.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: How are you gonna transfer those from your DVD player to your receiver to your speakers?
Speaker 0: You don't have that.
Speaker 0: you're gonna have six wires coming out of your Frickin stereo or one e player one digital wire, but then you have to have a fairly Good bus to say a day even if you have a digital wire, okay, so you have one digital wire.
Speaker 0: You know ludicrously fast It has to be to be able to transfer enough data in You know so that the audio comes out without being delayed.
Speaker 1: now computers could do it But are you gonna spend a computer's worth on just the audio part of your DVD player?
Speaker 0: No, that's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: So they've invented many technologies to do surround sound and I will explain them all briefly Or at least the ones you care about briefly.
Speaker 0: The first one was Dolby surround.
Speaker 0: Dolby surround is what they used in the movie theaters back in the day And basically what they did is they took stereo sound analog stereo sound and on each One of the two channels they phase shifted another channel.
Speaker 0: now this if you played this out of normal speakers It wouldn't sound quite right because you have this, you know audio on top of audio but the receiver the equipment that received the signal would take the audio and Basically split up.
Speaker 0: because you know, you have two waves.
Speaker 0: one is phase shifted.
Speaker 0: So when something's in phase that's when the humps of the waves meet the humps of the waves and the dips in the waves Meet the dips.
Speaker 0: So if you phase shift it you have these humps meeting the not You know sort of off.
Speaker 0: and when you face if you have a phase shifted wave on top of another phase shifted wave with math You can split them up again.
Speaker 0: So if you have four you have stereo sound Four waves to a phase shifted on top of each other to create a new wave.
Speaker 0: then you split it up on the other end.
Speaker 0: Now you can have four speakers worth.
Speaker 0: so they did left right center and rear and that was the original Dolby.
Speaker 0: You know just no normal Dolby surround.
Speaker 0: then they came out with Dolby Pro logic.
Speaker 0: Dolby Pro logic was basically Dolby surround but better.
Speaker 0: in Addition they had another feature and this feature allowed you to take stereo sound, you know.
Speaker 0: So if you had a CD right back in the day with just Dolby surround You couldn't listen to a CD and surround sound.
Speaker 0: you put a stereo CD in there.
Speaker 0: It was like the quadraphonic record days.
Speaker 0: If you had a stereo record, it would only play out of two speakers.
Speaker 1: now You could probably make it play out of four But it would just play the same thing out of two in the same thing out of the other two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could duplicate say okay, whatever you're playing on the front right play on the back, right?
Speaker 0: That doesn't really help you though.
Speaker 0: It's just stereo sound with more speakers and more loudness.
Speaker 0: It doesn't actually surround sound You can't.
Speaker 0: you won't hear the x-wing flying around behind you but not in front of you You know, you won't hear the laser going over your left shoulder towards your front, right?
Speaker 0: so Dolby Pro logic what they did is using some math that I'm not going to explain.
Speaker 0: they had a system where you could take a stereo CD or a stereo audio signal and it would figure out a way to split that up.
Speaker 0: not split it up so much but do math and Calculate a diff a new.
Speaker 0: it would generate a brand new.
Speaker 0: not brand new but from the stereo sound it had He would figure out what should go on the center channel and what should go on the rear channel.
Speaker 0: So even if you didn't have a surround sound DVD or laserdisc because that was in the Dolby Pro logic one days It was laserdisc.
Speaker 0: You could still hear your CDs in Surroundish sound on your all your speakers and it wouldn't just be copying.
Speaker 0: Then came Dolby Pro logic 2 which is mostly what we're using these days.
Speaker 0: What Dolby Pro logic 2 does is Is not really?
Speaker 0: you know, it takes the same old Dolby Pro logic and improves upon it and It also allows you to take mono audio, right?
Speaker 0: And if you put it in matrix mode, it can actually up mix the mono to be stereo Right to to surround sound and it also takes around sound stereo sound and can upgrade it to 5.1 instead of 4.0.
Speaker 0: So now your normal old CD that you bought at the store with Dolby Pro logic 2.
Speaker 0: You can listen to that in 5.1 surround sound and it's not like the people making the CD Decided in advance what audio would come out of which speakers or anything.
Speaker 0: the receiver that you're using just sort of figures it out And you can put it in different modes.
Speaker 0: you can put in matrix mode movie mode music mode game mode and Depending on which mode you pick it Changes the way it figures out what comes out of the other speakers and it sounds different.
Speaker 0: and that's why when you push those buttons On your stereo, it says haul movie whatever and that's what it's doing.
Speaker 0: Dolby Pro logic 2x is the same as Dolby Pro logic 2 only they added support for 6.1 and 7.1.
Speaker 0: So if you're one of those crazies with seven speakers in a subwoofer, you're to your stereo CD.
Speaker 0: you can hear on all your speakers.
Speaker 1: I'll be honest I like surround sound but it's never really been worth it to bother with the mess and the wires and wireless sucks.
Speaker 0: But Dolby Pro logic specifically is a way for you to take non things that aren't in surround sound and listen to them on your surround sound system and they will sound better and they will be on all your speakers in a Good way.
Speaker 0: that sounds good if you things are set up right now.
Speaker 1: why did I?
Speaker 1: because I made a throwaway comment about this sort of thing in a preview show and Basically, the reason I said that was simply that the majority of people who have surround sound systems and use this sort of thing Have no idea how it works now not in terms of math or in terms of the signals or whatever You know, I don't care if you know that.
Speaker 1: you don't need to know that.
Speaker 1: You don't need to know how internal combustion works to drive a car But you need to know what all those buttons on the dashboard do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and a lot of people and I've been to their houses.
Speaker 1: They'll have a surround sound system and It's not in surround sound and it never has been.
Speaker 1: they don't have it set up right at all And they always like oh I got the surround sound.
Speaker 1: It's great, but it's not surround sound and they can't even tell they don't know.
Speaker 0: they don't know.
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 1: Especially with the pro logic it always acts like yeah, it's working Yeah, it's in surround and it might kind of be but not really and not so great Nope,
Speaker 0: so right now people complaining about guitar hero 3 on the Wii and they're like, oh my pro logic doesn't work.
Speaker 0: Well, no actually you're a fool.
Speaker 0: and in fact It could be possible that the pro logic would not be working properly and they still wouldn't even know because if it wasn't working properly Stereo sound would come out their receivers would turn with pro logic it to surround sound and they wouldn't know anything was wrong Even though something very well could be wrong because they have no clue how it works.
Speaker 0: However, the on the GameCube or you know the Wii or something if you you know You can say some of the games are in Dolby Pro logic 2 or whatever Which means they specially constructed and did the phase shifting whatever, you know to decide, you know in advance What would come out of what speakers but still is just a stereo, you know audio signal and it also, you know Tells your receiver ever to go into game mode, you know, which is so it sounds the way they wanted to sound in games.
Speaker 0: But the problem in guitar hero the reason people are noticing a problem is because the game is broken and it has mono audio and Mono audio can only be upgraded to surround sound with pro logic if you're using pro logic 2 in matrix mode.
Speaker 0: so because of that people are looking at the receivers and they're seeing that the little pro logic light isn't turning on and They're realizing that sound isn't coming out of any of the speakers except like one in the middle or just like the front ones.
Speaker 0: And now they realize there's a problem even though they have no clue what the problem is or why or anything.
Speaker 1: So the game is however broken.
Speaker 0: the game is yes.
Speaker 0: I do think Non mono sound is is I have to say not acceptable and they really should sort of put a map put the game out again With stereo sound with some sort of recall.
Speaker 0: not but and again, I've been playing the game with mono sound You know on our stereo TV with no surround sound.
Speaker 0: We don't have any surrounds.
Speaker 0: We just please TV speakers.
Speaker 0: I haven't noticed any problem.
Speaker 0: It sounds great to me.
Speaker 0: I don't really.
Speaker 0: I didn't even notice.
Speaker 1: well, I didn't notice it one but this has nothing to do with that.
Speaker 1: the practice mode in guitar hero 3 is Garbage because when you play it at any slow speed almost every song just sounds like a horrible noise.
Speaker 0: That is that is true Unlistenable noise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think stereo might help that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but probably not.
Speaker 1: I'm not that confident But - there's a bunch of songs for if you activate star power at certain times.
Speaker 1: It sounds really bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's true really bad.
Speaker 0: So the only other thing I have to teach you about here is all those other surround sounds the DTS the Dolby digital.
Speaker 0: These are all digital surround sound, right?
Speaker 0: This is something completely different from what pro logic is.
Speaker 0: pro logic takes an analog stereo signal and makes it into you know Set figures out and sends audio to your speakers depending on what came in this digital someone in advance, you know decided Exactly what audio would go to which speakers.
Speaker 0: and it's it's digital like an mp3 or a WAV file at zeros and ones.
Speaker 0: Right and the zeros and ones get sent to your receiver and your receiver looks at those zeros and ones and then figures out What analog audio signals to send to which speakers based on the zeros and ones?
Speaker 0: Now the first thing you need to know is about PCM.
Speaker 0: All you need to know.
Speaker 0: a PCM is this a WAV file?
Speaker 0: is PCM?
Speaker 0: you take an analog audio signal and stereo You turn it into zeros and ones.
Speaker 0: that's called PCM Surround sound DTS and Dolby digital all those things use something that's not PCM.
Speaker 0: Well, it is PCM, but it's not.
Speaker 0: It's called AC 3 but AC 3 is is you take say 5.1 channels of audio and you compress them.
Speaker 0: It's lossy.
Speaker 0: You're losing audio.
Speaker 0: It's not full.
Speaker 0: It's not like if you had three stereo waves separately for six channels.
Speaker 0: It's less than that.
Speaker 0: You're losing something like when you make an mp3 and you lose audio.
Speaker 0: You're losing something when you do this.
Speaker 1: granted the point of mp3 is that you lose audio that nominally humans can't hear right?
Speaker 0: But AC 3 is you're losing something.
Speaker 0: so it's not full six channels, but you'll notice a lot of audio files They're listening to like Oh DTS.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's so much better.
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 0: No, it's just more speakers DTS and all these things.
Speaker 0: what they do is they take six channels of audio and using AC 3 they are able to make a PCM wave.
Speaker 0: that Actually and using some crazy thing that I can explain contains a lot more audio.
Speaker 0: But you know, they had to compress it which is how it fits.
Speaker 0: they send that AC 3 Which is also PCM kind of over to the receiver and the receiver says oh DTS a I see This is DTS AC 3. what audio do you want me to send?
Speaker 0: to which speaker and in advance?
Speaker 0: It was decided which audio would go to which speaker.
Speaker 0: so your receiver takes splits up decodes that AC 3 Which is all zeros and ones and figures out what audio to send to which speaker.
Speaker 0: and that's how it works.
Speaker 0: That's that's all there is to digital surround sound and digital surround sound is pretty damn good And I think it's it has a lot of uses.
Speaker 0: For example, if you want to hear those x-wings flying around behind you the DTS Adobe digital is the way that's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: If you want to play half-life 2 and bad guys shooting behind you, this is also how that's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's is how it works.
Speaker 0: The thing is you need to have a Surround.
Speaker 0: you need to have.
Speaker 0: first of all the sound that you're listening to has to be encoded.
Speaker 0: this way the hardware that is sending it to your receiver has to be sending it in a digital form with like an optical audio cable of some sorts or you know and the receiver has to support that particular format and then you have to have enough speakers to connect and have all those outputs go out and Most people have no clue how they had to set that up or how it works or anything.
Speaker 0: and that's how surround sound works.
Speaker 0: That's that's really all there is to it.
Speaker 0: There's I mean anything more would be like the math of how they split these things up and how the waves fit and how they do The compression which you really don't care about.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: most movie theaters as far as I know They just go full-on and they just have you know, a track of audio fully and lossless for every single You know channel that they want.
Speaker 1: do they?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty I think they do.
Speaker 1: I'm just curious.
Speaker 0: That's my guess.
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't they?
Speaker 0: you know, they get these movies with these digital projectors, you know Why wouldn't they just send one more disc with the audio on it?
Speaker 0: I don't know, but are you sure if they don't do that?
Speaker 0: They probably just use like that, you know, the most DTS you can use which would probably be like, you know I guess what 6.2 channels something like that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think we're done for tonight though We stayed late in the city.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I want to go to bed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but in general I think the the opinion is you know Despite how surround sound works in my opinion Unless you're really listening to one of those movies that needs surround sound like the matrix or Star Wars or something.
Speaker 0: Or unless you're playing a video game like, you know counter-strike We're hearing the bad guys behind you or it's a really cinematic game like a Resident Evil.
Speaker 0: Maybe Surround sound is largely useless and sort of a vanity thing A lot of people buy to show off like ooh, look I have surround sound when really it's it's not it's not that great.
Speaker 0: I mean I have surround sound on my PC for you know games so I can hear people behind me.
Speaker 0: But in the living room, I we just use the TV speakers.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.