Speaker 0: It's Thursday December 20th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: It's the state of the podcast.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Nobles.
Speaker 1: Nobles you mean like an RC pro-am the tires that you buy after you buy the regular tires.
Speaker 0: Oh, man I never got good tires.
Speaker 0: I was went for the big engines.
Speaker 1: Oh, you gotta buy the good tires are you also in addition to the big engines?
Speaker 0: You're not gonna win, but no no no not that kind of Nobles a much more Fun kind of knobbly.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's more fun than RC pro.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna play RC program right now.
Speaker 1: Why isn't that on the virtual console?
Speaker 1: god damn it?
Speaker 0: It should be I'd pay for half of it.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm too.
Speaker 0: at least RC program and RC program - we're pretty much some of my favorite racing games ever.
Speaker 1: Yep, all right.
Speaker 0: Can did we even talk about that in the racing games show?
Speaker 1: I think I did bring it up.
Speaker 0: I hope so if we did not feel quickly.
Speaker 0: yeah, but yeah We've been limping along here at geek nights for the last 420 some episodes with the mixer we bought at the start of it.
Speaker 0: all that you be 802 You're a wreck.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: We actually before that didn't have a mixer at all.
Speaker 0: well before that we had a Logitech free stick microphone that I pointed straight up on one side of the room with a gain turned all the way up on my Sound Blaster like ancient PCI card that I've had since my first real computer.
Speaker 1: And still the sound card we're using that is still the sound cover.
Speaker 1: you need to do something about that's the part We really need to fix.
Speaker 0: yeah, but I think I fixed that.
Speaker 0: we'll see we'll find out.
Speaker 0: But this little mixer has done us really well.
Speaker 0: I mean if you're not some sort of crazy like Podcaster who cares and just goes nuts and does for her if you don't have a lot of people You really don't need much more than the UV 802 or the equivalent.
Speaker 0: You know it's got two microphone pre amplifiers and all that business.
Speaker 0: But over the years we upgraded We got a little compressor to go along with that and then we learned that compressor wasn't so great And we lost the power cable to it.
Speaker 0: I think I lost the power cable to it.
Speaker 0: So we bought a real compressor Realized that it was a thousand times better.
Speaker 0: And yet we never upgraded the mixer and every now and then we thought hey we got a bunch of people over.
Speaker 0: let's get them all on the show.
Speaker 0: and That always sucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it always did quite and kind of suck.
Speaker 1: I mean I third microphone always sound like shit And that was even worse because the person using it was the person who had the least experience using it.
Speaker 0: Yep, so we had to give all the other people crap.
Speaker 0: you might remember.
Speaker 0: I think Otacon was probably the worst ever.
Speaker 0: we had like seven people and we wanted to do a roundtable, right?
Speaker 0: we had our two like okay microphones and then like crap microphones and There's only two microphone inputs on this thing.
Speaker 0: so I had him plugged into like all these other holes And I just turned the faders all the way up, and it didn't work at all.
Speaker 0: that sounded like crap.
Speaker 0: It was quite the shit but not good, you know Scott has a good job, and I have a good job and I Realized suddenly that I can buy stuff if stuff is better, and I want it.
Speaker 0: I can just buy it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know why.
Speaker 1: you know all the other podcasters and like webcomic people in such-and-such.
Speaker 1: They're always like donate to me so I can get all this nice stuff and improve the things I'm doing for you for free.
Speaker 1: and we're like We have jobs and we can just afford all those things.
Speaker 1: do those other people not have job?
Speaker 0: That's kind of low.
Speaker 0: I mean not everyone is an IT professional.
Speaker 1: No, but they whatever they are they should have a good job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it's the deal.
Speaker 0: the real deal There is that you don't need better stuff.
Speaker 0: usually geek nights would probably be just fine if we kept using this Ancient like $60 mixer forever.
Speaker 1: then what the hell am I giving you money for?
Speaker 0: Well because we we decided we wanted to do more.
Speaker 0: I think you decided yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 0: I actually bought more of a mixer than you thought I was going to and I'm gonna pay the difference.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but now I'm giving you money, so you can play with knobbly's.
Speaker 1: and what do I get?
Speaker 1: nothing?
Speaker 0: Ah, you know you get.
Speaker 0: the next time we want to have a roundtable or an interview You don't have to sit there for 20 minutes while I hold four Microphones in front of my mouth yelling into him and moving a bunch of knobs on a crappy mixer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but instead I have to suffer you now Fiddling with knobs and yelling all weekend.
Speaker 0: see this luckily aren't you going out of town Saturday morning?
Speaker 1: That's only one day.
Speaker 1: It's always takes you like weeks to do this shit.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: I don't think it will this time.
Speaker 0: I think I know enough about mixers at this point to where I can just because part of the reason it took so long before is that I Didn't know a lot about mixers when I first got this stuff.
Speaker 0: and now I know that there's certain things a mixer can have that makes Podcasting a million times easier, and I made sure I got a mixer that freaking has that alrighty ah.
Speaker 0: But I now have sitting next to me a Zenix 1832 fxpro.
Speaker 0: this thing is a lot bigger than it looked on the website.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's how things tend to go.
Speaker 1: I mean look at my subwoofer.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was the best.
Speaker 0: Scott got this nothing.
Speaker 0: We've talked about this before but he needed speakers for his computer And he wanted to get good ones and he showed me what he was getting.
Speaker 0: I thought wow that looks pretty good.
Speaker 0: And he used to get home from work before me back then and he messages me, and he's like There's a refrigerator box here, and I think it's my speakers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you want to know the speakers I have Do they still make them?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there.
Speaker 1: It is the Logitech z5500.
Speaker 1: I got it for like 200 bucks.
Speaker 0: They're good speakers.
Speaker 1: They're right.
Speaker 1: They're amazing.
Speaker 1: you can even use them for like your living room, but but the subwoofer is much bigger than If you think it is.
Speaker 0: now you might look at it and say no it looks pretty big.
Speaker 0: I think I know how big that is.
Speaker 0: it's bigger than you think it is.
Speaker 1: the Z5500 subwoofer is like as big as an ottoman.
Speaker 0: I rest my feet on it But I'm staring at this mixer now, and I have such a desire to start fiddling with it So fiddling with the knobs.
Speaker 0: so excuse me if I trail off periodically.
Speaker 1: all right anyway.
Speaker 1: today I think maybe yesterday the Firefox 3 beta 2 came out all right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wasn't that right about the time when you were having some weird Firefox crashes.
Speaker 1: No well not really but anyway Firefox 2 is generally just being kind of shitty like I really wanted to stop using it because it takes up so much memory and It's unstable Etc, etc.
Speaker 1: It's it's slow You know and the other browsers are better, but I have this sort of dependence.
Speaker 1: I can't live.
Speaker 1: I can't do anything without certain Firefox extensions like I can use a different browser But I need firebug I need adblock.
Speaker 1: I need these extensions more than I need Firefox and but those things only work with Firefox.
Speaker 0: luckily I use very few extensions.
Speaker 1: That's good, but I need a lot of those extensions.
Speaker 0: web development I get pretty much.
Speaker 0: I use Fark.
Speaker 0: it a delicious plug-in.
Speaker 0: doesn't matter which one.
Speaker 0: I pretty much install a different one everywhere I go cuz I always forget which one I use and I think that's it now.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, I'd blocked off.
Speaker 1: I use like Google browser sync and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I haven't posted on Fark in like a month, so I don't think I need Fark it anymore.
Speaker 1: Nope, but yeah.
Speaker 1: So I start using Firefox 3 beta 2.
Speaker 1: I set up like a separate Firefox profile for it and whatever and I'm using it and I can say that I wouldn't recommend anyone.
Speaker 1: go and use it yet because it's still sort of beta and you have to do tricky Stuff to keep it from ruining your stuff.
Speaker 1: you got now and most of the extensions you depend on will not work with it.
Speaker 1: Like adblock works with it just fine But like firebug you have to go get a special version of it and no no other extension worked at all.
Speaker 1: The plugins work just fine.
Speaker 1: You said to install them, but I I can tell you that when Firefox 3 finally comes out it is going to be the return to what made Firefox great the Fastness and the stableness and the not using so much memory and the wicked fast JavaScript and all that.
Speaker 1: so the outlook is good.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna do some news?
Speaker 0: I think we should I?
Speaker 0: Wasn't sure what to talk about?
Speaker 0: I mean usually there's a news that just jumps out like oh, I got to talk about this I got opinions about this but I'm kind of avoiding stating all my opinions in the US political arena until we eventually do a show about all that business and There wasn't really anything.
Speaker 0: I mean my opinions are kind of known on a lot of issues.
Speaker 0: at this point I mean pretty much any news I bring up.
Speaker 0: half of you out there who listen can say oh I know what rims gonna say about.
Speaker 0: that Kind of defeats the purpose of doing commentary on news because I at least I hope that we are not your primary source of news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hope not kind of like The Daily Show where more people get their news than probably should.
Speaker 0: but so Japan's defense minister is Arguing lately that perhaps Japan should take a more active role in Military affairs worldwide and this has been an issue for a long time.
Speaker 0: I mean for those of you who are unaware.
Speaker 0: ever since World War two Japan has had a constitutional prohibition From having a military except for very specific and somewhat ambiguous defensive purposes.
Speaker 0: Now there's been a lot of read first president of Japan or a history textbook that both One of them might be a little more accurate Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all three.
Speaker 0: then you'll be set either that really have three different ideas of what's going on, yeah so Japan has been taking more and more of a role in world affairs.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of people.
Speaker 0: there's pretty much arguments on both sides that well, really there's three sides of the arguments.
Speaker 0: there's one group of people who argue that Japan should remain completely pacifist as a model for the world and as this ideal that yes, It's possible as long as people aren't all bastards will be pacifist and the u.s.
Speaker 0: Is pretty much bound to protect Japan from anything Yep, but there's another group of people who say Japan Has gotten past World War two and that maybe they're not the threat to the world that they once were.
Speaker 0: That's true also and that perhaps Japan being a nation kind of like Germany who had lost.
Speaker 1: Where you're going with this is Larry's?
Speaker 0: Yeah People who had known that, you know, they've known warfare.
Speaker 0: they engaged this nation.
Speaker 0: not the individual people because not that many people are still alive who went through all that in World War two, but a nation that fought a war like that and lost and now can enter the world as a Fairly objective peacekeeping force.
Speaker 0: I mean I think the Japanese to the JSDF as a peacekeeping UN kind of force would probably be fantastic and I can see an argument for Japan taking a wider role in purely peacekeeping or purely humanitarian efforts worldwide.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now there's the third argument here that Japan should Militarized for right-wing crazy reasons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's bad now.
Speaker 0: I Generally disapprove of this but luckily so do most rational people except katsu now.
Speaker 0: There is a fourth Argument here that is surprisingly gaining more traction than I would have expected.
Speaker 1: I haven't heard of a fourth argument.
Speaker 1: What this news to me?
Speaker 0: Well, this fourth argument has been put forth by two high-ups in the current I guess cabinet of Japan's government.
Speaker 0: Alright, so the most recent person to bring this up is Japan's defense minister.
Speaker 0: the current one Oh, is she Bob?
Speaker 1: So it's not like the equivalent of old rummy but in Japan something like that.
Speaker 0: I'll admit that my understanding of Japanese politics comes down to what I read in sanctuary coupled with first president of Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 0: So, uh Yeah, but I know they don't have a president because FPOJ was about them getting one Yep, and and I know it's pronounced deed and that's about as far as I got.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah It's all old men - oh and they have prefectures So that each guy comes from some brief.
Speaker 0: you learned that from initial D more so than from anything else.
Speaker 1: I knew they had prefectures before initial D.
Speaker 0: But yeah anyway, so Shigeru Ishiba is arguing that perhaps the US imposed 1947 pacifist constitution might be a great hindrance if ever aliens invade in Japan has to fight them off Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I don't think he's kidding.
Speaker 1: Is he sure he's talking about Chinese, right?
Speaker 0: I think he's talking about little green men green men.
Speaker 0: So maybe blue men.
Speaker 1: So Atlanteans and Iceland.
Speaker 0: Ian's I'm I'm.
Speaker 0: I guess I could make some jokes that I'm not gonna make but I'm trying the best I can here.
Speaker 0: If they here's a quote from him.
Speaker 0: if they descended saying say people of Earth let's make friends it would not be considered an urgent unjust attack on our country.
Speaker 0: and There's another issue of how we can convey our intention intentions if we don't understand what they are saying.
Speaker 0: We should consider various possibilities.
Speaker 0: There's no need to do this in the defense ministry But I want to consider what to do by myself.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah blah Yeah, I don't think this is a joke.
Speaker 0: and unless there's some crazy Mistranslation where he's using UFO in the correct sense to mean an Unidentified intrusion into Japanese airspace, which I don't think he is Then yeah Yeah, all I can say is that as bad as the u.s.
Speaker 1: Is and as stupid as a lot of our politicians are right the worst they do is like You know being corrupt or evil or bad or invade and occupy multiple foreign countries and that's great.
Speaker 1: But they they not you never get.
Speaker 1: Where's the last time you thought something stupid on this kind of stupid in the
Speaker 1: u.s.?
Speaker 0: All throughout the Cold War?
Speaker 0: Yeah in the Cold War all throughout the Cold War Not since then a lot a lot of craziness happened during Vietnam and also, you know I can argue and was during the Cold War Well near the end the Vietnam as a separate entity from the Cold War.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about the specific Subconflict.
Speaker 0: Mmm I mean when I say Cold War, I guess I meant the kind of high-level strategic ideals of the Cold War.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean like since you know The wall came down you never see like high up US government people saying anything.
Speaker 1: That's crazy bad shit on this kind of level.
Speaker 0: um I would argue that I would rather have this kind of level because if Rummy and all those people Were arguing about whether or not we should have a defense force capable of fighting off aliens Instead of say invading and occupying multiple foreign countries and hostile nations and such for no good reason.
Speaker 0: I I'd rather be arguing about the aliens.
Speaker 1: Is it better to have smart evil people in charge or stupid?
Speaker 1: Well-meaning people?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I don't know anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know right that's the dilemma.
Speaker 0: now I can make a high-level argument.
Speaker 1: at least our evil people aren't stupid.
Speaker 1: They're they're evil.
Speaker 1: They know what's going on.
Speaker 0: I would argue that intelligent people should consider all possibilities.
Speaker 1: and when considering I mean if I had a government I would have some sort of plan somewhere to file, you know, sure It doesn't hurt to write a plan if this crazy thing that's not impossible happens.
Speaker 0: The US is famous for that.
Speaker 0: the US has detailed plans for pretty much every possible world situation.
Speaker 0: Some of the plans might suck but we do this partly as a military exercise.
Speaker 0: It's something that you know students of military strategy You know as an assignment.
Speaker 0: The assignment will be something like you guys get together and come up with what to do if we suddenly needed to invade Canada because they had nukes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just cuz you know, the US makes a plan about everything.
Speaker 1: So sometimes people see that.
Speaker 1: Oh the US made a plan about this.
Speaker 1: That's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: No, it's just.
Speaker 1: they do make plans about everything.
Speaker 1: That's what they do.
Speaker 0: But now and intelligent people you have to consider the possibility of an unforeseen Alien threat and I say alien to mean on like completely unforeseeable alien in the absolute alien sense.
Speaker 0: But I think this guy is not taking it on that intellectual.
Speaker 1: no, he's definitely got a Marvin the Martian Thermal detonator kind of action.
Speaker 0: So he's only the second Japanese official in this cabinet to Argue about this.
Speaker 0: to quote chief cabinet secretary Nobutaka Machimura Personally, I believe they exist.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: all those Crazy conspiracy people, you know who are always yelling about aliens or whatever and they're always saying hey government release your documents that you know You've been hiding, right?
Speaker 1: Well, here's some guys high up in a government who have access to top-secret documents like that and they believe it's real.
Speaker 1: They're on your side.
Speaker 1: Yet where are these top-secret documents that they would be revealing to convince you that they aren't just full of shit?
Speaker 1: Oh, there aren't any because it's a crazy conspiracy and it's not real.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright, that's enough of that.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: I got okay, so There's a guy a guy you say Named Paul karison.
Speaker 1: Paul karison you say yes He has a disease from Oregon, but I think he moved to California now.
Speaker 0: Oh Okay, I think I know where you're going with this and he has a disease called Argyria.
Speaker 0: now you might this is somewhat famous for being the affliction of crazy Libertarian guy and various crazies.
Speaker 0: It really only affects crazy people and one lady who didn't know better.
Speaker 0: Yep
Speaker 1: so basically, you know, we like to talk in the show about homeopathy and homeopathy homeopathy and Acupuncture and whatever right and a lot of fake medicines, right and we always complain, you know Fake medicine is bad because someone will take the fake medicine and instead of real medicine and then they'll those get sick and die.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, somebody will you know, take the.
Speaker 1: you know They'll spend money on fake medicine and then some scamming person gets a bunch of money or you know.
Speaker 1: But as bad as homeopathy is as bad as acupuncture is.
Speaker 1: The worst that can happen with acupuncture is some evil scamming Acupuncturist who might even actually believe in it.
Speaker 1: get some money and you might get an infection from the needles.
Speaker 0: I mean the only possible thing beyond that would be if you refuse or didn't accept Real treatment from a real doctor in lieu of acupuncture, but that again your fault.
Speaker 1: Yep Homeopathy the worst that can happen.
Speaker 1: nothing unless you refuse other treatments and the homeopathists get money.
Speaker 0: I still love when James Randi to prove to Congress.
Speaker 0: There was bullshit basically ate like.
Speaker 0: he does that all the time Yeah, but he eats like 10,000 times the so-called lethal dose of homeopathic sleeping pills.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it says no side effects.
Speaker 1: He's like, oh, that's not that's true.
Speaker 1: No effects at all, huh?
Speaker 1: All right, but this guy Paul karison he believed in some other bullshit medicine.
Speaker 0: I will point out that colloidal silver Does have antibiotic properties.
Speaker 0: it does and it can be used for treatment and it was used a long time ago.
Speaker 0: However Treating yourself with this drug is a lot like treating yourself with ancient obsolete medicine.
Speaker 0: Even the crappiest modern antibiotic works a thousand times better and with a million less side effects.
Speaker 1: even penicillin Which doesn't really work so well anymore works a lot better than colloidal silver.
Speaker 1: colloidal silver at this point in time is Effectively useless and obsolete as a medicine.
Speaker 1: It would be like trying to use a 1 megahertz IBM ps1 to make web pages.
Speaker 1: It's just it's you don't do that.
Speaker 1: It's pointless.
Speaker 1: You're only gonna hurt yourself.
Speaker 1: So this guy he drank some colloidal silver and he also rubbed it onto his face to treat a skin problem.
Speaker 1: We know that's not even one of the things that colloidal silver can do Yeah, but rubbing it on the face also had no effect.
Speaker 0: I mean the guy's stupidity really showed in the video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically You know some doc some bullshit quack doctor, you know, they these people say that you know colloidal silica is everything except for Argyria which it causes Which they don't say.
Speaker 1: that this is a fairly well-known syndrome I guess since yeah any real doctor could would have said what the hell don't do that?
Speaker 1: What the fuck's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Basically what happens if you drink colloidal silver over a long period of time and not even you just drink enough of it?
Speaker 0: Well, it has to be over a long period of time.
Speaker 0: Usually yeah Usually like drinking a glass of colloidal silver water is not going to do this But it'll make you sick if I'm out.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it's not too good.
Speaker 0: Actually, I probably won't if I won't have any ill effects.
Speaker 0: poop silver not really basically, what it'll do is over time these silver ions and will Migrate throughout your body to your skin and then lodge themselves there and as a result you will turn blue.
Speaker 1: Yes, this guy has basically turned.
Speaker 0: My skin is blue for the last decade because I've known about this forever And I've always liked looking at pictures of people who were dumb enough to do this to themselves.
Speaker 0: But I've never seen someone with this much.
Speaker 1: this guy's apparently been drinking it forever And he's probably he might still be drinking it.
Speaker 1: I think oh he is.
Speaker 0: you realize in the video that the reporters like so you turn blue.
Speaker 0: Are you still drinking it?
Speaker 0: He's like hells.
Speaker 0: Yeah cures, whatever.
Speaker 1: And he also the guy refuses to go to a real doctor To seek treatment because a doctor could probably do something to.
Speaker 0: actually I believe that it is untreatable.
Speaker 1: once It's not totally it's partially treated like one lady who did it to herself Who actually realized that you know it was stupid afterwards and you know went to seek treatment and realized that the question was a quack And they were lying to her and it was bullshit.
Speaker 1: She went and they were able to like sort of scrape her skin some.
Speaker 1: so now she's sort of patchy instead of solid blue.
Speaker 1: Great, yeah, but basically this guy was getting all ostracized in Oregon so he moved to California Hopefully where he will be more accepted.
Speaker 1: Uh Yeah Even if I will accept I'm not gonna discriminate against someone because they have blue skin.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna discriminate someone because Blue skin tells me you're a moron who believes in quack medicines.
Speaker 1: You're probably a moron all around and I don't have anything to do with you because you're moron.
Speaker 1: Do you believe that silver is cares everything?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean silver is real nice.
Speaker 0: I like silver.
Speaker 0: I think it's my favorite precious semi-precious metal.
Speaker 1: It's not for drinking It's for making silverware Cups and fighting werewolves and plates and metal.
Speaker 1: Yes werewolves.
Speaker 1: That's what it's for.
Speaker 0: Don't drink silver It's not for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah things of the day.
Speaker 1: It's a holiday season.
Speaker 1: You know that?
Speaker 0: uh You know what.
Speaker 0: sadly I didn't notice it at all I don't you know.
Speaker 0: drive past malls and work in New York City and have to go buy that bell ringer Every single time I leave the Lincoln building.
Speaker 1: Yeah, dang it dang it dang it dang it dang it dang it dang it dang.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that guy's not getting my mom.
Speaker 0: actually he was gone today.
Speaker 0: He was the side and in his place with a tuba player.
Speaker 0: I was very happy The tuba player is help helping him love Christmas tuba players.
Speaker 0: I got to admit That's one of my favorite things walking around the city in holidays, but I thought you didn't like the Salvation Army.
Speaker 0: I don't like the salvation from the side army, but I like Christmas tuba players a lot.
Speaker 0: All right I just like tubas especially to boost tuba solos.
Speaker 1: You're joking.
Speaker 1: at work today One of my co-workers is all sick sneezing and coughing all over the place.
Speaker 1: so the guy was like you sound like a tuba.
Speaker 1: Go home ha.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so, you know we go people.
Speaker 1: they buy the Christmas cards or the holiday cards or whatever you fucking call.
Speaker 0: No, I haven't bought a holiday card in years either.
Speaker 1: I'm not a fan, but I didn't realize until today.
Speaker 1: It might be interesting to see some cards from other places besides the US, you know I thought you know cards in general were sort of a US thing, but I guess not.
Speaker 0: I know they're a very British thing.
Speaker 0: I think but people apparently in the United sorry in Albion People actually write letters in Christmas cards instead of just buying a card that has a pre-written poem and then signing their name.
Speaker 1: That's cuz.
Speaker 1: they know how to write.
Speaker 0: Oh snap Wow, that was kind of self-deprecating.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway Yeah, those smart people think they're so smart knowing how to write.
Speaker 0: might it might just be the accent.
Speaker 1: maybe Here is something extra cool.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 1: It's pretty simple.
Speaker 1: These is a gallery four pages worth of images that are Holiday cards from Soviet Russia.
Speaker 1: Oh, man They holiday.
Speaker 0: man Are they all?
Speaker 0: are they all what I think they are or are they all just normal?
Speaker 1: a lot of them have rockets on them.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, I really airplanes and cccps and planets and spaceships and cosmo All right, I got I think I got an idea.
Speaker 0: I think I got a really good idea.
Speaker 1: print them out and use them.
Speaker 0: I think what I'm gonna do cuz I got these contracts for printing shit for geek nights.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I should send these to them cuz even if the copyright isn't expired, whatever.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna the copyrights Russian.
Speaker 0: I don't think I need to worry and I'm totally gonna use those as Christmas cards forever more.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna start sending you guys are you have a hard time picking one out?
Speaker 1: Cuz there's a lot.
Speaker 0: I'll just print like 10 of each Go nut.
Speaker 1: But yet Soviet Russian Christmas cards.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is about Soviet Russian.
Speaker 0: everything that I like except I guess Soviet Russian politics as evil as Soviet Russia was.
Speaker 1: in reality their aesthetic style of the government art agency was high quality.
Speaker 0: I just in Soviet propaganda and Soviet architecture and I don't know why I like these things.
Speaker 0: so it's like the message of the But you know what I think it is art Awesome.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: what I think it is too is that if you look purely at the propaganda and the literature the fake you know the literature.
Speaker 0: that's not accurate.
Speaker 0: if communism worked the way people wanted it to like if it actually worked and if this idea of you know Collectively together all of us sort of if that were true and it really worked then that's pretty much the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think also for me It's that they they had such an emphasis like a countrywide emphasis on like science you know like big guy with a hammer and a gear and a and a rocket
Speaker 0: at least in theory and Somewhat in practice, but there was also the idea that if a rocket scientist screwed up He kind of disappeared which wasn't good.
Speaker 0: No, or if a scientist said something that kind of went against communism up.
Speaker 0: Yep It just shows you the people who are doing evil can still make good art, I guess on the side Yeah, but at the same time people with good intentions or I guess movements with good intentions do not always imply good results?
Speaker 1: No, not at all Right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day and we're probably gonna talk a lot more about these in the near future.
Speaker 0: But there is something called Ted Ideas worth spreading.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna link to it.
Speaker 0: It's basically an annual I think conference where smart people get together and lecture to other smart people.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I don't know how to go there, but I'd like to go I'd like to go Now.
Speaker 0: now you might be thinking.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah rim you totally want to present there.
Speaker 0: That's not gonna happen Are you kidding?
Speaker 0: These people are so much smarter than me.
Speaker 1: these people These are like the geniuses of the world like Nobel Prize winning level genius type people.
Speaker 0: I would I would pay a lot of money and spend a lot of vacation time to just go and listen because these These are amazing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but luckily they they.
Speaker 1: the rules at Ted or when you're giving your presentation, you know You're not allowed to sell anything.
Speaker 1: It's a non-commercial deal.
Speaker 1: And also the videos are all online.
Speaker 1: You can watch them so you don't really need to go.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is Probably of all the ones I've watched my favorite one and I doubt anything from this year is gonna top it.
Speaker 1: But this is you didn't watch the Bill Clinton one.
Speaker 1: Did you know shit?
Speaker 0: No, I didn't.
Speaker 1: Bill Clinton's my man Bill talks about the Rwanda's.
Speaker 0: Ah Cuz I read is I read about how we thought about the Rwanda's and if he says what I think he's gonna say I might cry.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll watch it after the show might have to but anyway With the possible exception of the one I haven't seen yet.
Speaker 1: There's like a hundred you haven't seen yet.
Speaker 0: Well the Bill Clinton one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not all of them are good.
Speaker 1: I watched a pretty bad one the other day.
Speaker 0: So well, was it bad in the sense that you disagree with it or was it bad in the sense?
Speaker 0: That was boring.
Speaker 1: I wasn't sure if I agreed or disagreed with it.
Speaker 1: I was sort of iffy cuz I didn't watch the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So I don't know.
Speaker 1: but the guy was not good at presenting But the guy in the video you're about to talk about was excellent at presenting.
Speaker 0: Holy crap Is this worth you watch?
Speaker 1: he has the public speaking skills of the awesome.
Speaker 0: He is a world famous neurologist.
Speaker 0: His name is Vileana or Ramachandran.
Speaker 0: I hope I pronounced that right.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna give it another try.
Speaker 0: I'll try.
Speaker 1: Vilean are Ramachandran.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this guy is real cool.
Speaker 0: We're in jeans leather jacket t-shirt kind of disheveled and he's like I said, he's a neurologist and I cannot describe this lecture other than Fascinating Absolutely fascinating and yet at the same time 100% accessible.
Speaker 0: you can know nothing about neuroscience Nothing about the brain nothing about psychology nothing about any of that.
Speaker 0: and yet you will understand what this man is saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah Watching the good videos on this website is like sitting in like the awesomest College classes because it reminds me of like, you know a college professor who didn't suck or every college professor Ever had who didn't suck where I'd sit in their class and just be like ah, man's the whole time.
Speaker 1: So this is this is worth, you know that these videos that you're available free online Be it that's like getting hundreds of thousands of dollars in college education for free.
Speaker 1: That's how quality this is.
Speaker 0: so I don't really want to spoil what he talks about really and I also feel like I couldn't do it justice, but he talks about a number of issues with the brain and he kind of explores Neuroscience from the sense of how do we study it?
Speaker 0: How do we know the things we know?
Speaker 0: and Basically he kind of brings it all together in the end and he seems he is fairly confident that he has found possibly the I'm being very vague here because I don't want to sound stupid the kind of the thing that makes humans humans the the structure in the brain that makes human consciousness on the level that we have it possible and The things he said are kind of revolutionary and amazing.
Speaker 1: He also talks about Bubo and Kiki.
Speaker 1: That's all.
Speaker 1: that's the amazing part.
Speaker 0: that part of the end is is so illustrative of everything that this lecture is about and it's kind Of amazing when he gets to the end and he pulls it all together.
Speaker 1: It's so obvious like you always knew.
Speaker 1: but you don't know.
Speaker 0: think about that.
Speaker 0: you He'll say it and you'll think wow Yeah That makes sense.
Speaker 0: But then he points out that that making sense is crazy.
Speaker 0: The fact that that can make sense is what makes humans humans and that all of that takes place in this part of the brain Called the fusiform gyrus.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, man You don't want.
Speaker 1: let me tell you the one thing I learned from this video If you have to lose any part of your brain do not pick the fusiform gyrus lose any other part first.
Speaker 0: It is very important that you remember this in the future.
Speaker 1: fusiform gyrus most important part of brain.
Speaker 1: Fusiform gyrus for the way even if you're like, I don't know about that I'm not a neuroscientist But it is the part of my brain that if I had to choose which one to lose last I would pick that one.
Speaker 0: Now knowing what I know, I think I would give up most of my senses before I would give up my fusiform gyrus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much or even part of my fusiform gyrus.
Speaker 0: God.
Speaker 0: Luckily.
Speaker 0: It's way in the middle.
Speaker 1: Yep It's in the safest spot for a reason.
Speaker 0: Alright, but I cannot stress this enough.
Speaker 0: you it.
Speaker 0: this thing's like 35 minutes long.
Speaker 0: It is worth every.
Speaker 0: you got nothing better to do.
Speaker 1: if you're what are you gonna do for 35 minutes?
Speaker 1: listen to geek nights.
Speaker 1: What the hell's wrong?
Speaker 0: This is I. I feel like a richer person for having watched this.
Speaker 1: Oh, definitely Definitely.
Speaker 1: Alright, so So copping out we did.
Speaker 1: we miss two Thursday shows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've been busy lately and we're gonna get a lot busier.
Speaker 0: You're lucky.
Speaker 0: We're doing a show tonight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was gonna go to sleep right about now.
Speaker 0: See basically and I was inspired to have this idea cuz I was listening to my backlog of fast karate And they were having some issues with Dave moving around and they kind of did a short State of the podcast address and I thought about that and I realized that we used to talk about the show from this meta Perspective a lot more early on and we stopped doing that because there's yeah, that's really not that interesting to new listeners.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hate
Speaker 1: talking about the show in the show I mean because while people who are already listeners want to hear us talk about the show in the show, you know And then stuff like that it you know for if someone's a new listener They they pit they turn on the podcast They start listening to us talk about ourselves and they're just like they don't.
Speaker 1: they totally have no connection with that.
Speaker 1: That's why all we always try to talk about you know the news is the things of the day and the topic and not try to talk about ourselves because I mean other than Our leader bit.
Speaker 0: but even then that's more like an anecdote.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that that only thing happened on the way to the forum.
Speaker 1: Yeah But that'll just make people tune out and we want you to tune in as much as possible except unless you're gonna go watch Viamar Ramachand, then you should tune out.
Speaker 0: so at the same time I feel like every now and then it is kind of important to talk about what we're doing here and where we're going with all this crap and Every time we think oh crap.
Speaker 0: It's Thursday.
Speaker 0: We don't have a show to do.
Speaker 0: in the back of my mind I always think we could talk about the show and then I think but wait a minute.
Speaker 0: It's too soon I don't want to do that all the time and I realized today that I've been saying that for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually I don't even think about talking about the show because it's.
Speaker 1: it's so automatically Discounted as an idea that it doesn't even come up in my mind.
Speaker 1: But rim brought it up and I said, you know what?
Speaker 0: Okay, whatever It's easy to do and actually there's a lot to talk about.
Speaker 1: I feel like the show is the show.
Speaker 1: We're in the third season now, right?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: We are well into the third season.
Speaker 0: So well over 400 episodes of this business.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: So I'm sort of getting the feeling now that there's a lot of things where the statute of limitations Have run out and we can sort of talk about them again even if we've talked about them before as long as there has been a Long as we're gonna say something significantly different
Speaker 0: plus work.
Speaker 0: There have been a couple of I guess points of change or linchpins in the I guess time scale of geek nights like when we first got a mixer and it was it went from To an actual show and then you know We got a compressor and I learned about audio and then when we got a better compressor in a Maran.
Speaker 0: Like there have been these points not just audio wise but like when we decided on a show format when we changed the show format when we decided to go with multiple feeds when we decided to start doing live shows at cons like all these times where we
Speaker 1: We added the geek bites.
Speaker 1: We added the geek backs.
Speaker 0: We took away things.
Speaker 0: we change things.
Speaker 0: We tried.
Speaker 0: I remember our first thing of the day music that epic failure that it was.
Speaker 1: I was I liked it a lot but listeners didn't.
Speaker 0: I spent like four hours making that happen.
Speaker 0: We tried it once everyone hated it never used it again.
Speaker 1: We should use it again in this episode.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna cuz I don't even know where it is.
Speaker 0: It's in like my my stupid like flack archive on the offline hard drive.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna go get that thing out.
Speaker 0: But actually in terms of everything that geek nights is we're kind of on a major cusp here Like I think in terms of what we do here.
Speaker 0: We're on the point of taking it to the next level.
Speaker 1: I think so I mean right now.
Speaker 1: Well, first of all, we've done a sort of you know Contests in the past and there's someone who famously keeps bothering us about one of them.
Speaker 1: Yep, and You know, we've never quite made prizes or swag even though a lot of people who do a lot less than us have prizes and swag, so we're actually Months away from having swag probably by February.
Speaker 0: We've got multiple artists.
Speaker 0: We've got an e-commerce solution.
Speaker 0: We're working on Mostly Scott.
Speaker 0: that's kind of like.
Speaker 0: we kind of yeah Like, you know if there were like the credits of geek nights the producer or whatever though Whatever Scott and I have kind of divvy that up all 50/50.
Speaker 0: So Scott's Drive right now is all the e-commerce crap.
Speaker 0: We have to put together before we can actually sell stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let me tell you e-commerce sucks ass.
Speaker 1: there's a reason people are using like eBay and cafe press cuz.
Speaker 0: doing anything else is a pain in the ass and My side now of this is dealing with the artists and getting them to finish our business.
Speaker 0: Yep, but you know what?
Speaker 0: It's equally difficult, right?
Speaker 1: But as soon it where it's not get we are gonna do it.
Speaker 1: We are closer than we've ever been to this.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna give any sort of definite date, but I ain't gonna guarantee that it will happen.
Speaker 1: I will guarantee that even if even if we all die.
Speaker 1: Well, not if we all die.
Speaker 1: That's the only thing that will stop from happening.
Speaker 0: if both Scott and I die Then it won't happen.
Speaker 0: But otherwise at the same time if only one of us dies Then another person will fill in and then if the other one of us dies It'll be geek nights with Joey Jojo and Shabba doo, right?
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's.
Speaker 1: it's gonna happen soonish.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get you nice leg for the holidays, but there will be a nice swag soon of some sort.
Speaker 1: That will also mean that there'll be prizes for anyone who's ever won a prize.
Speaker 1: I know we had a contest like a words podcast contest, right?
Speaker 0: We've got a list of a lot of people who are gonna believe you have a list.
Speaker 0: I do you know.
Speaker 0: my list is if I search for a certain couple of words in Gmail I have a list of all the people I promised prizes to that have ever ever Bothered me about it.
Speaker 0: If anyone ever emailed us or me and said hey, where's my prize?
Speaker 0: I have a filter that just lists all those emails.
Speaker 0: Cuz I added him to that every time I saw one.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, so I have a list of all the people who have bothered me about a prize.
Speaker 0: So if you're owed a prize and you've never bothered me now is your time to bother me or geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yep, and we'll I guess what we're gonna do is we're gonna go through that list of people who deserve prizes and you know Whatever and then we'll you know, we'll verify that all those prizes are really things we want to award and whatever.
Speaker 1: Alright, so that's that's the first thing that's going on.
Speaker 1: the second thing I'm finally redoing the website, you know basically I've.
Speaker 1: we've tried a bunch of times to get web designers or other people to help us out because I want a slick web 2.0 Website that you know looks professional on man web 3.0 semantic web.
Speaker 1: I know right but That sort of failed.
Speaker 1: like anyone who's actually high quality at that Doesn't want to do our dinky little job because it's just a dinky little job.
Speaker 0: and all the people who have given us awesome designs Either disappeared or never followed through or those designs were awesome, but infeasible.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like how my mom needed the basement stairs fixed, right?
Speaker 1: So she wanted to hire a carpenter but none of the carpenters would do it because this job was too small.
Speaker 1: But all the like that, you know, they're just the guys who happen to know how to do it.
Speaker 1: You know small-time guys, they wouldn't do it because they weren't you know, they weren't real carpenters.
Speaker 1: They didn't actually follow through and do the work.
Speaker 1: So it took her a long time to actually find someone to do it.
Speaker 1: now I realized that you know, I'm I designed the current well I sort of stole parts of someone else's design and then you know combined it with my CSS skills to make the current design.
Speaker 1: If I recruit calm and the forum is you know, the default forum theme, which I'm not gonna change And you know, it's I think it's terrible but apparently a lot of people don't think it's that bad at all.
Speaker 1: So my skills at that have increased.
Speaker 1: they'd have an increased enough to where I can make fancy web 2.0 websites that look great.
Speaker 1: But they've increased quite a bit and I've I think I've got something that's gonna work out.
Speaker 1: So probably in a few weeks I'll have that you know polished up enough to put it on the site and then they'll probably still be some more polishing afterwards.
Speaker 1: But we're gonna have the website.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be better than it is now and it's gonna be easier for you to do stuff And there's gonna be a lot more information on it.
Speaker 0: Yep and pursuant to that There are going to be a lot more feeds a lot more ways to get geek nights a lot more ways to customize how you get geek nights for what you want to Listen to a lot more ways to integrate other business with geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean we're gonna.
Speaker 1: probably you know right now all we have is the Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday in the total feed.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be a lot more stuff besides that.
Speaker 0: well, there's the experimental feed.
Speaker 1: No, that's right.
Speaker 1: this experimental feed We're gonna add in the supplemental feed, right?
Speaker 0: Yep That's gonna be anytime cuz we've been appearing semi regularly now on Friday night party line and we've appeared on other shows in the past.
Speaker 0: So I think anytime we appear on any sort of media out there We're gonna link to it.
Speaker 0: and if it's something that we can link to that's audio We're gonna have a feed that'll let you just download whatever shows were on.
Speaker 0: So if we're on anime world order for whatever reason you'll just you'll see that episode of anime world order with us in it In that feed.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We should also like we should keep our current total geek nights feed.
Speaker 1: Right is just you know, every episode of geek nights the last hundred of them at least.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should have a total rim and scott feed also.
Speaker 1: that in you know Sort of like the supplemental plus the experimental plus the we'll have some sort of like the geek nights uber feed.
Speaker 0: that has everything.
Speaker 1: We're gonna have all kinds of feeds.
Speaker 1: So no matter what kind of geek nights listener you are You'll have something that'll you.
Speaker 1: you'll have some combination of feeds that will provide you with The stuff you want to listen to and only the stuff you want to.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean one thing too that I really want to get going because it wasn't an issue right away.
Speaker 0: But now that we have so many episodes it's getting to the point where there is no feed that has some of our earliest earliest episodes on it because Having more than a hundred anythings in a feed causes problems.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So we're probably gonna have archival feeds too.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not.
Speaker 1: there's nothing wrong with RSS technology that prevents there from being so many feeds.
Speaker 1: it's mostly a limitation of WordPress where if I want to have feeds with a bajillion items in then I have to go into WordPress and say yeah put like a bajillion items in this feed, you know, there has to be a number.
Speaker 1: I can't just say infinity.
Speaker 1: I have to set a number plus.
Speaker 1: I have to keep changing that number plus.
Speaker 0: the feed gets bigger and more unwieldy and different readers crap out at different sizes.
Speaker 0: And it's just.
Speaker 0: it's not Plus.
Speaker 0: if anything ever happens and you like your feed reader screws up expect to download 800 episodes of gig nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why I never.
Speaker 1: I don't recommend I don't and I don't recommend anyone else allow their pod catchers to automatically download episodes on Their own or at least more than like a set number like never more than five.
Speaker 1: or yeah it's like I use iTunes and what I do is I update the feeds and then all the new episodes appear and I push get Next to every episode.
Speaker 1: because sometimes, you know I don't listen to every episode of every podcast only click get on the ones I want to listen to and I delete the ones I don't before even downloading them.
Speaker 1: and I I think that is the way that people should manage their podcast.
Speaker 0: So we talked a lot of us.
Speaker 1: it helps us out because then we know, you know If you download every episode automatically and only listen to half we don't know that we see that you downloaded every episode.
Speaker 1: So we can only assume you listen to all of them.
Speaker 1: So only download the ones are you listen to?
Speaker 0: but also we talked a lot about having DVDs of like DVD season 1 DVD season 2 and higher quality and all this and that is Currently not super feasible.
Speaker 0: Like I don't feel like it's worth it.
Speaker 1: We that was something we actually came pretty close to.
Speaker 0: Completing the DVD is done in terms of the fact that we have it.
Speaker 0: We have it all.
Speaker 0: just actually making it and printing it and finishing it up.
Speaker 0: It's like to have the little website that would come with it be perfect Would take more effort than I think it's worth.
Speaker 0: I don't think enough of you want DVDs of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the DVD probably isn't gonna happen because you know sure we could you know Put geek nights every all the episodes on a DVD and sell the DVDs or whatever.
Speaker 1: But in order to make DVDs, it's not something we can do on demand We'd have to print a whole bunch of them and to have you know If you did that we want to have nice covers on the DVDs little cases, you know.
Speaker 1: And we'd want to put you know other extras on the DVD.
Speaker 1: But the it would take like two DVDs just to do season one.
Speaker 1: So at this point it would be like five DVDs for all of geek nights and that becomes Ludicrously expensive ludicrously difficult.
Speaker 0: It's a pain in the ass You know, and I don't think the demand is there except I don't think the demand is very.
Speaker 1: I think the demand is very high Among a very small number of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah dial-up users.
Speaker 1: Yeah dial-up users.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I don't think the geek nights DVD is gonna happen.
Speaker 1: You might again see Some sort of geek nights promotional CDs at a convention or something.
Speaker 1: But other than that Don't wait on those DVDs.
Speaker 1: that I'm sort of sad because I told myself way back in the day that you know So many webcomics and podcasts and other internet, you know artists of sorts Promised things and they don't come through on them.
Speaker 1: and I said that's not gonna be me I'm gonna come through on the promises not gonna make any promises I don't come through on and I feel like I feel like I promised the DVD even though I don't know if I actually did But I feel like I did and we're not gonna come through on it.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, ah, so but for now on no more shit-talking.
Speaker 0: Now in terms of actual geek nights production, you know how we make the show how we do the show How we record it all that sort of technical stuff.
Speaker 0: My room is turned slowly more and more into a relatively Usable studio because you have a knob fetish yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: and we I've been acquiring equipment and things over the years and also ever since we did the show at katsu khan last year where we brought all of our equipment and we set it up and we routed all the audio for the whole video game area into our stuff.
Speaker 0: and I've learned a lot since then.
Speaker 0: and in terms of production values I think we've gotten to the point where I'm.
Speaker 0: we're jumping from amateur to professional in terms of our equipment Will be once I get this mixer going and I get the box and all the routing and everything set up.
Speaker 0: We're going to have a fully professional rig that would be capable of recording an entire Band like a rock band or whatever we wanted.
Speaker 0: We've got everything now and be portable.
Speaker 0: Yes It'll actually be in despite the fact that this mixer is ginormous
Speaker 1: And I hate saying I know
Speaker 0: you know what it's so big that the word is warranted
Speaker 1: uh-huh,
Speaker 0: but it's still a lot more portable sadly and we're gonna be set up in relatively short order to where we can record a lot of people in our studio at the same time and do all sorts of roundtables and Multi interviews and like group interviews over Skype and all these sorts of things Trivially.
Speaker 0: so expect a lot more roundtable discussions a lot more interviews.
Speaker 0: We've actually got a lot of interviews that were lined up and just put on hold because it wasn't easy to do an interview quickly.
Speaker 1: I mean we've in the past We have actually tried to do some interviews that fell through.
Speaker 1: like the only time we've really done Skype action is when someone else is recording and we were skyping them, you know, yeah I mean we were supposed to interview Jim Vowles and that failed because the Mac failed us.
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway, you know we net with this new mixer.
Speaker 1: I think well rim will finally be motivated to set up the Skype and We'll have be able to have a lot more microphones in the room that all work properly.
Speaker 1: So I gotta have a lot more podcasts that are more than just.
Speaker 1: you know The usual geek nights us to talk about stuff and I think that's very necessary Because if you haven't noticed we're sort of running out of things to talk about.
Speaker 0: well only on Wednesdays and full Thursdays days.
Speaker 0: and well Wednesdays we were running out until I read comics again.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if we start watching anime again Wednesday, I'll be okay.
Speaker 1: I think we'll start watching anime again the new year.
Speaker 1: I have a strong feeling that the new year is gonna be anime season because I still have a bunch of video games, but I'm probably gonna blow through those during the holiday season and I got a bunch of comics on the floor But I'll probably blow through those in the holiday season also and then after that it's anime from and there to the horizon.
Speaker 0: I can say this once all this is set up and going you might think how could the audio be better than it is?
Speaker 0: It sounds pretty good, which I think it does.
Speaker 0: I think we're one of the best sounding podcasts out there.
Speaker 1: Well, I think a lot of people seen are you really?
Speaker 1: You know, it sounds okay, but most people seem to say it sounds really good.
Speaker 0: So, all right well, I mean having listened to other podcasts and listen to the radio a lot in the past and that sort of thing and I Mean, I'm perfectly frank.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna beat around the bush other than you know twit and the super professional podcast.
Speaker 0: I think we're one of the best sounding podcasts out there.
Speaker 0: audio wise.
Speaker 1: Well, I think you're just sort of obsessed with the audio quality so much.
Speaker 0: And the thing is a lot of people said early on and don't worry about it No one cares.
Speaker 0: but or oh, we can't tell it.
Speaker 0: a lot of people say like when we first got the new compressor Oh, I can't tell the difference, but I made an extra for the DVD that I'm gonna put in the experimental feed at some point.
Speaker 0: I might remake it once I've used the new mixer and it basically took clips of geek nights continuously from the first episode.
Speaker 0: so the most recent episode just seamlessly integrated and You hear the audio quality just kind of gradually get better and then at the end it played like just a midpoint like a third of the way through geek nights and then the most recent episode and You couldn't really hear the difference.
Speaker 0: so well If when the gradual changes, but when the newest episode and an old episode were next to each other It was like night and day.
Speaker 0: It was crazy and I played it for other people and like wow
Speaker 1: Yep, and we'll probably add to that, you know some new mixer episodes and such
Speaker 0: I think it's I think geek nights after all this new stuff is set up is going to be Exactly as professional sounding as is possible with 96 kilobit per second.
Speaker 0: mp3 is on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yep Okay.
Speaker 1: Oh also I'm what I forgot.
Speaker 1: what are you gonna say?
Speaker 1: I was gonna say something that I forgot it.
Speaker 1: So keep talking I'll remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could turn that into an outtake but I don't feel like editing.
Speaker 0: I'm tired and I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Um right now, you know, we made this experimental feed.
Speaker 1: A lot of people like put more stuff in there blood just cuz you know When people see a feed and it doesn't have stuff constantly in it They sort of we.
Speaker 1: we made no promises about how much stuff would be in there.
Speaker 1: So screw you.
Speaker 1: Alright, we only promise that there's gonna be stuff in all the other feeds and there is.
Speaker 1: so, you know Compare us to your mega Tokyo's and then you know, you should feel good.
Speaker 1: Don't be complaining You know, and we're like mega Tokyo then you can complain.
Speaker 0: but man geek night sucks and I'm sad all the time.
Speaker 1: yeah, actually the reason that there isn't a lot of stuff the experimental feed the primary reason is because We podcast as much as Libsyn can allow.
Speaker 0: Yes, we are actually see, you know when I said we're getting professional audio in a lot of ways Like the whole geek nights operation is kind of at the point where we either have to go professional.
Speaker 0: now That doesn't mean live off of it.
Speaker 0: full-time job Don't even.
Speaker 1: that's not not quitting my job.
Speaker 0: That's one my jobs awesome and two.
Speaker 0: that is so not on the horizon.
Speaker 1: unless you guys Collectively send me enough money to equal my annual salary I'll tell you what inside of like a month.
Speaker 0: I'm not quitting if you if geek nights if you guys can get to us $150,000 a year before taxes.
Speaker 0: then we'll quit our jobs and podcast full-time.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's a lot of podcasting that is that's.
Speaker 0: that's pretty much I would.
Speaker 0: you would get four times as much heat nights that way because you realize that if Podcasting or something like this was my full-time job It's kind of like Howard Stern whatever you might feel about the guy the guy it loves radio.
Speaker 0: He's obsessed with radio.
Speaker 0: He's a radio file and that man because it's his job.
Speaker 0: There's a reason there's like eight hours of Howard Stern every day because he just does it all the time because he loves doing it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and we would probably do something similar.
Speaker 1: He can fill a lot of those eight hours with commercials and other people talking.
Speaker 1: so it's it's easier for him.
Speaker 1: They would be for us.
Speaker 0: He's got a whole staff sitting there telling him stuff while he's doing the show.
Speaker 0: It's kind of crazy Yeah, but in terms of everything else like not counting living off of it, but in terms of how we handle geek nights We're really at the point where it's either going to be a professional operation in every sense of the word from this point forward or it's not gonna happen anymore and I feel like we're going in the professional direction.
Speaker 0: We're all professional equipment.
Speaker 0: now We treat it professionally and in terms of our industry relations.
Speaker 0: We are treated professionally now.
Speaker 0: I mean when I submit things to do a like a live show at a convention somewhere.
Speaker 0: It's not Oh, yes, you want to be a panelist here?
Speaker 0: it's I'll forward you to the handler for guest relations or the live programming whatever guy and We don't.
Speaker 0: we're not really.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to I mean, I don't want it.
Speaker 0: I'm not trying to say like oh, we're so awesome.
Speaker 1: But it's more like yes, you are You're just trying to say in a disguised manner.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to not appear to be a bragger at which you are.
Speaker 0: I am a bragger, but I'm trying to say is that we're from this point forward.
Speaker 0: I feel like that the geek nights operation is going to be a professional operation and that our The way we handle everything from our website to our relations with all of you To the email to the forum to the to everything is going to be a lot more professional starting in the new year
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm
Speaker 0: and for good or ill that's the direction we're going.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I don't think.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 1: I don't think people who are fans of geek nights Now are gonna suddenly be like, ah geek night sold out blood.
Speaker 1: That's that's not gonna.
Speaker 0: well professional does not mean making money.
Speaker 1: Well, no, but I don't think anything is gonna happen to where people who are fans now are gonna turn on us.
Speaker 0: I think what it means is that the show is going to get a lot more Streamlined and a lot more solid as time goes on.
Speaker 0: there's gonna be fewer missed episodes.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be fewer episodes where rims coffin in the background or I don't know.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna go get that larynx surgery or not?
Speaker 0: No, because I got you realize that I can get rid of all the coughing with this new.
Speaker 0: I got a mute button.
Speaker 0: I got a cough button.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Is there one on that mixer thing?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Is it a noiseless button?
Speaker 0: Yes So I could.
Speaker 0: I could.
Speaker 0: it's it's great But it's also just the fact that you know in terms of when I say we're being professional.
Speaker 0: what it means more is that When we started doing the show we had this idea of well if we don't like this or it doesn't work out We're just gonna stop.
Speaker 0: we are I think right now at the point of no return.
Speaker 0: There's no way we could stop doing geek nights and ever be satisfied for the rest of our lives.
Speaker 1: Well anything, you know the stats we have to track the number of listeners and such is very unreliable.
Speaker 1: But if you look at the graph right the graph continues to go up.
Speaker 1: It's not going up at some exponential rate.
Speaker 1: it's sort of going up a little by a little but it's always up and I guess as long as it goes up for semi obligated to continue.
Speaker 1: I mean if it went down then we could be like, oh, I guess we're doing bad let's just yeah, but but I guess to sum all that up cuz that was kind of a rambling rant partly cuz I'm really hungry, but What do you want to eat?
Speaker 0: gig nights is pretty much to the moon or bust at this point?
Speaker 0: And we are not going to stop.
Speaker 0: if what it would take for us to stop doing geek nights would be ludicrous at this point Oh god rim just got shot in the head.
Speaker 0: Ah, oh my fusiform gyrus.
Speaker 0: But now what that me and I?
Speaker 0: the reason I realize this is that about three months ago Scott and I decided that Starting with season three for three or six months a temporary thing.
Speaker 0: We were gonna cut back on geek nights.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, it was hard to come up with show ideas and we were.
Speaker 0: we were kind of at our maximal creative output.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were.
Speaker 1: we needed a break really and we said alright What if we just did two episodes a week - and then - the other - like Monday Wednesday in the next week could do Tuesday Thursday
Speaker 0: and alternate and then we were gonna do that for like three months and then we'd and it wouldn't be like we'll do This until we're better.
Speaker 0: It was gonna be like we'll do this for this number of weeks and then it will be back to the show as normal on To this date, so there's no way to back out.
Speaker 1: I thought it would be something more like, you know, we we could transition to doing just two of the episodes a week.
Speaker 1: So it would still be doing the four shows but you know half as many of each show.
Speaker 1: But also we take up that extra Libsyn and use it to do other things like more experimental feed more other stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe maybe make a new show.
Speaker 1: who knows part
Speaker 0: of it also was really just to go in other directions for all not just in terms of the podcast itself, but other things we can do because What kind of happened to us is that I think there is only so much that a human being can do in a day.
Speaker 0: or just like the output you can have is limited unless you're Osamu Tezuka and between our jobs and Our blogs which you noticed neither of us had posted in in a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah and geek nights and Board gaming and all the things we have to do to have things to talk about on geek nights It got to the point where I literally had zero free time for like a month straight.
Speaker 0: Yeah like there was it.
Speaker 0: there was a whole month where my life was nothing but work geek nights things for geek nights and then like Trying desperately to work on all my other projects and failing and I think we're we're kind of at our maximal creative out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I wanted to use geek nights as a platform for other projects But instead geek nights sort of ate up all the available resources for all the projects.
Speaker 1: So it's like I need you need to do.
Speaker 1: I need it as the platform But then again if it takes up all the resources like I've used all my all my you know Wood to build a platform and now I know I have no wood left to build the house on the platform.
Speaker 0: So our choice at that point was either to Basically do what it takes to make the show professional enough to where we will be able to do it with less effort with less maintenance with less time cost.
Speaker 0: and That required a significant investment.
Speaker 0: because pretty much up to this point.
Speaker 0: We've invested very little money in geek nights.
Speaker 0: We've pretty much played it by the skin of our teeth.
Speaker 0: I mean the Marantz cost more than everything else we'd ever bought.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much and like when we bought new microphones it was like holy shit jacket.
Speaker 0: now Like to get beyond the diminishing returns.
Speaker 0: to get to the next step in terms of streamlining our operation Required a somewhat substantial Financial investment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think for it to get any better than it is Now we'd have to hire an employee and that's not out of the realm at this point.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 1: You don't have enough money though.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends because I could see scenarios where that could work out.
Speaker 0: But basically We've decided to go a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: so we're now investing substantial Sums of money relative to our incomes in geek nights Which means if geek nights fails it is through no lack of effort or investment.
Speaker 0: No So as a result We are able to defray a lot of our time costs by spending money and as a result I think you're gonna see a lot as a result of time I did.
Speaker 0: we're gonna see a lot more coming out of us in the next year.
Speaker 1: Hopefully.
Speaker 0: if you don't that means we're just shit talkers and I the new mixer didn't get me anything and we failed at everything in Life, I only stand by the things I said.
Speaker 0: I Have big dreams.
Speaker 1: what on for the record?
Speaker 1: I'm not a shit talker if I don't do the things.
Speaker 1: room said I would do.
Speaker 0: cuz you know What did I say you would do?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I said we'll try.
Speaker 1: I'm just.
Speaker 1: I don't want anyone give me grief for not doing something.
Speaker 1: Someone else said I would do.
Speaker 1: I'm the only who makes promises for me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, kind of like how the prize situation is pretty much entirely in my realm right now.
Speaker 0: exactly exactly Yeah, but at the same time the website is entirely in your realm.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: what did I should talk though?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it kind of works out now It's kind of like.
Speaker 0: I mean I handle one thing Scott handles the other thing.
Speaker 0: like when I like I'll just email Scott every now And then and say hey, we're doing these live shows at katsu khan.
Speaker 0: He says, okay, and then he'll email me.
Speaker 0: This is what the website's gonna look like and I say, okay Yeah, yeah That's it's just the way it's gonna have to be.
Speaker 0: So I guess the state of the podcast is good.
Speaker 0: good not stopping.
Speaker 1: Yeah better than other podcasts.
Speaker 1: I think so Yeah, and considering a lot of podcasts bigger than I seem to be going a little downhill.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that could be bad for podcasts as a whole though.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the thing is we have plans for that.
Speaker 0: that I'm not gonna talk about now because we've gone on forever and once I've Said this before but I'm really hungry.
Speaker 0: But we have plans to invest in not so much promoting ourselves because we've never really promoted ourselves substantially accepted
Speaker 1: conventions is a
Speaker 0: yep, but we have plans to invest in promoting the idea of podcasting as a whole and Regardless of if any other podcasters are on board with this.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I think that's what's really necessary is like, you know, Nintendo did the same thing.
Speaker 1: They said huh?
Speaker 1: We don't need to sell wheeze even though they succeeded at that and DS's they need to.
Speaker 1: you know There are people out there who don't buy video games.
Speaker 1: We need to get them to buy video games first.
Speaker 1: It's like we don't need to get more geek nights listeners.
Speaker 1: We need to get more people to listen to podcast period.
Speaker 1: then we can get more geek nights listeners.
Speaker 0: So expect Inroads in that direction in the coming next several months, maybe a year.
Speaker 0: That's not a short-term plan.
Speaker 1: Also, why not everyone out there?
Speaker 1: It's holiday season.
Speaker 1: You're gonna meet your relatives.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see your friends.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see your families, whatever.
Speaker 1: Make sure that everyone, you know everyone you see on the holidays all your families and friends.
Speaker 1: Make sure they know the reality of podcasting.
Speaker 1: They know what it is and Maybe find them a podcast they'll be interested in and get people to listen to podcasts.
Speaker 0: We're not saying tell them to listen to geek night.
Speaker 0: No We're saying make sure they know.
Speaker 0: unless you think they'll like geek night make sure your World War two buff Grandpa knows that there are like a hundred World War two podcasts and he can listen to them whenever he wants.
Speaker 1: Yep, make sure you know your Mom your grandma who's knitting and your aunt who's baking.
Speaker 1: listen to the baking podcast and the knitting podcast.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: on that note the state of the podcast is hungry and I'm gonna stop now.
Speaker 1: Okay good.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.