Speaker 0: It's Wednesday March 28th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek night.
Speaker 0: tonight We review the first volume of Keiko Takemiya's to Tara.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So a while ago we decided to have a couple of contests here at geek night since we had a bunch of various free stuff to lay around and We thought it'd be fun.
Speaker 0: and one of those contests Which is over is relevant to tonight.
Speaker 0: And I must say you guys really disappointed in terms of telling us about the worst anime ever.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: are people just not paying attention to?
Speaker 1: people want contests.
Speaker 1: Do you not want contests?
Speaker 0: Well, we got a lot of entries But I'll be honest the entries were all pretty crap or didn't really follow the rules so much or didn't actually do what we asked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're you know.
Speaker 1: while there were you know some entries there weren't a lot compared to how many people I know We're out there listening to this also compared to the Thursday night contest which got more quality entries than I know how to deal with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what the hell guys?
Speaker 1: maybe we just won't give out a prize because everyone lost.
Speaker 0: I just don't think anyone's actually seen that much bad anime Or if they have they don't obviously have the ability to write effectively about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when we say hey, we want you to write something and you just say yeah, this anime was pretty bad That does that's that?
Speaker 0: no I suppose I didn't want to have to say that.
Speaker 0: I guess grammar counts.
Speaker 0: some of them are just not readable and some of them it.
Speaker 1: It's like you didn't even write a paragraph.
Speaker 1: most of these things are less than two sentences.
Speaker 1: now compare I was and if I was gonna enter this contest I would have written a multi paragraph essay.
Speaker 0: now compare They expected to Thursday night where not only we get a ton of entries for the worst podcast in the world contest But a few of the entries pushed the one or two page mark.
Speaker 0: They wrote diatribes about how bad these things were with examples.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what you got to do people.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get free stuff without doing some work here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we're gonna go through them, but if no one gave us a good entry We're not gonna give you the MD guy soundtrack.
Speaker 0: No well mail you something maybe but it's not gonna be MD guys.
Speaker 0: No, it's too good for you.
Speaker 1: Well, it's pretty bad.
Speaker 1: Maybe they'll be.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually look at all the entries and with a lot of time and care.
Speaker 1: So maybe there is one in there, that's good enough, and we can give them the empty guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I don't know I gotta go look.
Speaker 0: so in the news you can't have ten years of Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Actually you have a lot more than ten years of Pokemon.
Speaker 0: well in April the TV show Pokemon that indoctrinated millions of young children around the world into the wonderful fantastic world of marketing is Gonna be ten years old.
Speaker 1: now think about that.
Speaker 1: the Pokemon TV show is ten years old.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: the Gameboy game is older, and the manga is older, so Pokemon is real old.
Speaker 0: Thing is though.
Speaker 0: They're not that much older.
Speaker 0: It surprises me in one that Wow Pokemon came out a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I feel old, but then at the same time Wow Pokemon wasn't around nearly as long as I feel like it was.
Speaker 1: well see the thing is Pokemon came out in the mid to late 90s and it's the mid to late 2000. so all that stuff that came out around then is becoming a decade old and it's kind of scary.
Speaker 0: But when I was in when I first got to RIT I remember you know you think back when I was a freshman in college to When Pokemon was around or whatever and I couldn't imagine a time in my life where there was no Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I couldn't fathom the idea that there was once a time when I never heard of Pikachu.
Speaker 1: I Can because there was such a time when I was no one who is born from here on out.
Speaker 1: in Western society We'll be able to do so let alone Eastern society.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe North Korea.
Speaker 0: They might not know about Pokemon.
Speaker 1: I mean, I just saw a picture yesterday of an airplane with Pokemon like paint job on it or a giant Pokemon decal.
Speaker 1: I couldn't tell which.
Speaker 1: well just the other day right on the plane you get Pokemon stuff.
Speaker 0: just the other day We were playing Smash Brothers since it's the best game on the Wii right now And I used Pikachu like three times.
Speaker 1: yeah, cuz you like to use Pikachu because yes, he's super cheap.
Speaker 1: He is that lightning that comes down from the sky so no one can attack you from above.
Speaker 1: they can only attack you from the Against mediocre players.
Speaker 0: Pikachu is cheap and amazing against anyone knows what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Pikachu is kind of useless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just the thing is if someone else is Pikachu you can't come at them from above because he'll drop the lightning on you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I'm playing against people who actually know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: I almost always use Falco.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, you're not.
Speaker 1: we're not that good at that game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, most I'm better than you.
Speaker 1: No, you're not.
Speaker 1: most people who know what they're doing at the game kick both our asses though real hard.
Speaker 1: We don't even have a chance to do damage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, luckily whenever the new one comes out I imagine I'm gonna sit down and put actual effort into being the best there ever was or at least in the top million.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and since I'm hoping that it uses more Wii type controls and less old-school fighting type controls I'll actually have a chance of because my old-school fighting type control skills are not so high.
Speaker 1: so if it's all about Wii controls I can definitely get ahead and Maybe be the best there is at Smash Brothers brawl.
Speaker 0: So there's really nothing else I can say about Pokemon.
Speaker 0: being 10 years old I could make it you can't something.
Speaker 1: 10 Pokemon joke but I already did and it's kind of lost his position as Pokemon came out when I was like in high school and High school 10 years ago.
Speaker 0: God damn don't think about it because then you're gonna remember.
Speaker 0: I mean remember that stupid sci-fi thing.
Speaker 0: I was watching wild palms.
Speaker 0: I saw that when I was like 11.
Speaker 1: So, you know Makoto Shinkai the guy who did plays promised and voices of a distant star and Some other stuff that we never saw.
Speaker 1: but now I realize it exists and I kind of want to see it.
Speaker 0: of things He is done that I have seen he's batting a thousand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's made basically two things that I've seen.
Speaker 1: They've both been basically the same only different.
Speaker 0: Yep We both disagree a little bit as to which one is better, but I agree.
Speaker 0: I would agree that they're both very good.
Speaker 0: I really liked place promised and I really like toshino car.
Speaker 1: Well, his new thing is called Biyoko's.
Speaker 1: no be also crew.
Speaker 0: five centimeter Five centimeter.
Speaker 1: that's called five centimeters per second.
Speaker 1: people aren't quite sure but it might be called five centimeters per second.
Speaker 1: Okay show.
Speaker 0: All right now considering that I've seen two different works by this guy I'm gonna hazard a guess that this somehow involves a boy and a girl who like each other in some way and then are Separated and are either trying to come back together or cannot come back together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically that's what it is he's.
Speaker 1: it's a three-part movie.
Speaker 1: I guess I don't know if you'd call it an OAV, but it's like three separate 30-minute things that go together and You can get part one on the bit.
Speaker 1: Torrance right now with the fansubs Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: It seems like this guy might be a one-trick pony, but that's not necessarily a bad thing.
Speaker 1: No, it's it's not.
Speaker 1: it's sort of like the guy who does snatch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's Madonna's husband.
Speaker 1: I think I Richie, you know, he only has a one trick but his trick is real good And I don't mind him doing that trick again.
Speaker 0: He dodges bullets.
Speaker 1: Avi It's like who else is a one-trick pony that does real good at that.
Speaker 1: one trick Nintendo Nintendo's real.
Speaker 1: Yeah, make a Mario game make another Mario game.
Speaker 0: See, I can't say Satoshi khan because wall you see something that he did and you think wow Satoshi khan did that?
Speaker 0: No, they're all still really unique and amazing and different.
Speaker 1: Yep It is sometimes hard to tell between someone who has a distinctive style Or artistic.
Speaker 1: I don't know theme Versus someone who is doing the same thing every time, you know, like Tezuka.
Speaker 1: if you see a Tezuka work, you know immediately It's a Tezuka.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know a Van Gogh painting when you see it.
Speaker 1: But Van Gogh is not a one-trick pony and neither is Tezuka.
Speaker 0: Well, the problem with.
Speaker 0: that is we'll get into in the rest of the show.
Speaker 0: to most people who read manga If you look at any manga from the 70s, you'll think wow, that's a Tezuka.
Speaker 1: Yeah, possibly Maybe so, but yeah, I guess you'd have to know who Tezuka was though.
Speaker 1: Some people don't even know.
Speaker 0: Well, if you knew if you showed him Phoenix and all those things look at this Look at this look at this.
Speaker 0: and then you handed him something else from the 70s and said look at this.
Speaker 0: They'd say by the same guy, right?
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: now, there's a show in Japan called challenger on fire.
Speaker 0: I don't know very much about it.
Speaker 1: It involves setting people on fire.
Speaker 0: it might rabbit it might damn.
Speaker 1: that's awesome.
Speaker 0: I want to see this see the way this particular episode works.
Speaker 0: my thing of the day That is is that they've got a hundred people in Japan many of whom are cosplay And the goal is they've asked all of them to name a hundred anime characters.
Speaker 0: So they all sit there with a little whiteboard and a shield between all the people around him on this big thing And they'll show an anime character like cutie honey or tuxedo.
Speaker 0: come in or Asuka and then Everyone left to write down the character's name.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: I thought it was name on.
Speaker 1: I can name 100 anime characters.
Speaker 1: It was just naming them.
Speaker 1: I could come up with a hunch.
Speaker 0: I guess it's recognize and know how to spell the name of a hundred anime characters.
Speaker 1: see not that would be okay in English But it's actually harder in Japanese because a lot of the characters like a complicated kanji in their name and while you might go Oh, that's so-and-so.
Speaker 0: if you don't know the kanji your SOL I'm not sure the rules of how exact they had to be and you could always just write things out in Kana.
Speaker 0: So it wouldn't have been that big a deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah I could tell.
Speaker 1: I can always tell someone got it right because they would.
Speaker 1: I couldn't.
Speaker 1: well I couldn't understand what they were saying 100%.
Speaker 1: you would see when they showed the answer.
Speaker 1: You know there'd be some symbols under the picture of the character And then you look at what the people wrote on their whiteboard.
Speaker 1: if the symbols match they got it right.
Speaker 0: I was very happy.
Speaker 0: I've learned enough hiragana that I actually recognized a few characters written names.
Speaker 1: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I could only learn katakana and more than one kanji, and then maybe any amount of Japanese grammar.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I digress.
Speaker 0: now it starts out.
Speaker 0: Okay And very quickly the number of contestants dwindles because ever if you get one wrong you're out done forever.
Speaker 1: What single elimination?
Speaker 0: single elimination?
Speaker 1: that's tough especially if they throw like an obscure character right away?
Speaker 1: But what if everyone gets it wrong?
Speaker 1: does everyone out?
Speaker 0: I'm not sure how they did it.
Speaker 0: see the things entirely in Japanese and while I picked out a few phrases like at one point He says the anime loving fan in green has lost or something to that effect that I have no idea What was actually going on?
Speaker 0: But it's easy to see.
Speaker 0: you can watch and figure it out, and they always say the name of the character Even though they don't write it in English so you can play along with the game and see if you knew him.
Speaker 0: I'll admit that after the first few I didn't know any of them for a while.
Speaker 1: I barely knew any of them like I knew Asuka, and I knew Kenshiro.
Speaker 0: Kenshiro.
Speaker 1: I knew some other ones Yeah, but a lot of these are just obscure like I knew that one of the guys is from like the super plastic wrestling Whatever it is, but I didn't know the character's name.
Speaker 0: Well the funny thing was some of them that were.
Speaker 0: I had no idea never seen him before.
Speaker 0: But you see all the contestants like oh duh, and they write it down like nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like that must be some show some old show that we've never seen.
Speaker 0: that must be like a goofy or a Donald Duck.
Speaker 1: You know this would be a fun thing to do at a convention.
Speaker 0: so actually I've already added that To our con repertoire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we just need to get a hundred pictures of anime characters on a laptop, and then yeah That's like you're making a PowerPoint And you just push space to reveal the name and you push space to go to the next picture.
Speaker 0: I've already sketched out exactly how we'll do it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna append to our Otakon I guess resume And we'll see if we do this at any cons with or instead of the anime match game.
Speaker 1: Let's prepare it and do it in the future.
Speaker 0: Maybe we could do it at katsu-kan or something we could do to some of the small cons this year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely like a test out, but anyway the other cool thing is that they've got some guests like special guests competing one of whom is Akira Kamiya who I've met at an amazement, and he is a super awesome voice actor who has been in pretty much everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a big-time guy.
Speaker 1: voice acted a whole shit ton of care.
Speaker 0: He's right up there with my man Takahashi Rioske.
Speaker 1: you forget his real name.
Speaker 0: I do forget his me too But yeah, he's as good as that guy.
Speaker 0: yeah He's also super awesome and super funny.
Speaker 0: the field of competition narrows very quickly to these two dudes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind of weird because the field of competition has some super nerdy people in it and some cosplayers And it's kind of scary.
Speaker 1: But the two dudes left at the end seemed kind of like normal geeky cool dudes and eventually the guy gets to like 75 if it comes down to one man.
Speaker 1: He makes it to like 75 or yeah cuz even though he's the winner He's beating everyone else.
Speaker 1: everyone else is out.
Speaker 1: remember.
Speaker 1: It's a hundred anime characters.
Speaker 1: He you know he has to make it to a hundred.
Speaker 0: now in the end you can't name 100 anime characters.
Speaker 0: in the end The saddest thing is the character that comes up is Zenigata from Lupin and now everyone knows that Agata.
Speaker 1: He knows an Agata obviously.
Speaker 1: I mean it's obvious.
Speaker 1: It's freaking said Agata.
Speaker 0: It looked like he didn't know Zen Agata's full name or he had trouble figuring out what kanji to write and he Puts around a little.
Speaker 0: he failed and they knocked him out of the competition.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think he couldn't write the name correctly.
Speaker 1: That's.
Speaker 0: I need someone who understands Japanese to watch this and tell me what he actually wrote so I figure out why he lost.
Speaker 1: if He didn't know Zen Agata, then this completely changes everything.
Speaker 0: How could you know all those characters and not know Zen Agata?
Speaker 1: I don't know if an American knows Zen Agata, and you don't that's.
Speaker 1: that's for shame.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: my thing of the day is a new blog.
Speaker 1: the blog has only been going since last month But it was.
Speaker 1: it keeps getting updated every day even today.
Speaker 1: the blog is Miotd.com.
Speaker 1: the tagline is we dig giant robots.
Speaker 1: Miotd stands for mecha image of the day.
Speaker 1: my thing of the day is the image of the day.
Speaker 1: It's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Huh I could see a few of our friends really digging that.
Speaker 1: yeah There's a guy.
Speaker 1: it says on the bottom of the blog cap copyright Patrick McFarland images copyright at original artists.
Speaker 1: So there's a guy Patrick McFarland who I must assume is making this blog and every day He finds an awesome mecha image and posts it And I think he's going to continue doing so.
Speaker 1: he started last month And he shows no signs of slowing down.
Speaker 1: and today's image is an awesome High-resolution CG rendering of my favorite mecha the vf1 s from Macross And it is quite awesome.
Speaker 1: So if you like mechas perhaps robots or planes or other?
Speaker 1: Mechanical bits from anime you should subscribe to the RSS feed of mecha image of the day.
Speaker 0: So these these aren't mechas that are also girls and not that I've seen yet, okay?
Speaker 1: That's that's yet to peruse the entire archive.
Speaker 1: But let me give you an example of some of the things you will find in there.
Speaker 1: You'll find things from Macross Gundam ghost in the shell golf force Ava Eureka 7 die buster super robot Wars Star Wars, let's see what Star Wars image.
Speaker 1: He's got in there.
Speaker 0: What could he have?
Speaker 0: what mecha was in Star Wars?
Speaker 1: It's an imperial star destroyer size chart.
Speaker 0: Oh, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh well seems like a cool side.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty cool.
Speaker 1: If you like mecha and my otd.com anyway segue.
Speaker 0: Tonight we're gonna review something that we got a while ago.
Speaker 0: We wanted to review right away, but we actually for the last couple weeks due to some sort of insanity Have a schedule.
Speaker 0: we have an internal calendar, and we actually planned out the show months in advance.
Speaker 0: Yes, so so as a result.
Speaker 0: we ended up doing other things first and while we wanted to do this We've just gotten to it now, and
Speaker 1: we basically you know Every month we'll sit down and we'll come up with show ideas for the next weeks and weeks and weeks And that way we won't come home every day going.
Speaker 1: Why do we do the show on?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: granted We've planned out months worth of Mondays Tuesdays and Wednesdays, and we've got like one Thursday ready to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, we'll work on that.
Speaker 1: We'll work on that this weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway tonight We're going to review something that has come out very recently so recently in fact.
Speaker 1: if you Google around You're not gonna find too much about it unless you know how to type it in Japanese where I'm sure you could find a whole Bunch of stuff in Japanese.
Speaker 0: probably yes But Keiko Takemiya's to Terra or Terra a or towards the Terra or however you want to translate it it's a manga that was written in the early 70s by obviously Keiko Takemiya and Before we get any further.
Speaker 0: I just like to say that I really like it But maybe it's cuz.
Speaker 0: I've been on a kick for this old 70s kind of manga lately.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think it's just this is the kind of thing that if my My likes were a bowling alley this sort of things is strike right down the middle.
Speaker 0: Oh, so you're into the shonen eyes space drama.
Speaker 1: No not really, but it's the it's see it's not really shown an eye.
Speaker 1: I mean well not yet.
Speaker 1: No Yeah as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: see this is published by in the United States by By vertical ink and vertical ink are the people who published you know?
Speaker 1: ode to kirohito And all that other good stuff like now.
Speaker 0: it's very uh.
Speaker 0: vertical ink as in vertical incorporated not as in vertical ink.
Speaker 1: oh yes Yes, that's right vertical incorporated.
Speaker 1: And they published this and when they were marketing it right they were like check out the new sci-fi Epic from the master of shoujo Keiko Takemiya.
Speaker 1: well shoujo in space.
Speaker 1: It's Star Trek shoujo.
Speaker 1: check it out.
Speaker 0: They're really pushing it as though it's shoujo, and I've also seen a lot of people call it an emo manga.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was on the bookmark that I took from the vertical ink booth at the New York.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it is on this bookmark.
Speaker 1: It said.
Speaker 1: What does it say?
Speaker 0: read it the bookmark says in space?
Speaker 0: No one can hear you cry to Tara the hit sci-fi emo manga by shoujo master Keiko Takemiya.
Speaker 1: now I don't know if they're just lying with this marketing or Pretending that it's a shoujo in order to get sales because shoujo is popular in the US.
Speaker 1: I don't know, but first of all Keiko Takemiya is definitely a shoujo manga artist.
Speaker 0: well I think that is primarily because here they kind of say that oh from the master of shoujo See Takemiya is considered by a lot of people to be one of the founding mothers of shoujo as a genre or an idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she's pretty much invented like be shown and in shown and I type stuff in the 70s.
Speaker 1: Well, she was
Speaker 0: a part of this group of people called the fabulous 49ers who I don't know much about But according to Publishers Weekly they were a group of woman artists and writers who quote Established and solidified the girls comics industry in Japan in the mid and late 70s.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently the other most significant person in that group was her former roommate, so It it's one of those tight-knit groups of people that you know busts out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I had heard the term fabulous 49ers before now.
Speaker 0: I know what that is.
Speaker 1: yeah I think I heard a new world order.
Speaker 0: now There's also a claim that Takemiya gave rise or was the founder of the idea of the genre of Bishounen manga?
Speaker 0: because she wrote something called kaze toki no uta Song of wind and trees.
Speaker 1: I think I've heard of that before.
Speaker 1: Anyway, all that is true But if you read to Tara volume 1 without anyone telling you anything The only answer that I think you can come up with is that to Tara at least volume 1 is a shounen siren Sci-fi manga, it's not shoujo.
Speaker 1: It's not be shounen.
Speaker 1: It's not shounen.
Speaker 1: I it's a man.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's like a Tezuka sci-fi.
Speaker 1: It's like Phoenix.
Speaker 1: It's the same exact genre as Phoenix volume 2 or Phoenix volume 6.
Speaker 0: granted I can see how people might want to call it shoujo or have shoujo leanings because it does focus a lot on characters personal thoughts and emotions and Interactions and possible love triangles and all that sort of thing a lot more than what you might expect from a typical OMG people in space blowing things up Yep,
Speaker 1: and while there isn't any be shown and shown and I action in volume 1 there is definitely.
Speaker 1: I can definitely see the series Going there in volume 2 or 3.
Speaker 0: Well an ishi verticals director of marketing and publicity says straight out that the Homosexuality comes in later volumes and there are only three volumes.
Speaker 0: So it's got to be coming pretty quick.
Speaker 1: as long as it's not yaoi No, it is manga is good enough that I can tolerate some shown and I action if the story around it is good.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like how in ghost in the shell you tolerate the three pages of you know Random lesbians and big boobs because the story is still good enough.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is those specific pages and that ghost in the shell while obviously no one can argue that they weren't just Gratuitous gratuitous horrible pornography.
Speaker 0: Yep at the same time the point that was being made There was actually fairly interesting.
Speaker 0: It just probably could have been made in a less sheer otastic way.
Speaker 1: Perhaps perhaps it could.
Speaker 0: I mean I can think of a couple ways I could make that point perhaps with stick figures that would convey the same meaning.
Speaker 1: I Could convey the same meaning without any pictures at all.
Speaker 1: I Could just use some words and in many different languages.
Speaker 0: But anyway to Tara is a fairly complex story and it is written in the 70s.
Speaker 0: so the art looks.
Speaker 0: if you didn't know anything about this artist and you pick this up and you would read any of Tezuka's works you might just think wow.
Speaker 0: This looks a lot like Phoenix or a lot like Tezuka.
Speaker 1: Yes I mean I looked at it and I said wow, this looks a lot like Tezuka except there are two key differences.
Speaker 1: Number one the number one obvious difference between the art in this and the art in Tezuka's works.
Speaker 1: Is that the characters?
Speaker 1: Faces and head shapes are a lot more shoujo-y than Tezuka-y.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have larger eyes larger pupils.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're a lot more expressive and a lot more realistic with small noses.
Speaker 1: Yep The bodies their bodies and like their poses and the clothing and all that sort of stuff is a lot like Tezuka.
Speaker 1: But the faces are definitely.
Speaker 1: they have a little bit of Tezuka in them, but they're mostly modern shoujo type faces.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though all the normal faces very often will cut away to almost Tezuka style humor or Little weird sketchy drawings or that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, depending on the level of zooming and you know, if it's a little panel on the side It might be more like Tezuka, but if it's a big panel, you know Where someone's standing up and it's all close in on one character.
Speaker 1: You'll get the full drawn-out shoujo face.
Speaker 1: secondly when she draws spaceships or Mechanics or things she puts a lot more detail and draws it a lot more in a modern style than Tezuka Like Tezuka would draw like a cartoony spaceship like, you know a little pointy rocket bit with some holes in it.
Speaker 1: You know like a little circular window She draws a highly detailed rocket ship that it looks a lot more like it would be fit into a Kira or something like that.
Speaker 0: then Anything Tezuka would ever draw though I remember if you read Phoenix you see that it uses a lot of very interesting Composition some of which works very well and some of which is just confusing.
Speaker 0: and there's a lot of that into Tara, too But it's a lot more subdued and generally makes a lot more sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't seem too highly Experimental with like layouts or anything like that, but it doesn't just stick to normal boring layouts.
Speaker 1: There's definitely some exciting stuff.
Speaker 1: She just doesn't go crazy with it.
Speaker 0: Yep There's a lot of profile zoomed in shot on the side while people talk next to it or Various almost a montage of different things while speech is happening.
Speaker 0: now the story of two Tara is both simple and complex at the same time and Actually reminds me of a great many other words some of which came before and some of which came after this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you can't help.
Speaker 1: but when you read this unless you are so uncultured and unwell read You can't help but feeling like you've read this story before like you've heard it before in a million other places Even if you can't quite put your finger on it.
Speaker 1: And I wonder this was made in the early 70s.
Speaker 1: now was this the first time this story was told and we missed it until now because language barrier.
Speaker 1: or Is this just another telling of the story that we've heard a thousand times?
Speaker 0: Well consider that it does remind me a lot.
Speaker 0: It's just of one thing in particular a brave new world.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit of brave new world going on there only in brave new world.
Speaker 1: The children were sort of engineered before Conception I guess, you know in test tubes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and in this one They seem to engineer the children after they get out.
Speaker 0: see the story is that the earth at that we live on they call it Tara over time eventually becomes overpopulated depleted and generally Untenable.
Speaker 0: it's on the verge of collapse and humans can't live there anymore.
Speaker 0: So with our vast technology we spread out into space and humans decide that the only way to save their planet and they also I guess they assumedly decide that saving the planet is the highest priority above all else for whatever reason
Speaker 1: that
Speaker 0: they must strictly control the way the planet is used and not let everyone come back to the planet in order to Perfectly use all the resources and ingenuity that humans have available to make the earth the paradise home It once was.
Speaker 1: and to do this, of course, obviously you put a computer in charge because people suck.
Speaker 0: Yes, I believe they call it superior dominion.
Speaker 0: It's a system where children are born.
Speaker 0: This is this isn't really a spoiler so much because this is generally brought about early on.
Speaker 0: but we're not gonna go into very much Detail because there are a lot of things you really don't want ruin for you in there.
Speaker 0: There's
Speaker 1: a lot of things you don't want ruined
Speaker 0: but basically children are raised in space by the computer and by the system and then brainwash along with technology to Have the chance of actually going to earth and then it on earth putting all of their effort toward making earth a better place Or a habitable place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it basically like they raise you in a certain way and then they fuck you and then they raise you in a certain way And then they fuck you and then eventually if you don't if you stick it within the system and you know Do that what the system wants you to do to the best, you know awesomeness and you're the super elite kind of guy.
Speaker 1: You'll end up on earth and now get to go to Tara where all humans want to go.
Speaker 0: now This is one nominally like a lot of stories.
Speaker 0: We've read before there was one volume of Phoenix That was very specifically about all of the migrants and emigres from earth long ago.
Speaker 0: Always want to return to earth and earth doesn't let him come back because it's too small and can't hold them.
Speaker 1: It's also similar to Phoenix volume 2 future where computers run the world because humans fucked it up.
Speaker 0: now that is the nominal background of what's going on, but the actual plot has more to do with the fact that a Byproduct of this system is that certain people bit by bit?
Speaker 0: Have started to manifest various things that you can almost call psychic powers.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's frayed up ESP.
Speaker 1: Yep It's sort of this part of the plot with these separate people who are cast out, you know for having psychic powers feels a lot like x-men or Like the matrix.
Speaker 1: maybe you know where certain people get out of the matrix because they're different.
Speaker 0: now these people who have the ESP.
Speaker 0: they're called the moo are Killed or cast out as soon as they are discovered.
Speaker 1: Well, it's mu so it might be mu.
Speaker 0: It's probably moo.
Speaker 1: Yeah stuff to tell.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the they're cast out or killed.
Speaker 0: they they don't want people to even know that this sort of thing exists.
Speaker 0: So the society adapts by coming up with ways to detect these people and dispatch of them early on so they can't cause any trouble.
Speaker 1: And of course, they're a group of them that were Unsuccessfully dispatched that are up to some sort of business.
Speaker 1: Yes that I won't spoil.
Speaker 0: Yes You do learn this right away that some of the two of the early main characters who are obviously both moo and living among these exiled people are soldier blue the quote visionary first leader of the moo and Pfizer's the quote blind fortune teller.
Speaker 1: soldier blue is the best character in the whole manga.
Speaker 0: I don't know I really like Keith onion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's alright.
Speaker 1: If you haven't had any soldier blue you see the story
Speaker 0: starts with Jomi Marcus Shen who lives in a normal life is a normal kid kind of bright in this whole system and one thing leads to another and there are implications that he may or may not be a moo and His parents worry about this and his friends yell at him and I really don't want to go any further without ruining What happens.
Speaker 0: because it goes the plot moves at a rather quick clip to put it lightly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it.
Speaker 1: even though the plot moves really quickly.
Speaker 1: I think it sort of has to move pretty quickly early on because the first at least half of this volume They're just sort of setting up the universe and the characters still I mean they introduced like really important characters Around the halfway point.
Speaker 1: it's like whoa You know and it doesn't really feel like the actual Main story starts until like the last third or quarter of this volume.
Speaker 0: Well, this volume has three parts.
Speaker 0: part one follows Jomi Marcus Shin the nominal main character through everything that happens to him his interactions with soldier blue and Pfizer's and it's good.
Speaker 0: Part two kind of starts the story over in that it gives the history and everything just like the first part did.
Speaker 1: Well, you got it.
Speaker 1: I think the reason that's there is because it was originally published serially in some anthology.
Speaker 1: Yes, so you had to retell that bit.
Speaker 0: but also It doesn't even talk about Jomi or any of these people and it focuses on Keith onion and all the people around him.
Speaker 0: These are people who are a part of this system Very much the system that you didn't know much about but was hinted at in the first part and you see this whole thing again From an entirely different perspective.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of like here's something going on in this part of the universe you know in this period of time and here's something going on in a different part of the universe around the same period of time and Then of course as in everything that does this the two things collide.
Speaker 1: OMG
Speaker 0: Yes now I very much enjoyed the second part a lot more than the first part partly because now it's a much more clinical look at how the society actually works and Kind of the veil is pulled off from your eyes and now you see everything at least everything as far as the main character can.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I did like the second bit more than the first bit But I felt like there was this potential of greater liking for this through the plot that was going on in the first bit.
Speaker 1: It just stopped advancing when it was gonna get to where I wanted it to be.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm sure and maybe volume 2 it's gonna get there and that's the part I'm really gonna like the second bit which really lets you see kind of the inside of how the society works Reminds me so much that it's almost painful of the paranoia role-playing game.
Speaker 0: I would say that the the society that has been created here without ruining much is almost exactly in the spirit of paranoia.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have the same silliness that paranoia doesn't have the silliness depending on how you play.
Speaker 0: There are different ways to game.
Speaker 0: that that's true.
Speaker 1: And while the system is not as complex as the system in paranoia It is definitely reminiscent.
Speaker 0: I think it is as complex inter I mean.
Speaker 0: they talk a lot about not fraternizing with people in different levels and there's the elites and Then there's the elite elites and there's the members and society is stratified and it's exactly like I mean paranoia.
Speaker 0: The game breaks up into three levels of I guess Cerebral ness when you play and this reads exactly like a game of the highest most serious level of paranoia would be.
Speaker 1: Perhaps perhaps it's definitely very similar And I wonder if the tell the guy who wrote paranoia ever read this as opposed to the first part Which in a few ways almost reminds me of Battlestar Galactica.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: I definitely feel like it's more of an x-men kind of thing.
Speaker 0: What's the plot of Battlestar Galactica?
Speaker 1: You're in space.
Speaker 1: Some people are evil.
Speaker 1: You have to teleport every so minutes.
Speaker 0: All right Never mind that that's not the the relevant.
Speaker 1: No, but think you see how it goes with x-men.
Speaker 1: is that x-men?
Speaker 1: there are mutants?
Speaker 1: who are cast out of society and You know.
Speaker 1: next men like what most of times people tell the story of the x-men.
Speaker 1: they concentrated one character like kitty pride or something.
Speaker 1: they show someone who's a normal person and they're you know living with their parents.
Speaker 1: and then all of a sudden they find out they're A mutant and their parents cast them out and then they run away and then they find refuge with the x-men.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm not disagreeing that x-men is also very much like this.
Speaker 0: But look at there's two things going on.
Speaker 0: on one hand this first bit with Jomi is very much the x-men thing of people who?
Speaker 0: Are different or cast out because they're different and normal people are afraid of them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: but at the same time there's this whole idea that I think is going to be a lot more important later the Journey home trying to find your origin trying to get a group of displaced people Through the desert for 40 days and find home or paradise or whatever.
Speaker 0: while this first part That is the true plot of Battlestar Galactica.
Speaker 1: while this first part of the first volume is a lot like x-men I definitely feel like it drops the x-men as soon as that first part is over and it goes into.
Speaker 1: you know The rest of the story which is completely different.
Speaker 0: now an ishi that that woman who is the public the PR person for this Says that to Tara was largely influenced by quote Japan student movements of the 1960s when college campuses became hotbeds of political unrest.
Speaker 1: huh, I wonder what sort of Political thing like ties this has because they don't know enough details about Japanese Politics to find any correlations between this and that.
Speaker 0: and also apparently the.
Speaker 0: the writer was very much a fan of Osamu Tezuka and she was influenced greatly by him.
Speaker 1: that was Painfully obvious just by looking at it.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's actually really cool to look at this manga because I like Tezuka manga, and I like modern manga and You don't really ever get to see how manga got like it's like you know that modern manga that you read today like Death Note or one piece or Naruto is influenced by Osamu Tezuka.
Speaker 1: all manga and anime is influenced by Osamu Tezuka the same way that all like Animation in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Is influenced by Disney because Tezuka was influenced by Disney.
Speaker 1: so I mean come on.
Speaker 1: But we see the modern manga, and we see the Tezuka manga.
Speaker 1: just because he's Tezuka We get to see his stuff, but you don't really get to see how it goes in between.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like if someone told you that you know there are monkeys And there are people and they never showed you the any of the in-between monkeys Which we have seen.
Speaker 1: and evolution is real, but with manga like I knew there was an evolution of manga But I never got to see the missing links, and this is one of those missing links.
Speaker 1: It's so half shoujo II style art and half Tezuka art.
Speaker 1: And it has elements a lot of elements of Tezuka storytelling and elements of modern manga storytelling, and it's together.
Speaker 1: yeah, and it's really cool because Manga from this era that I assume must be similar is not published in English.
Speaker 1: often This might be the first time
Speaker 0: and even if you haven't read a lot of manga Don't worry about picking up something like this because while it's old it Reads a lot like modern manga and you won't have trouble following it for the most part other than there's a few times where it's Hard to tell who's speaking, but that's more just a function of how the art is done, and how the speech bubbles are drawn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know actually now that I think about it This could be not you know because it's a great work on its own But it might be a very useful work of all the people who like Modern manga, and they refuse to read anything that looks old or might be old.
Speaker 1: you could give them this and they could enjoy it You know because of the way it is a modern manga But you could use it as a bridge to pull them over to the other side and get them to read the older good stuff.
Speaker 1: You know that they are now that if they looked at now.
Speaker 1: They would be unwilling to read now.
Speaker 0: I believe it's worth mentioning that there was a movie adaptation of this made in I believe uh-huh, I don't know anything about it and I don't even know who the director is Hideo onchi.
Speaker 0: There's nothing on the anime news network encyclopedia.
Speaker 0: I didn't feel like doing any further research.
Speaker 1: I highly doubt this movie is available in English anywhere.
Speaker 0: It looks like it was released in the u.s.. On VHS in the 90s really.
Speaker 1: That's a VHS.
Speaker 1: I gotta get.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm not looking at for that at the anime cons and the dollar bins.
Speaker 0: more importantly toward the Terra.
Speaker 0: a TV show is Debuting very soon.
Speaker 1: Yes in like in a few months.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see a few months now According to this April 7th so on April 7th like I guess the week after that because depending on how fast they fans of it You're probably gonna see to Tara episode 1 on the bit Torrance with subtitles in English.
Speaker 1: That's pretty freaking awesome a brand new anime series with modern animation, and it's gonna be way cool.
Speaker 1: We should link to the Japanese website for that.
Speaker 0: well There's a picture here on the anime news network about it and the character designs.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say without seeing the move.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure it looks like they're gonna take a somewhat interesting take on Translating these character designs into animation.
Speaker 0: I do think they're pretty though They remind me a tiny bit of duo say uh a tiny bit, but not they definitely have the old leaning still there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven't seen enough of them But I they.
Speaker 1: I think they remind me a little bit from what I remember of like all the of the stars.
Speaker 1: Is you know like the crests of the stars and the banners of the stars?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know how much of those have you seen?
Speaker 1: barely any cuz.
Speaker 1: I saw about half of Christ But I seen barely of that and I've seen barely of screenshots from this.
Speaker 1: so That's what I'm going on.
Speaker 0: and now what else can we say?
Speaker 1: It's an awesome manga.
Speaker 1: You should buy it.
Speaker 1: you can get this manga on Amazon for 12 less than $12.
Speaker 1: all right, it's like twice the size of a regular manga.
Speaker 0: yes It is quite hefty and there are only going to be three volumes, so you're not.
Speaker 0: even if you don't like it It's not like you're committed to something huge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you buy it, and you don't like it You don't have to buy two and three.
Speaker 1: no one's making you and if you do like it You can get the ending of this thing in two more volumes.
Speaker 1: You can have a whole manga series without having to buy a hundred volumes of something you know even like Death Note is like 12 Or 13 volumes.
Speaker 1: This is just three and on Amazon They're eleven dollars and sixteen cents.
Speaker 1: So you if you like it you have no excuse not to buy the whole thing and read the whole thing.
Speaker 1: the next volume The current volume the first volume came out in February the next volume will be out in April and the final volume It'll be out in June.
Speaker 1: so if you're the kind of person doesn't like to wait in June just go out and buy all three at once and You probably won't have a problem if you buy them on Amazon.
Speaker 1: if you try to find them in the store You might have a little bit of trouble But I've actually seen these around so it might not be as hard as you think to find them.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.