Speaker 0: It's Monday September 17th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about the business technology disconnect.
Speaker 0: Sam preenie Let's do this.
Speaker 0: It's coming.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I can contain myself.
Speaker 1: Our listener should be glad it did not come or else this podcast might not exist in its current Might.
Speaker 0: not probably wouldn't.
Speaker 1: yeah, well we did go to work today wisely Very wise yes.
Speaker 0: I'm very glad that I did not skip work today in order to play a certain game a game that possibly I have been waiting for for a decade different a I mean if you waited for anything longer in your entire life You know what.
Speaker 0: no no nothing in my life.
Speaker 0: Have I waited this long for?
Speaker 0: because Duke Nukem I wasn't actually waiting for.
Speaker 0: I never believed that game would come out.
Speaker 0: But this I mean I saw the videos.
Speaker 0: it was like this game is coming out soon, and that was like eight years ago.
Speaker 1: Yep, but anyway the point is is that we were thinking about.
Speaker 1: they said the beta version of the game would come out today and because We pre-ordered we would get into that beta with you know just automatically.
Speaker 1: but They didn't say what time would be coming out and a bunch of people were like oh, it'll come out at midnight You know wherever time zone they happen to live in.
Speaker 1: and smarter people said no It'll come out midnight valve time so 3 a.m.. Eastern time, and then people said oh No, it'll come out later in the day because you know they got to work on it and stuff And there's also the chance that it won't come out.
Speaker 0: But that arguments silly.
Speaker 0: if they give a date and then they need the extra eight hours to do something to it something's wrong.
Speaker 1: yeah, well currently it is a what like.
Speaker 0: It is currently 7 45 p.m.. Eastern Standard Time.
Speaker 1: Early tonight if it's 7 45 here, then it's six five a quarter to five In valve headquarters, so they got some time before they push the button.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: I'll see.
Speaker 1: I guarantee they'll push the button before midnight Pacific time.
Speaker 0: I only give it a 60% chance of it coming out today.
Speaker 1: I give it a 90%.
Speaker 1: well Considering the track record of Team Fortress 2 there is a chance that it will come out though and there'll be a problem which is not included in my 90% estimate.
Speaker 1: for example it could come out and All the servers will be full of people and no one can play.
Speaker 1: it could come out and the server won't work.
Speaker 1: It could come out.
Speaker 1: no one will have servers set up.
Speaker 1: It could come out and it doesn't work period.
Speaker 1: it could come out and it only works on some systems because the beta and it's Buggy.
Speaker 1: there's all sorts of scenarios, but could come out.
Speaker 0: and then the low.
Speaker 0: well You know what I'll bet.
Speaker 0: even right now the load of kids sitting there Reloading steam Constantly.
Speaker 1: it could be quite a load.
Speaker 1: and that brings me to the point I want to make.
Speaker 1: if you're one of those people who when something's gonna happen on the internet.
Speaker 1: Let's say I don't know.
Speaker 1: Engadget is live blocking blogging an Apple press conference or game is about to come out or You know any sort of.
Speaker 1: there is something impending.
Speaker 1: you know like there's something about to happen There is news coming out about it or something is going to happen sometime But you're not sure exactly what time.
Speaker 0: yep like sometime tonight Nintendo will announce their new game Semprene.
Speaker 1: right if you're sitting there reloading the video game website constantly You're wasting your time.
Speaker 1: Well, you shouldn't do that.
Speaker 0: There's always gonna be the tier zero person the person who is the first one to see the updated Business business.
Speaker 1: that's a person is mo and business know who that person is the blogger who's paid to do it.
Speaker 1: That's what that person is.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 0: No it's always some punk kid, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: There's punk kids who do it too, but for example you don't have to stay up Reading.
Speaker 1: you know the Engadget whatever.
Speaker 1: as they update it live blogging Which I think is pretty stupid.
Speaker 1: When you could just wait until they're done and then read the whole thing at once Why waste you?
Speaker 1: think about how much longer and how much more time you're wasting?
Speaker 1: Reloading it constantly?
Speaker 1: yeah I mean one sentence at a time and half the time you reload.
Speaker 1: there isn't even a new sentence for Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 0: In the time you spend reloading you could just be playing some other game and practicing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know think about all today.
Speaker 1: if you would have sat there trying to get Team Fortress 2 all day You would have been reloading for over 12 hours Constantly and you would have never gotten anything for your efforts.
Speaker 0: I mean you don't.
Speaker 0: there's the tier zero person.
Speaker 0: you know the person who actually sees the thing and the tier one person is like The blogger who finds out about it, and then it's all over the internet from that.
Speaker 1: yeah If you're just browsing the web or doing your thing.
Speaker 1: you know you sit around waiting doing something else.
Speaker 1: when it happens You'll find out within minutes.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna find out within a second.
Speaker 1: You'll find out within minutes.
Speaker 1: And you know what in the grand scheme?
Speaker 1: think about this and those minutes.
Speaker 1: you didn't get to play the game the first five minutes.
Speaker 1: It was out.
Speaker 1: you played it ten minutes after it was out.
Speaker 1: well Would you rather play the game ten minutes after it comes out or?
Speaker 1: Are you willing to save the get the?
Speaker 1: you're basically in order to get those ten minutes of game time into your life?
Speaker 1: You're gonna have to spend like 12 hours not doing anything else.
Speaker 0: see the thing is it's a hindsight problem and that you can't really know.
Speaker 0: like let's say I Would have done the effort if I'd known to get an extra ten minutes or day or whatever out of tribes, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because that game there was a limited amount of time.
Speaker 0: I could have played that game.
Speaker 0: I guess it saddens me that there was time in my life when that game was playable And I was not playing it.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm that is still.
Speaker 0: I mean my my brain is kind of a loop.
Speaker 0: you know what I was like rims gonna play an FPS and it goes through this constant loop of what I'm gonna play and It always starts at can you play tribes - and the answer is no.
Speaker 0: and then I move on to another game.
Speaker 1: Even if I could play tribes - there was just something about like the first few weeks when the game was brand new and the servers Were loaded with a bajillion people, and it was awesome.
Speaker 0: We walked around our IT Constantly.
Speaker 1: Alright, we're done with that.
Speaker 0: Yes suffice to say we might suddenly stop doing this episode.
Speaker 1: The message here because it's tech day.
Speaker 1: the message for tech day is don't be a stupid asshole reloading constantly.
Speaker 1: Just wait do something else.
Speaker 1: with your time You're not missing anything.
Speaker 0: in the very least.
Speaker 0: if you're gonna be reloading have a Gameboy open.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just set an auto-reloader World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: have the auto-reloader and Play World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then and play a Gameboy game.
Speaker 1: I'll even tell.
Speaker 1: even go so far as to say reloading World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: Playing World of Warcraft is better than reloading something to see you can do them all at the same time.
Speaker 0: right now in my life I could be reloading steam playing World of Warcraft Playing Final Fantasy Tactics or Pokemon on my Gameboy and watching an anime.
Speaker 1: I guess so.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got a multitask Yeah, but reloading is stupid a waste of time.
Speaker 0: All right, so tech day news.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna cop out with some lame-o tech news roundup, even though I think our last tech news roundup was justified.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it was.
Speaker 0: the problem is there's still like five or six newses.
Speaker 0: I really want to talk about.
Speaker 1: I will talk about one of them.
Speaker 0: I am gonna talk about one of them.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure you're all aware that some news came out not too long ago that the new iPods had a problem Where due to something and this was attributed to such things as evil Apple or some conspiracy or whatever.
Speaker 0: But I'll get to that.
Speaker 0: You could no longer use anything but iTunes to update music on your iPod all the new iPods at least.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, and There was a rabble on the internet.
Speaker 0: Oh shit those fuckers.
Speaker 0: It's all.
Speaker 0: it's all over now.
Speaker 0: It's ruined.
Speaker 0: Well, uh, it's been 36 hours since that was announced and it's been fixed.
Speaker 0: It's been cracked.
Speaker 0: It now works in Linux again.
Speaker 0: I imagine everything's gonna be patched shortly.
Speaker 1: Let me let me discuss the technology of what was going on here for a second Unlike other mp3 players like say for instance a Sansa or a kawan?
Speaker 1: The iPod has an iPod and an iTunes database on it, right?
Speaker 1: So like a Sansa if you have a Sansa you just put mp3s on it and the Sansa looks at its own File system sort of like when you're on your computer just browsing around folders.
Speaker 1: It browses around its own folders looking for mp3s and whatever it can find and it puts them there for you to play It.
Speaker 1: just it just finds them.
Speaker 1: So all you have to do is put files on your Sansa and you're good to go.
Speaker 1: The iPod unlike other players doesn't look to see what files it has.
Speaker 1: It looks just in this database file that it has and that database file tells it what files are available for playing.
Speaker 1: That's why if you just use your iPod like a hard drive and put some files on there You can't actually play them.
Speaker 1: You need to use iTunes or something to add the files to your iPod.
Speaker 0: It's now there's a lot of rationale and reasons and speculation as to why exactly Apple does Number one.
Speaker 0: real truth is that because of the DRM in iTunes and the fact that they want you to be able to play music That is DRM on your iPod There is a vested interest in them having some measure of control over what goes on and does not go on the iPod.
Speaker 1: Actually that has nothing as absolutely surprisingly the DRM has nothing to do with.
Speaker 0: What's the rationale?
Speaker 1: reason they have the iTunes database is because they are able to store arbitrary metadata about the files that you have on your iPod.
Speaker 1: That's how that feature.
Speaker 1: where you listen to a podcast you pause you sync, you know, you play again on your iTunes You sync you go to your iPod you pick up where you left off all those sorts of features that they have on there Were and the album, you know The the crazy advanced album art they have and other stuff works because they have a database that allows them to store metadata.
Speaker 1: That's what allows you to do like the on-the-fly playlists are and then sync them up to your iTunes, huh?
Speaker 0: So what you're telling me is that all the crazy conspiracy wackos on the internet who tell me that no It's all because Apple is evil and DRM and blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: I might not be accurate.
Speaker 1: I can tell you that the it is sucky that the iPod does use a database file to allow you to play files on the iPod in terms of not wanting to use iTunes.
Speaker 1: However, the only reason that it would not gain them any advantage in terms of digital rights management.
Speaker 1: The only advantages it would gain them are in terms of adding features to the iPod that I must regretfully admit other players do not have these features and One of the only ways to get those features would be to implement an equivalent sort of database thing.
Speaker 0: Now the news was that in the new updates and everything what they did is they had a hash.
Speaker 0: But it wasn't like hashes per files was a hash of the whole database.
Speaker 0: So basically if you modified anything in the database at all, you know put an mp3 file in there or whatever The hash wouldn't match.
Speaker 0: So your iPod would just say oh, I guess I don't have any music.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure exactly if it was a hash of the database, but it was a hash nonetheless.
Speaker 1: And if you wanted to you know, we know how the iTunes database is structured and they keep changing it.
Speaker 1: But it's pretty easy to figure out how it.
Speaker 1: you know, it works and that's why you can use other programs besides iTunes.
Speaker 1: You can use Winamp or GTK pod or Amarok to manage the files on your iPod and have it work.
Speaker 1: But they added a hash.
Speaker 1: now a hash is a one-way math.
Speaker 1: So they create a number based on something and they put that number there and then they can use that number To figure out whether your iTunes database is good or bad.
Speaker 0: think of it.
Speaker 0: It's like a. it's like a checksum.
Speaker 0: It's a thing where you can.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah, you can calculate this number based on known math from a set of data and If you know the number then you can test any set of data and find out with reasonable Certainty if it's this exact same set of data.
Speaker 1: So this made it very difficult.
Speaker 1: You couldn't modify the iTunes database and still have it match the number and you couldn't reverse the number because it's one-way math.
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, you know, you could.
Speaker 1: If I do 1 plus 1 is 2. right now I give you the number 2. tell me what math I did to come up with the number.
Speaker 0: It might have been 1 point 5 plus point 5.
Speaker 1: You don't know and you need to know those original numbers to get it to work.
Speaker 0: So now of course one-way math is not absolutely one-way because you can reverse engineer things often times Yes, but that's for other reasons other than the math itself.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah But the point is is that because of this one-way math you couldn't modify the iTunes database and have it work anymore in the new iPods.
Speaker 1: Well, someone just figured it out and you can use non iTunes again.
Speaker 1: Now people are saying oh, it's because Apple doesn't want anyone using non iTunes.
Speaker 0: and that may well be yes.
Speaker 0: Because well Apple has fussed with the way iTunes sharing and things work in the past and those fucks things have just happened to break A lot of third-party support.
Speaker 0: Yeah granted third-party Linux II type just fix it almost right away every time that may be.
Speaker 1: However, I do want to say that this sort of hashing feature in the iTunes database could have potentially other Uses than preventing you from using something besides iTunes.
Speaker 1: It could support other advanced features.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually look into great detail to figure out if there are doing anything with it But there are reasons to do it other than Preventing people from using non iTunes with their eye.
Speaker 0: Well from what I've read and these are mostly comments on slashdot and tech blogs But a lot of these people seem to have done some research It looks like it's a hash of either the database or all the data on the iPod or some large large chunk.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and It's the only possible use anyone could think of for it Is that you could tell if the database were corrupted and flag it as corrupt very quickly.
Speaker 1: Oh, that is true.
Speaker 0: And however, they could do that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and the performance gained by doing it this way is pretty negligible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well who knows why they decided to do it.
Speaker 1: We'd have to ask Apple programmers You don't want to talk about anything and not allowed to legally.
Speaker 1: so, you know, whatever you want to think, you know Cuz we have no evidence.
Speaker 1: either way You have no evidence about anything when it comes to Apple and their internal doings or how any of their stuff works.
Speaker 1: So you can just think whatever you want and we'll just this.
Speaker 1: that's what the information is.
Speaker 1: That's all I can say.
Speaker 1: alright, so tour.
Speaker 1: I think someone yelled at us for not mentioning tour specifically during our Anonymity episode even though I basically said everything there was to say about tour other than the word tour.
Speaker 0: Tor is basically a system.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna talk about the tech at all but it's a system whereby you can connect to this network and Have traffic routed through it such that you can effectively be absolutely anonymous.
Speaker 1: Right, so there's a. there'd be a server out there with an IP address and Every like a million people are using that server.
Speaker 1: and now all every you visit a website.
Speaker 1: They think that server visited the website you visit.
Speaker 1: you download some prong.
Speaker 1: They think that server downloaded the.
Speaker 0: it's a little more complicated than that And there's a lot like there's hopping around and we're not gonna get into all that.
Speaker 0: but it's a system whereby as long as you buy into the system and you can bet and the system is Trustworthy and the people running it are trustworthy and tour Technologically seems to be fairly trustworthy is the side effect of that is it's oftentimes slow.
Speaker 1: Yep The thing with happened here is some guy in Germany was running a tour server.
Speaker 1: this server, of course Was had a lot of people using it.
Speaker 1: So basically you have a computer and as far as the internet is concerned There's like a million people's worth of internet traffic all coming from this one IP address.
Speaker 1: You know this IP address is visiting like a thousand websites simultaneously and it's downloading a hundred mp3 simultaneously and god knows what.
Speaker 1: in Germany many things are illegal.
Speaker 1: That should not be because Germans hate freedom and Someone in Germany.
Speaker 1: Well this I agree should be illegal.
Speaker 1: They posted a bomb threat on something.
Speaker 1: All right, it should be illegal.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't be allowed to post bombs.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what it already is illegal I know so but that's fine, but they do hate freedom in Germany that regardless and They traced that back to the tour server.
Speaker 1: And of course someone who posted the bomb threat was smart I guess from a technology standpoint and used tour so that they couldn't be traced.
Speaker 1: and I bet they probably still don't know who posted The bomb.
Speaker 0: and you know what they're never gonna know because tour is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yep, the guy who's running the tour server was arrested.
Speaker 0: now this bothers me.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a tricky issue because on one hand you could I mean I think anyone can see the value of a of a trustworthy law enforcement Agency being able to track down the source of any communication, especially in the case of a threat or something like that or something Actually clearly illegal where no one would object to it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but at the same time Why don't citizens have a right to?
Speaker 0: Facilitate other people being anonymous.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't want to be hyperbolic here.
Speaker 0: Making it illegal to run a tour server or arresting someone who runs the tour server is not much different than arresting people who sell Masks or arresting someone who agrees that any mail they get they'll just mail to someone else.
Speaker 1: Yes I must say there is definitely a problem and I think you know some.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what side of this I'm on is in That rat people outlaw things that are wrong.
Speaker 0: Like we're outlawing murder or outlawing robbery Outlawing stabbing right even if you're a libertarian I think you can agree that.
Speaker 0: yes, I think it's a society.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna let people murder lying child for yes.
Speaker 1: But then people want to outlaw the tools that are used to.
Speaker 1: you know Commit these crimes.
Speaker 1: and you know in some cases such as the kitchen knife where a device, you know Is used by so many people that they're unwilling to give it up and such it'll cause a problem.
Speaker 1: if they outlaw it They don't outlaw it.
Speaker 0: but on the other hand some devices, you know if they're or items physical goods if they are less popular say lock picks or There's a lot of a lot of states in the US at least restrict the ownership of certain kinds of lock picks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though I can make those lock picks.
Speaker 1: I know and they outlaw Items that could potentially be used for crimes even if they have also non criminal uses that are useful I mean if there was an item that had no non criminal uses.
Speaker 1: such says, I don't know You know what a bank robbing machine I think I could deal with outlawing the bank robbing machine that had no other use.
Speaker 0: What if someone planted a bomb in the money bags in a bank and the bank robbing machine could then be used to safely get?
Speaker 0: All the money with the bomb.
Speaker 1: I'm saying Hypothetically if the bank robbing machine had no other uses like in that situation It would just get the money and leave with and leaving the.
Speaker 0: let's go one step further and go to the opposite.
Speaker 0: There is nothing in this studio right here right now Anywhere we can reach or see that could not be used to commit a crime.
Speaker 1: I guess you could use just about anything in some way to help.
Speaker 1: you can make a crime.
Speaker 0: I could hit you over the head with the Marantz I could infringe on copyrights with my computer.
Speaker 1: Yes, and I really do not think that it should be illegal to sell or make Almost anything or use almost anything in a non-criminal way.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess maybe poison gas you probably shouldn't have in your house.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah when it comes to physical things like weapons that I think there are a lot more justifiable reasons.
Speaker 0: But when it comes to any sort of computer device That's such an ephemeral world and it's one of those we don't understand it.
Speaker 1: if something has even one Legitimate use I don't think it's right to say you can't have that now.
Speaker 1: Let me finish the details of the story.
Speaker 1: The guy basically we didn't know he was arrested until all the charges are dropped and he was able to talk about it.
Speaker 1: but basically what happened is he went and he was explaining to the police about Tor and they didn't get it.
Speaker 1: and Then some people had to come and explain it and they sort of said oh we made a mistake and they let him go.
Speaker 1: No, this seems to have a lot only that.
Speaker 1: but the whole time they never took down the tour server or anything.
Speaker 1: They just knew that that guy was associated with that server and they got him.
Speaker 1: Oh never touching the server.
Speaker 1: Wow That shows their incompetence.
Speaker 0: That's the exact opposite of the u.s.
Speaker 0: Where if they suspect you or something they pretty much the server was far away somewhere.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're I just couldn't find it who knows?
Speaker 0: but seriously in the u.s I don't know all you non-us Ian's but if you're are even suspected of a computer crime of any kind You know like to do a crime of any kind Warrant to come into your house and they see computers they take them.
Speaker 0: They'll pretty much take all your computers and oftentimes you just will never see him again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you are any sort of criminal where they get to go into your house and you know raid it Even you're not taking all computer stuff Absolutely everything because they just love finding evidence on your computer.
Speaker 0: That's why you have a bluetooth or wireless sand That's hidden in the ducts or that's why you just encrypt your hard drive.
Speaker 0: No, no, cuz I don't care.
Speaker 0: if they you know, oh no, they're gonna get my data.
Speaker 0: They see that I look at Deviant something porn and I visit I don't know bad websites like FARC But I don't want to lose my data.
Speaker 0: So if I have a wireless saying I don't care if they see what I had I just don't want them to take it and not give it back.
Speaker 1: Oh, let's see.
Speaker 1: You know what they do when you When they come to get you most of the time all the police at least untrained, you know Untechnical police in this country.
Speaker 1: I've looked into what they do when they're doing investigations.
Speaker 1: They have this program called in case which is you know, isn't that the thing that only runs in Windows?
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's.
Speaker 1: it's a program that has been held up, you know in the court of law in the United States.
Speaker 1: so evidence collected by in cases submissible in court and Admissible in court and all it does is look at your hard drive on the bit level, you know It understands a bunch of different types of file systems and it collects all the files It can find on your.
Speaker 1: you know Reading your hard drive sort of at the lowest level it sort of tries to reconstruct your file system Figure out what kind they are and pick out whatever files it can possibly find.
Speaker 0: granted There are a lot of ways around and that's deniable encryption.
Speaker 1: Yes, but that's all they can do They don't you know, they they very few police other than I guess You know some high-level FBI type people will be intelligent enough or have the training enough to do any other sort of Investigations.
Speaker 1: if you know wireless San in your ducks and you didn't have a hard drive in your computer They would run there in case they'd be like, hey, there's no hard drives.
Speaker 0: What do you do with the hard drives?
Speaker 0: they pray accuse you of tampering with the evidence.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they wouldn't have the fuck clue what to do.
Speaker 0: That's why what you do is you have a dummy hard drive with Windows 95 and like some spyware and that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then your defense is the spyware did it and meanwhile your sand full of wares is just fine in the ducts.
Speaker 1: That's a good way to go.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we're not here to tell you exactly how to break the law and get away with it.
Speaker 0: That's for another Monday show.
Speaker 0: Haha I don't know that.
Speaker 0: it seems like a much more a lower level issue.
Speaker 0: Is that and this happens all over the world now, there are encounters between citizens of countries and law enforcement where law enforcement either are ignorant of the law or Ignorant of the crime and as a result when in doubt They really can't do anything but arrest people and it just causes trouble.
Speaker 1: I think the problem is is if they really stood by innocent until proven guilty.
Speaker 1: when in doubt you don't arrest people.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem is now.
Speaker 0: I'm not arguing either way.
Speaker 0: I'm just pointing out I think the real problem there is that Innocent until proven guilty or innocent beyond a reasonable doubt when it comes to technology and things on the internet.
Speaker 0: I Can say as an as a technology expert, I think Scott will agree that Situations where there isn't a reasonable doubt practically don't exist because there are so many ways That someone else could have committed any computer crime and there's almost no way to prove that you did jack or shit on the
Speaker 1: unless You have physical evidence like a camera Videotaping me at a computer in a building.
Speaker 1: I broke into typing away
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if you want to get away
Speaker 1: or in my possession files on Disks that that are contained illegal things that I definitely put there because you know But you
Speaker 0: have to have physical evidence that you put them there because you can't prove that.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, the computer might have been compromised, you know on a non networked machine in my house at CD ROM Fingerprints are on the CD like that, but I mean technology things like the RIAA.
Speaker 0: now that everyone's fighting the lawsuits It's turning out that wait a minute they can't prove it all that anyone did anything because all they have to go on is an IP address and There if all your evidence is electronic, there is always reasonable doubt.
Speaker 1: You might as well just not even go to trial.
Speaker 0: I think the only exception to that is certain kinds of data that are signed cryptographically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just about in which case you have no evidence because you can't decrypt it.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe if a conversation were signed and you can then say yeah beyond a reasonable doubt that person X sent this data To person.
Speaker 0: why I guess two people communicated this much data.
Speaker 0: We can't say more than that, but we know that fact.
Speaker 1: Yep, you could do that, right?
Speaker 0: It's time for sempre knee of the day.
Speaker 1: All right, that's not gonna go and stop it.
Speaker 0: What it's no good I believe you started it.
Speaker 1: I didn't start it.
Speaker 0: Ah, right.
Speaker 1: Anyways in like the 70s.
Speaker 0: So I remember a while ago we talked about as a thing of the day one of them some of those old old old flash Incredibly
Speaker 1: old school beats,
Speaker 0: you know those old kind of pre mean like before or around the time of all your base flash videos like coinbad or Hyaku Hyaku go juichi
Speaker 1: never do coin bird.
Speaker 0: Yes, I did coin bird.
Speaker 0: Okay, I did coin bird as an example of those things gone.
Speaker 0: horribly wrong All right, but I think Hyaku go juichi is the most well-known.
Speaker 0: That's the one with The Pokemons and the dead hobo in the room and Colin mockery and fee we Herman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well right around that time possibly a little bit before I don't remember exactly.
Speaker 0: there was another one that was commonly known to his hat baby and The URL which is gone now was Colin was talking about it and I forgot it But he I watched a bit of it today and I remembered it now.
Speaker 0: This is a this is really old and poorly done.
Speaker 0: But now that I know the whole story It's actually a lot more interesting.
Speaker 0: They would have thought I'll tell the story.
Speaker 0: Well, the original URL was come dot to slash Hatton.
Speaker 1: Oh, I remember now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this is one of those things where the people would pass links around like hey Check this out zombocom.
Speaker 0: Oh man.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll trade you back.
Speaker 0: Check out this thing.
Speaker 0: come to dot Hatton.
Speaker 0: Well, the video doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 0: It's basically a bunch of poorly pixelated people with a hat that kind of moves from person to person and this happy old guy and The song is spelled out phonetically with fake subtitles, but unlike Hyaku go juichi.
Speaker 0: It's Gibberish.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not actually gibberish.
Speaker 0: It's Swedish.
Speaker 0: You see apparently in 1984 in Lebanon someone recorded a song called Hobby tick for the wedding of the daughter of one of his friends and it's sung in Arabic.
Speaker 0: I'm paraphrasing from the website here.
Speaker 0: in 1984 plus aka 1985 in Sweden.
Speaker 0: a UN officer named Nyberg Got a cassette of this music brought it back to Sweden and gave it to his son Patrick.
Speaker 0: So in the 90s Patrick and his friends were drunk and they realized that the name of the song how beat ik sounds kind of like the translated Habib is singing in Swedish and A lot of the words in the song if sounded phonetically kind of sound like things from a popular drinking song in Sweden that involves a hat.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So someone made an mp3 flash combination and Among all the people in Sweden.
Speaker 0: This was like the funniest thing ever.
Speaker 1: I imagine if I was Swedish and I was familiar with the song and the drinking game It would be the funniest thing ever.
Speaker 0: So it came to the US and people found it and they still thought it was funny.
Speaker 0: But just because they thought it was weird the same way He was right.
Speaker 0: Hyaku go juichi is whatever he's whatever The point.
Speaker 0: actually I had no idea what that word was for like five years until Emily told me the point is.
Speaker 0: The point is is that well the real point the thing of the day is not just oh, here's the history of hat, baby.
Speaker 0: And oh, here's an archive of hat baby where you can watch it.
Speaker 0: I'll warn you.
Speaker 0: It's pretty bad.
Speaker 0: Someone made this website that explains the entire history of this with translations explanations pictures screenshots the whole deal.
Speaker 0: Mad props to this person for tracking down all this information.
Speaker 1: It could just be made up.
Speaker 0: I'm reasonably certain that this is true.
Speaker 0: I validated it from numerous sources.
Speaker 0: I looked at all other other people who have translated the song and gotten similar results.
Speaker 1: Okay, then yeah, whatever Alright, so my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It's a video site, but this video site the videos aren't really that great.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch them until today, but they didn't really entertain.
Speaker 1: However, it is still thing of the day worthy.
Speaker 1: This site is called.
Speaker 1: I hate young people.
Speaker 0: calm, huh?
Speaker 1: Damn kids get off my lawn And I think the point of this site is they want to get videos of old people complaining about punk kids.
Speaker 0: So what the kids move too quick?
Speaker 1: I can't see him can't get him with the shotgun something like that, and there's also a few videos of punk kids complaining about old people.
Speaker 1: and You know generally old people don't like us punk kids and they're always complaining and I like seem to forget when their parents would complain about them and they're rocking and they're rolling and now they're complaining about our hip and enter hopping That I've never got that.
Speaker 0: And it's happened for as long as we've had civilization that the parents of any generation Think that the music of their kids is stupid
Speaker 1: not just the music but the entire culture of their kids they like look down on it like it's like it's crap and worthless and Like they're like, oh, it's not even music It's just just like their parents said all that rock and roll is not even music It's just noise.
Speaker 0: and you know what we're seeing.
Speaker 0: the same thing accelerate.
Speaker 1: I mean the thing Nintendo fanboys.
Speaker 0: look back look on kids who only have a ps1 or a ps2.
Speaker 0: is man?
Speaker 0: You punk kids don't know anything about video games.
Speaker 1: I don't understand though because like I Look back on the old people and I say well there was a culture and I look at the people younger than me and I said Well, there's a culture and I don't look on any of it.
Speaker 1: Like I don't say all those punk like I don't like the emo music, but I don't say oh, that's not music It's not worth having.
Speaker 1: But the these old people they had people treating them the same way that they're treating us when they were kids.
Speaker 1: Listen to the rock and roll and they didn't learn the lesson at all.
Speaker 0: What I realized
Speaker 1: is I learned a lot of a lot
Speaker 0: of the complaints that old people were making just from what you were playing In the background, we're kind of weird Like young people fill up the train and get in our way and like make it difficult for me to get off the train.
Speaker 0: But I don't think that has anything to do with a young people.
Speaker 0: I think that's just.
Speaker 0: you're too old to be on a train.
Speaker 1: I think yeah.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of things they perceive as being young people is like.
Speaker 1: as they get old You get slower and then things happen to you and you can't.
Speaker 1: you're not as able as you were before.
Speaker 1: When you see the young people moving the way you moved when you were young You don't ever think that you're a slower.
Speaker 1: you think they're getting.
Speaker 1: they're fast and in the way where you know Whereas actually the problem is is that you're slow and old and in the way and they're trying to get around you because you're holding Them up.
Speaker 0: the other constant complaint that they kept bringing up was yeah these kids with technology Some that didn't wasn't even really any specific complaint.
Speaker 0: It was just these kids got to stop it with the iPods and a statement like that doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't make any sense at all.
Speaker 0: I just I can't imagine getting to a point in my life ever where I would stop advancing along with technology or where I would Say all right everything made after me is new and crap and everything made before me is old and crap.
Speaker 0: And I'm staying right here where I am.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: How did how can someone get that way?
Speaker 1: Stop trying especially when you're you know from a generation that was treated the way they're treating us.
Speaker 1: It's like they didn't learn.
Speaker 1: they just kept the same anyway.
Speaker 1: The thing on this site that I find really funny is that they are.
Speaker 1: not only do they have some videos that they took on The street obviously you know with their own camera but there's they're asking for people to submit like their own webcam videos complaining about young punk kids and As a right
Speaker 0: what old people know how to use a digital camera.
Speaker 1: and as of right.
Speaker 1: now There are three videos on the site.
Speaker 1: one of them I didn't watch any of these but one of them is titled I hate old people.
Speaker 1: so of the three videos And I hate young people calm that were webcam videos submitted by users.
Speaker 1: I think at most two of them are actually old people.
Speaker 1: They don't look that old.
Speaker 0: they look maybe like 30s 40s Something old people can't make 10 YouTube videos.
Speaker 1: It's so funny is that they're asking old people who hate this sort of thing to Use this sort of thing to be like young people to complain about you.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's a trap?
Speaker 1: No wonder.
Speaker 1: There's only three submissions and one of them is yeah a young guy It makes.
Speaker 1: no you know.
Speaker 1: what they should have had is they should have had old people.
Speaker 1: Send in you know rigging Nickelodeon's with you know.
Speaker 1: could their complaints about young people?
Speaker 1: You know just holding up signs and in all the pictures in black and white or something.
Speaker 1: Or maybe send us like you know they're.
Speaker 1: they're.
Speaker 1: they're Edison wax cylinders with their complaints about young people and wax cylinders.
Speaker 0: with a business There's so much crisper than modern CDs and flak files.
Speaker 1: Tell me about it.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's analog right so the resolution is infinite.
Speaker 1: Okay, do you wanna talk about the show now right?
Speaker 0: so Speaking of technology.
Speaker 0: We don't have to go long about this because it's actually a pretty to the point issue.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got a lot to say though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do too, but we could.
Speaker 0: most of the things I have to say I can actually break up into much more specific shows.
Speaker 0: All right the idea is simply that corporations in Particular partly because of the fact that they they outlive the people who form them And they tend to have kind of a mind of their own like bureaucracies in any other form Tend to Misapply technology and/or have problems that could be easily solved with technology that either They don't understand they could be solved or they do But they don't know how and they're unwilling to pay or listen to people who do understand.
Speaker 1: Oh, they don't even realize they have a problem Or it's.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: basically the only way to sum it up in a few words is to say companies don't understand technology.
Speaker 1: That's and I could just go into just like a million different ways in which they don't understand it.
Speaker 1: like People will have a company and they know they want to get something done with technology But they'll ask for something that is technologically impossible.
Speaker 1: like I've known two or three people already who work in like 3d animation Modeling companies in some way and someone will say Make Toy Story for me in like a day or a week, and it's like okay you obviously don't understand that that takes like a hundred million dollars and a giant facility and it takes a team of like A hundred people a few years
Speaker 0: or people who in a tech company.
Speaker 0: Here's a good example Because it's not just you know Optimistic or stupid possible solutions things.
Speaker 0: It's also just not using the tools you have to do a job much more efficiently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the exact opposite.
Speaker 1: problem.
Speaker 1: is they they want to use technology so much They want to do something impossible or there's something very possible and very easy They could do to greatly improve their business, but they don't do it or don't even think to do it.
Speaker 0: You think I mean, we just need to send them to ZomboCon for like five minutes.
Speaker 1: I mean anything's possible except making Toy Story in a day, right?
Speaker 0: But like here's a good example.
Speaker 0: at a company I may or may not work for currently There's a form that is filled out whenever you want to make a new PC and it says you know What image to put on the PC and what?
Speaker 0: Applications and what name it's gonna get and where it's gonna go and who's gonna own it and all this business.
Speaker 0: And it's a digital form that populates the database and then other applications pretty advanced.
Speaker 1: They're actually doing something, right?
Speaker 0: I know and that's that's what bothers me because they're so close.
Speaker 0: Okay so then that form is then used from about in the back end by people who can one it populates the Inventory database and two from there the people who actually do the imaging get all the information and the process is semi-automated.
Speaker 0: So, uh say this company gets a big contract and they're gonna roll out thousands and thousands of pcs and say they Do to a weeks long effort have compiled a database of all of these pcs That have to be replaced and everything that needs to go on them.
Speaker 0: So now I've got a database of all the pcs that need to be put out Yep And I've got a separate incompatible database of all all the ways to make a PC that'll actually get them made.
Speaker 1: so you write a script to read from one and write to reformat and write to the other.
Speaker 0: or You ask rim to manually do data entry into the stupid goddamn form in the one database from the other database.
Speaker 1: because why don't you just write a script?
Speaker 0: because I don't have access to the back Ends of either of those databases and no one under no one hypothetically in this hypothetical company Understands that maybe you should have a DBA who could just do this and then no work needs to be done by
Speaker 1: That with like two SQLs and a bash.
Speaker 0: I could probably make the point that this that the hour the billable hours that hypothetically would be spent on this hypothetical project at this hypothetical company by a hypothetical employee named rim would cost more than Hiring a goddamn external consultant to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the thing is is that companies they they either Try to get there to get their hands in the technology too much or they stay away from it too much.
Speaker 1: This is how if you're a business person, right?
Speaker 1: The first thing you need to do is get competent technology people.
Speaker 1: I know that's difficult if you you don't know enough about technology to get good technology people.
Speaker 1: But let me just tell you this if you're if you're not able to fire half your company because they've been replaced by computers Then you don't have good technology people.
Speaker 1: Yes I mean that might sound callous but in and there are a lot of exceptions to this technology people at companies I mean like it is cruel that you know Firing people and they lose their jobs because they've been replaced by machines and all that.
Speaker 1: but regardless of that When I think about you know, setting up IT for a company to make their business run better.
Speaker 1: I think the measure of my success is how many people's jobs I can automate And how much less there is to do because computers do it all.
Speaker 1: that's what I consider making it better.
Speaker 1: That's what's supposed to happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I mean there are a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: companies fuck this off.
Speaker 0: You can never fire everyone.
Speaker 0: you're always gonna need people and also a lot of times you'll make them.
Speaker 0: You don't have to fire people.
Speaker 0: instead because you've removed You know the bullshit paperwork that you know 80% of your employees have to do all the time.
Speaker 0: Now all that all those billable hours can now be spent on your actual company's business Which means you can either fire those people or do a bunch more business.
Speaker 1: Yep But basically what you want to do to hit is first get the good technology people, which might be hard But once you have good technology people, all you have to do is tell them what you want.
Speaker 1: So for example, this is a good idea.
Speaker 1: come to Scott and say hey Scott I need a list of this.
Speaker 1: Alright, if you just tell me that I'll have a list of that in like a you know a second cuz.
Speaker 1: I just know the command.
Speaker 1: I just whoop and there it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah now maybe a technologist like if you ask me make a Cisco router that does blah.
Speaker 0: I don't remember all the syntax offhand, but you know what by the next by 24 hours from now?
Speaker 0: I've already looked it up and done it.
Speaker 1: See what I think saying is Cisco.
Speaker 1: rather does blah is already too deep for them to be telling?
Speaker 1: Well, yeah true.
Speaker 1: They want to say you want to say we need to have these computers, you know Not even that.
Speaker 1: they want to say we want actually able to do this.
Speaker 0: I think you inadvertently brought up a big issue that the core issue The core deal here is not just that they don't understand technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the real problem is that a lot of businesses Don't document and don't understand their own business Processes on any fundamental level at all.
Speaker 0: and a lot of people say oh like ISO certification all those things are BS.
Speaker 0: But a lot of those business II type certifications what they really do is come into your company and look Do you have a process an actual process as in?
Speaker 0: could an outside person come in?
Speaker 0: Look at a product like an input and an output.
Speaker 0: an input being customer wants X output being Product is shipped to customer and could they read Documentation that would follow the path of that product and all the things that an employee has to do at each step of the way From start to finish.
Speaker 1: Yeah, for example, if I came to your factory and I got a job as assembly guy assembly line guy number 10 Is there a piece of paper or a binder of papers that tell me how to do that job?
Speaker 1: And could I read that binder and then perform that job?
Speaker 1: because that should be true of every job.
Speaker 1: There should be a binder that says how the job is done.
Speaker 0: Yes, obviously there are exceptions for highly technical Highly.
Speaker 1: Well, you don't say well, I mean for example for my job, right?
Speaker 1: You wouldn't say do this exact thing to do the job here.
Speaker 0: Let me break it down because I actually deal with this a lot on an enterprise level.
Speaker 0: What you need to look at is not you know what the person does.
Speaker 0: It's more what are the inputs and outputs at each stage?
Speaker 0: and then can you reduce the number of inputs?
Speaker 0: or can you?
Speaker 0: Lessen the impact of these inputs on the person doing the process.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And I could go into stupid boring detail about it but a lot of businesses even very large businesses and I've worked for a couple of very large companies and I can say for a Fact that a lot of them don't bother with this though.
Speaker 0: Actually IBM was really good about it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm If you don't understand your processes and I mean really understand them Then no amount of technology is gonna help you because you're not even going to be able to ask a technologist to do your process.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so forget technology.
Speaker 0: That's not even the issue.
Speaker 0: You need to understand what your business does long before you can hire someone like me or Scott to make it go better.
Speaker 1: But even then if you just hire someone like me and you don't even know your process Odds are give you or any.
Speaker 1: like any company I've ever seen I can just walk in and hang around your business for a few days Probably a few hours and immediately see things that could be vastly improved by technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean God my company.
Speaker 0: now I could definitely I could I'm dead serious single-handedly revolutionized the way my company works Yeah, and it would be trivial.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't even need to hire extra people.
Speaker 0: I could do it in the spare time I have at work now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I go.
Speaker 1: every place I've worked, you know I look at the way things are done and I say well if I just did this This job would take like 10 minutes a day instead of two full-time people.
Speaker 0: the thing is though that sort of argument isn't really feasible because in a large corporation or even a medium-sized one with Bureaucracy and with you know, the business is running and all that sort of thing It's not really fair to say.
Speaker 0: Oh just hire a technologist and they'll fix things for you because while that's kind of true Oftentimes if you do it that way the solution that is put in Won't always be the most documented thing or more importantly you won't understand what the person did So you won't be able to ask him or anyone else how to make it better.
Speaker 1: Yep Also, the thing is that you know, the only excuse I think because a lot of people say, ah, you know The technology fails to help the business to the full potential because the people in the business not understanding not caring Etc.
Speaker 1: etc.
Speaker 1: But there's only one excuse that I think is the okay excuse for Not improving your business with technology to make it You know more efficient when possible and that is profits because there are cases where.
Speaker 1: well we could do this And if we did that it would make all this work easier and such but that would cost us like a bajillion dollars.
Speaker 0: We don't have for example Say my business process is really dumb and anyone could do all the steps of the way and it's super labor-intensive.
Speaker 0: But because anyone can do it I hire a bunch of nobody replaceable people and that's a lot cheaper than streamlining the process and hiring competent people
Speaker 1: Yep, or even just hiring one computer guy who will set up a computer to do the work at these 10 minimum wage people.
Speaker 1: You know I mean like you think about how much it costs to like buy and maintain a machine that flips burgers Versus just hiring some teenagers.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: that's why a lot despite the fact that people say they will be eventually McDonald's and Burger Kings are not automated in the US because labor even in a country like this with you know Inflated standard of living and everything is so much cheaper than technology for menial job.
Speaker 1: and then even then okay So you the machine is cheaper than the employees, right?
Speaker 1: I gotta maintain them you gotta maintain the machine even then it's still cheaper.
Speaker 1: You have to pay the guy who maintains the machine and that guy.
Speaker 1: you know, he's a smart guy and he needs a lot of Money, he's not gonna work for the chump change.
Speaker 1: But that guy for that one guy you could hire like a thousand burger flipping kids.
Speaker 0: But for most companies, especially medium-sized and larger Larger companies that have a bunch of people sitting in offices like doing paperwork If you have more than say a hundred employees then I say this is almost universally true.
Speaker 0: If you understand your business process and document it and then you go to Technologists and say I want to implement this process better Nine times out of ten that's going to happen and your company's gonna save so much money You can't even
Speaker 1: believe at least in the long run.
Speaker 1: in the short term You're gonna have to spend thousands of dollars on computer equipment, but in the long run You're gonna save so much money on paying people to do crap and wasting time doing crap.
Speaker 1: You were wasting time on before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I guess I can't stress this enough.
Speaker 0: The issue is not oh people just don't understand technology.
Speaker 0: The issue is people don't understand their own businesses.
Speaker 0: Therefore not understanding technology is not actually hurting them that much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even if they did understand their own business, it's they don't.
Speaker 1: really they don't.
Speaker 1: It's like they can't grasp completely how technology can help them and to technology people who also don't understand the business.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it's really obvious to us how certain business processes could be extremely streamlined.
Speaker 1: Like I see people like for example in my job, right?
Speaker 1: Someone was they were faxing in pieces of paper.
Speaker 1: All right, someone was manually checking over those faxes one at a time and entering them into a spreadsheet, right?
Speaker 1: so we made a web form and we the people who are sending in the fax is now fill out the web form which goes directly into the database and then if you want a report I push a button and a report comes out and Without someone like me they wouldn't know that that was even possible or an idea or anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yet it improves that.
Speaker 1: that's now the person who looked over the faxes Doesn't have to do that anymore saving hours and hours.
Speaker 0: I guess I should clarify that.
Speaker 0: for a business with very simple or very obvious and trivial business processes Then the business process angle doesn't apply.
Speaker 0: but for larger companies or companies that have complex business processes Almost no amount of because you know, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: a company that big they think oh we got to be all high-tech It's the higher tech people to do tech stuff.
Speaker 0: but if they don't understand what those tech people actually need to do specifically at least in terms of The technology needs to have these inputs and these outputs Then the technology is gonna fail and not be efficient and cost a lot of money.
Speaker 0: and then they'll think oh, yeah Those technology people fucked us and then they won't ever try to increase the technology again in the future.
Speaker 1: Well in many ways it mirrors, you know average consumers buying technology at the stores.
Speaker 1: They don't understand their own needs.
Speaker 1: They buy things that don't meet their needs or exceed their needs and they're just not wise when it comes to Solving their problems with technology.
Speaker 1: and that is the one, you know people think all computer nerds.
Speaker 1: They know how to make these crazy machines work.
Speaker 1: what we do But most importantly is we know how the best ways to get the machines to make life easier And a lot of people don't do that.
Speaker 1: You see people like with their Windows machines full of a bunch of programs everywhere And it's it just shows you.
Speaker 1: they have this machine and they might know how to.
Speaker 1: I am an email and stuff But they don't know how to do things in a way that Significantly increases the productivity in their life or saves them a lot of time.
Speaker 1: That's really the purpose of these machines.
Speaker 0: That's why there's such a stigma especially among I don't want to say older people because that's a stereotype That's I mean there's truth in it, but it's definitely not globally true.
Speaker 0: but people who aren't as familiar with Technology tend to look down as technology saying that it's not actually more efficient or it's just a time waster.
Speaker 0: It's not any better.
Speaker 0: and a lot of that's just because they don't understand how to use the technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean I my computer and a lot of that is that other people don't understand how to use it either and they see all These people who should know not knowing and it just.
Speaker 0: it's kind of this self-perpetuating stigma.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and I think that that's really if you want to get ahead in the technology world You have to be able you have to be yet to get the skill and the knowledge to know How you check now not just how to use a computer or how to program it or whatever but how to apply?
Speaker 1: technology to solve problems and make life better for Individual people and groups of people in a very significant way and be able to execute on that.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that is where I mean IT.
Speaker 0: I'm an IT guy.
Speaker 0: I'm an IT professional.
Speaker 0: I've worked at like super big corporations.
Speaker 0: I have a degree.
Speaker 0: Scott has a degree in computer science.
Speaker 0: But while I can configure routers and configure switches and write firewall rules That's not the value of a technologist because you can hire someone fresh out of you can buy a book at borders.
Speaker 0: No not even that you can hire some high school kid who got his MSCE and his CDNA who can do those jobs just as well as I can because it's basically making license plates.
Speaker 0: It's trivial once you once someone knows the commands to type the commands don't change.
Speaker 0: The important part is Someone who can look at a business and say you need this router and you need these computers and this system.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you who to hire to make that work and then that person doesn't have to do anything else But the person who can go to a business or a person and say based on what they tell them and by questioning them and interrogating Them.
Speaker 0: All right based on what you've told me.
Speaker 0: I think I have a solution in mind that will meet all of your needs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can come in.
Speaker 1: I could set up you know a database cluster and a web application and a client-side application and With that you should be able to.
Speaker 1: it'll cost you this much right now, but in another year It's gonna save you this much time and this much money.
Speaker 0: companies need to be willing to hire people who will honestly Appraise the situation and just tell them exactly what needs to be done.
Speaker 1: You need to let those people do what they want to do and don't try to mess with them because they know better than you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a matter of translation.
Speaker 0: It's the person who translates between the business speak, you know well, I got 40 users and they need to access their web jiggers and The IT guy just translates that into Scott speak which is all right.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make a database that does this and put it on this server and do that.
Speaker 0: Yep I think we're done.
Speaker 1: I guess they're just generally pissed off.
Speaker 1: when we see companies, you know working We see people going to work and we see people doing things like using a spreadsheet for a day Having a database and not we'll make it up.
Speaker 0: close and personal Podcasting.
Speaker 0: this is a podcast right?
Speaker 0: Yeah it take and this is no exaggeration All of our all the people we know who do podcasts with rare exceptions It take in the time it takes them to record edit and put up one hours worth of content.
Speaker 0: We do a whole week.
Speaker 0: Yep, no exaggeration none.
Speaker 1: I mean you do more than a week.
Speaker 1: This show will be uploaded and done within four minutes of me hitting stop Wow, yeah, and other people, you know, listen to their entire show and then while they edit it that way So that would at least take us an hour per show.
Speaker 1: This shows probably over what.
Speaker 0: now the whole process is automated.
Speaker 0: once we're done recording I click make the show and then I type upload dot py Basically and I have programs that do all the post-processing.
Speaker 0: everything's uploaded it.
Speaker 1: it would take a human hours to do this But it takes a computer seconds and that's why computers are great And that's why all the people using garage band and when they edit their show They listen to the entire show all the way.
Speaker 0: and that's why I searched on Craigslist for podcast And I realized that there's a lot of money in consulting for companies who want to do a podcast but don't understand how?
Speaker 0: Learn the shit or pay someone who knows This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.