Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, October 30th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm companion to you and this is portal tonight geek nights Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I Beat that phantom hourglass on the train home today.
Speaker 1: Oh, did you?
Speaker 0: I did I didn't get anywhere near all this stuff in the game, but you on a scale of one to five minish caps.
Speaker 1: How was it?
Speaker 0: Wait one to five minish cap?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a thousand minish caps.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I know I guess minish caps are bad.
Speaker 0: So it would be zero minish caps.
Speaker 1: Ah, you see it was a trick question.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's good.
Speaker 0: It's not like the best.
Speaker 0: It's not like SNES Zelda or anything like that, but you know, it's a good game, you know.
Speaker 0: And it's like it's sort of weird cuz it's unlike other Zelda games Which like minish cap was sort of all bad, you know and Zelda 64 was sort of all good.
Speaker 0: This is sort of like some parts are really good like that Goron dungeon.
Speaker 0: That was the fucking dungeon Goddamn, but the main like the the ocean Kings dungeon.
Speaker 1: so bad From what you and Alex were saying.
Speaker 1: the co-op or not the co-op but like the multiplayer DS action It hasn't got.
Speaker 0: it has a multiplayer mode and like many DS games They sort of tack on a multiplayer mode like say New Super Mario Brothers.
Speaker 0: They tack on some multiplayer.
Speaker 1: Ah, I still can't express to you enough how disappointed I was in that because it they could have done something amazing with that Multiplayer.
Speaker 1: instead they made something insipid, right?
Speaker 0: Well, the multiplayer they have tacked on to Zelda Phantom Hourglass is actually sort of related to a part of the game and is actually Quite good.
Speaker 0: It's it's fun and strategic and it's like it's a good two people game.
Speaker 0: So Phantom Hourglass will probably talk about it more if when rim plays it.
Speaker 0: but some parts of it are great some parts of it annoying It's if you have a DS and you're looking for a game that'll take you know 10 to 20 hours of fun.
Speaker 1: get advanced wars to.
Speaker 0: if you are advanced wars You don't have it already.
Speaker 0: But you know, this is this is on the list somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though speaking of new games I you know Scott works in the city and Emily works in the city and I well didn't have to go anywhere Yesterday.
Speaker 0: cuz you're not starting work until what next Monday Guy Fawkes day.
Speaker 1: Yep, but So Scott says that well, you should go get guitar hero 3.
Speaker 0: Well, I was gonna go get it on my way home, but I remember that rim wasn't going to work.
Speaker 0: He was.
Speaker 0: he's unemployed for a week.
Speaker 0: So I said, why should I fucking get it?
Speaker 1: You go get it Yeah, and curiously enough it would sold out a GameStop.
Speaker 0: I figured that already it would be sold out just about everywhere.
Speaker 0: That's why I wanted you to run around town looking for it, but I didn't have to run around.
Speaker 1: I went to the target next door and they had plenty.
Speaker 1: However, they were sold out of the ps2 version apparently and at the GameStop I asked the guy and sure enough the PlayStation 2 version of guitar hero 3 sold out immediately.
Speaker 0: Well, that makes the most sense considering, you know PlayStation 2 is the only system that has all the guitar heroes and most people who have guitar hero have it on those systems.
Speaker 0: Right, and if you're gonna buy guitar hero 3, why would you get it for?
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 1: The 360 a system where you're only gonna have one guitar.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, no the 360. you can have more guitars because guitar hero 2 is on the 360.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even if you only have ps2 guitars Which most people do right if you have ps2 guitars already the game isn't any different on the ps2.
Speaker 0: not not significantly different.
Speaker 0: So you would get the ps2 version because you already have guitars like.
Speaker 0: we got the Wii version, right?
Speaker 0: Which I think was a good choice, even though it goes against my prior plan.
Speaker 0: I think It was a good idea.
Speaker 1: It's worth it.
Speaker 1: I got to say though The funny thing is the Xbox 360 version didn't sell at all.
Speaker 1: the GameStop had it and the target had a pile of them.
Speaker 1: But what did sell out was the Wii one and there were three left.
Speaker 1: the first one was dented to all hell.
Speaker 1: So I reached behind and grabbed the second one.
Speaker 1: and while I'm looking at it, you know doing my mental check of yes It's the Wii version.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's the right one.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 1: I hear a guy right around the corner and he's talking to a target employee.
Speaker 1: He says yeah, I was in the Wii section I can't find guitar hero through.
Speaker 1: and then he comes around the corner goes Oh, never mind.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then he looks goes back past the dented all hell.
Speaker 0: one grabs the other.
Speaker 0: we know someone bought that dead All hell one.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, cuz there are only three lovely within like 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: But yeah, we got it.
Speaker 0: it is I must say of all the guitar hero guitars I have used and I've used the original the guitar hero to ps2 and I've never used the 360 ones But this is the best one yet.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: one that because I'm gonna bust right in this is my news - this game came out All right The guitar won the net comes off which is just great for carrying the stupid thing around And the faceplate comes off and we're gonna be able to buy all skin cool faceplates.
Speaker 1: I'm waiting for some sort of Mario with an axe.
Speaker 0: I'm waiting for something really cool.
Speaker 1: Perhaps maybe perhaps link with an axe or shadow with an axe.
Speaker 0: something cool will come out I guarantee you.
Speaker 1: now it came with all these stickers, but with one exception.
Speaker 0: the stickers are all I think the old guitar heroes Also came with stickers.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: the stickers are all stupid and actually Because the guitar is white and the wiimote is white and the wiimote sticks in the back But kind of pokes out through the front I think it looks pretty snazzy in this kind of black and white minimalist way and
Speaker 0: I don't
Speaker 1: plan to modify
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 0: I also think it looks pretty snazzy and I will not be buying a faceplate.
Speaker 0: That is gaudy.
Speaker 1: I will tell you that now also genius on the upper like right on the top of the guitar.
Speaker 1: They put a little analog stick meaning one.
Speaker 1: you can play Mario 1 with the guitar Which I did and it's actually not that hard to do.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it was like green is a and red is B reason the analog stick is there so I don't need navigate the Wii menu and Actually turn the game on without having to use another score.
Speaker 1: Of course Scott gets home and he picks it up.
Speaker 1: He's like, ah, can I use it just?
Speaker 1: and he starts trying to point the guitar at the TV.
Speaker 1: He's like, it's not working.
Speaker 1: This is bullshit.
Speaker 1: And I'm like Scott.
Speaker 1: There's an analog stick Scott.
Speaker 0: There's an analog sticks and then I was listening to you like two minutes later.
Speaker 1: He's like, oh wow, there's rim.
Speaker 1: check it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much Tom and not listening to you.
Speaker 1: But I saw complaints on the internet about guitar hero 3 one of which was that the game Lags.
Speaker 1: and all I have to say is no if the game is lagging then some of your audio-visual equipment is broken.
Speaker 1: Yep, or you set it up poorly or something because the game does not like at all.
Speaker 1: Nope, and the guitar is heavy.
Speaker 1: It's solid.
Speaker 1: the noises when you screw up come out of the Wiimote and not out of the TV and that is so hot.
Speaker 1: That is so hot, especially when we're gonna play some co-op.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I'll hear it coming out of Scott's guitar.
Speaker 0: Oh, I hear it coming out of rims guitar more.
Speaker 0: so.
Speaker 1: well I think my favorite thing is that when you activate the star power Not only does the music get echoey and loud and don't you hear the crowd yelling and screaming?
Speaker 1: But you get some vibration going on in the in the guitar vibration coming out of the guitar and it makes it Just.
Speaker 0: it feels like guitar also vibrates a little bit when star power is, you know acquired.
Speaker 0: It's like you have star power Just so you know.
Speaker 1: plus because you're using the Wiimote which has I guess better accelerometers.
Speaker 1: It does that I never Activated the star power by accident something that happened all the time in the original guitar.
Speaker 0: So always activated the star power successfully on purpose Yep.
Speaker 1: And also like I can hold the guitar kind of up and it doesn't go like oh if you've tilted it activates.
Speaker 1: if you just give It a good knock up or a knock down it activates.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just got to you know, shake the accelerometers a bit to activate it.
Speaker 1: The song selection is of course Fantastic.
Speaker 1: I don't think I need to get into that.
Speaker 0: I am though I think that I've yet to play all the songs or unlock them all but it does feel like so far You know being I guess most of the way through the game that there's a lot me It's called legends of rock so I can.
Speaker 0: I can see why it's got all these awesome songs painted black.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that you know are already know like classic awesome rocks Hot shit.
Speaker 0: I gotta say these songs rock.
Speaker 0: However The thing I liked about guitar hero 1 & 2 is like this especially in guitar.
Speaker 0: There are lots of songs that I had never heard before and did not know and restored, you know sort of more independent I guess not completely independent but more independent and less record company.
Speaker 0: that I didn't know.
Speaker 0: but we're awesome and it feels like this game is Lacking a large quantity of those types of songs.
Speaker 1: So the only real thing this game is lacking I mean I could go in more about the Wii version or whatever, but it's fine Is that there's no Queen and there's no Led Zeppelin.
Speaker 0: That's just not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: now I know Scott I I think agree and I think you will too that if I were Led Zeppelin I would make a deal with them and release Stairway by itself for like 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: because you know people would buy that.
Speaker 0: I would buy it.
Speaker 1: I might do.
Speaker 1: But think about just a guitar hero stairway edition Ten bucks.
Speaker 0: I would buy only ten maybe 15 maybe.
Speaker 1: because imagine playing stairway here.
Speaker 0: I just Yeah, also we can't on the Wii.
Speaker 0: you can't buy spare guitars yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that changes I'll go buy one.
Speaker 1: The thing is you can play over the internet with the WFC.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, so cuz I want to do the co-op campaign with you.
Speaker 0: So I can't do that without another guitar.
Speaker 1: Well, I imagine we'll get a guitar pretty quick and - we're going to a party.
Speaker 0: I think next weekend They're not gonna have we guitars there.
Speaker 1: But if he buys guitar hero 3 for the Wii he's not.
Speaker 0: he's gonna buy for the ps2 because he's already got one to do.
Speaker 1: He's a dumbass.
Speaker 1: he's got all the ones for the ps2.
Speaker 0: He should accommodate us.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh for the Wii.
Speaker 0: Yes buy the Wii version then give us the guitar that you don't need.
Speaker 1: Now two other things I got to say.
Speaker 1: the there's this dual mode Where like in the single-player like you'll finish a set maybe an encore something.
Speaker 1: Sometimes someone will come and challenge you to a duel and at first I thought God This is gonna be the stupidest thing ever.
Speaker 0: It's not stupid.
Speaker 1: It's awesome actually doing it.
Speaker 1: It's pretty fun.
Speaker 0: and the songs and it's like, you know the first, you know, who is it?
Speaker 0: It's um Tamarello, I think yeah, and it's like.
Speaker 0: and then in the second one Yeah, they had they had him, you know play this song, you know for the challenge and it's wicked cool.
Speaker 0: You know, it's and it's not something you can hear anywhere else.
Speaker 1: And the thing is I am at I mean DDR had a battle mode and it kind of like reviewing the whole game for the show.
Speaker 1: Hey, that's fine Because we have nothing but positive things to say about our top.
Speaker 0: no, there's some negative things.
Speaker 1: There's news on the internet that supposedly I meant about our main topic not about Guitar Hero 3.
Speaker 0: Oh that the Dolby Pro Logic 2 if you're using that and the Wii version does some audio problems.
Speaker 0: That's what I read on the internet.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm not gonna get into it But if you know how Dolby Pro Logic works, well, you get what you deserve.
Speaker 1: Yep, and You can't get a spare guitar yet Yeah But from what I might the rumor mill is that they want.
Speaker 1: they push this game out and they didn't want to risk Not having enough guitars or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yep and cuz they knew anyone who bought the game was probably buy an extra guitar and I don't think they could have made as Not enough guitars to release the game and have it.
Speaker 0: It's like what would have happened was you would have gone to GameStop and they would had a pile of game.
Speaker 0: You know discs there and no guitars and you know, they would have sold, you know Only half as many games right away.
Speaker 1: Plus as I saw the game is selling out and a lot of places I don't pretty much everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the only What.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna say?
Speaker 1: I was gonna talk about how.
Speaker 1: the opening video they they have personified the god of rock in this game and you see him and all I want to say about that is that he looks exactly the way the god of rock should is a cross between Satan and Thor.
Speaker 0: There's one more thing what do you have to say, but I forgot it.
Speaker 1: Oh good game.
Speaker 1: So yeah Well, I can't - a lot of our friends made fun of us because we were not so good at Guitar Hero Because we never played it and we always said if we actually own the game we get good real quick and they're like I'm reminding them.
Speaker 1: Well because we're getting good real quick.
Speaker 0: Don't remind people of our shit.
Speaker 0: Talk.
Speaker 1: Our shit Talk is coming true.
Speaker 0: We're number one rule of shit talking.
Speaker 0: Don't really shit.
Speaker 0: Talk.
Speaker 1: I'm not really shit talking.
Speaker 1: I am preemptively bringing up the fact that I'm going to own some people at some battles in the near future.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: So what do you have in the news?
Speaker 1: Okay, so better than Guitar Hero 3 for the Wii.
Speaker 0: not my news.
Speaker 0: yours was not a news.
Speaker 0: It was a geek bite says cheating.
Speaker 1: It's also a news.
Speaker 1: It's both.
Speaker 0: I did - mine's actual news in the board gaming land.
Speaker 0: You know Mayfair games I do.
Speaker 0: they have a new policy.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yes the new policy is that If they're gonna sell a game, you know, then you're a game retailer.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're a gaming store, right and you buy some settlers copies, right?
Speaker 0: You're not allowed Now according to Mayfair games to sell those settlers copies for more than 20% off what you paid for them.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: No 20% off manufacturers suggested retail price.
Speaker 0: All right, huh, and this is legal, you know I mean Apple does this.
Speaker 0: no one's allowed to discount iPods, you know This.
Speaker 0: this used to be illegal and I think it's legal now.
Speaker 1: I don't think it should be legal but that's not the point.
Speaker 0: that's besides the point.
Speaker 0: but this is legal.
Speaker 0: now people have you know Talking about how it is legal.
Speaker 1: Well, because it's kind of a cut like I mean, I guess the way it would really work It's just that a company's within its rights to just say well, I'm not selling to you.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much what they're gonna do.
Speaker 0: If you let's say you order you buy a bunch of copies of settlers and you sell them for five bucks each.
Speaker 0: You know where you sell them at cost.
Speaker 0: then Mayfair games is gonna not let you buy any more copies of settlers.
Speaker 1: But the thing is you can't discount them too much or you're not gonna make any money.
Speaker 0: So but I think the problem here is what they're specific their specific goal in mind, right?
Speaker 0: Is that?
Speaker 0: Online retailers with no overhead Can put a much bigger discount on the games.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah say the local gaming store.
Speaker 1: however, this sets a bad precedent in the long run because uh There have been other games in the past particularly games workshop games where similar policies were in place.
Speaker 0: Yeah games workshop is nefarious for putting all sorts of restrictions Like websites are not allowed to use the games workshop logo on their site and they're not allowed to use certain words on their site.
Speaker 0: And you know, they're not allowed to cut the prices more than a certain amount.
Speaker 0: You know a games workshop has games workshop stores one of them's in New York City.
Speaker 0: I know where it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: Or you can order from their mail-order catalog and
Speaker 1: yeah, even though honestly I'll tell you this if you ever want anything games workshop the best way to do it play on find I know on eBay cuz there's always someone who realized that those games are bullshit and is selling their whole collection for not so much.
Speaker 0: Another good idea is to instead of playing Warhammer find some other miniatures game that is not made by games workshop Where the prices are not fixed on the miniatures and play that instead.
Speaker 0: It's just as good.
Speaker 1: if you just want to play Warhammer and you don't want to buy and deal with all the crap Find a friend who's really into Warhammer and just say hey, I kind of want to play Warhammer They'll give you an entire army just cuz they're desperate for someone to play with.
Speaker 1: could be you'll lose but you'll get better.
Speaker 0: It could be.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is is that there's some price fixing going on in the board game world And I think I'm pretty sure they're trying to you know crack down on.
Speaker 0: you know the internet retailers which kind of pisses me off because I like buying from the internet more than I like buying at the store because the Store is like 15 20 minutes away.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing cuz I'm sure doesn't have the wide selection of the internet or the low price.
Speaker 0: Well, except millennium games except millennium games.
Speaker 1: I will our way.
Speaker 1: I mean think when I will try hours away I'll drive to millennium games five hours away in Rochester, New York to buy board games oftentimes before I'll order them online.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but only that's one store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one not everyone has a millennium games.
Speaker 1: I think the real problem I mean I want to end people might argue that Well, maybe this will give a shot in the arm to the local game store in the gaming community and make gaming as a whole more.
Speaker 0: No, that's gonna make game buyers pissed off at Mayfair and I want to buy Mayfair games.
Speaker 0: They're just to get in games mad cheap.
Speaker 1: Well, my argument against that is is beyond.
Speaker 1: what Scott said is simply that game stores that foster community Don't need a shot in the arm like that because they can do just fine on their own.
Speaker 1: Game stores that fail tend to not realize that their biggest asset are the people who come to their store Yeah, and that by tricking them into coming to their store all the time They'll end up making a lot of money just from the fact that those people get other people into games who then go to the Yeah,
Speaker 0: but if you're Mayfair games right and let's and your customers are these stores you know and let's say 10 of the stores are awesome and foster a sense of community and are able to sell their games and 50 of the stores are not then you're not gonna make a lot of money because those 50 stores are Shitty at selling your products and there's not much you can do about.
Speaker 1: but you know what?
Speaker 0: in that case the stores not suck.
Speaker 1: Unlike games workshop Mayfair doesn't own these stores.
Speaker 1: if I were a Mayfair I'd say fuck you all and just Whoever online and if they sell things discounted I got the same amount of money either way.
Speaker 1: So I don't care.
Speaker 0: The problem is is they sell more if they can get all these stores to buy their stuff and keep it on the shelves Whereas online you're only get says the thing with with online You know selling is that the number of things you sell on.
Speaker 0: say amazon.com.
Speaker 0: right every book Amazon sells is a book Someone reads right.
Speaker 0: but meanwhile Every book that borders buys from the publisher.
Speaker 0: those might not all get read.
Speaker 0: So the publisher likes it when borders buys their books because borders buys a bunch of books Even if people don't actually buy them in the end.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah I like that.
Speaker 1: but are the borders near us where they have like one of every crappy manga just to have a shelf full of Manga, no one buys that manga because no one goes to?
Speaker 0: that is great.
Speaker 0: The cows just graze on it the manga cast.
Speaker 0: Yeah The way to make money as a publisher of things is to sell a lot of your product to retailers who will keep it on Shelves, which means you get money.
Speaker 1: whether any you know customers actually buy that probably depends I mean because one of the things that could be returnable well one of what destroyed Dungeons & Dragons back in the second ed days was at a point where there were a million books and they really weren't selling.
Speaker 1: and Then all at once all the Walden books just said, you know what we're sending all of this crap back And TSR almost went bankrupt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it goes a good times.
Speaker 1: If only they had gone bankrupt instead of being bought out with arts up that coast fall got to container items has bro.
Speaker 1: Hey, at least they did something smart.
Speaker 1: They got rid of whatever crap they had before and now forgotten realms is the actual campaign setting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's funny though how Wizards of the coast now sort of has like this monopoly over more and more of gaming.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's really just has bro.
Speaker 1: And luckily it hasn't affected me because I buy so few games.
Speaker 0: I got burning wheel books.
Speaker 0: You can take them from my cold dead hand And so D&D fuck you I don't care.
Speaker 0: and I've got my Tigris and Euphrates Which I bought for Mayfair Games before the price fixing days and you can take that from my cold dead hands, too.
Speaker 1: You know, we'll stop this very quickly and get to the main bit.
Speaker 1: but I just would like to say one thing too because I know a lot of you always are just kind of salivating for news of our burning wheel exploits.
Speaker 1: now that we're making the change and I would just like to say that Let this previous weekend when the Visigoths came and for once didn't destroy our house Because they came for less people per unit time.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna yeah, yeah, but regardless of all that there they were good But we're good.
Speaker 1: We played full-on burning wheel like straight and everyone knew the rules for the most part and we just hit the ground running.
Speaker 1: and all I have to say is That was the most fun I've had role-playing outside of being in the physical presence of Luke Crane since high school.
Speaker 1: That was so hot.
Speaker 1: it play burning wheel by the go to Luke Burning.
Speaker 0: we think about when he played.
Speaker 0: all I got to say is this the only I'll give you this anecdotal evidence When we play D&D, I'd be like getting up and getting food and going to the bathroom and kind of sleep.
Speaker 0: I there was the point at which I wasn't even doing much and I didn't want to get up to pee cuz I didn't want to miss Happen was awesome.
Speaker 1: I did a thing and I do this great awesome thing.
Speaker 1: great success all around.
Speaker 1: and then Pete tries to do something and it fails Miserably and causes horrible problems for us, but you know what both were equally awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was good times.
Speaker 1: So seriously We you know, we talked about our switching to burning wheel.
Speaker 1: and yeah, D&D is not so great You know what?
Speaker 1: I think I am done with Dungeons & Dragons forever.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine anything that would make me switch from burning wheel.
Speaker 0: No, I really couldn't.
Speaker 1: It's it's such a hot system.
Speaker 1: I all of you should buy it.
Speaker 0: I mean, even if you don't play it, it's 25 bucks for two books.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: And you know what if nothing else It's really fun to make characters in burning wheel.
Speaker 0: It's so fun.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I've been wanting to remake mine.
Speaker 0: so bad I might do it right.
Speaker 1: Alex Scott and I sat down one day and made characters and didn't even doing.
Speaker 0: I might say it's more Fun the entire hero because that's what I might be doing right after this show.
Speaker 1: You know, it kind of is.
Speaker 1: but I'm actually.
Speaker 1: when D&D ended I wasn't thinking.
Speaker 1: Oh man time to get some food.
Speaker 1: I was thinking oh man.
Speaker 1: I want to play more burning wheel.
Speaker 0: Fight for what I believe in things of the day Statress.
Speaker 1: it's just countries stasis statress like state wrists or state tris.
Speaker 1: It's countries states countries falling down From the north to the south and you got to rotate them left and right and land them where they go And it's actually really really fun.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 1: That should teach you a lot about Geographies, yeah, I was surprised how on one hand I knew a lot more than I thought I did about certain areas But on the other hand, I didn't know anything about some area.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw you playing.
Speaker 0: it was a map of Europe, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I totally like the Balkans like I knows the names of a bunch of countries over there like, you know, Serbia.
Speaker 1: See, I know that whole area like Hers a Covina.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh is it anyway, so you see that's how that place would be.
Speaker 0: just big gap I would fuck it all up.
Speaker 1: See I remember it cuz like one's eating the other one like an amoeba and I know that whole area But other places not so much.
Speaker 1: I forgot where Andorra wins.
Speaker 0: I have no clue where Andorra goes.
Speaker 0: I know where Cyprus goes But it's kind of fun.
Speaker 1: It's worth five minutes of your time.
Speaker 0: All right, so here's a cool flash game called electro city.
Speaker 0: It's supposed to be an educational flash game, but whatever.
Speaker 0: basically it's sort of like Sim City in a way And you've got this little tiny grid.
Speaker 0: It's like five by five and there's a little coast and maybe some mountains and some woods and in the middle Square is your city and that's the only square that's gonna have your city on it.
Speaker 0: So basically you're trying to do.
Speaker 0: you can do stuff on every other square to try to make your city bigger, right?
Speaker 0: I mean you have money right and you can adjust.
Speaker 0: there's basically four things.
Speaker 0: You're trying to balance here your money.
Speaker 0: you get more money if you raise up, you know the taxes But then people get unhappy.
Speaker 0: So the happiness is the second thing you're trying to balance.
Speaker 0: you want to keep the people happy.
Speaker 0: You want to get lots of money.
Speaker 0: when you get a lot of money?
Speaker 0: You can build things.
Speaker 0: mostly.
Speaker 0: electricity is what this game is teaching you about, you know, so you you start out with like one wind farm and You know, you can build up all sorts of different electricals, you know supplies, you know coal gas oil Whatever.
Speaker 1: I was wrong.
Speaker 1: Sarajevo is the city.
Speaker 1: Herzegovina is not a city But it's a tiny tiny tiny little part of Bosnia.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway The fourth thing you're trying to manage in this game is the environment.
Speaker 0: So it's like money happiness power Environment and it's a turn-based game.
Speaker 0: so you have a hundred and fifty turns and you can only do so much per turn and You're trying to get the city in the middle to be as big and bad as you can but also have the happiness.
Speaker 0: be as happy as you can as much money as you can as good an environment as you can in a 150 turns and it's it's pretty fun.
Speaker 0: And I've gotten like.
Speaker 0: the best score I got was a plus a plus C a plus because my population was low But I managed to get lots of electricity a great environment lots of money and lots of happiness.
Speaker 0: Just not enough people.
Speaker 0: so I Felt like if I would have pushed it any harder to get more people, you know Building another gas plant or something that would have ruined the other things, you know I've always kind of like games like that where they give you a like.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like a Figure out the optimal way and it's kind of a once you've beat the game you're done with it forever but getting there is really fun.
Speaker 0: It's also very slick and Very well designed and it's a. it's a fun experience and it's flash and it's free and it's semi educational.
Speaker 0: I think it's supposed to be educational.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: So play it.
Speaker 0: It's fun.
Speaker 1: So speaking of games you should play.
Speaker 1: I figure we should at least devote one episode to this because I really think it was probably the Greatest triumph in game development and design Since tribes - it is probably better than tribes - all things considered design Yeah, I mean tribes - was a great game.
Speaker 1: probably a better game in terms of you know, a different multiplayer single-player realms.
Speaker 0: I think in terms of like.
Speaker 0: You know like game design as you know You get out you get a book about video game design and this this game is like the game that follows every rule in the book tribes - is just a game that didn't follow most of the rules in the book.
Speaker 0: It just happened to be a game that was right up our alleys.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't consider like, you know some like greatest game ever.
Speaker 0: it's like our greatest game ever for the kind of game we want.
Speaker 0: but portal is Might be.
Speaker 1: maybe I'd go one step further and say that portal wrote a new book.
Speaker 0: It may be it just write a new book this game chapter in the book.
Speaker 1: perhaps this game was just so slick like I and I. even the zero punctuation guy was like.
Speaker 1: I have nothing bad to say about this game.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I agree with him entirely that zero punctuation guy.
Speaker 0: I watched every one of his videos because now that I discovered him I have Agree with everything he has said in all of his videos.
Speaker 0: 100% agree so as until a future further notice.
Speaker 0: if you wonder what Scott or rim thinks about a video game and the Zero-punctuation guy has talked about that video game assume we agree 100% And don't wait for us to review it because it's like dazing taking the crazy out of Richard Carrey.
Speaker 1: Okay, I don't think I need to but I guess very briefly.
Speaker 1: portal is a game Released by valve.
Speaker 1: you might remember valve from such games as half-life Half-life 2 counter-strike team fortress - -.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this is the third game in the orange box.
Speaker 0: in the orange box you get.
Speaker 0: well No, I guess the fifth game in the orange box but yeah, you get.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: half-life 2 episode 2. half-life 2 episode 1. half-life 2 team fortress 2 and portal and We already talked about team fortress 2 enough.
Speaker 0: We're not speaking about it again.
Speaker 0: Half-life - we had to wait till rim plays all those games even though I've played them to death.
Speaker 0: I just haven't had time and I Should be bioshock first.
Speaker 1: I killed one boss.
Speaker 1: I got a key and then I just I've been doing other things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know right.
Speaker 0: and now we got guitar heroes and we got DS action.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but damn it Yeah but portal.
Speaker 0: we both beat portal because the thing about portal is it only takes like a couple hours to beat and in fact my Second and third times through.
Speaker 0: I didn't beat it entirely a second or third time, but I'm after beating it once I can just burn through the game like I can get up to the weighted companion cube in like 15 minutes Probably even less.
Speaker 0: it's like whoosh.
Speaker 0: I can just get through.
Speaker 1: Yeah Which is great.
Speaker 1: because and I have to say if you've played the game and beaten it Play through with the commentary because we're not gonna talk about everything They say in the commentary simply because they say it better
Speaker 0: than I don't see all the commentary because I didn't beat it in commentary Mode.
Speaker 1: I got almost to the end so far.
Speaker 1: once they started talking about how they made the portals work and how they dealt with the physics and
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it seemed like everyone who is who played the game, you know They was interested in it for a different reason Like I was interested in it for like the programming reasons Like how do they program those portals and other people were interested in like, how did they render those portals?
Speaker 0: You know other people were like, how do they design this level to be all clever like, you know.
Speaker 0: And it they the commentary has whatever the your interest is in the behind the scenes They cover it somewhere in that commentary and it's way cool way cool.
Speaker 1: Very insightful, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if remember our whining episode we were like.
Speaker 0: you don't know anything about game design.
Speaker 0: if you watch You know the commentaries for this or team fortress You will see What the kind of things that they are thinking in their game design and why you should stop whining and why they're smarter than you Are.
Speaker 0: it was obvious.
Speaker 1: the story of portal is that you're some woman and you wake up Somewhere and a computer tells you to do things
Speaker 0: you wake up in like our picture labs some sort You don't know and it's part of something called our picture and they're doing a scientific experiment and you're
Speaker 1: it.
Speaker 1: You're like the test subject.
Speaker 1: the computer directs you around to all these tasks and it's obvious that it's kind of like a lab and Your promised cake at the end of all the experiments.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're promised all sorts of nice things.
Speaker 1: You're pretty much just promised cake.
Speaker 1: Also other things you will be baked and then cake will be served.
Speaker 0: There will be a party for just for you Everyone will be there.
Speaker 1: Well, except for all right You gotta make this not be to what movies.
Speaker 1: you see what I always say a quote fast.
Speaker 1: whenever they review a movie they like They just kind of like remember when blah happen.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, remember when blah happened.
Speaker 1: Don't do that.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and then actually review the movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that could be.
Speaker 1: If it's a bad game, we'll just go right into it.
Speaker 1: Well, this sucked and this sucked but I could probably spend an hour just quoting the computer and be happy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so while you're doing this, you know, these these test experiments because you're the test subject Basically they're puzzles and you do them one at a time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the real the core of the game is that there's this gun you can use to put portals two different kinds of portals But they're really like there's two different portals that are linked on any surface.
Speaker 0: Yeah One blue and one orange at any one time and you go in the blue you come out the orange you go in the orange You come out the blue and they're connected.
Speaker 1: you look through do whatever you want.
Speaker 1: So like say I'm in my room now You know what?
Speaker 1: I'll link to a penny arcade that shows you exactly what the portals are the slide.
Speaker 0: Yeah That was so great.
Speaker 1: If you shot a portal directly above you into your ceiling and directly below you into the floor You would fall forever through your room continuously.
Speaker 1: You can shoot one in front of you and behind you and poke yourself in the back.
Speaker 0: Yep You could put one Under your feet and then put one above your head and then drop a block into the one on the floor and it'll crush you.
Speaker 1: That's a great use I know right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically.
Speaker 0: you know, this portal thing in itself is way cool.
Speaker 0: But also they came up with all sorts of clever uses for the portal.
Speaker 0: For example, you know You could put one on the wall way high up and then one on the floor right in front of you.
Speaker 0: You go in the one on the floor and you pop out of the wall way high up and you start falling really fast.
Speaker 0: Then you fall back into the one on the floor again And you already have all this acceleration because you were fault.
Speaker 0: You were free falling for you know, however high up the portal was let's say it's 20 feet up in the air You're just free-falling for 20 feet.
Speaker 0: Oh You're coming out of a portal on the wall.
Speaker 0: You're going pretty fast.
Speaker 0: You're gonna keep going pretty fast whoosh and you can use that to get to all sorts of high up places.
Speaker 0: Yeah You have to or like.
Speaker 1: there's a big button on the floor somewhere like up high And so I shoot a portal above the button and then I shoot a portal Underneath a block and the block just falls through then out the ceiling onto the button and then I continue
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and the puzzles are done especially if you play through the commentary.
Speaker 1: the puzzles are so perfectly designed to teach you how to use this gun and yet at the same time provide interesting challenging environments and Then the thing happens and the game goes all crazy and then it's just awesome from that point forward like unceasing awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the commentary they do spend a lot of time talking about how they designed.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: there's only what like, you know, so many missions 19 and then there's the endgame, right?
Speaker 1: Which is like it's like half the game is more than half the game.
Speaker 0: the missions.
Speaker 0: the goal of those missions is to sort of teach you how to deal with the portal gun and They talk about in the commentary a lot about how they structured the missions to teach you all the skills in an intuitive and Good learning curve way.
Speaker 1: cuz think it's not like a team fortress game where you'll learn just by playing over and over again.
Speaker 1: This is a game that you're expected to play through from start to finish not play over and over and over.
Speaker 1: So they've got to teach you about this world they've created.
Speaker 1: they've got to teach you about all the kinds of puzzles They're going to give you and they've got to set you up so that you'll be equipped Mentally to be able to deal with the later parts of the area.
Speaker 0: They teach you a skill then they reinforce that skill.
Speaker 0: then they teach you another skill.
Speaker 0: then they teach you how to use that skill In combination with one you learn before.
Speaker 0: then they reinforce that.
Speaker 1: and you know It's educators could do well to take a hand from portal.
Speaker 0: Oh they could.
Speaker 1: indeed I foresee a future of education being done very differently And I I I don't think we should lock children in a lab with a slightly homicidal Computer and see who makes it out.
Speaker 1: No, but at the same time that would make a very Spartan robust society.
Speaker 1: maybe But I and there would be cake.
Speaker 0: the one thing I worry about with portal though is you know It's such a clean and sit like the design of it and the learning curve of it.
Speaker 0: when a gamer plays it they go.
Speaker 0: Oh non gamers could play this.
Speaker 0: it'd be amazing and I think it would but I Don't think that portal does a good job of teaching you basic FPS skills, and I haven't tried this yet.
Speaker 0: But my theory is like my mom could not play portal because she would first need to learn.
Speaker 1: You know WASD aim with the mouse shoot with the mat, you know It's kind of like how grandma can't use Firefox because she doesn't know how to move the mouse yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and portal does.
Speaker 0: it has a great learning curve for anyone who already has basic FPS in skills But I don't.
Speaker 0: I am not confident that if you do not already know how to at least do the basics of a 3d FPS You know walk around and shoot at things that you will be able to do portal right away.
Speaker 0: You'll have perhaps some trouble and take some minutes to get used to it.
Speaker 0: Sadly I think the best way to learn those skills is just a beat quake - yeah beat quake - or beat half-life 1 on easy or Something like that.
Speaker 0: You know the only thing I can think of in the world that actually teaches Basic FPS skills is the half-life 1 training mode.
Speaker 0: Do you know anything else at all?
Speaker 1: Uh, you know what did you know?
Speaker 1: what did it for me?
Speaker 0: Hmm a good 14 years of playing FPS Just to go from never having played a 3d FPS with the mouse and keyboard to Being able to walk around and shoot with confidence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just think I mean the basics.
Speaker 1: doom when doom came out and I got doom.
Speaker 1: I Didn't know how to play FPS.
Speaker 0: is you suck?
Speaker 0: But you were able to.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: How long did it take you before you knew understood how to walk and shoot and aim at things?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well that didn't take long.
Speaker 1: But being able being confident and being good and not being afraid when I see any bad guy Well, no, we're not talking about bad guys.
Speaker 0: I'm just talking about getting a handle on the controls so that you don't have to constantly think about.
Speaker 1: you know Yeah, but at the same time I had previous video game and experience.
Speaker 1: I mean my parents couldn't play portal and my parents couldn't play quake - yeah, they just wouldn't get it.
Speaker 0: So well, really I wish valve would sort of redo the half-life 1 training mode somehow or make something similar Just sort of like take someone who's never played a mouse and keyboard PC FPS and get them up to speed to where you know They would have the skills where they could beat half-life 1 if they started it, you know
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: at the same time there's a little bit of that.
Speaker 1: was that theory We were talking about the other day with Alex mechanism design theory where they set up Environments in such a way as to encourage a certain kind of gameplay which they desire.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it works.
Speaker 1: And I thought well, I just I think we'll leave it at that.
Speaker 1: I think those principles could be applied to many arenas Many many areas.
Speaker 1: So what really makes portal great?
Speaker 1: I mean aside from the fact that it's polished It's perfect.
Speaker 1: Like every puzzle is so meticulously designed The tolerances are exact the the the hints are just enough to make you figure it out and you will figure it out.
Speaker 1: But yet to feel like it was a huge accomplishment and it kind of was.
Speaker 1: But there's a lot more because if it was just that it would have been a pretty good game.
Speaker 1: I think what made this game shine beyond anything else is Just the computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean not only do you have this game with the probably the best learning curve ever Extremely polished, you know everything right that could be polished.
Speaker 0: Amazing puzzles, you know, it's only a few hours long, but there's never a dull moment.
Speaker 0: But they added this incredible like it's not this most complex.
Speaker 0: Oh my god blow your mind.
Speaker 0: plot.
Speaker 0: it's sort of a obvious transparent kind of plot, but the the way they pull it off is It's sort of you know, it's real for you at least while you play and it's incredibly humorous and quotable and Endearing I mean it.
Speaker 1: and also it's so self-consistent.
Speaker 1: And I mean, we're really gonna avoid spoiling anything because there are some things that could be spoiled that are fantastic things involving cake Things that have probably been spoiled for you already on the rest of the internet and might be spoiled obliquely if you're intelligent.
Speaker 1: But I'll say this Knowing or being able to guess what is going to happen will in no way detract from what actually happens.
Speaker 0: No, no it because I knew a lot Knew about what it's sort of obvious like if you've ever watched any sort of like sci-fi anything in your life You start this game.
Speaker 0: You immediately know everything there is to know about the basic of the plot.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: there's no mysteries for you.
Speaker 1: There's no surprises really, but the game just it does it so subtly and so well.
Speaker 1: I mean it starts out in the very beginning and the computer is just very much like.
Speaker 1: this is a science experiment.
Speaker 1: We're going to do blah.
Speaker 0: Please step out of the blah and do the blah and do the blah and I immediately if you have any you know Any literary knowledge whatsoever you go.
Speaker 0: something evil is going on.
Speaker 0: I am in danger.
Speaker 1: well, not necessarily because it starts out really benign and like bit by bit.
Speaker 1: Little things are wrong about the computer or about the environment or little things are just off sort of like a game of paranoia Or a game of lacuna.
Speaker 1: there was such a paranoia moment Because I remember way back in the day when Luke was running different Luke not Luke crane.
Speaker 1: I was running a paranoia game for us a paranoia larp and The computer spits out the sheet with the instructions of where we're supposed to go and to do that He holds his hands up and he like starts pushing the paper toward us and then he stops and I go to grab for it And then he starts pulling it back in and I and I only got half of it
Speaker 0: And I didn't
Speaker 1: know what to do after that because it was like go to sector 7 something scribble
Speaker 0: tear Yep, and it's like there's a point in the game where the computer is telling you what to do and it's like yes to beat This one you're going to need
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: My favorite is be very careful under no circumstances.
Speaker 1: Should you?
Speaker 1: It would be very dangerous.
Speaker 0: It's gonna become a quote fest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this puzzle is impossible.
Speaker 0: Just give up.
Speaker 1: That was I. I just I love that.
Speaker 1: I think what sums up the humor of the first half of the game is there's a moment where the computer says Due to the protocols of the experiment then you will not be monitored during the next experimental chamber and you walk into the chamber and there's a camera there Immediately looking at you and then there's another camera looking at you the whole time.
Speaker 1: But also I was talking about being self-consistent that you know, there's these computer things everywhere and they have cameras watching you.
Speaker 1: But there's also every now.
Speaker 1: then you see kind of these glass windows way up high and you see like office chairs in there like.
Speaker 1: obviously Scientists are gonna be in there observing you but you
Speaker 0: don't ever actually see like shadows or anything up there moving around
Speaker 1: And then you like later in the game I always I was thinking like I got to get up there I got to see what's in there and sure enough I get in there.
Speaker 1: later I start like I bust out of places and I I get to places I probably shouldn't be and I find somewhat disturbing things but also hilarious things.
Speaker 0: I think what the game really does is it provides you with this really sleek sort of.
Speaker 0: you know Not even like it's.
Speaker 0: it's not even like a real gritty world like half-life 2 is you know?
Speaker 0: It's so.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like being in an Atari game or like Tron or something like that, you know It's not a real world It's a video game world.
Speaker 0: and then they'd let you Slowly but surely bust out of that world and go behind the scenes where there's a real gritty world.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's like a minor Chekhov's gun Like they show you those rooms and you see him and you think I'm gonna get back.
Speaker 0: But at the same time it really brings back That whole feeling of like when you'd play a Nintendo game and you would get to like some secret room And you'd be like, oh man I'm in the secret room behind the scenes and I'm supposed to be here Sort of like in Zelda 1 if you go to the top right and you walk against the wall and you go to the place Where the guy gives you a hundred rupees or something like that, you know.
Speaker 0: And it gave me that same feeling even though it was so obvious.
Speaker 0: and so Chekhov's gun and so right, you know Protruding and you know what it still worked.
Speaker 1: I got the feeling despite the game being pretty straightforward.
Speaker 1: It was kind of unnerving to be in those places like to be behind the scenes in this game and I Remember at one moment where I get into.
Speaker 1: I'm in one of those rooms and I'm looking back out of the test chamber and I got A little chill for a second.
Speaker 1: Yeah but I cannot stress enough how Absolutely fucking hilarious the game is after the thing happens about a little over halfway through like when the real game starts.
Speaker 1: Yep, I I can't.
Speaker 1: I don't even want to quote anything.
Speaker 1: I don't want to ruin it, but it's we ruined quite a bit, but it's really funny.
Speaker 1: This is one of the funniest games I've played ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was quite the humor.
Speaker 1: This is funnier than half the comedy movies I've seen in my life.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, definitely This means not Monty Python funny.
Speaker 1: Don't get me wrong But you don't know what that thing does and neither do I so our best bet is just to leave it alone And I'll deal with it later.
Speaker 1: Yeah alone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Do we want to say anything else about portal?
Speaker 0: I guess if you you should probably buy the orange box.
Speaker 0: if you're any kind of human being buy it for you know if you really must.
Speaker 0: if you have a 360 you but if you have to buy it for the 360 if you have a PC that can run it and you're a Windows user Get it for the PC because I think that's the better way to get.
Speaker 1: don't need much of a PC.
Speaker 0: No, if you can play half-life 2 the original you can play this.
Speaker 0: This isn't like, you know that new crisis game or anything that requires a monster PC, you know If you buy a Dell right now, not even the most expensive Dell you can play it's gonna work.
Speaker 0: If though you really think that you like are never gonna play like multiplayer FPS is or FPS is we have to shoot bad Guys, you know like you're really against that or you really don't think that's ever gonna be it for you.
Speaker 0: Then I think that is really the.
Speaker 0: you know You're that kind of person and maybe you don't have a lot of time to play a lot of games like that.
Speaker 0: You know, there might be that person and I'm pretty sure there is.
Speaker 0: I do think there is a case to be made for buying portal on its own.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: what's it?
Speaker 0: 20 bucks something like that?
Speaker 1: I would have paid 40.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's that good 50 60.
Speaker 1: Well, if you're gonna pay, you know that much money you can get the whole orange ball Yeah, but what I'm saying is that portal is worth a lot more than you're gonna have to pay for it Even if you buy it in the least optimal way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I guess if you are You know, you should buy it.
Speaker 1: in what order is without Question the best Pete the best gaming experience of the last year or two Now without like.
Speaker 1: there's no argument against that.
Speaker 1: it is such an amazing.
Speaker 0: It's it's $20.
Speaker 0: You can even watch the trailer for free on steam power.
Speaker 1: So even if you're not good at FPS is you can beat this game in under five hours.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah If you can solve like the I mean if you can solve puzzles then you can beat this game.
Speaker 0: It's it's a it's a puzzle something like if you can beat like Lola one Then you're more than good enough to beat portal plus like the game itself is, you know Two three four hours depending on how quickly you burn through it.
Speaker 1: But they also have the commentary and they have this challenge mode.
Speaker 0: Good God Challenge mode equals.
Speaker 0: hard challenge mode equals.
Speaker 0: I'd only beat like a little over half of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's two.
Speaker 1: there's.
Speaker 1: there's challenge things like beat this room with as few portals as possible, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's it's the same rooms you've done already, but it's like okay You did this room before.
Speaker 0: right now do it with only like two portals and it's like oh my god.
Speaker 0: But some of the other ones are like, okay do this level again, but we slightly modified the level.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the advanced ones are just really hard things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I beat like four of those.
Speaker 0: I think maybe three but yeah They're really wicked hard.
Speaker 0: so if you even if you beat the game and you know because the learning curve goes up and up and up and up and It's so exact but you know, it doesn't ever reach the max like it doesn't go to the maximum They could have made it keep going, you know They could have had 10 more levels 20 more levels Until they would have started getting things that were as hard as they could be.
Speaker 0: we had to use all your skills in combination But they don't and they just added like six challenge levels that do record, you know, bring the difficulty up higher.
Speaker 1: now I got two more final things to say and I think we'll be done All right, one there's a song at the end of the game.
Speaker 0: Everyone knows about the song at the end of the game.
Speaker 1: I just want to say do not listen to the song before you have played portal.
Speaker 1: Just just let it be this thing that you don't know about and just go into it blind.
Speaker 1: That is the best way to experience that.
Speaker 0: so it was an article by the guy about I guess Interviewing the guy who wrote the song or made the song on dig today or something.
Speaker 0: So check that out after you beat the game.
Speaker 1: and two is it wrong of me to find those sentry guns Incredibly adorable?
Speaker 1: and now they're really bad about knocking them over.
Speaker 0: They made him that way on purpose, but I do not feel bad about knocking them over.
Speaker 1: I felt really bad even though they didn't blame me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't blame you.
Speaker 1: I Think you know that that was part of the only thing they didn't say that they should have said was it's a living?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that would have been perfect.
Speaker 1: I think I would have just.
Speaker 0: I think you know.
Speaker 0: think about it though, right?
Speaker 0: That was supposed to be making sentry guns like you know for military purposes.
Speaker 0: So think about that.
Speaker 0: on the eerie sci-fi level someone was making Weapons that were sort of nice to actually use as real weapons out in a battlefield.
Speaker 1: Where are you?
Speaker 1: Please come back.
Speaker 1: Yeah Seriously We're done.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.