Speaker 0: It's Tuesday April 24th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we tickle your fancy with Tikal.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So after all these years I finally finally I'm taking the goddamn train to work instead of driving and I got to say it's pretty terrific.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a good time to start cuz now you can train your pokemons on the train.
Speaker 0: I can and I did in fact train pokemons for about half the time on the train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I can't train pokemons the whole time because I get tired and I try I fall asleep.
Speaker 1: But I got like two badges today.
Speaker 1: So I'm doing pretty good.
Speaker 0: Well, I go in and out of Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I actually played a lot more Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I still hadn't beaten the Phoenix, right I would be playing that Exclusive of everything else until I beat it.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: I still got to play hotel dusk - oh, yeah You can wait on that one.
Speaker 1: It's not going anywhere.
Speaker 1: There's no rush on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't have a terrible rush on the Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I'm in no Terrible hurry to start cock fighting with 12 year olds.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm pretty sure that this game people are still gonna be playing it and battling each other for some time to come and I mean no one.
Speaker 1: no one really likes to battle until they've leveled up all their pokemons.
Speaker 1: So it's gonna be a while before everyone is leveled up all the way and then the real battling will start in a few months And by then I'll be alright pretty much.
Speaker 0: all I'm waiting for is I like mudkips.
Speaker 0: So I got to get three or four of them and they'll be set to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's that hiker with three geodudes?
Speaker 0: I got him, okay But yeah surprisingly I get on the train and there's no seats because the train is absolutely full.
Speaker 0: I transferred onto the real a commuter train from the city except there's one seat and In the seat and it's empty and in the seat directly next to it is some punk gamer kid playing some game on a PSP.
Speaker 0: All right, so I sit down next to him and I open up my DS and I start playing on my DS.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, and he looks over and I look at him.
Speaker 0: I nod.
Speaker 0: he nods we turn back to our games.
Speaker 1: That's how it's done Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you didn't say uh, you're no good.
Speaker 1: You didn't say uh, you're no good Botha gamer.
Speaker 0: Yeah granted not too long after that.
Speaker 0: I had a gay guy hit on me, but that's the story for another time.
Speaker 1: Okay So I was driving out of the parking lot at the train station and You know I'd make a right turn out of the train station and coming up on the other side of the road.
Speaker 1: or is a car in Front of that car?
Speaker 1: are punk kids on bikes.
Speaker 1: Ah punk kids.
Speaker 1: These are probably middle school kids.
Speaker 1: Are they rolling around weaving slowing down train like they were good trying to bike as fast as they could to get away from the Car behind them because there wasn't really a sidewalk there and they were biking in the road, which is fine.
Speaker 1: But yeah, they were like, you know sort of racing somewhat like go go go go go, right.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what kids do.
Speaker 0: I mean they hurry up everywhere.
Speaker 0: They run as fast as they can in whatever direction to go And at any time, yep
Speaker 1: so you had three punk kids riding bikes as fast as they can straight and You know, I just try to pass them slowly on the right and then I'll be on my
Speaker 0: way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't want to accidentally kill a punk kid.
Speaker 1: No, it's not good.
Speaker 1: so as I'm driving up as is expected the kid the Punk kid in the rear just falls over.
Speaker 0: Why am I just like out of the blue?
Speaker 1: Well, he was sort of biking, you know crazily and his bike was going back and forth.
Speaker 1: He was doing the push push.
Speaker 0: Oh, he was a push pusher.
Speaker 0: Yeah for those who are unaware and Not that I mean, I'd like to mountain bike and I've out and bike forever, but even Scott knows this.
Speaker 0: So if you ever biking and you find that you stomp down one foot and then you stomp down another foot and you just stop Stop-stop back and forth.
Speaker 0: There's a term for that.
Speaker 0: It's called push push.
Speaker 1: Yes, you realize a bicycle is a Cycle.
Speaker 1: you spin the gear which is a circle in a circle you keep pushing Constantly evenly without stopping and in fact you should on the upswing lift the foot up a little bit.
Speaker 0: So you're not resisting yourself and if you're really cool you get some clips.
Speaker 0: So when you're bringing your foot around you can actually pull up and add even more power.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's at a bicycle.
Speaker 1: So anyway, this funky it falls over like wham like suddenly like pedal pedal pedal floor and and you know The weather is all nice.
Speaker 1: So I just stopped right next to him and I'm like kid You all right, the people behind me were like honking.
Speaker 1: I was like whatever.
Speaker 1: and the kids, you know, he moves around.
Speaker 1: so I'm like, oh he's alive and he goes.
Speaker 0: well He moves around so he's on the ground squirming and gurgling.
Speaker 1: He was getting up even though his bike looked broken.
Speaker 0: well, of course he was getting up.
Speaker 0: he was impaled.
Speaker 1: Yeah His bike his bike was obviously broken.
Speaker 1: I saw at least a pedal and possibly a handle broken off.
Speaker 0: See now now my guess here is that obviously he's a little chubby and he's pushing pushing That's a lot of force.
Speaker 0: on that pedal Alternating he probably just snapped the pedal and went right down like a like a fat kid on a bike.
Speaker 1: probably He wasn't that fat, but he was definitely the fat kid.
Speaker 1: And yeah, he was pretty funny because when he was lying there he was like, ah I Got to admit I've done that a lot in my life.
Speaker 0: and when I saw that on Family Guy So in the news Jack Thompson, I Didn't think I'd ever have to talk about him again, but luckily it's over.
Speaker 0: We don't have to worry about Jack Thompson anymore.
Speaker 0: There is no chance that he will be newsworthy again until he dies.
Speaker 0: You see Jack Thompson is now irrelevant.
Speaker 0: He's I go over all the news.
Speaker 0: Wait.
Speaker 1: He's always been irrelevant.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't see what the news is.
Speaker 0: He's always been irrelevant.
Speaker 0: as far as smart people are concerned.
Speaker 0: He was somewhat relevant to the media who for whatever reason lent him some credibility And he was very much relevant to parents who don't know anything.
Speaker 0: people paid attention to him Lawyers at least for a little while.
Speaker 0: this new him a little bit judges entertained his crazy notions at least nominally.
Speaker 1: But I have never seen any judge entertain his notions Generally, well generally he entertains the judges.
Speaker 1: Well, it's crazy notions.
Speaker 0: I guess I would say they entertain them and that they did not immediately have him locked up.
Speaker 1: They almost did.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: they did But it's kind of come all the way around and just recently I don't even need to talk about what he's been doing lately because the media has started pointing out that he's a crazy Nutbag and that no one should listen to him and that he's just insane.
Speaker 0: Hooray, so I will not ever bother talking about Jack Thompson again.
Speaker 0: unless one he starts playing video games Or two he dies.
Speaker 0: one of the two is going to happen at some point.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure he's at least played a video game once.
Speaker 1: mean he had you know What he's had to play a pac-man at some point, you know, at least a pac-man there's a chance.
Speaker 1: He never has there's a chance but I'm pretty sure he's played a pac-man and he's definitely at least seen Some games at some point.
Speaker 0: has he really?
Speaker 0: because I remember reading some of the things he said and he would make Statements that sound very much like the guy in 40 year old virgin.
Speaker 0: We was trying to lie about how he'd had sex once.
Speaker 0: It's like touching a touching a sandbag.
Speaker 1: It's it's it's like a bag of sand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Luckily, I see your wife ago.
Speaker 0: Are you into photography?
Speaker 1: What's it like?
Speaker 0: But it's over.
Speaker 0: I had to say something because I'm actually kind of surprised that the media has turned on him just yet because I'd figure right around.
Speaker 0: now is when they'd want to push it one last time before they do the You know turn around take a different position on an issue.
Speaker 0: So suddenly it's news again.
Speaker 1: You know, it seems to me like the media in general is trying to do something different with the.
Speaker 1: you know The whole crazy VT whatever business, you know because every time and you know there's been something like this what ends up happening is the media reports on it the way they've been reporting on things for the past decade or so and The backlash against the way the media does that reporting increases every single time.
Speaker 1: So I think someone had the genius idea I don't know who it was.
Speaker 1: But whoever they are is smart to say hey Let's change it up and do things differently.
Speaker 1: so we don't get this annoying backlash You know because they got a really rough backlash from actually the people at Virginia Tech who were like, hey go home media We don't want you here and that they've never had that before.
Speaker 1: and I think that woke someone up.
Speaker 1: and it seems to me Like someone is paying attention to what blogs say.
Speaker 1: and it seems like in a lot of like not just with the Virginia Tech thing But with a lot of things I get the feeling that real journalists are reading blogs and dig and that sort of thing Getting the general vibe of what those people are saying and then presenting it through their media in a you know Journalistic fashion,
Speaker 0: you know I really wouldn't be surprised because You can very quickly figure out the sentiments of the majority of internet people just by reading three or four forums.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'll see where this goes but I really don't care either way.
Speaker 1: It's just interesting.
Speaker 1: Alright, so if you're cool, you don't just play video games.
Speaker 1: You also play the German board games.
Speaker 1: If you don't play the German board games, you're not cool.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: I'm just I'm just sorry you suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I didn't know about German board games until I got to college.
Speaker 1: Yeah well if you don't play the German board games There's still hope for you If you're not dead yet And you're not about to die because you have a chance to play them and become cool.
Speaker 1: Not only do you have a chance to play them and become cool, but you can play them without buying them.
Speaker 1: well without buying them physically and without having to find friends who can play them.
Speaker 1: because the two German board games that I would most highly recommend you play before any others are Settlers of Catan and Carcassonne.
Speaker 1: and well Microsoft for some time is on the rights the video game rights to Settlers of Catan and I think they have a website where you Can play it for money.
Speaker 1: You have to pay them to be able to use it, but I supposedly really good and I think they just bought the video game rights to Carcassonne in the US and in May Settlers is gonna be on the Xbox Live and in June the Carcassonne is gonna be on the Xbox Live and there's a lot of screenshots and they look a pretty
Speaker 0: hot now despite the fact that Settlers is at its core a Terribly flawed game.
Speaker 1: Settlers is a terribly flawed game.
Speaker 1: If everyone knows how to play and everyone knows all the rules Then it pretty much just comes down to randomness who wins.
Speaker 0: and that was really put into relief when I entered the tournament.
Speaker 0: and But I think I've talked about that before.
Speaker 0: Yeah But despite that a lot of people the fact I'd say the vast majority of people including gamers Including people who are really into all sorts of gaming really don't play the German board games.
Speaker 0: They just don't know about them.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a thing that you wouldn't think on your own to just go and get into.
Speaker 0: You need to see someone else and have them get you into it.
Speaker 0: in most cases I mean, that's how we all got into it.
Speaker 0: That's everyone.
Speaker 0: I know got into it and Putting a game like Settlers on Xbox Live like that is Perhaps the most perfect way to get people into German board gaming ever.
Speaker 1: But it does seem like, you know, we got into it when like 2000 ish 2002 ish maybe I don't know it was 2000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and It seems like ever since then.
Speaker 1: It's just been growing.
Speaker 1: It's like no one ever on German board games.
Speaker 1: people only You know get into it.
Speaker 1: They never get out.
Speaker 0: Yeah at my worst you don't have enough time to play as many games as you want But you always want to play one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as soon as you're into it, you're into it and I just see more and more people.
Speaker 1: It's totally spreading like a virus.
Speaker 1: and you know first it's Settlers and then it's Carcassonne then you'll see people playing Puerto Rico and then it's teeny and the game's over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, once you hit teeny You're pretty much the hardest of hardcore board gamers as far as I can see.
Speaker 1: I could see.
Speaker 1: eventually like I'd say When we're old men like T&E will be as big like the biggest game like huge I mean really hopefully T&E in general.
Speaker 0: I'd like to talk about that some of the staying power of different kinds of games.
Speaker 0: because We despite how much we love board games.
Speaker 0: We still hate the majority of board games.
Speaker 0: It's already said over the years I think we own every board game that's ever been made that's worth playing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except for the ones that just came out in Germany that we haven't are the ones we don't know about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we're many.
Speaker 0: we seek them out as best we can.
Speaker 0: but despite the fact that Settlers is kind of a flawed game It's also a wonderful game especially if you've never played a game like that before because it has in it all of the elements that make German board gaming or euro gaming in general so different and so much more intellectually stimulating than American style board games and it encapsulates it all into this one simple game That's easy to understand.
Speaker 0: the game includes most importantly a lot of social elements And I can't wait to hear transcripts of some Xbox Live gamer kids with that Xbox Live chat Trying to trade brick and sheep and wood and grain.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yo dude hook me up with some leet bricks.
Speaker 0: Yo, man, I gotta tell you I need some sheep for this wood.
Speaker 0: I got here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't hold ten wood.
Speaker 1: But so yeah Settlers, you know, it's one of those games where it's not a great game But it's like the perfect entry-level game.
Speaker 1: so it's sort of like how No one who's brand new to video gaming can really play Counter-Strike because it's sort of this advanced game That's you know Not easy on a complete the first time
Speaker 0: I played Counter-Strike and this is someone who had played Action Quake 2 for years.
Speaker 1: I literally would just die I couldn't do anything but someone who's played Counter-Strike will tell you that I don't know.
Speaker 1: Team Fortress Classic is a sucky game, you know, and it kind is.
Speaker 1: but if you've never played an FPS before Team Fortress Classic is like the game to play to learn how to play a team FPS.
Speaker 0: Yep, because once you once you play that game you've learned everything.
Speaker 0: now You can play weapons factory or Team Fortress 2 or whatever is coming out now.
Speaker 0: You'd have all the basics down.
Speaker 1: Yep, Carcassonne is the same way only it's actually a good game worth playing.
Speaker 1: So you can sort of get a double bonus here and that you're gonna play Settlers of Catan.
Speaker 1: learn how to play German board games get good at them learn to like them and Figure out why they're awesome.
Speaker 1: But eventually you're not gonna like Settlers anymore because you're gonna figure out everything that's wrong with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless you're just dumb and then you're gonna get Carcassonne Which is a game that will learn you the next kind of German board game.
Speaker 1: get you into some tile laying action And then you're never gonna get bored with that one because it's actually good game.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean despite how much we've played Carcassonne we still haven't solved it and We haven't determined that it's not random but nor have we in any way found evidence that it is random.
Speaker 1: Yeah, generally with the greater numbers of tiles the randomness decreases But at the same time with greater numbers of tiles the randomness increases.
Speaker 0: Yeah but the thing is the Real quick.
Speaker 0: the best way to tell if a game is random is once you play it with a few people enough and you've got A bunch of people, you know who are generally equally and/or maximally skilled at a game people who have played the game So much that they're super good at it that if they play it against someone with moderate skill They would just cream them without quest.
Speaker 1: Yeah For example, if I played against like three noobs at settlers I would win every single time because I'm better than they are.
Speaker 1: but if he played again if I played against rim and Alex Alex and someone else who is really good at settlers basically, you know, we would all be maximum good.
Speaker 1: No one could be better.
Speaker 1: No one would win every time.
Speaker 1: it would just come down to the dice.
Speaker 0: Yep So if we played settlers a lot and eventually got to the point where the distribution of wins over time Averaged out to where everyone won an equal number of times and at that point We it was obvious that the game was actually random.
Speaker 1: at that point You might as well just roll a dice whoever rolls the highest number wins the end.
Speaker 0: now Carcassonne to this day there is still a very clear and frequent victor one person wins more often than everyone else always no matter what we do to the game and There's no way.
Speaker 0: randomness is the factor because everyone has generally equal playtime and Generally equal skills.
Speaker 0: So there are still tricks and things that make the game non random.
Speaker 1: Yep But yeah, these games are gonna be an Xbox Live and if you've got an Xbox, which we don't but you might and You should be playing these and not playing anything else on the Xbox because anything else in the Xbox isn't as good as this.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean I can't stress this enough.
Speaker 0: settlers of Catan is I'd still would put it on a list of the ten most important board games ever Made.
Speaker 1: yeah, maybe not best but definitely most important and you know what it is best.
Speaker 0: just eventually you solve it you move on.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you want to get a motorcycle you get a little 250 cc motorcycle You learn how to drive the motorcycle you're real good at and you're happy and then you realize that the 250 cc has a lot of limitations that you didn't know about because you didn't know about Motorcycles and you never ever ever want to ride the 250 cc motorcycle again and you get a thousand cc motorcycle But you still remember that 250 cc and you remember how important it was for you learning.
Speaker 0: Yep, and of course one final bit of news that I figure we should bring up.
Speaker 0: I heard PC gaming said oh Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard it was dead.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that's old news.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone plays PC games in the entire world.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: I not at all.
Speaker 0: I mean that that's what I saw.
Speaker 0: I read it somewhere on the internet.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know all these Macs and Linux everywhere.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's not a surprise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean no one runs Windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I like mudkips things of the day.
Speaker 0: So we both got video game things of the day because of course it is well nominally gaming day But tonight video game day at least until we get into board games.
Speaker 0: We're actually talking about games all around anyway, a Lot of games especially on consoles have a lot of beta versions or test versions or test concept art or whatnot.
Speaker 0: That unlike with PC games never sees the light of day.
Speaker 1: Well, it does see the light of day just doesn't ever get seen by normal people Like if there's a beta of I don't know I never sees the light of the internet.
Speaker 0: common folk like myself and yourself Do not see the beta screenshots from Mario 1.
Speaker 1: No, because these games are developed by guys at a company in a place where there's high security.
Speaker 1: They're not allowed to take pictures.
Speaker 1: No one goes in.
Speaker 1: No one goes out except the guys working on it.
Speaker 1: Everyone's got contracts where they don't tell anyone anything.
Speaker 1: They don't give screenshots to any Reviewers or magazines until everything's already.
Speaker 0: also when they make versions a lot of times for testing they'll make Cartridges of it internal cartridges and things and it's not like a PC game when it's a cartridge game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what the games I'm looking at are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you see coin heaven has found a site called unseen 64 and there they have Beta screenshots from a whole host of games many of which aren't good or I'd never heard of.
Speaker 1: however Oh, I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 1: These are all real.
Speaker 1: I mean some of them probably are some aren't who knows but they're all cool.
Speaker 1: Nonetheless.
Speaker 0: Well, they're all from a site That's not in English.
Speaker 0: Aha, so be warned there.
Speaker 0: However one this is a bunch of screenshots from various early incarnations of various Mario games.
Speaker 0: I think my favorites are down at the bottom.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of stuff from what Super Mario World looked like when they were first working on it back when Mario 3 was still Fresh in their minds.
Speaker 1: Yep So that's my favorite actually because it shows you like how much Mario 3 was kept in the Super Mario world.
Speaker 1: They kept the question about the music note blocks.
Speaker 1: They kept the raccoon tail They kept all this stuff and then they kept the turtles, you know walking on all four legs instead of just the hind legs And it shows you just how much they changed during the development of that game.
Speaker 1: They basically started out with just Mario 3.
Speaker 0: my favorite picture here has to be hands-down The really creepy sad scary Luigi from whatever version of Luigi's Mansion.
Speaker 0: I don't know if this was actually gonna be in the game But if Luigi's Mansion had looked like this I would have been so much more likely to play it.
Speaker 1: I'm not a big fan of that picture there.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like that aesthetic a lot more than the goofy kind of New style that Luigi's Mansion actually was.
Speaker 0: yeah, I still can't believe you bothered beating that game.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, it was actually fun.
Speaker 1: It just wasn't long enough to be worth playing ever again, and there wasn't any replay value at all.
Speaker 1: So Luigi's Mansion is an okay game.
Speaker 1: It has some fun bits plus.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of booze.
Speaker 1: booze will always get me to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know by the time you're catching your 90th general boo regard.
Speaker 1: It's only one general boo regard.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, don't they all have different names?
Speaker 0: Yes, even though they're all actually identical.
Speaker 1: No, they're not.
Speaker 0: No, there's like several different archetypes or whatever, but it's mostly the same deal.
Speaker 1: Well, no pretty much each boo.
Speaker 1: There's like a trick you have to do to catch each one.
Speaker 1: That's what the game is like the puzzle of how do I catch this boo?
Speaker 0: That's the point I don't know.
Speaker 0: You just didn't look like you were having fun playing it.
Speaker 0: I spent a lot of your time yelling and complaining while I was sitting playing counter-strike next to you.
Speaker 1: I don't really remember complaining so much but I beat it and I'm done with it.
Speaker 0: I remember hearing a lot of all right.
Speaker 0: There he is.
Speaker 0: Fuck you wanna Went to the wall.
Speaker 0: Where'd he go?
Speaker 0: Another one.
Speaker 1: Ah, I don't remember that but it wasn't a very memorable game.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll play it again.
Speaker 0: You know what you do that and I'll continue to train pokemons.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm definitely gonna be training pokemons alright, so I think a long time ago one of my thing of the days was some preview images from a Art gallery that would be dealing with 8-bit arts or 8-bit related arts.
Speaker 1: Well, guess what?
Speaker 1: at the gallery 1988 in LA Just a little while ago.
Speaker 1: They opened up a new show a new gab.
Speaker 1: What do you call it?
Speaker 1: I don't know a show a gallery open an Exhibit exposition.
Speaker 1: I don't know called.
Speaker 1: I am 8-bit and it is awesome and these guys went to it on the opening night when it was crazy crowded and they took pictures of pretty much Everything there.
Speaker 1: So if you can't go to LA you can still see all the awesome arts.
Speaker 0: Thank you internet.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you a lot of these arts are freakin awesome.
Speaker 1: Holy shits I mean some of them are better than others But goddamn some of them are the highest quality like I would buy if this was for sale.
Speaker 1: I would buy half of it to hang up on the walls in the house.
Speaker 0: I think that's part of why we go to cons.
Speaker 0: I spend most of my purchasing time in the artist alley especially like Otakon instead of the real dealers room because all the cool stuff are the Handmade custom art that's based on video games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta say some of my personal favorites.
Speaker 1: Well, my number one favorite is on the first page.
Speaker 1: It's right in the middle.
Speaker 1: It's the Donkey Kong one.
Speaker 1: It's hard to miss it and it's ah I want that.
Speaker 1: so if I had to pick just one thing here to get I would totally get that.
Speaker 0: I mean one.
Speaker 0: it's in that style that we both really really like - it Looks like a movie poster for an old movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, three.
Speaker 0: It's Donkey Kong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's tough to beat that.
Speaker 0: I mean if we ever make a geek nights poster, I want it to be almost exactly like that only instead of a monkey It's us another.
Speaker 1: another notable favorites are like the homemade plushies that of the burger time guys the Donkey Kong's Last Supper The giant plastic rack full of a bajillion little clay miniatures of a zillion characters the swamp statue.
Speaker 1: There's so much good stuff here that if you're a fan of video games video game culture.
Speaker 1: You need to go look at everything here because it will entertain you greatly.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: You said the word swamp and my brain went off and I was thinking and I realized what would be an awesome Product.
Speaker 0: All right, so, you know a lot of people have Venetian blinds, but you know Sometimes you have those that you pull down.
Speaker 0: the plastic sheet that blocks the window entirely like the vinyl sheet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what if you had one of those where both sides of it were a perfect image of a thwomp that you pull down?
Speaker 1: That's not bad.
Speaker 0: I would.
Speaker 0: I want that in my window now.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Well you go do that.
Speaker 0: Okay, I will.
Speaker 1: oh I just see another really good one here it's got.
Speaker 1: I can't tell if it's a Mario or Luigi, but he's wearing the tanuki suit and He's warming his hands by a little fire with eyeballs.
Speaker 1: It's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Why is he with eyeballs?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know the kind of fires that jump out.
Speaker 0: Oh the ones from the pyramid world in Mario 3.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that kind of fire.
Speaker 0: Yep a Charmander kind of fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah that guy the Calcifer cat how does your matter make that little fire?
Speaker 1: Anyway, he's a fire Pokemon But it's a dragon breathe fire dragon breathing fire.
Speaker 0: I can understand but to be constantly on fire I mean, it's like those pipes that they have next to an oil field that keeps burning.
Speaker 0: Is he just constantly putting gas out?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I also want to tell you one last thing about this art gallery.
Speaker 1: if you go to page four and you scroll down You'll start seeing these.
Speaker 1: someone did some really good art of.
Speaker 1: they drew the mug shots From punch-out of all the bad guys starting with glass Joe and they drew all the guys, you know beaten up.
Speaker 1: They didn't draw them, you know before they got beaten up They drew them post getting beaten up and you scroll down and it's like alright glass Joe Piston Honda You know King hippo Pot soda Popinski and and then at the bottom There's a really good joke that you should see.
Speaker 0: I'm because I haven't actually looked at this yet and Scott can vouch for that because he's been Constantly trying to make me go over there and look at most of these.
Speaker 0: I've seen a couple from a distance that he you know made me look up as he turns his laptop over but I've been mostly Being difficult and staying over here by my desk working on things.
Speaker 0: Is the last picture just little my little Mac.
Speaker 0: no cuz he lost and then Mike Tyson actually won.
Speaker 0: So it's not a picture of him.
Speaker 0: No, cuz that's the joke I would have made.
Speaker 1: It's a much better joke than that.
Speaker 0: It's a much more obvious joke that I can't believe you didn't figure out Alright, so Scott just showed it to me and I think my joke was a lot better than what's actually there Which is pretty lame.
Speaker 1: I think it's a funny joke.
Speaker 0: That's a really unoriginal joke.
Speaker 1: I know it's unoriginal.
Speaker 1: That's why it's funny.
Speaker 0: No, I would submit the opposite you suck.
Speaker 1: So anyway also props to the Katamari pac-man.
Speaker 0: So tonight we are reviewing as we are want to do an old board game partly because we don't have so many new board games though at Gaming for hope we did in fact play a board game that we are going to be talking about as soon as we buy it So we can play it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not a hundred percent sure that it's a game with infinite staying power.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's definitely not I'm sure that but it's definitely an awesome fun game that we are going to recommend to you.
Speaker 1: But we will not talk about that now.
Speaker 0: tonight We will talk about another game a game that isn't nearly as good as that game, but it's still a fun game.
Speaker 0: It's also this game has a lot of nostalgia for me because it's one of the first board games I ever bought after I got into German gaming.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It was pretty much this El Grande and settlers that I got right away.
Speaker 1: Well, the game we were about to talk about is the winner of the 1999 spiel des Jahres and the 1999 deutsches spiel prize.
Speaker 1: It is designed by Wolfgang Cramer and published and Michael keel sing.
Speaker 0: I only know Cramer I don't know the other guys either.
Speaker 1: I thought it was only Wolfgang Cramer.
Speaker 1: That's why I hesitated.
Speaker 1: Yep It's published by Rio Grande games in the US and some other and Ravens burger and abacus elsewhere I guess and the game is to call T ik al also known as tickle by us.
Speaker 0: Now Tikal is part of this trilogy.
Speaker 0: I think was called the mass job.
Speaker 0: It says right here.
Speaker 0: It's called the mass trilogy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are two other games that are very very similar to Tikal made by the same other Thematically similar other similar and ways than that.
Speaker 1: Yes, and they have the action point system.
Speaker 0: Yes, hence.
Speaker 0: They're very similar.
Speaker 0: They share a great many game mechanics Tikal and the other two games are Java which we've played and I think I'm the only person in our crew who likes that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I only played it.
Speaker 1: I don't know how.
Speaker 1: if I played both Java and Maya I know I've played at least one of them and I only played the other than one of them that I have played once.
Speaker 1: So I barely remember.
Speaker 0: it's not Maya.
Speaker 0: It's Mexico.
Speaker 0: Okay, Kyle Java, Mexico.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: We I've never played, Mexico?
Speaker 1: Okay, so then Java is the one I have played and I only played it once.
Speaker 0: job is the one where basically all three of these games the main thing they have in common other than theme and cover art and General game mechanics.
Speaker 0: The main thing is that all of these games have this system where they'll give you a number of action points on Your turn.
Speaker 0: so say you get ten action points and there are a number of actions you can take and each action takes a number Of action points.
Speaker 1: you have this little card in front of you and the card will say You know putting a guy on the board cost one point moving a guy cost one point building a house cost three points.
Speaker 1: So on your turn you let's say you could ever if I if what I just said is true.
Speaker 1: You could build three houses and put a guy on the board.
Speaker 1: That's ten points.
Speaker 0: You're done or you could put ten guys on the board.
Speaker 1: Yep It's up to you to use your ten victory or action points in any way you want According to the prices laid out on the card and the prices later to the car.
Speaker 1: don't change.
Speaker 1: It's just that's what it costs to do things.
Speaker 0: It's a very elegant system.
Speaker 0: However in Java in particular after playing the game three or four times I figured out exactly how they determine the number of action points to give you.
Speaker 0: well, yeah, so it's a German game.
Speaker 0: So obviously what they did is they went to a German pub because actually in Germany From what we have heard tell a lot of people play these games just recreationally all the time.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what we hear.
Speaker 1: I don't know how much true it is, but that's what I hear.
Speaker 0: Well, hence I said that's what we hear tell.
Speaker 0: Yep, but they went to a pub.
Speaker 0: They found a bunch of Germans who were sitting around and they put this game in front of them and they gave them 20 action Points and said play the game and the game progressed normally.
Speaker 0: then they told them they gave them all a round of beers and they gave them 19 action points instead per turn and they played Again, and every time they gave him a round of beer and they took away an action point.
Speaker 0: the moment the exact moment a fistfight Broke out they knew exactly how many goddamn action points to put in that game.
Speaker 0: Goddamnit did Java just you never had enough points and the game just hurt constantly and Your option was basically screw another player Horribly and totally or do something totally ineffectual and get like one point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it's basically was beautiful The way everything works out and the way everything costs in order to do anything.
Speaker 1: It's like it'll get to your turn right and you'd be like, alright, it's my turn.
Speaker 1: I can get a bunch of points if I do that thing over there.
Speaker 1: How many you know?
Speaker 1: How can I use these 10 action points in order to achieve that thing that will get me a bunch of victory points?
Speaker 1: And so I can so I can win the game in Java.
Speaker 0: You're always one short So you always got a plan two turns ahead, but the moment you think you're planned ahead Someone else who's playing just puts one of those tiles right in your way and it's all over.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's like, alright I'll do this and this and this and this and this and I. there's no way I can do it.
Speaker 1: I don't have enough points.
Speaker 1: Good God I guess I'll just use these points to fuck someone else because subtracting five from them is almost as good as adding five to me.
Speaker 0: Now luckily to call does not have that problem even though I don't think it's a problem.
Speaker 0: I think you guys are all just wusses.
Speaker 0: I love Java.
Speaker 0: I think it's a great game.
Speaker 1: I only played it once.
Speaker 1: I barely remember it.
Speaker 0: Well Tikal is.
Speaker 0: the basic idea of Tikal is that you are some sort of archaeologist and you lead an archaeologist team and You are going through various jungles digging up temples and digging up treasures.
Speaker 0: Yep Meanwhile, there are a bunch of other archaeologists with their own teams And they're also going around digging up temples and digging up treasures and you want to dig up more temples and treasures than they do And better ones.
Speaker 1: that way you are the famous explorer and Archaeologist and they are the loser.
Speaker 0: So the way the game progresses every round you draw a tile you look at it.
Speaker 0: The tile might have some stuff on it.
Speaker 0: You place the tile on the board.
Speaker 0: then you spend ten action points.
Speaker 0: doing things and things include putting Archaeologists on the board putting your one really fat archaeologist on the board.
Speaker 1: He's like a triple archaeologist superpower.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's gigantic.
Speaker 0: he must be one of those Nazis in an Indiana Jones movie.
Speaker 1: He must be.
Speaker 1: I don't know what he is, but he's really powerful.
Speaker 0: Or like you can move guys around.
Speaker 0: you can excavate a temple which makes it more valuable by digging up more of it.
Speaker 0: And oh, it's bigger than we thought.
Speaker 0: you can dig up some treasure.
Speaker 0: You can seal someone else's treasure and leave some crap treasure in their space instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz like.
Speaker 1: the way the treasures work is pretty simple is each does so many treasures in the game and there's three of each kind.
Speaker 1: So when you get a treasure you want to get a bunch of the same treasure like let's say I get.
Speaker 0: well The reason is whenever you score one treasure is worth one point one set of two is Worth three points and a set of three is worth six points.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely want set.
Speaker 1: So let's say I dig up the elephant mask.
Speaker 1: I want to get more elephant masks.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get like some gold jewels or anything.
Speaker 1: I want to get elephant masks because I've already got one.
Speaker 0: now the other interesting mechanic there is that yeah You can spend action points to swap treasures with people but you can never break up a set of any number.
Speaker 0: So the game and also due to the nature of the game, you know that before the end every single treasure will come up.
Speaker 1: Well, they might not all get dug up before the end of the game But they probably will.
Speaker 0: every single treasure will be available in the game.
Speaker 0: It will be there and you could get it if you wanted it.
Speaker 1: if you really really really wanted it you could get it.
Speaker 1: It's possible that someone might just make it very difficult to get and there's no reason to go for it.
Speaker 0: See the way the game progresses though that all.
Speaker 0: in fact I would say that no competent player Would ignore a treasure that was out by itself like that and I can't see any situation where people would ignore a treasure.
Speaker 1: Well, someone could line it up in such a way that you'd have to move a guy over so much territory But there
Speaker 0: are always multiple ways to get something and if they spent all their time doing something like that They lost the game for themselves already because they're not a competent player.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends.
Speaker 1: It could just be a weird map that one time.
Speaker 0: So, you know I think the way the game progresses in the way the types of tiles are No player who has the chance of winning the game could do that.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There is no way to do that and win the game if everyone is equally confident because that you've already wasted a tile placement.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's true.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 0: So it won't come up ever unless you're playing with people who suck at the game.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so you draw a tile.
Speaker 0: it might have stuff on it.
Speaker 0: You place it you take your ten actions and you're done and then everyone goes around draw a tile play a tile take ten action points.
Speaker 0: Eventually someone draws a volcano.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: It's a volcano and not a temple of something.
Speaker 1: We're not trouble.
Speaker 0: now Here's the fun mechanic of scoring.
Speaker 0: when you score the volcanoes drawn you all go around Everyone takes ten action points and then scores one at a time.
Speaker 0: and the way you score is really simply.
Speaker 0: you count up your treasures And then for every temple that's excavated look to see who has the most Archaeologists there.
Speaker 0: whoever has the most gets the points.
Speaker 0: if you're tied nobody gets any points, right?
Speaker 1: So let's say there's a temple there and the temple is a five-point temple and I have four Archaeologists there.
Speaker 1: rim draws the volcano.
Speaker 1: He moves five Archaeologists there now and then he's done and he scores his five points for that temple.
Speaker 0: Yep So now it's Scott's turn to score.
Speaker 1: I move two more Archaeologists there to get six which is greater than rims five and I score the points for that temple.
Speaker 0: So now we both got the same number of points.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time rim might go ha ha ha I'll move so many guys there and now you had all those guys already sitting there expecting to get five points.
Speaker 1: But now all those guys that you spend action points are useless.
Speaker 1: They're not getting you anything.
Speaker 0: It's not quite the traditional system of have the most guys everywhere get the points whatever because you score one by one and getting points for yourself does not Necessarily preclude anyone else from also getting those points.
Speaker 0: And in fact it if you're playing the game mathematically each guy you put there Decreases the percentage chance that another player will be able to get those points or in the very least Increases the opportunity cost of getting those points.
Speaker 0: So you have to play a lot of percentage statistics games and you have to do a lot of calculations to figure out For each guy I put there how many points on average.
Speaker 0: am I denying the person by forcing them to put another guy there To get the same number of points.
Speaker 0: It's not nearly as straight up as other games are.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like alright if that guy wants to get all he could get all these points right now with his ten action points.
Speaker 1: So if I do this, alright now I'm denying him those points.
Speaker 1: or if he chooses to get these points He's denying himself all those other points over there and you just kind of have to maneuver your guys in such a way that not Only do you get as many points as you can?
Speaker 1: But you make it as hard as possible for other people to just get a whole bunch of points and you make it as Expensive as possible for them to get some more now at its core.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: that's the whole game.
Speaker 0: when you get to the end you do a final scoring round.
Speaker 0: whoever has the most points wins and There are a lot of really interesting ideas here.
Speaker 0: I mean what I said.
Speaker 0: you can excavate temples.
Speaker 0: that makes them more valuable For when you have guys on temples you can spend the time and action points to dig them up.
Speaker 0: and every time you dig them Up, they're worth one more point.
Speaker 1: So let's say I'm sitting as a temple and the temples worth three points.
Speaker 1: It says three on it right and I got a guy sitting there.
Speaker 1: So I tell the guy hey guy dig and the temple becomes worth four points.
Speaker 1: Hurray.
Speaker 0: All right, great You think all right, why don't you just dig up every temple you've got?
Speaker 0: Well doesn't mean someone else could just take your temple from you by having more guys there.
Speaker 0: Yeah digging up a temple Spending your resources your action points to dig up that temple does not fruit does not in the end Guarantee that you will get any of those points.
Speaker 0: You might dig up temples and never ever get the points for them if everyone else just keeps jumping in.
Speaker 1: Yep so I have a guy in a temple I dig it up and I dig it up and now it's worth six points.
Speaker 1: and then Ray moves a bunch of guys over there and takes the six points from me.
Speaker 1: and now I can't move enough guys in to get The six points back.
Speaker 1: I basically just gave rim a whole pile of action points.
Speaker 1: Yeah That hurts real bad.
Speaker 0: So the game comes down.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of not so much risk management But definitely you have to look at opportunity costs and calculate opportunity costs of every possible action as quickly as possible in Order to determine how worth it it is to defend something or more importantly how worth it It is to expend your precious limited resources to improve something that may not be yours in the future.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other thing in this game is you have to notice opportunities on the board like oh There's a way I can get all those points over there.
Speaker 1: if I do this if I spend my action points in this clever way You know building a tent or something like that.
Speaker 0: Aha I pulled a really clever one because we played the game not too long ago so we could review it and It's a trick that I thought about but I never had the opportunity to do and it worked out so well.
Speaker 0: Alex had a really valuable temple and he had a few guys defending it.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I think he had two guys there, but there was no one anywhere near it at all.
Speaker 0: So he didn't have to worry and it was worth a lot of points.
Speaker 0: a scoring round came up And there's one thing you can do in the game where you can only do this twice and there's a high heavy heavy Cost for doing it and not only does it cost a lot of action points But it also costs you physical guys.
Speaker 0: you lose Archaeologists permanently, but basically the mechanic comes down to.
Speaker 0: if you are winning a temple you can Sacrifice all your guys there to basically put an archaeologist with the machine gun on top of it And now it is yours no matter what forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so let's say there's a temple sitting there.
Speaker 1: It's worth like eight points.
Speaker 1: So I I don't want to let anyone have it.
Speaker 1: I don't want anyone to get those eight points, but me and I dug up most of it.
Speaker 1: So there's no way I'm letting anyone else get those points and I've got like five Archaeologists there and rims got two.
Speaker 1: so I say alright screw this and I kill those five Archaeologists and so I can't use them anymore in the game Which is pretty rough because you only have a limited number of the guys available to you in the game
Speaker 0: And if you're not using all of them at all times you're probably losing.
Speaker 1: well You have to spend the first part of the game getting them all onto the board But once they're all on the board you use them all at all times.
Speaker 0: Yeah But you got to be careful because if you put too many out too quickly You very much hamper yourself in terms of taking future actions because now you're limited in your sphere of influence.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also if you put not enough out early enough You're not gonna get enough guys on the board to take control of anything.
Speaker 0: I actually have Exact numbers of guys I put out in different rounds of the game that I play.
Speaker 0: I play the same way every time yeah, and I win a lot of the time But I partly that's cuz I played this game more than everyone else because I bought it way back and I played it with this Whole other group of people a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't wonder him getting those points and I say alright I kill all these five archaeologists and they go away and I'm fucked.
Speaker 1: But now those are my eight points in every scoring round from now until the end of the game.
Speaker 1: no matter what.
Speaker 1: I don't have It I can concentrate elsewhere.
Speaker 0: now think about it.
Speaker 0: It's not just now.
Speaker 0: this temple is super well defended.
Speaker 0: It's no matter what.
Speaker 0: no one else can ever get these points nor can they ever take these points away from you.
Speaker 1: It's huge Yep, however, there is a quite a disadvantage that is not so obvious that okay Let's say I got five guys there rims got three right rims.
Speaker 1: three guys right now are sorta.
Speaker 1: they're not gonna move.
Speaker 1: They're gonna stay there to fight You know to get these points and I you know if I can hold rims guys there and they're not really useful because he doesn't Want to make him leave to go do something else, but he's not.
Speaker 1: they're not doing anything sitting there.
Speaker 1: So I'm sort of keeping rims guys hostage.
Speaker 1: by sacrificing my guys I'm losing five guys, which is a lot worse than rim effectively losing three guys.
Speaker 1: But now by putting the machine gun guy on top of the temple rims three guys are free and they can go do something else Because they're no longer a use for him there.
Speaker 1: They're doing now.
Speaker 1: he knows that there's no reason to keep him there and he can go run away and grab something else.
Speaker 1: It's might be worth more points.
Speaker 0: So Alex had a temple that was moderately defended and is worth a lot of points.
Speaker 0: There was no one really near it But I had calculated and I had kept my three guy my one Archaeologist who's worth three points and it was near the end of the game the fat guy.
Speaker 0: Yep the fat guy.
Speaker 0: So I had exactly enough points to where.
Speaker 0: when it was time Right during a scoring round because I happen to be scoring before him and he was counting on those points I spent all of my action points to move my three guy over to that temple and then cap it.
Speaker 0: Oh He he was so pissed.
Speaker 0: It was beautiful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing with the three guy is there's quite a bit of strategy surrounding the three guy.
Speaker 1: It's all your archaeologists are worth one and they cost the same to move.
Speaker 1: and they're Basically, if you're looking to see who has the most in an area you count them as one.
Speaker 0: Yep so say then now look say you've got four guys and you want to move into the next tile and say it cost two action Points to move across that barrier to the next tile.
Speaker 1: moving those four guys across cost you eight points Yep, but the three guy is a single guy who's worth three.
Speaker 1: So if I've got this guy next to a temple and you've got two guys next to the same temple I win because he's worth three.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but to move him around you move him around as if he's only one guy because he's only one guy.
Speaker 1: So if it would normally take two action points to move a guy from one tile to the next Right.
Speaker 1: This guy takes two to move from one tile to the next but to take three guys across the same barrier would cause six points.
Speaker 0: So he's really useful now in terms of more advanced strategy.
Speaker 0: the real uses of this guy are Mostly to go gather treasure because he can move quickly and he counts as multiple guys.
Speaker 0: He can dig up a bunch of treasure really quick really easily no matter where it's hidden.
Speaker 1: yep, because normally you need one guy on a tile can dig up one treasure per turn and you can dig up to top two Treasures per tile per turn maximum.
Speaker 1: So if you're gonna go get a treasure you can move this guy over there and it costs a lot less to have him move to the treasure tile and Then he can dig up two treasures all on his own because he's worth three guys.
Speaker 0: Now the only other real use is if you put him in a temple dense area and if especially if it's an area That's contended between you and other players You can use him to leverage around and to guarantee that you'll score something over there.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like a heavy hitter.
Speaker 0: other than that A lot of players like to use them a lot early on and move them around a lot and waste action points when they could Have done things more efficiently and also a lot of people They make the mistake of thinking he's more valuable than he is and you really shouldn't be above Suddenly using him in a blitz to capture a temple with a guard and lose him from the game to suddenly take the upper hand Somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially if it's like in right before the second scoring round That's probably a good time because then you get a whole bunch of points for it But you still used him to dig up some treasure before.
Speaker 0: well, it also doesn't help that on many playings of this game I've discovered that in general There's the only two ways to score are the temples and the treasure.
Speaker 0: the treasure is mostly useless and you can very much win Mostly ignoring the treasure.
Speaker 1: you can't ignore.
Speaker 1: we can't completely ignore the treasure.
Speaker 1: You won't win that way.
Speaker 0: However, it's trivial to gather at least one set which will keep you in the game with almost no effort and no research research expenditure.
Speaker 1: Yeah It does seem like if you actually try to get a whole lot of treasure You end up having to spend a lot of action points unless you're just so lucky that you're the one who always draws the treasure Tiles in which case it's just luck And you end up getting a lot of points for it But not enough to actually win.
Speaker 1: and if you spend all those action points getting all those treasures You're not gonna have enough action points to get any temples and you're not gonna win that way.
Speaker 0: Now not to get into a lot of detail about the core down mechanics We could talk forever about the relative value of treasures, but the truth is playing this game multiple times.
Speaker 0: There is one primary Fairly obvious path to victory and once you see one person use this method the all the game really comes down to is Placing tiles in such a way that you can cordon off an area of the board where it's very difficult for other players to get To.
Speaker 0: yet you can easily move guys in or have guys there and then you proceed to with very few guys Control a great number of temples dig them up as fast as possible and leave one or two guys on each getting a whole ton Of points, I've never seen a good player win any other way consistently.
Speaker 1: Yep, the thing is if everyone's a good player, they'll recognize when you're trying to do this they'll look at the board and they'll say
Speaker 0: aha
Speaker 1: so and so is going to be able to do this in that area over there and Then with the tiles that they draw hopefully they'll be able to stop you.
Speaker 0: now You see this is the one kind of problem with the game early on and they recognized it.
Speaker 0: that all right.
Speaker 0: So everyone's good and they realize that tile placement matters more than anything.
Speaker 0: Placing tiles in ways to get more points is the best way to win.
Speaker 0: So now the most important thing on your turn is what tile you drew, but the tiles are drawn Randomly, well, they're drawn semi randomly.
Speaker 1: the tiles have letters on the back ABCD in terms of what you draw.
Speaker 0: They're random.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only non random factor is the progression of the game in terms of what kinds of tiles can come up.
Speaker 1: Yep early in the game, you'll always get tiles that are easy to move between and Generally the temples on them aren't worth so many but the treasures on them They'll get.
Speaker 1: you'll get tiles with a whole lot of treasures late in the game.
Speaker 1: You'll get temples that are worth a lot of points and you'll get.
Speaker 1: if you get a treasure tile It'll probably only have two treasures on it.
Speaker 1: Maybe three.
Speaker 0: but when I say random I mean that the tile you draw you have no control over that.
Speaker 0: you're stuck with it and the luck of the draw.
Speaker 0: you might Never draw a treasure tile never get to place one.
Speaker 0: You might always get temples that are useless You might always get open land and as a result Advanced players could easily make a valid point.
Speaker 0: that I only lost because I draw crap tiles and sometimes that's true.
Speaker 1: Most of the time it's not because things tend to even out but it's still at least once I've lost simply because I just kept drawing tiles that weren't worth anything.
Speaker 1: So there was nothing I could do with them.
Speaker 0: in the trend of a lot of older German style games.
Speaker 0: There is included Alternate rules and the alternate rules.
Speaker 0: It's the exact same game for the most part except that now instead of playing the game with a random tile drawing everyone starts with a number of victory points.
Speaker 0: you then in a Incredibly clue G mechanic that I really don't like but that might just be a factor of the times bid Victory points.
Speaker 0: you bid straight up the victory points You need to win because whoever has the most at the end wins for who gets to pick the tile first.
Speaker 1: Yes, you'll draw.
Speaker 1: let's say there's four players, right?
Speaker 1: You'll draw four tiles from the stack and you'll say alright who wants to?
Speaker 1: you know, whoever bids first will say You know how many victory points they're willing to spend to pick a tile first and then someone else will say how many victory points?
Speaker 1: They're willing to spend to pick a tile first and you go around and around and around and whoever is willing to spend more Victory points will be able to draw tiles before the other people do and you can see all the tiles that are available.
Speaker 1: So you're not gonna be like, you know bidding to get some mystery tile you're bidding for.
Speaker 1: Oh, I definitely treasure there.
Speaker 1: I want that treasure real bad.
Speaker 1: I'll spend three victory points to get that treasure tile.
Speaker 0: Now the problem is going into this alternate rule set and we all fell for this.
Speaker 0: We thought alright There's gonna be a lot of bidding.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a bidding game.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be great.
Speaker 0: Actually, the bidding is really not fun.
Speaker 0: It generally tends to fall into the cyclical pattern of one person will keep going first or one person will keep going last or Scott'll keep over bidding for treasure tiles.
Speaker 1: I only did that once.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, you did it enough in the early part of the game to lose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did it once in the early game I spent way too much for this one treasure tile and then I realized I couldn't do what I wanted to do with it.
Speaker 0: what really sucked was that at the end we counted the difference in points and It really might have made the difference if Scott hadn't bid that much.
Speaker 0: if I would have won I might have won.
Speaker 1: Yes, it but it was not a good move.
Speaker 0: The truth is that the bidding mechanic isn't meant to be used as a bidding mechanic.
Speaker 0: You know, you shouldn't just be bidding like I'll bid one two, three four and all that fun stuff.
Speaker 0: All it is is that generally if there's a great disparity in the value of the tiles that come up There will be a quick Correction where the tile that is worth the most will cost the person who gets it a little bit.
Speaker 0: thus evening out the randomness.
Speaker 1: It's basically a hack to make the game a little less random That I would have a lot less problem with it if it was more fun.
Speaker 1: that way it's like, okay We've made the game less random.
Speaker 0: We've also made it less fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like.
Speaker 1: and now the game is sort of fair and you can't complain that you only Lost because you didn't get the tiles you wanted because you could have gotten the tiles you wanted.
Speaker 1: However, now the game is not interesting as it was because there's no more.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of the game is the excitement of here because the first thing you do on your turn and the most important thing you do is draw a new tile show it to Everyone and put it on the board and that's always like what tile is it?
Speaker 1: Whoa volcano?
Speaker 0: And usually about three quarters of way through the game and this happens every single time I've ever played.
Speaker 0: Yeah players will start because it can affect the game.
Speaker 0: So during Scott's turn Alex and I both draw our tiles and look at him and go haha You're not gonna believe what's coming up.
Speaker 1: You're really not supposed to do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It only would matter if we were timing our turn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does matter for you.
Speaker 1: you get time to think about where you're gonna place it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter because the other problem with this game is that for a good player?
Speaker 0: It's so painfully obvious where you should put things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not like this board for Tikal has a whole lot of spaces on it So and there's not too many places that you can legally place your tile.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Yeah, it's not a difficult decision.
Speaker 0: I guess the end sum of all this is that Tikal is a fun game the first few times you play it and is otherwise Generally, not a great game.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think it's a definitely a good game.
Speaker 1: It is worth playing many times Yes, but in the long run, you're probably just gonna be like to call maybe play it once every few months or so Every year part of us that we played it.
Speaker 0: I played it 15 or 20 times over the course of several months and then it was it wasn't really solved and that someone could Always win but it was solved and that everyone knew exactly how the game was gonna progress and it wasn't fun anymore.
Speaker 0: So I put it away and just recently we pulled it out again partly because we're desperate for new goddamn games to play.
Speaker 0: We've been playing the games we have constantly and Tikal was hidden upstairs.
Speaker 0: We kept forgetting I owned it.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, if you want to play to call you can go and buy it which shouldn't be too difficult Isn't it?
Speaker 1: yep, that's what I was about to say.
Speaker 1: if you go to spiel by web.com s p i e l b y w e b dot com It's this fun website that lets you play a certain set of German board games for free Against other people on the internet.
Speaker 1: the way it works generally is you go to this website It shows you the game you take your turn and then it emails you when it's your turn again and you go back to the website and you take your turn and then an Emails you when it's your turn again, and that's all you do.
Speaker 1: and to call is one of the games that they have available there And it's free.
Speaker 1: So if you've never played to call you can go there and read the rules and And you can play a game for fun and you will see if you like this before you spend any money on it.
Speaker 0: But in general, I wouldn't recommend if you see it buying the whole mass trilogy.
Speaker 0: I would definitely recommend Java ahead of Tikal.
Speaker 1: I like Java a lot Can't say because I only played Java once so I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't remember it I don't know.
Speaker 0: just I feel like the game play of Java is more interesting.
Speaker 0: while you're playing to call falls into this lull slash rut about Just over halfway through the game where you stop caring because you already know who's winning and you already know They're winning by a lot.
Speaker 0: and yet you generally start to feel how the game is gonna progress and while someone could catch up You still you'll feel that coming the game doesn't surprise you a lot the game doesn't stay interesting.
Speaker 0: I really feel like I just want to go play with my mudkips instead of playing to call about halfway through.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I definitely see that about halfway through.
Speaker 1: The worst is when you're not winning because then it feels really terrible because like you you'll generally Spend a bunch of action points and if you're losing you'll spend a bunch of action points And then someone else will be like, haha That was a waste of action points.
Speaker 1: watch this and then suddenly all those action points You just spent will be wasted because you'll like dig up a temple and someone will take you from you or you'll move a bunch of guys into a temple and then someone else will put the machine gun guy on top and you're like Ah, I just lost all those action points that I just spent and it feels like ass and it basically at that point You've lost and you don't really want to play anymore.
Speaker 0: The other problem is all those fun tactics We were talking about like oh I jumped in on your guy or oh you didn't count but I had enough guys over there even though it didn't look like it to suddenly take that temple from you or Scoring around.
Speaker 0: look where I put the volcano.
Speaker 0: Because after you've played the game a bunch of times those stress there is no trick.
Speaker 0: That is not obvious if you take the time to actually look at the board before you take your turn.
Speaker 0: There is no way you could ever be caught off guard by a trick unless you weren't paying attention Or you hadn't played the game a lot before.
Speaker 0: so that aspect of the game disappears pretty quick And then you're left with a generally boring game.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the recent times we've played I was only surprised once when Alex put down the empty tile and then immediately put the tent on it and unloaded a whole bunch of guys right into that big Temple.
Speaker 1: remember that.
Speaker 0: I remember that I was expecting it, but it wasn't gonna hurt me.
Speaker 0: So I didn't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just didn't see that coming.
Speaker 1: Like that wasn't even an option for like in my brain and then now it is Yeah,
Speaker 0: well part of it is that like the way the game is there are options that on a logical level Especially for a novice player and even for experienced players just the way the game is set up.
Speaker 0: You'll know intellectually that yes Theoretically Scott could by spending X action points put this here and take that temple from me But you don't think they'll actually do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: why would he actually do that?
Speaker 0: He won't do that, but then he does it because it's actually the best thing to do and you were just stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like cuz it seems the way the action points work like to build a tent which can.
Speaker 1: it's a basically a guy factory.
Speaker 1: It costs five five action points.
Speaker 1: That's half your turn to build a tent, right?
Speaker 1: But the tent allows you to make guys pretty much on a brand new tile.
Speaker 1: That's crazy powerful.
Speaker 1: So people will spend those five action points build the tent in a crazy way and do something crazy dangerous That you wouldn't see coming because you don't expect someone to spend five action points.
Speaker 0: Like you feel as though spending five is way too expensive But then you realize that no it's worth exactly five.
Speaker 0: you get five action points worth of value from doing it.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it's Oh snaps.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean if you see to call for cheap or used pick it up.
Speaker 0: It's fun, especially if you if you're kind of new into German board gaming If you just played settlers and Carcassonne, you're looking for something more.
Speaker 0: Tikal is definitely still one of those fun starter games and I highly recommend it for that.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's definitely light enough that someone who's not the master can understand the game and how it works and have a lot of fun With it.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's really easy to teach.
Speaker 0: However, the rules are pretty piss-poor.
Speaker 0: the rule book.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's our rule book?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe the rules have been updated?
Speaker 0: just go online and find an abridged rule instructions because this is one of those older games where the rules teach you by example and the rules rationalize things that don't need to be rationalized like.
Speaker 0: the rule book goes out of its way to point out that the way guys get Between your camps is with secret passages and it says this a bunch of times and there's a lot of sentences in the rule book That provide no information at all.
Speaker 0: They are just there in your way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: alright I like the board games to have a theme or otherwise you get you know dice wars But what's wrong with dice wars?
Speaker 1: nothing, but at the same time I don't want the theme to be all up in the rules.
Speaker 1: The theme should just be you know The pictures on the tiles and you know what the pieces look like or the kind of game or the kind of game it is.
Speaker 1: Oh then again I mean But I don't want you to write about secret passages in the rules.
Speaker 1: that where that doesn't mean anything everything that's written in the rules Should be how to play how the game work.
Speaker 0: now You can cetera draw the secret passages or you could mention them in the sidebar or in a note or in a call-out Box or God call.
Speaker 0: I've been doing physio too much for some sort of thing and it's okay.
Speaker 0: But the moment you clutter the actual rules with that garbage is no good is yonder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's very under Sort of like it were actually.
Speaker 1: the secret passages reminded me of clue.
Speaker 0: Ah Clue.
Speaker 0: there's a game that was fun when I was six and then I figured it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if only that game was more complex, it would still be.
Speaker 0: the worst thing is the best game.
Speaker 0: I used to piss my family off because basically the only strategy to clue is to Maximize your going around to all the rooms because the rooms is the only part that you can't just say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't just say in the billiard room unless you're in the billiard room But you can always say with the knife no matter where you are.
Speaker 0: So what I would do is I'd go around to half the rooms real quick and then I'd sit in one room for like 10 rounds and I and I'd even say and I'd say that my family was so mad sad the knife in my hand and I had professor plum in my hand.
Speaker 0: I'd be like professor plum With the knife in the billiards room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then if no one said anything, I'd be like I win.
Speaker 0: You guys are all chumps.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and no one thought to do things like that.
Speaker 1: So that's What is a very solvable and easy game, but I actually prefer Simpsons clue, which is more fun.
Speaker 0: That's how every German board game is eventually except for the true great classics and even those might be that way someday.
Speaker 0: We're just not smart enough to figure it out, which is good enough.
Speaker 0: Yep, but like settlers and Tikal You'll.
Speaker 0: eventually you'll figure them out and they won't be fun anymore.
Speaker 0: but if you're new into board gaming or you just really need to change it up check to call out if You're more discriminating.
Speaker 0: Check out Java.
Speaker 1: I never played it.
Speaker 1: I played it once and I don't remember it.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing the Dragon's Den has it For kind of cheap because it's an open box and the only reason I didn't buy it last weekend was that I didn't want to Carry it around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll buy it next time.
Speaker 0: I go to Mars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, think.
Speaker 0: the other thing is I think there's also an open Java and millennium Because remember I got that end decker for like 25 bucks.
Speaker 1: Well this weekend.
Speaker 1: I'm going to Mars and you're gonna millennium So we'll communicate.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.