Speaker 1: It's Thursday, June 7th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we talk about the great the awesome the amazing Lord.
Speaker 1: Admiral Horatio hornblower You know what one of my favorite pastimes is Sleeping sitting in traffic on 287 trying to drive to white Plains to pick up a tuxedo.
Speaker 1: Oh I couldn't go during work because actually I was getting part of my car fixed this morning.
Speaker 1: So I had to wait until after work.
Speaker 1: I just I left a little bit early You know went up the sawmill gonna catch 287 across to that God awful.
Speaker 1: Westchester Mall and go in and pick up my tuxedo and go.
Speaker 1: so, uh, I get to the exit that says 287 and I pull about 20 feet down it and then I realized the traffic has just stopped.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not going anywhere and it was.
Speaker 1: it's not like it was an accident or anything.
Speaker 1: It's just that's what that road is like.
Speaker 1: pretty much Well in that part of it going in that direction at that time or the other direction pretty much 287 between the Hudson River and White Plains is not actually a road.
Speaker 1: It's a parking lot I don't use.
Speaker 0: I use it mostly in the Jersey side like for the Tappan Zee Bridge West.
Speaker 0: I don't use the eastern part of that see over in Jersey.
Speaker 1: It's pretty nice.
Speaker 1: That's how we get to all the good places we go.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz it's sort of.
Speaker 0: it's like the east-west Highway because Jersey has the two big north-south highways the turnpike in the Garden State But 287 is sort of the east-west and it allows you to get from New York to Jersey Without going all the way to New York City to use like the George Washington Bridge.
Speaker 1: You can use the Tappan Zee Bridge Yeah, but now after an hour driving I get there no big deal.
Speaker 1: All right the crowd of people waiting around This after-hours tuxedo let alone the people crammed inside of it was staggering.
Speaker 1: Wow Basically though I realized that while they're all it was the same deal.
Speaker 1: where there's only like two people running the store and they're all you know, like avoiding eye contact with anyone waiting and just like trying to get work done and Dealing with police.
Speaker 0: They were trying to get work done as opposed to standing there looking at you going.
Speaker 0: Sorry You have to wait.
Speaker 1: Well the work they did Seem like they're doing real work.
Speaker 1: I don't know how that company is set up But it doesn't look like anyone ever does real work.
Speaker 1: They all do like barely useless looking paperwork or they just kind of stand there looking at pieces of paper and not moving.
Speaker 0: Why do they have paper?
Speaker 0: It's it.
Speaker 0: they should only have tuxedos, I guess maybe scissors Computers.
Speaker 0: What else do they need regardless like white chalk stuff to do Taylor?
Speaker 1: I did something I don't often do because I generally whenever there's some sort of Self-organized system because it looked like people are kind of form themselves into a line, but it was not explicit.
Speaker 1: It was entirely implicit and people were kind of going along with it and I realized this is going to be a bad situation.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have to wait here forever and I decided at that point that it was time To in the in the full use of the prisoner's dilemma defect against society.
Speaker 0: There you go, and I just walked past.
Speaker 1: all the people walked right up to the lady who was typing stuff in somewhere said, excuse me I'm here to pick up a tuxedo and before she could say, you know, you're gonna have to wait or stand in line.
Speaker 1: I just kept right going with.
Speaker 1: I got to catch the flight.
Speaker 1: I just got to pick this thing up.
Speaker 1: I arranged with the lady before to pick it up at 530 and before she could say she stopped for a second and she went to say something else and I just kept talking and I kept talking and I every time I stopped if she started to protest I said something else and This worked beautifully and eventually she realized that there was no way short of interrupting me and you can't interrupt the customer To make me go away.
Speaker 1: So she gave me my tuxedo and then I went on my way past all those people.
Speaker 1: I saved about an hour and a half awaiting and Other than a little bit of confusion with what they were actually supposed to give me which I sorted out eventually.
Speaker 1: I Realized that it's over.
Speaker 1: I've defected.
Speaker 1: I just wrote orange on the piece of paper and collected my thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: That's how it's done when people are giving you shit.
Speaker 0: You gotta take control You can't let.
Speaker 0: you can't let stupid people fuck it up for the for you.
Speaker 1: well see the thing is.
Speaker 1: it's kind of funny because this happens at conventions a lot where a Connell say don't line up or there won't be a system of waiting for something because they don't want people to spend their whole con waiting for something.
Speaker 1: So people who are stupid or People who don't realize what's going on or people who just feel entitled to wait despite being told not to or despite They're not being a system will often create a mini society on their own and expect other people to follow the rules of this tiny Society they have created.
Speaker 1: they'll stand in a line that they've made up and expect people to stand behind them and I like the fact that Otacon and all the good cons Respond to this usually by forming a line somewhere else and not letting those people in until last.
Speaker 0: yeah That's always good too.
Speaker 1: And in the real world when there's no con staff to deal with anyone I think the best solution is just to walk past these people because they'll never say anything.
Speaker 1: They'll just get indignant and then I can just go on my way.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do about it?
Speaker 0: What if you don't have any authority to control me or tell me what to do, then what are you upset about now?
Speaker 1: There's a difference.
Speaker 1: if there's a real line like you're in line at the grocery store to pay and someone cuts in front of you That's not cool.
Speaker 0: That's a real line.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm saying when there isn't a real line if some group of people just arbitrarily Desides that they're gonna make some up some rules up, you know, it doesn't have to be a line.
Speaker 0: It could be anything like, you know, we've decided no one in this room can say this word.
Speaker 0: It's like no.
Speaker 1: That reminds me of that Penn Jillette.
Speaker 1: when there's that woman who went on and on about her No one swears in her business and this big deal about.
Speaker 1: you shouldn't swear in this whole thing.
Speaker 1: and her friend was there Interviewing her about it and then at the very end the friend just said fuck and the woman totally freaked out.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think the friend said shit, but she said something like that.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: She said a bad I think she gave the friend like a sign to hang up in her store and the friend was just like oh shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah Yeah, but also a little hint for all of you out there.
Speaker 1: the technique I used to get service will work in most Service situations.
Speaker 1: The key is don't be rude.
Speaker 1: Don't yell.
Speaker 1: Don't be like that.
Speaker 1: I gotta be out of here.
Speaker 1: Be very polite.
Speaker 1: In fact, if you want even be overly polite be act a little bit stupid.
Speaker 1: Give the impression that you don't Understand that they are busy or that there is a line or that that you have to wait.
Speaker 1: Just keep bringing things up and like oh, well, I gotta pick this up cuz the flight man flying to Rochester blah blah blah oh, but I gotta pick up this yeah, duh duh duh duh and my dog and They can't call you out because they'll get in trouble.
Speaker 1: The only thing they will be able to do in most cases is serve you immediately and be done with you.
Speaker 1: Lesson number eight in rims how to get what you want by defecting on society.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So what do you got in the news?
Speaker 0: I'm real tired and I'm all.
Speaker 1: hey Scott is real tired.
Speaker 1: I got to admit I came home and usually when I come home I get irk.
Speaker 1: Scott comes home I get the tirade of oh my god rim.
Speaker 1: What did I see on the internet today?
Speaker 1: but a video of some guy getting hit in the nuts and there's this tech news and he just talked about it at.
Speaker 1: and today I Came home and other than the fact that Scott's car was there I had no idea Scott was home until I walked into the living room and he didn't acknowledge my presence.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, so what he got in the news say is a pretty funny Park style news.
Speaker 1: Oh, usually I'm the one who cops out and does the FARC.
Speaker 0: No, it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: What do you want from me?
Speaker 0: and we were laughing about this at work.
Speaker 0: anyway, so some guy has.
Speaker 0: He's a 22 year old guy and he had muscular dystrophy.
Speaker 0: So he's in a wheelchair now.
Speaker 1: All right, that's bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, I think he was it.
Speaker 0: see I didn't read all the details and he was at a gas station.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, he was crossing a highway in his little electron.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I know I figured out cuz I did read the FARC headlines, but I didn't follow up.
Speaker 1: I think I know what FARC headline refers to your story.
Speaker 1: Okay, I So involving a land speed record of a wheelchair something like that.
Speaker 0: Okay, so he's going across the highway in his little wheelchair and The semi-truck didn't see him.
Speaker 0: well the story here says that the semi-truck didn't see him and His wheelchair got caught on the grill of the semi.
Speaker 0: So basically the semi is behind this guy pushing him forward and it took him on the highway for a bunch of miles and it took him up to 50 miles an hour and People kept calling 911 and eventually the cops believed it because they didn't believe it at first.
Speaker 1: I Can imagine being the guy on the front cuz that but imagine being the truck driver when you finally get pulled.
Speaker 0: Believe it until he saw it.
Speaker 1: Imagine this you get pulled over by the police and you're like officer my speeding.
Speaker 1: They're like, no, you're pushing a disabled man in the front of your truck in a wheelchair.
Speaker 0: Yep I would probably just laugh and be like Yeah, I was actually said the ride was kind of fun if it wasn't for the fact that you know If a few more miles he would have died because his tires would have disintegrated.
Speaker 1: I just can't imagine what situation in the physical world would actually bring this about and I wonder whose fault It was.
Speaker 1: was he in a crosswalk?
Speaker 1: was he Jay?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess Jay walking isn't the relevant.
Speaker 0: Well here the ear two things I thought of the guys at work.
Speaker 0: It was their thinking.
Speaker 0: I mean, obviously the story says that this was you know an accident which is I guess the most believable situation.
Speaker 1: No, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Oh really there are two alternate scenarios that I think are pretty plausible.
Speaker 1: The reason I don't deny is that I can't think of many human beings who would willfully put themselves in either of these situations.
Speaker 0: Well, you know if you look at the guy the people at work some co-workers thought that he was trying to off himself and I personally if you look at the way that The wheelchair is like stuck to the grill of this truck It looks like he tried to get it stuck there like it's like perfectly wedged in.
Speaker 0: so either it's Coincidentally just just the right.
Speaker 0: Well, it's nice or he tried to take a ride on this truck.
Speaker 1: It just seems weird that the truck would somehow have hit him in order to move him this way and yet he was Oriented in the proper direction.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: That's why it's.
Speaker 0: I think while it's most likely an accident as the story says I think there's a good chance of Him going for a wild ride or I guess there's a least chance of the three.
Speaker 0: is You know off himself because they're trying to off himself.
Speaker 0: There's a lot easier ways to do it.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe he's one of those people who you want to off yourself, but you don't really want to die.
Speaker 1: It's just you know, you're going to die.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna off yourself for whatever reason ahead of time.
Speaker 1: So instead of just killing yourself you do increasingly dangerous risk-taking awesome things like the guy who trained surfed.
Speaker 0: oh, maybe I think the The funny thing here is the guy has this shirt that says I'm a pepper.
Speaker 1: That wasn't what I expected.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's like this red shirt.
Speaker 0: it says I'm a pepper and it's pretty funny.
Speaker 1: You know now that I think about it.
Speaker 1: This does remind me of a story that this was a year or two ago where a guy called 911 from his car on a freeway Claiming that his accelerator for whatever reason he couldn't close it and he couldn't stop the car and his brakes.
Speaker 1: Just he held him down and they wouldn't stop the car enough for him to get out.
Speaker 1: and now they're busted Because he held him down and he's actually an excuse to speed down the highway.
Speaker 1: So he's going down the highway with the basically the pedal down going as fast as car will go.
Speaker 1: The state troopers still clear off the road to give the guy room until he runs out of gas or whatever.
Speaker 1: But like 10 miles down the road, there's a big toll booth thing that there's no way he'd make it through like.
Speaker 1: he'd probably just die.
Speaker 1: and magically the car like comes under control and he brings it to a stop like a mile before that thing.
Speaker 1: and Then you know mechanics suspect the car and find nothing wrong with it and I think the guy went to jail or something.
Speaker 1: I don't remember how that.
Speaker 0: see.
Speaker 0: I would have gone through the toll booth at the full speed Until I made it over the state border, then I'd slow down.
Speaker 1: Ah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: You really would have had to rig that ahead of time.
Speaker 1: Did the guy really think that the police wouldn't get a mechanic to look at what was going on in his car?
Speaker 0: Maybe what you could do is sabotage your car on purpose.
Speaker 1: See, I don't think he thought I think it was in the car and he thought I know how I can get away with this.
Speaker 0: I Kind of what is clever plan through.
Speaker 1: I mean once in my life I did that not now with the lying part But the put the pedal all the way down and just held it there For a long time and the car got up to about a hundred and twenty six 27 and the whole time
Speaker 0: the car was shaking.
Speaker 1: No, the car wasn't shaking.
Speaker 1: No that car.
Speaker 1: It wasn't really shaking It was just.
Speaker 1: obviously I would not be able to turn it quickly.
Speaker 1: The real issue was that I only kept it at that speed for about five minutes because the whole time I'm thinking if There's a cop totally fucked if there's a cop I'm totally fucked.
Speaker 1: didn't.
Speaker 1: time felt like it slowed down because I was so worried about there being a cop.
Speaker 1: I know right.
Speaker 1: the thing is there were no other cars on the road.
Speaker 1: My only hope was that relativistic effects would create a situation whereby I could slow the car down before The cop got the radar on me.
Speaker 0: a good chance of that.
Speaker 1: Either that or maybe because there was no trees.
Speaker 1: It was an open plane in the middle of Canada.
Speaker 1: No trees.
Speaker 1: No other cars.
Speaker 1: Theoretically a cop just sitting there would have no frame of reference and couldn't figure out how fast I was going Unless he had the radar pointed.
Speaker 1: I doubt he had the radar pointed.
Speaker 1: cuz there's no one on the road.
Speaker 1: You know what never saw a cop the whole time.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, he could also gotten you with a laser.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he could have but he would have had to have the laser ready.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah pretty much All right.
Speaker 0: What's your news?
Speaker 1: So a long time ago like eight years ago I read this article about how muscle tone in terms of you know, how good your muscles look Has a lot to do with the many many small movements you make constantly and that people who fidget There is overwhelming evidence that people who fidget are thinner have more muscle tone are stronger and are generally healthier Despite the fact that you know they fidget.
Speaker 1: and fidgeting is often very annoying when you see someone else doing it or when you're doing it yourself when you know, You shouldn't know.
Speaker 1: Well up.
Speaker 1: a bunch of new studies recently apparently have found fairly strong genetic links linking genetics and fidgeting and to they have further brought forth all this evidence that people who fidget are a lot thinner and very rarely become obese.
Speaker 1: obese people rarely fidget mmm.
Speaker 1: and Because you know, you're constantly exercising all your muscles.
Speaker 1: And I just point out that I fidget quite a bit and so does Scott.
Speaker 0: I fidget all the time.
Speaker 0: That's how come I'm not fat.
Speaker 0: Even though I lead a sedentary lifestyle which and don't exercise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see we have this funny running gag about the sedentary lifestyle with Scott.
Speaker 1: I bring it up at all opportunity.
Speaker 1: Scott could be sitting there like out of the blue, you know, we're in a car and he'd be like, ah I don't know my leg fell asleep or Man my legs a little stiff cuz you know We're in the road car for like eight hours and I'd immediately say well if you probably wouldn't have that problem If you didn't lead a sedentary lifestyle,
Speaker 0: yeah, that's what he does.
Speaker 0: That's what I do.
Speaker 1: That's my shtick.
Speaker 1: It's a very annoying shtick and I found this article interesting.
Speaker 0: compared to most people who do lead sedentary lifestyles I'm not so sedentary.
Speaker 1: Well because you fidget Well, I mean.
Speaker 0: but like think about the people who sit on a couch and watch TV for like six hours a day.
Speaker 1: No while you lead a sedentary physical lifestyle, you're basically in the jet-set of the internet.
Speaker 1: So, I guess it evens out.
Speaker 0: I'm not so sedentary around the relative scale of people in this country.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta give you that.
Speaker 0: I gotta give you that I am moderate on the Activity you don't have.
Speaker 1: it's like I own it as groove in the couch.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't exercise but I also don't sit down and not do anything.
Speaker 0: Don't eat.
Speaker 0: Like even if you look at my co-workers They sit there all day at work and only get up to go to the bathroom once and like for lunch I have to get up like every like half hour and move around and tell these other people just sit there all day.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh god, I couldn't stand that.
Speaker 1: even at IBM a lot of times It'd be like 3 45 on a Wednesday and I just feel like yeah And I just get up and wander a mile or two over to one of the other buildings I'd never been into and just walk around it for 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: I just get up and like stretch next to my chair and then do a little dance and one
Speaker 1: time I got lost I wandered Over into a part of the fab I'd never been in before and it was way way far away from where I should have been and I totally got lost for like A half hour and I couldn't find my way out of the building.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 1: Luckily, I got back and no one even noticed I'd left.
Speaker 0: so yeah shows how important your job is.
Speaker 1: Well, it was my job.
Speaker 1: there was mostly figure out solutions to problems Like we have a problem with X and I just my job was if I come up with the solution implement it.
Speaker 1: Otherwise Generally be idle Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we really need to.
Speaker 0: I don't know this.
Speaker 0: It's still a big problem.
Speaker 0: the idleness at work There should never be.
Speaker 0: I don't this at work.
Speaker 0: It should be either.
Speaker 0: I'm at work working or I can go home Huh?
Speaker 1: I just remember when I worked at the Ritz the worst job I ever had.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe the second worst job I ever had?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's a really tough call.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the worst job I ever had.
Speaker 1: I mitigated that somewhat by being the absolute best pizza chef they ever had and then deciding that it was better for me to be The absolute worst pizza chef they'd ever had.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got stories about that place But uh any time I was idle they'd walk over and just look at me and say in all seriousness if you got time to lean you got time to clean and I would look at the filth that had been accumulated over the past several decades on the floor where I was standing and I would straighten up and stop leaning and They would look at me and realize that I had just punned them.
Speaker 1: Yeah and just walk away shaking their head.
Speaker 1: But then they come back over with a mop anyway, but at least I had that tiny victory and I quit not too long after.
Speaker 1: Yep things of the day.
Speaker 1: So if I what's your favorite robots got?
Speaker 1: Of all robot robots now not cyborgs not power suits not giant robots.
Speaker 1: I'm talking just straight-up robot my real robots any robot it could be from a cartoon.
Speaker 1: Perhaps I don't know.
Speaker 0: the most powerful robot is Voltron But I.
Speaker 1: but Voltron is nothing without the people who pilot him.
Speaker 0: That's not the point.
Speaker 1: I think I would have to go with hedonism by hard to pick one robot.
Speaker 0: You're gonna pick hedonism, but hedonism bod has provided more enjoyment in my life than any other robot This is about isn't even as good as bender?
Speaker 1: How delicious Yeah, plus he doesn't.
Speaker 1: mod just comes up in casual conversation all the time lately.
Speaker 0: Mostly cuz you're playing that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah We got to buy that game and then we got to review it on the show.
Speaker 0: cuz good guy Talk about it on the show And it's like a part of a cop a whole episode about all the games we played it gaming for hope or whatever?
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: But anyway, my thing of the day here is the Hubo FX one chair BOTS.
Speaker 1: I am now one step closer to being able to should I desire it live like hedonism bot Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: It's basically just a walking chair.
Speaker 1: It's it's kind of like I don't know how to describe it.
Speaker 1: Just look at a picture of it.
Speaker 1: I Guess it'd be theoretically useful if you were handicapped and you wanted to.
Speaker 1: I don't know climb mountains or go over rough terrain.
Speaker 1: I think it's neat and I couldn't find anything better and I wasn't just gonna use a clip from The Simpsons again Which you were about to do because it was quite a high quality Simpsons clip.
Speaker 1: it was because I have indeed played that game before.
Speaker 0: maybe we need a whole week of Simpsons clip thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's such a great cop-out, but too bad.
Speaker 0: We already used some of the best ones.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's plenty more.
Speaker 0: there are plenty but they're not, you know It's like you want to have them if you're gonna do it.
Speaker 0: You want to the best ones?
Speaker 0: You can't go with like these.
Speaker 1: weak one Alright anyway, so what do you got?
Speaker 0: What do I have?
Speaker 0: That is a good question.
Speaker 0: Well, you may remember that the there's a guy named Penn Jillette, you know that magician Atheist guys big and fat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a funny super libertarian.
Speaker 0: Yeah that guy He's.
Speaker 1: he's really smart, but he's also really dumb.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's this interesting dichotomy where it's like I'm with you I'm with you.
Speaker 1: I'm with you.
Speaker 1: God that was stupid.
Speaker 1: But then he gets points because whenever he says something stupid he knows.
Speaker 1: and then he says but I'm just a big stupid fat guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's just his.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like he's just learned these defenses like he thinks he's right but he'll just say I'm a big stupid fat guy.
Speaker 0: What do I know?
Speaker 1: We know someone else who used to be like that a lot of own ocean a name.
Speaker 0: But but anyway, he used to have this podcast that eventually it was also an actual radio show.
Speaker 0: They happened to podcast it but the pops cast was more popular than the radio show.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So eventually they ended it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, eventually they ended it for various reasons and whatever.
Speaker 0: but Basically It was a time on the show where he told a story about a patent.
Speaker 0: He had a real patent a real patent.
Speaker 0: He has a patent.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I figured oh, it's probably for some like, you know Device like a trick device he needs for a magic trick that he invented or something like that.
Speaker 0: No, no, it's nothing like that.
Speaker 0: The thing he has a patent on is the Jill jet.
Speaker 0: That's what he called it because his name is Penn Jill et and this thing is a jet of water.
Speaker 0: So he called it the Jill jet.
Speaker 1: the story he told of how we came up with it was pretty funny I gotta say.
Speaker 0: basically what it is is you have a like a hot tub or a bathtub or something like that and You know you arrange that the tub is shaped in such a way that you can sit on it and there was a hole with a jet of water coming out of it.
Speaker 0: and if you're a woman and you sit on the seat a Jet of water will pleasure you and that is the Jill jet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically from what I get the general gist of it where he came up with it was you know People sitting around in a hot tub.
Speaker 1: They always think about why don't I edge up to that thing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then he realized why don't I just put him in convenient places to do that?
Speaker 1: Yep, of course.
Speaker 1: He's also a big pervert which really helped.
Speaker 1: I think yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 0: So I you know, Google has had this patent search for quite a while now And I just never actually bothered to go look at it.
Speaker 0: But for some reason this week I just ended up there randomly at some point and I said, huh?
Speaker 0: What patent should I search for?
Speaker 0: so I searched for like fire to see if anyone patented fire?
Speaker 0: Then I searched like the wheel to see if anyone to patented the wheel and I learned that Every freaking different design for a tire rim like on a car has been patented Like every possible shape you can come up with has been patented by Bridgestone.
Speaker 1: I just came up with a new one Yep full of spikes.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, so then I said hey, why don't I search for the Jill jet?
Speaker 0: and I found it It is actually not.
Speaker 0: it is not listed.
Speaker 0: as the Jill jet is listed as the hydro therapeutic stimulator.
Speaker 1: See Scott sends me this.
Speaker 1: he doesn't say what it is.
Speaker 1: So I look at the patent and at first I think oh, is it some BS like made-up hydrotherapy?
Speaker 1: Or is it some real hydrotherapy?
Speaker 1: or what is this?
Speaker 1: And he said just keep looking at it.
Speaker 1: I keep looking at it.
Speaker 0: then Ben Gillette Yeah, it's it's a let's see.
Speaker 0: The filing date was January 9th, 1998 and it was issued in July of 1999.
Speaker 0: It's patent number five nine two.
Speaker 0: Oh nine, two, three.
Speaker 1: So, uh, wait a minute by god, is that her ratio?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it wasn't the best segue but I had to go with it even though I don't think they actually say those exact words.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kind of like a people always misquote Shakespeare and just add lies don't ever said.
Speaker 1: but anyway Horatio hornblower.
Speaker 0: A lot of people have no idea what the hell Horatio hornblower.
Speaker 1: However, awesome people do and if you want to be awesome, you should check Horatio hornblower out.
Speaker 0: Well Horatio hornblower is a fictional character created by cs forester for a series of novels And it's based on a real life person named Horatio.
Speaker 1: Nelson.
Speaker 0: Yes now now when we say based on we mean in the loosest sense Yeah, I mean what do they have in common, let's see awesome in the british navy Awesome named Horatio named Horatio Granted the.
Speaker 1: the one important difference is that Horatio hornblower in the novels actually ends up Piloting the ship that carries Horatio Nelson's body in his funeral.
Speaker 1: Uh, which is great because he gets assigned this honor and he's walking out and he realizes this isn't an honor.
Speaker 1: This is crap because if I do the job perfectly no one's gonna care because of course I did the job perfectly But if anything goes wrong, i'm totally fucked because I just lost Horatio.
Speaker 1: Nelson's body.
Speaker 1: There's nothing to gain from this and everything to lose.
Speaker 1: this totally blows.
Speaker 0: Uh, that's a good one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, now scott hasn't actually read the books.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have but scott has seen the shows as if I yes what they did is, uh, let's see When did they actually do that?
Speaker 1: It doesn't really matter I don't want to get into who directed it or whatever.
Speaker 0: No, no, but I just wanted to say what year they came out with the uh in 1998 through uh itv and a and e. Uh teamed up and made a mini series of television shows even though they're more like movies Yeah, they're all like two hours long.
Speaker 0: Yeah of Horatio hornblower stories and they started out with like one set of them of like four movies and then they came out with like a couple more and A few more and then they were done.
Speaker 1: So i'm going to tell you what Horatio hornblower is about and then we're going to tell you what it's really about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the books by cs forester are in my opinion some of the greatest nautical fiction written in english ever.
Speaker 1: Well, uh, Now here are my reasons why i'm a huge fan of cs forester.
Speaker 1: I put him second only to damas in terms of my writing.
Speaker 1: I like and maybe uh, I'm not gonna get into that now They are written in a very exacting style in that he did his research and A lot of it is very accurate or at least plausible.
Speaker 1: It gives you a good sense of what being in the british navy was actually like.
Speaker 1: and while it is romanticized It is romanticized in a fairly realistic way because it romanticizes a lot of things that are not terribly romantic.
Speaker 1: Now aside from that the writing style He had this gift of where and I think some famous writing critic said something similar, but when you read these books He uses all the jargon of nautical the world the nautical world All the things that you don't know what these things are the mizzen mask the top sales all these things
Speaker 0: Some of the things are
Speaker 1: coming into elise shore and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: And he never explains whenever it is ever.
Speaker 1: And it's kind of like what the show's like er did where all the jargons there and all.
Speaker 1: but unlike that All the jargon is used properly or at least 90 percent properly.
Speaker 1: And while you read it, you really feel at the end of any given book or after like any particular maneuver Like, you know exactly what's going on and you know exactly what what happened, you know, what was going on, you know You could be a sea captain.
Speaker 1: You know how to.
Speaker 1: I could deal with that.
Speaker 1: Obviously the storm came in So I pulled in the top.
Speaker 1: souls not heave too.
Speaker 1: But then you think about it and you realize that you have no fucking idea What actually happened.
Speaker 1: your brain just tricked you into thinking you did because of the way he wrote it.
Speaker 1: yeah, and it's.
Speaker 1: and he makes scenes where they're taking a bunch of barrels of beef and Lugging them onto the ship.
Speaker 1: be really dramatic and really on the edge of your seat.
Speaker 1: Oh shit They're gonna drop it heave heave.
Speaker 1: Oh, we got it.
Speaker 1: Uh, and it it's hard to explain.
Speaker 1: You just got to read these books.
Speaker 0: The thing is the stories.
Speaker 0: while they're well written and exciting adventure stories with lots of drama and action And awesomeness They're not really deep or meaningful or no literary.
Speaker 1: They're a lot like the james bond books in that only in the water.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and a little bit better.
Speaker 1: I would say with cannons and honestly Here's the plot of every horatio hornblower book generally.
Speaker 1: Horatio was on the land.
Speaker 1: The land is boring and sad.
Speaker 1: london is stifling and everything sucks.
Speaker 1: He may or may not have a wife or a lover but he's kind of sick of her and wishes he was in the ocean.
Speaker 1: Hooray, there's war now.
Speaker 1: He's in the ocean.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: He has to get everything together and it sucks.
Speaker 1: his crew sucks.
Speaker 1: He's seasick through the trials and tribulations of sea.
Speaker 1: the crew becomes awesome.
Speaker 1: Then he meets a woman.
Speaker 1: he cheats on whoever he was with on the land.
Speaker 1: if there was someone with this woman.
Speaker 1: This woman then either dies or the woman back on the shore dies so he can be with whichever woman he wanted.
Speaker 1: In the course of this he does something awesome.
Speaker 1: his best friend dies and he ends up at the end of the book Wishing he was back at sea.
Speaker 0: But of course you say he's like the hero of the entire british nation.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the whole time The end of every book is like he's sailing back and he's like, oh crap They're gonna court-martial me because I suck and everything about me sucks and I totally screwed this up.
Speaker 1: And then they make him a knight or the order of the bath or they give him a gigantic pile of money Or they commend him or whatever and all his fears are put to rest.
Speaker 1: and that's the end.
Speaker 1: They're total formulas.
Speaker 1: every book's the same.
Speaker 1: if you unless you really like this stuff just read one of them It doesn't matter which one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just watch the freaking movies because that's all I see now the books aside Here's what he ratio is really about because you watch these shows.
Speaker 1: basically Horatio hornblower is a show where the good guys look like good guys and they always win.
Speaker 1: The bad guys look like bad guys.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: The bad guys are all french and spanish and the good guys are all english Yep, or uh simpson or simon or whatever his name was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was british but yeah, it's like every episode of the tv show is like there's one guy who's like You know the the kind of annoying guy who's he ratio has to go around with who's not?
Speaker 0: You know good and everyone else is good and yep.
Speaker 1: And then there's the bad guy and it's like the guy appears bad music bad guy doing bad things.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, look he's doing bad things but he can't do anything about the guy until the very end of the episode.
Speaker 1: when suddenly everything comes together he kicks him ass and Everyone bad gets what's coming to them.
Speaker 1: every time you dislike a character Everything you want to happen to them happens to them.
Speaker 0: No more than what you want to happen.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I think the I don't.
Speaker 1: we're not ruining anything because he's got to watch these but Watch the first episode of Horatio, which I believe is called the duel.
Speaker 1: They might have named it something else depending on the release.
Speaker 1: It's the first one Mr.
Speaker 1: Midshipman hornblower And not only does the bad guy gets what get what's coming to him?
Speaker 1: But the bad guy leaves the plot for like an hour and you think he's won and then the bad guy's back You're like, oh shit And then the bad guy loses in like the most double epic awesome way you could ever imagine.
Speaker 0: I think the other great thing about it is in Horatio.
Speaker 0: There's all sorts of characters It's like.
Speaker 0: as for as many characters that are the bad guy that you hate This character is that is just awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh captain peleu if I were ever to be gay for a man it would be captain peleu because he's just so badass and heroic and he always knows what to do.
Speaker 0: and He does it and he gets the shit done.
Speaker 0: the thing He's the captain and you have to move the boat and there's no wind.
Speaker 1: so he gets in a little boat and he rose And it's like oh, yeah And the best part is you always keep coming back to him because that's the ship Horatio's on.
Speaker 1: But then every time Horatio is on his own It's always trouble because peleu's not there and you always feel like oh if peleu were here.
Speaker 1: But then horatio starts becoming more and more awesome and peleu realizes this and realizes that this kid's gonna be me someday and he will someday because well There wouldn't be another episode.
Speaker 1: if he didn't what really helps is that aside from being the baddest ass Motherfucker in the history of the world with the possible exception of washington Washington peleu Is the most sarcastic motherfucker in the history of the world.
Speaker 0: it's it peleu like he always.
Speaker 0: I can't even do the peleu humor because it's just so Amazing.
Speaker 0: what he does is he'll he'll be like you'll come back on the boat Horatio will come back on the boat and peleu will be like, oh you screwed up there blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you follow the orders?
Speaker 0: blah blah blah and horatio would be like, uh, something something excuse something and peleu You'll be like, oh, oh, is that right?
Speaker 0: You know you think uh, you know, you think this and this.
Speaker 1: you think you're smarter than The admiralty.
Speaker 1: you think you know what the best thing to do with that ship was.
Speaker 0: well, you know what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you don't.
Speaker 0: you Are 10 times as smarter than you thought you were.
Speaker 0: and then it'll be like you've been promoted.
Speaker 1: And the guy it's this the sarcasm is so powerful that it hits you like a brick.
Speaker 1: It's fantastic.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like if rim came up and i'd be like, oh rim you think uh, you wouldn't ten dollars, huh?
Speaker 0: You think you won ten dollars?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you didn't win ten dollars.
Speaker 0: You won a hundred dollars you piece of shit.
Speaker 0: And then it's it's like what?
Speaker 1: He says it like he's scolding you but it's it's like It's like you bastard you made lieutenant and by the reverse token when he's actually scolding someone It's all that but without the sarcasm at the end.
Speaker 0: You're like, oh that really hurt And it's hard to tell if he's about to turn around or not.
Speaker 0: plus when he actually scold someone it's it's pretty much If you're talking to him.
Speaker 0: You basically hear the same thing out of his mouth no matter what and then at the end You're either gonna get like a sack full of money or whipped.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you don't know which one there's no way to tell until he's done talking.
Speaker 1: now aside from him All the officers on the ship racers on for the early episodes the indefatigable aren't also Just sarcastic and snippy and hilarious.
Speaker 1: and while this is a very serious show There is a I guess it's a very it's a very british show and then there's so much humor constantly.
Speaker 1: It's you know, epic epic epic.
Speaker 1: Oh my god a fight.
Speaker 1: epic epic epic Little quips little bips when a ballsy comes back in the wrong war at the end with all those guns in his belt on the horse In the french uniform.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's a good part.
Speaker 1: you're like.
Speaker 1: how's that guy gonna get out of it?
Speaker 1: the whole army's dead.
Speaker 1: He's the only one left and then he comes riding over with the guns like i'm awesome.
Speaker 1: Look at me.
Speaker 0: well I think they also do that to show you that there's a bunch of characters on this boat and For a lot.
Speaker 0: horatio is not like the admiral of the whole navy right away.
Speaker 1: No, he's just like a crap midshipman.
Speaker 0: He's not even the captain of the boat yet.
Speaker 0: No, he's not even a lieutenant.
Speaker 1: He's acting lieutenant.
Speaker 1: He's only acting lieutenant because everyone above him got killed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so all they have to show you Somehow that the people that are above horatio are above him because they're better than he is right now.
Speaker 0: yeah, so, you know captain pelli of course always has an opportunity to be awesome, but like Mr.
Speaker 0: Bowles doesn't have an opportunity to be awesome that often so in one episode He's got to be more awesome if he's a higher rank than horatio.
Speaker 0: So they give him a chance to be awesome like one in one episode and sure enough.
Speaker 0: He's awesome.
Speaker 0: You don't get to be a higher rank than horatio and also be worse than him or else you die.
Speaker 0: And then horatio takes a spot.
Speaker 1: See horatio Does what like sanctuary does for me with yakuza.
Speaker 1: where if if being in the navy?
Speaker 1: Back then was like being horatio hornblower or captain pelew.
Speaker 1: That's the best life.
Speaker 1: I would live that life in a second too bad.
Speaker 0: That's not what it was like.
Speaker 0: No, there's a lot of rat eating.
Speaker 1: It's a little more like the books because the books are a lot less funny and a lot more.
Speaker 1: Wow, a lot of people just died.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of people just died.
Speaker 1: But here it's like A lot of people just died.
Speaker 1: That was awesome.
Speaker 1: When the uh, it's like if someone with a name does dies It's it's no big deal when lord watch his name takes his marines around the back and kills all the french and he's just so like lackadaisical about.
Speaker 1: he's just like Fire patoom patoom fire patoom patoom.
Speaker 0: He's a british like army lord, right?
Speaker 0: He's got like a whole bunch of guys with rifles and muskets and things and he's on a horse and he's just so bored all the time, but then he's confident because he's just so Badass, but he's also his ass.
Speaker 1: His marines are so much better than those french soldiers.
Speaker 0: I know he's just like.
Speaker 0: it's like if you had a bunch of navy seals and you had to kill like a bunch of 13 year olds.
Speaker 0: you just be like All right guys go get him move out in the humvee.
Speaker 0: Yeah, shoot him.
Speaker 1: It's like what formation doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Just walk shoot him.
Speaker 1: now shoot that guy.
Speaker 0: Are we done yet?
Speaker 0: I think we killed them all.
Speaker 0: All right, let's pack it up.
Speaker 1: guys Like they set you up in a normal crap show.
Speaker 1: you meet this lord and Horatio has to work with this lord and he's like Oh, it's a lord.
Speaker 1: He's only in the army because blah blah blah He's not doesn't know anything and you expect like the show to progress some guy who paid for a commission.
Speaker 0: He's not actually, you know a good army guy.
Speaker 0: He's just some guy who paid to get a title but instead He's cool.
Speaker 1: And while he's a lord, he's still cool.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, the guy who's supposed to hate The french guy who's on their side Not only do they make him a really unlikable guy.
Speaker 1: They make him a billion times unlikable.
Speaker 1: I mean he carries the guillotine with him and he's just cutting people's heads off and he's an asshole And he's stupid.
Speaker 0: that's the french guy you're supposed to hate.
Speaker 1: but there's the other french guy who's just dumb Who's not actually evil, but you like that guy because he tries so hard and at the end when he gets what's coming to him He basically gives the speech of I fucked it up.
Speaker 1: I know it Get out of here.
Speaker 1: So you don't die too.
Speaker 1: This totally sucks.
Speaker 0: well, he's one of those people where you know, there's a line between bravery and stupidity where it's like because bravery is all about Taking a risk and you know in order to accomplish something that otherwise would not be accomplished and succeeding.
Speaker 0: If you take the risk, that's too large that there's no way you could have succeeded because it was such a dumb risk.
Speaker 0: Like, you know if you take the 10 chance But then you know that your skills and abilities actually make it like a 50 chance.
Speaker 0: That's heroism.
Speaker 0: If you take the 1 chance and no amount of skill and ability can make it a 2 chance Oh, you mean like, uh buying a lottery ticket?
Speaker 0: Yes Exactly.
Speaker 0: It's like if you want to go rescue someone from a burning building, right?
Speaker 0: And you know that you're really fast and you've got a suit on that will protect you somewhat from the fire and you know where the person is in the house and All right, you know, you've got you're probably you're going into a dangerous situation.
Speaker 0: It's a huge risk.
Speaker 0: You could die.
Speaker 0: odds are against you but You know that if you try really hard you can do this and you do it and then you're hero.
Speaker 0: If the house is like completely engulfed in flame and the people inside are on fire and there's like a gas tank sitting right there And you run in i'm gonna save them and then it explodes and you die.
Speaker 0: That was just stupid.
Speaker 1: But the way it works in the ratio world is it.
Speaker 1: it's basically the brit.
Speaker 1: as far as this show is concerned Britain is a meritocracy.
Speaker 1: the more badass you are the higher rank you are if you are a high rank But you never get to see the king You do in the books.
Speaker 1: yeah, and it's really funny but it's like In this world.
Speaker 0: following the rules of the british navy the king must be like an actual god.
Speaker 1: The king is just god walking around smiting people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's kind of funny because the people you know They're in the british navy.
Speaker 0: So they're always like god.
Speaker 0: saved the king blah blah king.
Speaker 0: Hooray the king.
Speaker 0: And they don't know the king.
Speaker 0: these people have no idea who the king is.
Speaker 0: They like they know his name.
Speaker 0: They might have seen a picture of him.
Speaker 0: That's about it.
Speaker 0: yet They're like in love with him.
Speaker 1: now when we watch horatio hornblower Traditionally we would get a big group of people together with a bunch of food and drink and we'd sit down And as a group watch an episode And we would turn on the subtitles to fight despite the fact that it's in english Because otherwise we couldn't hear what they're saying.
Speaker 1: amidst the yelling and screaming and cheering and booing It's kind of like shakespearean theater back in the shakespeare days.
Speaker 1: for us It's this big loud riotous affair and that is my in my opinion the only way to watch horatio.
Speaker 0: Yeah well I thought that you know like it was a show to watch with a lot of people and I still think it is a Show to watch with a lot of people and have fun so that when the crazy thing happens everyone goes.
Speaker 0: Oh at the same time and it's a good experience but Watching the show with less people is that was actually still really good because it's such a good show.
Speaker 0: It holds up.
Speaker 1: each one of these would stand on its own as a movie that I would just go see in the theater And pay my 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: Oh and go see in the theater I would have.
Speaker 0: it's definitely like the best a tv movie can be or direct a dvd movie can be So not a theater movie.
Speaker 1: Well, they're regardless.
Speaker 1: They're awesome.
Speaker 0: They are awesome.
Speaker 1: now Getting into them.
Speaker 1: My advice is thus the first episode is probably the best one to watch.
Speaker 1: However, I will point one thing out The first episode is different from all the rest in that It's a little slow.
Speaker 1: in the beginning It seems like this is going to be a tedious long running boring Drama, like the first half of the movie is just so I would say boring.
Speaker 1: almost Everything sucks.
Speaker 1: It sucks to be here ratio And that is very purposeful because it builds you up and builds you up and by the end you're just.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the second half of the first uh episode slash movie is what the rest of the entire show is like.
Speaker 1: the payoff Of the first episode.
Speaker 1: it's huge like and ludicrously huge.
Speaker 1: it's in the last five minutes.
Speaker 0: The last five minute payoff is so amazing that you'll it would be worth another half hour of boredom just to have that The.
Speaker 1: I never would have expected what happened in a million years.
Speaker 0: It happened and it's awesome.
Speaker 1: I could watch that scene over and over again.
Speaker 1: It's just brilliant and then pretty much from that point forward the whole show is exactly like that all the time.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, so if you want one that's funnier as opposed to just like the payoff like that just to really get into it You can watch the fire ships or watch the wrong war.
Speaker 1: the third one because that's the one that has a lot of the humor in it.
Speaker 0: Yep, I think that's the fourth one.
Speaker 1: I think oh, yeah, it is the fourth one.
Speaker 1: The third one is the spanish prison, which is also really good because I really like the guy who runs the spanish prison.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the don is a guy.
Speaker 0: But yeah ratio horn blower is awesome old school british navy action Not very deep not very meaningful, but action adventure Comedy and awesomeness.
Speaker 1: ahoy if you're not sure if you'd like this if you liked master and commander.
Speaker 0: This is better Yeah, it is better.
Speaker 1: And if you like this and you haven't seen master and commander see it Yeah, because it's good.
Speaker 0: It's not as good as ratio.
Speaker 1: Yes However, it does have a very horatio like moment when when the guy does the thing to himself.
Speaker 0: Yep I was thinking of the same moment.
Speaker 1: Yep All right We'll leave it at that because I got a long weekend ahead of me And I smell the lamb cooking downstairs and I really want to eat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah The smell of lamb doesn't do it for me.
Speaker 1: Well, you're just not human.
Speaker 1: Lamb is my third favorite meat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right after steak and steak.
Speaker 1: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all The rss feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and rpgs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com Or you can send audio feedback via odeo.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an odeo on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in itunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.