Speaker 0: It's Wednesday February 21st.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We discussed katsu khan 13.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know what I did today?
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 0: I played raptor call of the shadows man.
Speaker 1: That game was hot shit.
Speaker 0: The game is still hot shit.
Speaker 0: Holy crap.
Speaker 1: I mean doesn't remember this way.
Speaker 1: I Generally really don't like shmups.
Speaker 1: I never.
Speaker 0: I think that's just cuz.
Speaker 0: your skills at them are super low.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: I mean even like when I was a kid like but no one had skill at shmups and all me and all my friends were Gonna play shmups.
Speaker 1: and there was a point when I could have played shmups and become good at them.
Speaker 1: And even then at that early proto stage when I was just as good as all my friends I just didn't enjoy him and enjoy a space invaders or a Galaga or Galaxian not so much.
Speaker 1: No, ah, I never really liked space invaders.
Speaker 1: It's one of my terrible dark.
Speaker 0: So I don't like space invaders, but I love me.
Speaker 1: However Raptor call of the shadows.
Speaker 1: I not only love but considered paying money for Holy in the day.
Speaker 1: now remember that was from an era Where software piracy was not only rampant and unchecked and not only did there not exist copy protection of any At any value at all.
Speaker 1: But most people of my age who had video games back then weren't even really aware of the idea that piracy was somehow wrong Or illegal.
Speaker 0: that's true.
Speaker 1: the first video games I ever got other than the stuff that came with our computer.
Speaker 1: some guy just gave me a bunch of discs and I just thought that games were free.
Speaker 0: and then one day I saw him in the store and I was like, oh, yeah So I gotta come straight out with it and say I used bit torrent to get the full version of the game.
Speaker 0: It was an ISO.
Speaker 0: I burned the CD.
Speaker 0: I used DOS box, which is this great program that allows you to basically run DOS inside of Windows or Linux or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's also DOS EMU which is better for normal applications But not so great for gaming.
Speaker 0: DOS boxes really come a long way and if there's a DOS game you want to play I mean this thing plays mech warrior 2.
Speaker 0: I think you can play just about any other DOS game.
Speaker 1: You've got mech warrior 2.
Speaker 0: it just requires a little bit of you know, relatively simple tweaking you know to get everything to work for any specific game and then What I had to do is I ran the installer from the CD and it totally just seg faulted.
Speaker 0: So, you know what I did.
Speaker 0: you're gonna love this.
Speaker 0: I copied all the files from the CD to a directory on the computer and in that director You know on the CD was rap dot exe.
Speaker 0: So I just ran the game.
Speaker 1: man That was I'm back in the day.
Speaker 1: All games are like that.
Speaker 1: I mean when I first got sieve - I just copied it from someone else's computer onto my computer And it just worked.
Speaker 0: I know isn't it crazy?
Speaker 1: But anyway as we said yesterday and if you couldn't all figure it out We're back from katsu khan.
Speaker 1: We survived and we are now going to review katsu khan since it is anime night.
Speaker 1: If you want to hear about the video game room at katsu khan, you should probably listen to Yesterday's last night's episode where we actually talked about that in detail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because half the khan or at least almost half the khan was just gaming of various sorts.
Speaker 0: So we reviewed that all yesterday on gaming day.
Speaker 1: And today we'll review everything else about katsu khan Plus, you know, we can turn this katsu khan experience into two shows though saving us a lot of thought and effort Not having to come up with another show idea.
Speaker 1: Awesome yeah, but before we do that we should do a little bit of news since you know, It is geek nights and every time we try to shorten the news or get rid of it.
Speaker 1: You guys yell at us.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I didn't mention this too much already because it wouldn't have mattered that much.
Speaker 0: But this weekend is the New York comic convention.
Speaker 0: take two.
Speaker 1: You might remember the previous year's New York comic convention Which I don't think the word debacle even begins to describe the catastrophic failure of that convention.
Speaker 0: well last year they tried to make a New York comic convention and they did and I tried to go to it and I failed Because they sold more tickets than they had room for human beings and they had a giant Convention in a very small space
Speaker 1: to the point that not even the guests of the khan or the VIPs were allowed in by the state Police and the fire marshal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even if you had even if you managed to get a ticket You were lucky.
Speaker 0: if you know, you could get into the room and there are people with pre-registrations Who couldn't get badges or couldn't get in.
Speaker 0: it was dude.
Speaker 1: There were guests of the khan standing outside going.
Speaker 1: what the fuck is this shit Charles?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now meanwhile while you were standing in line trying to deal with that business.
Speaker 1: I was not there Because I generally don't like comic conventions and I knew better for other reasons and I guess I'm psychic I must have guessed that somehow something bad was gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Well the thing I would have known that something bad is gonna happen if I had known the crucial piece of information that they were Advertising the convention on television.
Speaker 0: and they're doing it this year, too.
Speaker 1: I don't know why in New York City where if you advertise anything on TV At least a thousand people are gonna knock on your door and ask what's up yet.
Speaker 0: So I don't think I don't know why they're advertising more than they have to.
Speaker 0: but whatever this year They're trying again and they seem to have learned from their mistakes.
Speaker 0: The Saturday badges are sold out.
Speaker 0: You can't get them anymore.
Speaker 0: So I assume that on Saturday that they won't have to turn anyone away because you'll know that there's no way in unless you've got A badge already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why I haven't mentioned the con so much is because it's not gonna be easy to get in If you just found out about it right now.
Speaker 1: Well, unless you want to go on Friday only but Friday only.
Speaker 1: now that I look at it is kind of lame.
Speaker 0: Well Sunday only is actually the hotness, but we're busy Sunday.
Speaker 0: My original plan was to wait and hear what people who went Friday and Saturday said and if they said good things That I would go Sunday only.
Speaker 0: but because of you know my life and what's going on.
Speaker 0: I have to go Friday.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're trying to make it sound like we're doing something awesome.
Speaker 1: We're playing D&D.
Speaker 0: Yep, which is awesome It is course, but yeah, so on Friday from 4 p.m.
Speaker 0: To 9 p.m.
Speaker 0: Which is the only hours It is open to the general public and badge holders as opposed to just insiders on Friday I will be there and rim might eventually be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I paid so I'm gonna go.
Speaker 1: I'm working in the Bronx.
Speaker 1: So hopefully I'll be able to slip over if I finish all my you know work business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I do to make money.
Speaker 0: I'll also probably start waiting in line around 3 Maybe 2 30 depends on what the train schedule is and all that jazz.
Speaker 0: just because you know most of the reason I'm going is because there's people I know that'll be there for the Internet's and While I'm waiting in line I can talk to them.
Speaker 0: So it's like having another hour doing what I would have done inside only outside.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so don't we're not doing anything at the con.
Speaker 1: if you run into us you don't.
Speaker 0: hey you don't have a table We don't have anything.
Speaker 0: We're just there as Guests not even as guests as normal con goers as normal schmucks.
Speaker 1: We're not press or anything.
Speaker 0: I might have a few flyers on me if they have a free shit table.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll put flyers on it.
Speaker 0: That's it, man.
Speaker 1: It seems like comic cons are the only cons.
Speaker 1: We're really not trying to do anything at.
Speaker 0: yeah There is a Podcasting alley at the.
Speaker 1: oh, that's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: Well podcasters are also great.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, they got.
Speaker 0: all the comic podcasters have little tables there.
Speaker 0: I assume.
Speaker 0: I don't know how big this is But oh, well, that's where they're.
Speaker 0: that's where some people might be.
Speaker 0: That's where I might be.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I make fun of most podcasters.
Speaker 1: all the podcasters We actually know or have met at cons have been cool so far.
Speaker 1: So in the little probably meet some more cool people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically my goal here is to network a lot.
Speaker 0: also There's gonna be a few comic creators like Rushkoff.
Speaker 0: He has a signing from four to five.
Speaker 1: I'll probably be waiting in line so you can say hey, I won your contest a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah Hey, do you know who I am?
Speaker 0: What's up?
Speaker 0: You're awesome and smart.
Speaker 0: sign my book.
Speaker 0: You want to be on my podcast?
Speaker 1: I didn't hurt to ask get him on the podcast, man I'll give you a dollar if you get him on the podcast.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna ask it doesn't hurt?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd give you the recording bit, but it's still broken.
Speaker 0: No, I don't need the recording bit That's all right.
Speaker 0: I'm also gonna try to go around the After I walk around the you know main show floor once to see what the story is because there's no comics I need to buy.
Speaker 0: yeah at all.
Speaker 1: Well, you're not looking for Silver Surfer Issue 138 alternate cover.
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: But that was the best Silver Surfer ever.
Speaker 0: I don't even think that's such a comic exists.
Speaker 0: Probably not.
Speaker 0: but I'm gonna go around the artist alley trying to get some more pirate sketches Because that is one thing there is to say about the comic conventions.
Speaker 0: is the artist alleys while they may not be as big or as friendly and as awesome as the anime convention ones the percentage of high quality artists that are in there is greater because usually the tables cost a lot more and The old the people who get them are like the people who have jobs drawing actual comic books But they're not the super famous guys to like the semi famous guys the guys who are gonna be famous soon.
Speaker 1: So anyway, Tokyo pop it looks like they are revamping the rating system They're going to use for their manga.
Speaker 0: Does anyone even really pay attention to the rating system?
Speaker 0: that's on the manga.
Speaker 1: I mean really Most people know what these ratings even the ones for like the ERSB or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yes RB I don't think anyone actually pays attention to that at all.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: as far as I'm concerned manga has two ratings.
Speaker 0: you ready?
Speaker 0: shrink wrap and not shrink wrap.
Speaker 0: Those are the manga rating system, though.
Speaker 1: You'll be happy to know that one now.
Speaker 1: It is much more fine-grained.
Speaker 1: They distinguish between moderate gore and extreme gore.
Speaker 0: So what's moderate gore?
Speaker 0: is that like?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Disemboweling or is that extreme go though interestingly they specifically call out occultism as you have to be at least 13 to read about occultism Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: and of course the most important thing you'll all be pleased to know that potty humor is all ages.
Speaker 0: Oh Thank God.
Speaker 1: I know I don't know we do without that I mean if potty humor was gonna be relegated to some higher level.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I could deal with that.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there'd be any manga for all ages.
Speaker 1: I Haven't read much in my life that didn't involve some form of potty humor.
Speaker 0: even in the count of mod and Christo There's a tiny bit You know would be hilarious like if somehow this rating system worked out or like Doraemon got a 13-plus You saw or Pokemon got a 13-plus.
Speaker 1: I could see that happening.
Speaker 0: That'd be hilarious.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, this stuff is meant for two-year-olds in Japan, but in the u.s.. Thirteen or older, please things of the day.
Speaker 1: Now in keeping with my I don't know semi theme kind of randomly I got another dragon ball related thing of the day here.
Speaker 0: Oh my god two dragon balls in one week.
Speaker 0: What is the world coming to?
Speaker 1: I don't know what's going on?
Speaker 1: I mean the Hitler thing.
Speaker 1: before and now I got this.
Speaker 0: you didn't plan on this one.
Speaker 1: no no however I am pleased that for the first time in a while my thing of the day I found it, and I dug it and it had one dig and now it has a lot of digs.
Speaker 1: It's on the front page.
Speaker 1: I'd like to think that I contributed a tiny bit to that.
Speaker 0: Oh, so your thing of the day you found it before it was on dig And then it got dug to the front page after you decided on it as opposed to our current system Where we tend to not have anything planned, and then we pick something from day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something that's already got a hundred or two hundred or a thousand digs.
Speaker 1: luckily a lot of people don't seem to read dig So it's okay.
Speaker 1: I know what's up with that, but anyway, but anyway a while ago.
Speaker 1: This is actually kind of old.
Speaker 1: It just made it to the internet.
Speaker 1: Dragon Ball and all that was re-released and in some sort of cool gesture a whole bunch of other manga Other than you know the great Dragon Ball master decided to draw their own interpretations.
Speaker 0: Who is the great dragon ball master Toriyama?
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 1: Just making sure I know who did Dragon Ball.
Speaker 0: I'm just making sure that sounds like the rim will usually say something like that to cop out when he doesn't know something.
Speaker 1: Not only do I know about Toriyama, but I watched a musical that involved him at an amazement last year.
Speaker 0: Wow, I know that he did the arts also for Chrono Trigger anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't help but tell that if you ever watch any of those FMV's.
Speaker 1: But anyway a bunch of mangaka did their own interpretations.
Speaker 1: You know kind of as a thank you and Here's a compilation of all of them, and they're kind of cool.
Speaker 1: The sad thing is I like several of them more than I like Toriyama's actual work.
Speaker 0: Also, I like many of them are from mangaka where I like their interpretation of Dragon Ball better than the manga They usually write.
Speaker 0: So it goes both ways sadly.
Speaker 1: I haven't read many of the manga listed there.
Speaker 0: I only read maybe a couple of them and heard of some most of them actually.
Speaker 1: yeah anyway What do you got for me all right?
Speaker 0: So I found this cartoon now from 1937 or 38. it was actually from 38.
Speaker 0: It was a Fleischer Brothers cartoon called all the Fleischer brothers.
Speaker 0: I think it's called all's fair at the fair, and it's about the world's fair.
Speaker 0: And it's a pretty good short cartoon.
Speaker 0: And I picked this cartoon as thing of day for two reasons.
Speaker 0: number one if you think dubbing is bad on anime today When Americans dub Japanese anime you got to see this thing about dubbing in 1938 in the original language.
Speaker 0: I mean mouths don't move.
Speaker 0: It's basically like Popeye where there's basically some yammering going on Very rapidly.
Speaker 1: I think yammering is the proper term which is like hey.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do this.
Speaker 1: hey they probably just found two homeless people sat him down in front of microphones and said watch this cartoon and talk and Say whatever.
Speaker 1: those people would be saying no just say whatever comes into your crazy hobo head.
Speaker 0: That's uh It's hard to tell.
Speaker 0: but second reason I chose this cartoon is because the world's fair is awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh shit is the world fair?
Speaker 0: us was well actually I looked on Wikipedia this technically still some sort of world Exposition thing whatever.
Speaker 0: 2005 it was in Nagoya and in 2010 it's gonna be somewhere else like Shanghai or something.
Speaker 0: but it's not the same.
Speaker 0: the world's fair was like an exposition of Everything that is great about humanity.
Speaker 1: It was just science and triumph and the human spirits and awesome waffles.
Speaker 0: And you know it was in New York in the 60s.
Speaker 0: my parents went to it and everyone I know went to it.
Speaker 0: who is older than me in my family?
Speaker 0: But I never got to go because by the time I was born it was gone.
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of that is that one.
Speaker 1: we have an internet and now we're just in four.
Speaker 1: I mean back then you'd go to the world's fair And you'd see.
Speaker 1: you know like visions of the future and new technology and way back in the day like new Technology that no one had ever seen before would be here or at least no one normal had seen.
Speaker 1: now if anything is invented It's on the internet immediately.
Speaker 1: I already know about it.
Speaker 1: I don't need to go look at it with a bunch of people at a fair.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well the difference is is that the world's fair is a place that shows Technology to all people and only people like us actually look up new technology on the Internet's.
Speaker 0: most people just don't care.
Speaker 0: But most people would go to an awesome fair where you lull them You know into seeing all this technology, and then you can inspire the awe of science Which is greatly lacking in our society?
Speaker 0: Yes, I think part of that is because we don't have the world's fair anymore.
Speaker 1: We got to the moon in 1969 and oh my god We got to the moon and now we don't care gonna build a base on Mars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever too much money fuck it Exactly, and I don't think the world's fair was not the biggest reason that the attitude changed But it was definitely a part if only a small part.
Speaker 1: I got some ideas, but we're not gonna talk about that.
Speaker 0: when I talk about that now all I gotta say is world's fair is awesome And whenever I go to Queens, and I see the remnants of the world's fair I go.
Speaker 1: So I got a nice segue here, you know what else is awesome katsu katsu khan 13.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, so yeah, we were at katsu khan 13.
Speaker 1: We're finally bringing you our coverage.
Speaker 1: I will may or may not intersperse it with the things we recorded at the khan which range from us Rambling to each other because it was easier than trying to talk over the din To us attempting to interview these Phoenix Wright cosplayers who?
Speaker 1: Refused to come over but then joined our forums Apologized for being timid and ended up being cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's up with that granted?
Speaker 1: We knew they were cool cuz they wasn't just Phoenix Wright.
Speaker 1: It was a whole Phoenix Wright cast.
Speaker 0: Yeah a lot of people did the the Maya and the pearl and the whatever cosplay that I have never seen anyone try before even though It's kind of obvious.
Speaker 0: you would do that because it was made for cosplay that character.
Speaker 1: Well, but anyway I suppose we'll just go semi chronologically since usually we don't try to plan these things out as planning always ends in failure.
Speaker 0: All right, we got to the car.
Speaker 0: Well, do you want to talk about getting to the con?
Speaker 1: I will go over this very briefly.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we can save the actual story for a geek fable Suffice to say as we're about to leave one.
Speaker 1: There was a horrible snowstorm in New York State which crippled much of the state.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got less of it than people farther north But we were still hit pretty bad with over a foot of snow.
Speaker 1: So Wednesday night Scott and I spent over an hour Trying to dig the four feet out of the driveway requisite to move the cars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have guys that the landlord pays to shovel.
Speaker 0: They didn't show up They suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's my money missing But anyway, so we dig the cars out and then we get some Chinese food.
Speaker 1: the next day We go to leave and buy various odd acts of gods and fate and running into snow banks.
Speaker 1: Scott's cars alignment was out of whack and we didn't have time to fix it.
Speaker 1: So we had to take my busted car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's the alignment but the car got you know pretty messed up in the wheels and the tires in general be trying to get it out of that driveway and Possibly before trying to get it out of that driveway.
Speaker 1: Yeah so at the beginning before we got to the con was basically total disaster and the fact that we Mitigated that entirely and still made it to the con on time amazes me even today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I basically went across this bridge with my car shaking like a monster brought it back over the bridge paid a dollar Toll just switched everything into rims car in about five minutes and then got on the road again.
Speaker 1: Yep, my car that was low on coolin Great.
Speaker 1: So whatever we got to katsucon Thursday night the staff in the video game room We're setting up and right away We realized that this was gonna be a good time because the staff were to had all their stuff together in a way that very few Cons ever do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like we got there and I was waiting by the front door and rim went to go find someone to help us carry The tub of shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah the tub that weighed between 40 and 60 pounds.
Speaker 1: There's probably more like 45.
Speaker 0: Who knows we carried that whole thing so far.
Speaker 0: It was a nightmare.
Speaker 1: We mostly me.
Speaker 0: Well, you didn't want to.
Speaker 0: I offer to help you a lot of times.
Speaker 0: You're less like.
Speaker 0: no, I got it.
Speaker 0: So if you got it, I'm not good.
Speaker 1: Sorry fine Yeah, so we I want to do that, you know one person on each side deal cuz that didn't work so well on the ice All right, so we dragged the thing into the car, you know, we need someone to help us carry it.
Speaker 1: So I go find you know Aaron in the video game room staff and they sent me.
Speaker 1: they basically offered me as many roadies as I needed and anything I needed.
Speaker 1: They accommodated us far more than we even needed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like the couple times that I went and I said, uh, you know Can I get something that it would be there event?
Speaker 0: You know pretty quickly or as quickly as reasonably possible and like when I then eventually After like by the middle of the day Friday, I didn't need anything and then they were like, do you need anything?
Speaker 0: I'm like, no, what could I need?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so once you go out again if you want to hear about the video game room at Katsu con We talked about it last night on gaming night suffice to say it was badass.
Speaker 1: We got all our stuff together.
Speaker 1: We waited for our friends to show up who all took different routes to the con.
Speaker 1: I note specifically our friend Scott Johnson who last year got lost for two hours in the city And I told him to take the metro.
Speaker 1: and this year.
Speaker 1: He Didn't take the metro and got lost for two hours in the city, huh?
Speaker 0: Mmm, how did that happen?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Katsu khan.
Speaker 1: This is no fault of the khan.
Speaker 1: You cannot park at the con.
Speaker 1: do not attempt to drive to Katsu khan.
Speaker 1: You're asking for trouble.
Speaker 0: actually if you stay at the Marriott across the road Which does not have rooms at special con rates.
Speaker 0: It only has normal rooms.
Speaker 0: That's why a lot of people don't know about it, but you can easily get a room at it.
Speaker 0: It's right across the street from the con and you can also park at it for a fee.
Speaker 1: I assume yeah, and you know pay twice as much of money you will.
Speaker 0: you will have to pay money But it is very convenient.
Speaker 1: or you can park at the hotel about a mile away and pay but regardless You want to stay at the actual con hotel.
Speaker 1: that adds so much to the experience of Katsu khan because it's pretty much The first or second biggest straight-up khan hotel khan of anything.
Speaker 1: yep, all the other anime cons are either in a stadium or in a convention center or they're small and Katsu khan has both things Going for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and once you if you're staying in the hotel I mean it adds so much that you can go back to your room and get stuff go to the dealer's room put stuff in Your room have a party in your room without having people tell people how to find your hotel.
Speaker 1: The fact that I can wander out of my room at 4 30 in the morning find that not only is Everyone still active at the con, but there's still a line for guitar heroes and DDR.
Speaker 0: That's good stuff right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you ever go to Katsu khan the website tells you in red bold italics Take the metro we parked at.
Speaker 1: this metro station has a ramp off of i-95 Yep.
Speaker 0: So if you're coming from the north You can basically get off and exit on the highway and there's a parking lot right there.
Speaker 0: And as long as you leave on the weekend, it's free.
Speaker 0: So you park you get on a train the train you switch trains once which is very simple.
Speaker 0: The metro is not complex, especially when compared with say the New York subway got it cost $3.30.
Speaker 0: well one way.
Speaker 0: so six dollars and sixty cents Lordy yet to get there and back and it takes you about a block away from the convention hotel.
Speaker 1: Yes It also because when you walk from this metro station the one block to the hotel You will see every good restaurant on your way.
Speaker 0: Yeah at the same block that this metro station has is everything you're gonna need near the convention all these restaurants the CVS Etc.
Speaker 1: Now I got to say cuz last year I was impressed by this and then I forgot about it Land the year before too because I hadn't ever been to DC before and I forgot that Scott had never been here.
Speaker 1: so we get to this metro station and we're about to go up to the con and We come across probably one of the longest escalators in the world.
Speaker 0: It's also incredibly steep and Amazing and awe-inspiring.
Speaker 1: I totally forgot about it.
Speaker 1: So I didn't the game another.
Speaker 1: so I'm gonna walk it up and Scott stops.
Speaker 1: He goes, whoa, look at this.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's totally World's Fair quality.
Speaker 1: And then I stopped and said ah shit.
Speaker 1: We got to carry this tub up that thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we get off the metro and a guy's like hey you want to take the elevator?
Speaker 0: We're like, no, we're cool with this escalator because the escalator that's right next to the train Platform is a little escalator.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh we can get up there.
Speaker 1: Just I'm pretty sure the guy muttered your funeral as he got on the escalator and left us to our misery.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then we see the next Escalator.
Speaker 1: cuz I again I totally forgot about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah I thought there was only gonna be one and then there was a hidden one.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Do not drive to katsu-kan.
Speaker 1: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: You don't need to bring that much.
Speaker 0: Well drive to the metro station near katsu-kan and then take the metro the rest of the way.
Speaker 1: Yes now before we continue, I guess we can talk a little bit about katsu-kan.
Speaker 1: I mean it's in DC at the Omni showroom.
Speaker 1: It's been there for two years now.
Speaker 1: I think it's gonna stay there for a while cuz the hotel look like it's growing out of the hotel.
Speaker 1: now I mean it it is but only in the sense that all cons are outgrowing their venues.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's not outgrowing it in any catastrophic sense yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there weren't really lines for anything besides Walk main events walking between any elevators.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll get to the elevators Yeah, but wait the first katsu-kan you.
Speaker 1: it used to be in Crystal City, which was alright But the Omni showroom is really a great area.
Speaker 1: There's tons of restaurants around of with various reasonable prices.
Speaker 1: There's a really really good sushi place right there.
Speaker 1: That is just expensive enough to keep the con riffraff out So there's almost no weight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean pretty much this location for a con of this size is absolutely perfect except for these small Fact that you can't drive right up to it Which is mitigated by the fact that there is a metro station.
Speaker 0: and actually I kind of like that because it filters out dumb people.
Speaker 1: Scott Johnson Alright.
Speaker 0: So what was going down at katsu-kan?
Speaker 1: Well, I talked about this last year.
Speaker 1: We mentioned it yesterday, but katsu-kan is Has a very well not very but has a fairly significantly different Demographic from most other anime cons in the north slash east.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was definitely I noticed I mean rim was like oh, yeah, it's all older people and it wasn't really so much all older people.
Speaker 0: There are plenty of high school kids But I noticed that there was a significant lack of middle school kids like in other cons.
Speaker 0: They'll always be middle school punk kids around like remember anime next whole ton of middle school and yeah high school freshmen's.
Speaker 1: Remember you never ventured into the bar area where all the people our age tend to hang out during the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's true also but Yeah, there were basically no middle school kids, you know, the average age was significantly higher than at other conventions.
Speaker 0: I've been to.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean literally this is one of the few cons for someone my age.
Speaker 1: if I was looking for someone cool to ask out or hang out with or if I was all flirty Wouldn't have to worry as much about trying to find someone actually of a reasonable age.
Speaker 0: It's not to worry like is that one in high school and you know on an individual level?
Speaker 0: But in general your time is going to be easier.
Speaker 1: Yes now as a result of this there's one thing that goes on a lot at Katsu khan and that is drinking.
Speaker 1: Katsu khan is probably the drunkenest con other than penguin Khan that I've ever been to and will ever go to.
Speaker 0: I mean two people On our match game panel were drunk.
Speaker 1: Yes, which added to the hilarity Scott Johnson's troop of friends were drunk.
Speaker 1: Oh god, if you walk around the con at any hour, there are a significant number of drunk people.
Speaker 1: I would say that a good 20% of the people at that con are drunk by two o'clock on any given day.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that, but there's a lot of drunkenness going especially if you include the staff not gonna name names But non critical staff who are engaged in non critical activities or not above drinking.
Speaker 0: How many times did staff come up to us and be like staff booze run?
Speaker 0: What do you want?
Speaker 0: Like two or three times that was so fantastic.
Speaker 1: I'm setting up and I didn't bring any liquor with me because I don't want I have to do stuff at the con.
Speaker 1: So I didn't plan to be drunk the whole time and to I didn't want to carry it.
Speaker 1: I actually took liquor out of that tub when I realized how heavy the tub was so I never anything with me.
Speaker 1: The staff comes up we're buying liquor and I said pick me up a bottle of Southern Comfort.
Speaker 0: and they said, okay And they did yeah, and I put it in a flask.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I put it in the foot.
Speaker 1: Now the thing is I didn't drink it from the flask through the whole con to get drunk.
Speaker 1: I drank it Saturday in sips throughout today because it was basically cough syrup.
Speaker 1: My throat was already gone by Saturday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually one thing I got to mention about this con.
Speaker 0: We bought those earbuds, right the the earplugs Yeah, the etymotic the $12 dealies.
Speaker 0: I forget what number they are Don't ask but if you go to etymoteic.com you can find them pretty easily.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: in-ear musicians quality headphones Yeah
Speaker 0: they basically
Speaker 1: you
Speaker 0: wear them and it reduces all sounds you hear by X decibels no matter what the frequency and I usually only bought them for concerts or Maybe if I'm going somewhere incredibly loud like there's gonna be a jackhammer in the street or something like that.
Speaker 0: You know but I wore them a lot at the convention mostly in the video game room where the comp the combination of all the music and The video game systems and everything else was making a tremendous amount of noise.
Speaker 0: And it actually had two side effects.
Speaker 0: one was that I saved my voice because I tend to talk louder than the things I'm hearing so that I can hear myself and Since I could hear myself talking pretty quietly.
Speaker 0: I didn't speak as loud So I saved my voice as opposed to what I would have had if I hadn't worn those.
Speaker 0: My voice would have been shot on Friday.
Speaker 1: now more importantly I mean we wouldn't have bothered if we were just you know people going to the con.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't say you should bring earplugs Only if you're gonna sit.
Speaker 0: where were?
Speaker 0: you were sitting for hours.
Speaker 1: see where we were stationed at the head of the video game room in the old-school cabinet gaming area where we were blasting music 24/7 and where we had a live DJ next to us blasting beats whenever He felt like it made a million arcade machines blasting music with pop and music right there blasting music We.
Speaker 1: we would have lost some hearing if we tried to stay in that room as much as we did.
Speaker 0: Small amount of permanent hearing damage now.
Speaker 0: the other side effect Was that because I talked so quietly in this loud room a lot of people couldn't hear me Which is very strange for me.
Speaker 0: people don't often say what did you say to me?
Speaker 1: Usually the entire front row crew is telling Scott to be quiet and stop yelling yeah So oh well, which is what it actually worked out.
Speaker 0: I was like ah these earplugs saved my convention, and they did even though I got slightly addicted to wearing them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott was wearing him.
Speaker 1: after we left the con I had to keep reminding him to not put them in and to take them out so I could talk to him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, also.
Speaker 1: I forgot to bring them to the rave which was alright cuz we only stayed in the rave for like an hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually when I wore them at the rave like I could totally hear the music It sounded great, and I took him out.
Speaker 0: it just hurt.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I don't know if that was relative or absolute though part of that was relative.
Speaker 1: part of it Was that you were standing a good five feet closer to the primary?
Speaker 1: Driving force of music.
Speaker 0: okay, there's a speaker right there cuz I took him out for like 10 seconds just to see.
Speaker 1: yeah I watch when you took it out your ear was directly in front of that thing okay?
Speaker 1: That's why I was kind of dancing with my back to it.
Speaker 1: ah Oh, yeah, but we'll get to all that as we're saying a lot.
Speaker 1: But we wore earplugs for most of the con just because it was loud and we had to actually do business.
Speaker 1: Yep, so aside from the video game room katsu khan is a typical khan.
Speaker 1: They have their main events room, which they is dual purpose.
Speaker 1: at night They use it for the rave during the day.
Speaker 1: these for the main events.
Speaker 1: They have I think the anime music video showings in there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: They got what else they have in there.
Speaker 0: Oh the P Landers II concerts are in there.
Speaker 0: Yes The cosplay is in there.
Speaker 1: We didn't actually go to the P Landers II concert, but our friend Corbin did.
Speaker 0: yeah There were two of them those one on Friday at 10 and one on Sunday at noon.
Speaker 1: If you ever go to a con and P Landers II is there you should see them at least once because they put on A pretty good stage show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's not really I don't know what the music is Like.
Speaker 0: I don't imagine it'll be my favorite music in the world But people are.
Speaker 0: it seems that while they're not the most famous thing ever and people don't go crazy over it And they won't draw a million people to the con It's still very entertaining and worth seeing especially if you're already at the convention and you have nothing better to do.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: It is very much more about the performance and the things they do than their music.
Speaker 1: Also, apparently though we were busy doing other things at the time they found their way into the gaming room Discovered the Wii area and proceeded to attempt to use them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they played a lot of Wii over there and people were very much entertained by seeing P Landers II play Wii.
Speaker 1: god I'm entertained by seeing P Landers II try to brush their teeth.
Speaker 0: They're just yeah, they're crazy dudes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I mean other guests.
Speaker 1: actually, this is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: but uh Ananth and Hawk from Apple geeks were at the con as guests and For various reasons due to the fact that Ananth is friends with our friend Ido and Ido was staying in our room with our friend Conrad Ananth ended up crashing in our room
Speaker 0: and being on our match game panel.
Speaker 0: Yes And everything.
Speaker 1: so once if you don't read Apple geeks, you should check it out Ananth at least.
Speaker 1: We didn't actually really talk to Hawk but Ananth is totally cool.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: He's a pretty awesome guy.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'll be honest.
Speaker 1: I don't read Apple geeks, but you'll probably find that entertaining though I will say that actually a Mookie was there from Dominic Deegan.
Speaker 1: He's a cool guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we see him at every con.
Speaker 0: We always stop by and say hi.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used to never read his comic.
Speaker 1: I was just like semi con friends with him and then I started reading his comic.
Speaker 1: So I guess I imagine I'm gonna start reading Apple geeks now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was pretty funny that when I got back from the con someone randomly I I don't know where it was But they linked to an Apple geeks comic and I was like, hey funny you should link to that comic there Considering I was just hanging out with those people.
Speaker 1: Yep, so, uh the con itself in terms of general goings-on was great.
Speaker 1: There were very few complaints.
Speaker 1: I went to the feedback form at the end because unlike most Katsu cons where I actually do all the con stuff we mostly spent our time providing entertainment to the con or Wandering around at what little time we could in the dealers room.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about those rooms there a dealers room.
Speaker 0: Actually, it was really awesome.
Speaker 0: Like I liked it Maybe more than any other dealers room except the Otakon one.
Speaker 0: I mean and the anime next one Don't forget the anime next one's also really good.
Speaker 0: I mean the selection of stuff that I wanted to buy was not as high as the anime next one But the atmosphere of the dealers room was probably the best atmosphere ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I talked about this last year, but it's in kind of this converted parking garage.
Speaker 1: So despite the fact that the con might be slowly running out of room.
Speaker 1: the dealers room has room to grow.
Speaker 1: It's huge.
Speaker 0: Yet there was space in the back or people are just standing there and they're like.
Speaker 0: it was funny because there are parking spaces And I'm like, dude, and they had this cool like ceiling put in.
Speaker 0: that was pretty nice and it was cool Spacious.
Speaker 0: the aisles were large.
Speaker 0: It wasn't crowded.
Speaker 0: You don't have to push people to see anything Yep, and the dealers were pretty quality also unlike Otakon.
Speaker 1: There's no BS Union can't sell food in the venue rules.
Speaker 1: So there was a bunch of dealers selling Pocky and stuff for pretty reasonable prices.
Speaker 0: The prices weren't reasonable right by it, but they you know compared to anywhere else there.
Speaker 1: Yes for normal con goers They don't have an Asian market next to them.
Speaker 1: They were reasonable prices.
Speaker 0: Yes for me.
Speaker 0: Those koalas were overpriced.
Speaker 1: now I generally don't buy much at dealers rooms anymore.
Speaker 1: I mean unless I see $5 DVDs or a captain Tyler box set for less than like 80 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if discounts are what you were after katsu khan was not the place.
Speaker 0: I mean there were a few places that had you know, the 20% off manga.
Speaker 1: one place had 30% off manga But it was all manga I had or didn't want.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean I got a few old manga for 30% off like a couple lone wolf and cub volumes and a dark horse manga.
Speaker 0: That's old and out of print, but that's pretty much it, but there's a lot of cool little stuff there.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was a generally good room, but I totally lucked out and I'm so happy with this.
Speaker 1: Randomly as I was looking through this one table that had some plushies on it I saw the little baby dragon from brave story the cute pink baby dragon Which that was one of my favorite parts of brave story, especially when his mommy arrives
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: and I thought god damn it.
Speaker 1: Here it is.
Speaker 1: I looked through.
Speaker 1: it was the only one.
Speaker 1: there were definitely no more and I thought crap this thing's gonna be like 30 bucks like that cactuar and I'm gonna be forced to buy it.
Speaker 1: But I'm gonna feel bad about spending that much money on something blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I flip it over.
Speaker 1: it was like 12 bucks.
Speaker 1: So I just I bought it without thoughts And I looked through the con.
Speaker 1: I went to the dealers room three more times and asked around there were no more.
Speaker 1: It was the only one.
Speaker 1: the guy didn't even know what it was who sold it to me.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Why I only charge 12 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm totally pumped about it.
Speaker 1: It's sitting next to me now looking at me.
Speaker 0: Yeah Am I?
Speaker 0: the only other things I bought in the dealers room besides that manga where I found a little tiny Plastic Tachikoma and it's like a set, you know, it's one of those ones you buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you buy a little cardboard box and you don't know what toy is gonna be inside.
Speaker 0: But this set the only options were like blue Tachikoma red Tachikoma green Tachikoma, right?
Speaker 0: So I bought it and I got orange Tachikoma, which is just fine.
Speaker 0: I didn't really care what color it was.
Speaker 1: So Scott where I'm bad the deal is.
Speaker 0: so I went after I bought this and I was done.
Speaker 0: I went back to the video game room where rim was sitting
Speaker 1: and I'm sitting there with his grin on my face
Speaker 0: And I'm like hey rim check out what I bought and I pull out my little orange Tachikoma
Speaker 1: and you cause
Speaker 0: about like an Inch not even an inch tall and made of plastic.
Speaker 1: now There's a famous movie that pretty much shows exactly what happened.
Speaker 1: You call that a Tachikoma.
Speaker 1: This is a Tachikoma because right then I had found in the dealer's room for also very little money.
Speaker 1: It was like 16 bucks a Really big high quality Tachikoma plushie.
Speaker 1: It's like a foot tall.
Speaker 0: Rim went mad with the plushies.
Speaker 0: He got two Big ass normal sized plushies of quality.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: See the thing is I don't buy cheap plushies I'll buy the highest of quality plushies and these happen to be really cheap and yet really high quality.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm pretty much plushied out at this point.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've got them all stuffed into a little box.
Speaker 1: I think I've got.
Speaker 1: I don't need any more.
Speaker 1: I'm almost set.
Speaker 1: I've got the dragon.
Speaker 1: I've got the Tachikoma.
Speaker 1: I've got the one-up mushroom.
Speaker 1: I've got the Cactuar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I am.
Speaker 1: I've got the initial D car.
Speaker 1: Yep, what else do I need?
Speaker 1: We've got the Cthulhu.
Speaker 0: not much.
Speaker 0: All right, so the dealer's room.
Speaker 0: Akatsukan I give it.
Speaker 0: I give it a A. It's a good.
Speaker 0: it's a good dealers All right.
Speaker 1: So on to the artists alley because we covered that there was supposedly ahead of time some controversy.
Speaker 1: you see Tex He was actually a good friend of ours who runs the artists alley.
Speaker 1: They kind of changed the rules of this year kind of like what Otacon did with their you know Strictifying it and worrying more about copyright and also with a twist of trying to promote original art more and the actual two-dimensional Art more and less fan art and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Now the internet made a big deal about this.
Speaker 1: to quote someone funny at the con the internet lost its shit about And there was this crazy uproar and a bunch of people actually contacted us Because you know they talked to us about the Otacon thing and they wanted you know, like are you gonna cover this?
Speaker 1: We're all set for interviews.
Speaker 1: We're all set to go.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be big protest at the con.
Speaker 1: The artist alley is gonna fail.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: So the thing is I didn't really worry about it because Texas Competent at what he does.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he wasn't worried about it either.
Speaker 0: apparently, you know at the end of it It's like he said at least I'm pretty sure is what he said is that at the end of the day?
Speaker 0: People just want to come in and have fun selling shit.
Speaker 1: And the thing is the quality of the artists alley was not Diminished in any way that I could tell from the previous year by the new rules.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I went in there.
Speaker 0: I saw the same stuff.
Speaker 0: I tend to see in artists alleys I saw.
Speaker 0: you know about the typical ratio of high quality to low quality.
Speaker 0: There are people selling crafts There are people selling fan art in various things like that.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean while the rules were stricter The thing is far more people want tables at Katsu khan than there are tables at which point you need some sort of arbitrary Mechanism.
Speaker 1: the mechanism he used looks like in the end It did cut out some less quality people and in the end as a result the artist alley was probably better than the previous year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean while the principles of the mechanism might be so agreeable with us at the same time You know as opposed to a lottery in which you're basically getting a random sampling and you could potentially end up with all crap and having some high quality people left out or a first-come first-serve where only the craziest people will get tables and the you know better People who might have less time to worry about this kind of shit and more time spending on art might not get in His.
Speaker 0: these rules actually semi filtered out some local.
Speaker 0: I mean low quality stuff.
Speaker 1: I guess I mean honestly Katsu khan's artist alley In my opinion is second really only to Otakon at least in terms of the Khans I go to.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean the other thing about the artists alley is that While it was staffed only some hours of the day It was technically open 24/7.
Speaker 0: now not every artist would sit at their table 24/7.
Speaker 0: of course they don't have time for that, you know, plus they want to do other stuff But it was always a fun hangout place, you know.
Speaker 0: nine at night You could go and maybe there'd be an artist to talk to.
Speaker 1: yeah or two.
Speaker 1: in the morning You'd go and hang out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah And plus if one of your favorite artists is in there maybe a webcomic artist hanging out there at nine.
Speaker 0: What better time to go and hang out and talk to them instead of during the day when there's a line of people going?
Speaker 0: Hi, how you doing?
Speaker 0: How you doing now?
Speaker 1: Of course, we went to the art show which was met.
Speaker 1: There wasn't anything notable really.
Speaker 1: we went into the porn area for a joke and there was like one thing hanging there.
Speaker 0: It was just like tasteful Normal paintings from a nude model.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was really surprised that it was tasteful back there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there was some less tasteful stuff that was in the non porn area.
Speaker 1: Yeah However, we're going through and we're pretty picky and we so we didn't really see anything that stood out other than stuff We've seen before.
Speaker 1: and then the last thing we looked at was really cool.
Speaker 1: There's a little shy guy Valentine's thing with two toads.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was a shy guy and he obviously wanted to ask out this toad girl.
Speaker 0: But the toad girl was all with the toad guys because the shy guy was too shy so he he missed out.
Speaker 1: It was really cute.
Speaker 1: It's the kind of thing we like and so sure enough We look at the name of the person who did it and at almost every con we go to We'll see this guy's art and think wow.
Speaker 1: This is awesome.
Speaker 1: Who is it?
Speaker 1: It's always the same guy.
Speaker 0: I mentioned him after the last Otakon show.
Speaker 0: his name is Brandon Kramer and his website is brandokay.com and His art is to awesomes.
Speaker 1: he I don't know what it is.
Speaker 1: It's a combination of skill and knowing what things to combine to make people like us lose our shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean I think what it is is that he does have a great deal of artistic talents from going to art schools and such.
Speaker 0: His artistic style and aesthetic appeals greatly to the likes of us as do it as does his subject matter.
Speaker 0: Yes, and his subject matter is our geek button.
Speaker 0: It's like a big hammer that just hits our geek buttons like a hundred times.
Speaker 1: Yep, so instead I mean you even had him draw something in your a pirate book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that way he drew bonebeard in the pie.
Speaker 0: I think he was the first one to draw in the pirate book and bonebeard is still super quality.
Speaker 0: bonebeard is so awesome.
Speaker 1: I think even when you fill the book even if bonebeard doesn't end up being the number one pirate He's gonna hold his own to the end.
Speaker 0: I think bonebeard will definitely hold his own.
Speaker 0: to end I got a scan in bonebeard at one of these days, but Yeah, also he was selling a new merchandise there.
Speaker 0: He had a sticker that said security provided by phanto.
Speaker 1: if you don't know who phanto is.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna cry for your soul.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's all we're gonna say about that.
Speaker 0: We bought those stickers.
Speaker 1: Yes I was going to put it in my car for the ride home in the window because it's a car window sticker.
Speaker 1: But I might be buying a new car and I don't wanna have to buy another phantos.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a $5 sticker, which is well worth it.
Speaker 1: But oh well Yeah, but this guy's awesome and we're gonna try to get him on the show at some point and interview him just cuz he's cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's way cool.
Speaker 0: And we're probably gonna get in to do some arts for us cuz we need arts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so watch out for him at any artists alley of any kind you go to.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the con itself was really well run.
Speaker 1: It's generally more a social con than other counts.
Speaker 1: The programming is light especially considering how many people are there?
Speaker 1: So while you'll do all the con stuff you go to the cosplay the anime music video showings go to a couple panels.
Speaker 1: Generally you'll spend most of your time hanging out with cool people.
Speaker 0: Yeah At pretty much any point in time The hallways were filled on both sides with people just sitting around hanging out and the lobby was loaded with people standing around hanging out.
Speaker 1: Yep, the lobby was half cosplay pictures half just cool people hanging out.
Speaker 0: That's actually something cool about katsu katas.
Speaker 0: instead of just people taking cosplay pictures randomly all over the place getting in the way They have little areas like in every hallway that say take cosplay pictures here and there's a sheet To make a nice background for your pictures and everything, you know.
Speaker 0: So it's like don't take your picture over there and get in everyone's way.
Speaker 0: There's a little out of the way do these?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a nook right here with a sheet that you can take pictures in front of this design for taking pictures in front of It.
Speaker 0: so people do that and it works out really well.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of cosplay photo photography traffic, even though there's a lot of cosplay photography.
Speaker 1: Yep, there were in fact a lot of nooks in the hotel many of which were unused and I think next year as the con grows We should poke into using those nooks more effectively.
Speaker 0: I think those nooks can be used in many many many ways for awesome.
Speaker 1: Yes, but generally, you know people would hang out in the video game room a lot Even though the video game room was more of a loud thumping party time all night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or they hang on the artist alley which was quiet and every time I went there even at 3 in the morning It was just people kind of quietly having.
Speaker 1: you know, normal cool.
Speaker 1: I'm a geek.
Speaker 1: You're a geek, too.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about the things we like conversations.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What about the Video rooms at katsu khan.
Speaker 0: Did you go into any at all?
Speaker 1: I don't go to video rooms to any con ever.
Speaker 0: Well, we usually go see live-action movies from Asia.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, the thing is katsu khan's video rooms were like any cons video rooms.
Speaker 1: They were well run.
Speaker 1: They've showed whatever.
Speaker 1: the cool thing was though that one of the rooms had a lot of live-action Asian cinema.
Speaker 0: We had two rooms of anime and one room of live-action But I would probably would have gone to the live-action room at some point.
Speaker 0: But the con program was organized in a way that made it slightly more difficult to figure out what the different movies were Mostly because you weren't willing to put the trivial effort.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I wasn't willing to put in any effort at all.
Speaker 0: So Not knowing what the movies were I wasn't willing to take the time out of my day to go and watch them.
Speaker 1: thing is you can tell by the titles which Ones were awesome and which ones weren't.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Let me look at some of these titles here electric dragon 8,000 V.
Speaker 0: 80,000 V. that's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: The hidden blade that's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: 36th chamber of Shaolin that's gonna be twice as awesome as anything you've said so far.
Speaker 0: Blood sport blood sport.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know that movie.
Speaker 1: I wonder if that was actually the van the which one is it?
Speaker 1: Is there some Japanese blood?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I have to look in these slightly disorganized program to find out.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think part of it was more that we were actually busy for the whole con and it ode to con.
Speaker 1: Other than our dying tradition of the Saturday midnight movie We tend to only go into the live-action rooms to watch stuff when there's nothing else going on.
Speaker 1: Yep, Katsu khan.
Speaker 1: We had stuff going on pretty much 24/7.
Speaker 1: So we really didn't have time to watch anything.
Speaker 0: I did stop in and watch Five minutes of an anime randomly just to see what the video room looked like and it was a pretty typical video room.
Speaker 0: You could see and hear the show from everywhere in the room.
Speaker 0: They were actually watching a dub and I found out later the show was Animation runner kuromi, which is a show I've heard the name of but never actually known what the show was about.
Speaker 0: and from watching five minutes The show is about this girl who runs around to all these animators around town and collects their work and brings it back to the animation studio and she has to pester all of them to get their work done on time and Only the bishonen guy gets his work done on time.
Speaker 0: So if you're looking for a cute funny show.
Speaker 0: that might be the one because it didn't look scary or bad in any way from My five-minute judgment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the showings at Katsu khan serve their purpose and we're done.
Speaker 1: Well, also the industry had set up a bunch of TVs around Showcasing.
Speaker 1: you mean funimation.
Speaker 1: Yeah funimation, which is doing?
Speaker 1: as far as I can guess funimation is doing well I'm anime.
Speaker 0: funimation I think recently made a press release that said we are number one in anime in the u.s.
Speaker 1: And I believe it because while I don't like all the things they put out lately they're the ones who have been consistently Selling stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they got the full metal alchemist in the one pieces and all the the big ones.
Speaker 1: They're also the ones who actually seem to have enough of a budget to appear at cons and give free stuff out again Which there's been a drought of free stuff from the industry for a while now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think another factor is where is funimation located?
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about that.
Speaker 1: I know more about the Japanese companies than I do about the American ones these days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I know the ATV is in Texas and like visas in California So they often don't show up at the East Coast cons.
Speaker 1: I mean, yes, it's really big all I used to know about pioneer because they used to put out all the stuff I like.
Speaker 1: yeah, they're genie on yep, and that's when I stopped knowing about them.
Speaker 1: Oh, well Yeah, but the showing rooms were good enough and they had you know, the demo stations all around showing.
Speaker 1: mostly it looked like moon phase.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just had TVs showing their latest stuff and demo DVDs to get people to like funimation and they gave away free funimation crap and funimation t-shirts and there were these funimation ad posters posted everywhere and They had a little booth in the lobby instead of the dealers room or anywhere else.
Speaker 0: and oh, they did their thing.
Speaker 0: Whatever Yep.
Speaker 1: Now briefly there was also the live gaming room which Smelled like the unholy armpit of the worst fanboy in the world.
Speaker 1: I swear to God.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whoever they?
Speaker 1: luckily the staff is fully aware of this.
Speaker 1: It was mentioned and men in numerous places.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they're going to deal with it next year.
Speaker 1: Also, we will probably hopefully be running German board game demos in there at late at night and not permitting smelly people.
Speaker 1: Oh god If there were smelly people, yeah, if a smelly person come into that video game room, they would have been dealt with too sweet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess the only other thing going on at kazakhon was all the panels which we didn't really go to any of them.
Speaker 0: So we can't say much about them.
Speaker 1: Well, I can say one thing.
Speaker 1: I showed up at the feedback panel because since I didn't do a much at the con That I could report on other than the fun stuff I did which I'll probably talk about some other night because you guys don't care about the funny stuff that happened in the room or the time when Bruce paralyzed the Entire crew with laughter for like five minutes.
Speaker 1: Okay We'll have to tell all those stories another time.
Speaker 1: but in terms of the con itself I didn't have much to report on.
Speaker 1: so I went to the feedback session to see what was What people talked about and I missed the beginning.
Speaker 1: but apparently our panel our game show was called out Specifically by someone in the audience as being the hot shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean our little game show at 10 p.m.
Speaker 0: On Saturday Which went like the guy was like all the panels sucked except for the anime match game.
Speaker 0: Yes, something like that Along those lines.
Speaker 0: I'm very exaggerating a little bit.
Speaker 1: The sentiment was repeated in our own forums where someone basically said wow your guys run a kick-ass game show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and when you actually look at the schedule for katsucon this year, you know, like I thought oh the programming's not light It's just a lot of the panels are uninteresting.
Speaker 0: Well, no actually on further examination There really aren't that many panels and most of them are uninteresting to most people.
Speaker 1: Well when I got to the feedback session the bid I'd missed where apparently we were talked about Before that they had a little whiteboard up that showed like things that have already been brought up and apparently like that's really smart.
Speaker 0: That shows how smart katsucon is that they would think of something like that.
Speaker 1: Oh katsucon runs their feedback panel.
Speaker 1: So Professionally, it's really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the con chair really knows how to deal with people who ask stupid questions and have stupid complain.
Speaker 0: I think I might go to it next year just for entertainment factor.
Speaker 1: yeah, it was really entertaining cuz.
Speaker 1: also people really had very few legitimate complaints and almost every complaint someone had was either answered immediately like well, we couldn't do that because of X or hey, that's a good idea or a Not to put it politely.
Speaker 1: they would say in a very polite way effectively your concern is stupid and you're a stupid person.
Speaker 0: You should feel stupid But then your complaint is bad and you should feel bad.
Speaker 1: But the thing is they didn't do it in it in a mean way.
Speaker 1: they did it in a very, you know, genteel way like well, we I had I acknowledge your concern and I Don't.
Speaker 1: we dealt with that thing.
Speaker 1: the way we would deal with it, you know, is that sort of answer?
Speaker 1: Yep, because some of the people were complaining about the dumbest things that you just couldn't give one dumb example.
Speaker 1: One guy was trying to complain about the elevator situation.
Speaker 0: Oh, what are we gonna do?
Speaker 0: We're gonna install more elevators in the hotel.
Speaker 1: one kid complained that the AMV Reshowing on Saturday was too early and he couldn't wake up early enough for it to which the con chair Basically said it was standing room only as it was.
Speaker 1: I don't think we missed any people.
Speaker 0: Hahaha, yeah, there was two.
Speaker 0: they showed the AMV's twice once at 6 p.m.
Speaker 0: Friday and once at 9 a.m.
Speaker 0: Saturday.
Speaker 1: Yeah apparently 9 a.m was too early and the guy was trying to Stammer out his complaint that people wouldn't be able to get up and see it and it would be better served showing it at noon.
Speaker 1: And no it was standing room only.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus at noon the cosplay rehearsal starts.
Speaker 0: They don't have time to do the anime music videos any early Hours to show.
Speaker 1: so this con was rocking at 7 in the morning.
Speaker 0: That's another thing.
Speaker 0: that surprised me is we were there Thursday So we woke up Saturday.
Speaker 0: what Friday morning?
Speaker 0: and the con started real early like as soon as people woke up Friday con started.
Speaker 0: There was no programming at the con until noon and there was no real programming until 3 or 5.
Speaker 0: So it was like whoa.
Speaker 0: There's a crazy con going on, but the only things actually happening are the 24/7 video game room The artists alley in the dealers room and such and such.
Speaker 1: now aside for our match game, which apparently went really really really well.
Speaker 1: I mean the people who were at it gave us a standing ovation and loved it.
Speaker 1: It was a full house.
Speaker 1: In fact people came up and left because the room was full and they couldn't really get in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was in a pretty small room relative to some of the other panel rooms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but our panelists were great.
Speaker 1: we actually had an aunt from Apple geeks and I'd over fallen and Conrad from c-squared and Corbin the concierge of sitcom and Scott Johnson the old man Scott Johnson the old man that Corbin is Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: actually Scott Johnson is cool You know, we make fun of Scott Johnson But he's actually Scott Johnson is just our favorite friend to make fun of because it's too easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean he is pretty much part of the triad of us when we go to cons.
Speaker 1: Yep, but anyway Corbin and Scott Johnson were a little drunk on the panel, which was both hilarious and frustrating.
Speaker 1: It was hilarious because they were really funny at the panel most of the time.
Speaker 1: It was also frustrating because us as hosts had to keep them in line drunk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was pretty difficult Like sometimes you just couldn't get them to write a real answer down like on one.
Speaker 1: Corbin drew the anal beads for the second time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Corbin just drew some anal beads and it was like dude all right, we know the anal beads are awesome, but You don't draw them as an answer.
Speaker 0: however,
Speaker 1: however, the funny thing was see me I don't want to have a big head here But I think it speaks to our skill at doing this because we've run this match game a lot of times Since our IT anime club, we've been running this match game and when he drew the anal beads the first time, you know, he drew it and shows it to the crowd and We pulled off this whole bit where we're like who?
Speaker 1: first of all half the crowd goes What the hell is that?
Speaker 1: and the other half of the crowd goes?
Speaker 1: Ah To which we did this whole bit of who there knows what that represents.
Speaker 1: you're all sick sick and awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then, you know, we're talking a little bit more and one guy in the crowd says you drew him wrong Proceeds to explain why he drew him wrong Which apparently the thing is drawing him wrong is the inside joke from our group.
Speaker 1: This guy either has the same inside joke or is a pervert.
Speaker 0: I think he's a pervert.
Speaker 1: either way is cool though.
Speaker 0: Cuz the tone of voice.
Speaker 0: I'm betting pervert.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is pervert at an anime con is not nearly so bad as pervert in the street.
Speaker 0: well, it is bad, but because there's so many like them and they're expected that it's just like a.
Speaker 1: Now anime perverts don't bother me so much.
Speaker 1: They're not causing problems.
Speaker 0: No, they're not causing problems, but I still not a fan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can you can be not a fan.
Speaker 1: I mean Daryl Surratt is not even a real pervert.
Speaker 0: Like if I see a guy peeping Tom in the street, I just go.
Speaker 1: That's a little bit different that's actually going beyond the law.
Speaker 0: I know that but you see my point.
Speaker 1: But anyway that that went really well.
Speaker 1: the other panels apparently they had a DS Pictionary game which went really well, I Heard tell from two sources that the how to draw a yuri panel was a half hour late and so Poorly executed.
Speaker 1: it was worthless Really?
Speaker 0: I was you think that someone who was gonna teach everyone how to draw yuri would want to get to it and do a Good job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, two different sources said that it was just this crap panel.
Speaker 1: And yeah, I don't really have anything more to say about it.
Speaker 1: According to Scott Johnson and Corbin who went to the anime club summit It was god-awful and horribly run.
Speaker 1: and because they're actually experts, you know Corbin runs an anime con and Scott Johnson Runs the club summit at Otakon every year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think he's now Otakon staff, you know Scott Johnson Scott and I ran the biggest anime club in the country for years on end Yep, so they went to it and they basically ran this panel from what they told us.
Speaker 1: I didn't go to it from the audience and hopefully they'll actually run this panel next year because I Believe.
Speaker 1: I talked last year about how lame this club summit panel was too.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: katsu kan.
Speaker 1: just the panels could be so much better and I don't know why they're not good.
Speaker 1: Many people complained about many of the panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't really know what you could do to make the panels better.
Speaker 0: I mean they had plenty of guests who could have had made good panels.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm sure there were diamonds in the rough and good panels, but I didn't hear anything about him.
Speaker 0: So and I didn't go to him.
Speaker 0: So what do we know?
Speaker 0: Yeah I the only and even with even the fact that I didn't go to any of them meant that None of the titles or description of the panels interested me enough that I would leave Playing Dig Dug to go to them.
Speaker 0: your panels had to be better than Dig Dug.
Speaker 1: people See I would have left Dig Dug to go to a few of them but past the Dig Dug before I could get to the panel.
Speaker 1: Now root beer tappers would always stop me.
Speaker 1: I walked out of the video game room at one point with the intention of doing something.
Speaker 1: I forget what I think was going to the bathroom or something And then I saw root beer tapper was open and then an hour later.
Speaker 1: I Forgot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh the bathrooms at katsu kana real nice.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I'll talk about this briefly.
Speaker 1: the hotel that katsu kan is in the Omni showroom in DC is Super fancy far more fancy than an anime con needs or deserves.
Speaker 1: It is great.
Speaker 0: Oh that reminds me this one other thing they do that's really nice.
Speaker 0: They have a special katsu kana room service.
Speaker 0: where for like.
Speaker 0: was it four dollars?
Speaker 1: I have something bad to say about that but go on you can bring like a hamburger to your room.
Speaker 0: The room service will come without paying the exorbitant room service fee.
Speaker 1: according to what everyone I have asked has said The that food was god-awful.
Speaker 0: Oh, I could expect that for four dollars, you know and someone bring you to your room.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get much.
Speaker 0: But at least they did something instead of just having room service.
Speaker 0: that's normal price Which is twelve dollars.
Speaker 0: for breakfast that should be six dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They also very smartly closed down for lunch and dinner the restaurant in the hotel Which is ludicrously overpriced and I had no anime fans can afford that even though last year We ate at it just because we didn't want to go outside in the cold and it wasn't.
Speaker 0: yeah If it was like a storm, I would totally pay the money to eat at it.
Speaker 0: I looked at the menu and it was just like $25 for a steak.
Speaker 0: that should be $17 and I was like, uh, no.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they shut it down in order to make more space for people to hang out.
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unfortunately people didn't realize they could hang out there's.
Speaker 1: they avoided it.
Speaker 1: So they'll.
Speaker 0: yeah, I never went down there.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize I could.
Speaker 1: yeah, there's actually even outside of the restaurant.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of couches and seating down there and there was pretty much DS action down there every time I walk by awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there wasn't as much DS action at this con as previous cons But I think that's just because everyone was being so social.
Speaker 1: there was no time And there was a DS hangout area in the game room that we didn't really go by but I think that needed to be more Clearly labeled as a DS hangout area.
Speaker 1: I think what I'm gonna do next year is I'm gonna run a bunch of Bomberman Download play tournaments and Tetris download play tournament and Diddy Kong.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna run some Diddy Kong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna run mad tournaments next year now that we know exactly the situation.
Speaker 1: Yep, and of course after the tournament ran went so well.
Speaker 1: But yeah panels kind of mad.
Speaker 1: from what I've heard and maybe from what I've heard from friends I trust but not from what I've seen I can't say more about it.
Speaker 1: We are going to try to run more panels at this con next year.
Speaker 0: Oh one other thing the registration line.
Speaker 0: I don't know what was going on because I didn't have to wait in it But it seemed like people were waiting to register like well past noon on Saturday.
Speaker 1: Part of that was because a lot of people show up for the one day at Katsucon.
Speaker 1: on Saturday or the two-day a Lot of people show up late.
Speaker 1: I'll show people checking into their hotel on Saturday morning.
Speaker 1: Wow Katsucon is a con where a lot of people show up early and a lot of people show up late.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you don't get your badge until like 2 p.m.
Speaker 0: On Saturday.
Speaker 0: If you plan on going to sleep Saturday night, there's really no point in coming.
Speaker 1: Hey, but you came way too late, man Yeah, I don't worry about that anymore because I pretty much show up to cons earlier and earlier.
Speaker 1: I mean we show up at Otakon Thursday at like noon and we leave Sunday at like 5 or 6.
Speaker 1: Katsucon we got there around 3 o'clock on Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: Oh one other thing I want to point out that Katsucon did that other cons should do is they put a piece of paper in the con bag that had the names phone numbers prices locations and such of all nearby restaurants banks dry cleaners the CVS and Important info about the metro but not the entire metro schedule.
Speaker 0: other cons kind of put this information in there Like maybe they'll have some names of some nearby restaurants and reviews of them or something.
Speaker 0: But they don't put down the phone numbers and whether or not they deliver or whether or not they have an ATM there or stuff Like that.
Speaker 0: like Otakon will have like $1 sign $2 sign $3 sign.
Speaker 0: How about this?
Speaker 0: one says four to five dollars or?
Speaker 0: Sixteen to seventeen dollars or six to seventeen dollars.
Speaker 0: That's the useful information right there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we're kind of going along.
Speaker 1: So I guess wrap this up in the con in general.
Speaker 1: I mean they moved all the furniture out of the main lobby, which was great.
Speaker 1: It gave him so much more space people to walk around and it prevented anime fans for breaking anything.
Speaker 1: They did this awesome thing where they taped.
Speaker 1: they taped off the hallways all the main hallways on the sides With basically sitting areas so people could just kind of sit and hang out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think also part of that was for line waiting.
Speaker 0: So if a line ever needed to be made anywhere They could have the people wait near behind the tape and people could still walk around Which definitely worked because when I was walking around near the incredibly long Registration line or main events line wherever it happened to be at the time I don't even know I never had a problem walking by as someone not who is not waiting in the line.
Speaker 1: Yep, we went to the rave on Saturday night and it was four or five times better than Otakon's rave easily hands-down.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the reason is because number one Otakon has the rave in that hallway and that small room next to the hallway.
Speaker 0: This rave was in main events.
Speaker 0: It took up the entirety of main events.
Speaker 0: It was one big giant rave.
Speaker 0: They had excellent sound equipment.
Speaker 0: They had excellent lighting.
Speaker 0: They had excellent everything.
Speaker 0: The in and out of the rave was excellent, you know with a whole bunch of doors.
Speaker 0: The DJ while he might not have been playing the best music in the world was good Satisfactory I guess I mean I want.
Speaker 1: I wish there would have been some happy hardcore or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what they were playing when he weren't in there.
Speaker 1: I mean we were only in there for an hour Yeah, but last year they played a but there was some OC remixes and more video game music two years ago was awesome Awesome.
Speaker 1: Awesome where they had 80s night on Friday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who knows what they were playing at the Times?
Speaker 0: You weren't in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when we were in there, it was standard rave music Not the greatest DJ in the while I'd say standard rave music.
Speaker 1: Otakon standard rave music is pretty much just a thumping bass.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that also has to do with the room.
Speaker 1: It makes it sound a lot worse than it is now because the the DJs at Otakon them in their live mix and these generally Just tend to play this very very minimalist techno and I hate minimalist techno.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also The only other thing is that there were.
Speaker 0: the rave was full of people tons of people But there was plenty of room to dance.
Speaker 0: you weren't like squished in and you also weren't too spaced out that it felt like you Were dancing alone.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There was very little circle and there were like two circles But they were kind of a and they kept getting broken up by real people dancing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there were lots of people dancing everywhere as opposed to people standing and looking around.
Speaker 0: There was also way too much glow stick going on and blinky.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing.
Speaker 1: No one was being obnoxious with.
Speaker 0: No, it was.
Speaker 0: there was only one guy who sweat swung him around, you know Most people kept them in their own personal space and they didn't have my long Ten foot strings swinging them around hitting people in the head or anything like that.
Speaker 1: I mean overall and every year katsu khan always proves me right.
Speaker 1: katsu khan has the best con dances and every con.
Speaker 1: if You're not gonna do the crazy awesome ideas that we want at least emulate what katsu khan does because they do it.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I mean free and Otakon doesn't use their main events when the rave is going on, right?
Speaker 0: So other than the fact that there are a bunch of chairs in there They could have a rave up there maybe instead of where they have it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's already there a DJ We just had to set up on stage.
Speaker 1: Also, there's the fact that katsu khan's dance for various reasons always smells horrible and katsu khan's dance didn't smell at all.
Speaker 0: Otakon's dance smells horrible.
Speaker 1: Otakon's dance smells worse than you said.
Speaker 0: you said katsu khan's dance.
Speaker 1: Oh, I meant Otakon.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think I think that has to do with the fact that it's in one big Well-ventilated room as opposed to a cramped hallway and then a cramped room.
Speaker 1: But I mean in general there was despite the horrible crampedness in the hallways of katsu khan.
Speaker 0: I meant in Otakon.
Speaker 1: I'm just talking about in general There's.
Speaker 1: there was almost no smell at katsu khan and except for that one gamer that one guy and they go one or two guys Who must have stuck up that game room?
Speaker 1: Yep, and there was also a Surprising lack of morbidly obese people.
Speaker 0: I mean there was a couple fat people, you know here and there.
Speaker 0: But usually you go to a con and you see a few people that are just holy crap fat and you see like a group Of people that are big fat comic book guy nerds katsu khan not so much really.
Speaker 1: I remember last year katsu khan There was this really really really fat dude trying to get it squeezed into this elevator and he couldn't fit in because the elevators are Actually pretty small at the door and like kids kept running around him getting in the elevators.
Speaker 1: We couldn't get in.
Speaker 1: He was getting really mad.
Speaker 1: So we tried to take the stairs, but the stairs are way too narrow for him to even fit.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: I also I kind of wish that we weren't on the eighth floor because you do have to wait for the elevators if you Want to use them at a busy time and a lot of people they get on the elevator if they want to go down while The elevator is going up making it far less efficient than it could be.
Speaker 0: but because everyone does it You also have to do it or else you won't get on the elevator.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm gonna get our rooms for next year toot suite and I'm going to specifically request a suite on the second floor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if we get a low enough room, I have no problem taking the stairs all the time, which would be awesome.
Speaker 1: No last year.
Speaker 1: We were on the second floor.
Speaker 1: It was so awesome.
Speaker 1: I wore my pajamas down to watch the pond the third strange psychokinetic strategy.
Speaker 0: Yep one other thing is that I did go down the stairs once from the eighth floor to the L floor and It actually took a lot less time and was a lot less painful than I thought it would be.
Speaker 0: However, the stairways are really really narrow and it was very narrow.
Speaker 0: Players don't fit.
Speaker 0: someone behind me was carrying nothing and I was carrying a bunch of bags and they would have passed me.
Speaker 0: So I had to kind of run.
Speaker 1: So of course in closing katsu khan was super badass.
Speaker 1: It's as always one of my favorite cons.
Speaker 1: We will definitely be returning every year.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's no way I'm not going to katsu khan next year.
Speaker 1: If you are anywhere near Washington DC You should also go to katsu khan and we're on the staff mailing list for the game katsu the gaming room and I gotta say It is so heartening to me that right now they're already planning what to do better next year.
Speaker 1: There's and not just like hey, we should do this, but they're getting on Skype.
Speaker 1: They're already coming up with concrete plans for how to make katsu khan better next year.
Speaker 0: Well, if you're gonna have a good con you need to plan this shit full gear in advance or else That's how this stuff works.
Speaker 0: So they're definitely on top of it.
Speaker 0: That's something I definitely noticed about katsu khan.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's because I can see more of the under workings than I can at other cons like Otakon But it definitely seems like the staff is all intelligent hard-working and they care and they try as Opposed to other cons where that isn't.
Speaker 0: that might may or may not be true, but it's not always evident.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm or you can send audio feedback via Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.