Speaker 1: It's Thursday March 15th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We ramble a bit about vacationing.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I'm on the train on the way home reading this book that I'm reading the adventures of Cavalier and clay and it's a damn good book and it deserved its Pulitzer Prize, but I'm not done with it yet Uh-huh, but anyway, you should all read it.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the cover of the book and on the cover of the book is the Empire State Building.
Speaker 0: I'm just looking at it and I'm like, you know what I Can go there if I want to any time you want.
Speaker 1: it's right there you pay a fee.
Speaker 1: They let you go up and look at the city and I've only been up there once.
Speaker 0: my grandma took me there when I was I don't know how young real young maybe eight maybe ten, you know, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I've never been in the Empire State Building let alone up it.
Speaker 0: So I said to myself, you know what?
Speaker 0: No reason I can't go up there.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna I'm gonna go up there.
Speaker 0: Maybe tomorrow No one could stop me.
Speaker 1: well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe it'll be closed maybe it's it's.
Speaker 0: actually I went to the website.
Speaker 0: it's surprisingly open like half for half of the week.
Speaker 0: You can go up there like 1 a.m And they'll let you up in the elevator all the way to the the observation deck.
Speaker 1: Now maybe the one day you decide to go be the day.
Speaker 1: There's a jumper.
Speaker 0: If there's a jumper that how does that bother me?
Speaker 0: Who's at the top when the jumper is at the bottom?
Speaker 1: I'll bet if someone jumped off the Empire State Building they would close it for at least a few hours.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go look up and see what happens.
Speaker 0: besides it's real.
Speaker 0: It's actually from what I remember when I went there.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess almost 20 years ago.
Speaker 0: I don't know how old but it's pretty hard to actually jump off the highest observation deck.
Speaker 0: that's like a hundred something floors up is inside you're looking out windows and The observation deck where you're outside is like on the 80th something floor And there's big fences.
Speaker 0: You'd have to be pretty awesome to get over that fence.
Speaker 1: I remember when I was up in Canada and I went to the CN Tower with a bunch of kids from my high school and Not only is it difficult to jump off the CN Tower.
Speaker 1: It's impossible.
Speaker 1: the observation deck the highest one They let us get to actually had this cage kind of around the entire thing all the way out to the edge.
Speaker 1: There was no way to get out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only other really tall building I've been to the top of is the tallest building in Israel and The observation deck was basically you're on a floor and you went out and there was sort of like a balcony You know around the edge of the floor.
Speaker 0: so you could go all around the building, but it was like a balcony.
Speaker 0: So there was actually a roof above your head the next the bottom of the next floor and there was a fence around the side.
Speaker 0: So you would have to basically break open the fence to get out and fall off.
Speaker 1: the one thing I learned I mean, I didn't actually see anything from the CN Tower.
Speaker 1: There was nothing but clouds.
Speaker 0: I Remember I saw a lot.
Speaker 0: I still remember I've only been to the Empire State Building once all to the top of it once.
Speaker 0: I've been near it a zillion times and I've went in the bottom part a couple times.
Speaker 0: But I've only been to the top once and I still remember that all the little cars they were so small.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, the cars are so small and you can see pretty much everything like you walk around to one side Statue of Liberty is over there and you walk around the other side and you're like, oh look There's the rest of New York over there and there's New Jersey over there and there's the boats over there.
Speaker 1: And but the primary thing I learned was that most people are Incredibly skittish even if all signs and all knowledge and all engineering point to perfect undeniable safety.
Speaker 0: Yep, there.
Speaker 0: I mean if you look over the edge, it's just sort of like this natural sort of vertigo inner ear kind of feeling That you know, it's like whoa.
Speaker 1: I don't know I didn't get maybe was just because I couldn't see anything but clouds but I actually on a dare Me and another friend of mine climbed out onto the fence and then back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz the fence was solid steel There's no way that was gonna break.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some people like whoa and then they run away.
Speaker 0: But like if I I look over the edge and there's sort of a natural internal subconscious Whoa, but then if I just stay there for a few seconds, it's like alright cool Yeah, but there were a lot of people who wouldn't even go near that fence.
Speaker 1: They kind of hugged the wall ten feet back and obviously were shaken Wusses and it wasn't just like one person who's afraid of heights cuz that I can understand but it was the vast majority of people.
Speaker 0: Wusses.
Speaker 1: more interesting was inside that floor cuz you know the top of the CN Tower is like this UFO kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's still like the Space Needle but not inside it.
Speaker 1: There's glass under you.
Speaker 1: You can walk on glass and just look down at the ground.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and times glass elevators can get you.
Speaker 1: You know how many people would not walk on that glass.
Speaker 1: and at one point I had nothing to do with this.
Speaker 1: But I was standing on the glass looking down and a couple of my friends were standing on the glass looking down and an unnamed other friend of mine walked over and stood on the glass and then proceeded to Get everyone's attention and then jump up and down as hard as he
Speaker 0: was about to say.
Speaker 0: But that's the thing about standing on glass is I you know?
Speaker 0: Looking down of course would be the same as the you know the whoa and then you get cool.
Speaker 0: But I would you know glass is sort of fragile most glass.
Speaker 1: It was like six inches.
Speaker 0: I know I know but most glass you encounter in your everyday life is fragile and easily Breakable and like if you stood on say the windows to your house, you might break them.
Speaker 0: So When you encounter something that looks almost exactly the same Like even I would sort of have to get down and test it and be like, okay It's six inches thick and then I would stand on it, you know, well it was expected that you stand on it.
Speaker 1: It was all over like the floor was covered in these giant tiles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then I've been.
Speaker 0: I'd be fine with it as long as I trust that the engineer of the building and the fact that I don't see dead bodies or anyone else falling down is enough for me.
Speaker 1: It's always like I remember we were at the New York Comic Con and they're all.
Speaker 1: there's rails everywhere to make sure you don't fall off all those balconies and walkways.
Speaker 1: and Imagine any modern public building like a mall.
Speaker 1: Yeah You
Speaker 0: know in a shopping mall when you're on the second floor Like the hallways in the mall are only on both sides of the mall and in the middle There's usually like a big hole and you can look down Into the first floor of the mall and there's a railing that goes around to keep you from falling onto the first floor.
Speaker 1: Imagine if there were no rails.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've been in a couple of buildings that were kind of like that and it's always a little bit not necessarily unnerving.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's just because so few buildings are like that.
Speaker 1: But also at the same time I can't really bemoan that fact because without the railings I wouldn't really blame someone for just walking off because sometimes you just stop paying attention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see if it didn't have the railings like I if I was alone in the mall I would be pretty confident just walking down the hallway with no railings.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe all right But there's other people there and also, you know I don't like to I don't like to have to really pay attention to not falling off.
Speaker 1: It'd be like if you were driving without the lines on the road.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz while I might not You know be stupid enough to walk off the edge and fall down to the first floor and hurt myself or possibly die.
Speaker 0: I might slip and fall or I might bump into someone or someone that might bump into me or who knows that lady might ricochet Something.
Speaker 0: someone might drop something like what if I drop something, you know, and I get down on my hands and knees.
Speaker 1: It's like what if you're just walking and then your cell phone rings So you reach to grab it and in that second you just walk right off the edge?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can see that happening all the time.
Speaker 0: It's it's good to have railings like that there.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's good to have a fence around the top of the Empire State Building.
Speaker 1: But yeah, anyway a little bit of news here.
Speaker 1: this is kind of close to home because I was looking on dig for stories to bury and I saw a story involving some sort of crazy voodoo ritual.
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 1: and I would have just I wouldn't have buried it because it just looked like an interesting story.
Speaker 1: But I was drawn to it because I thought I saw the word Yonkers.
Speaker 1: So upon further investigation I see the word cemetery and I think back that whenever the sawmill Parkway floods I have to take this little detour around and right next to my work There's this big cemetery at Yonkers and I'm thinking there's no way.
Speaker 1: there's no way.
Speaker 1: and I read the story and sure enough this happened Right next to my work and it wasn't just any normal voodoo ritual.
Speaker 1: I suppose I should start from the beginning.
Speaker 1: so police were called because apparently there had been some suspicious people around and Then upon investigation they noticed that six of the headstones had been knocked over face down grave tipping.
Speaker 1: now As of the time of this posting they hadn't actually looked to see whose names were on those gravestones.
Speaker 1: They're gonna investigate that to try to you know, figure out who did this.
Speaker 1: But that wouldn't have been a big deal.
Speaker 1: in and of itself vandalism happens in graveyards fairly often.
Speaker 1: they also noticed that there was a pumpkin and Inside of the pumpkin was some animals heart covered in pepper and full of needles.
Speaker 1: alrighty Also was were various accoutrement of some sort of voodoo or Santeria or whatever.
Speaker 1: all those Interesting religion.
Speaker 0: It's someone who spells You know like magic with a CK at the end and says I'm a Wicca It has a pentagram neck.
Speaker 1: or at least someone who believes that they're a practitioner.
Speaker 1: because actually I've read many stories recently where especially in Florida there has been a rise in Finding the evidence of those sorts of rituals as immigrants conduct them at night.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: It was just.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not like they're harmful It's not gonna hurt you.
Speaker 1: if you see someone hung a small piece of chicken from a tree in the middle of the woods Well, it might get you with its bad odor.
Speaker 1: Yeah or rotting or if you're running through the woods You just kind of smack into it.
Speaker 1: So they found a bunch of other things and I think the thing that they found that was most interesting Was and I'm quoting effectively a plastic rooster wrapped in a red bandana Buried halfway into the ground Also wrapped in some Calvin Klein underwear and pinned to.
Speaker 1: this was a note with a person's name on it.
Speaker 0: So do you remember that episode of Ren and Stimpy?
Speaker 0: That was my thing of the day with the bad juju on Tuesday the 17th.
Speaker 0: That the fact that that reality is crazier than that episode of Ren and Stimpy.
Speaker 1: Wow investigators believe that they looked at well that the heart was actually outside of the pumpkin and Forensic analysis revealed that the heart was in the pumpkin and then was taken out.
Speaker 1: and they believe that that was a ritual symbolizing ripping the victim's heart out of his body.
Speaker 0: So the guy's a pumpkin.
Speaker 1: I guess The funny thing is there's a reasonable chance They're gonna catch whoever's involved because they knocked down the six gravestones and they wrote the name of their victim on the thing and all This stuff.
Speaker 1: so all they have to do is find the people who had the things done to them or the families.
Speaker 1: Find out who's enemies of this family and then I'm sure along with the descriptions of the shady individuals who were hanging around that night I think it's gonna be funny.
Speaker 0: I just want to see these voodoo people.
Speaker 0: cuz voodoo people.
Speaker 0: they gotta look funny.
Speaker 0: There's no way.
Speaker 0: there's no way that it's gonna be like some clean-cut guy and wearing like a suit and a tie.
Speaker 1: It's not like the Mormons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's gonna be some crazy Baron Samity type shit, and it's gonna be mighty entertaining to see voodoo people.
Speaker 1: What if it's just an immigrant and he had a kid here and the kids just a dumb funk and he tried to do some Old ritual that he didn't know anything about and he's just some 13 year old going to high school.
Speaker 1: That's our middle school or whatever.
Speaker 1: that'd be middle school.
Speaker 0: That'll be kind of I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know I could.
Speaker 1: half of me would say these are this is people who have some sort of crazy religion.
Speaker 1: half of me would Say these are punk kids who read something on to internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, you know Randy doesn't Randy sell those Randy voodoo dolls say voodoo me haha doesn't work.
Speaker 1: I don't know if he's sold him, but I've seen him.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He's like yeah here go voodoo me all you want.
Speaker 0: I'm not worried about it It's not real All right, so rim we've often talked about the fact that you know It's kind of sad that it's easy to get away with murder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is pretty easy to get away with murder.
Speaker 1: I mean Scott and I have conversations like this a lot and along with the front row crew where if you if Someone wanted to commit a murder and they didn't and they wanted to get away with it And they actually didn't have a motive other than getting away with it There's no way they'd be caught if they're even halfway intelligent.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so one thing you're gonna want to do to make sure you don't get caught if you're planning on murdering someone is To go on the Google and search for how to commit murder.
Speaker 0: I Recommend actually doing the search You know so that you can get away with it and perhaps learn something about murdering.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess if you want to be successful, I don't know even though I don't want you to be okay anyway But make sure that you delete your search histories and perhaps.
Speaker 1: Okay, so your hard drive So Google didn't give it up.
Speaker 1: It was just whoever knotted the murder was Google didn't give it up.
Speaker 0: Basically, you know, they were suspected of murder.
Speaker 0: the cops came and took the computers the cops Investigated the computer and oh, let's see.
Speaker 0: What's in this search history?
Speaker 0: how to commit murder instant poisons undetectable poison Fatal digoxin doses Wow, huh?
Speaker 0: I wonder who killed this guy.
Speaker 0: Could it have been his wife who searched on Google for how to kill?
Speaker 1: This is interesting because what how to kill from tank, please Kill.
Speaker 1: see.
Speaker 1: she should have just bought that book with cash.
Speaker 1: She would have been all set.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then burn the book when you're done.
Speaker 1: actually, I don't think in tank police.
Speaker 1: that was a book.
Speaker 1: I think it was a periodical.
Speaker 0: It was definitely a magazine.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this is an interesting dichotomy because at one on one hand this woman was smart enough to use Google as opposed to any other Search engine and was smart enough to do her research.
Speaker 0: Then she was also stupid enough to get caught.
Speaker 1: You know what she might be smart and just not computer savvy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean even without this incredibly damning testimony that you know be of the people who investigated the computers They suspected her enough to take the computers and get a warrant to search them in the first place.
Speaker 0: So she can't be that smart.
Speaker 1: See, that's the one good thing is while it's easy to get away with murder nominally It's not nearly as easy to get away with murder where you have an actual motive.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like if I killed a rim.
Speaker 0: that's real hard to get away with.
Speaker 0: if I killed Random guy who lives in another state while I was passing through the town on a road trip There's almost no chance of getting caught less as a camera.
Speaker 1: That's why serial killers are so scary because a lot of times they don't have any connection to their victims.
Speaker 1: They pick them semi randomly or maybe based on you know, they want to kill blonde Asian pygmies or whatever there and they also barely leave any evidence behind or they leave a ton of evidence.
Speaker 1: But because there's no lead the evidence is useless.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean, all right, you got fingerprints You got DNA got a picture of the dude with his mask on.
Speaker 1: That doesn't help you at all If you have no idea who it is have no lead at all don't even know what state to look in.
Speaker 0: Yep, but yeah one thing you're gonna I guess.
Speaker 0: if you don't want to get caught You should search on Google for how to do your crime better and maybe you'll find this episode That will tell you to keep your computer secure.
Speaker 0: perhaps deban them or something, but don't do that because uh I want you to get caught.
Speaker 1: Well, don't do it to commit murder.
Speaker 1: do it for something good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Things of the day.
Speaker 1: I'm a big fan of roller coasters.
Speaker 1: when I was in high school I was a much bigger fan of roller coasters mostly because back then I could still ride them.
Speaker 0: We can still ride them now.
Speaker 0: We don't even though we want to.
Speaker 1: well because they're all very far away.
Speaker 0: Well, I tried to get everyone to go that this past summer and we ended up not going Partly because every time we all got together we had better things to do.
Speaker 1: that didn't require as much travel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we could have done it.
Speaker 0: just people didn't you know want to put in the requisite time and effort in money?
Speaker 1: well I hate to say it.
Speaker 1: the real issue for me is that I've been to Cedar Point and I really if I'm gonna ride roller coasters again.
Speaker 1: I want to go to an equivalent park.
Speaker 0: I Think it's just because you've only been to Cedar Point.
Speaker 0: You don't realize that other places also have good rollercoaster?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they only have one or two.
Speaker 0: Cedar Point has more roller coasters in one place than any place in the world Perhaps but other you know crappy places only have one or two like Six Flags.
Speaker 0: New England has like five or six.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh five or six have a lot Maybe even ten.
Speaker 0: I don't know I haven't counted.
Speaker 0: But yet there are other places have enough roller coaster point.
Speaker 0: is there's rides to be worth it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz the problem is they're all kind of far away.
Speaker 1: We'd have to drive a couple hours, and they'll cost a lot to get into.
Speaker 0: that's what it cost to do those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's cheaper than Disney World Which is like hundreds of dollars to get in first.
Speaker 1: actually if you like roller coasters There's no reason to go to Disney World.
Speaker 1: as much as I like Disney World.
Speaker 1: They they pretty much have crap for roller coasters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not a roller coaster park.
Speaker 0: It's a theme park.
Speaker 0: Yeah, big difference you go there for a different reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you go to Cedar Point.
Speaker 1: you pretty much have to be hardcore about roller coasters.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna have fun.
Speaker 1: There's nothing else there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, these are the most.
Speaker 0: other places tend to have more of a variety.
Speaker 0: They have other things.
Speaker 0: Concentrate just on the roller coaster.
Speaker 1: well when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: That's what I was into.
Speaker 1: I really liked roller coasters for a variety of reasons.
Speaker 1: But anyway this I've ridden almost every kind of roller coaster.
Speaker 1: I could go at great length about all the different kinds, and how you might think one's one kinds the other whatever.
Speaker 1: There's a kind of roller coaster that I did not know existed until now.
Speaker 1: I guess you would call it a human-powered steel coaster meaning Effectively you get in these bicycle like contraptions And you ride it on a roller coaster track.
Speaker 0: now, what if you're not strong enough to make it up the hill?
Speaker 1: I Imagine that either there's a lift to get you to the top Then you only have to get up the little bits.
Speaker 1: if I designed it I mean the website doesn't say no one answered that question for me.
Speaker 1: if I designed it I'd make it with kind of a ratchet mechanism like you know when the roller coaster clicks going up You know what that clicking is.
Speaker 1: in most cases It's actually little hookies going click click click click click.
Speaker 1: So if the chain breaks or they lose power or whatever instead of falling back down it just sits there.
Speaker 1: Yep That's what that is.
Speaker 1: I would put the same thing on this.
Speaker 1: so if you get tired going up the hill You just stop as opposed to falling to your death.
Speaker 0: ah That's a good idea, but what if you like?
Speaker 0: what if one person is really you know unfit?
Speaker 0: And they take forever to get up the hill?
Speaker 0: they're blocking the person behind them and that could ruin your ride.
Speaker 1: I also imagine that they have contingencies in place or maybe because it's Japan.
Speaker 1: They just don't let fatter unfit people on.
Speaker 0: oh, it's Japan all right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's actually at a washes on high land park in okayama.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and the thing is most roller coaster parks are built in flat open land.
Speaker 1: This thing is built like on the side of a mountain and this roller coaster just on this mountain.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's easier to build then because you can use the mountain as the support for the higher parts of the roller coaster And that's you have to build less supporting poles.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: They did that in Vegas.
Speaker 1: They built a roller coaster whose hill was on top of a big building Yeah, which was kind of cool.
Speaker 1: the roller coaster was kind of crap But that was just the fault of the roller coaster design not the idea.
Speaker 1: yep, but check out these pictures this thing.
Speaker 1: It's very difficult to frighten me or to a nerve me or anything all right any amusement park ride.
Speaker 1: I once rode a ride that is banned in every state of the Union except Michigan and Kentucky.
Speaker 0: What ride is that?
Speaker 1: it's this carney ride that basically you spin around in a big?
Speaker 1: Circle and inside of the circle there are four pods and the pods spin around Independently and the ride is not controlled by a computer.
Speaker 1: the ride is controlled manually by a carney with three big levers Uh-huh, and he has to manually Spin all the different bits and move it around and time it and if he does it wrong the ride can generate enough force To actually crush you.
Speaker 0: You ever ride the roundup.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I know I don't know much about carney rides.
Speaker 1: I only know a lot about roller coasters.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think I found the roundup.
Speaker 0: yep here It is.
Speaker 0: I found a picture of it on.
Speaker 1: is the round up worse than chaos.
Speaker 0: This is the roundup.
Speaker 1: Oh, I've been on those.
Speaker 1: you base are awesome.
Speaker 0: You're.
Speaker 0: basically there's a big ring and the ring has around the edge of it a fence And you stand up against the fence in his little booth.
Speaker 0: It's a centrifuge Yeah, and you hold on to it, and it spins around and then it drops out.
Speaker 0: no and then it goes up Goes around and up hence the roundup.
Speaker 1: well when I went to space camp One thing that had there was the same kind of deal only didn't go up.
Speaker 1: It just went around in a circle and the floor drops away, and you just kind of get.
Speaker 1: sit there stuck against the wall.
Speaker 1: Well while we were riding at the guy running it says well you kids keep quiet if I do something awesome.
Speaker 1: And we all said yes, and he proceeded to because he was in the control booth area in the center.
Speaker 1: That doesn't spin or like it spins But at a different rate.
Speaker 1: he got up and he jumped over to where we were and stood straight up totally horizontal and ran around The centrifuge jumping over all of us kids.
Speaker 0: Those are good right good time.
Speaker 1: and then he pulled out.
Speaker 1: he had a can of beer with him and all this other stuff And he's tossed it around with the other guy doing all these tricks and awesome stuff And then he warns us again not to say anything And then he gets back in the center slows the thing down and lets us all get off.
Speaker 0: So a human powered roller coaster.
Speaker 0: you say human powered roller.
Speaker 0: it might be crazy enough to work.
Speaker 1: I particularly like the third right-hand corner of fear or whatever.
Speaker 1: they call this one corner.
Speaker 0: Do they really call it the third corner of fear?
Speaker 1: they call it something like that.
Speaker 0: Do you pass out in that corner?
Speaker 1: Pori katani, okay, couldn't deal with this.
Speaker 0: I wonder how many people got that initial D Joke, and how many didn't.
Speaker 1: well it's Thursday, so only the coolest of cool people listen to Thursday, okay?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so flicker is obviously the photo album of the 21st century.
Speaker 0: if you don't know about flicker Have you been living under a rock or what?
Speaker 1: It's one of those drop the e to talk about the way twit classifies websites.
Speaker 0: well You know I don't often usually think about flicker in terms of me putting my photos somewhere so that they can be downloaded a lot without losing bandwidth to me or without costing me a lot of money, and I never really think to go and say I wonder who what really cool people are on flicker like.
Speaker 0: imagine if someone was like I don't know like my mom's cousin who's a geologist, and she goes to volcanoes and stuff.
Speaker 0: if she had a flicker That'd be pretty damn cool.
Speaker 0: Well, you know it'd be even cooler, and it actually exists.
Speaker 0: the Los Angeles fire department has a flicker.
Speaker 1: I like I like firemen pictures.
Speaker 0: It's really awesome because you have pictures like the pictures that are the newest are of the Los Angeles Marathon of 2007 and all the people who like passed out, and they're wheeling them away on wheelchairs and stuff.
Speaker 0: and Then they got slightly less recent pictures of them putting out a brush fire in some park with Helicopters carrying water.
Speaker 0: and then they got pictures of some lady who drove a car into a swimming pool And this car is at the bottom of a swimming pool.
Speaker 0: and basically any time the Los Angeles fire department sees something crazy There must be someone there who's taking these really good pictures and putting them up in this.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure official Los Angeles fire department flicker And it's.
Speaker 0: it's pretty the photos are really high quality, and it looks official to me.
Speaker 1: Well my dad is actually I mean he's high up in the Detroit fire department one of the top dogs And when I was a kid I remember whenever we went for walks He he had the nose for cuz.
Speaker 1: actually you'd be surprised how many house fires there are in Detroit.
Speaker 1: But if he smelled a fire we track it down, and it may sound weird But a pastime of my family was watching houses burn as firemen tried to save them.
Speaker 1: Hey, he'd also listen to the scanner.
Speaker 1: We drive out and watch fires fairly often more often than you'd think would be prudent or expected.
Speaker 0: Well you can relive that by looking at this flicker account because there's a lot of fires and a lot of car wrecks And a lot of firemen putting them out.
Speaker 1: I do like pictures of fire a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean I remember the the calendar my dad gave me when he was this internal fire department calendar And it was just pictures of houses on fire.
Speaker 0: Here's a car upside down next to a fire truck.
Speaker 0: They're cutting down a tree with a chainsaw.
Speaker 1: they got any of them using the jaws of life.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there are jaws of life pictures.
Speaker 1: I like the jaws of life a lot.
Speaker 0: I also like the up.
Speaker 0: Here's like Like la fire department command staff salutes chief bamatter.
Speaker 0: Okay, fire chief and first lady of the fire department.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's some sort of ceremony.
Speaker 0: They're all wearing their firemen uniforms of fanciness, huh?
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of good pictures in here.
Speaker 0: if you like fire.
Speaker 0: You like firemen.
Speaker 0: This is a good flicker.
Speaker 0: If you look at it, there's a lot of pictures.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's anyone who dislikes a well-oiled fireman.
Speaker 0: There's 54 pages of pictures here Up.
Speaker 0: the very first picture is the official seal of the LA fire department and the second picture is the US flag.
Speaker 1: So we were downstairs with Alex and Emily eating tacos that I'd made And we were trying to come up with a show to do tonight as we seem to be doing lately.
Speaker 1: We're not really planning ahead these last few weeks.
Speaker 0: No, no planning ahead at all.
Speaker 0: We should plan ahead next week this weekend.
Speaker 1: I will see.
Speaker 1: luckily It looks like all of our plans to go out of town have followed through.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: I got stuff to do no matter what happens So it doesn't matter to me.
Speaker 1: but we realized that pretty much the best resource we have to figure out what to do Thursday shows on is Other people who are in our house.
Speaker 0: Of course usually when we ask people what to do the show on they come up with the same ideas we have or they come Up with no good ideas and it's not very helpful.
Speaker 1: tonight We got a bunch of good ideas and probably the best one at least the easiest one to do.
Speaker 1: right now We're gonna talk a bit about family vacations and vacationing and travel and all that.
Speaker 0: Well, it is spring break.
Speaker 0: I think for a lot of people if now if not soon.
Speaker 0: So vacations are pretty relevant topic in that regard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus it it's kind of interesting how my life as a geek well first as a as a child and then as a geek child and now as and then as a college geek and now as a full-grown geek how Vacationing always has these different connotations.
Speaker 1: and it's changed as to what I consider a vacation as time has gone on.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I mean it went from the family vacations You know driving in a van with the whole family including grandma down to Florida and back and then you know to college where we didn't Have any money.
Speaker 1: so vacations were like go to a con and not have food to eat.
Speaker 0: Vacation was sit in the apartment and I'd have to do schoolwork.
Speaker 1: I got to admit those are still some of the best vacations I've ever had.
Speaker 0: those were some damn good vacations that summer We spent at RIT.
Speaker 1: not going to RIT was probably one of the best summers of my life.
Speaker 0: It's definitely one of the best summers.
Speaker 0: I cannot deny.
Speaker 0: and then now we have money again sitting around playing putt-putt DDR listening to euro beat.
Speaker 0: good times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd work at de Bella's play order.
Speaker 1: You go five times a day Randomly driving to the beach or trying to play badminton with Luke.
Speaker 1: Those were good days one time.
Speaker 0: We tried that.
Speaker 1: No, we tried to play badminton twice.
Speaker 0: We did we?
Speaker 1: we did.
Speaker 1: We didn't succeed in playing the second time.
Speaker 1: We couldn't find all the bits cuz we lost something on the net.
Speaker 0: I actually saw a really good badminton video on the internet.
Speaker 1: So I'll find it uses thingy today next week, man I was really good at badminton when I was a young kid.
Speaker 0: I was also.
Speaker 0: I'm probably still really good at bad.
Speaker 1: I'm terrible at it now.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm not good like I could play professionally or a competition.
Speaker 1: No, you ever see my professional badminton thing.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: I was gonna use the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: so of course, I've seen it.
Speaker 0: but I'm better than Most at people at badminton because I actually tried to play it a lot.
Speaker 0: Nah, I'm also okay at volleyball a little bit.
Speaker 1: I'm.
Speaker 1: it's surprising.
Speaker 1: I'm better at volleyball than you'd expect but yet at the same time I often will fail Spectacularly at the critical moment in volleyball.
Speaker 0: That's pretty.
Speaker 0: I'm equal in skill.
Speaker 1: I think I can serve really well.
Speaker 1: really what like people were making fun of me at IBM and the volleyball team where this Intramural thing going because I was generally useless and I could set up for a spike Kinda, but half the time I'd send it off in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: See spiking is the only like real deficiency I have in volleyball.
Speaker 0: just as I can't jump high enough He's spiking I could do.
Speaker 1: I couldn't set up.
Speaker 1: I couldn't return a normal volley.
Speaker 1: All I could do was spike.
Speaker 0: Do you know the technique kinda?
Speaker 1: People taught me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just I wasn't good at.
Speaker 1: I always screwed it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't screw up.
Speaker 1: But here's the thing I would surprise everyone cuz the one thing I could do really well is serve.
Speaker 0: So everything's not hard.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I could do the jump overhand serve.
Speaker 1: that came in like a bomb and no one ever returned it.
Speaker 0: I do that too.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's not difficult.
Speaker 1: So I'd get like eight points for my team and then I'd spend need like the rest of the match until I was losing ten points.
Speaker 1: Yes, pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, good job.
Speaker 1: So as a result, I was useless.
Speaker 0: You're the MVP of the other team.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yeah, so Vacations.
Speaker 1: now we're cons and Wildwood and all that.
Speaker 1: now that we have money.
Speaker 1: We're actually considering doing Vacations again actually planning to go somewhere.
Speaker 0: I want to go.
Speaker 0: I think what I want to do is I want to go far away Because most of the time when I was vacationing as a kid I mean we never left the East Coast pretty much.
Speaker 0: I've never been west of Michigan in Ohio I've never been west of Chicago.
Speaker 1: Maybe I mean I've been as far west as Chicago in the north and I've been as far west as parts of Tennessee in the South.
Speaker 0: I've been as far south as Florida and as far north as Canada Ontario and I've been as far east as Israel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of crazy and backwards Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean as a young kid every year our family always went on two vacations And one of the vacations was always to Cedar Point for a weekend Mm-hmm or sometimes just a day depending on finances and time or whatever.
Speaker 1: But I went to Cedar Point every single year of my life and when I was two years old My parents brought me along until I moved away to RIT and I haven't been back since See pretty much every year.
Speaker 0: My family would go on a Most years.
Speaker 0: my family would go on a real vacation.
Speaker 0: That was about a week long maybe longer to somewhere often It was a New Hampshire or Florida.
Speaker 0: once I think we went to Lake George with some cousins and had a little cottage.
Speaker 0: that was a fun time.
Speaker 0: a lot of a lot of has silly memories for that one power outages and as Result water outages and hilarity my brother stealing M&Ms.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of good anecdotes on that one.
Speaker 0: But you know also I think probably more than once every year we would go on like a day trip somewhere like oh Let's go to museum.
Speaker 0: Let's go somewhere else That's you know, and we just do stuff.
Speaker 1: we did a lot of things like that.
Speaker 1: that just seems All families do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't really count as vacation.
Speaker 0: But yeah for real vacation We would do it like once a year go somewhere.
Speaker 1: See we always had the Cedar Point vacation Which was like the family ritual it came down to.
Speaker 1: they'd always pack up the back of the station wagon in bed.
Speaker 1: So me and my little brother could lay there playing our little games our game gear Gameboy or whatever for the two-hour drive.
Speaker 1: It's amazing how when I was a young kid a two-hour drive was this eternity.
Speaker 1: and if I wasn't entertained at every moment along The way I would be so crushingly bored that I just couldn't stand it.
Speaker 0: That is true I agree entirely.
Speaker 0: and now a two-hour drive is nothing.
Speaker 1: I know a two-hour drive.
Speaker 1: That's not this less than a day trip That's the normal course of business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember driving to New Hampshire.
Speaker 0: if I look at a map now It's only like four or five hours to get there to you know to the place you went to vacation there.
Speaker 1: But you remember it being this.
Speaker 0: but I remember it being this incredibly long boring drive.
Speaker 0: But now I could drive there if I wanted to.
Speaker 0: it's not a big deal.
Speaker 1: I think part of it to take the adult position here.
Speaker 1: when you're a kid You don't have as many memories as an adult.
Speaker 1: You don't need to spend as much time in reverie or thinking about your past or recalling things or relaxing.
Speaker 1: You were trying to do as much as you can in as little time as possible with spastic kid energy.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is.
Speaker 1: But now I'm older.
Speaker 0: array for portable video games.
Speaker 1: Yes but aside from that the big vacation my family went on is we drove down to Tennessee a bunch of times or we went down to West Virginia for the Jeep jamboree so my mom could fiddle around with off-roading and jeeps and all that fun stuff.
Speaker 1: Went on a lot of camping trips.
Speaker 1: one time we took my grandparents giant conversion van and drove down to Florida and back for Disney World and a whole bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: I remember going to the Cape Canaveral Space Museum and Space Camp and Huntsville and all sorts of just you know Typical family vacations.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did the same shit most of the time we want a vacation.
Speaker 0: I don't remember a single vacation.
Speaker 0: we went on where there weren't video arcades involved.
Speaker 0: It was pretty much.
Speaker 0: Hey, let's go play video games.
Speaker 1: Yeah Actually, I was spoiled with arcades cuz cedar point has one of the biggest old-school arcades out there.
Speaker 0: You haven't been to sesame place.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's not the biggest.
Speaker 1: I can't pretend.
Speaker 1: It's the biggest.
Speaker 0: The place we went to in New Hampshire Was the fun spot is there which is pretty much the arcade of the country perhaps of the world?
Speaker 0: We went there because fun spot was there.
Speaker 0: my parents pretty much like gave up on going to places.
Speaker 0: You know that happened to have an arcade and we went to the.
Speaker 0: we went on vacation to the arcade.
Speaker 0: That was also a lake so my mom was happy.
Speaker 0: there was a lake and there were restaurants and touristy crap.
Speaker 0: But we would spend a lot of time playing mini golf and video games.
Speaker 1: yep I remember one time when we were at Cedar Point, and it was stupidly hot out in the middle of a heatwave.
Speaker 1: It was over a hundred degrees So we had to get out of the heat for a little bit.
Speaker 1: we weren't gonna stand in line for an hour and die Even though not too long after that they put in these misters, which are actually really cool.
Speaker 1: They misted you in line with a big fan and water, so you didn't get hot.
Speaker 0: sounds good to me Yeah But anyway.
Speaker 1: So we went into this arcade the giant arcade at Cedar Point and me my little brother my mom and two other kids Rotated in and out on a Simpsons arcade machine until we beat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Simpsons arcade.
Speaker 1: Yep It was a dumb game, but you know what?
Speaker 1: for some reason It's just the vibe of playing it with a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: it can't be beat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all those all those games that ran on the same system Ninja Turtles X-men and Simpsons.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there were others.
Speaker 0: the dungeon dragons is similar, but not quite the same.
Speaker 0: better definitely better.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's better, but the the Cooperative four or more player beat-em-up arcade games definitely need to see a comeback.
Speaker 1: Well in general any sort of cooperative gameplay.
Speaker 1: I want this more and more and I'm lacking it more and more.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean we ghettoize.
Speaker 1: it will play Advance Wars against the AI and teams or things like that, but it's not the same.
Speaker 0: No, it's not the same at all Alright, so I remember I never really thought about.
Speaker 1: I mean I just assumed every area summertime time for the vacations.
Speaker 1: They're always over the summer.
Speaker 0: No they weren't always over the summer with us.
Speaker 0: like sometimes we would go on a vacation in the winter you know to go to Florida and Sometimes you go vacation in the summer.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you go vacation in the spring.
Speaker 0: Actually, I think most of the vacations were in the spring or the winter vacation You know from school because in the summer we typically went to summer camps and other things and thus it wasn't vacation vacation time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I remember the first trip I went on like major trip by myself was flying down to Florida for the citrus bowl with the band.
Speaker 1: But I wouldn't really call that a vacation because while I spend time on the beach in a Disney World and all that I also spent a lot of time working because it was a band outing.
Speaker 0: When I went on vacation my family.
Speaker 0: if we went to an amusement park It was all is probably one in Florida like a Disney World or Universal Studios or something like that.
Speaker 0: Most of the time we went to normal Amusement parks like Six Flags.
Speaker 0: it was never with my family.
Speaker 0: It was always with summer camp or with school or with some other you know group that didn't involve my Blood relatives see that wasn't until I had a car and then because I guess I didn't go to camps or anything.
Speaker 1: But I remember once I had a car and I realized that wait a minute I can go to Cedar Point or the beach or whatever anytime I want.
Speaker 1: My junior year of high school, I went to Cedar Point like 12 times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically if you went to school in Connecticut or at least where we went to school It was pretty much a close to 100% guarantee that your school was gonna take you on some vacation Somewhere if you paid.
Speaker 0: and you know, what's funny side of the permission slip?
Speaker 1: all the schools in southeast, Michigan Every single one of them at least all the public schools all the trips other than you know field trips and everything in the summer.
Speaker 1: We're always to Cedar Point and nowhere else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they typically always took us to Riverside But which is became Six Flags New England.
Speaker 0: They also would take kids to Boston and when you're at elementary school in Connecticut They will take you to the freakin mystic aquarium and mystic village like a thousand times.
Speaker 0: You will get so sick of going to mystic.
Speaker 0: You'll just want to kill yourself.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, there is one other place We always went to always there.
Speaker 1: I forget what it was called, but there was this historical reenactment village.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Sturbridge Village.
Speaker 0: you would go there too.
Speaker 1: Yeah I forget what ours was called but we'd have to live there like the pioneers for a whole day and it was this Competition and at the end the judges based on what you had done would decide whether or not you lived.
Speaker 0: Oh, it wasn't like that.
Speaker 1: But I remember bartering with the Indians.
Speaker 1: I end up giving the Indians guns so we could get food and then the Indians used the guns to raid the village and took The food back and then we all died.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was awesome.
Speaker 0: That sounds more awesome.
Speaker 0: what we had?
Speaker 0: we typically cuz it's all colonial up in New England.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so everything it tends to just be like you go to Sturbridge village.
Speaker 0: It's a village and like you'll go into say the Baker and they're actually just selling cookies in there.
Speaker 0: But the lady's dressed up like a colonial lady and she's you know teaches you about colonial baking and tries to sell you cookies.
Speaker 0: and then you go into like another building and like.
Speaker 0: this is what schools were like in the when it was colonial times.
Speaker 1: and But for the mess blacksmith day to skip a bit for the last several years Vacations for us at least for Scott and me and the rest of the front row crew.
Speaker 1: front row crew have basically become Going to Wildwood for a week after Otacon because conventions are not vacations for us.
Speaker 1: their work.
Speaker 1: They're fun.
Speaker 0: Well their work now they used to not be work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if they weren't work, I don't know how many I would go to.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: I mean once you've been to some It like there's not much for us to do outside of work at conventions any.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I would go to Otacon or I'd pick one or two conventions and go to them every year no matter what.
Speaker 1: But I wouldn't go to 10 or 20 conventions a year like I do now.
Speaker 0: No that pretty much if I wasn't doing anything conventions other than being an attendee.
Speaker 0: at this point I'd pretty much only go to Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it seems like there's a definite distinction between Vacations for relaxing and vacations for doing.
Speaker 0: well if you're doing is it really a vacation?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of people seem to look at vacation as time away from their mundane work life Enjoying themselves somewhere Mmm.
Speaker 1: I mean I've gone on some vacations where I did stuff the whole time.
Speaker 1: I crammed as much as I could in and I've been on vacations Particularly that half a month or so where we lived in Wildwood where I didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: I just laid on the beach and That's what we've been doing a lot lately.
Speaker 1: every year It's like we do Otacon the big trip, and then we just lay on the beach for a week.
Speaker 0: I think that's the way it's got to be.
Speaker 0: if we didn't land a beach for a week after Otacon We would be DED yep.
Speaker 1: Well remember.
Speaker 1: We couldn't talk for about three days.
Speaker 0: It's true the most recent one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not looking forward to what's gonna happen at this Otacon Especially if they let us do all the stuff we've proposed to do.
Speaker 0: yeah You know actually I think there's a kind of vacation that we haven't really gone on at least yet is business trips.
Speaker 0: like my dad Goes to a lot of places on business like to do business.
Speaker 0: I want that work.
Speaker 0: I've done that for IBM several times Yeah, but you've never gone on like a business trip to say Ireland or California or actually South America.
Speaker 1: I probably could have if I'd stuck around IBM longer because we did do a lot of work with some people in Dublin.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact a guy from there came to our department a bunch of times to do business trips.
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 1: all I remember is that because IBM paid for it he got a rental car.
Speaker 1: That's the only way to get around in America.
Speaker 1: He got a sports car and I remember one day I was walking out of the office And I'm ready to go home and I see him getting into his little sports car that he's rented and he tore out of that Parking lot at over a hundred miles an hour.
Speaker 1: He was enjoying that.
Speaker 0: I definitely Eventually wanna if I have to keep working for a long time.
Speaker 0: I want to have a job where there's some sort of business trips going on.
Speaker 1: a lot of jobs I've looked at but didn't apply to.
Speaker 1: they always say, you know a percentage of travel like this job involves 40% Travel or 20% travel and they always present it like it's a bad thing Like somehow that's gonna be some sort of detriment that I'm gonna have to go into Interesting places as opposed to just sitting in a cube all day.
Speaker 0: I think the problem is a lot of business travelers.
Speaker 0: when they travel, you know A lot of people are just too serious about their work.
Speaker 0: They go somewhere they do their work.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're the kind of people who are afraid of being someplace new.
Speaker 0: You know that the traveling itself actually not always pleasant, you know, not everyone likes to fly on planes Yeah, but you always get to fly business class yeah, but that's not always that exciting trust me.
Speaker 0: and You know you're tired when you get there.
Speaker 0: you have business to do.
Speaker 0: You don't get a whole lot of time to hang out and do what you want because they make you come back pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: Well the same time a lot of people do business traveling.
Speaker 1: they spend a lot of time doing nothing the whole evening in the hotel, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: and That's not a problem for people like us because we have things like Ds's and the internet so we can enjoy ourselves no matter where we are We can always do something if nothing else.
Speaker 1: if I had to go on a two-week business trip I could catch up on all my reading and I could catch up on all my video games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that is one thing is that I think a lot of business travelers might not make the most of their time in other places.
Speaker 0: But I could also see that it'd be upsetting if you were someone who tried to make the most of your time and you didn't Get enough time out there.
Speaker 1: Well what you do?
Speaker 1: I know a lot of people do this like say you got a business trip to I don't know Japan.
Speaker 1: So and the business trip is a week.
Speaker 1: take a week's vacation right after it.
Speaker 1: Stay in Japan on your own dime for the rest of the week and enjoy it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could try and go for that.
Speaker 0: It's not always easy You know.
Speaker 0: but and plus you have to you got.
Speaker 0: usually when you spend your vacation days You're planning that well in advance and business trips seem to sort of come up.
Speaker 1: No, they don't.
Speaker 1: only if it worked for a weird company.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think they would tell you about your trip somewhere else like a year in advance.
Speaker 1: I have most business trips I've known generally when I'd be going months and months and months ahead of time.
Speaker 0: That's not bad.
Speaker 1: granted all my business trips were two super lame places, but I'm not gonna get into that.
Speaker 0: I guess we just won't know enough about business trips until we go on some.
Speaker 0: though.
Speaker 1: whenever hotels I mean whenever we get hotels for Otakana Katsu Khan, and you know the hotel always has business or pleasure I always say business because I'm doing more business than I have anything else.
Speaker 0: It's a funny one.
Speaker 1: Yeah But honestly we're and we're gonna see who else wants to go in on us.
Speaker 1: But probably next summer we're thinking of actually going on a trip to overseas somewhere.
Speaker 1: We're not sure where.
Speaker 1: yeah We got a lot of vague ideas.
Speaker 1: I guess this isn't a contest or anything.
Speaker 1: But where do you guys think we should go?
Speaker 1: where should rim and Scott spend a week?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think my ideas are pretty much to go see ancient shit like go to Greece Go to Rome and go to South America.
Speaker 0: Yep anywhere where there's ancient stuffs.
Speaker 0: I want to see old shit.
Speaker 1: I mean not to say that I don't want to go everywhere.
Speaker 0: I mean I'd love to spend time in Ireland If I had a plane I would just fly around the world and see everything.
Speaker 1: But I mean really we're thinking Italy Greece and somewhere along the Mediterranean.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to go to Turkey.
Speaker 0: Turkey is not so bad.
Speaker 0: I'll go.
Speaker 0: something's warm.
Speaker 0: No warm is good, so the Alps are out.
Speaker 0: So it's Everest.
Speaker 1: Everest can wait didn't you want to climb Mount Everest?
Speaker 0: I do, but it's cold.
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 0: Want to go up there because I didn't realize that you could see space from up there.
Speaker 0: But I also don't want to go because it's hard and it's cold Yeah, and a lot of people die and a lot of you will die and they just leave you there.
Speaker 1: Yeah plus I mean think about it all the technology we've got and all the Massive amounts of planning and engineering and time and effort you can put into climbing Mount Everest and a lot of people just still die.
Speaker 0: Couldn't we just make like an Everest evader or something all right?
Speaker 0: Just like fly up there with a helicopter, and I fly back down.
Speaker 1: I don't think you could do helicopters.
Speaker 1: I don't think it would be too wise.
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 1: well one.
Speaker 1: the air is thinner that high.
Speaker 1: I don't know how high helicopter you can go.
Speaker 0: bring some air with you.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about the air.
Speaker 1: the helicopter flies in.
Speaker 0: I know bring some with you.
Speaker 1: So you're saying pressurize the earth.
Speaker 1: yep, yeah Plus wouldn't taking an escalator kind of defeat the point of climbing Mount Everest?
Speaker 1: Uh if the point is to see space then no I think the point is more to prove that you can do it.
Speaker 0: see I don't really care about that.
Speaker 0: I just I was.
Speaker 0: actually I had no interest in seeing Mount Everest until I heard that you could see space.
Speaker 1: You heard that from an anime.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: I think we've gone off to some tangent.
Speaker 1: so before we wrap this up Don't forget.
Speaker 1: We've got a contest going.
Speaker 1: the deadline for entries is next Thursday by midnight.
Speaker 1: the contest.
Speaker 1: in case You don't know tell us about the worst goddamn podcast out there.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of rules.
Speaker 1: you can read the forums for details.
Speaker 1: it has to have a website.
Speaker 1: It has to have existed for at least 20 episodes.
Speaker 1: I forget all the details.
Speaker 1: They're written down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't just send us a link.
Speaker 0: you got to tell us why it's the worst podcast ever.
Speaker 1: also I will tell you guys now We've gotten a lot of entries and several of them are really good.
Speaker 1: So I want you to enter.
Speaker 1: don't skimp on this bonus points.
Speaker 1: if it's a popular podcast that sucks But you're up against some pretty stiff competition.
Speaker 0: Also, it's gonna take us a while to listen to all these podcasts and judge based on your descriptions and the podcasts Which one is really the worst and who should win.
Speaker 0: yeah, so don't expect a winner to be announced very soon.
Speaker 1: Also, I gotta say some of these podcasts.
Speaker 1: I listen to them a little bit and some of the write-ups you guys sent in.
Speaker 1: I Am dumbfounded at how bad some of these podcasts are.
Speaker 1: I really didn't expect it to be that bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like I can draw.
Speaker 0: if I try to draw something I'll draw some stick figures, maybe something a little better than a stick figure.
Speaker 0: It's bad, you know.
Speaker 0: But imagine if I drew that bad stick figure Put it up on a deviated art and said check out my awesome arts and then kept drawing them For weeks and weeks and weeks without acting like they were awesome and was totally serious about it.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure if it's hilarious or sad yet because on one hand I hate to rag on someone who is on their own dime Providing content to the world trying to do something because they think it's good someone who has a hobby is excited about it But at the same time it's really hard not to have a rofl session about a super nerdy kid Trying in halting halting nerd speak to explain the difference between Captain America and Captain Marvel.
Speaker 0: So They're both dead.
Speaker 1: yeah, we're Spoilers.
Speaker 0: oh no I Think we're done.
Speaker 0: We are done.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.