Speaker 1: It's Wednesday January 3rd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we finally get around to talking about an absolutely fantastic anime project.
Speaker 1: blue cheek you SOS Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So it's anime day and nominally manga and comics day.
Speaker 0: Whoo Took long enough to get to this day.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, we only didn't even do a Monday show this week.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Nope I didn't do a Monday show the week before either.
Speaker 0: Just all about not doing Monday shows.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: Cuz I got a good idea for Monday show for next week.
Speaker 1: No, really Yeah, I think we're gonna have a pretty good.
Speaker 1: We're gonna get back on track starting next week with Mondays.
Speaker 0: I think you might be shit talking.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: We'll see what it's like Monday night when we're sitting around doing pre-production.
Speaker 0: We will see what it's like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I cut myself with a box cutter today.
Speaker 1: Why like we in some sort of box cutter fight?
Speaker 1: maybe maybe I was all right who won the box.
Speaker 1: In other news I have conquered the potato guns that con bad and I know God for us.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, they gave us.
Speaker 0: we got potato guns as gifts and potatoes randomly.
Speaker 1: Yes, and You know clown pistols are well and good until you've had a potato gun.
Speaker 1: Yeah that doubles as a one-shot water pistol.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean and I tried to use it and it didn't work quite intuitively But it I thought it was all.
Speaker 0: it's just a shitty $1 potato gun for the dollar store, but no metal.
Speaker 0: It's a really good potato gun.
Speaker 0: That's actually shoots potato pretty well.
Speaker 0: You just have to know how to use it.
Speaker 1: Yep The trick is to jam the thing into the potato and then twist it off to the side to get a full-spud loadout Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I still wish you had the kind of potato guns that shot whole potatoes.
Speaker 1: We could make one in about 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: We need some PVC pipe.
Speaker 1: We need some PVC pipe and some ether That's right, or possibly some butane if we're wusses, we should make potato light bulbs also Right, so what's wrong?
Speaker 1: potato light bulbs, I can't think of anything wrong with potato right bulbs, that's right That's right.
Speaker 1: so in Useless and tossed aside anime news and I'll mention this only briefly only because I saw it and I couldn't believe it Airgear one of the worst shows to come out in recent memory.
Speaker 0: that I mean that show with the rollerblading.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the the roller flying.
Speaker 1: Yeah hard.
Speaker 1: Here's the take the the fighting this of bleach But remove all the characters and everything interesting about it.
Speaker 0: then take Dragon Ball Z and remove everything at all Except for the fighting and then wait, so wait see me Dragon Ball Z in its purest form.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, and then take initial D and remove everything but the races and when I say everything I mean including the people talking during the races.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and you get air gear a steaming pile of something horrible.
Speaker 0: You have to add rollerblades also.
Speaker 1: They're not even really rollerblades.
Speaker 0: They're like roller things.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: There are the roller.
Speaker 1: break your neck because that couldn't happen in the real world.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: work you die And it's exactly right.
Speaker 1: All right, not only is this show crap.
Speaker 1: I don't remember if we reviewed it or if we just said it sucked But well get a whole show on it saying it's a. I think we did.
Speaker 1: it got picked up.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be released in February by a DV.
Speaker 0: Wow, okay.
Speaker 0: So wait, they could pick up air gear perhaps one of the assets shows ever but they couldn't pick up.
Speaker 0: I don't know What show are we watching Nana?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Nana Let's see.
Speaker 0: What else?
Speaker 0: He know Tori's not on DVD.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, but air gear is coming out.
Speaker 1: So it's all okay.
Speaker 0: great it's.
Speaker 1: It's rated MA.
Speaker 1: I mean the show is not.
Speaker 1: I figured it first.
Speaker 1: All right They're just targeting that, you know, nine to fourteen year old crap show demographic, which apparently is very profitable Mm-hmm, but the show is rated MA and it's got a lot of Nakedity in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I thought he lit.
Speaker 0: the dude lives in a house with a bunch of girls and he lusts after that one really awesome girl.
Speaker 0: Who's better?
Speaker 0: Roller flying than anyone else?
Speaker 1: Yeah, this show is not good news, no, it's not and despite being not good news it got picked up Correct.
Speaker 1: I could talk more about it, but I think it stands on its own.
Speaker 0: If I'm ever a bajillionaire, I'm gonna buy all the anime companies and only license the good shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, remember how we were bitching about how the anime industry is secretive.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then anime world order before that was bitching about the anime industry was secretive.
Speaker 1: Well, they've been bitching again about how they anime industry is secretive.
Speaker 1: great and I'm gonna bitch about it now to continue the cycle because I want to know what rationale they had to pick up this show.
Speaker 1: Who's gonna pay?
Speaker 1: $29.98 a DVD for four episodes of poorly animated kid rollerblading?
Speaker 0: That's a good question because I don't know anyone like that.
Speaker 1: I really want to know is this gonna be profitable?
Speaker 1: I want to know if the show makes money, but there's no way to know.
Speaker 1: I can't know.
Speaker 1: there was absolutely No way for me to know if the show is successful or not.
Speaker 0: Nope But you know what?
Speaker 0: I do know is that there are companies like vertical who are publishing high-class stuff like Buddha and ode to kirohito.
Speaker 0: That not too many people read yet somehow they're very profitable.
Speaker 0: So why cannot a TV do the same thing and publish the high quality high brow stuff?
Speaker 1: That not too many people watch yet is somehow profitable cuz they probably spent like 14 million dollars on this air gear license.
Speaker 0: I think what's happened is this could be true.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: is that maybe Japan has realized maybe that we're not?
Speaker 0: They're not as dumb as we think they are because we always say all those Japanese don't understand the American anime industry, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Maybe the Japanese.
Speaker 0: when the first in when people went over there to try to license anime for the first time Those are super super super nerdy guys, right and Japan was probably like my Japanese animation industry was like hey These American anime industry guys are so dumb We can rip them off and they've been ripping us off for years and years and years and years.
Speaker 0: American anime industry is just so dumb and so stupid though all those anime executives in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Don't know shit.
Speaker 0: that's why they keep dubbing things poorly and Paying too much for licenses from Japan.
Speaker 1: Solved it.
Speaker 1: They're probably sitting around in their secret space.
Speaker 0: like we have faith that someone who's an executive must be a smart person Someone who's in charge of a big company that makes a lot of money that you know Does all this stuff and is still in business and still profitable must be a smart person.
Speaker 1: SEO is still in business.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think.
Speaker 0: I think it's becoming more apparent that a significant possibility that the people in charge of the anime companies in America are just all complete idiots every last one of them and Japan knows it and that's why it sucks for us.
Speaker 1: We get a lot of feedback for the show and I can't wait to hear the feedback from that statement.
Speaker 0: I can't wait either.
Speaker 0: so I said it cuz we I. I'm not saying it's true I'm saying it is a distinct possibility because anyone who licenses air gear and thinks it's going to sell.
Speaker 0: I Couldn't come up with another reasonable conclusion.
Speaker 1: What I wonder and I mean there are shows that are not good that make a lot of money And I wonder if these shows are profitable.
Speaker 1: What if air gear makes them so much money that they had no choice but not to license it?
Speaker 0: then I don't know what to say about American anime fans because you know Even though I know what to say about American though American anime fans right tend to kind of like shows like Naruto and bleach and these kind of crap fighting shows.
Speaker 0: They tend to also dislike the same, you know, it's like everyone sort of agrees on what the crap is.
Speaker 0: You don't see air gear fans at the cons, you know.
Speaker 0: And when you start bringing up good stuff, you know people all teens tend to agree on a lot of the good stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, even the even the Naruto and I was hanging out at an amazement.
Speaker 1: There was a crowd of Naruto.
Speaker 1: I was trying to quiet them down because they were making a ruckus at like 4 in the morning in the middle of the con.
Speaker 1: They we started talking about anime and they all obviously very much like Naruto and they all also very much Understood that cowboy bebop was probably the best anime thing ever made.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah speaking of cons Anime, it's the new year.
Speaker 1: That was a very nice segue.
Speaker 0: Yeah fair It's the new year and anime cons comm which is your number one site for anime con information has released their Year in review of anime cons.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good article.
Speaker 1: You probably want to read the whole article.
Speaker 1: We're not obviously gonna comment on the whole I don't know.
Speaker 0: they talk about stuff like how you know Clamp showed up to anime Expo and how anime next also made manga necks, etc.
Speaker 1: How Otakon and Katsucon both had artists alley controversies.
Speaker 0: Well, no, they're talking about the Katsu.
Speaker 0: if they were talking about Katsucon talking about the last Katsucon They only talked about the Otakon artists alley controversy.
Speaker 1: Well, no, they mentioned Katsucon and the upcoming controversy because they've announced for Katsucon the new rules.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but they don't talk about.
Speaker 0: it's mostly about last year.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway in this article is a list of the ten largest anime conventions in North America.
Speaker 0: According to that cons reported attendance, so The thing is is you know, depending on how a specific convention counts their attendance.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at you.
Speaker 1: anime Expo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't actually know how any cons report their attend.
Speaker 1: Well, we know how Otakon and Katsucon a lot of those cards count them though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're pretty sure we know but we're not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 0: so a lot of the numbers could be off but With the best estimates that are available to us These are the ten largest anime conventions in North America last year number one.
Speaker 0: I'll start at the top Why not?
Speaker 0: is anime Expo with forty thousand something people total and thirty two thousand?
Speaker 0: Well about thirty three thousand of which actually paid to get in.
Speaker 0: about seven thousand people went for free.
Speaker 1: eight thousand people yeah, I mean that in could that'll include like staff and Panelists dealers the dealers the artists alleys the guests.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends.
Speaker 1: some cons charge dealers to get into the con in addition to having.
Speaker 0: yeah I don't know if they count as paid or not.
Speaker 1: I don't know tough call These are fuzzy numbers, but considering that I've been to many small not many But I've been to enough of these cons to where I think the numbers are accurate enough.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anime Expo is still huge Otakon.
Speaker 0: it's estimated that there were about thirty three thousand total and about 22,000 paid.
Speaker 0: Wow According to that estimate ten thousand people at Otakon getting free including us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Otakon does seem to be very liberal in its letting people in free.
Speaker 1: I mean I've paid for one Otakon in my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But then again, we've done stuff at every Otakon.
Speaker 0: I know the question is it's like should Otakon keep letting all these people in free or Are there people getting in free that should be paying what?
Speaker 0: That's a pretty big discrepancy between the total people there and the number of people paying.
Speaker 1: what Otakon should do very simply like a third Of the con is there for free is vet out somehow the quality of the panelists so that the people they're letting in free are Definitely worth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if there's 10,000 total and 23,000 paid members The panelists are such a small portion of those 10,000 free.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: because remember think about how many panels there are and multiply that by four and then count all the dealers who pay For a table.
Speaker 0: anyways, the dealers gotta pay like 750 bucks for a table.
Speaker 0: a lot.
Speaker 0: You know, if you don't make up like $750 and selling shit.
Speaker 0: It's not a good deal to go to Otakon as a dealer.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't know if I was the dealer I wouldn't go to Otakon just for the fact that the competition in the Otakon dealers room is fierce.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would go and buy spot in the dealers room of Otakon not to be a standard anime merchandise dealer.
Speaker 0: But to do some other sort of dealing like, you know if I was another con or You know just a pimp geek nights.
Speaker 0: We've very much considered that it's not worth 750 though, not yet.
Speaker 0: Not yet artist Sally's much cheaper.
Speaker 0: Okay, next comes a con.
Speaker 0: I don't know where that is, but they had 12,500 people.
Speaker 0: I think it's a Texas, right?
Speaker 0: I'm not quite sure.
Speaker 0: It's been surprising that a con that I don't even know where it is is the third biggest.
Speaker 1: Of course right after that is anime north with pretty much the same number of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yep Akon's in Dallas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have a decent number of friends who go to anime north.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anime north's in Canada and you know, I didn't think that that many people went to.
Speaker 0: I thought it was a middling size Con.
Speaker 0: apparently it's much larger than I thought.
Speaker 0: it's like whoa, maybe we should head out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only problem in Montreal or is it in Toronto?
Speaker 1: It's uh, it's in Ontario.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: yeah I honestly don't remember because every year I thought I'll go to anime north and I'd look and Another con would coincide with it to say in Toronto.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go to Toronto me either.
Speaker 0: Okay anime central still big.
Speaker 1: and the thing is anime central doesn't look like it's grown very much because it I don't think it was Much smaller than that years and years ago when I used to attend on a regular basis.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that cons are pretty much sort of.
Speaker 0: we're not gonna see a lot of con growth anymore.
Speaker 0: You know, it's I mean unless you put there aren't too many places left for cons to be big That there isn't a con already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, in fact a lot of cars aren't too many people who would go to cons that aren't already going to come.
Speaker 1: Well part of it's that a lot of cons are in places where they get a lot of people and they would continue to grow.
Speaker 1: But they can't fit more people where they are and there's no suitable venue near enough to where they currently are to keep most Of those people around.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm pretty sure that every convention venue for anime cons in North America is already being used.
Speaker 0: I think we're nearing like the What's it called?
Speaker 0: terminal velocity of Con growth.
Speaker 1: Well keep in mind once a beacon builds the con center on the waterfront We're gonna have to start see if they actually do that.
Speaker 1: There aren't any anime conventions in Middling downstate New York yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah that it would be a good place, but there's no venue.
Speaker 1: Well, we got a way for that venue to be built.
Speaker 0: Yep All right next comes fan of a con which I've heard the name and they estimate 10,000 people.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good too.
Speaker 0: There's a kind of didn't hear of.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'd be on a click to find out where it is.
Speaker 1: anime weekend, Atlanta.
Speaker 0: That's anime world orders favorite con had about 9,000 people.
Speaker 0: All right, so it's a half an Oda con.
Speaker 0: It's not so bad.
Speaker 1: next anime Boston is another one that I've always wanted to go to but it always either conflicts with another con Or conflicts with another con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, it seems like a big con.
Speaker 0: It seems like it's worth going to but it always conflicts with something.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the timing of it is, but it's pretty bad.
Speaker 0: They should try to move it.
Speaker 0: I think they would probably get more.
Speaker 0: they probably be able to get over that 10,000 maybe like 15,000 Sakura con.
Speaker 0: they said 8300 total 7,500 estimated paid.
Speaker 0: doesn't Sakura con in Seattle.
Speaker 1: I think it's out in Washington.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's competing with the packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah as basically competing with packs sort of for the North Pacific Coast Convention crowd.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway last and certainly not least the con that we will be talking about a lot in weeks to come because we are going to be Doing awesome things at it.
Speaker 1: katsu.
Speaker 1: Con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're going to katsu con the 10th biggest con.
Speaker 0: apparently 6,400 people estimated about 6,000 paid.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and so we're gonna be in When like a month the weekend around February 18th, I think 18th is the Sunday when we'll be driving back home.
Speaker 0: Okay, so that weekend katsu con we're gonna be there doing more than we have ever done at any convention ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except I think yeah, I think katsu cons problem is they say katsu con.
Speaker 0: in the article It says how katsu con used to be keeping pace with Otakon because it is in a relatively similar geographic location.
Speaker 0: I think the problem the reason katsu con hasn't been growing is because the hotel and transportation situation in DC is pretty difficult Whereas in at least in Baltimore, there's a bunch of hotels all around the convention center.
Speaker 1: Well, they're.
Speaker 1: I mean I've gone to several katsu cons and there I think a lot of reasons why katsu con is not growing that much anymore And why in fact, it seems to be kind of stagnant not that it isn't a good con.
Speaker 1: But yeah, DC really just kind of sucks to travel to.
Speaker 1: I mean It's difficult to fly there and get to the con.
Speaker 1: the hotel fills up and you got to get shoved into some overflow hotel somewhere.
Speaker 1: The Metro is not terribly useful.
Speaker 1: The hotels are so expensive that it cost me a lot more money to go to katsu con than it does to go to Otakon.
Speaker 1: Yeah quite a bit more Yeah, and also the vibe of katsu con is very different from other cons.
Speaker 1: The crowd tends to be older tends to be a lot more people our age there.
Speaker 1: there's a lot more drinking a lot more older people walking around talking quietly about anime and There's really not so much of a young kid family-friendly presence that a lot of other cons seem to exude.
Speaker 0: They also talk about the lack of growth of Otakon.
Speaker 0: like compared You mean Otakon did grow but compare usually Otakon grows tremendously and this year they only grew by a little bit and didn't reach their cap.
Speaker 0: and they have a separate article about why that isn't such.
Speaker 0: and I'm really starting to think that One big barrier to a lot of cons growing any further is the fact that hotel and transportation situations are kind of difficult.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean we're tired of dealing with it.
Speaker 1: Otakon.
Speaker 1: last year every hotel in the city was sold out like months and months and months before the con and I bet there's a lot of people who probably wanted to go to Otakon but couldn't get a hotel and just gave up.
Speaker 0: and There's a lot of people who would go to Otakon because it's fun time.
Speaker 0: They're not saying it's not a fun time or that they don't want to go but it's just not worth even if they get a hotel room and it's just such a hassle to do it and Get there and transport that it's not worth it.
Speaker 1: Of course Those people should listen to our three-part series on how to attend anime cons to learn that that's not true.
Speaker 1: You can go to cons very easily if you plan a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, there's not enough smart people - You don't need to be smart.
Speaker 1: You just need to listen to geek nights that that would be smart though Things of the day Hot damn.
Speaker 0: So, you know all those videos that like the stop-motion things you see where people jump take a picture jump Take a picture and then eventually, you know, it looks like they're flying around on their knees.
Speaker 0: There's been a lot of them on YouTube lately or the ones where you know.
Speaker 0: They take a picture of him standing then standing a little bit to the right and then he slides around.
Speaker 0: Well, this is nothing new Like I thought it was something new when I saw it, you know about a couple years ago on the Internet's, you know with the famous And Yeah, well apparently some guys in 1952 or 53 beat him to it if I may.
Speaker 1: yes
Speaker 0: It was some Canadian that like the national Canadian film, whatever it's called made a video in 1952 in cut while and I guess not a video a film in 1952 in color with a story of these two guys who were neighbors and they fight over this flower that grew You know right between their properties and such, you know, and it's got this message of love thy neighbor and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But the point of it is it does the cool stop-motion stuff that everyone has been doing recently on YouTube that they seem to think Is so awesome, you know these.
Speaker 0: they do the whole jumping up and down thing and they do some other stuff, too.
Speaker 0: That's a lot more creative and interesting than what anyone else has done At least when anyone else has done recently that I've seen.
Speaker 1: this is definitely worth watching it.
Speaker 0: Plus it was 1952 people.
Speaker 0: you are not original nor creative.
Speaker 1: Well by that logic I mean Right, so over the weekend the party one of our dear friends Lisa showed us a video that her brother had done and this video is now currently on YouTube.
Speaker 1: and Normally, we wouldn't have such an incestuous linking for a thing of the day, but this is pretty damn funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, usually, you know some kid makes a video for a school project or whatever and sometimes they're okay and sometimes they're kind of Lame, but this is actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: I mean it's about lucid dreaming and coca puffs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't really want to ruin it.
Speaker 1: But suffice to say the operative point here is that Whenever someone is killed in this dream or whenever there is blood instead of actual blood or gore Appearing it is replaced by cocoa puffs which can be eaten to induce a state not unlike the quickening from Highlander.
Speaker 1: awesome, and I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just watched this video.
Speaker 1: It's like 10 minutes long and I guarantee it's worth laughing at.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean I laughed a few times.
Speaker 0: I thought it was gonna be lame or whatever and it wasn't really lame.
Speaker 1: I remember what time when you didn't kill your friends and eat their cocoa puffs.
Speaker 1: Yeah So tonight we're going to talk about something that I can't believe we haven't talked about.
Speaker 0: well, I think we were going to talk about it and then we held off for a week.
Speaker 0: and What happened was you just never ended up actually making a show about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I thought back I could practically remember talking about it But now we never.
Speaker 0: we might have mentioned it in passing But we clearly did not have an episode on it where we talked about it in enough detail.
Speaker 0: Talked about on the forums though.
Speaker 0: So people on the forums You probably know about this already.
Speaker 1: Yeah This is something special and I really think that everyone out there who is that any way shape or form a fan of anime or?
Speaker 1: Science fiction will want to see this Okay.
Speaker 0: Well first off there was this guy named Shigeru Komatsuzaki.
Speaker 0: now, he's sort of an important guy basically way Back in the day like the 40s.
Speaker 0: He was a famous Japanese science fiction illustrator and model designer.
Speaker 1: Now he has worked on such notables as Thunderbirds Atragon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he did a lot of shit.
Speaker 0: basically Atragon was this boat with a big drill on the front that could fly and shoot and it was sort of crazy and It was his famous science fiction novel.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he wrote the novel, but he Definitely illustrated the Atragon and designed the ship and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: And that novel had a lot of things based on it.
Speaker 0: a lot.
Speaker 0: there was a live-action movies Atragon which because of marketing reasons were merged with the kaiju universe of Godzilla.
Speaker 1: and Now think about that.
Speaker 1: in America when they want to market something They always add like a product that they can sell like when Home Alone 2 came out they added that talk boy thing.
Speaker 1: They always have some sort of product tie-in for marketing or like a little kid.
Speaker 0: So rather than take the great sci-fi story of Atragon just make a live-action movie.
Speaker 0: They made a kaiju movie.
Speaker 1: What does that say about Japan when if you want to alter something for marketing you add kaiju to it?
Speaker 0: Yep anyway, that's what they did.
Speaker 0: and There's an anime Atragon, which is a two-part OAV called super Atragon.
Speaker 0: We watched this after Otacon a couple years ago Because somewhat Scott Johnson bought it for cheap in the dealer's room.
Speaker 1: Scott Johnson bought a DVD for cheap.
Speaker 0: gee When does that happen?
Speaker 0: I don't know what.
Speaker 0: wait wait as he does he not bought a DVD for cheap in the last five seconds.
Speaker 0: That might be a record.
Speaker 1: We have it on good authority that the source material for super Atragon is very very good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, apparently this the original novel of Atragon is awesome.
Speaker 0: Really awesome.
Speaker 0: But I can't find it in English or I would buy it and read it now.
Speaker 0: the anime The two part OAV of super Atragon Not so great.
Speaker 0: Not good.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: It starts out.
Speaker 1: actually it starts out really really good.
Speaker 1: It has so much potential.
Speaker 1: It looks like it's gonna be so cool.
Speaker 1: And I mean it starts out with like nuclear bomb going off like Hiroshima time and then crazy stuff happening and aliens in the sea and submarines.
Speaker 1: But I guess the OAV cut all everything that was good out in order to make the adaptation from the novel and what we had left was mediocre animation and a long Meandering plot that doesn't really go anywhere.
Speaker 0: But you can tell when you're watching super Atragon that whatever this was based on wherever they got The ideas for this particular, you know, it's the way they tell the story in super Atragon that sucks.
Speaker 0: But you can tell that the original story that they are telling you was good before they told it.
Speaker 0: Yes It's like some guy trying to tell you about something awesome that happened, but he doesn't know how to speak.
Speaker 0: That's what super Atragon is.
Speaker 0: Anyway way back in the day.
Speaker 0: This guy made some Illustrations called earth SOS and they were pretty cool illustrations.
Speaker 0: I'd like to see them Just now.
Speaker 0: well, not just now but when July.
Speaker 0: I think Yeah in July of 2006 through December 3rd 2006 some people because Come on Tzuzaki died, I think in late 2001 early 2002.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not too long.
Speaker 0: He was 85 though.
Speaker 0: So, I mean, come on, you know get the guy credit.
Speaker 0: They decided to make a six-part OAV based on the earth SOS Illustrations.
Speaker 1: this is called predictably enough project blue earth SOS orange pen project blue cheek you SOS.
Speaker 1: if you can't figure out what the word cheek you means I suggest you stop listening to our show.
Speaker 0: all right project blue earth SOS is kind of difficult for us in the English-speaking world to see because well only one episode has been translated and put on the internet as far as I can tell yeah And a few of our friends.
Speaker 1: we haven't tried but other people have looked around for Roz and not really found much of anything Outside of the first episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a six-part OAV.
Speaker 0: It was on TV I don't know but you know They put them all on TV one at a time and I think it's done now, but It's got to be on DVD at some point and when that happens, we'll eventually see it.
Speaker 1: I guarantee this is gonna come over to America in some way shape or form.
Speaker 1: if nothing else It'll get released on DVD in Japan and then the fansubbers will make quick work of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now we can't talk a lot about what goes on in the show because in the first episode It's basically a lot of build-up a lot of setting Everything call the puzzle piece.
Speaker 1: character introductions set up you're introduced to all the characters and then at the end of this first episode All hell breaks loose and then the show begins in earnest and that is right when the closing credits start.
Speaker 0: Yep It's freaking awesome.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: I The basic premise here is that now well first off the style.
Speaker 1: the style is really cool.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a mix between futurism and Read or die plus Encyclopedia brown plus at your God and you get this show and you get this show.
Speaker 0: It's if you've watched read or die not the TV series the original OAV and yeah The TV series can die in a fire.
Speaker 0: You like that kind of style where you know there's people doing all kinds of high action stuff with fancy gadgets and Technologies, but there's also this sort of old style at the same time.
Speaker 0: That's what actually good.
Speaker 0: that's not what actually guys that's what project blue earth SOS is.
Speaker 1: I mean the setting the way it's set up It's kind of like the future as it was probably imagined by people in the 50s.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's based on a guy's illustrations from the 40s.
Speaker 0: So he was drawing what he thought the future would look like which means he was including the technology from his time.
Speaker 0: You know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's what this guy thought the future would look like The way the anime is done.
Speaker 1: I thought there's a lot of aesthetic liberty taken and it definitely they're going for the retro future.
Speaker 1: Look, I mean part of the opening is that there's this new maglev train using a special g-reactive engine.
Speaker 1: It's like the future of transportation and energy.
Speaker 1: It's a maglev train.
Speaker 1: maglev Future future maglev awesome.
Speaker 1: all the reporters lined up Documenting this are using old-style cameras with flash bulbs like old flash bulbs.
Speaker 1: So the guy holds up the stick and it goes poof and they they're recording on to reel to reel film not digital Recorders or anything like that and then it like it shows a shot of the city and they're all.
Speaker 1: there's all these elevated trains going Around but the elevated trains have propellers on the front pulling them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this guy's at one point they sit down to watch a movie to learn Oh, that's the best part.
Speaker 0: the butler pushes a button and down from the ceiling this automatic lowering thing Pulls down a reel to reel video projector with the film already loaded and then you get this grainy Flickering thing that they all watch.
Speaker 0: meanwhile, they have hover cars.
Speaker 1: Hover cars that look like 1950s car.
Speaker 0: Yeah hover cars, but the controls are like 1950s buttons.
Speaker 1: I think the other one of my other favorite parts is when there's a car chase a really well done and quite interesting car chase where the hover car at one point she the person driving it needs to turn around and spin and do something cool and proceeds to work the clutch and shift gears.
Speaker 1: and I really wonder what the hell she was doing shifting gears on a thing that has no possible.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine what that did.
Speaker 0: I don't know either but it's you know, it seems silly But when you actually watch it, you don't really know.
Speaker 0: it doesn't stick out like a sore thumb.
Speaker 0: It's just this really awesome read-or-die kind of style.
Speaker 0: That's very Awesome, especially if you're an anime fan.
Speaker 0: if you're an anime fan, you'll just watch this single.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: It's all awesome Holy crap, awesome.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Even if you're not an anime fan.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is the kind I remember way way back I showed my dad a read-or-die and he thought it was pretty badass even though you know It's kind of weird and you really really wouldn't think that.
Speaker 1: I guess non anime fans would like that sort of thing But there's a certain level of that kind of aesthetic beyond which even normal people will love this.
Speaker 0: I think it's just.
Speaker 0: it just feels really fun to watch all this stuff because you have that like the bright colors and You have some sort of familiarity with this old technology While at the same time you go ooh and aah at this fancy future sci-fi shit.
Speaker 1: I mean while they're doing you know There's the reporters with their flash bulbs and this maglev train and then one of the main characters Billy Kimura Kimura comes down out of the sky on this crappy jetpack.
Speaker 0: Yep Good times.
Speaker 1: So the actual plot is that scientists in 1995 have developed this G reactive engine Which they're not really very detailed on what this G reactive engine is at all and it requires people is fuel something like that.
Speaker 1: I Get the impression that it's more just very high technology like something beyond what humans would normally be capable of.
Speaker 0: Yep, but they've got this thing and they test it out on a fighter jet Which is where you test out all new engines.
Speaker 1: now We're gonna spoil the first five minutes because this is we can't.
Speaker 1: we don't want to spoil the awesomeness that happens later But we have to spoil something or there's really nothing we can say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they're testing this awesome reactive engine and this jet takes off and it goes crazy crazy fast.
Speaker 1: It's a total success like mach 13 14 15 21 22 23 Stupid fast.
Speaker 1: So the test is a success.
Speaker 1: before the test pilot can come back this weird Rainbow glow appears and before anyone knows it the ship and all the stuff Disappears, yep, so the react and right before the guy disappeared.
Speaker 0: He was like UFO Oh God.
Speaker 1: So now this reactive engine has disappeared and everything associated with it and the research scientists are sitting there going.
Speaker 1: Ah Fuck.
Speaker 1: so then fast forward there.
Speaker 1: They've got this maglev train the G reactive engine.
Speaker 1: They know it's a success.
Speaker 1: yeah, the
Speaker 0: show takes place like five years after that
Speaker 1: and they're about to debut the first maglev G reactive train and Obviously something happens at this point or else there wouldn't be a show
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm
Speaker 1: not really gonna ruin any more than that other than that a dog climbs up a ladder faster than a human could.
Speaker 0: That was a good part when the dog went up the ladder, I mean the characters are all young and awesome.
Speaker 0: Lotta breast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is a character named.
Speaker 0: Dr breast and he has a daughter who is like eight and her name is Lotta breast l o TTA space BR ESD.
Speaker 1: now I know that the Japanese people are overall a very intelligent people and there's no doubt in my mind that that was fully Intentional there.
Speaker 0: It has to be intentional.
Speaker 0: There's no way that I can.
Speaker 1: The little girl's name is Lotta breast her older sister.
Speaker 0: It's not her sister.
Speaker 0: It's like this girl who like hangs out with her what I like her nanny or some whatever.
Speaker 1: the woman who she is often with Is could be described as smoking.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, I mean for an anime character.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, obviously I preferred two-dimension to women.
Speaker 1: Good luck with it Yeah, but we've also got penny Carter who was kind of this Vagabond smart kid who has his dog Washington Washington being the best character.
Speaker 0: It's actually penny Carter.
Speaker 0: is this sort of poor or he's not poor but he's an MIT Graduate and he's sort of like the lone hacker where the dog right and he's real smart and he gets shit done.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, you also have Billy Kimura who is like a mega zillionaire kids you and he's also really smart.
Speaker 0: So you've got like two encyclopedia Browns with the same goals Competing to see who does it first and one of them's like just some poor smart kid and one of them's a rich smart kid.
Speaker 1: Now add to that effectively penny from Inspector Gadget.
Speaker 1: Yep, and A bunch of other super badass people.
Speaker 1: I can't say anything more about that.
Speaker 0: You know, it is.
Speaker 0: it's like penny Carter And also he has a dog.
Speaker 0: He's like the male penny from Inspector Gadget.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except everyone's badass There's no non badass.
Speaker 0: What's?
Speaker 0: his name is not so much bad, I don't know how much Captain Clayton I don't know how much of a character he's gonna be long-term I don't know how much either but Captain Clayton is sort of not a bad.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know who else is?
Speaker 1: Those two guys who get axed who got axed those guys who get shot by that thing halfway through the show.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: Those guys were not so badass.
Speaker 0: They weren't real characters though.
Speaker 0: They didn't have names.
Speaker 0: No No, anyone with the name is at least kind of badass.
Speaker 0: I mean Captain Clayton is at least smart a little bit But everyone else is just super awesome like haha.
Speaker 1: and they're super awesome in the reader.
Speaker 1: die way.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of show where if you show to a crowd of people there will be regular and periodic yelling shouting screaming and cheering.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, you know guys will get trapped and the army guys yelling at him and then the army guy gets distracted for a second Cuts back.
Speaker 1: the two chairs are empty.
Speaker 1: The crowd goes nuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know now that I realize that this came from a trigon.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of similarities, you know the there's the UFOs kind of thing, but no one really knows about it.
Speaker 0: and You know, there's the big ships of mystery and there's a lot of similarities.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of mystery that's probably going to be revealed as the show goes on.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I mean, they really lay it on pretty thick too with that green-haired girl.
Speaker 0: Oh man that they lay it on heavy.
Speaker 0: It's like whoo, here's a green-haired girl.
Speaker 0: She appears mysteriously before two characters.
Speaker 1: Oh, don't forget.
Speaker 1: She says something cryptic.
Speaker 0: She says something cryptic and then disappears.
Speaker 1: That one thing to be said about this show is that each episode is 45 minutes long.
Speaker 1: So it goes longer than what you'd expect from but there's only six episodes.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of like getting six mini movies because the first episode in itself I watched it.
Speaker 0: you could have told me that that was an anime movie or something like that and I would have believed you Totally well.
Speaker 1: plus it it'll play out like a 13 episode show probably in terms of the amount of plot in it.
Speaker 1: Because while it's 45 minutes, that is an action-packed 45 minutes.
Speaker 1: They don't.
Speaker 1: you will never get bored watching this.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It's so sad because you know when it comes to new anime, there is not a great quantity of it.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, what are we watching right now?
Speaker 1: We're watching Nana.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's Death Note, but we read the manga already.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna watch like five key episodes from Death Note and that's it.
Speaker 0: But we'll see how much time I have to watch it.
Speaker 0: The Kemo Nozomi whatever is kind of okay But we have to see where that goes and you have to wait for it to come out or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much the previous set of TV shows.
Speaker 1: We haven't watched yet.
Speaker 1: So we're not even looking at what's coming out now?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's nothing coming out now.
Speaker 0: We have to wait for a new season again.
Speaker 0: It'll be a few months and then there'll be more anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we'll catch up.
Speaker 0: Maybe we will catch up Maybe not who knows?
Speaker 1: of course catch up.
Speaker 1: We're also currently watching A standalone complex second gig finally.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I mean of all the newer anime, you know this came out in 2006. this is the thing to be most excited about.
Speaker 0: it's probably the best anime of the past year or two hands down.
Speaker 1: I'm real excited about this.
Speaker 1: I mean pretty much.
Speaker 1: Nana is what brought my favorite show.
Speaker 0: It's like I watch Nana, you know, and I like it and it's good, but I'm not excited about it.
Speaker 0: I'm not like oh Nana.
Speaker 0: I can't wait for more.
Speaker 0: This is like I need to have this now.
Speaker 0: Where is it?
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: I want to buy a DVD.
Speaker 0: here is $50.
Speaker 0: Where is it?
Speaker 0: You're dumb.
Speaker 0: Why did you not give it to me?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess what I could say just for mostly for the benefit of people who might be listening.
Speaker 1: I don't know months or years from now from the archives if you see project blue earth SOS in DVD form No matter what it costs.
Speaker 1: There is no reason not to buy it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if there's a Japanese if you speak Japanese you should just buy the region 2 DVD.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right now if you can play it, there's really no reason not to.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's the only hesitation I have is that we've only seen the first 45 minute episode.
Speaker 1: You're worried at my gonzo.
Speaker 0: Well, it does take a strong turn at the end of the first episode and I imagine that turn Leads into the plot of the remaining five episodes.
Speaker 0: So it could be that after it takes that turn the show is not as good.
Speaker 0: I highly doubt it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I mean it would be so hard to screw it up.
Speaker 1: Chevalier kind of did that course.
Speaker 1: I only saw two episodes, but Chevalier the first episode.
Speaker 1: I was so pumped about this show that had everything cool in the world in it.
Speaker 1: And then the second episode was like a rock falling into a well.
Speaker 0: No, that sucks.
Speaker 0: That sucks real bad.
Speaker 0: I didn't think it the Chevalier was that bad, but it definitely well, it's falling to a well.
Speaker 1: It didn't hit the bottom yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah for all I know it might recover.
Speaker 1: It might just be one bad episode.
Speaker 1: They might have just made the second episode Accidentally crappy.
Speaker 0: that is possible.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: anyway Project blue GQ.
Speaker 0: SOS is the awesome anime.
Speaker 0: You need to see it there.
Speaker 0: you know, I noticed that pretty much like the science fiction anime tends to be the awesome and also the animes that are based on Novels as opposed to manga tend to be pretty strong also.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's just because novels in Japan are more serious and we like more serious anime.
Speaker 0: You know in manga tends to be not always as serious.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a lot of serious mom.
Speaker 0: there is serious Mom doesn't get released in the US and it doesn't get turned into anime as often.
Speaker 1: God every time I go to Akino Kunia There's that wall of manga for me.
Speaker 1: It's nothing but Yakuza and politicians and more Yakuza.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's all in Japanese and no one translates it.
Speaker 1: Yep No one makes anime and I would I'd love to just learn Japanese to read it all.
Speaker 1: But I flipped through a couple of them and there's more kanji than I could ever learn in the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: I'm having enough trouble with Basic grammar here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, here's an awesome awesome science fiction anime appeals to all ages Kicks ass.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of fun a lot of colors High quality brand new and of course in closing take that Daryl Surratt.
Speaker 1: Where were you reviewing this show?
Speaker 0: The they probably either didn't know about it, which I doubt or They didn't see enough of it to talk about it, but they didn't even mention it at all.
Speaker 0: So what?
Speaker 0: maybe they haven't seen it Who knows?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We should have done this show a long time ago.
Speaker 0: We just I don't know why we It's like we saw it.
Speaker 0: We mentioned it on the forums because it was so good and then we just never did an episode.
Speaker 1: I guess I just assumed that we'd done an episode.
Speaker 0: I also did but I just started our website for the word project and I don't see anything that includes this up this show.
Speaker 1: but think about what that says.
Speaker 1: this show was so badass that we Imagine that we had done a show about it when in fact we had not.
Speaker 0: I guess it's cuz.
Speaker 0: we just talked it up so Much outside of the show.
Speaker 1: We basically did four or five shows about it to all of our friends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we talked about in the forums a lot.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 1: Yes, we did.
Speaker 0: All right, I think it's time to go to bed.
Speaker 0: We need some sleep.
Speaker 1: Yeah We've been a little tired tonight and last night due to the fact that we haven't slept pretty much at all since I don't know Last Friday, yeah, we're gonna do a show tomorrow and then next week we will resume doing awesome non-tired shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got a good bit lined up too.
Speaker 1: So be prepared.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.