Speaker 1: It's Thursday July 5th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: fire.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Man, this week is just swinging with anecdotes.
Speaker 0: I Ran a foul of a low-class person on my way home from work today.
Speaker 0: that ended mostly in hilarity and possibly also in police action.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I'm riding my bike, you know, I get off the train I get on my bike and I brought my bike back home.
Speaker 0: It takes like 10 minutes to ride my maybe 15 minutes if I'm not in a hurry.
Speaker 0: and while I'm riding I'm riding in the street like you do on a bike because it's actually illegal to ride bikes on the sidewalk here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's illegal to ride bikes on the sidewalk almost everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless you're a little kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm riding and This guy comes up behind me and he guns his engine.
Speaker 0: Alright, I have my hand out already because I'm signaling I'm about to turn left and I turn left and for some reason he suddenly like slams on his brakes And almost like spins out like yeah right behind me like yeah, uh-huh, and he almost hits me.
Speaker 0: So I say hey watch where you're going and I keep riding and then I hear some sort of Garbled scream from behind me as I'm riding.
Speaker 0: I hear the engine in.
Speaker 0: He bumps into the curb as he's trying to do a k-turn on this narrow two-lane road.
Speaker 0: He eventually turns around and proceeds to start chasing me in his car.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So, uh at this point I get up on the sidewalk on my bike and I keep going and he rolled out in his window And he keeps driving and the stream of profanity that is coming out of his mouth.
Speaker 0: Basically, he's yelling.
Speaker 0: fucking bicycle faggot fucking in my way fucking stop that bike.
Speaker 0: I'll kick your fucking ass Son of a fuck fuck fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a question.
Speaker 1: All right If you if there was if it was legal to have a concealed weapon in this state And you had all the necessary paperwork would have been legal to like shoot his tire or something?
Speaker 0: No, you can't just take a revenge.
Speaker 0: No unless if I could make a case that he was coming at me with the car.
Speaker 0: then Shooting the tire is the best non-lethal way of preventing them from killing me.
Speaker 1: Well, were there any witnesses?
Speaker 0: not yet.
Speaker 1: So you could have said he was coming at you with the car.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: No, it gets better.
Speaker 0: Okay So he starts yelling and yelling and I'm up on the curb and I stopped for a second and he stops and he Opens the door of his car to come and beat me up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, uh, I just started biking again and this 30 whatever year old guy the guy was in his mid 30s at least Obviously can't catch me.
Speaker 0: so he gets back in his car and starts chasing me and the whole time I realize now All right.
Speaker 0: This guy's gonna follow me.
Speaker 0: I wonder if he realizes that bikes can go places cars can't go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder if he's thought his clever plan all the way through.
Speaker 0: obviously not never mind the fact that I've already got his license plate.
Speaker 0: I took a picture of it with my cell cam.
Speaker 0: Ah, I took a picture of him with my cell cam and his car.
Speaker 0: I'm sitting there and I just start riding and he's following me the whole time yelling and screaming out the window and he keeps making like he gets ahead of me and then he stops to try to get out of his car and come fight With me and I just avoid him and keep biking and he's getting very very perturbed.
Speaker 0: So finally I just stopped and I hold my cell phone up and I say dude.
Speaker 0: I'm about to call 9-1-1.
Speaker 1: Yep, what do you say now here?
Speaker 0: This is the test.
Speaker 0: see this test for me was the test of.
Speaker 0: is this person stupid independent of all of his other problems?
Speaker 0: And he says that don't fucking matter.
Speaker 0: I know all the police and beacon.
Speaker 0: they won't lay a hand on me.
Speaker 0: come over here.
Speaker 0: I'll kick your faggot ass.
Speaker 1: Call the police and beacon now.
Speaker 0: I wasn't gonna call 9-1-1 yet.
Speaker 0: I was just gonna file a deposition later.
Speaker 0: I'm already dealing with the police aspect of this.
Speaker 0: cuz I already has license plate number.
Speaker 0: So I basically and I said, uh, I don't think that's gonna help you and I'm just I want to see how he reacts.
Speaker 0: Cuz there's nothing he can do to me.
Speaker 0: He can't get me.
Speaker 0: he obviously doesn't have a gun or anything because he's at the point where he already would have used it and I kind of want to see where this goes because
Speaker 1: I would have let him attack you and then kicked his ass cuz Self-defense I was and then the police would have come and wasn't
Speaker 0: really in the mood to get into a fight with someone plus remember No witnesses at this point.
Speaker 1: You got to go somewhere with his witnesses and then let him attack you.
Speaker 0: so I just keep riding and he's following me obviously Until I go to the ice cream shop or something following me home now.
Speaker 0: I cut around the other street.
Speaker 0: This is on for plank.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh So I just kind of keep going and I go onto our street and I go past our house.
Speaker 0: cuz I don't want to lead Him to my house.
Speaker 0: I'll get to why in a minute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Finally, there's a gas station.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of people filling up their gas.
Speaker 0: So I just stopped my bike there and he pulls up yelling and cursing and gets out Completely oblivious to all these people staring at him.
Speaker 0: and he's yelling and screaming at me.
Speaker 0: and every time he comes forward I just kind of backed my bike up a little bit because there's no way he could catch me.
Speaker 0: There's no way he could even close the distance and He keeps yelling.
Speaker 0: You're gonna disrespect me on my face You're gonna.
Speaker 0: you're gonna come get me.
Speaker 0: then he's yelling and yelling and yelling and I'm just sitting there and at this point One more time I say dude and this time I lied.
Speaker 0: I will admit I lied at this point.
Speaker 0: I said and I quote dude I already called the police.
Speaker 0: I've got your license plate number.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of people are watching you.
Speaker 0: What do you think you're gonna get away with?
Speaker 0: and he says I'll kick your ass.
Speaker 0: They can't lay a hand on me.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna kill you.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna go to jail.
Speaker 0: But but I'll kick your ass to which I say You know if you kick my ass, you'll go to jail, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's called assault.
Speaker 0: And as long as He's already committed assault.
Speaker 1: Well, I know.
Speaker 1: but like if when the police come they ask you they ask rim Do you want to press charges?
Speaker 1: and if you say yes, he goes to jail.
Speaker 0: so he's still freaking out.
Speaker 0: He's not backing down the threat of the police isn't scaring him at all.
Speaker 0: I'll get to why this is all relevant in the end because there is a lesson to be learned from all this.
Speaker 1: Don't be stupid.
Speaker 0: So at this point because I don't care anymore.
Speaker 0: I just started laughing Openly and loudly and he gets so like the fury in his eyes is palpable You can feel it.
Speaker 0: and he keeps taking a step forward like yeah, like he's gonna come get me but I'm on a bike and he can't come get me.
Speaker 0: and Eventually, I just keep laughing at him and I just keep laughing and laughing and laughing and eventually gets back in his car And yells.
Speaker 0: if you weren't such a pussy fucking faggot, maybe you would have stood up to me like a man Uh-huh to which I said and I said something about.
Speaker 0: basically I implied that maybe I am homosexual and maybe I find you attractive And then he drove away.
Speaker 0: I took one more picture of his car yeah, and then I stood there and there's all these people standing around at the gas station looking like what the hell and One of them's like.
Speaker 0: do you actually call the police?
Speaker 0: and I'm like nah Okay The police know I already filed a police report.
Speaker 1: All right, and I think you rode your bike to the police station And no, I just called him.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna give him a full deposition called the non 9-1-1 police.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what is the?
Speaker 0: Looked it up again.
Speaker 0: I got it myself.
Speaker 0: I had it my old cell phone.
Speaker 0: Remember when we saw that guy cutting up?
Speaker 1: we really need one of those like seven one ones in New York.
Speaker 1: So, you know that we can call when we don't need nine one one, but we need some police.
Speaker 0: Well, I just put the local police for like beacon and fish kill in my cell phone and everyone else I would have rode all the way to the fish kill police station and just like stood there be like, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the fish kill one's nice.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of cops there.
Speaker 1: Apparently the fish kill police station is the envy of all the other police station.
Speaker 0: I wonder why.
Speaker 0: fish kill is a relatively small town.
Speaker 0: It's not a city like beacon It's just a town and it is my impression now my impression.
Speaker 0: This is not a fact because I have not researched it.
Speaker 1: However, I research it.
Speaker 1: I read a newspaper article about it.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: I get the impression It is my opinion that possibly the reason fish kill has one of the best police Buildings and the finest police forces with the best cars and the most money pretty much in the tri-county area here might have something to do with the fact that fish kills a big town on one side of the street called route 9 and then there's a little bit of fish kill on the other side of route 9 and I think that the city of fish get.
Speaker 0: well the town of fish kill Writes more tickets on that tiny stretch of route 9 over which they have control.
Speaker 0: then could possibly be reasonable.
Speaker 0: That's my guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's where they get their money.
Speaker 1: But the fish kill police department is probably the largest Municipal building in this area outside of the actual city of Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 1: It's bigger than any town hall of any of these towns.
Speaker 0: It's bigger than beacons police department City Hall combined.
Speaker 1: Yep It's got like a gym and all sorts of stuff in there.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 0: They have more.
Speaker 0: they have so many police cars.
Speaker 1: It's kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Lesson number one and I think I mentioned this back when I explained how to Not that I recommend it run away from the police and the answer was pretty much be on a bicycle.
Speaker 0: This applies even more so to non police.
Speaker 0: if you're on a bicycle There is almost no way that any human being who is not also on a bicycle can cause harm to you if you're smart Because bikes can go where cars can't go.
Speaker 0: bikes can turn quicker bikes can go faster than anyone can run for longer.
Speaker 1: A bicycle is the most efficient means of transportation.
Speaker 1: Period.
Speaker 0: well that is in short bursts to get away from an attacker.
Speaker 1: well I know but in general it also is the most of it.
Speaker 1: a geared bicycle is the most efficient means of transportation in terms of energy per going and So it's really tough for anyone to beat you as long unless their bike is better than yours and their own land.
Speaker 0: I've learned something else too.
Speaker 0: Generally, if someone is a costing you odds are they're not in the best shape and they're definitely not a biker.
Speaker 1: That's also probably true.
Speaker 1: They could be some asshole biker.
Speaker 0: Yeah But an asshole biker is usually the kind of guy who kicks the in like the door of an SUV when they cut him off Or something.
Speaker 0: those aren't the people who will chase another biker down and try to kick his pussy faggot ass, huh?
Speaker 0: Moral number two and this is the reason why while I'm filing a police report I am not going to press charges.
Speaker 0: and I learned this because I lived in Detroit for a long time and I lived in New Baltimore which is a nice town, but there was also a lot of Shall we say trashy people and then I lived in a really nice area and I've moved around a lot.
Speaker 0: But whenever you are involved in any sort of altercation with someone who is now this is an ant they have to be both very poor and Very stupid.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Oh one of these factors alone is not enough but if both of these are true unless you have a good reason to you don't want to get involved no matter what because if someone is poor and Stupid let's take the example of this gentleman.
Speaker 0: He's obviously poor.
Speaker 0: It was a pretty crappy car.
Speaker 0: He was wearing this battered white shirt with sweat stains on it.
Speaker 0: He didn't look like the most well-off guy Mm-hmm and his addiction manner of speech the vocabulary he used.
Speaker 0: I have a pretty good picture of his the social class in which he lies Mm-hmm, so he doesn't have much to lose.
Speaker 0: There's not much you can do to him.
Speaker 1: besides if you're not gonna get jailed and what are you gonna get?
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get money from suing him.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get damages or anything.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much jail for him or no jail for him.
Speaker 0: more importantly He is stupid.
Speaker 0: notice how despite the fact that I could have called the police and that there were multiple witnesses Watching this exchange.
Speaker 0: He still continued to escalate the situation Obviously either not caring or unaware of the possible consequences of attacking a person in broad daylight with a video camera a cell cam and several Witnesses.
Speaker 1: if the police are on their way I'm sure the gas station also had some security cam.
Speaker 0: That's what I actually.
Speaker 0: I made a point of being right where the camera was pointed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, you can never tell those little black domes.
Speaker 1: They could be looking at.
Speaker 0: it's not a black dome It's just a camera.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so obvious now.
Speaker 0: people like this because I have many anecdotes from my childhood where someone would you know call the police on a poor and stupid person in town and The poor and stupid person having nothing to lose and not being afraid of the ramifications would often retaliate.
Speaker 0: They'll do things like figure out where someone live and then Key their car up one night in the middle of the night or egg their house or let the air out of their tires or smash The windows or stalk them or things like that.
Speaker 0: get their friends to attack them in an alley one night.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm poor people who are also stupid are not afraid of the consequences of their actions partly because they seem to be ignorant of the Consequences of their actions or they have nothing to lose.
Speaker 0: So I'm so your best bet when dealing with the situation like I've described where you're in no danger is not to press charges But to simply file a police report.
Speaker 0: that way it's on file And if you ever run afoul of them again And they cause trouble You've already got it on record that they've accosted you before and now the book will get thrown at him twice as hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah Still it kind of makes you realize You know as much as we look down upon police brutality and not about to change that opinion that is one You know.
Speaker 1: poor stupid people have nothing to lose.
Speaker 1: One thing they have to lose is getting the shit beat out of them.
Speaker 1: You know, that's sometimes, you know, I mean putting him in jail.
Speaker 1: they don't care, you know, they probably care.
Speaker 0: The problem is they don't expect that they'll actually go to jail.
Speaker 0: The guy kept going on and on while he was yelling about how he knows all the police in this town and they won't lay A hand on it.
Speaker 1: So you should have gone to fish kill.
Speaker 1: Yeah been like we're a fish kill now.
Speaker 0: Well, actually no cuz.
Speaker 0: when he said that I was like, ah, dude I called 9-1-1. the state troopers are coming not the local police.
Speaker 0: And he stopped for a second and he just ignored that and said it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I know them too.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I'm sure dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure Yeah, so when running afoul of people who are both plus I'm sure if you know Even if I was Fred like a fireman and I was friends all of the cops.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they wouldn't, you know, put me in jail if I beat someone up.
Speaker 0: I also note that I will admit I got quite a bit of enjoyment out of this and I probably could have just gotten away Quicker, but I kind of wanted to see what he would do.
Speaker 0: So I just kept laughing at him and he just kept getting more angry Yeah, and I wish I could have had a video of it.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should go ask the gas station guy if he'll give it to me.
Speaker 1: This is actually a lot more fun.
Speaker 1: if it happens in like New York City or something Right, cuz like the police will already be there kicking his ass.
Speaker 0: Well, not only not only that but
Speaker 1: you know If you're walking down the street and like someone starts something like let's say someone tries to mug you or take your wallet or something Right, and there's actually other people around who are not accomplices of them About half those people are gonna help you out and there's gonna be basically a huge beatdown of like five on one.
Speaker 0: It's like when you were there and that purse snatcher tried to grab them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was walking to work.
Speaker 1: I think we talked to me talk about this on the show years ago.
Speaker 1: We can tell it briefly a long time ago like a year two years more than two years ago When I worked in the different part of the city at the old job.
Speaker 1: I was walking to work one day from Grand Central to the work and I passed well.
Speaker 1: walking by the Think the south side of Bryant Park and on the other side of the street I hear a scream and I see some guy trying to grab a giant purse from this lady.
Speaker 0: I don't get those giant purses.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't get it either.
Speaker 1: What are you carrying?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but he grabs it and he starts to run and he gets about two parking spaces away and I'm like, huh and then I'm gonna go run across the street and Meanwhile three other guys on the other side of the street already grabbed him and beat him up.
Speaker 0: Basically a crowd of like all the people who got there after he was beat up or like.
Speaker 0: is it under control?
Speaker 0: you got him You got him like everyone in New York City will just jump on something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah And then a one policeman shows up and puts handcuffs on him and they make sure the guy doesn't get up like stands on him Or something, I guess I don't know.
Speaker 1: and then everyone stands around while he writes a report.
Speaker 1: Then I go to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that was my day.
Speaker 0: yep, so I in the news.
Speaker 0: So, you know Godwin Mike Godwin as in Godwin's law exactly what Godwin's law Which most people don't understand or misquote, but I'm not gonna get into that.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get into it.
Speaker 1: you are Yes, so let me tell you the story about Steve Godwin in some.
Speaker 1: Mike Godwin in summary receive Godwin.
Speaker 1: Yes, Mike Godwin First of all, he was.
Speaker 1: he's a lawyer, right?
Speaker 1: He's a. he's sort of a counsel I don't know.
Speaker 1: a counsel is a different kind of lawyer, whatever.
Speaker 1: I'm sure all of our lawyer listeners will know he was the lawyer for Steve Jackson in the Steve Jackson versus United States Secret Service case.
Speaker 1: Oh and Steve Jackson one.
Speaker 0: Uh, I just like to note that if any of you are unfamiliar with that court case You should look it up.
Speaker 0: Anytime you think that our government the United States government is capable
Speaker 1: of an intelligent conspiracy
Speaker 0: yeah, if any time you think that the government is evil and Conspiring to do evil things and like the secret government the shadow, whatever That story will remind you very quickly that it is probably not the case.
Speaker 1: Yep, he then became a lawyer for the electronic frontier foundation, which is awesome.
Speaker 1: They're the people who have a bunch of lawyers who are fighting to you know Get rid of all these stupid laws like the DMCA actually legal wiretapping.
Speaker 1: they were
Speaker 0: largely behind the blue ribbon campaign, which is a part of internet history now, but Basically back when the internet started really taking off in the mid 90s The idea of freedom of speech on the internet was sharply contested in the United States and there was a large Campaign to make sure that we had freedom of speech there.
Speaker 1: Yep, the EFF's major contribution has been that they got they won the case that lets us all use very powerful encryption.
Speaker 1: He also wrote a bunch of books and the character Mike Godwin that a difference engine is named after Godwin.
Speaker 0: Yep, that was the Zimmerman case.
Speaker 0: right the encryption thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: I don't remember exactly I don't remember offhand.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then Alright, so then he came up with Godwin's law Which is and I state ahem as an online discussion grows longer the probability of a comparison involving Nazis or Hitler Approaches one that is Godwin's law.
Speaker 1: and he came up with it.
Speaker 1: note.
Speaker 0: It does not say anyone loses an argument.
Speaker 0: It just says that Hitler's gonna come up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's all it says.
Speaker 1: So this guy who is involved with Steve Jackson games the EFF and he made up Godwin's law.
Speaker 1: cuz he's fucking.
Speaker 1: Michael Godwin Did all these amazing things and he's like an uber geek person.
Speaker 1: He's a person that's very important geek.
Speaker 1: You should know about him and he's still alive and still awesome.
Speaker 1: Well, he just changed jobs.
Speaker 1: You know what he is now.
Speaker 0: What is he now?
Speaker 1: He's general counsel for the Wikipedia Hot day.
Speaker 1: So if the Wikipedia gets in trouble Mike Godwin is gonna be the one to help him out.
Speaker 0: The Wikipedia is also known among possibly the rest of the world as Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: yes, that's right.
Speaker 1: It's an inside joke in my work.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah He is the general counsel for the Wikimedia Foundation.
Speaker 1: Talk about a guy who's like done every.
Speaker 1: he'd been in every sector of geekdom as someone awesome.
Speaker 0: He's a minor hero of mine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Mike Godwin, you should know about him.
Speaker 1: He's awesome, right?
Speaker 0: So the 4th of July Independence Day in the United States went by.
Speaker 0: it's part of the reason we had a special yesterday.
Speaker 0: also to all of you who are relatively new I would like to Teach you about some of the code words we use on geek nights.
Speaker 0: You see whenever we call a show a special episode that is code word for and I quote Raymond Scott are too lazy to do an actual show.
Speaker 0: So they're just gonna record something and put it up and call it special.
Speaker 1: That's exactly right Hahaha.
Speaker 0: but anyway apparently the state of Minnesota there is a law that they want to pass.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's passed yet or what.
Speaker 0: I read this article very skim ishly.
Speaker 0: Basically, they want to make it illegal to sell flags American flags within the state that were not produced in the United States Punishable by up to a thousand dollar fine and 90 days in jail.
Speaker 0: No, no, no Or anything.
Speaker 0: I would like to point out that that is in violation of a great many international trade treaties.
Speaker 1: well I was gonna say it's in violation of the Constitution of the United States of America because if it's a flag from another country then it's interstate commerce and thus the federal government has Purvey over that.
Speaker 1: I guess not mistake.
Speaker 0: I guess they could.
Speaker 0: they could make the argument I guess that because it they don't want them to be sold within the state.
Speaker 0: So they're not interacting with the feds because it can come in the borders.
Speaker 0: You just can't be sold.
Speaker 1: I guess I could order one from another state.
Speaker 1: Then what are they gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: I'll order a thousand of them from oriental trading company.
Speaker 0: See now, uh, I just want to point out that Minnesota Loses a little bit of the respect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Minnesota never had much of the respect any.
Speaker 1: I mean, what the hell does that state have now?
Speaker 0: I've seen that there are a lot of other states that have similar laws.
Speaker 0: However on further investigation, it looks like most of those laws Don't say you can't sell Nondomestically produced flags in the state.
Speaker 0: They say these states cannot buy Nondomestically produced which is very different.
Speaker 0: No, that's it.
Speaker 1: You can you can have a law like that.
Speaker 1: I'm that's a law that says this is how the state will spend its taxpayer money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is there's nothing wrong with that kind of law.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with that, but I just can't believe that then in this day and age this sort of jingoist restrictive trade bullshit still happens.
Speaker 0: I mean Globalization works only if it's actually global and it's actually free.
Speaker 1: Yeah a lot It's a people always complain.
Speaker 1: you see all those people protesting the World Trade Organization and stuff And they're kind of right in the kind of wrong.
Speaker 1: The problem here is that the World Trade Organization wants.
Speaker 1: quote free trade, right?
Speaker 1: Free trade on paper means that anyone in the entire world right can trade Absolutely freely with anyone else in the entire world.
Speaker 1: I can engage in commerce with a Chinese guy and not have to pay any government's extra money.
Speaker 1: It'll just be money goes from me to the Chinese guy and goods come from him to me or vice versa And no one gets in the way except of course you have to pay for someone to ship it, but that's it.
Speaker 1: That's what free trade means is.
Speaker 1: anyone can do business with anyone perfectly openly with no interference Of course, as long as you're not doing illegal business Like I don't know buying guns or bombs or anything like that.
Speaker 1: The problem is is that the World Trade Organization actually?
Speaker 1: fights so that big companies and federal governments can trade freely but individual people Cannot and thus it won't work if you do that.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is it's a little more complicated.
Speaker 1: it is.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to keep it simple here.
Speaker 1: I can not let her episode.
Speaker 0: I can sum it up much more simply.
Speaker 0: the majority of the people Protesting the WTO or the World Bank or all those things have no idea what those organizations even do and they're just dirty hippies For some reason have jumped on the ravel bandwagon.
Speaker 1: Thanks for saying what I was thinking.
Speaker 0: I've talked to these people.
Speaker 0: I've read what they wrote on the internet unless they're anarcho primitivists.
Speaker 1: Uh, you mean like the Unabomber?
Speaker 0: Yeah No, no, cuz he was actually he.
Speaker 0: while he was a crazy nut at least he was not an anarcho primitivist.
Speaker 0: He went all the way with his anarcho primitivism.
Speaker 0: Okay, it was Emily who knew someone who met a guy who claimed to be an anarcho primitivist.
Speaker 0: So we basically.
Speaker 0: what that meant was he didn't have any furniture in his dorm room except for his laptop where he Yeah, he would go on forums and talk about anarcho primitivism something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I've tried to talk to these people before and they don't even know what the or what these acronyms stand for.
Speaker 1: These people are idiots Yeah, but anyway free trade is good as long as everyone gets free trade.
Speaker 1: and it's funny How we have a federal government fighting for free trade while some of the states are doing the exact opposite.
Speaker 0: Well, it's just BS jingoism and hopefully I'm.
Speaker 0: there's a possibility that this bill was just put forth by some guy.
Speaker 0: He wants to rabble rouse the jingoism.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean state legislatures aren't full of you know, all awesome people, you know You don't have to be some great Legislator to get on to the state, you know, you can simplify that regular expression and just define something legislators.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I could.
Speaker 0: Things of the day, you know Scott I got to say off Billy Jean, she's not my lover She's just the girl.
Speaker 0: said that I'm the one but kids not my son Uh-huh, so apparently well not apparently I just I found a video of it.
Speaker 0: So I want to share this with all of you.
Speaker 0: Michael Jackson first performed his classic trademark moonwalk in 1983 on a television special called Motown 25 Yesterday today forever and here's a video of it and all I got to say one the moonwalks.
Speaker 0: awesome, too.
Speaker 0: I'm glad that I can see the first time it happened.
Speaker 0: and three.
Speaker 1: Michael Jackson was so cool back then and now he's the exact opposite.
Speaker 1: How the fuck does that happen?
Speaker 0: I mean when I was a kid, I was a huge fan of Michael Jackson.
Speaker 0: I got to say now that I'm it's kind of like with MC hammer.
Speaker 0: now that I'm older and It's in the past and I go back and watch this dancing in the singing I'm so much more impressed by it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess when I was a kid I just didn't appreciate awesome dancing, even though I still liked MC hammer and Michael Jackson as a kid I didn't really appreciate their talents or former talents.
Speaker 1: And now I go back and look at it again and unlike he-man which now looks like crap don't watch he-man.
Speaker 1: I look back at Michael Jackson MC hammer and other.
Speaker 1: you know Things I enjoyed as a kid and some of them are more awesome now than they used to be.
Speaker 1: of course Some of the people are less awesome now than they used to be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but seriously Michael Jackson was awesome was Yeah was if only he hadn't gone crazy.
Speaker 1: How does this happen?
Speaker 1: I mean like look at us.
Speaker 1: We're kind of cool We're not famous, but we're internet famous.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I definitely think we crossed the line of internet fame, right?
Speaker 1: How could we possibly?
Speaker 1: Become like that like how could we take a downturn like that?
Speaker 1: I just don't see a possible Path.
Speaker 1: I could go down where that would be the end up like that.
Speaker 0: Well part of it might be that we weren't child stars.
Speaker 0: We weren't internet famous before we could handle being internet famous.
Speaker 1: I guess that is significant factor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also the fact that there was a lot of pressure on kid Michael Jackson And he was you know pretty much the biggest pop star in the world.
Speaker 1: I mean like what about kid Tiger Woods?
Speaker 1: He's alright.
Speaker 0: He doesn't have a problem now I guess I mean it also depends on the person the family all those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I do agree.
Speaker 0: I can't see us going crazy and mad with power.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean next year when geek nights has a hundred thousand listeners.
Speaker 0: I Don't see my life changing.
Speaker 0: Anyway anyway.
Speaker 1: so This moonwalk that Michael Jackson did did he invent it?
Speaker 0: well?
Speaker 0: You see there's a lot of information about this.
Speaker 0: if you really want to go read the Wikipedia Now I cuz I actually didn't know that Part of it was based on some of the things that Marcel Marcel used to do back in the 50s.
Speaker 0: If you don't know who that is get off my podcast Yep.
Speaker 0: But as far as I can see and this is also on YouTube the first moonwalk was before that was videotaped Was performed by well?
Speaker 0: I'll just let Scott take it from here because it's a thing of the day is my thing today.
Speaker 1: so in 1955 there was a tap dancing guy, and he was an awesome tap dancing guy, and you know I like some old-style dancing.
Speaker 1: I've done old-style dancing things of the day before and this is a guy named Bill Bailey.
Speaker 0: dude Scott.
Speaker 0: I'll randomly watch the Charleston while we're waiting to do that.
Speaker 1: one of my favorite things to do is that People doing the Charleston is just so awesome.
Speaker 1: Why don't we?
Speaker 1: I just look on YouTube to find people doing the Charleston all the time.
Speaker 0: Why don't we do the Charleston?
Speaker 1: It's hard.
Speaker 0: Let's learn it.
Speaker 1: We have to learn other dances first.
Speaker 1: No not like the Haruhi Susan me dance.
Speaker 0: so which one should we learn first?
Speaker 0: that or the Charleston?
Speaker 1: we have to learn like Basic dance moves that you know you like fundamental parts that we can add together into the Charleston.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just Napoleon dynamite it?
Speaker 0: Let's just get every music video Michael Jackson ever did and learn the poppin lock straight up Cuz.
Speaker 1: then we're only gonna be able to do that one dance.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: If we learn ever.
Speaker 1: if we learn the parts of dances Then we can recombine them later to construct new dances Sort of like learning to fish rather than being given a fish kind of like when you're playing DDR.
Speaker 0: I mean you might be able to do the up left down left combo and the up right down left combo But if you can combine the two without screwing it up.
Speaker 1: yep, so anyway this tap dancing.
Speaker 1: Bill Bailey regardless of anything else You should watch this because awesome old tap dancing can't be beat, but at the end of this video.
Speaker 1: He moonwalks oh my god 1955 there's a dude moonwalking after he's done tap dancing.
Speaker 0: I don't doubt that Michael Jackson saw that video.
Speaker 1: I also do not doubt that he saw that video lightning.
Speaker 0: huh, maybe we should get the show short.
Speaker 1: no That's all right.
Speaker 0: well the power did go out earlier.
Speaker 0: luckily We have.
Speaker 0: we have UPS's.
Speaker 0: we have four UPS's.
Speaker 1: see if the power goes out You just go save and then exit and turn the computer off.
Speaker 0: yep actually We could still upload the show even if the power was out.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah We could send it over to my computer.
Speaker 0: well our network equipment is all on the UPS in addition to all our computers.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you if you sent it over to my laptop really quickly my laptop on its battery power could connect to the wireless router And then we could upload the show.
Speaker 0: yep Now listening to that song I'm sure you could guess as what we're talking about tonight Even though it could be any number of things.
Speaker 0: perhaps We're talking about that style of music perhaps.
Speaker 0: We're talking about that song, but now we're talking about the subject of that song.
Speaker 0: Tonight we are beginning a long-running series on perhaps Scott's favorite thing in the world some of my favorite thing in the world.
Speaker 0: It's it's probably your second most said word yeah, but that doesn't mean it's my favorite thing.
Speaker 1: Just cuz I say something a lot doesn't mean it's my favorite.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: so you saying Scott that the topic of our show is not your favorite thing.
Speaker 1: No, it's not my favorite thing.
Speaker 0: is it in the top three?
Speaker 0: probably okay?
Speaker 0: Tonight we're gonna talk about fire.
Speaker 0: we entitle this episode fire part one.
Speaker 0: oh I figured you'd take it away from there Scott captain fire.
Speaker 1: Oh Anyway fire is pretty goddamn awesome.
Speaker 1: You get you.
Speaker 1: just if you start a fire you get light you get heat you get danger You get a weapon you get a tool.
Speaker 1: It's kind of hard to beat fire.
Speaker 1: even cavemen knew that much.
Speaker 1: the thing is actually that Most animals at least on earth seem to be afraid of fire Which you think is good because fire hurts if you touch it.
Speaker 1: you know if you like light a fire Not to.
Speaker 1: most animals are gonna run away from the fire.
Speaker 1: if you have a campfire near your camp.
Speaker 1: It's a good way to keep away bears and raccoons and things from eating you in your sleep.
Speaker 1: Humans aren't so afraid of fire.
Speaker 1: I mean some of them are but some humans are pyromaniacs.
Speaker 1: They love fire.
Speaker 1: They like they set themselves on fire even now.
Speaker 0: I do note that there's no pyromaniac chickens.
Speaker 1: No no there aren't.
Speaker 0: so Maybe there are yes, and they're just really unfulfilled now.
Speaker 1: I don't know if there's any evidences or studies or things for this or anthropologies or whatever, but I am pretty confident that the pyromaniac nature of some human beings was a Significant contributing factor to the advancement of human civilization.
Speaker 1: the fact that you there is at least some humans who were not afraid of fire And we're curious about fire and thus investigated it and learned to take advantage of it is Why we are here today with computers and clothing and cars and everything else.
Speaker 1: fire is just that important I?
Speaker 0: Think there's actually a little bit more to it than that.
Speaker 0: you think there's more to it.
Speaker 0: I would actually go forward to say that it's not fire in general.
Speaker 0: It's just danger.
Speaker 0: I mean think of the.
Speaker 0: anytime there's a natural disaster something horrible crazy happens.
Speaker 0: something weird happens.
Speaker 0: something dangerous happens While many people flee.
Speaker 0: I note that whenever something like that happens pretty much Universally animals avoid it.
Speaker 0: whenever there is something strange Animals avoid it, but humans tend to be drawn to it for better or for worse.
Speaker 0: yes In fact I would.
Speaker 0: I would point out that I would say it's more often for worse than for better.
Speaker 0: Yes, but for every thousand humans who died in a fire I think what it is is in the short term right.
Speaker 1: it is worse because people are going into crazy dangerous situations.
Speaker 1: Oh for the individual yes for the long term and for the entire species of human beings I think it has been better.
Speaker 1: it might not be better now.
Speaker 0: But for every thousand humans who died in a fire one of them cooked some meat or made some metal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well made metal.
Speaker 1: You don't make metal you Smith it well.
Speaker 0: No, no some fire could have ended up causing some metal to melt out of a rock or something or invented eternal combustion Or something like that.
Speaker 0: Maybe external combustion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or spontaneous human combustion Which is fake?
Speaker 0: Just got to get that out there.
Speaker 1: I thought it happened at least.
Speaker 1: no never.
Speaker 0: no It's never been documented.
Speaker 0: at every single time someone who's claimed spontaneous human combustion.
Speaker 0: The odds were that the person was a smoker living alone and died in their bed, huh?
Speaker 1: I thought I heard a story that like someone was sitting in a chair, and then they were dust on the chair.
Speaker 1: Nothing else was burned.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that can happen.
Speaker 0: There's a clear physical process for that happening.
Speaker 1: Oh, so what is it?
Speaker 0: It has to do with the fact that there's fat in the body.
Speaker 0: you basically burn like a wick and a super hot fire will Form right there, but due to the nature of that kind of fire it won't burn anything else.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's pretty interesting, so I guess let's see that's the phenomena I had heard about and that's why I assumed in spontaneous human combustion was real.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, no I guess it's just that phenomena and that phenomenon can happen But it's not spontaneous.
Speaker 0: most of those people either dropped a match on themselves or were smoking in bed or had an oxygen tank Or there was an electrical fire, and they were too old to wake up.
Speaker 1: all right all right Yeah, but there can be spontaneous non-human combustion.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, like if you have a stack of old dry magazines That's really tall in a bad place.
Speaker 0: Yep, or latex gloves with baking soda on them Yeah, that could do it, too.
Speaker 1: So watch out for that.
Speaker 1: or do it on purpose in a safe place or you know what.
Speaker 0: if you're in an old house It's not a good idea to go to an old light switch.
Speaker 0: Just flick it on and off a bunch of times as fast as you can.
Speaker 0: That's not the best idea.
Speaker 1: No, I guess not.
Speaker 0: so uh or if your fuse is gone You know the fuse fell out or the fuse is busted.
Speaker 0: you don't have a new fuse even though I've only lived in one house that had fuses in my life, so I own one fuse that in my bag of electrical stuff.
Speaker 0: but I Fuses aren't used in houses anymore.
Speaker 0: if you have a house that has a fuse and the fuse burns out And you don't have a replacement fuse Don't put a quarter in the fuse box or or a penny or a wire or a bullet a Bullet.
Speaker 0: remember that apocryphal tale of the bullet replacing the fuse in the car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not good.
Speaker 0: Louis black tells the story like it's true.
Speaker 1: It's not Yeah, a lot of people tell stories like the true that they're not.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we should do a show on that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, why don't we tell some humorous fire anecdotes?
Speaker 0: Well get the show over with I often as a kid like to set things on fire, but I was not a pyromaniac.
Speaker 1: Well, I also like to set things on fire and I like to play with fire.
Speaker 1: But I knew it was dangerous and I was slightly more afraid of getting hurt than I was willing to play with the fire.
Speaker 1: And also my parents are pretty strict about not letting me play with fire.
Speaker 1: So it was a rare opportunity I got to do dangerous fiery things.
Speaker 0: See I was completely the opposite.
Speaker 0: I wasn't afraid at all.
Speaker 0: I had a fresno lens.
Speaker 0: I melted asphalt with it.
Speaker 0: I set leaves on fire.
Speaker 0: I've set fireworks on fire with the fresno lens.
Speaker 0: In fact, I am very lucky that I have all of my fingers because I was drawn to fireworks much like moth to the flame.
Speaker 1: Yeah fireworks are illegal in Connecticut and you know some people around bought them and used them but my parents did not.
Speaker 1: So I was stuck, you know looking out my window at night at the people across the street with their fireworks, dude I was the kid having Roman candle fights with his friends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, shoot bottle rockets at each other.
Speaker 0: We tie army men to bottle rockets that at all their bottle rockets tied to them.
Speaker 0: one time We took one of those popper, you know, the little snapper throwers and we emptied out Oh, I had the snappers all the time.
Speaker 0: We emptied out the contents of like four bags of them into one gigantic thing.
Speaker 1: It's hard to do that because they'll snap when you try to open them up.
Speaker 1: There's like a little rock in there And yeah, we were real careful.
Speaker 0: It took a long time.
Speaker 1: It's really hard.
Speaker 1: That's why they're filled with sawdust is to keep them from snapping.
Speaker 0: a bunch of them went off and a few of us got hurt.
Speaker 0: But we did it and let me tell you it worked.
Speaker 0: That's all I'm gonna say.
Speaker 1: it sure does work I can.
Speaker 1: we've combined many of them into one before.
Speaker 0: our favorite thing to do where there's this one kind of firework that nominally it would shoot up into the air with wings and fire really really high and Coast for a while with different colors and then explode.
Speaker 0: so we'd tie like three of them together and then we'd have a fuse that would eventually light all three and we'd set that off and The basically what would happen was it go up into the air and then about halfway up It would suddenly change direction
Speaker 1: and the
Speaker 0: odds were that would come straight for you Pretty much without fail.
Speaker 0: It would come straight for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah even nowadays You know where I'm allowed to play with fire and I could play with fire pretty much whenever I want and I don't really care About playing with fire and I have things to play with fire.
Speaker 1: I'm still kind of afraid of actually more afraid of getting hurt with fire than I ever was.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'll know that I'm not - I don't I can't blame you because fireworks are dangerous.
Speaker 0: But you were you pull you had the method of hold the match.
Speaker 0: hold the match as soon as you think the fuse went.
Speaker 0: You were already across the street.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean cuz you know all I think about is I Imagine myself like standing right in front of a bottle rocket that's lit and just standing there not moving I've done and then it firing into me and I hit my bottle rockets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I imagine what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: and I imagine like that little tiny stick like going right through my body and then exploding and like Blowing my head off and I don't want that to happen.
Speaker 0: See ya the answer is maybe it's just cuz I've been hit by fireworks a lot.
Speaker 0: But when you shoot a firework like that like a bottle rocket.
Speaker 0: Unless it hits you in the eye the odds of serious injury are pretty low.
Speaker 1: I'm just kind of afraid of injury.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not afraid of fire.
Speaker 1: Like if this just a fire is sitting there.
Speaker 1: I'm like, ooh, and I'll play with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'll always throw stuff into it.
Speaker 0: Yep, but like those little UFOs we were shooting off It's impossible for those to hurt you even if they just went straight for your face.
Speaker 0: Maybe there you're pretty much fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah Granted much of my non-fear fireworks has to do with being incredibly lucky and not having been hit by them in a dangerous way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what other ways that I have fun with fire besides.
Speaker 0: my primary fear and the reason we didn't shoot for so many fireworks Off wasn't police.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wasn't afraid of getting burned.
Speaker 0: I was afraid of the police busting me.
Speaker 1: I wonder what the penalty is for fireworks in New York.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: as a kid I wasn't afraid of the police with fireworks because I'm a kid.
Speaker 0: I'm invincible as far as I can see.
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 1: a fine a jail?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's probably a fine and they take away all your fireworks.
Speaker 1: Oh, I wonder how much the fine is cuz I'd be willing to pay the fine if it wasn't so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is then they take away all your fireworks and I'm sure that's why you got to set them all off and Then pay the fine.
Speaker 0: I'm sure the fine is greater if you get caught again.
Speaker 1: Well, no, you set them all off before they catch you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is they come pretty set them all up at once with one giant fuse.
Speaker 0: I Got a story about that, but I'll save it for another time.
Speaker 0: That's special.
Speaker 0: So we have anything else.
Speaker 0: or is this gonna turn into that one episode of twit?
Speaker 1: No, I could talk about all like.
Speaker 1: I've done a lot.
Speaker 1: I remember at summer camp We not just fire but we also like threw sodium in the lake.
Speaker 1: That was a lot of fun.
Speaker 1: But we I remember the one thing we did at summer camp is the summer camp was this very science II summer camp full of.
Speaker 1: We had a chemistry lab and Basically, the chemistry lab meant turn on the Bunsen burner and throw stuff into it and see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah And I remember if you would threw all the different things in there to get all the different colors like if you threw iron Filings into it you would get these sparks.
Speaker 1: and if you threw like this other powder into it get it would turn green and That's how I learned how fireworks worked.
Speaker 1: if you like take green stuff and iron Filings and you put them near a fire with some gunpowder, whatever.
Speaker 1: you would make a firework that had sparks and green and It was really fun.
Speaker 0: I love stuff like that.
Speaker 0: I always wanted to make fireworks as a kid, but my fireman dad dissuaded me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he explained how dangerous it is to make fireworks real dangerous.
Speaker 1: Another thing we did at summer camp is we we were going to.
Speaker 1: you know You make a campfire every week and you know You hold some hot dogs on a stick over it and then you eat him.
Speaker 1: Right if you took the plastic bag that had the hot dog buns, you know, well that previously contained hot dog buns.
Speaker 0: You don't throw that in the fire you don't throw it in the fire.
Speaker 1: That's dangerous releases poison gas if you hold it above the fire.
Speaker 1: enough above the fire that it won't burn Like, you know poison gas but enough above the fire that it will be heated up and warmed so that it will melt.
Speaker 1: when the drips of plastic fall into the fire one at a time they go.
Speaker 0: Well, I think You win the fire Contest here because while I know about fireworks, I never thought of that.
Speaker 1: I didn't think of it either.
Speaker 1: the can't the counselor who knew how to do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I didn't play much with fire itself other than actually One of my favorite pastimes as a kid and part of this came out of the fact that my dad was a fireman in Detroit.
Speaker 0: We lived there in the 80s.
Speaker 0: If you don't know much about the city of Detroit.
Speaker 0: I suggest you read about something called Devil's Knights But devil's night is sort of universal then no now Detroit devil's night is not like it is anywhere else.
Speaker 0: All right, it's better now, but back in the day the city fucking burned to the ground every year.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh It was bad.
Speaker 0: We're talking fire bombs and houses Say Michigan cultural phenomenon.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I know my shit when it comes to Michigan.
Speaker 0: All right, don't you?
Speaker 0: don't you be treading?
Speaker 1: Decline of devil's night arson.
Speaker 0: Michigan's the only state as far as I know that is declared war both on a foreign nation and on another state.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: my dad was a fireman So when he was off-duty he still had the radio and everything and we had the police scanner and the fire scanner with the real chip so we could actually Listen everything and whenever there was a fire nearby or we'd also we'd always go for walks like the Sunday walk.
Speaker 0: We just walk around the neighborhood.
Speaker 0: talked to all the people.
Speaker 0: it was good fun.
Speaker 0: as a kid My dad could smell a fire from like 40 miles away And he could tell you if it was a car fire or a house fire or a factory fire or whatever And it was close enough.
Speaker 0: He could find it.
Speaker 0: so more often than you'd expect.
Speaker 0: My family would show up at the scene of a fire and just kind of hang back and watch the house burn down and watch the Firefighters tried to.
Speaker 1: was your dad a fireman?
Speaker 1: wasn't he supposed to save the people or whatever?
Speaker 0: Not when he's not on duty.
Speaker 0: There were other firemen who were perfectly capable of doing that.
Speaker 1: Really so like if you're a fireman and you walk past a fire you don't do anything cuz other firemen take care.
Speaker 0: He didn't have any equipment on him.
Speaker 0: if there was an emergency I'm sure he would have.
Speaker 0: but remember in an old house fire when like there's an old house that's on fire It's already too late to save the house.
Speaker 0: They're not trying to save the house They go in and save the people.
Speaker 0: Once the people are out their primary duty is to save the neighboring houses not to save your house.
Speaker 1: That sucks also.
Speaker 0: Detroit firefighters are one of the few fire departments left in America that if they're trying to save a building or put out a fire They practice internal firefighting meaning
Speaker 1: even
Speaker 0: if there's no one to save They will March into the building with hoses and put the fire out from the inside.
Speaker 1: Is that more effective?
Speaker 0: Yes It's also much more dangerous.
Speaker 0: I know that Most fire departments from what I've read Will fight the fire from the outside and do damage control more so than stopping the fire at its core.
Speaker 1: Can you spray into the window or something?
Speaker 0: Oh, you can you can.
Speaker 0: hey, I'm not gonna talk about that in detail.
Speaker 0: Maybe if you guys are interested I could do a special just when Scott's out of town about that.
Speaker 0: But firefighting is pretty cool and it's kind of related.
Speaker 0: It's all in the show.
Speaker 0: I got an anecdote.
Speaker 0: My dad wanted to be a policeman when he was young.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and his father and his father's father were firemen and His dad when he learned that my dad wanted to be a fireman as policeman of a policeman?
Speaker 0: Yes, yes as two very appointed questions.
Speaker 0: He said first.
Speaker 0: Do you know any happy firemen?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you and Bob and all the people we know and yeah, they're all pretty happy.
Speaker 0: Do you know any happy cops?
Speaker 0: and I know that we lived in Detroit at the time and my dad became a fireman.
Speaker 0: Yep You got any fire anecdotes before we end this.
Speaker 1: Um We saw that car fire as we draw.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: We I forget where we were driving from or to.
Speaker 1: was it.
Speaker 1: I don't was it from Otacon to the shore?
Speaker 1: I don't even remember.
Speaker 0: I think we were driving to Albany.
Speaker 0: I don't remember at all.
Speaker 1: But basically we driving and we saw like a huge plume of black smoke and we're like, whoa big fire.
Speaker 1: We go around this corner on the highway and there's a van and Basically, the van is super on fire.
Speaker 1: like fire is coming out all the windows of this minivan coming out of the front of the car.
Speaker 1: It's just super on fire.
Speaker 1: It looks like someone poured gas in the car and then threw a match in there and ran away.
Speaker 0: now Luckily, we saw obviously the entire family standing back from it.
Speaker 1: Did we see?
Speaker 1: I didn't see them.
Speaker 0: I saw people standing back from the car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't see people in the car or outside of the car.
Speaker 1: So I wasn't sure they were standing way back.
Speaker 0: All right, they definitely had the look on their faces of what the fuck.
Speaker 1: Yes But just for the thing that really makes this story is the fact that Was it slightly before we saw the fire or slightly after we saw the fire?
Speaker 0: I think it was just after we saw the fire.
Speaker 1: a cop pulled over someone for like speeding on our side of the road while The giant fire was on the other side of the road and there was no EMS or police at that fire.
Speaker 0: yet.
Speaker 0: No it was just a car on fire on the side of the road and we know they knew because I called 911 and I said car fire and they can tell where I am from the GPS whatever.
Speaker 0: and they said on the throughway I'm like, yeah, he's like my marker X and I'm like, yeah, he's like.
Speaker 0: we know about it.
Speaker 0: Thanks click.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, good times.
Speaker 1: Fire eyes are awesome.
Speaker 0: I imagine we'll do more fire episodes in the future when we have nothing better to talk about.
Speaker 0: If you have ideas for Thursday shows tell us or else you can hear about fire some more.
Speaker 0: Granted I think I could talk more about fire.
Speaker 0: I'm starting to remember a bunch of Situations I've been in in my life that involve fire.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well this weekend We were gonna go to anime next and now we're not because we'll talk about that on Wednesday Yep, and the weekend after this weekend, we're going to Connecticut.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about that next week.
Speaker 0: suffice to say we're doing anything.
Speaker 0: nine live shows at least Yeah, and the weekend after that is Otacon where we're doing hopefully four live shows.
Speaker 0: Oh, man This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.