Speaker 0: It's Thursday, May 10th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights Tonight failing to come up with anything better.
Speaker 0: We go down the list of listeners suggested Thursday.
Speaker 0: show ideas.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I have a message.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone involved in the organization I'm about to call out is ever going to listen to our show and that's fine, but to after hours formal wear.
Speaker 1: ah Fuck you die in a fire.
Speaker 1: I. Your after hours formal wear is now on my like top 15 Boycotted businesses, well, I don't know enough about the company itself.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't care about business I know, but that one employee definitely and oh particular branch definitely.
Speaker 1: Here's the.
Speaker 1: the background story is two friends of ours are getting married.
Speaker 1: Hey, this is gonna be fun.
Speaker 1: I gotta get a tuxedo for it and it has to be the right kind of tuxedo and they registered through after-hours formal wear Whatever.
Speaker 1: I just have to go to this place one of them get fitted then go before I drive to the wedding pick up The tuxedo and then drop it back off the next Monday.
Speaker 1: No big deal.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I Go eventually because it turns out that there aren't any Anywhere near our house at all.
Speaker 0: There is one in the one mall like 15 minutes up the road.
Speaker 1: It's more than 15 minutes.
Speaker 1: Remember to actually get to that mall and a park somewhere to get into that stupid place and then to get back?
Speaker 1: it takes about 45 minutes to go to the mall not counting doing anything.
Speaker 0: if it doesn't take 45 minutes to get to the mall actually Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: Oh, it does to get and come back.
Speaker 0: Oh in the der driving total to get there and come back me Which is what I said.
Speaker 1: And it's often taken us a bit more than that just because all the other issues on the road and construction or slow traffic Or usually because we stop in other places.
Speaker 1: Well, usually because Scott says it doesn't take so long.
Speaker 1: But every time I watch my cell phone and I keep track of exactly how long it takes It's always a lot longer than Scott thinks it is.
Speaker 0: next time we're gonna tell look you don't show me the stopwatch though I think you're trying to hide something.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So next time we're gonna look at the clock.
Speaker 1: when we anyway look at the clock It's a gigantic pain in the ass to go up there.
Speaker 0: It is a gigantic plus.
Speaker 1: remember It's not like I can really go on weekends cuz we're always busier out of town on weekends.
Speaker 1: So I'd have to go on a weekday After work when it's already 630 by the time I get home and I'm already sweaty and that road because of rush hour.
Speaker 1: It would take 45 minutes just to get to the mall in the rush hour.
Speaker 0: in the rush hour Absolutely, which is the only time we can go.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So finally after two weeks of trying to go to the stupid place we end up going halfway up the road.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I convinced Scott to drive me the rest of the way to the stupid mall where I didn't need to go.
Speaker 0: I didn't know either think about how nice I am.
Speaker 0: rim never goes anywhere.
Speaker 0: He doesn't need to go no matter how badly I need to go.
Speaker 1: Yes, I do.
Speaker 1: When I drove you to the grocery store a bunch of times when all I needed was like a bag of apples I didn't really need him.
Speaker 1: When was this back when I still drove around?
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus I drove your ass around for years in college and not so much.
Speaker 0: That was we didn't in college.
Speaker 0: We never went anywhere.
Speaker 0: We needed to go cuz we didn't need to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did groceries.
Speaker 0: We didn't need groceries.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 1: No anyway, Mr.
Speaker 0: Meal plan.
Speaker 0: I needed a more than you did.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so we finally get up there and the employee is basically just standing there and yet he will not serve me.
Speaker 1: He keeps saying we're busy.
Speaker 0: I'll get to you in 45 minutes and he just stands there the guy I went into the store cuz I was mostly just.
Speaker 0: you know If I'm at the mall, I'm not gonna spend my time waiting with rim doing his BS.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go around the mall and maybe Save the trip, you know, so I actually get something out of my trip to the mall.
Speaker 1: We did get something out of it.
Speaker 1: We saw that horrible bootleg anime store.
Speaker 0: Oh he did Yes.
Speaker 0: But so I go in there to get rim.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: what's the deal?
Speaker 0: and I see this guy.
Speaker 0: he's standing there leaning on the counter Holding the tape measure Obviously, he's a tailor of some sort and he's just standing there not talking not doing anything.
Speaker 1: and he keeps saying Oh, I got an alteration to do you'll have to wait.
Speaker 1: You'll have to wait.
Speaker 1: You'll have to come back.
Speaker 0: Why aren't you doing it?
Speaker 1: So I stuck around.
Speaker 1: I said, alright, I'll come back and I came back.
Speaker 0: I should be glad that I wasn't the customer.
Speaker 1: a good half hour 35 minutes later, and it's a little busy now.
Speaker 1: He's obviously the only employee in this stupid place and he still will not serve me.
Speaker 1: And when I try to ask him like hey I have places to be is there any way?
Speaker 1: all I need is to be measured For this tuxedo, it'll take a second and he's just so rude.
Speaker 1: He basically won't serve me at all.
Speaker 1: And so I'm like, uh, well, can I make an appointment?
Speaker 1: He's like we don't do appointments.
Speaker 1: So I'm like well fuck this and I just leave because at this point I've wasted almost 50 minutes on this stupid thing.
Speaker 0: I would have yelled at the guy until and like either he would had to start a fight with me and go to jail or Something okay.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Combat.
Speaker 0: I really I would have just yelled at the guy until he caved in seriously at that point.
Speaker 1: See at that point I decided all right.
Speaker 1: I just will not give your store my business.
Speaker 0: I that also but I would have also yelled at him and so not giving him my business I get home.
Speaker 0: I've given up like if I yelled at him and then he gave in and said, okay, I'll size you like.
Speaker 0: no I don't want it now cuz you suck.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I go home and I look online and he's after-hours formal wear have pretty much zero useful locations Anywhere people live there aren't any down in Manhattan I can go to.
Speaker 1: that are accessible.
Speaker 1: They're all in like Long Island or New Jersey way out of my way.
Speaker 1: So I end up driving to one in some stupid town in the strip mall somewhere in New York.
Speaker 0: Oh, you went to another one and you know what?
Speaker 1: Hmm the exact same goddamn thing happened.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, one implode this time.
Speaker 1: The guy was actually busy, but while he was actually busy He would not take the time to help me and he couldn't tell me when he could help me.
Speaker 1: and I waited there for well over a half hour.
Speaker 1: and he's just answering the phone and answering the phone and answering the phone and filling out paperwork and there's all these and just These in stores just can't seem to deal with any number of customers.
Speaker 1: and the guy was totally rude and I After waiting too long.
Speaker 1: I had to go back to work.
Speaker 1: Fuck this and I left.
Speaker 0: I would just stop trying.
Speaker 1: So today worth it.
Speaker 1: So today I drove to fucking white Plains.
Speaker 1: You actually tried again to the worst mall.
Speaker 1: This is the mall.
Speaker 1: I bought the Apple in Mac.
Speaker 1: This is probably the worst mall in the world.
Speaker 1: And when I say the worst, I mean, it's opulence.
Speaker 1: It's super expensive.
Speaker 1: It's gigantic.
Speaker 1: It's designed like a maze.
Speaker 0: That's white Plains.
Speaker 1: It very specifically is designed to not allow people to get in without cars.
Speaker 1: Easily, that's white Plains and I hate this mall.
Speaker 1: I can't stand being in there.
Speaker 1: just painful for me to be in there.
Speaker 1: So I drive 45 minutes to this place during the workday and I go in and I go to this after-hours formal wear and the exact same Fucking thing happens to me again, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, three times three different stores same deal.
Speaker 1: the employee acted in the same manner wouldn't serve me.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of other people waiting.
Speaker 1: they're just doing bullshit paperwork or answering the phone or just standing there.
Speaker 1: and Finally, they're helping the person before me after I've been waiting for an hour.
Speaker 0: Wow And and you didn't yell at them any of these three times.
Speaker 1: No, I I was so paid.
Speaker 1: This is probably the most sufferance of fools I've ever engaged in in my.
Speaker 0: I don't even know why you suffered a single fool.
Speaker 0: You didn't have to.
Speaker 0: you shouldn't have had to.
Speaker 1: I've done this all for the sake of my two friends who are getting married And I'm gonna get to what the moral of all this at the end because I've made a resolution in my life.
Speaker 1: So the people in front of me like this one guy and this other guy and this other guy They're just standing there and I figure they need something quick they need to be measured and it ends up being this gigantic thing where They don't like the pants because the pants are too tight and the guy who's saying the pants are too tight is Wearing pants that are like eight sizes too big hanging off his ass.
Speaker 1: I can see his ass.
Speaker 1: and yet he wants to wear his tuxedo low like that and the lady's like, um You can't wear a tuxedo that way.
Speaker 1: and they go through this whole thing.
Speaker 1: and then she trying to scan his credit card his credit card doesn't work and the name's not right in there and all this crap and Finally I get served.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I didn't think that was gonna happen.
Speaker 1: and Well, it's gonna cost me more than twice as much as any tuxedo.
Speaker 1: I've ever rented in my life.
Speaker 1: Wow for one it's a hundred and fifty bucks.
Speaker 0: four hundred fifty bucks.
Speaker 0: I just buy a tuxedo because the tuxedo is like four hundred bucks But the thing is to rent one for one night.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: how many times have I had to wear a tuxedo in my life?
Speaker 1: I will name them.
Speaker 0: Yes, however, let me submit this I know you if you owned a tuxedo for four hundred dollars Would you wear it in your?
Speaker 0: you would intentionally wear it at times that were not necessary?
Speaker 0: You would wear it more than three times and it would be worth it to buy one for $400 as opposed to rent one for 150. now
Speaker 1: Scott while I agree with you on that point in most cases because
Speaker 0: I do
Speaker 1: Like to dress up a lot more than I have chance to and I will just wear a suit to work if I have any Excuse at
Speaker 0: all,
Speaker 1: but a $400 tuxedo is kind of crappy for one and I don't like tuxedo.
Speaker 0: It's a $600 tuxedo.
Speaker 0: You have to wear it four times for it to be a good deal.
Speaker 1: It is my opinion that Tuxedos are Horrible and ugly and unstyling.
Speaker 1: I really don't like tuxedos.
Speaker 1: Oh, we agree on some.
Speaker 1: I much prefer to wear some sort of nice Three-piece suit.
Speaker 1: I like suits.
Speaker 1: I like sport jackets.
Speaker 1: I hate tuxedos.
Speaker 1: They Everything about them bothers me.
Speaker 1: They're not actually fashionable.
Speaker 1: They just pick what's fashionable and then you have to wear it.
Speaker 0: I think the point of dress clothes is Now this is they're similar to sunglasses.
Speaker 0: the more money they cost the more people they look good on.
Speaker 0: even a fat ugly nasty guy He looks alright in a tuxedo because it covers so much And it's so slick itself that if you're an ugly horrible person you wearing that you're okay to look at.
Speaker 1: But the thing is when I see a tuxedo ever The only thing I think is that guys either go into a wedding or a high school prom because no one wears Tuxedos anywhere else.
Speaker 0: at least not guys even wear tuxedos to prom so much anymore either.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we all did but my tuxedo cost me 40 bucks to rent and it was the same tuxedo.
Speaker 0: Well, there's also a kid size.
Speaker 0: There's a lot less material going.
Speaker 1: I wasn't a kid size.
Speaker 1: I was the same size in high school.
Speaker 1: Now Anyway, actually, I'm a little thinner now.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, I could go on and on but I just think tuxedos are kind of ugly and garish And I really don't like them.
Speaker 1: and while there are occasions where a tuxedo I would feel would be justified like a white tie Formal dinner that is not the time kind of tuxedo you get at a mall in white Plains.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of tuxedo you pay a lot of money for.
Speaker 1: yeah So, uh, there's no reason for me to buy a tuxedo and I'm gonna have to spend this hundred fifty bucks and all that.
Speaker 1: So I finally get the thing and the lady's like, I'm sorry it took so long blah blah blah and I was very nice to her despite all this and I pay my hundred and fifty bucks on my credit card and I walk out and I decided now from this point forward in my life other than this wedding because I've already committed to it.
Speaker 1: So I got to wear the stupid tuxedo.
Speaker 1: I will never in the rest of my life I give my solemn word Wear a rented cheap or crappy tuxedo to any occasion for any reason for any person ever.
Speaker 0: Again, I already had that resolution and I've never even worn a tuxedo in my life.
Speaker 1: I have ever put into a situation where a tuxedo is necessary and I feel that I really need to wear a tuxedo.
Speaker 1: I'm going to get a custom real tuxedo and I'm going to pay whatever that costs and whatever it costs to get served right away.
Speaker 0: You're paying so much money that they'll put the other customers make them wait longer.
Speaker 1: I hate to say this but I used to think when I was a kid and I'd see people who would spend like Ungodly amounts of money for something that was effectively the same as something that I got cheaper Only for the convenience of having it in an easier fashion.
Speaker 1: But now I fully see the value of that because time is so much more valuable than money.
Speaker 0: Yes I agree with that it is.
Speaker 0: it is worth it for me at this point I have so I have enough money to pay for convenience.
Speaker 0: However, I don't really think any to.
Speaker 0: for me personally Almost no clothing is work.
Speaker 0: No single item of clothing or a single Arrangement of clothing to be worn at the same time is worth more than like $50.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well this cuz I really don't care about arrangement.
Speaker 1: at the same time I mean all my pants cost more than $50.
Speaker 0: I mean my shorts cost like 20 but like if I was to pay $50 for a single clothing it would have to be like some super awesome one-of-a-kind like Metroid anniversary shirt Signed by the guy all right met for some reason.
Speaker 1: I thought I thought you were going to say Metrosexual and instead you said Metroid.
Speaker 1: I think that is one of the defining things that makes geek nights what it is.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: but Honestly geek nights officially on endorses.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess you never did endorse.
Speaker 0: but we anti endorse all tuxedo rental place.
Speaker 1: Especially no just after hours for hours formal wear because the times I rented tuxedos in my youth for other events I did not have nearly this difficulty.
Speaker 1: I walked in well.
Speaker 0: So wait now don't you have to go to one of these places to pick the tux?
Speaker 1: Oh, oh you realize before this wedding on Thursday I have to either during rush hour or sometime during the day.
Speaker 1: Drive all the fuck way out to white planes.
Speaker 1: go to this goddamn mall again pay for parking.
Speaker 1: walk 20 minutes Mall.
Speaker 1: yeah, it keeps the riffraff out.
Speaker 1: It's like three bucks.
Speaker 1: It's just to keep riffraff out.
Speaker 1: white planes I really don't like white planes.
Speaker 0: white planes is where all these rich uppity Jews live.
Speaker 1: See I don't mind the people who live there on mine the the atmosphere of the commercial sectors there and the roads Because 287 is on my shit list of the ten roads.
Speaker 1: I desire least ever beyond.
Speaker 0: Well 287 like Tappan Zee bridge connect New York to New Jersey All right to 87.
Speaker 1: east of like the Tappan Zee not All right to 87 pretty much anywhere where we live.
Speaker 0: east of 80 east of like 87 is no good.
Speaker 1: No, pretty list of nine god during rush hour anywhere near 87 anywhere in ten miles in either direction of 87.
Speaker 1: You don't want to be anywhere near that goddamn road.
Speaker 0: No, you don't want to be near turn rush.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but after hours I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna complain to the company because the what how come you're not gonna complain because the Best they're gonna do is send me some kind of promotional thing, but I don't ever want to go.
Speaker 0: Maybe you'll just get some money back at you from your hundred and fifty dollars.
Speaker 1: I hope so.
Speaker 0: cuz I at the worst they send you a coupon.
Speaker 1: at the best you get your money back and maybe some redemption $150 would have turned the g4 7900 GS that is sitting next to me and my half-built computer that I really want to end this show and finish building.
Speaker 1: cuz that Motherboard is so pretty.
Speaker 0: It's a really nice motherboard.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you.
Speaker 0: I hope it works in Linux.
Speaker 1: You know what the motherboards so nice.
Speaker 1: if the current kernel doesn't support it I'll suffer through mint windows a couple months.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's so nice.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Ah, okay.
Speaker 1: We have a nerd gasps.
Speaker 0: Okay, so now that we're done Yeah, so fuck you.
Speaker 0: after hours formal wear and every employee you have also I just want to say but we could do a whole show on this.
Speaker 0: Oh, I Really?
Speaker 0: Don't like the current American tradition of weddings, and I think it's stupid.
Speaker 1: Oh, we're doing a show on that.
Speaker 0: Granted granted our friends are actually going about it in a much smarter way than most people in a smarter way than most people but They are not taking it to the extreme that I would prefer which is go to the courthouse.
Speaker 0: It takes ten minutes and cost like five bucks.
Speaker 1: My mom did it pretty awesomely when she remarried.
Speaker 1: They went to the courthouse did a nice little ceremony.
Speaker 1: It was really.
Speaker 1: it gives a really well done ceremony and it cost what I don't know not much All right, and then we went back to our house and they had a gigantic Hawaiian pig rose.
Speaker 0: And how much did that cost?
Speaker 0: not much and you know what your mom's awesome.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: That's how it's got to be people.
Speaker 1: You don't need to spend but I set up the music.
Speaker 1: I did the music for my mom's wedding and it worked really well.
Speaker 1: because we had this big surround system I just hacked it into my brand new computer and I played the music people spend like Mike.
Speaker 0: there's a guy at my work.
Speaker 0: He's going to a wedding right and he's like part.
Speaker 0: He's like like sub the best man.
Speaker 0: he's like this.
Speaker 0: so he's one of the groomsmen yes, and He had to go to a dinner rehearsal yesterday, that's what I have to go to Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta go Friday for that But that'll be fun because I get free food and then he's got to go Do the tuxedo thing today and then he's got.
Speaker 0: the wedding is gonna last all weekend and the people who are having the wedding It's costing them $75,000.
Speaker 0: Ah, all right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Now I have a very similar story in my work where we were talking about weddings and whatever Back it.
Speaker 1: I want my old work back at IBM.
Speaker 1: I was a lot more vocal about my opinions because the people there Generally were a lot more.
Speaker 1: I would I want to say intelligent but Interested in debate and arguing as opposed to just sitting there.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So also I actually ate with them.
Speaker 1: I don't really eat with anyone at my current work So I really don't have much opportunity to argue with anyone Mm-hmm, and we had an argument where I was talking about how you know.
Speaker 1: If you go to a flower place and you say you want flowers for an event They give you X price.
Speaker 1: if you send someone else in and order the exact same thing, but say it's for a wedding They'll charge you quite a bit more money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I a lot of people have verified this.
Speaker 1: you can verify it yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah if
Speaker 0: you want to verify get two friends go to a florist and say I want a bouquet of These flowers and then pay for it and then send your other friend in to get the same exact flowers But say it's for a wedding specifically and see what they charge you.
Speaker 1: Well, really not for a single bouquet but for like a flower arrangement, yeah the flowers for an event that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Yep, but yeah, we got to do another show on that.
Speaker 1: cuz we've got actual things to talk about.
Speaker 0: Hey weddings What.
Speaker 0: there's no point in spending so much money on one single party.
Speaker 0: You could have gone on vacation You could have bought a house.
Speaker 0: You could have bought a car.
Speaker 1: You're an $75,000.
Speaker 0: you could have bought a BMW which would have lasted you for many years.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't Finish my anecdote, okay I just kind of went nowhere with that.
Speaker 1: So we're talking and I was like and he's talking about a wedding and he's like this wedding is gonna cost.
Speaker 1: it was Same kind of number.
Speaker 1: you just gave some ludicrous number for this crazy amount of money on the wedding and I was like You know, you probably they could have had the exact same wedding for maybe not half that price But at least a significant percentage off without having to sacrifice any of the quality and the dude didn't believe me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people just refuse to accept that they fucked up.
Speaker 1: but if they believe you're a total day It's your special day it you got to spare no expense because this only happens once it's your special day.
Speaker 0: That's the argument.
Speaker 0: every other fucking day except this it's a day I'm signing a contract.
Speaker 0: if I want to celebrate signing a contract I'll have a party like party can't go over a certain level of fun.
Speaker 0: It doesn't take that much to get fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the thing is like a hundred bucks a fire and some meat.
Speaker 1: See the thing is I have no problem with the idea of a wedding or any of that or even marriage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only thing that bothers me is the wedding planning.
Speaker 0: That is that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: in the United States.
Speaker 1: We're not disparaging weddings.
Speaker 1: We're disparaging the wedding planning industry much like the funeral home in I was just gonna mention the funeral home the prison industrial complex.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so in the news, oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott didn't expect this cuz I kept this all bottled up for the last three weeks.
Speaker 0: Well, I knew that you had the trouble the first time but I didn't know you had three more trouble.
Speaker 1: never in your wildest dreams.
Speaker 1: Would you think that I would have the same problem at two additional store?
Speaker 0: I'm surprised that you didn't like blow those stores up and that you're not on the news as some sort of terrorist Because it's their special day.
Speaker 1: so, uh These this was on slashdot and it appears that the United States government very much is outlawing wedding ceremonies.
Speaker 1: Yes Wants to somehow limit the access that people have to satellite imagery of the earth.
Speaker 1: And all right, I had a lot more to say about this, but we've already gone a while with our ranting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'll keep it short.
Speaker 1: I don't think that the government really has the right to prevent access to pictures of things from public space.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much
Speaker 1: also the fact that it's not like the u.s Controls all the satellites and there's a lot of commercial satellites out there and satellites from other countries And it's not like you can't get access to this and I really don't see how a short of shooting down a bunch of satellites This is feasible at all.
Speaker 1: and in fact It bothers me even now that like Google Will if India because this happened India complained that you could see some of their industry and some of their military stuff on Google Earth.
Speaker 1: so Google very nicely blurred it out and I say that's crap.
Speaker 1: if you're a government and you're trying to hide your military operations You've got to deal with the fact that there are satellites out there and that me Rim can sit here in my house and look at your shit.
Speaker 0: for thousands of years of human existence We had no reliable maps.
Speaker 0: Look at old maps.
Speaker 0: They suck.
Speaker 0: all people needed better maps.
Speaker 0: With maps we can actually go around the earth and know where shit is.
Speaker 0: It's very important.
Speaker 0: and now we finally have perfect maps.
Speaker 0: We have high-resolution imagery of the entire surface of the entire planet.
Speaker 0: It's so incredibly amazing and there are people who want to take that away.
Speaker 0: We should put those people away Alright, so my news.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: we were going to discuss this a lot now I don't know how much we're gonna discuss it.
Speaker 0: It's an article about on CNN money.
Speaker 0: calm about for gas saving.
Speaker 0: myths, right?
Speaker 0: There are things they've evil believe about saving gas some things that even I believed that are true and or not true.
Speaker 1: is the acetone trick in there?
Speaker 0: no nothing.
Speaker 0: if anyone ever tells you that adding something to your fuel some sort of fuel additive or Putting a sticker on your gas tank or some sort of magnet somewhere in your fuel all those stupid stickers All of those things are complete bullshit.
Speaker 0: They will not if they're think about this right it?
Speaker 0: your Chevy your your General Motors, right?
Speaker 0: You want to put the highest possible number you can on the windshield of your car for fuel efficiency, right?
Speaker 0: Now imagine if there was a sticker that if you put it on the gas tank up the fuel efficiency Wouldn't you put that sticker on every car and thus raise the fuel efficiency of all your cars?
Speaker 0: And then a lot of people would buy your cars because there was so much more fuel efficient, huh?
Speaker 0: I wonder why they don't put these stickers on the gas tanks.
Speaker 0: Oh because it's just a fucking sticker.
Speaker 0: Goddamn anyone who believed that is an idiot anyway, so that's the first myth.
Speaker 0: the second myth now.
Speaker 0: This is a myth that I believed and that okay if you turn on your air conditioning Or you open your windows while you're driving it hurts your gas mileage now.
Speaker 0: This is true.
Speaker 0: however, it is apparently.
Speaker 0: according to various studies the amount of significance to how much gas mileage you lose by opening windows or turning on air conditioning is Really not that much compared to other factors.
Speaker 1: However, I do point out because kinda argued about this quite a bit before the show and in the interest of time We'll leave all the argument out because we came to a consensus that this study is technically correct.
Speaker 1: But what speed were they going at?
Speaker 1: 55 65 65?
Speaker 1: I think that that starts to break down when you're going.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: 8090.
Speaker 0: yes, if you're going really fast and you've got like the sunroof and all the windows open that is gonna hurt you a measurable amount.
Speaker 0: Still not as much as some other factors But you're probably at going fast on the highway.
Speaker 0: You're probably a little bit better off with the air conditioning and going around town.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really matter Seriously, yep Well, there's also the fact that I mean my personal experience.
Speaker 1: one of the things I've always done as long as I've owned cars is Every time I fill up the gas tank, I always fill it and then I click the trip meter.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I used to do that now I stopped.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got out of the habit because I go to the gas station so not often now.
Speaker 1: Well, the main reason I do it is that I always always keep track of how much gas mileage I'm getting and in fact I used to keep a spreadsheet of every time I filled my tank the gas mileage I'd gotten I'd always calculate it Mm-hmm and that way I could see not necessarily trends in my driving because I know pretty well from you know years of experience How different kinds of driving affect my gas mileage?
Speaker 1: What I did is I use this to tell if anything is going wrong with my car Because if my gas mileage starts dropping in a trend something is wrong.
Speaker 1: Mmm and several times I have been able to use this to realize that something was indeed wrong.
Speaker 1: Like my transmission was kind of going My front end was a little out of alignment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you can you sell that by the tires.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the next myth is apparently a myth that I did not know that it's cheaper to buy gas on Wednesday because gas prices go Up on the weekend and while this is true Sometimes that some yet gas can be more expensive on the weekend Sometimes some places on the whole.
Speaker 0: if you buy all your gas on Wednesday as opposed to just buying it when you need it It's not gonna make a significant difference in how much you spend on gas.
Speaker 1: Yep, if anything the best strategy is just to go buy gas in New Jersey.
Speaker 0: Yep Here's another myth that I actually believed.
Speaker 0: now I thought that like light bulbs the turning on your car used quite a bit of gas.
Speaker 1: In fact, my driver's ed instructor in high school even told me that.
Speaker 0: yep So it's like okay if you have a choice between you know sitting in your car and letting it idle without moving anywhere for like Five minutes or turning it off and then turning it on five minutes later.
Speaker 0: I thought that it was probably a better idea just to idle there.
Speaker 0: and but if you waited like ten minutes Then it was probably a better idea to start and stop the car.
Speaker 0: Apparently if you have a modern car, but you do you have a modern car Your car does not have a carburetor unless it's an old hot rod or a really old classic car Like a Model T or some 50s car.
Speaker 0: your car has fuel injection.
Speaker 1: Yep And you have a thing called that coil the inducting coil or something like the thing that broke on my Sunfire twice, right?
Speaker 0: You have fuel injection.
Speaker 0: You do not have a carburetor in your car.
Speaker 0: old NASCAR actually still uses carburetors.
Speaker 0: it's why one of the reasons I hate NASCAR.
Speaker 0: but Therefore if you are idling for even 30 seconds Like if you're stopping at someone's house like putting something on there like your UPS guy you stop you put something on their porch you Get back in the car.
Speaker 0: It's worth it to turn the engine off?
Speaker 1: Well, maybe not UPS guy because that's diesel.
Speaker 0: No, actually UPS themselves is why I said UPS guy.
Speaker 0: They did a study and they told all the UPS guys to turn off the trucks whenever they get out hot Damn, and they save money that way.
Speaker 0: They also make only right turns when whenever possible.
Speaker 0: I knew that.
Speaker 1: I think we talked about that.
Speaker 0: All right, here are some ways.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: Those are the factors that people thought were significant to fuel mileage, but are not.
Speaker 0: here are the significant factors.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: pretty much there's only two.
Speaker 0: you can save about like seven percent or so using your cruise control.
Speaker 0: Cruise control saves you money on the highway number.
Speaker 0: two, if your tires are properly inflated that's gonna save you something Reducing weight in your car.
Speaker 0: if you take the golf clubs out of the back out of the trunk when you're not going golfing That's gonna save you in the long run because you have less weight in your car.
Speaker 0: that that's actually a factor But the most significant factor by far.
Speaker 0: it can save you anywhere from 15 to 98 cents a gallon.
Speaker 0: It's just don't go too fucking fast.
Speaker 0: I mean, we're always talking about how speed limits are bullshit and in when it comes to safety versus Towns trying to rob people from out of town to support their local governments.
Speaker 0: Yes speed limits are bullshit.
Speaker 0: However, it's absolutely true that if you were to drive your car say 85 90 miles an hour on the highway all the time that would use a lot more gas because your car is not very Aerodynamic.
Speaker 1: Yep, it depends really on exactly what kind of car it does transmission.
Speaker 1: What kind of engine?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if you had a Ferrari you could probably go eight.
Speaker 0: I mean the Ferrari doesn't have good gas mileage to begin with but going 85 in the aerodynamic Ferrari or Lotus Eliz a is Not going to hurt the overall gas mileage of the car compared to what the car gets for gas mileage with his giant v8 engine.
Speaker 1: well my current car and Obviously I keep track of my gas mileage I get the best gas mileage at about 74 miles an hour like just under 75 is when I get Absolute optimal gas mileage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not really sure where my car gets optimal gas mileage It's a little hard to tell mostly because I didn't keep perfect track.
Speaker 0: I kept semi track but like between 65 and 75 somewhere around there It's mostly the RPMs that I look at, you know If I keep it around between 2,000 to 3,000 RPMs, I can get the most out of the car all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you want to be in that good power band.
Speaker 1: Yep Things of the day.
Speaker 1: this was on dig and I'd saw it for a while.
Speaker 1: People are posting.
Speaker 1: that is really old But I don't care because it's new to me and I think it's new to a lot of people.
Speaker 1: It's a video called Mother's Day picture Rofl.
Speaker 1: the tea is silence.
Speaker 0: Oh, yep.
Speaker 0: That one's new to me also.
Speaker 1: Well, uh, I ignored it for a while because it didn't look like it was gonna be something funny And it didn't really get super dug up or anything, but we eventually clicked on it because there was really nothing on dig yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just like.
Speaker 0: this is a video I probably never would have clicked on in my entire life and I just really didn't care about a Mother's Day picture.
Speaker 0: It looked like some stupid thing two guys put together.
Speaker 0: That wasn't funny.
Speaker 0: So I just ignored it, but we're so bored We clicked on it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, well it not only met expectations but far exceeded them and I did Rofl.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not the funniest thing ever but it was pretty funny and I didn't expect it to be funny at all.
Speaker 0: So the win for them can't ruin anything.
Speaker 1: But suffice to say the moment the first instance where he just punches the other guy in the nipple That is that is when I just started cracking up.
Speaker 0: It's a good video.
Speaker 0: You should watch it.
Speaker 0: It's funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't say more without ruining the joke.
Speaker 0: Alright now a while ago.
Speaker 0: I think rim had a thing of the day which was the algorithm dance, which is a dance from a Pitaka rasui G. Yes.
Speaker 0: So this is a video of also the algorithm dance, but It's not.
Speaker 0: It's not from the TV show where they're doing the algorithm dance.
Speaker 1: This is from a prison in the Philippines where they have a record breaking performance of The algorithm dance by the prisoners, you know I was talking a lot about my top 10 and top 15 list in the rant at the beginning of this Filipino prison.
Speaker 1: Real-high on my do not want to be list.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: I definitely don't want to be in the Filipino prison.
Speaker 0: However, it seems to me like the Filipino prison actually from this video alone, which isn't much to judge by Seems to be a lot better than the American prison, which I imagine is full of just lots of rape in the.
Speaker 1: well Here's the problem.
Speaker 1: My knowledge of American prison comes from a lot of documentaries.
Speaker 1: So I actually have real knowledge, but to be more silly my media knowledge comes from Oz Mostly and that prison comics I picked up at mocha.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that was good one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what I got about that.
Speaker 0: You know that.
Speaker 1: you know what?
Speaker 1: I like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got it somewhere.
Speaker 1: You know, I like more than killing people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nothing stab Except maybe biscuits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this video has no shivs.
Speaker 1: I was really expecting a shiv, you know The part where they swing left and right.
Speaker 1: I was just waiting for one person to just have a shiv in his hand.
Speaker 0: It seems to me like they run those prisons a lot like military detention centers Like they have these guys lined up and following orders and stuff, which is an American prisons.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's how it goes Prisons not so bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course, it's shanker be shanked.
Speaker 1: Of course, but you can make sangria in the toilet All right, I'm aware it was out of order.
Speaker 0: yes, I know All right, so we couldn't figure out what to do today.
Speaker 0: well, we have a couple.
Speaker 0: good we had a bunch of ideas.
Speaker 1: We have to crab people's just because we went so long on.
Speaker 1: You know the opening bit.
Speaker 1: Yes that we wouldn't do either those ideas justice.
Speaker 1: We're holding off off on him.
Speaker 1: Also that new computer is just looking at me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's already late here much later than I thought because rim has caused me great delays today.
Speaker 0: Well partly because we were playing out the Cold War again and building a computer and we spent a lot of time in between The two halves of the show and whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I said I did remember last week I promised that we were gonna.
Speaker 0: I asked for listeners suggestions and listeners gave suggestions on what to do on Thursday night.
Speaker 0: So I said last week since we asked for the suggestions whether we think they're good or bad We're gonna do them anyway, because you asked for them.
Speaker 0: So if they suck it's your fault.
Speaker 0: Well, I Realized today that you really suck Is?
Speaker 1: I think the interesting thing is that we get a lot of ideas from email a lot in the forums and Most of the things people suggest are the same thing over and over again.
Speaker 1: You know many people say do an episode on food.
Speaker 0: We've already done like two episodes on food.
Speaker 1: you realize there was a time When every Thursday we ended up talking about food for a while because we had nothing better.
Speaker 1: We got our friend Adam on the show and we literally made the show about food because he happened to have a funny food anecdote.
Speaker 0: Yep, and The other thing is people give ideas for shows that are so generic and broad.
Speaker 0: It's like what do we say?
Speaker 0: It's like you do a show about food.
Speaker 0: What do we say about?
Speaker 0: There's a whole TV network about food.
Speaker 0: There's a lot to say.
Speaker 0: last week It was actually kind of okay because the guy had specific questions.
Speaker 0: He had a whole episode outlined.
Speaker 0: I mean, it wasn't really, you know, really cohesive with a central idea But it was a show that was doable because there were questions and I answered them.
Speaker 0: There were specific discussion topics, which we could discuss.
Speaker 0: and how do you discuss?
Speaker 0: Alright, someone says food Discuss.
Speaker 0: what the fuck do you say?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean maybe they're assuming to play devil's advocate here that we're so awesome that we would take their seat of an idea and Create from it a more specific idea.
Speaker 0: if I could do that.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't need your suggestion.
Speaker 0: I can think of food also.
Speaker 0: Thanks.
Speaker 1: Oh, can you now?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I just thought how can you prove it?
Speaker 1: Because you've the wells been taint.
Speaker 0: I find you ready.
Speaker 0: I'll do another one.
Speaker 0: You ready sleep discuss.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 1: Also, I don't get enough.
Speaker 0: No, I never have Nope the end.
Speaker 0: So I just came up with actually a great idea for a show.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read all these ideas for shows that we're not gonna do and tell you why.
Speaker 0: Let's start at the bottom here.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: I gotta find an idea.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay Ebbe in the forum says so.
Speaker 0: I searched the front page for ninjas and nothing pulled up oddly enough.
Speaker 0: So unless I screwed up you guys really need to do a podcast about ninjas in all caps.
Speaker 1: All right one.
Speaker 1: We've already made it very clear that we're on the side of pirates.
Speaker 0: That is quite obvious.
Speaker 0: If you haven't noticed our talk like a pirate day episode.
Speaker 0: We really are pirate fans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't do walk like a ninja day.
Speaker 0: No, you don't.
Speaker 1: however back when I DJ that rit anime club the pirate ninja thing I was in fact DJ plunder if you can't figure out what kind of DJ I was.
Speaker 0: Also, I don't think I've ever dressed up as a ninja yet I have dressed up as a pirate quite often.
Speaker 0: I own many articles of pirate Costumery.
Speaker 1: I dressed up as a ninja when I was in middle school And in fact, I bought my ninja outfit from an actual well not my like.
Speaker 1: it wasn't a ninja outfit But I bought actual karate clothes from some karate place.
Speaker 1: It wasn't really probably a real karate place, but it was one of those McDowjoes.
Speaker 1: But I bought of all the stuff there And then I went somewhere else and I bought Basically the thing that you would expect a bank robber to wear and I put it over my face and I became a ninja.
Speaker 1: I'm still laughing about my dojo and I had two Real shuriken shuriken shuriken that I immediately lost throwing them at things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I threw one at a tree.
Speaker 1: it bounced off the tree bounced into the bushes never saw it again.
Speaker 1: Later, I was out in the woods.
Speaker 1: I threw one at a piece of wood and it fell to the ground in the leaves.
Speaker 1: I never found it again.
Speaker 1: Lost him both within the span of a week.
Speaker 0: So ninjas is not something we can really do a whole show on.
Speaker 0: Keep saying the word McDowjoe over and over again and laughing I use that word kind of often I don't know.
Speaker 0: I haven't heard it and like it's a word I knew but it didn't Come around in a while.
Speaker 0: So it's funny again.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's scroll up a little bit.
Speaker 1: I also owned a pair of nunchucks And I would like to point out that the number of times I hit my target with them was fewer than the number of times I hit myself in the nuts.
Speaker 1: I Threw them away There.
Speaker 1: that was the ninja episode.
Speaker 0: all right HMTK Steve says how about doing a show on the whole carbonated beverages hurt me thing?
Speaker 1: Uh, very simply that's just one of Scott's quirks.
Speaker 1: There's nothing more I can say about that.
Speaker 1: on my end.
Speaker 0: I don't like to drink carbonated beverages.
Speaker 0: It doesn't feel good.
Speaker 0: If you want to force me to do it It's not like.
Speaker 0: I'm afraid I'll drink one because I just don't like to.
Speaker 0: so why should I?
Speaker 1: I'll point out that while Scott Very clearly refuses to drink alcohol ever.
Speaker 1: He did try that hobo wine.
Speaker 0: I did try the hobo wine I'll you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: he also tried a spoonful of rum once.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's not like I'm afraid to death It's I don't enjoy it.
Speaker 0: So I don't do it intentionally.
Speaker 1: and he said if I ever actually make it he'll at least try a sip of grog.
Speaker 0: But I haven't gotten around to trying to make just to know what it tastes like cuz it's grog.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I said we're on the side of the pirates.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, he also says what about a show on landing tech jobs and what sort of salary you should request and/or expect?
Speaker 1: hello Thursday Ideas, well, did he do that in a Thursday thread?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Oh, ah, man, you were so close.
Speaker 0: All right, Wally B man Thursday show idea.
Speaker 0: How about a how not to suck at cooking?
Speaker 0: well, that's a little more specific than the Food idea.
Speaker 1: I think I can answer though.
Speaker 1: You could probably also answer why we're not doing this.
Speaker 1: I think the answer is we suck at cooking.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I don't suck at cooking as badly as people who make TV dinners and they can only cook ramen and maybe an egg.
Speaker 0: But then again, I'm not good enough at cooking to where I'd ever consider Thinking that I have the right to tell anyone else how to do it.
Speaker 0: most often I ask other people how to cook and I would probably like a cooking podcast.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should look into that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe that'd be a good idea.
Speaker 0: So you didn't give me a Thursday show idea, but you gave me a go downstairs and look for cooking podcast idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean we're only proficient between the two of us and cooking maybe 20 or so like actual dishes and Beyond that it's trial and error.
Speaker 0: Yep Beyond that while the B man goes on to say start off simple with a grilled cheese then maybe spice it up with a deluxe.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: anyone can make a grilled cheese.
Speaker 0: When I was in Boy Scouts they made an awesome grilled cheese.
Speaker 0: damn now, I'm gonna have to go make one or four.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: Eat grilled cheese quite a bit and people have actually more than one person has told me on more than one occasion I make a pretty damn good grilled cheese and I'm gonna let you all in on the secret because it's not that hard to make a good grilled cheese.
Speaker 1: number one if you think that a Microwave is in any way involved in making a grilled cheese sandwich kill yourself because you're wrong.
Speaker 0: one time My friend's mom made me a grilled cheese with a microwave.
Speaker 0: It was mushy and disgusting.
Speaker 1: Number two use a teflon nonstick pan.
Speaker 0: Number three unless you have a real grill like at a burger joint where it's a big flat hot piece of metal Yeah, which is basically a similar thing.
Speaker 1: I mean has the same effect.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: You want a big flat hot piece of metal.
Speaker 1: That's all you want.
Speaker 1: Don't try to use one of those sandwich making machines.
Speaker 0: Well, if you have the garlic cheese presser thingy not it's not some sort of you know electronic device or anything.
Speaker 0: It's just a clamp.
Speaker 0: If you have the grill to hide the clamps You want me to use these clamps the clamps that I. yes If you have the grilled cheese clamp, you can use it and I actually prefer the grilled cheese clamp method But it's not necessary.
Speaker 1: So here's what you do make the pan hot.
Speaker 1: hot enough to where the butter will go When you put it on but it won't burn but not hot enough to where the butter will turn brown Before you can put the bread on.
Speaker 0: also it has to be hot enough to melt cheese.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but luckily you can get around that really quickly.
Speaker 1: The best way to tell is if you sprinkle water on it Does the water bubble up and go pretty quickly?
Speaker 1: if so You're ready.
Speaker 1: take a stick of butter.
Speaker 1: go all over the pan to make a nice pool of butter.
Speaker 0: also go all over the bread.
Speaker 1: No, see I don't do that.
Speaker 0: I see I put the butter on the bread.
Speaker 1: See, you know, I you don't want to do that.
Speaker 0: Usually I like to do it that way.
Speaker 1: You just put it on the in the thing and let it melt and then you drop a piece of bread on it.
Speaker 1: Then you drop either one or two slices of cheese to pay anyone good cheese.
Speaker 1: Don't use American cheese.
Speaker 1: use any other cheese.
Speaker 0: American cheese is okay.
Speaker 0: I actually if you're gonna use American cheese, don't use Kraft singles.
Speaker 0: get like slices of nice American for the deli.
Speaker 1: I particularly recommend Monterey Jack for grilled cheese sandwiches because it's good and it has some flavor But yet it's not so flavorful that you can't do other things to the grilled cheese.
Speaker 0: now Here's the really all about the melting point of the cheese.
Speaker 0: You don't want to use a cheese that's all mushy and you don't want to use a cheese that won't melt.
Speaker 1: you got your looks Really works really really well to yeah munchy cheese also works.
Speaker 1: Yep So then you then you put the piece of cheese on.
Speaker 1: now the critical part.
Speaker 1: I always sprinkle a little bit of dill in there on the cheese.
Speaker 1: Oh you just adding your shitty cheese and Dill and sometimes a dash of oregano on the outside when it's almost done.
Speaker 0: No, I really know it's just a tiny day.
Speaker 0: It acts it works pretty well.
Speaker 0: I like butter cheese and bread toasted.
Speaker 1: So anyway, you got the cheese on don't put the other piece of bread on yet.
Speaker 1: Now what you do is you take a small cup of water and you take a pelt the lid to your pan and you Dump a little bit of water in the pan and then you cover it.
Speaker 0: So, you know don't put the water too close to the bread.
Speaker 1: Don't get the water wet.
Speaker 1: Don't get the bread wet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's gonna ruin your grilled cheese sandwich.
Speaker 0: It'll make it all mushy.
Speaker 0: You want to put the water far away from the bread?
Speaker 0: But you want it to steam and then you put the lid on and it keeps the steam Around the bread and in the pan under the lid so it can melt the cheese But it doesn't make your bread soggy unless you do a whole lot of water.
Speaker 1: So see you're grilling the bread and now you've melted the cheese.
Speaker 1: now Put the third the piece of bread on top pick the grilled cheese up Melt more butter into the pan quickly and then put it upside down on the.
Speaker 0: if you would have just put butter on the bread In the first place you wouldn't have to do the quick butter melting in the pan business.
Speaker 0: Plus you could then butter both sides of the bread instead of just one side.
Speaker 1: You're only supposed to butter one side.
Speaker 0: butter both sides of the bread.
Speaker 1: You're not supposed to do that in a grilled cheese.
Speaker 0: It's the way to go.
Speaker 1: hi, I think your grilled cheeses are pretty nasty.
Speaker 0: then butter is the best anyway, yeah Oh, obviously, you can see why a whole episode cannot be done about food by us.
Speaker 1: Well, it could because we could probably go on arguing about how to make a grilled cheese for another 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: But all right, here we go.
Speaker 0: Next idea HMTK Steve again.
Speaker 0: He says after reading Hungry Joe's post about old toys.
Speaker 0: I think the dynamic duo I guess that's us should do a show on toys from their childhood.
Speaker 0: We did.
Speaker 0: we did do that episode.
Speaker 1: It's one of our most popular episodes ever.
Speaker 1: it gets downloaded constantly to this day and it's an old shitty episode - yeah We did it.
Speaker 1: We just say the same thing.
Speaker 0: so duplicate and a hitman heart says Star Wars and Star Trek seem to be obvious topics or a general non anime movie show.
Speaker 1: I'd like to talk about it.
Speaker 1: Scott doesn't know anything about nor does he like Star Trek.
Speaker 0: nope I do not like Star Trek and I know very little about it.
Speaker 1: and Star Wars.
Speaker 1: I think we did an episode.
Speaker 0: did we do an episode in Star Wars?
Speaker 1: if we didn't then we will and thanks for the suggestions.
Speaker 0: Not much to say about Star Wars other than we really like Star Wars and we think the same things about it that most Other people see.
Speaker 1: I disagree.
Speaker 1: I think there's a lot to say about Star Wars like what we.
Speaker 1: I would talk a lot about Why I liked it and the scenes I like.
Speaker 1: the things I like.
Speaker 0: Vader is awesome.
Speaker 0: X-wings and TIE fighters are awesome.
Speaker 0: The Emperor's awesome.
Speaker 1: I talk about the aesthetics I like.
Speaker 1: I talked about how much or little of a an effect George Lucas probably actually had.
Speaker 1: I talked about the new Episodes and why I think they failed compared to the older ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could do a show by myself for at least a couple hours about Star Wars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it's also still sort of a too general a topic.
Speaker 0: It's like are we gonna talk about the books and the comics and the movies and the TV shows?
Speaker 1: And we could be an overview of the Star Wars universe.
Speaker 0: We could have like a whole Star Wars podcast.
Speaker 0: It's not a Thursday show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: I think it would have been a good Thursday, but Scott was now on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was only Scott.
Speaker 1: I thought it was cool.
Speaker 0: Star Wars is too big an idea.
Speaker 1: I was ready to do the Star Wars episode anyway.
Speaker 0: Any or a general non anime movie show.
Speaker 1: You realize for the first I don't know like five months of geek nights We always defaulted to do in Thursday about whatever movie we just watch.
Speaker 0: Also lately we really kind of stopped watching Movies besides anime movies and even then there's not so many anime movies granted.
Speaker 1: The only reason is that we haven't had time and once the Netflix queue goes off the anime that we've been getting to review We're gonna see a bunch of movies again.
Speaker 0: It's just I think mostly lately.
Speaker 0: There are just too many anime fan subs and we only really have time to watch things in like small blocks as opposed to big Hour blocks to you know and such and also we tend to do some up to do something else instead of watch something.
Speaker 0: We'll always play a game or make something or podcast instead of watching a movie if we have the option.
Speaker 0: Okay, I was thinking a Thursday show talking about strange interesting foods.
Speaker 0: You guys have eaten again with the food again with the food Although the topic is a little more specific, but it's also broad because we eat lots of strange and interesting foods.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is very little of what I eat is interesting to me because like all that like the dim sum breakfast A lot of that stuff is really weird to a lot of people but to me, it's just food that I like.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure what the line is in terms of interesting.
Speaker 0: Oh rim I think you also purposefully eat a lot of foods that just not many other people eat.
Speaker 1: Why like why?
Speaker 0: You're always like what you just talked yesterday about.
Speaker 0: you ate the pet but ten.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what cuz?
Speaker 1: I'd never had it before and I finally had it and it's fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: I didn't say it wasn't but I'm saying you intentionally seem to go out of your way to try all kinds of foods Especially if you think or if they are unpopular in the first part, I won't disagree with.
Speaker 1: I do like to try all sorts of Different foods.
Speaker 1: I'll try just about any food once because I'm curious about it and I've discovered a lot of good foods that way I don't see any backing for the second part at all.
Speaker 0: is all your favorite foods are unpopular in America?
Speaker 1: food What are my favorite food Scott?
Speaker 0: See what does rim really like?
Speaker 1: because I can tell you what one of my fav my favorite white castle White Castle is pretty popular.
Speaker 0: White Castle is not so popular sides.
Speaker 1: I really like White Castle.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with that?
Speaker 1: You're saying that somehow I like White Castle because it's rare or because other people don't I?
Speaker 0: just one of the things you like My favorite meal is raw red meat.
Speaker 0: How is that weird?
Speaker 1: How is that?
Speaker 0: Special because most people don't get it.
Speaker 0: So raw that's only thing, you know, you always but as it tastes better raw.
Speaker 1: That's the only reason.
Speaker 1: if I didn't like the taste of it raw I wouldn't waste my 20 bucks on a steak getting it raw.
Speaker 1: I'd get it cooked.
Speaker 1: However, it tastes the best.
Speaker 0: Last week you had to cook pretty raw and then you put it back on there.
Speaker 1: Actually, I cut it in half.
Speaker 1: I ate half of it raw and I cooked the other half to be rare because I wanted to have both.
Speaker 0: Yeah, always and they know you're putting your dill on your grilled cheese to make it weird.
Speaker 0: No one does that.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know how I learned to put dill on my grilled cheese from the dill bottle.
Speaker 1: the bottle of dill had some suggestions on it.
Speaker 1: It said like what dill is used for and I also looked on some recipe sites and it says that dill is really good on Pork and anything with pork.
Speaker 1: It's really good to be mixed with cheeses and any cheese dish Grilled cheese.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I started putting it on grilled cheese and it's really good.
Speaker 1: Dill is also really good in omelettes and scrambled eggs.
Speaker 0: You just put all sorts of it's like.
Speaker 0: you can't eat something Just plain.
Speaker 0: you always got to reach for that spice box and put all sorts of crap on all sorts of crap.
Speaker 1: I put dill on my grilled cheese.
Speaker 0: you do lots of stuff like what?
Speaker 0: Whenever you cook anything you like just throw so much crap.
Speaker 1: when?
Speaker 1: what do I put in there when I make sauce?
Speaker 1: Sometimes I put a bunch of paprika in to make it spicier.
Speaker 0: You do lots of stuff like what.
Speaker 0: whenever you cook there's always ends up like being four or five spices out.
Speaker 0: You buy like all kinds of spices that I would never even think of using.
Speaker 0: never.
Speaker 1: I haven't bought spices in over a year.
Speaker 0: You just keep using the ones you already bought.
Speaker 1: cuz I bought all the spices I use.
Speaker 0: Yeah You use a lot of spices.
Speaker 1: so I'm saying but I haven't run out of any of them.
Speaker 1: The only one we ran out of we didn't actually run out of.
Speaker 1: we just lost it and then we found it later.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you're not.
Speaker 1: I don't see where you're coming from with this.
Speaker 0: You spice up your food so much and you feel like ketchup on your eggs supposed to put ketchup on a.
Speaker 1: no You're not.
Speaker 1: you realize more Americans do than don't.
Speaker 0: yeah, there are most Americans who don't.
Speaker 1: oh, okay?
Speaker 1: Anyway besides you're the one who makes the McDonald's egg.
Speaker 1: I make an omelet, and you know I make it like.
Speaker 0: I don't make an omelet when I make an omelet We would never was the last day made an omelet the last time.
Speaker 1: I made an omelet.
Speaker 1: I failed yeah Last time before that a few months ago, and I made an omelet with onion I don't think so and some slightly stale taco cheese.
Speaker 0: Who ended this happen?
Speaker 0: You realize I get home before you every day Yeah, so you could just make up any story, and then I supposed to assume.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: So now I mean if we don't have any food eat, and I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: I make some eggs or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right, so let's keep going up this list of ideas.
Speaker 0: how much time do we have left in this crazy?
Speaker 0: We can stop any time good God, so we'll only do a couple more of these ideas.
Speaker 1: We should stop now.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll do one more.
Speaker 1: uh All right, it's all.
Speaker 1: you Antitrust laws all right that would be a topic that require a lot of research and a lot of effort.
Speaker 0: And what do I know about any trust laws?
Speaker 0: you're not allowed to be a monopoly.
Speaker 1: um I know quite a bit.
Speaker 1: I could talk about the history of antitrust laws and all the things that start you know during the Industrial Revolution and the oil industry.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, yeah Rockefeller and all them, but even so Requires a lot of research.
Speaker 0: What do we know about any trust laws?
Speaker 0: that you know.
Speaker 0: it's more of a sudden.
Speaker 0: economist would know so we'd have to research it.
Speaker 1: Well, I know about the history of them, but that's just because I took.
Speaker 1: you know basic high school Civics and basic high school history.
Speaker 0: yeah, but it's like it's also.
Speaker 0: This is another too broad an idea You got.
Speaker 0: it's got to be more specific like history of antitrust laws, or what are the antitrust laws?
Speaker 0: or recent?
Speaker 0: Antitrust Infractions like we could talk about.
Speaker 0: we could do a whole show on Microsoft's antitrust.
Speaker 0: That's a Monday.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I'm just saying in general you know that's I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think you're asking too much of these people.
Speaker 1: I mean they just need to give us a seed idea and then we go from there.
Speaker 1: we can pick what direction we want to Go with the idea.
Speaker 0: It's true, but it just feels like going through these ideas.
Speaker 0: You know people submit them And we don't actually end up thinking up a better show to do.
Speaker 0: besides talk about all the ideas people came.
Speaker 1: That's just because all the ideas are food.
Speaker 1: Don't ever suggest food.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna do food episodes.
Speaker 1: We're done.
Speaker 1: Go listen to a cooking podcast be and then tell us which ones are good.
Speaker 1: Yes This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.