Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, May 8th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we teach you all about the old old NES game.
Speaker 1: rescue the embassy mission.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So today I saved a crow and as a result, I almost missed my train.
Speaker 1: Why would you save a crow?
Speaker 0: Well, I I changed trains between the nice train that takes me up to Croton and then the diesel ugly smelly train that takes Me the rest of the way.
Speaker 0: and you know over the train tracks in most places in downstate, New York There's a lot of those big glassed in walkways.
Speaker 0: You go up the stairs go across the tracks come down to whatever platform you're supposed to be on.
Speaker 0: Yeah well none of the windows up there open and somehow this big crow had gotten himself up there and he didn't know how to get out and He was banging into windows back and forth.
Speaker 0: He'd obviously been at this for a while.
Speaker 0: He was pretty tired.
Speaker 0: His mouth was hanging open and he had this look of what.
Speaker 0: what am I doing wrong?
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: Ah and people were kind of avoiding him and every now and then someone walk over like they're gonna help him and then they'd think and realize They couldn't come up with any way to help him short of grabbing him, which probably wasn't the best idea.
Speaker 1: No crows are kind of dirty and nasty.
Speaker 0: No, they're not really dirty and nasty not like pigeons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those pigeons are dirtier and SDR doesn't mean crows are not dirty and they're not.
Speaker 0: The only reason I didn't grab the crow was that I really didn't feel like getting my hands picked up Because I'm pretty sure I could have caught him.
Speaker 0: he was still pretty dazed up there.
Speaker 1: Well, I realized that you know short of say hummingbirds and things.
Speaker 1: You can grab a lot of birds if you really want to but you got a really want it for real.
Speaker 0: Emily knew someone who not only could grab seagulls, but liked to Wow Okay, I don't like to but I'm pretty sure that I could.
Speaker 1: and one day when I get some gloves.
Speaker 1: I'm totally grabbing pigeons Just to prove it to myself that I can do it.
Speaker 0: We'll have to get a video of it.
Speaker 0: Send it to pen Like see what you did see what you made us do.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I decide alright I can't?
Speaker 0: I go down to my platform and then I think no I can't leave that crew up there.
Speaker 0: so I go back up and I try to and I realize that the best way to the course of action after I realized that There's no way to open any of those windows is to as best as I can direct the crow Toward the stairway and shoot which is also glass all the way down it and trick him into going all the way down and then flying away Mm-hmm, but if I make any sudden moves or direct in the wrong way He just flies into a window and hurts himself further.
Speaker 0: So it was kind of like a puzzle game and I spend several minutes kind of like Maneuvering very slowly and like put my arms in different ways and I get him to go down the stairs and then stair by stair I kind of push him down and then eventually he gets outside and he sits there for a minute and he's like I don't know like he expected there to be another glass wall in And then he flies away really cautiously and then he shits about four times and then he disappears.
Speaker 0: He was like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess he was stressed out.
Speaker 1: Maybe he wasn't shit.
Speaker 1: unless he's flying I don't know.
Speaker 1: They don't shit when they're standing.
Speaker 0: So I saved him and then I ran to my train and that was my story for today.
Speaker 1: They just there reminds me when I was a kid one time.
Speaker 1: and there's a bird in the yard And it was there for days and it was hobbling around.
Speaker 1: So we called.
Speaker 1: he tried to figure out who to call to take care of this bird.
Speaker 0: animal control.
Speaker 1: we called various animal controls and Eventually, we got to someone who didn't tell us to call someone else and they said what kind of bird is it?
Speaker 1: I'm like, I don't know It's a bird.
Speaker 1: It's hobbling.
Speaker 1: They're like, well, what color is it?
Speaker 1: I'm like black.
Speaker 1: They're like, oh, it's a crow.
Speaker 1: Whatever We're not doing shit for it.
Speaker 1: Nah, apparently Rim cares more about the animal crow than the animal control.
Speaker 0: Well, you realize that animal controls primary duty is to remove dangerous animals.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there weren't so many dangerous animals for them to remove in my town.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like what a week?
Speaker 0: what they usually do is remove like a rabid whatever that's water.
Speaker 1: Yeah We've called them for that before, you know skunk during the day Strange badger or raccoon during the day in the backyard.
Speaker 0: See when I was a kid Not badger, but there was a skunk in high school who would come out during the day all the time, but he wasn't rabid.
Speaker 0: He was just old and pissed off.
Speaker 1: It's even worse At least worse for people.
Speaker 1: Yep So today there was a pleasant surprise that no one expected and the people who released the surprise didn't even say anything about it And it was up to the people on the internet to discover it for themselves.
Speaker 1: You may know that Google has a program called Google Reader.
Speaker 1: It is an RSS feed reader.
Speaker 1: you subscribe to RSS feeds and it Allows you to read all the news in those feeds and a very convenient and easy to use interface on a web page.
Speaker 0: sadly While a wallet is definitely probably the best RSS reader out there period I don't find it that useful.
Speaker 0: But that's just me.
Speaker 1: I pretty much read all the news on the internet exclusively through Google Reader.
Speaker 1: See the original Google Reader sucked.
Speaker 1: It was just kind of fancy but not too useful and the recent the new Google Reader Pretty much beats the shit out of blog lines and in all those other things.
Speaker 0: I really only use it so I can read headlines from news sites that are blocked at work So I know what the news is when I get home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty good use right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's the only use.
Speaker 0: I never use it outside of work ever.
Speaker 1: See I subscribe to like 30 something feeds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just find if I try to get all the news in my feeds I either get a lot of duplicates because all the sites get a lot of duplicates.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't like that.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it at that point.
Speaker 1: Oh, see I just I get so many duplicates, you know I basically scroll down and I process the headlines in my mind very quickly And when I see something that I actually want to read I click I open a new tab and I keep going and I've seen Something before.
Speaker 1: I just keep going.
Speaker 0: see the thing is if I just go to dig slash dot FARC right in a row I see 99% of what I would have seen in Google Reader and if I need any like Oh real news.
Speaker 1: I also hit the Google News to have Google News dig and slash dot in my Google Reader and a FARC in there.
Speaker 1: And it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: only it's about taking me less time.
Speaker 1: that's what it's about.
Speaker 1: You know, it takes me longer to go and read dig.
Speaker 1: it would take.
Speaker 1: that's like, you know If I wake up in the morning, there's like three new pages of digs after read three pages worth it all that scrolling.
Speaker 1: I can go through everything a lot faster in Google Reader.
Speaker 1: It takes me less time to process the same information.
Speaker 1: That's what it's about.
Speaker 0: So I guess I don't don't go through everything because a lot of it.
Speaker 0: I don't care about Everything.
Speaker 1: the stuff I don't care about I just scroll right past.
Speaker 0: that's what the use of dig is for me.
Speaker 0: I just only look at what's on the front page.
Speaker 0: And if it didn't if it's not on the front page when I go to dig it's probably irrelevant.
Speaker 1: Oh, but see what if something was awesome was on the front page when you weren't looking at it for yesterday.
Speaker 0: It depends on how awesome it is.
Speaker 0: one the videos.
Speaker 0: there aren't enough videos period so I see them all no matter what and for Anything else if it's that awesome.
Speaker 0: It's on FARC and I see everything on FARC.
Speaker 1: Well, regardless it takes me less time to process all that same news on one page where everything is just a single line as Opposed to many pages of things are spread out.
Speaker 0: It really doesn't help that the vast majority of RSS feeds are garbage.
Speaker 1: Well, that's another advantage of Google Reader.
Speaker 1: Is that it handles?
Speaker 1: Yes, it's.
Speaker 1: it's good enough to handle crappy RSS feeds in ways that other readers do not.
Speaker 0: that is definitely true.
Speaker 0: If only could handle the dupes on really poorly done RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, so this Google Reader, which you're this gaming day, so you probably don't care about Google Reader Google without saying a word released a special version of Google Reader that you can use on the Wii
Speaker 0: Hot damn,
Speaker 1: so if you got your Wii browser and you know that we news channel is pretty good I kind of like it, but it only reads the AP news wire doesn't read any other news.
Speaker 1: Well now you can go to Google Reader and your Wii Opera and do the same sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Only any news you want you could read.
Speaker 1: you can listen to geek nights.
Speaker 1: Well, if you had enough RAM in the Wii, which you know But you could read geek nights is webpage through the Google Reader.
Speaker 0: If only they would just set it up to where you could plug a flash drive into the Wii and it would just work as RAM for the browser.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they they only did that in the DS.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're gonna do that on the Wii.
Speaker 0: If only they'd released the Opera DS cartridge in the US.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think they're on their way to doing it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they're not gonna be a while.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna release the DS fat version in stores, you're gonna have to special order that that's fine.
Speaker 0: I don't have a DS fat.
Speaker 1: I know but I'm awesome.
Speaker 1: I don't really want the Opera DS browser.
Speaker 1: Anyway, cuz I have a laptop.
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 0: I want it because one I don't have a laptop.
Speaker 0: and even when I get a Laptop, there's a difference between like say I'm just walking and I want to check something really quick pulling the laptop out booting it Connecting to the Wi-Fi versus just I got my DS out.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's probably my pocket.
Speaker 0: I just go whip bam slash dot and then I leave.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't really have that need.
Speaker 1: and like I used to have that ability when I had the blackberry whatever and I never really Used that.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I see myself using it A lot for is suddenly hitting a Google Maps while I'm out in the city somewhere.
Speaker 1: I had Google Maps on the blackberry and I never really used it.
Speaker 0: I don't know I see myself using it a lot but part of that is cuz I go to places that I'm not familiar with all over the Bronx Using a little book or a paper map more often, but well to see that little books.
Speaker 1: great unless you're looking for a business Yeah, yeah, and if I was, you know looking for something like that if I really needed this feature suddenly I just used the one on my phone.
Speaker 0: because Yeah, well unless I hack my phone I have to pay quite a bit of money.
Speaker 1: I had to pay like five bucks.
Speaker 1: It's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do have a new phone.
Speaker 0: No, I got my razor.
Speaker 1: Oh great.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 0: It's okay It was free.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's better than any cell phone.
Speaker 0: I've ever owned which I that's true I can say about every cell phone I have ever owned.
Speaker 1: that is also true.
Speaker 0: and in two years, I'm gonna get a new phone.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's true.
Speaker 1: Also Yeah, so if you want to read some RSS feeds Google reader We the cool thing about this is they actually have Like things bound to the different buttons on your remote and that's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: how they got a web page To recognize the remote buttons like, you know pushing button one does this and button two does that and plus and minus?
Speaker 1: You know do this and that and that's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: that they got a web page to recognize those things.
Speaker 1: It's not easy to do for you non tech people out there.
Speaker 0: So a water of Nintendo fame came out and there's a lot of articles and headlines basically saying something along the lines of hardcore gamers will be satisfied by the end of 2007 in regards to the Wii and the article is actually very long.
Speaker 0: It comes from an interview with Iwata and I'm not gonna go through all the points He makes because he talks about a lot and I if you're a Nintendo fan or a video gamer at all I highly recommend that you read the transcript because You'll get a lot of insight into the direction Nintendo's heading and also a lot of the Ideas that Iwata has personally about gaming.
Speaker 0: he says that currently there are 45 Wii games in development and another 79 DS titles though many of them are second party.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I guess all I can really say about the gaming part is that it's about time Because the DS when it started didn't really have so much for it.
Speaker 0: It was kind of a waste and after I played the three games I bought I really didn't use it much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got the DS.
Speaker 1: I'd like Mario 64 and it was like I still I'd.
Speaker 1: never after I other games came out for the DS I stopped playing Mario 64.
Speaker 1: I never went back to it.
Speaker 0: See luckily.
Speaker 0: I'd never played Mario 64.
Speaker 0: So that was actually pretty fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was fun because I while I had played Mario 64 in the past.
Speaker 1: I hadn't played it out.
Speaker 1: So this said played it out for me and I don't need to play Mario 64 ever again for a long time Yep.
Speaker 0: But the DS finally is coming to its own and games that fully use it or at least Really respect all the capabilities of the DS are coming out.
Speaker 0: and I mean if you need any indication of how well the DS is going You still can't buy one in Japan.
Speaker 0: They're constantly sold out no matter what the DS sells crazily.
Speaker 0: It's amazing and I can see why the DS is still I would say the best console in the world right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's probably oh, it's the best console ever.
Speaker 1: It could be I don't know.
Speaker 0: I I think in a few more years I would consider it the best console ever in terms of the use.
Speaker 1: I've gotten out of it unless something else comes along that can unseat it.
Speaker 1: but as of right now I think the DS might be the best console ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah but the Wii is still in the same boat that the DS was when it first came out with one important difference which I think is hurting the Wii in terms of gamers like us and the so-called hardcore gamer which is I really don't like that word because People really use it in a lot of different ways and the media really Throws it around and it really isn't a useful word anymore.
Speaker 0: because what constitutes a hardcore gamer?
Speaker 0: But the DS did really poorly early on in terms of there weren't good games for it And then the good games came out.
Speaker 0: the Wii Did really well right away because of Wii Sports and there weren't too many other great games.
Speaker 0: The Wii is still doing really really great and selling out because of Wii Sports Which is great for most people.
Speaker 0: but people like us.
Speaker 0: I haven't even touched the Wii in months because the best game on it is still WarioWare for the Gamecube.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not the.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna do it that way then the best game for it is probably I don't know Pac-man first Pac-man first like four swords or something like that.
Speaker 0: But but the DS had some hard-hitting games coming out because.
Speaker 0: well I don't know if it was because but I would assume it was because that was how to sell it the moment It wasn't selling so well You got to do something to get people to want of DS and now everyone wants a DS.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the big difference is that when Nintendo was coming with the DS, right?
Speaker 1: Everyone was super skeptical.
Speaker 1: They were like, there's no way What's his third pillar shit?
Speaker 0: I was gonna have to kill.
Speaker 1: I was skeptical.
Speaker 1: I was like at work.
Speaker 1: I said when I bought the DS at worst This is gonna be another virtual boy and at best it'll be awesome.
Speaker 1: So I can't lose by buying it because at the worst I own the virtual boy, which I wouldn't mind doing so.
Speaker 1: Everyone was skeptical of the DS.
Speaker 1: so not too many people ran out and bought it right away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did for no good reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't even have a podcast back then.
Speaker 0: It's not like we were gonna review.
Speaker 1: I did for the reason I just said at worst It was gonna be virtual boy, and I wanted one.
Speaker 1: so it came out and there weren't so many good games right away.
Speaker 1: But I basically bought every game that might have been good for it.
Speaker 1: I've got a lot of DS games now and they're all.
Speaker 0: most of them are really good But the Wii I think partly everyone who was skeptical of the DS thought All right, I learned my lesson never doubt Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Wii is gonna be hot shit.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: by the time the Wii came around the DS had already proven itself and people were like Oh the DS.
Speaker 1: we were skeptical of that and it was awesome.
Speaker 1: And now here's the Wii.
Speaker 1: Oh, no reason to be skeptical anymore.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be as awesome as the DS.
Speaker 0: and I think the Wii is selling solely Solely on the merit of its potential because it currently doesn't have the merit to justify the sales It has.
Speaker 1: is is the Wii is a pile of unfulfilled potential.
Speaker 0: However, if the DS is any indication that potential will eventually be met I imagine it will be met within 12 months.
Speaker 0: and I think if all 12 months when all these games come out because these are All the games that I'm personally waiting for these are games that a lot of people are personally waiting for.
Speaker 0: They didn't wait to buy a Wii to get these games, which is great for Nintendo because you got your money early.
Speaker 0: But I think when these games come out in the end of this year There's gonna be a huge surge in Wii playing suddenly.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be quite insane.
Speaker 0: I mean I smash brothers?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and until then the Pokemons and the DS will hold everyone over.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Good God the Pokemons.
Speaker 0: Yeah all I have to say about that is I had never played a Pokemon game until this one and I'm glad I didn't because if I had played a Pokemon game when I was young and I had infinite free time coupled with zero Responsibility and infinite boredom, I'd be fucked now.
Speaker 0: I would have known everything about Pokemon and I wouldn't have known calculus.
Speaker 1: Yeah Possibly what a good thing.
Speaker 0: the Pokemons didn't come out until like I was already in high school and stuff, but Particularly the Smash Brothers brawl because the GameCube was as far as I was concerned nothing until Smash Brothers came out and basically One Smash Brothers came out.
Speaker 0: the GameCube became a Smash Brothers machine for like six months.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean we played it every day.
Speaker 0: Everyone did.
Speaker 0: yep, and this one's gonna be better.
Speaker 0: I'm certain of it.
Speaker 0: I'm so looking forward to this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one last thing about that Miyamoto interview.
Speaker 1: in that interview He mentions Def Con which I think is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: that Miyamoto knows about Def Con and respects it.
Speaker 0: actually Iwata made a really interesting point about Second Life and he basically said that he has no interest in it and He kind of gives the impression that he thinks it's dumb and that no one will remember it in a fairly short order.
Speaker 0: Hmm and a lot of people are speculating that this might be him indirectly saying that he thinks MMOs are garbage Which means there's probably never going to be a Pokemon MMO Probably which is possibly a good thing for the world.
Speaker 0: But I really think that as much as I dislike MMOs just for the the bare nature of what they are I will not deny that a Pokemon MMO would probably make more money than you can possibly imagine.
Speaker 0: It would probably be the like.
Speaker 1: it would one of the few possible ways to beat World of Warcraft right now.
Speaker 1: It'd be a Pokemon MMO
Speaker 0: because I know a lot of people who would play a Pokemon MMO
Speaker 1: like a giant multi-continent world where everyone walks around catching Pokemon Training them and then fighting each other where you
Speaker 0: upload all the Pokemon you have from all your Pokemon games to the Nintendo server and your Pokemon are now guaranteed and taken care of forever and
Speaker 1: like every they give you can play this MMO with their DS or your Wii or your PC or your cell phone or Whatever and you can even like buy collectible cards and they'll interact with the MMO.
Speaker 1: It would be the king of kings.
Speaker 1: Everything they tried to do with stuff like hack sign or that new thing that guy keeps trying to market to us will actually Succeed if Pokemon does it.
Speaker 0: I mean if I even if I didn't have venture capital or anything I would stake pretty much everything I own all of my fiscal assets on the success of a Pokemon MMO.
Speaker 0: I would also like without even a hesitation no hesitate Things of the day right along with the main bit here.
Speaker 0: my thing of the day is a video that I found when I was looking for some video footage of rescue the embassy mission.
Speaker 0: that contains footage from rescue the embassy mission and Golgo 13 for the NES and it's basically one of those silly music videos and they make the characters dance and it's kind of Funny.
Speaker 0: and that's all I got to say about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, rim found this video and I was like, ah, it looks like some random YouTube crap.
Speaker 1: and then we watched it.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it was actually slightly amusing.
Speaker 0: I mean, it was pretty dumb at first and I thought all right Is this just some guy playing a song he likes while he plays this game and then right away?
Speaker 0: The one guy does this little dance and then I realized exactly what was going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's the greatest video, but it's great because it meets it beats expectations Which is why it's worth being a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Yes, also in case you don't want to get a hold of the ROM or actually play this game You can see exactly what this game is all about.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So a while ago.
Speaker 1: I did a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: you know some roguelike games a type of adventure RPG game that is popular among certain circles of people.
Speaker 0: I had a really bad one called dungeon hack that I eventually got rid of.
Speaker 1: All right Well today I have for you a list of games that are in the point-and-click adventure.
Speaker 0: You know, you're off your space quests Quest for glory police quest the star quest star games.
Speaker 1: Yep, the you know anything involving the word quest?
Speaker 1: King's Quest Anything maniac mansions all those sorts of games Monkey Island.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you like those kinds of games a deja vu shadow game.
Speaker 0: Ah Shadow game one of my favorite games ever.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's relevant actually to today.
Speaker 0: I open the door.
Speaker 1: death How you alright death Alright, so if you like those kind of games.
Speaker 1: Here is a list of 20 point-and-click adventure games that are going to be out this year.
Speaker 0: Are any of on the DS?
Speaker 1: I don't think so I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think they're mostly talking about PC ones that you can down.
Speaker 0: Ah, it's still to me one of the greatest crimes that no one has gotten a license to take all of those quest for glory whatever games and Put them on the DS.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean there are some point-and-click adventures to the DS.
Speaker 1: I mean you got your Phoenix right which is sort of like that.
Speaker 1: You've got your.
Speaker 1: what's that are the lost in blue type stuff?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they're they're really different.
Speaker 0: They're not the same kind of game?
Speaker 0: No, they're not and I see no reason not to port them.
Speaker 0: Those games would definitely fit on a DS cart.
Speaker 0: They do super well.
Speaker 0: I'm almost sure of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't understand why people like they always concentrate on making like new crap games and they're just Already existing easily ported games that can sell a lot.
Speaker 1: It's like why do they just don't?
Speaker 1: uh, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway game publishers just aren't thinking but and yet we can't get a dev kit and do it ourselves.
Speaker 1: No, if you like point-and-click adventures, here you go.
Speaker 1: This is what you have to look forward to in the year to come.
Speaker 1: Have fun.
Speaker 0: So back when I was a kid one of the many many Nintendo games that I owned and/or rented Was rescue the embassy mission rescue colon the embassy mission.
Speaker 1: The game was called just rescue but you know, the subtext was the embassy mission.
Speaker 1: Yes released in 1990 by Kemco the same people who did shadow gate and deja vu deja vu to ha how about that?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now for some reason we were reminded of this game recently.
Speaker 0: I don't even really remember Why.
Speaker 0: I think it's because I often go off and hum the the song doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo Doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: get the ticket ticket ticket ticket ticket ticket ticket ticket Gets crazier as you get into a more dangerous situation when you're in a less dangerous situation.
Speaker 1: It just goes doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 0: there's only one other song that really infiltrates our consciousness like that and that's the song from doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: Because I was humming the song as I often do we were reminded of risky embassy mission.
Speaker 1: He said hey Let's do a random show In an old NES game that you can really only play if you get the rom or get the cartridge.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a unique game, and I'm surprised that no one has ever tried to remake this game on another console.
Speaker 0: Yeah, alright.
Speaker 1: This is a game in which you are a team of, what, like SWAT guys, or SEALs, or some sort of military strike force.
Speaker 1: Think, uh, Section 9, Ghost in the Shell type of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're basically just the SWAT team.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's an embassy.
Speaker 1: There's an embassy.
Speaker 1: It's in- it's in- it's in town.
Speaker 1: The embassy in town.
Speaker 1: Who knows what country it's for.
Speaker 0: Ono is terrorists.
Speaker 1: Ono is terrorists.
Speaker 1: They have taken over the embassy.
Speaker 1: They are holding all the ambassadors hostage.
Speaker 1: You have to rescue the ambassadors.
Speaker 0: Are you a bad enough dude to rescue the hostages?
Speaker 1: You have to rescue the hostages, and kill all the terrorists, and then you win.
Speaker 1: And you've only got so many minutes to do this because there's a bomb or something?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: I think that's just when diplomatic relations break down, or they kill the hostages, or... It doesn't really matter.
Speaker 1: You only have, like, 10, 15- you don't have much time to save these hostages.
Speaker 0: You're very- The SWAT is pretty flimsy.
Speaker 0: Don't even worry about it.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So, what do you do to rescue these hostages?
Speaker 0: Well, see, here's what makes the game really unique.
Speaker 0: In that, one, for a Nintendo game, it was far more complex than most other Nintendo games of the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was- but it was really short, you know, so it was like a really complex, but really condensed.
Speaker 0: Basically, they came up with these four different games that in and of themselves were not a whole game.
Speaker 0: Like, they wouldn't have been worth buying a cartridge for, but they were really fun.
Speaker 0: At least, most of them were kind of fun.
Speaker 0: One of them was super fun.
Speaker 1: One of them is stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of them is pretty stupid, but it was also awesome because of how I learned how to do it.
Speaker 1: Yes, yes.
Speaker 0: But, they combined them all together, and the game basically goes through four phases.
Speaker 0: And each phase is basically a separate game, but each one is contingent on the previous one in some way.
Speaker 1: Yep, the phases actually affect each other, and it feels like you're controlling this entire team, executing every part of an actual mission to actually rescue ambassadors.
Speaker 0: Now, there have been games that have done the FPS part of this game that have been very similar.
Speaker 0: I mean, Counter-Strike even is a lot like this in some ways.
Speaker 1: Yep, but Counter-Strike doesn't have the first three parts that are nothing like the part that is like Counter-Strike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now I'm not going to pretend that the whole game is great, because the last part kind of sucks, the third part...
Speaker 1: Really sucks.
Speaker 0: ...is awesome because it's hilarious, but it's not good.
Speaker 1: No, the first part is awesome, and the second part is okay.
Speaker 0: I would love for someone to make a game that was just the first part and was really long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would also love that.
Speaker 1: It would also be fucking impossible.
Speaker 0: So basically, you control the four phases of the game, and the first phase is you've got three snipers.
Speaker 0: Jumbo, Kemko...
Speaker 1: I think it's Jumbo, Mike, and someone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, right.
Speaker 0: Kemko is in the second half.
Speaker 0: Doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: So you've got these guys, these three.
Speaker 1: And they have to get in position to snipe.
Speaker 1: They're just standing around, you know, like by the squad car or whatever they're near.
Speaker 1: And they need to get into sniping position on the three sides of the building that face the street.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the game actually gives you this fun interface where it shows the blueprints of the building and the area around it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically it's a street that's in the shape of a U, and the embassy is in the middle of the U, so it's surrounded on three sides by street and one side by other buildings.
Speaker 1: So you have to get a sniper basically into a hiding position on each of the three sides of the embassy that are facing the street so that you can shoot into the embassy to kill a terrorist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it gives you this fun interface where it shows you the blueprint and everything.
Speaker 0: And it doesn't really matter, you don't really have control, but you pick like, "Alright, I'm gonna send the three snipers
Speaker 0: out.".
Speaker 0: "Alright, now I'm gonna send Kemko to repel down the thing, I'm gonna snipe with Jumbo, I'm gonna do this and this and
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 0: And it's kind of like you're the commander of this SWAT team operation.
Speaker 1: So in this first part where you get the snipers in position...
Speaker 0: Which is pretty much the whole game.
Speaker 1: Which is pretty much the whole game, is really cool because it's a side-scrolling stealth game, sort of like Metal Gear, not really.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you've got your dude, and there's searchlights from the terrorists in the embassy, and they're going around.
Speaker 1: And if the searchlights see your sniper walking down the street, they're gonna shoot him and kill him, and there's nothing he can do about it.
Speaker 0: Well, they might not kill him.
Speaker 0: The thing is, if you get spotted by the searchlights, they open fire.
Speaker 0: And depending on what you're doing, or who it is shooting, the odds of getting hit are pretty high, but they're not 100%.
Speaker 1: It's not 100%, but you're usually gonna get killed.
Speaker 1: The idea is to avoid the searchlights, and then you win.
Speaker 0: So you've gotta slowly make your way down the street to get to a building where you can then have a sniper position without getting shot.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So you walk from left to right.
Speaker 1: But, so, is that interesting?
Speaker 1: You just walk from left to right, avoiding lights.
Speaker 1: That's just the timing of walking.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: There's more interesting things to it.
Speaker 0: You see, despite the fact that it's an NES game, and the biggest problem with a lot of early NES games was if you wanted to do anything complicated, there were only two buttons and the D-pad.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And Start and Select you really couldn't use for gameplay stuff.
Speaker 0: Very few games use those buttons for gameplay stuff.
Speaker 0: Mhm.
Speaker 0: So, games had to do stupid tricks like, alright, hit A or B to do two different things, and hit A and B at the same time to do something else, or hold up and B or up or whatever, and it usually was very clunky and difficult to use.
Speaker 0: But in this game, the control scheme is fairly elegant, and yet, you have a lot of options.
Speaker 0: You can walk, you can dive, you can jump behind things, you can roll, you can duck down and crawl.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can get in a prone position and shimmy along the ground in two different directions.
Speaker 1: I think the reason that this was actually able to do this is because there's no shooting.
Speaker 1: Now you have both buttons used only for movement maneuvers, and there's nothing to shoot.
Speaker 1: You're just trying to dodge.
Speaker 1: So one button is roll, and one button is jump behind stuff.
Speaker 1: Well, up is jump behind stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You can do all sorts of things.
Speaker 1: You can end up and duck, do different things.
Speaker 0: And I gotta say, as a kid playing this game, my nerves were shot anytime I played, because this game, nowadays, I don't care, like whatever, but when I was a kid, it's kind of like how Castlevania 2 was really creepy to me.
Speaker 0: Playing this game and trying to avoid those searchlights, you get really freaking nervous, because you see, alright, the next place I can hide, because you can always, if you can get into a little building, or behind a bush or something, you're safe.
Speaker 0: But there's not always something to jump behind.
Speaker 0: So it'd be like, you go, go, go, go, go, go, ah, safe.
Speaker 0: And you can sit there as long as you want.
Speaker 0: The timer keeps ticking down, but you have like 15 minutes.
Speaker 0: 15 minutes.
Speaker 1: 15 minutes for the whole game.
Speaker 1: The more time you waste putting snipers in position is less time for sniping.
Speaker 1: Let's say you get all the snipers in position, and then you do all your sniping, and then you get in the building, and you've got a minute left.
Speaker 1: Now you've got a minute to kill all the remaining terrorists and rescue the hostages.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: It's not going to happen, because you took too long.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So there was always, I'd get safe, and then I'd sit there, and it took such a mental effort to force myself to pull the character out of the safe spot and run past the next gauntlet of searchlights.
Speaker 1: So you try to get these three snipers in position.
Speaker 1: Getting the first one in position is pretty easy.
Speaker 1: Getting the second one in position is kinda, sorta easy.
Speaker 1: Getting the third one in position is really hard, because he has to go really far, and he has to go into a lot of tricky situations.
Speaker 0: Until I watched a video of the completion of this game in an optimal manner, I had never seen the end of the sniper guy path.
Speaker 0: I had never gotten Jumbo to the end.
Speaker 0: Jumbo had never survived.
Speaker 1: Now keep in mind that this game has many, many different difficulty selections.
Speaker 1: You can set this game anywhere from stupidly easy to impossibly ludicrously hard, and the game changes drastically depending on which setting you choose.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of in-between settings, so you can work your way up slowly to actually beating the impossibly hard mode.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But even on the impossibly easy mode, I never got Jumbo over there.
Speaker 1: That's how tricky this game is.
Speaker 0: Now, what always bothered me was that, why didn't they just take the back door to whatever building they're gonna snipe?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess there's only one street in the world.
Speaker 1: And the game wouldn't be fun, because the most fun part of the game wouldn't happen.
Speaker 0: The really cool thing too is that there aren't lives or anything.
Speaker 0: You just have three snipers, three guys who bust into the building, and that's it.
Speaker 0: And if a sniper dies, he's dead.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Use the next sniper.
Speaker 0: And you don't have to get all three snipers in position.
Speaker 1: You don't have to get any of the snipers in position.
Speaker 0: No, you have to get at least one.
Speaker 1: You have to get at least one?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm pretty sure you have to get at least one.
Speaker 1: Well, let's say you only get two snipers in position.
Speaker 1: Well, let's say I get the one for the left side of the building and the one for the north side of the building.
Speaker 1: I'm just not gonna be able to snipe on the east side of the building.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there might be terrorists over there, and I can't kill them this way.
Speaker 0: Now I gotta kill them the hard way.
Speaker 1: Actually, I think it's technically northwest and south, but you get my point.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If I get two snipers in position, I can snipe two sides of the building, and the third side of the building goes unsniped.
Speaker 0: Now, while it's fairly primitive, it does something that so few games do, partly because it's hard to do, and partly because it's not worth the effort to do, because most people wouldn't care.
Speaker 0: But I love the idea of a game where succeeding at the mission, you continue.
Speaker 0: Failing at the mission does not end the game.
Speaker 0: The game continues with the ramifications of having failed that mission.
Speaker 0: Imagine a game like Advance Wars, where if you lose a battle to, say, take a port, now the war continues, but you don't have that port.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: No games really do that, but this game kinda does in a really primitive way, where if only one sniper made it, you've only got one fucking sniper now.
Speaker 1: Yep, but at least if those other snipers die really quickly, then you'll still have a lot of time.
Speaker 0: I would usually just kill Jumbo, because it wasn't worth just spending all that time only to die.
Speaker 1: Yep, because remember, the whole game only takes, like, 15 minutes, and then you're done.
Speaker 1: I think actually in the harder modes, you have less time to do the whole game.
Speaker 0: Now the best part, and I want to point this out, on the screen where you pick guys, whenever it shows a guy, one of the snipers, it's like the blueprint map, right?
Speaker 0: The guy's little avatar is, like, popping up and down, bursting through the paper, and it's really, really funny.
Speaker 1: It is pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, you get the snipers in position.
Speaker 1: Now what?
Speaker 1: Obviously, you snipe!
Speaker 0: Sniping is frustrating, and frustrating, but at the same time, it's really not that bad, because a lot of other games, like Golgo 13, tried to do sniping on the NES, and it was ass!
Speaker 1: Basically, all you do is you have this circle, and you move this circle, you can look at one side of the building, depending on which sniper you're using, you know, so, and you can switch between all the snipers at will.
Speaker 1: So if you have all three snipers in position, you can say, "I want to snipe with that sniper now.
Speaker 1: Ah, forget that, I want to snipe with this sniper
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 1: And you can just snipe to your heart's content.
Speaker 1: But every second you spend sniping is the second you're spending not beating the game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And I'd always have this debate where, "How long was I going to sit there waiting for someone to walk by a window and blow them
Speaker 0: away?".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So when you snipe, basically you look at one side of the building, depending on which sniper you're using, And you can look at any window, and there's, like, nine windows.
Speaker 1: And all you do is you have this targeting reticle, and you move it around, and there's nine windows in each side of the building, or twelve?
Speaker 0: I don't remember, I think it's nine.
Speaker 1: I think it's nine.
Speaker 1: And you look in the windows, and if you shoot a window, it breaks.
Speaker 1: And if you see a shadow in the window, you shoot it.
Speaker 1: And if you shoot and successfully hit that guy in the window, he dies.
Speaker 0: And they simulate, you know, it's difficult to snipe, but the cursor kind of moves around a lot, really annoying, but it's not super annoying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not like those games where it just flies around the screen and you can't control it, but the targeting reticle will move a little bit on its own, and sometimes you'll miss the guy you're trying to shoot because of it.
Speaker 0: Now, the thing I really liked was that the guys walk around, the terrorists walk around dynamically, and they could come anywhere, it's kind of random.
Speaker 0: The thing that was hilarious was, sometimes you see a guy, like, peek out a window and walk away, and then he comes back, and you shoot, and say you miss, and you've shattered the window now.
Speaker 0: He'll probably just come back and look out the window again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the movement of the guys in the building is sort of random.
Speaker 0: The terrorists are stupid!
Speaker 0: You can shoot four guys in a window, and there's obviously a pile of four dead bodies behind that window, and a fifth terrorist will walk over, "Huh, I wonder what happened here," and just poke his head out the window.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sometimes that'll happen, sometimes it won't, it's kind of random.
Speaker 1: Generally what I do is I do each sniper that I have available, I'll check out each window for maybe ten seconds each, something like that, five seconds each, just to make sure.
Speaker 1: Then after I've checked all the windows, I'll scan them all once more really quickly to make sure there isn't an easy kill, then I'll go to the next sniper.
Speaker 1: Because sniping, all it really does is make the final part of the game easier for you, because there'll be less guys.
Speaker 1: Every guy you kill sniping is a guy.
Speaker 1: you don't have to kill walking around inside the building with your assault rifle.
Speaker 0: Now, the third part of the game- The bad part of the game.
Speaker 1: I think it's cool, but I want to present- It's cool, but it sucks.
Speaker 0: The third part of the game, from the eyes of a kid, Rim.
Speaker 0: Little Rim.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Who got this game?
Speaker 0: from Blockbuster, he rented it.
Speaker 0: It might have been Mammoth Video, I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: I don't remember where I played this, but I played it, and I remember seeing it in a video game magazine, but I definitely did not own it.
Speaker 0: So I got this game, never played it before, didn't have an instruction book.
Speaker 0: And I get to this part of the game, where I pick one of my guys, and I say, "Alright, go
Speaker 0: in."
Speaker 0: And I pick which side of the building and which row of windows I want.
Speaker 1: Yep, because that's what you do.
Speaker 1: You have a guy on the roof, and he needs to get in the building.
Speaker 1: So he's going to rappel down the side of the building, and crash through one of the windows.
Speaker 0: So it shows me my guy hanging just over the roof, like just down the side of the building, from a rope, like he's going to rappel.
Speaker 0: Alright, and it doesn't say what to do.
Speaker 0: So I hit A, and my guy swings out, and swings back in.
Speaker 1: He basically kicks off the side of the building.
Speaker 0: And then lands back on the exact same spot.
Speaker 1: And then swings back, and he's leaning against the building again.
Speaker 0: On the exact same spot.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, "Alright, that's what that button
Speaker 0: does.".
Speaker 0: So then I hit down, and he moves down a few inches, and then falls to his death.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he just lets go of the rope and dies.
Speaker 0: Shit.
Speaker 0: So I take my second guy, and I hit down, and he falls to his death.
Speaker 0: Third guy, falls to his death, game over.
Speaker 1: It's really annoying, because all you should have to do with this part of the game is hold down, to move down, to the part of the window you want to- That's not how rappelling works.
Speaker 1: I know, but that's how it should work in a video game.
Speaker 0: No, because in the video game, it's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: I think in this part, it suffers from being too simple.
Speaker 0: They could have made it more complex and cool.
Speaker 1: Eh, I think it's just, the part of it is not obvious, and it's too finicky.
Speaker 1: It's not like an exact precise control.
Speaker 0: You have to kind of rock down up, down up, down up, and slowly murk your way down.
Speaker 0: And you can pick which window.
Speaker 0: You can go in the third floor- third floor- the third floor or the second floor.
Speaker 0: What I learned as a kid is that you cannot make it to the first floor.
Speaker 0: The rope's not long enough, and it just breaks.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So basically, you push down, and before you fall to your death, you push up, and your guy will lean against the building.
Speaker 0: And as a kid, once I figured it out, I was so nervous, and every millisecond that he was going down, I was afraid it was going to break.
Speaker 0: And I'd be like, da-nup, da-nup, da-nup, da-nup, da-nup.
Speaker 0: Now here's where the sniping really came into play.
Speaker 0: Let's say you take a guy, and you bring him down a little bit, and you get to the window.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, there's a terrorist in the window.
Speaker 0: You can't break the window, the terrorist is right there.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Shit.
Speaker 0: Now you gotta go back out, go to the sniper, have the sniper take the terrorist out, if he's still there.
Speaker 0: The cool thing is, if you do that, your guy is hanging there above the window waiting.
Speaker 0: You can't shoot your guy though, I tried.
Speaker 1: Yep, so eventually you find a window you want to break into, so you push that A button again to swing away from the building.
Speaker 1: You swing in, you kick the window, the window shatters, even if it was already shattered by snipers before, and you're in the building.
Speaker 0: And now suddenly the music's rockin', you gotta kill all the terrorists, not kill the hostages, it's an FPS with the map on the side.
Speaker 0: It's basically Shadow Gate, only quick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all you do is you push forward to go forward, left to turn 90 degrees left, right to turn 90 degrees right, back to go back, one screen, and A to shoot.
Speaker 1: And that's all you do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you gotta aim the gun too, so if you suddenly, you'll hear like "putt putt putt putt putt", and that means there's a terrorist in the room with you.
Speaker 0: And you turn around frantically, and you see a guy in green, and maybe he dodges to the right or dodges to the left, or maybe he starts shooting at you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if there's a terrorist to the right of you, you don't see him, but you might hear him or know he's there.
Speaker 0: And if you don't turn around and shoot him quick enough, you're dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you basically can only, it's not like an FPS with a smooth, you know, viewing, you can just kind of move and look around.
Speaker 1: It's, you only have a view of, you know, straight ahead, and if he's to the right, he might as well be who knows where.
Speaker 0: And those terrorists are fucking dangerous, let me tell you, especially on the hard difficulty.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least it lets you turn around very quickly, so you can, you know, you basically go into a, you take a step forward, you spin around in a circle, take a step forward, spin around in a circle.
Speaker 1: Now, on the easy mode of this game, there's a map, and the map has little dots on it that tell you where the terrorists are at all times, and where the hostages are at all times.
Speaker 1: And you can basically beat the game without even looking at the actual shooting screen and just looking at the map.
Speaker 0: Yep, but in the harder difficulties, one, it won't, the map will show terrorists, but it won't show all of the terrorists.
Speaker 1: Or it won't show the hostages, or it won't show any terrorists or hostages.
Speaker 0: And two, the harder the difficulty, the more tricky the terrorists are, and you gotta aim your gun more to actually get 'em.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it just kinda, it gets harder and harder and harder, but it's really not that hard.
Speaker 0: Well, the worst thing is, you always have an itchy trigger finger, and I pretty much shot any hostage I saw.
Speaker 1: Yeah, shooting hostages sucks.
Speaker 1: Basically, a hostage is a guy in a blue suit, as opposed to a guy in military camo, who doesn't, who has a gun.
Speaker 1: And you'll often turn around, see a hostage and shoot, or shoot every time and kill all the hostages, and that's not good.
Speaker 1: You can't do that.
Speaker 1: That loses you points.
Speaker 1: So you just keep doing this until you kill all the terrorists and save as many hostages as you can, and then the game is over, you win.
Speaker 1: Depending on how well you do, how much time is left, how many hostages you save, how quickly you kill the terrorists, how many of your guys died, you get a better ending, and then you can try again.
Speaker 0: Now, this is one of those games that, for when it came out, I think it was a pretty good game.
Speaker 1: It was frickin' awesome when it came out.
Speaker 0: Because in the very least, it's a game that tried to do something new, unique, and different with the NES, and it did it pretty well, all things considered.
Speaker 1: And I don't know any games that have really tried this since.
Speaker 0: I really wish a game would.
Speaker 1: I mean, even in FPSs these days, which could easily replicate this sort of thing, where everyone fulfills a different role in a multiplayer FPS, and one guy has to snipe that side of the building, and another guy has to snipe another side of the building, and some guy controls the spotlight in a machine gun on the building, and some other guy has to rappel down and then go into the building, and some other guys are the terrorists in the building, and that could be pretty cool.
Speaker 1: You could totally do that with Counter-Strike.
Speaker 0: I always think, because I used to make Doom levels and stuff, and I messed with Doom, and pretty much once games got 3D, I didn't have the time to deal with making maps and frickin' Quake or Counter-Strike or any of that.
Speaker 1: It's just too hard and sucky to do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it gives me an idea.
Speaker 0: You could make a scenario in Counter-Strike that was very much like this game, where you position individual players on the counter-terrorists, like some of them were snipers.
Speaker 0: They started in buildings with sniper rifles and terrorist hostages.
Speaker 0: You could do something pretty similar.
Speaker 1: That's the thing, though, is that FPSs tend to not have assigned roles.
Speaker 1: They tend to go with, you can choose your role, like Team Fortress.
Speaker 1: You choose which class you want to be.
Speaker 1: You want to be the medic, sure.
Speaker 1: You want to be a scout, sure.
Speaker 1: This would require the assignment of roles, which is something people don't like, or something FPSs don't seem to ever do, really.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, Natural Selection never really did it in the "the game does it" way, but it definitely did it in the "the players have to organize, and the commander has to assign roles on his
Speaker 0: own.".
Speaker 0: Like, you guys defend this.
Speaker 0: You guys do this.
Speaker 0: You're the healin' man.
Speaker 0: You're the ninja.
Speaker 0: That sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Unless the other players on the other team don't do it, then no one has to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like stuff like that, and I wish more games did it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, for anyone who isn't cool and old school and doesn't remember Rescue the Embassy Mission for the NES, now you do.
Speaker 0: Play it at least once.
Speaker 0: The first part of the game is really fun, and it's worth it to get good at that part of the game.
Speaker 0: Kind of like getting good at Bionic Commando.
Speaker 0: You'll feel good when you get jumbo to the end without dying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Rescue the Embassy Mission is a game worth playing, definitely.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's a game worth beating on the hardest mode.
Speaker 0: No, fuck it.
Speaker 0: It's not a great game.
Speaker 0: It's a great game in terms of the potential, and in terms of when it came out.
Speaker 0: It's not a great game nowadays, but I think someone could take what it was on, say, the Wii, and make it a fucking awesome game.
Speaker 1: It's definitely a significant game that everyone should know about and pay attention to.
Speaker 0: Now, I think in the future we're gonna have to do a review of fucking Shadowgate.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I haven't really gotten that far in Shadowgate without just reading his guide.
Speaker 1: I beat Shadowgate maybe a quarter of the way through.
Speaker 0: I beat Shadowgate on my own as a kid through trial and error over the course of like nine months.
Speaker 1: I beat Deja Vu with trial and error.
Speaker 0: Ah, fucking Deja Vu.
Speaker 0: That game was awesome, and by awesome I mean it was really hard.
Speaker 1: I've got Deja Vu 1 and 2 for the Game Boy Color.
Speaker 0: Ooh, I never played 2.
Speaker 1: I mean, either.
Speaker 1: I have it for the Game Boy Color.
Speaker 1: I never played it.
Speaker 0: Basically, Shadowgate was, no matter what you do, death.
Speaker 0: Deja Vu, same game.
Speaker 1: Yep, yep, oh well.
Speaker 1: Yay, Kemco.
Speaker 0: I think my favorite death was when you get suddenly and randomly dissolved by acid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of those ones that were random were the funniest, but I also like the dragon barbecue one where you go into a room, it gets hotter.
Speaker 1: You can take a treasure.
Speaker 1: It gets hotter.
Speaker 1: You take a treasure.
Speaker 0: Well, no, what it was is you go into the room, right, and there's a bunch of treasures laying there, and a dragon on the other end.
Speaker 0: One of the treasures is a shield.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: If you don't pick up the shield, the dragon just fucking kills you.
Speaker 0: If you pick up the shield, you block the fire, but the shield gets hotter and hotter and hotter.
Speaker 0: Eventually, if you stay in that room, the shield just melts, and then you die.
Speaker 1: But it allows you the chance to pick up a few of the other treasures.
Speaker 1: You have to know which ones you need and which ones you don't.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The best part was.
Speaker 0: at one point you find a scantily clad woman chained up in a room, and all this game taught you about scantily clad women chained up in rooms is that the only thing you should ever do with a scantily clad woman chained up in a room is stab her through the heart with an arrow, because any other course of action leads to your death.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And that was Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com.
Speaker 1: And if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other talk shows, it's actually recorded at night.