Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Thursday August 16th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: on throwaway Thursdays we talk about candy.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So this morning it looked like it was gonna be a nice normal day.
Speaker 1: I woke up almost on time I Left.
Speaker 1: I didn't stop at the coffee shop ride my bike with Emily.
Speaker 1: We're gonna get to the train station and There's almost no traffic.
Speaker 1: Everything's great the weather's perfect.
Speaker 0: There's no traffic.
Speaker 0: We're driving around town.
Speaker 0: We're not like getting on 84 or anything.
Speaker 1: usually there's a lot of traffic in our way trying to bike to the train station.
Speaker 0: I never have traffic ever going to the train station.
Speaker 1: well the traffic It's more along the lines of a lot of cars are going by and a lot of cars freak out when they see a bicycle And they swerve over the double yellow and almost cause accidents.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't see people freaking out.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you do.
Speaker 1: you ride your bike to the train station in the morning No, but I ride my car around bikes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you normally in front of me and people behind me and they don't freak out much of the time when I'm riding my bike and I'm Like.
Speaker 1: I'm not in the shoulder I'm in the lane at the far right like I'm supposed to be cars will like cross Bowl all four tires over the double yellow like to the other opposite side of the road and then drive past me.
Speaker 0: Well, they are they doing it in a freakout way like whoa or they just getting out of your way?
Speaker 1: Well, they're getting out of my way even though legally they shouldn't be over the double yellow And then the oncoming traffic is freaking out and swerving into the shoulder.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just stay far to the left.
Speaker 0: I don't go over the WL line.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna hit a car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what I'm saying is a lot of people just go all the way over the double yellow.
Speaker 0: And but the other thing is a lot of times You know, it's like I get stuck behind a bike person when the the lane is too narrow And you know what legally you got to stay behind that biker.
Speaker 0: I do until I have an opening especially like if I can't see cars coming, you know It's like you know that big turn when you leave the train station of the route.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, you can't see what's coming around that corner.
Speaker 0: If you go over that line even a little bit you can be dead.
Speaker 1: The thing is though Remember, you're a generally smarter and have more.
Speaker 0: But I don't see the people in front of me or behind me in their cars doing anything different from what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: Maybe because I'm biking.
Speaker 1: I see the reaction of every car that passes me dealing with a bike.
Speaker 1: Sometimes people honk at me.
Speaker 1: Sometimes people suddenly notice me and then swerve.
Speaker 1: I don't notice that a lot of people honk a lot of people flip me off Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: Mostly on my way home more than my way to work.
Speaker 1: But anyway come down the road There's a long awesome hill.
Speaker 1: Well, it's awesome in the morning because I get to fly down repaved it.
Speaker 0: It's very nice.
Speaker 0: I know
Speaker 1: it was great for rollerblading now, but on the way home, it kind of sucks because it's really really steep
Speaker 0: Uh-huh,
Speaker 1: but going down the hill and there's traffic completely stopped filling the entire hill all the way to the bottom
Speaker 0: Yeah I basically I turned right in my car Onto this hill and I said, uh-oh and I turned around and I went the other train station entrance, which is just fine.
Speaker 1: So some dumbass trucker with a super long truck I mean I'm talking longer than a long cat has backed into this driveway and now cannot get out but cannot back in any further.
Speaker 1: So he has stopped completely perpendicular to the flow of traffic 100% blocking the road in both directions with no possible way to get around.
Speaker 0: It's sort of a what.
Speaker 0: it's not technically a one-way road But you're not allowed to leave the train station onto that road.
Speaker 1: Actually, I've seen a lot of people leaving the train station onto that road.
Speaker 0: I've seen police pull people over.
Speaker 0: I know even the train station where they're not supposed to.
Speaker 1: actually I saw the same guy do it three times.
Speaker 1: So today I actually stopped because there was an MTA cop sitting there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I even the license plate in the make and I'm like this guy does this almost every day at this time Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So he said he'll be waiting for him tomorrow.
Speaker 0: All right but anyway the point is is that you're only allowed to go the other way on that road.
Speaker 0: if you were say stopped at one of the Houses on the road or there's a business And there's a.
Speaker 1: there's another business that this truck was going to and this dumbass truck is stuck And he's stuck to the point that there's a fence by on one side There's.
Speaker 1: even the pedestrians really didn't have an easy path to get around this truck Yeah, because you had to climb over the fence.
Speaker 1: I just kind of said screw it.
Speaker 1: and I just rode past the truck and made him stop for me Mm-hmm, but he was stuck and he couldn't get out and there's a lot of cars and people were getting out of the cars the passenger side and walk in and yelling at the guy and People are like trying to turn around but they couldn't because the cars behind him were too close.
Speaker 0: I turned around immediately and I wasn't that I just a whoop and I got out of there.
Speaker 1: But a lot of people ended up missing their train because of this dumbass truck.
Speaker 0: The truck should have gotten a ticket for obstructing the road.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is I complained to the MTA police since I was talking to the guy anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, they're MTA police.
Speaker 0: They don't have jurisdiction over there.
Speaker 1: No, no no but the thing is they took the complaint because he said a lot of people complained and Metro North take stuff like that seriously and they're gonna follow up with the local police and That business is gonna get in some trouble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty cool that the subways and the trains have their own police.
Speaker 1: Yeah, think about that.
Speaker 1: That's how badass.
Speaker 0: New York State downstairs separate police for the trains in the subways.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're real police.
Speaker 0: It's not like they're fake police But they're the police that they just have jurisdiction on trains where normal police don't have jurisdiction and they don't mess around.
Speaker 1: plus the all the employees of the trains have the same rights as police officers in terms of if you assault them Minimum sentences and all that business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of laws that protect Subway and train and bus employees, you know, because sometimes they have to go like if you're the bus driver Who has to drive in the shit town, you know, they make a law that says alright, don't fuck with the bus driver Yeah, which is fine.
Speaker 1: Yep But yeah, I just that was the most interesting thing that happened to me today.
Speaker 1: Then I went to work and now I'm back home.
Speaker 0: Me too.
Speaker 0: Hooray.
Speaker 0: Tomorrow's Friday.
Speaker 1: It is You don't have to make a show, haha, however Friday night the first of the Visigoths are going to be surrounding This capital of geek house doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna run away to Carthage and where pray tell is Carthage I don't know.
Speaker 1: You're gonna lock yourself in the bathroom upstairs and just hope everyone goes away.
Speaker 0: Let's just pretend that my room is Carthage All right.
Speaker 1: The thing is Carthage didn't really survive the Visigothic invasion.
Speaker 0: There's a Mediterranean Sea in the way.
Speaker 0: I can't hear you.
Speaker 0: You're a little far away.
Speaker 1: And then of course, we're playing D&D on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Yep, and some burning wheel on Saturday Yeah, and some drunken Horatio possibly on Saturday, but it's gonna be a good weekend.
Speaker 0: All right News do you have for this weekend?
Speaker 1: Well speaking of transit and New York City, this actually has nothing to do with that at all.
Speaker 1: So in LA as you might know on the other side of the country You know, you know what?
Speaker 1: This reminds me of this segue was much like the way I remember stalactites versus stalagmites.
Speaker 1: Stalagmites Might hang from the ceiling, but they fucking don't know.
Speaker 0: they don't anyway.
Speaker 1: This is a mashup of Google Maps and the homicide statistics of Los Angeles County.
Speaker 0: Oh, so this is a lot like that sex offender map plus Google Maps that I saw though
Speaker 1: I gotta say while a significant portion of sex offenders didn't actually do anything wrong and just you know peed in public or something We looked up every sex offender in our area and they were all like horrible rapists.
Speaker 0: They're all rapists or child molesters or other horrible things.
Speaker 0: I mean most of the people that are gotten by sex offender laws are sex offenders But we're not gonna talk about this.
Speaker 1: No, no, but this is the same kind of mashup.
Speaker 1: only it's Murders in LA and you can break it down as all statistics.
Speaker 1: You can look for man slaughters only.
Speaker 1: Yeah You can look for the age the right incidents only.
Speaker 1: no just murders All right.
Speaker 1: Here it is.
Speaker 1: It has age categories ethnicity categories gender cause of death.
Speaker 1: There are only four blunt force gunshot Stavin and other stab.
Speaker 0: Well, it's that is it's a Stavin.
Speaker 1: It's a stabbing.
Speaker 1: Ah, I Like other does it?
Speaker 0: does it separate it by like, you know, big knife little knife shiv.
Speaker 1: No, no It's just blunt force gunshot stabbing other day of the week.
Speaker 1: and then they have two special categories killing by police and Suspected domestic incident.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: And by clicking all these you can suspected domestic incident.
Speaker 0: So definitely a domestic incident doesn't count.
Speaker 1: Uh, I imagine that a definite one is also suspected of being one.
Speaker 1: I mean if you shoot a guy and I see you shoot him, I suspect that you shot him.
Speaker 0: I also know I also know that you shot But it could have been Illusion you could have been seeing things.
Speaker 1: Here's what I do.
Speaker 0: That'd be crazy If you're like a magician and you find a way to do a magic trick to make it look like you killed someone in the Street and know what everyone's fooled but you didn't.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like that The street magician who had the trick where he breaks the car window and then acts like he freaks out runs away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, only that guy.
Speaker 0: I think I actually broke a car window.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I really think it was staged either way.
Speaker 0: Go on.
Speaker 1: All right, so I've learned two things from this one.
Speaker 1: There are a few places in LA that are really fucking dangerous.
Speaker 0: uh-huh, so don't go to those places and to.
Speaker 1: if you were between the ages of 20 and 29 are Hispanic or black are a man and It's a Sunday.
Speaker 1: watch the fuck out.
Speaker 0: But why did they get killed on Sunday?
Speaker 1: There's more murders on Sunday than any other day.
Speaker 0: So just Sunday stay at home watch football.
Speaker 0: Maybe the football has something to do with it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's like that, you know the Was it the LA?
Speaker 0: let's see San Francisco 49ers LA Raiders the Raiders.
Speaker 0: I think it's the Oakland Raiders now though.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: The California football team's not so good.
Speaker 0: people get pissed when they lose.
Speaker 0: maybe who knows?
Speaker 1: Well, it might also have to do with paydays or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's blue laws out there and man can't get his man juice.
Speaker 0: I know California has the blue laws.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: You never know.
Speaker 1: because New York has some blue law.
Speaker 0: That's because we're in the Northeast but New York is New York, but those laws are old.
Speaker 0: California is new.
Speaker 1: I didn't find it hilarious when Dave from Dave and Joel's fast karate for the gentleman was spending time in New York City and was Amazed at the fact that pretty much 24/7 you can buy a beer just about anywhere.
Speaker 1: In fact, you can buy a beer at the train station from a guy who will sell it to you right before you get on The train.
Speaker 0: well, you're on a train the trains that go to Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Some of them have a bar car where you can buy beer on the train.
Speaker 1: I love New York, right?
Speaker 1: But anyway There are similar statistics now that a lot of people are able to put this data together.
Speaker 1: There's an unrelated story I'm not gonna bother linking to it about how police officers are looking at data like this and determining Areas where crimes are likely to happen at certain times and they're just putting cops there and crime rates are going down pretty significantly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like the crime is gonna move elsewhere like.
Speaker 0: I forget what city it was but they noticed that the majority I'm not gonna kill you over here Let's go to that place this low crime and no cops and I'll kill you over there.
Speaker 1: The majority of stabbings occurred outside of check cashing places on paydays in poor neighborhoods.
Speaker 0: That reminds me when I was one time I was leaving Shea Stadium and I saw the funniest thing ever.
Speaker 0: There was a you know next to Shea Stadium There's like an area where there's a whole bunch of like Korean auto shops.
Speaker 0: But if you go down the street a bit, there's another area and I saw in one sort of like You know shopping building of some sorts.
Speaker 0: There was a check cashing place and the same structure directly adjacent was a liquor store And it was a stool in between the stores and on that stool was a homeless man I guess he begs for money from people who just cashed their paycheck and buys liquor with it.
Speaker 0: He's like not even fooling anybody, you know, and he sits in the prime position much like the Silk Road.
Speaker 0: that guy That guy indeed.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I find things like this fast Marco Polo of Queens and I wish there were some sort of national database of crimes that I could Then look at in a system like this because I think that would be really cool.
Speaker 0: How about a cell phone application that says hey go this way to avoid the cry or you're entering a high crime area.
Speaker 1: You know stuff like that, you know, I just realized suddenly This is the exact opposite of that.
Speaker 1: what if we made a little application for cell phones or PDAs or Wi-Fi businesses?
Speaker 1: or maybe if we even sold a gadget and you Know those services where it'll like.
Speaker 1: beep if there's a gay guy nearby with the same thing or beep if there's a guy into S&M Nearby into the same things you are and your dating services.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things like that.
Speaker 1: What if you made one that allows you to specify yourself as a weed seeker or weed seller?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure they have those.
Speaker 0: it's called Pre-pay cell phones.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, I mean what if it was automatic?
Speaker 1: Just you know your Nintendo DS.
Speaker 1: you sell a bootleg cartridge and the DS goes Whatever.
Speaker 1: a guy's got weed near you and you can just buy some.
Speaker 1: it's a lot safer than the shoe method or all.
Speaker 0: or So a cop goes on the internet and buys one and walks down the street and says he got weed he got weed Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: There's some plausible deniability there.
Speaker 1: and two you can always say are you a police officer?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, or you make it really secret.
Speaker 1: you ask people when they buy him if they're a police officer.
Speaker 0: Are you done?
Speaker 1: I'm done All right.
Speaker 1: I was I could keep going.
Speaker 0: So there's been something that's been pissing me off lately.
Speaker 0: Oh Fancy that actually I think I've complained about on the show before but now I'm gonna super complain about it.
Speaker 0: So there was a flight an airplane on July 29th, and it was flying.
Speaker 0: Oh From Caracas, Venezuela to Newark.
Speaker 0: I've been to Newark.
Speaker 0: It's it's in New Jersey, right and Bad weather caused the plane to be diverted to be more.
Speaker 0: Ah It sat there For about five hours with passengers on board as food and water ran low and toilets became filthy.
Speaker 1: Now that wasn't it?
Speaker 1: not just filthy but overflowing?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's kind of hard to say exactly what this particular situation was because different statements by different people give varying Situation reports.
Speaker 0: it could be anywhere from there was everything was just fine - it was the worst thing ever.
Speaker 0: The thing I want to point out is that the people on this plane unlike other planes, which I don't respect.
Speaker 0: I respect this plane from Caracas because after a while the people's they got rowdy and they started clapping in unison and banging on the overhead containers in you
Speaker 1: all right and
Speaker 0: I guess what happened though was pretty stupid and that the I guess the one of the stewardesses was a bitch of some sort and She must have called the police and was like people are getting violent and rowdy.
Speaker 0: and since it was like an international flight You know, they didn't let him into customs or anything.
Speaker 0: They just sort of took him off the plane and treated him like criminals and they you know We're calling the people names and treating them like shit.
Speaker 1: All I have to say to that is because because this sort of thing happens a lot and I don't know if many of you Fly a lot in the US and it doesn't happen all the time and not especially to business travelers But more often than it should airlines totally fuck people and don't help them out in any way.
Speaker 0: Yes But the point I want to make here is specifically When the problem with a plane is that like like for example today that truck was blocking the road The bus that was stopped there was a bus that couldn't get around the truck a bus that was supposed to go to the train Station.
Speaker 0: the bus just let everyone off at the top of the road and everyone walked down to the train station who wanted to Right big deal an airplane.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work like that.
Speaker 0: They don't let people off airplanes.
Speaker 0: You just have to stay on until you get to the gate and they let you depart.
Speaker 0: You know properly and you can only get on the airplane when they tell you to and it's.
Speaker 0: it's very controlled You know, you can't just get off the plane.
Speaker 0: if it's you know on the ground or whatever You can only do it.
Speaker 0: You're basically trapped and at the mercy of the people who decide where the plane goes.
Speaker 0: I think that's pretty much true in all countries though.
Speaker 0: It's not like a US thing.
Speaker 0: However There's been a problem and a lot of stories at least a lot of stories on the internet.
Speaker 0: I don't know how often it actually happens.
Speaker 0: where a plane it's happened to me as it happened to you.
Speaker 0: You know you realize that maybe never happened to me.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's just bad luck.
Speaker 1: But the last time I flew without incident was when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: I've never flown without incident I mean I've never flown with incident.
Speaker 1: every time I have flown or attempted to fly since I graduated high school has ended an absolute disaster.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's a lot of situations where a plane leaves the gate Which means now you can't get off and it sits outside on the ground mind you?
Speaker 0: not in the sky on the ground Not moving for a very long time hours and hours and hours on end, right?
Speaker 0: And the thing I don't understand about this is okay.
Speaker 0: If a plane isn't ready to take off right now, like I can the runway is free.
Speaker 0: I'm going.
Speaker 0: don't leave the fucking gate.
Speaker 0: Don't leave don't close the door.
Speaker 1: The reason is because they want to use that gate for other things.
Speaker 1: They want to get that plane out of the way.
Speaker 0: I've never been to an airport where every gate has been in use.
Speaker 0: There are always not aliens and plenty and plenty and plenty of extra gates that are not in you.
Speaker 1: Not all planes can go to all gates.
Speaker 1: Not all airlines can use all gates.
Speaker 1: There's all sorts of reasons for that's a bunch of bullshit.
Speaker 0: If they have a bunch of gates any plane that needs to should be able to use any gate.
Speaker 0: fuck them The any gate that it'll work with.
Speaker 1: you can't really manage there also.
Speaker 1: Well, I agree that generally that situation is crap.
Speaker 1: Your solution doesn't work perfectly.
Speaker 0: also If there's no gate You can still you wheel up the stairs next to the plane and people walk down the stairs onto the ground.
Speaker 1: the rationale is That is dangerous.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, they let me do it in Florida all the time.
Speaker 0: You can always board right onto the Disembark right onto the ground.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on where you are and where the plane is and there's only Areas they can wait can taxi over to a designated area, but you're forgetting the primary thing.
Speaker 1: Anything that would help the customer in that situation would cost the airline more money.
Speaker 0: Pilot has to sit on the plane for a zillion hours - yeah, so does all the crew and everyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it sucks what.
Speaker 0: they don't want to sit there.
Speaker 0: They should fuck it.
Speaker 0: Why don't they fucking complain?
Speaker 0: No one should ever be forced to sit out on an airplane Not going anywhere for more than like 30 minutes ever Scott The.
Speaker 1: the reason it is this way is that no one cares enough except the people who get fucked by it and they have no Power at all.
Speaker 1: What do you what are you going to?
Speaker 1: do?
Speaker 1: not fly if you raise a ruckus?
Speaker 1: They arrest you.
Speaker 0: if somebody if I was stuck on a plane for more than like an hour I would literally get everyone on the plane into a mob Force the crew to let us open the door and leave.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be violent or hurt.
Speaker 1: anyone got it wouldn't matter They unless you were I'll use the emergency chutes and get off the plane.
Speaker 1: That's illegal.
Speaker 1: You'd all be arrested.
Speaker 0: That's fine It's civil disobedience.
Speaker 0: I'd want to go to jail.
Speaker 0: It's better than being stuck on a goddamn plane.
Speaker 1: the civil disobedience wouldn't work because no one cares.
Speaker 1: You just go to jail.
Speaker 1: everyone else would fry get off free they target use the instigator and Then everyone else will go about their business and no one would care that you were in jail.
Speaker 0: That's not the point.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know I agree with you.
Speaker 0: That's how civil that's so civil disobedience work.
Speaker 1: I'm just pointing out the civil disobedience only works if a lot of other people do it with you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and no one else cares enough sadly.
Speaker 0: That's tough.
Speaker 0: You got it.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: You get you get the blood boiling.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I'm not gonna.
Speaker 1: it's not gonna have it.
Speaker 1: I'm just I'm.
Speaker 0: the point is is Basically I say that if these planes if you have a plane and it's not going anywhere and the people want to get off And you don't let them off.
Speaker 0: I say that's illegally detaining people and they should go to jail.
Speaker 0: You can't just hold people there if they don't want to be there and there's no reason you can't bring them back.
Speaker 1: FA regulations let them do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the FA regulations are bullshit and they're basically in contradiction with the with civil rights.
Speaker 1: The thing is also you agree to all of that when you buy the ticket.
Speaker 1: if you don't agree with that You don't have to fly.
Speaker 1: flying is not a right.
Speaker 0: I know it's notice.
Speaker 0: I haven't been flying lately.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 1: that's why I never fly and that's probably the only thing is right FA regulations.
Speaker 0: These people flew from Caracas.
Speaker 0: They don't have any FA in Caracas Yeah, but they're in the US.
Speaker 1: agree to that shit when they were in Caracas Actually, they probably did because they bought a ticket that went to America.
Speaker 1: So they had to buy a ticket.
Speaker 1: that ends up being I'll take it this legitimate next time.
Speaker 0: next time I do fly I'm gonna look and I'm gonna see if it says you agree to Be stuck on the tarmac or go wherever the plane goes no matter what, you know and such.
Speaker 0: I don't think it says that on there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is is BS.
Speaker 0: It has to stop and if people need to start, you know if you no one wants to sit on a plane like this.
Speaker 0: if you're stuck on a plane like this you have to get rowdy and Freaking.
Speaker 0: make sure that airlines know that people aren't gonna stand for this anymore.
Speaker 1: It would only work if everyone did it and not I think everyone's got to start doing it.
Speaker 1: Because remember most people don't care.
Speaker 1: people just think that this would all.
Speaker 0: I think people care that you don't want to sit on.
Speaker 0: the Place got ours.
Speaker 0: The thing is I think there's wusses.
Speaker 0: they care They're just also wusses Scott.
Speaker 1: You realize that most people as far as they're concerned have to fly and get where they're going So they just do.
Speaker 1: this would all be solved if people who disagreed with how airlines were run just didn't fly.
Speaker 1: The thing is people fly.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the problem is it's a monopoly.
Speaker 0: There's no.
Speaker 0: Every stoop is not like an.
Speaker 0: if there was an airline that say didn't have this stupid policy and would bring you back to the Gate I could do that airline instead, but it's not a monopoly because there's a lot of competing airline.
Speaker 0: No, it's.
Speaker 0: it's not a monopoly like that.
Speaker 0: but the point is is that all of the airlines have the same bullshit rules and There's no alternative to flying to get places in an efficient manner.
Speaker 0: You know, like, you know It's not like I can take the train and get to Florida in a day.
Speaker 0: The train takes two days Scott.
Speaker 1: all the grocery stores have the same rules.
Speaker 1: You can't walk in naked You can't walk in without shoes on.
Speaker 0: those are rules of the whole world there the country.
Speaker 1: But the thing is I don't have a choice.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: I mean it's not a monopoly.
Speaker 0: but yet I can't change when you don't have a choice and you should have a choice.
Speaker 0: The only solution is to get rowdy.
Speaker 1: Well, I just don't think it's gonna happen because most people don't.
Speaker 0: it happened right here.
Speaker 1: I am exercise New York Times.
Speaker 1: I'm yeah, and I don't.
Speaker 1: I think no one's gonna care.
Speaker 1: I'm just being realistic about this.
Speaker 1: Most people don't care about much at all.
Speaker 0: I think people care about being stuck on a plane for ten hours.
Speaker 1: Most people never get stuck on a plane.
Speaker 1: Yeah, hey, most people don't even fly.
Speaker 0: I think people who get stuck on planes.
Speaker 0: None of them want to be there.
Speaker 1: I took a much more practical solution.
Speaker 1: I just vote with my dollars and I don't fly and if I have to go somewhere to fly I have to fly to Get somewhere.
Speaker 1: I'm either going to take all of those factors into account.
Speaker 1: I mean very few things are going to convince me to get on an airplane these days.
Speaker 0: I'll only get in an airplane when there is basically it.
Speaker 0: There's no other way like I have to go to London.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not gonna take the slow boat.
Speaker 1: I would seriously consider road tripping two packs instead of flying.
Speaker 1: I would seriously consider plus that be kind of fun Especially if we got all our friends to go took a week and a half.
Speaker 0: The only reason I wouldn't is because I don't have enough vacation days to do so.
Speaker 1: actually I do.
Speaker 1: I realized that despite Otakon in the week of awesome and everything.
Speaker 1: I have another two weeks this year.
Speaker 0: I'll go use them I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: but yeah, not enough vacation days.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I also have like two months worth of long-term disability.
Speaker 1: I got to come up with a way to use my long-term disability.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a baseball bat with your name.
Speaker 1: I don't get sick days.
Speaker 1: I get choice time days.
Speaker 1: I can use for whatever I want I get a month's worth of them.
Speaker 0: I get infinity sick days and like a number of personal days plus holidays.
Speaker 1: But I get long-term disability and I accrue it continuously and of course all my things roll over forever.
Speaker 1: There's no limit how many I can have.
Speaker 1: But if I'm out for more than five days due to illness then I don't lose vacation days I lose long-term disability days instead.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so I'll just break your leg or something.
Speaker 1: Broken leg really wouldn't be an excuse to not go to work.
Speaker 0: Concussion.
Speaker 1: How about vague pain based diarrhea illness?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I'm gonna be out for a week.
Speaker 1: Sorry Shady note from a doctor Everybody It's doctor In flammable means in flammable water country.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's bullshit.
Speaker 1: when they hold you on a plane while it is I think your idealism is a little bit misguided and wall.
Speaker 1: I agree with all of your sentiment as a practical man.
Speaker 1: I don't think enough people give a shit.
Speaker 0: You just sit on the plane.
Speaker 0: What would you do?
Speaker 1: What I would do is not fucking fly.
Speaker 0: You're already on the plane.
Speaker 0: It's already stuck.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 0: Well, if I've been there for five hours You want to get the exact scenario?
Speaker 1: Here's what I would do.
Speaker 1: I would very diplomatically gauge the mood and possibility of joining me of everyone else on the plane and if I could determine that Not not just a majority but a plurality of the people on the plane would rise up with me Then I would set up a situation whereby everyone rose up and yet no one would be able to point to me as being the instigator.
Speaker 1: That way I could just be part of the crowd.
Speaker 1: I probably wouldn't be singled out in any prosecution that followed and I could still have all the media impact.
Speaker 1: That is what I would do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even so the end result is if they don't let you off the plane or taxi you back Somehow someone opens the hatch and you'll go down the emergency chute.
Speaker 1: I would also outside Regardless just sue the airline in civil court.
Speaker 1: I come up with some.
Speaker 0: I would definitely sue the air airline and at least small claims Court.
Speaker 0: I'd get a lawyer like immediately.
Speaker 1: The thing is I have a lawyer so it'd be free for me to sue.
Speaker 1: I just have to take the time off work to deal with.
Speaker 0: there would definitely be some suing going on no matter what.
Speaker 0: Plus, you know what you could do is you could set them up to where the damages are very high Unbeknownst to them like if I was of going on a trip to make like a two billion dollar business deal or something.
Speaker 1: I think is you can't sue for things like that.
Speaker 1: Oh, come on All that stuff is covered in the thing the contract you agree to.
Speaker 1: when you buy a plane ticket You basically say I agree to the possibility that I will not fly anywhere.
Speaker 1: What about this?
Speaker 0: What about this?
Speaker 0: You're ready?
Speaker 0: I have diabetes and they didn't let me take my needles on the plane cuz they're not allowed And I've been stuck on the plane for too long.
Speaker 1: if you have diabetes There's rules where if you fill out the proper forms, you are allowed to bring them on the plane.
Speaker 0: Ah, there's got to be a catch.
Speaker 0: There's got to be a way to fuck them.
Speaker 1: There are no way you it would have to be so premeditated and There's got to be a way.
Speaker 1: Things of the day.
Speaker 1: I'll be real quick about this.
Speaker 1: This is an old video.
Speaker 1: I have it.
Speaker 1: In fact, I have this original video in my collection of fucked up videos from way back in the day But I saw it on the internet and I remembered it and all I want to point out is that this kind of prank I like because one it proves to you whether or not your friend whoever you were pulling this prank on is Able to deal with a dangerous and stressful situation in a calm and collected manner or not.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: The only problem with the prank is you're a gigantic asshole.
Speaker 1: if you actually attempt it Why?
Speaker 1: Well because if you do it the person who is the prank II Might react in a way that is dangerous to you or others.
Speaker 0: I guess that might be true.
Speaker 1: the prank is basically a guy is filled in with a light switch something and he acts like he's being shocked and he plays some electric shocking sounds and The guys standing there Freaks the fuck out.
Speaker 0: I would have just you know body checked you off of the light switch as is supposed to be.
Speaker 1: Well, actually I'm right.
Speaker 1: I used to help other people with that stuff.
Speaker 1: They always kept an aura around and if someone was shocked You're supposed to use the aura to hit him off of the lab.
Speaker 0: if I had an or I would have hit you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a bunch of things you can.
Speaker 0: the thing is you basically wouldn't that suck?
Speaker 0: you pull a prank to get hit.
Speaker 0: So you get you the prank er gets hit.
Speaker 0: It's kind of dumb.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's a lot of pranks like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean imagine if you're trying to fool me into freaking out and I end up hitting you.
Speaker 1: Oh It's like that famous video of there's this cool black guy and he's walking up to do a trick-or-treat in the house And oh, yeah, and there's a scarecrow and it's sitting there but the scarecrow is actually a dude and The scarecrow suddenly jumps up would order and the black guy must have been a boxer Because he perfectly just punches the guy in the face immediately
Speaker 0: and then he's like, oh shit, dude.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Are you okay?
Speaker 1: Man but the hit was solid it was beautiful.
Speaker 0: It was it was majestic.
Speaker 1: I gotta say While that prank is awesome, and I love pranks if you're gonna pull the prank You've got to be ready for someone to punch you.
Speaker 0: Yes all right.
Speaker 1: so all I want to say is the expression on the guy on the right's face as He goes from shock to screaming to shock to screaming.
Speaker 1: He kind of opens and closes his mouth a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: It's hilarious.
Speaker 1: And then when he punches the guy in the face with the banana equally hilarious.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so there's a website I found I think someone sent this to me or something.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure whoever you are.
Speaker 0: I forget who you are.
Speaker 0: Sorry Anyway, it's called polar Rose calm and what.
Speaker 0: this is the beta test of a new technology That's actually intuitive and I think pretty cool.
Speaker 0: It's like well, you know you go around the internet and someone says check out my new thing Twitter and you're like, whatever dude I don't get it.
Speaker 0: This is something I totally get and I think is awesome.
Speaker 0: You know, all right, check this out first.
Speaker 0: It's a Firefox plug-in also an IE plug-in but not yet.
Speaker 0: It looks in your browser at pictures on web pages.
Speaker 0: Oh, it looks for faces of people and it attempts to recognize them.
Speaker 0: If it doesn't recognize them it puts a little like Rose on like it like adds to the graphic this like lapel pin.
Speaker 0: That looks like the polar Rose logo right and you can click on it to sort of tell right like the name of who the person is and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: and If on another website someone else looks at another picture of the same person and they have the extension It'll say we're pretty sure this is Scott Reuben, you know, is it Scott Reuben?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: No information about him So you'll be able to browse the net with in Firefox with this extension and just looking at pictures of people It'll tell you who a lot of those people are even if the web page doesn't tell you that's really cool It is I do.
Speaker 0: I think it's really cool and it'll really help.
Speaker 0: for you know going around the internet Just looking at pictures of people Recognizing them recognizing famous people, you know It'll improve facial recognition technology, you know across people at like different ages.
Speaker 0: So like, you know someone with a low a young and someone old with the who are the same person It'll name them both the same and maybe it'll be able to start recognizing people, you know From a picture and now when they're younger.
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 1: I just really really look forward to the day Which I think is gonna happen in our lifetime where I can wear glasses or have a cyber implant or whatever probably glasses
Speaker 0: Where
Speaker 1: it'll just show everyone's names floating over their heads all the time and it'll just figure it out based on technology like this.
Speaker 0: And then if I double click on those names, I'll get their Facebook Yes, or maybe it'll tell me stats about him.
Speaker 1: Like the last time I attempted to kill them.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: or you know Maybe they'll be red which means they're evil and they're gonna get me.
Speaker 0: but green means they're not PvP.
Speaker 0: I'm alright Okay, right.
Speaker 1: So this is one of those kind of throwaway Thursdays throwaway Thursdays.
Speaker 1: You can always tell a throwaway Thursday because we either Review a movie which means we couldn't come up with anything better.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna talk about What movie today or we talk about a food related topic?
Speaker 0: Yeah food.
Speaker 0: It seems like there's a lot of requests and a lot of show ideas for food.
Speaker 0: We could probably turn Thursdays into food days if we wanted to.
Speaker 0: I still didn't have a big drumstick as the icon.
Speaker 1: Yeah Our best food episode ever was when we had our friend Adam odd.
Speaker 1: I was a good food episode when he told the story of him and his friends.
Speaker 1: all Americans in Japan Basically eating all.
Speaker 1: they ate all the sushi.
Speaker 1: There was an all-you-can-eat like sushi like sushi and food place.
Speaker 1: When basically you can eat all you can eat for like an hour and you pay a set price They ate it all.
Speaker 1: they just ate everything.
Speaker 1: that came until there was nothing left and no one knew what to do.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So today I'm gonna talk about Candy, I like candy All right, so the thing about candy first off I want to say is that when I was a kid candy was like gold.
Speaker 1: Oh candy was like a Halloween was my favorite holiday like a Jolly Rancher was like a silver dollar.
Speaker 1: I mean when I got candy I was always I had this debate because I'd be holding it.
Speaker 1: and it's do I eat it all now or do I save some?
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I might not have candy five minutes from now, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Basically, I couldn't be happier than if I had candy all the time when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: as long as I didn't eat so Much I got sick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which only happened twice a year the eggs and every year was the same times.
Speaker 1: It was always Halloween night and then the night after Halloween.
Speaker 0: so now Candy, I still like some candies not all candies.
Speaker 0: Actually, I think I don't like less candies than I used to but I like different candies And I don't like it as much and I eat it a lot less.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean when I was a kid I would eat pretty much any amount of candy you gave me.
Speaker 1: give me enough time there.
Speaker 0: I didn't like every candy when I was.
Speaker 1: one thing I've never liked are those goddamn puffy circus peanut.
Speaker 0: No, I don't like those good guy.
Speaker 0: Ah, I don't like neko wafers.
Speaker 0: They're disgusting.
Speaker 1: I like neko wafers suck.
Speaker 0: I don't like any of the old, you know.
Speaker 0: on Halloween old people give you candy.
Speaker 0: That's always different from normal people, you know, it's like normal people.
Speaker 0: give you an M&M give you Snickers Give you three musketeer little Reese's blow pop.
Speaker 0: old people gave you like Something really weird and it sucked.
Speaker 1: see a lot of times I was leery of those things.
Speaker 1: my dad would always say at least try it before you knock it and a lot of times it Was really good.
Speaker 0: No, I tried all of them and they all sucked anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah candy.
Speaker 0: It's yummy.
Speaker 1: See the thing is We should break this down into topics like good ideas because I don't know what else to say besides listing the favorite and most Hated candies, I mean favorite of all time.
Speaker 1: if I count my childhood and my adult life to this day I still really like Kit Kats.
Speaker 0: Favorite of all time is hard to say it would.
Speaker 0: I really like some Reese's peanut butter cup.
Speaker 0: I really like some blow pop.
Speaker 0: I like some bazooka Joe.
Speaker 0: I like some three musketeer.
Speaker 0: I like some Milky Way, you know, but like there's some you know what.
Speaker 0: no favorite of all time a good dive.
Speaker 0: Has this one candy?
Speaker 0: It's a sir.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's a circle of chocolate with a mint cream in it.
Speaker 0: It's perfect.
Speaker 1: Actually when I was a kid I used to really really like those Andy's man.
Speaker 0: These are awesome because I would never buy them in my house.
Speaker 0: My grandma always had them.
Speaker 1: so whenever went to my grandma's house if you like Andy's candies Oh, man, when I was a little kid It was like the crazy treat because my parents were always little to buy him because we bought him all the time.
Speaker 1: So every now and then they'd be like we're buying them.
Speaker 0: those after eight things also work.
Speaker 1: The thing is I liked him but I liked him mostly because of the mint.
Speaker 1: and I remember as a kid I'd always be like man.
Speaker 1: I wish I could have one where it was mint on the outside and chocolate on the inside and then they made those and then They made those.
Speaker 0: and uh, we should buy some next time.
Speaker 1: right the grocery thing is I don't like him anymore.
Speaker 0: Oh, I still love them.
Speaker 1: They're great thing is I mean, I liked him as a kid But now that I've had better mint and better job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it isn't that minty.
Speaker 0: I would like them more if they were more minty.
Speaker 0: that is not only that it's the Rappiest chocolate and they're really kind of dry and stiff actually dry as if I found them to actually be kind of mushy.
Speaker 1: You gotta like leave them out warm to get them that way.
Speaker 0: No, actually you put them in the fridge.
Speaker 0: That's what I do with them.
Speaker 1: I just I don't like them anymore.
Speaker 1: They're the chocolate so cheap.
Speaker 1: The mint flavor is so cheap.
Speaker 0: They could be much improved if you use a high quality dark chocolate and a more minty or mint.
Speaker 0: I agree, but they're still alright cuz it's still mint chocolate.
Speaker 0: But yeah Let's talk about can't admit M&Ms cuz.
Speaker 1: candy bars are the big one.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid I could eat like a double king-sized Snickers bar and not even blink.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely I could eat a freakin Charleston chew when I was a kid and not blink.
Speaker 0: Charleston shoes actually kind of one of the few chewy things I do like.
Speaker 1: I used to eat mostly Snickers bars and Anything with puffed rice in it like crackles.
Speaker 1: Leslie's crunch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like those.
Speaker 0: I like pretty much all candy bars except for butterfingers.
Speaker 0: They're disgusting.
Speaker 1: Ah, see that I liked.
Speaker 1: there's one kind of butter finger That was different.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 0: I don't like anything with the coconut.
Speaker 0: I'm enjoying mounds can both suck a dick Got nuts.
Speaker 0: No moms.
Speaker 0: Don't yeah, so I think the one I'm so the one I ate more than any other was the three musketeers.
Speaker 1: Ah, seals were okay.
Speaker 1: I ate them a lot mostly because my grandparents bought them all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I might prefer the Milky Way technically but for some reason I just always ate three musketeers And I was three musketeers.
Speaker 1: There's like they were actually not that bad for you.
Speaker 0: Well, because the chocolate on the inside is sort of like this light and fluffy kind of mousse.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's mostly artificial cancer-causing stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's in lieu of you know, I guess fat card attack causing stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean when I was a kid, I liked the dense candy bars like the Snickers bar Which was just like caramel and peanuts and chocolate, you know, that's one thing the Snickers commercials that I remember.
Speaker 0: We're kind of honest which is hey, are you really hungry?
Speaker 0: Do you need to something to hold you over and so you can get a meal?
Speaker 0: Snickers does work for that?
Speaker 0: It's a. it feels like a lot of food in a very small amount of space.
Speaker 1: See it used to and I used to eat them all the time.
Speaker 1: course.
Speaker 1: as a kid I think back to how much food I ate like from the ages of nine to about 19 Aside from drinking like six or seven cans of dr.
Speaker 1: Pepper every single day and drinking like two glasses of orange juice every morning.
Speaker 1: I Ate like a Snickers bar every day too.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid I could eat like especially high school years.
Speaker 0: I could just eat a zillion foods Especially candy, but I was a bottomless pit for eating food.
Speaker 0: now not so much.
Speaker 1: I don't know I really can't eat a candy bar like almost any candy bar except a Milky Way.
Speaker 0: I can but I can only eat like one.
Speaker 1: see I can't like the thought and it only if I'm hungry The thought of eating an entire Snickers bar or an entire anything other than like a fancy-pants chocolate bar some white chocolate or something White chocolate.
Speaker 0: I could eat just infinite white chocolate.
Speaker 1: white chocolate is like the best thing especially if it's real white chocolate.
Speaker 0: I mean fake white chocolate is okay, but real white chocolate expensive.
Speaker 0: It is real expensive.
Speaker 0: God damn goddamn is right.
Speaker 1: Actually, it's not even chocolate but the worst thing I ever did but also the best thing.
Speaker 1: we were in Wildwood right and You can get really good fudge in Wildwood.
Speaker 1: like for fudge places though Douglas is the best.
Speaker 0: Douglas fudge is the best for they have a pavilion.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I got I free was like Chocolate and peanut butter fudge like mixed together and I got one bar of you know One of those like four and a half inch five inch long bars of fudge.
Speaker 1: It's like an inch square by an engine and I was carrying it around and I just ate the whole thing like a candy bar Yeah in the span of like five minutes like ice.
Speaker 0: it's weird because I remember fudge being heavier and more filling in the stomach But see it really isn't so much.
Speaker 1: Well, it kind of is.
Speaker 1: I was fooled.
Speaker 1: You see I could use.
Speaker 1: I could have probably eaten a half of that thing had been okay, but I ate the whole bar.
Speaker 1: That was like a quarter pound of fudge mm-hmm and About 20 minutes later.
Speaker 1: I started to play DDR and I made it through half of one song and that was the end of that Alrighty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's weird.
Speaker 0: It's like when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Whatever it tasted better was better and it did nothing else matter.
Speaker 0: now I'm older.
Speaker 0: what I look for in candy is tastes real good, but it's also real light.
Speaker 0: It's like cheesecake which isn't really candy But it tastes like candy.
Speaker 0: is?
Speaker 0: I want to eat a cheesecake where I can eat a lot of it without filling up.
Speaker 0: I want to be light and fluffy, but I want it to taste just as good as the super dense like Rising.
Speaker 0: it's like I go someplace and they have like the super dense chocolate cake.
Speaker 0: I just can't eat that anymore even though I love the taste of it.
Speaker 1: that's what it really comes down to.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid like I could eat half of a cheesecake no matter how dense it was and I could just eat dense foods and foods that had like more calories per pound than is Reasonable for human being to consume nowadays.
Speaker 1: if I try to eat dense food like that I just can't.
Speaker 1: my body says whoa, you don't need this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you do I buy one of those big thick like chocolate dessert cakes.
Speaker 0: that but you know, I could eat like a Slice of it that's pretty thin and that's and then I'm done and I'd have to share it with like a whole table of people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean my grandma used to make these brownies and they were like the best brownies in the world, but they were Ultra dense.
Speaker 1: they were like a half inch thick and they were heavy.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like when you pick up a piece of metal and it's heavier than you expect.
Speaker 1: That's what these things were like and they were full of walnuts.
Speaker 1: Oh, they were the best things ever, but now I can't imagine eating more than like a square inch.
Speaker 0: Yeah without getting sick It's just too much.
Speaker 1: I just and I still can eat the same amount of calories.
Speaker 1: I just can't eat those dense foods.
Speaker 0: It's got to be over time.
Speaker 0: You got to spread it out thin, you know, I can eat a thousand calories.
Speaker 0: It just takes me half a day.
Speaker 1: You can't eat ten calories.
Speaker 1: You can't eat ten peeps.
Speaker 0: I can't eat a single peep.
Speaker 0: They're disgusting.
Speaker 1: I can always eat one because the first peep I think hey a peep and I eat it.
Speaker 1: And then I feel sick and I remember what peeps taste like and I remember what they feel like in your stomach.
Speaker 0: peeps are not Good, they're not.
Speaker 0: they're disgusting.
Speaker 0: I don't know why anyone eats them.
Speaker 1: You know, that's another thing.
Speaker 1: I can't eat things that they may not be dense, but they're just so sweet like cotton candy Cotton candy.
Speaker 1: I used to love cotton candy.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of as never big on cotton.
Speaker 1: I loved it It was great.
Speaker 1: But now I eat cotton candy and it just hurts.
Speaker 0: See the sweetness doesn't really bother me so much.
Speaker 0: I mean for me sweet equals taste good, you know, it's like oh People say this is too sweet.
Speaker 0: I'm like what you mean?
Speaker 0: It tastes too good, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: for me I think a lot of it is that I started eating and drinking a lot of different things after I went to college and then to you know to New York City and all this business.
Speaker 1: and like drink, you know drink a Japanese soda like a ramune or like a seltzer spritzer or anything like that.
Speaker 1: and They're not.
Speaker 1: they don't have a lot of calories in them and they're really kind of light and they're not super sweet.
Speaker 1: They just they have flavor.
Speaker 1: and now I can't drink super sweet things.
Speaker 1: Like I can't even drink.
Speaker 1: Dr Pepper, which was my favorite drink in the world for much of my life.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's because I just don't drink soda at all.
Speaker 0: So like because that you know A lot of kids and you drank a whole shit ton of soda at some point in your life Even if not currently and I just never did.
Speaker 0: I drank mostly apple juice, which is you know, so I don't know.
Speaker 1: See, I don't think that's it because it didn't desensitize me.
Speaker 1: In fact, if anything the more soda I drank the more I crave sweet things.
Speaker 1: And once I stopped drinking soda partly because soda was expensive in college and I was kind of poor Well, I went for a top point at all this time and then yes I didn't water real expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not cheaper than water.
Speaker 1: It's only cheaper than crap bottled water.
Speaker 1: Yeah but I just found that I couldn't drink super sweet things anymore after I stopped drinking soda for a couple years kind of like How we used to watch TV.
Speaker 1: I used to watch a lot of TV and then I went to college and I didn't watch any TV because I didn't have time.
Speaker 1: And then I'd go home for a while and the TV beyond.
Speaker 1: and it wasn't just Oh TV it was Wow TV is really painful to watch and crappy.
Speaker 0: Oh, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: I still have the same experience with television, but if I'd been watching TV all through college, I wouldn't have felt that way.
Speaker 1: I just would have watched more TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think so does the same way it could be but Maybe candy is also the same way.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid maybe what I just kept eating candy at the same rate, you know, and and When I you know when I finally got money if I would have spent it all on candy Maybe I still would have kept on with the candy eating though
Speaker 1: I think part of it too is just that kids need a lot more sugar calories than adults do
Speaker 0: they do.
Speaker 1: I mean as a kid think about it I get a bunch of candy and then I'd run around the house for like two hours like hitting my brother and jumping on the couch and having a pillow fight and running outside and chasing the dogs and rolling around and
Speaker 0: Just to play a video game.
Speaker 0: I needed candy.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, and now I don't run around so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I still do but even now I can't.
Speaker 1: of course I can drink a Red Bull just fine.
Speaker 1: I can drink like five Red Bulls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: I can't drink ten Red Bulls Yeah, but I mean the energy.
Speaker 0: it seems like, you know kids get their energies from the sugar, you know They're immediate energies and adults go for like the caffeine or the Red Bull.
Speaker 0: and I wonder you know, what's better?
Speaker 0: Maybe adults should just be going for the sugar some more.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: actually as a kid.
Speaker 1: I went for the caffeine - In middle school, I was one of those kids who carried around the Jolt Cola every day.
Speaker 1: And in high school, I was one of those kids.
Speaker 1: I would I would basically keep two liters of soda in my locker.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about some other candies.
Speaker 0: We talked about the candy bars.
Speaker 0: I know rim has something to say about this.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about gum.
Speaker 0: All right, I like gum, especially bazooka Joe and doublemint.
Speaker 0: I As a kid had braces for like eight years Braces for a while and I didn't chew gum while the braces were going on.
Speaker 0: But I did before and after.
Speaker 1: the longer I mean as it went on when I had braces and had braces and couldn't chew gum gum the memory of what gum was kind of kept Elevating like.
Speaker 1: it was this mystical thing and I kept gum was this awesome thing that I missed and I wanted it more and more As time went on.
Speaker 1: and I remember I got my braces off and I was like goddamn goddamn goddamn son of a bitch And I went got some gum and I chewed it and I remember my orthodontist gave you gum.
Speaker 0: So sugar-free gum.
Speaker 0: as soon as you were dad the braces off.
Speaker 0: He had it at like every station.
Speaker 1: mind it to hitting there and I wouldn't chew it because I those sugar-free thing.
Speaker 0: Ah, they are disgusting.
Speaker 0: I do not like the sugar.
Speaker 1: No, I went straight to a store and I bought me some double mint double mints.
Speaker 0: good.
Speaker 1: I like the double mint, but I Don't like bubble gum.
Speaker 1: I don't like the flavor of bubble gum.
Speaker 1: I don't like bubble gum flavored things.
Speaker 1: The only bubble gum I can stand is double bubble.
Speaker 0: see double bubbles.
Speaker 0: actually the gum I can't stand.
Speaker 0: it seems like the flavor of bubble gum is disgusting.
Speaker 0: well, no if people can't seem to agree on exactly what it is because Everything that calls itself bubble gum tastes different like bubble.
Speaker 0: Yum disgusting.
Speaker 0: bubble tape disgusting.
Speaker 0: Oh bubble Disgusting.
Speaker 0: you've reminded me of bubble tape disgusting but zebra striped gum not so disgusting.
Speaker 0: It's kind of fruity but bazooka Joe is the only bubble gum that tastes good.
Speaker 0: I carefree is okay.
Speaker 0: ish not really.
Speaker 0: but the rest of them all kind of suck.
Speaker 0: and the only other good gums are non bubble gums like double mint or Trident the the cinnamony trident.
Speaker 1: I pretty much actually.
Speaker 0: I used to chew Big Red like cinnaburst when I was a kid, but now cinnaburst I can't hand.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got a fucking story.
Speaker 0: I know you had this story.
Speaker 0: I set it up for you.
Speaker 1: You're beautiful Scott.
Speaker 1: So in high school My school was the pilot program along with a few other schools in the area You know, there was cinnaburst and all those related burst with mint a burst flavor crystals, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, so they tried to market fruit a burst and fruit a burst didn't do so.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I didn't but I don't think any of the a burst is still around.
Speaker 1: but cinnaburst lasted the longest cuz it was pretty Good, it wasn't as good as Big Red back in the day, but the flavor crystals kind of worked.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so my high school got a shipment as part of this promotion of like four or five pallets of this stuff.
Speaker 1: We're talking like tens of thousands of individual five-stick packs of fruit a burst and they gave them out in the school And they did all this stuff with it And then they just stopped doing it and the school still had all this gum left over Fast forward.
Speaker 1: I am a member of the quiz bowl team.
Speaker 1: My school is quiz bowl team is actually super super good partly because a senior who was on the team at the time Was to the gum.
Speaker 1: alright but as advice to say quiz bowl was like this awesome thing because basically we went to these tournaments and we were super into it and we had all these fun superstitions about like you can't shave if we've been out of streak and all that business.
Speaker 1: and The guy who was in charge of the gum was also in charge of the quiz bowl And in charge of the gum meaning the gum was in one of his Offices because they didn't have anywhere else to put it and he refused to throw it away.
Speaker 1: So every time we went to a quiz bowl tournament He'd give everyone on the team one of these packs.
Speaker 1: and it became this tradition of you Open the pack and you start chewing and you're not allowed to stop chewing until you lose a game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you'd have this fruit a burst in your mouth and if we were on a streak for about nine hours You could reverse why you don't like gum.
Speaker 1: you could refresh in an emergency with like another stick or something but you could.
Speaker 1: you had to keep the gum in your mouth pretty much until you lost a game and Sometimes we'd switch it up like at the lunch break.
Speaker 1: We'd refresh and we take all new gum and that was well and good.
Speaker 1: just vertebrates wasn't that bad?
Speaker 1: even though you know If you chew gum for way too long you start to get a headache you start to feel like shit.
Speaker 0: Indeed you get really clean teeth though.
Speaker 1: Yeah But that wasn't so bad because the tradition some a lot of times we'd lose tournaments on purpose Just so we could go play Euchre in football for the rest of the time.
Speaker 1: Nah with the other teams who also lost on purpose.
Speaker 1: pre meditated Lee and then a bunch of shitty teams went to the Championship and our coach would yell at us like what the fuck those teams all suck.
Speaker 1: Why do you get eliminated?
Speaker 1: But anyway, so, uh fast forward two or three years now I'm a senior in high school.
Speaker 1: The tradition still goes.
Speaker 1: the fruit of burst is two years expired.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh, it tastes like I don't know what it tasted like.
Speaker 1: it was disgusting.
Speaker 1: It was so brittle.
Speaker 1: you bit into it and it would try to crack into three or four pieces.
Speaker 0: I hate when gum goes stale like that.
Speaker 1: It's basically ah, uh, all I want to say is the team kept up the tradition.
Speaker 1: I however While I kept up the new fruit of burst.
Speaker 1: no, cuz you couldn't buy fruit burst anymore.
Speaker 0: you bought different gum.
Speaker 1: I just had different gum and I acted like I was true in the fruit of burst But I was totally chewing double min.
Speaker 1: That's the way to go and I want to say everyone else as far as I could tell Was true in the fruit chew in the fruit of burst and I knew it because I saw him spit it out And it was always when you spit it out.
Speaker 1: It was so brittle and expired.
Speaker 1: They would break up into like two or three pieces.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh, yeah Yeah, I remember in high school.
Speaker 0: The winter fresh is really popular, but I never liked winter fresh.
Speaker 0: It's disgusting All right, that's all I gotta add there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember way back before Altoids became like super commonly marketed everywhere.
Speaker 1: Altoids were pushed on me by the high school teacher when I was in middle school of the bay.
Speaker 0: I don't like out toys either.
Speaker 1: I don't understand him.
Speaker 1: I fucking love out.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It's just peppermint.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: There's nothing to it.
Speaker 1: It's just super strong peppermint.
Speaker 0: I'm not a fan.
Speaker 0: I like Man, I like peppermint even but Altoids not so much.
Speaker 1: I don't know but I was in middle school You know, we were all into that.
Speaker 0: Yeah extreme caffeine blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: I wasn't into that.
Speaker 1: I was avoid caffeine avoid Altoids kind of report and parcel to that, you know, yeah extreme caffeine extreme mint.
Speaker 1: check it out.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna need a whole package of peppermints, right?
Speaker 1: I think a lot of people bought him because of the tin Yeah, and because they were really strong and they were kind of a cult thing.
Speaker 1: and then Altoids decided it was time to market them Full-on.
Speaker 1: and Altoids are really popular now.
Speaker 1: There's a million flavors.
Speaker 1: I like most of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah What are the kind of candies can we talk about here?
Speaker 0: We got gums.
Speaker 0: We got Candy bars.
Speaker 1: I used to love Reese's peanut butter cups as a kid.
Speaker 0: I still like them, but I don't anymore.
Speaker 1: I can't eat them.
Speaker 1: They taste like fake crap.
Speaker 0: They do taste like fake crap, but it's good fake.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: It's terrible Reese's, you know pieces.
Speaker 1: Reese's pieces are awesome.
Speaker 0: No, they're disgusting.
Speaker 0: They've always been Dave.
Speaker 0: It's never been the same or as good as the peanut butter Reese's pieces.
Speaker 0: like ghetto child.
Speaker 0: that sucks.
Speaker 0: You can go to hell.
Speaker 0: No M&Ms are the way to go.
Speaker 0: Reese's pieces are like whenever I eat Reese's pieces Cuz I thought I was getting M&Ms.
Speaker 0: then I get Reese's pieces then go.
Speaker 0: what the fuck?
Speaker 0: I thought I was expecting fucking M&Ms this bullshit.
Speaker 1: M&Ms are okay But I always like the M&M was peanuts in him.
Speaker 0: M&Ms with peanuts are superior to M&Ms But M&Ms are okay pretty much anything.
Speaker 0: This is M&M on.
Speaker 0: it is gonna be good in some fashion.
Speaker 0: I mean even when they came out with all those crazy M&M flavors like mint and peanut butter M&Ms and etc, etc.
Speaker 0: None of them were as good as the actual peanut M&M, but they were okay.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't go for them on purpose.
Speaker 1: But let's just talk about candy that sucks.
Speaker 1: I think that's more fun candy that sucks.
Speaker 1: I remember nerds nerds.
Speaker 0: They're okay is?
Speaker 1: I ate him but to this day I don't know why cuz I didn't like him there.
Speaker 0: There's just nothing.
Speaker 0: they're not bad But there's nothing really awesome.
Speaker 1: those came to those packages where there were like two different sides to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: You know, what sucks is pretty much any lollipop.
Speaker 0: That isn't either a blow pop the regular charms pop or a dumb dumb.
Speaker 0: if it's not one of those three lollipops It sucks.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I like kind of those old-school rock candy pops.
Speaker 0: No, no good.
Speaker 0: Like and you see like, you know the old-fashioned like giant swirly lollipops.
Speaker 1: Those are terrible.
Speaker 0: Those don't actually taste good.
Speaker 0: They're disgusting.
Speaker 1: Also, they're really hard to eat.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna finish it.
Speaker 1: You're gonna get sticky all over no matter what you try to do and then you're gonna drop it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it did.
Speaker 0: I don't see the purpose of those other than decorations.
Speaker 1: So does he can carry it around and say I has a lolly I guess but they're disgusting and there's no point to them.
Speaker 0: If it's not a charms lollipop or a dumb dumb, it's ain't worth shit.
Speaker 0: that includes tootsie pops.
Speaker 0: They suck I don't care how many bites it takes.
Speaker 0: They're not good.
Speaker 0: Tootsie rolls are good.
Speaker 0: Lollipops are good.
Speaker 0: Tootsie roll pops are not.
Speaker 1: I liked all those weird.
Speaker 1: I don't know if even tootsie roll made him but they were like vanilla, but they were a tootsie roll.
Speaker 0: I don't remember those.
Speaker 0: I've never heard of such.
Speaker 1: actually I remember as a kid.
Speaker 1: I really like mothballs.
Speaker 0: I don't know what a mothball they're basically just a fireball is.
Speaker 1: there's malted milk balls.
Speaker 0: Thing is atomic fireballs.
Speaker 0: Remember when I was a kid?
Speaker 0: There's this mystique about them like oh man eat atomic fireball used to have like a cup and some water there.
Speaker 0: So you wouldn't hurt yourself with them.
Speaker 1: I would just eat like two of them.
Speaker 1: They were great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just loved him.
Speaker 0: It was basically like a double cineverse in a way.
Speaker 1: what I didn't like though were all those sour candies Like the ones that were like so sour it hurts floating head on them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all the ones hated those also.
Speaker 0: I never understood why anyone ate them.
Speaker 1: a lot of people ate him just to prove how badass they were.
Speaker 0: I think there was.
Speaker 0: there was sort of this trend of candies that were just sort of.
Speaker 0: can you eat this?
Speaker 0: How awesome are you like?
Speaker 0: you'd go to the public pool and at the snack bar you'd get him or the ice cream man would?
Speaker 0: Sell them to you.
Speaker 0: and it was sort of cult around, you know At least this cult following of kids around crazy candies like the atomic fireball.
Speaker 0: Can you eat it?
Speaker 0: Oh, man I don't know if you can.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: He ate it.
Speaker 0: Oh Whoa, he's powerful Goodness.
Speaker 0: power level is over 9,000.
Speaker 0: He could withstand the 10,000 power level.
Speaker 0: candy.
Speaker 1: I just one thing I really always thought were crap or good and plenty's good and plenty's a crap Good.
Speaker 0: do not like jawbreakers.
Speaker 1: My mom ate jawbreakers.
Speaker 1: Ah, like all the time.
Speaker 1: She fucking loved those things.
Speaker 0: They're not good They're just.
Speaker 1: not only she really liked him But she always chewed him up and I remember one time she chewed one up and I was stuck in her throat.
Speaker 1: She had to go to the hospital.
Speaker 1: when she got back All I could say was I told you those things were bad, but she was eating one on the way home.
Speaker 0: So, uh, they're just they're not good jawbreakers.
Speaker 0: No, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Well, what are the candies?
Speaker 0: Can we think of Twizzlers?
Speaker 0: Oh, I love fucking love Twizzlers.
Speaker 1: See I loved Twizzlers Until one day I had real licorice, you know, what fuck Twizzlers.
Speaker 0: No real licorice is actually I don't like.
Speaker 1: I love real licorice.
Speaker 0: No, I don't like it.
Speaker 1: I just I like a Hennes cookies.
Speaker 0: I like liquor black licorice disgusting.
Speaker 1: Oh, I love I love me some licorice just rancid act.
Speaker 0: But only the plain Twizzlers.
Speaker 0: if it's not Twizzler brand if it's some other brand or if it's not the default flavor of Twizzler It tastes like ass.
Speaker 1: I can still eat a Twizzler though.
Speaker 0: Don't get me wrong I just I only like the plain Twizzler and it's awesome.
Speaker 0: But all other kinds I once I remember.
Speaker 0: I actually this is sort of a sad story.
Speaker 0: in a way I was at someone's house for a sort of party in high school, right and there was some Twizzlers there And I just kept eating them and kept eating them kept eating them And I think I ate most of them or all of them like a whole bags worth almost, you know high school I could do that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yep, and Because I had so many Twizzlers I was sort of hyped up and I sort of ended up playing Warcraft 2 on his computer And everyone else watched.
Speaker 0: it was watching Holy Grail, which I'd never watched.
Speaker 0: But since they didn't try to sell me on it or anything I didn't realize what I was missing and I ended up watching it later at some other time.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: Yeah I want to do a show talking about that movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the first time I saw it We should right laugh so hard that I'd miss jokes.
Speaker 0: But basically I was sitting there playing Warcraft 2 which I couldn't play at home and on the other side of the room All these people were laughing hysterically and I was just like yeah, whatever I'm playing this game, which I can't play at home.
Speaker 1: That is really sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Twizzlers they fuck with my brain.
Speaker 0: I couldn't make good decisions.
Speaker 1: The things I always really there's all those stupid gimmick candies like the bloody the ring pops.
Speaker 0: No, they're ring pops are just shitty pops.
Speaker 1: that on a ring Yeah But they were really popular when I was in school and everyone wear them around the school.
Speaker 0: the ones that were actually Okay, because they were practical the ones that came at the push pops that came out of a tube Didn't taste so great They didn't taste bad and it was practical to push him back in the tube and you wouldn't get sticky or anything.
Speaker 1: Actually, I really like those suckers that were like a big sucker at the top with like an O on them And then the stick was just kind of this like piece of paper rolled up That was kind of in a u-shape stuck into it in two spots.
Speaker 1: They're like generic cheapo suckers.
Speaker 0: I don't remember those.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: We call them suckers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a lollipop.
Speaker 0: Fuck it's not a lollipop.
Speaker 1: lollipop sounds very effeminate.
Speaker 1: I question your sexuality.
Speaker 1: Sutter.
Speaker 0: sucker sounds very.
Speaker 1: it's not erotic.
Speaker 1: It's not a lolly.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to go lick my lolly I'm gonna suck on my sucker.
Speaker 0: Goddamn it.
Speaker 0: You're gonna suck on some dick is All right.
Speaker 0: Can we think of any other candy related things to talk about?
Speaker 1: I don't have many more anecdotes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of them involve all their foods or jello or I like just chocolate bars Just flat chocolate like a bar of dark chocolate period.
Speaker 1: oh, man Dark chocolate is like the best thing ever other than white chocolate.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why I mean milk chocolate I guess is edible, but I don't like seek it out often.
Speaker 0: You know, it's usually I want dark chocolate or white chocolate.
Speaker 0: Why do they have this milk chocolate and these other?
Speaker 0: you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: come on It's probably that much more expensive or harder to make.
Speaker 1: Well, the one thing I've learned is that when it comes to chocolate Other than like the highest end of the spectrum the more expensive chocolate is superior.
Speaker 1: Well Except for except for brain brand name crap and like ultra fancy chocolate.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is is this like cooking chocolate?
Speaker 0: right which is like real chocolate, but you can't eat that.
Speaker 0: it's meant for cooking and it's it's.
Speaker 0: it'll ruin you if you try to eat it.
Speaker 0: and Then there's like Godiva chocolate which is better than your average store chocolate.
Speaker 0: you know Hershey's or whatever.
Speaker 0: Hershey's actually isn't so bad, but It's cost so much money for Godiva chocolate that it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not worth that money.
Speaker 0: Hershey's is a better deal because for Hershey's you can get a shit ton for like a dollar.
Speaker 1: I wasn't saying you should buy the expensive shot.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying the expensive chocolate is really freaking good.
Speaker 0: Godiva chocolate is freaking good, but it's not worth the price.
Speaker 0: However, there are other chocolates you can get that are more expensive than Hershey's but worth the enhanced price such as a Toblerone Or something all the Toblerone.
Speaker 0: Toblerone is awesome.
Speaker 0: It comes in a cardboard box and it's got all these little triangles.
Speaker 0: You can break them off one at a time and they got nice little nuts in them And it's good.
Speaker 0: The chocolate is better than Hershey's chocolate.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, actually along those lines.
Speaker 1: those Ferrero Rochers.
Speaker 0: I'm not a fan of the Ferrero Rocher.
Speaker 0: I don't like it.
Speaker 1: So I used to like those a lot.
Speaker 0: No, Greg was the one who bought them.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I bought the Cadbury eggs.
Speaker 1: Oh the Cadbury.
Speaker 1: do you see how the Cadbury eggs are smaller now?
Speaker 0: I do see that and notice I haven't bought any last year in This.
Speaker 1: I used to always think I liked him.
Speaker 1: every time I ate one.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually like it.
Speaker 0: see I like the cream on the inside.
Speaker 0: There's nothing about that cream.
Speaker 0: The chocolate is just normal chocolate.
Speaker 0: big deal, right?
Speaker 0: And it's just a chocolate container for this awesome cream that they make.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the hell's in that cream and Making them smaller means a lot less cream and all I want is that cream and like a tube or something.
Speaker 1: I remember I saw a website up that the idea of that made me a little nauseous.
Speaker 1: I saw a website where a guy tried to cook a cake and he replaced eggs with Cadbury eggs.
Speaker 0: That didn't work.
Speaker 1: It didn't work.
Speaker 0: No I think what they should do is I realized that I can just buy frosting which is you don't know cake frosting is just Crisco And sugar basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's basically just trans fat and sugar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I realized I could just eat frosting.
Speaker 0: Why do I need to get cat?
Speaker 1: that was a bad revelation in high in college when we were kind of poor and we realized that In terms of like, you know taste and enjoy ability and all that Crisco and sugar aka Frosting was a lot cheaper than ice cream.
Speaker 0: You could just buy a tub of like cake frosting for like a dollar and then take a spoon and have at it And if you ate it really slowly That was a pretty good deal for your money and we did that probably more often than we should have.
Speaker 0: No, I think we did it about the right number of times.
Speaker 1: I still think that more than one is more times because you should have learned your lesson.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I learned a lesson.
Speaker 0: It tasted really good.
Speaker 1: I learned my lesson.
Speaker 1: I felt pretty crappy after that.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I felt great.
Speaker 1: Actually what I used to do a lot in college is just eat cookie dough.
Speaker 1: I'd buy a tube of cookie dough just eat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't do that.
Speaker 0: But when I do make cookies, I eat some of the cookie dough and I like.
Speaker 0: I like cookie Dough ice cream a lot.
Speaker 1: I don't know why cookie dough.
Speaker 1: ice cream is awesome.
Speaker 0: It's a. the thing is people seem to make this mistake with the cookie dough.
Speaker 0: ice cream.
Speaker 0: Is they used to in the early days not put enough cookie dough in there?
Speaker 0: It's like what the hell you should be freakin loading this thing up with huge junk.
Speaker 1: Basically, I want cookie dough with ice cream and not the other way around.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Actually the best thing in the world along those lines.
Speaker 1: We've already gone on long enough.
Speaker 1: I think we'll end on this.
Speaker 1: I used to work at the Bella sub shop in Rochester.
Speaker 1: Well that one summer the summer of awesome where me Alex and Scott lived in Rochester.
Speaker 1: I just play Puerto Rico ten times Yeah like every day and I drove to the beach a bunch of times up north a bit and we just kind of Live the lives we would live if we had nothing to do except live our lives.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I worked at this de Bella sub shop to have money to buy food and I learned from the veterans that in the back freezer I mean de Bella's has really fucking good cookies in and of itself.
Speaker 1: the cookies they have are awesome.
Speaker 1: If you're ever in Rochester, New York buy one of their chocolate chip cookies with walnuts.
Speaker 1: You will not regret it.
Speaker 0: I don't think you're gonna regret most chocolate chip cookies.
Speaker 1: No, but these cookies are above average.
Speaker 1: Alright, they're awesome.
Speaker 1: So they get.
Speaker 1: I mean they don't make the dough there But they buy the dough frozen and then they thought and they bake them fresh.
Speaker 1: The dough is sent in cookie form frozen.
Speaker 1: It is stored in the back.
Speaker 1: it does not freeze to the point that it is rock hard.
Speaker 1: if you open an individual package of a cookie and Eat it in its frozen state it is perhaps one of the top 10 most Delicious things in the world.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's that good, but it's really damn good.
Speaker 1: You've never had it.
Speaker 1: I was dubious.
Speaker 1: Someone's like go in the back and eat the frozen cookies and they were freaking out about it.
Speaker 1: So I'm like whatever.
Speaker 1: so I go back there one day and I'm clean and I'm like, you know what?
Speaker 0: All right, and I ended up eating like five of them and then I probably good but they can't be that you're so good.
Speaker 0: I like a cookie.
Speaker 0: which cookie?
Speaker 1: which cookie which is real good?
Speaker 1: Yeah cookie which has got to be like super dry ice frozen though.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing about a cookie which is I want the cookies to be like not warm but cold but squishy You know, they got to be chewy cookies, right?
Speaker 0: But the ice cream has to be freaking like solid hard vanilla ice cream with chips.
Speaker 0: I like when this chips even
Speaker 1: though I like it to be hard at first but with ice cream sandwiches or anything like that I love it the most if the ice cream around the edges is so melted that it's not gonna drip yet But it basically just mushes into my mouth.
Speaker 0: I don't like that so much.
Speaker 0: I like hard ice cream.
Speaker 1: All right, we've talked long enough about that.
Speaker 1: We're going into ice cream territory.
Speaker 1: I think that's gonna be another show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's probably a lot of other candies out there.
Speaker 0: We could just talk and talk and talk about how we hate the watermelon flavor Jolly Rancher and ah watermelon flavored anything That's not a watermelon tastes like an asshole.
Speaker 0: Yeah and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: and well, I guess we'll just Leave it for another time.
Speaker 0: We did a show about candy throwaway Thursdays.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share a like 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.