Speaker 1: It's Monday September 10th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: It's that time of the year and we cop out with a tech news round out.
Speaker 0: Let's do this due to lack of Open EBIT news such and because we're doing a show full of news.
Speaker 0: if you looked at the title I'm just gonna start with a little geek bite.
Speaker 0: I guess it's sort of a geek bite.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it really.
Speaker 1: yeah Why is that?
Speaker 0: well so work right.
Speaker 0: everyone.
Speaker 0: They have an exchange server and everyone with their Microsoft's offices is using outlook whatnot.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: We have like freakin group wise.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah an IBM.
Speaker 0: We had Lotus Yeah, but you know one of my my co-worker the only other Linux guy the other developer He uses like evolution with the exchange plug-in and stuff and I tried to get that to work.
Speaker 0: and it kind of works.
Speaker 0: But it's not perfect and it's kind of slow and laggy and I'm Not a fan.
Speaker 0: So I just been using the pop you know and it works for me, but The pop stopped working because the system in guy I don't know.
Speaker 0: He broke it does not fix it, and he won't restart the mail server.
Speaker 0: ha so I have been using the IMAP and Switching to IMAP from pop was kind of a pain because of the way you know desktop email Applications work.
Speaker 0: Oh of course.
Speaker 0: You know Gmail is awesome and desktop email applications suck.
Speaker 0: Let me get that right out of the way.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I mean once I went to Gmail I'm never going back.
Speaker 0: so in switching to IMAP I said well I can use any.
Speaker 0: I don't have to use evolution here.
Speaker 0: you know which is what I've been using.
Speaker 0: I could use anything.
Speaker 0: so I tried evolution and Thunderbird and silfied and K-mail and they all suck balls, and that's all I got to say.
Speaker 0: is Desktop email clients all suck balls every last one.
Speaker 1: none of them are good I guess the few I use.
Speaker 1: before I gave up on them I was never really happy with.
Speaker 1: and now that I have Google they all do.
Speaker 0: they all are exactly the same.
Speaker 0: None of them offer features.
Speaker 0: some of them might be lacking of features because they're the light ones.
Speaker 0: But like you know evolution came out and those big four right.
Speaker 0: they have all the same features.
Speaker 0: They do all the same things.
Speaker 0: they work in exactly the same way.
Speaker 0: There's really no differences except for you know the specific arrangement of the interface.
Speaker 0: But the interfaces are generally all the same.
Speaker 0: There's only slight differences that aren't very meaningful, and you could use them all interchangeably, and they all suck balls Huh, so no news just a geek bite.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you're using some sort of desktop email client with pops or IMAP Stop it.
Speaker 0: It's not good.
Speaker 1: Yeah granted almost everyone has to use something like that at work, but frankly I couldn't care less what my company makes me use because it's their time.
Speaker 1: And if they want to use something slow and inefficient whatever it's not see.
Speaker 0: it's not about you know what I care It's it's you know.
Speaker 0: I'm using this thing.
Speaker 0: I don't want it to be any more unpleasant than it has to be.
Speaker 1: I just don't care.
Speaker 1: worst case.
Speaker 1: I just stopped reading my email at work.
Speaker 0: Oh Right.
Speaker 1: so along those lines.
Speaker 1: I don't have a news either, but I don't have a geek bite I have a geek back.
Speaker 0: Oh, man's I didn't see any in there.
Speaker 0: What do you see?
Speaker 1: well?
Speaker 1: This one's a slightly old one from not that old from August But from Vicus who was written to us, and if you other is it vicious.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: It's not because it's spelled differently It's vic hus yeah, which I think is just a way of internet spelling vicious sort of like Leac mudkips.
Speaker 1: You know what I refuse to.
Speaker 1: that's like that.
Speaker 1: way back I played the realm right and we formed a little clan or guild called the harpers.
Speaker 1: We all had names from all the D&D books But the name Al Minster was already taken.
Speaker 1: so I had my friend the great wizard el minister.
Speaker 0: That's a really good one.
Speaker 1: I just I couldn't deal with that.
Speaker 1: Okay Vicus rights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you guys have a great point about the incestuous nous of podcast networks.
Speaker 1: I believe this is in reference to when we were complaining another geek back When we were complaining about all of our friend podcasters for promoting each other all the time.
Speaker 0: Well, it was when I did a geek back where someone suggested we make a podcast network.
Speaker 0: And I said podcast networks are stupid.
Speaker 1: if we don't need one yeah, but anyway to continue Just feeding off of one another for common listeners, but in the example of comics podcast I'm obviously Clawsing over some pretty bad grammar here.
Speaker 1: Sorry, dude.
Speaker 1: Isn't the listenership really going to grow depending on how many people have an interest in comics?
Speaker 1: I mean even the most casual of podcasts out there that discuss common book comic books don't seem accessible to non geeks now.
Speaker 1: Uh, I think you're kind of wrong here in that.
Speaker 1: well I guess technically you're perfectly correct.
Speaker 1: a comic podcast can theoretically only have as many listeners as there are podcast fans plus the I don't know one to five percent of people who listen to podcasts about things they don't care about and there are people like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't think you seem to realize that I would say maybe Maybe five to ten percent of comic book readers.
Speaker 1: if that and I'm talking about the upper bound I've ever even heard of a podcast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there are a zillion comic book podcasts and in terms of geekeries out there It's you know that have podcasts like comic books is one of the geekeries that has a lot of podcasts.
Speaker 0: You know talking about it, but even then there are so many more people who are into comics.
Speaker 0: I mean even though that is such a small number of people relative to other things because comics are sort of you know marginalized and niche these days especially in the US That and podcast there's just so many more Despite the small number of comics readers.
Speaker 0: There are even less podcast listeners.
Speaker 1: It's I mean that's how that's how small podcasting is because other people have said this to us before Hey, if you're just focusing on geeky stuff, then you've already got all the geeks and you're not gonna grow from there.
Speaker 1: No, we don't have any of the geeks.
Speaker 1: We have so few people listening to podcast period right now.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean if We're limited basically by the inability to get more people to listen to podcasts Period not the fact that there aren't enough geeks out there I mean think of this.
Speaker 1: let's look at the world of anime, you know, Japanese animation.
Speaker 1: according to Wikipedia There are only like two or three podcasts about anime.
Speaker 1: there even have any reasonable listenership or worth.
Speaker 1: and Yet how many people who watch anime listen to podcast?
Speaker 1: we go to Otakon.
Speaker 0: think about we go to Otakon.
Speaker 0: There's 20,000 people at one convention.
Speaker 0: how many people listen to anime world order?
Speaker 0: Yeah, not that many.
Speaker 1: We spent most of the time at our artists alley table explaining to people what a podcast was.
Speaker 0: Some people were like I was like, you know, they were like, I don't have an iPod.
Speaker 0: I was like wait, they're like, I don't even have a computer.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people who don't have the internet kind of like how on a recent anime world order Dara was doing his con report about the anime fans who were off the radar like the people who go to one con and they've never been on the internet and They just don't know about anime.
Speaker 0: They never been to and you don't even know there's any such thing as a con.
Speaker 1: well No What he was saying is a lot of those people end up at like one local con and their their anime culture Isn't known to most people because it's not on the internet.
Speaker 1: It's not there.
Speaker 1: You'll never see it.
Speaker 1: These are the people who've never even heard a cowboy bebop never heard of Otakon never heard of a podcast don't have internet access.
Speaker 1: They're like 30 years old and they like I don't know whatever they like Go to a dealer's room see a CD are obviously that's legitimate.
Speaker 0: They have no idea.
Speaker 0: They're just completely clueless.
Speaker 0: They like anime because they've seen it somewhere and they're into it, but they're so clueless as about how to like, you know Really get into it.
Speaker 0: It's it's a total mystery to them and they're totally out of the loop.
Speaker 0: and you know what?
Speaker 0: Those are the vast majority of anime fans.
Speaker 0: There are thousands upon thousands upon thousands of those people out there and As soon as they listen to an anime podcast, they're not one of those people anymore.
Speaker 1: So I guess the moral here is that the topic of a podcast has almost nothing to do with limiting the audience because there are enough people out there to Satisfy the demand for just about any topic in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there's a podcast.
Speaker 0: I keep bringing it up because it's some example.
Speaker 0: I remember from the early days of podcasting There was a podcast about Australian real estate.
Speaker 0: Think about that.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean that island is pretty big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know but that podcast could get a bunch of listeners think about like every real estate agent in Australia.
Speaker 0: That's thousands of people probably but then no one knows to listen to podcasts.
Speaker 0: That's their limitation Not the lack of potential audience the lack of actual audience.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, I guess my advice to all you podcasters out there and aspiring podcasters is don't play promos for other podcasts.
Speaker 1: Don't like.
Speaker 1: I'll promote your podcast if you promote my.
Speaker 1: don't even bother with that because if you're listening to podcasts at all They're gonna find your show no matter what you do if they want to listen to it.
Speaker 1: And there's no reason to market to these people or even care about these people.
Speaker 1: no offense to all of our listeners, but You've really got to do the Nintendo thing the blue ocean.
Speaker 1: go out there and find the people who really want a radio show about Making very detailed models of I don't know the woman who played Wonder Woman's breasts
Speaker 0: But they have no idea that it exists and you have to let them know
Speaker 1: find them and tell them hey You know what?
Speaker 1: There's a radio show or a video show or a TV show or whatever on the internet.
Speaker 1: That's about everything you like for free.
Speaker 0: It's totally free and you can watch it whenever you want or listen to it whenever you want wherever you want.
Speaker 0: OMG, yeah, you don't even don't even tell them like a specific show.
Speaker 0: You don't have to pimp any show in particular.
Speaker 0: Yes Get people who are not podcast viewers and listeners to become podcast viewers and listeners and then as soon as they realize how the Technology works and how they can take advantage of it for their own entertainment They will find the show or that they want to listen to or watch on their own.
Speaker 1: I mean look at Connecticut.
Speaker 1: we did a panel on podcasting.
Speaker 1: We didn't even really say what show we did for a long time or talk about ourselves at all.
Speaker 1: We talked about all the other podcasts we like.
Speaker 0: So stop trying to like up your listener numbers by trying to like group together people who are gonna be listeners of your show anyway, and just Get more listeners into the you know, make the market grow rather than trying to eat out a bigger piece of this incredibly small pie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, thanks Vikas.
Speaker 1: You brought up an interesting point of discussion and it allowed me to once again poke fun of the practices of my fellow podcasters.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know how many of you are old enough to remember this song even though I can't really say that too Seriously because the song is even a little bit old for a Scott and myself.
Speaker 1: It's kind of it's not old It's the nostalgia that it is intended to evoke is definitely for a generation slightly older than us.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's for sure.
Speaker 0: But I've heard the song everyone's heard the song Even if you don't know who sings the song, you know the song Yeah, but I would wager that a lot of our listeners don't.
Speaker 0: I could imagine that the punk kids don't know but everyone else knows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mostly I brought that up because one all the people are old enough.
Speaker 1: so going god God, damn it you punk kids and it going.
Speaker 1: wow We're all Because that's the worst thing when someone younger than you is complaining about how old they are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I digress.
Speaker 1: so you've all heard the song.
Speaker 1: I hope we didn't start the fire.
Speaker 1: You know, we didn't start the fire.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna sing like Dave and Joel always try to do.
Speaker 1: but uh I'm not gonna talk about my feelings on that song.
Speaker 1: but very briefly I'm generally of the mind that the song is kind of a cheesy cop-out.
Speaker 1: It's one of those ideas of hey I'm just gonna load this song up with Nostalgia, even though it's actually really really repetitive and not that insightful or meaningful or anything.
Speaker 0: Well lyrically I would have to agree with you musically.
Speaker 0: It's an it's an average pop song.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just.
Speaker 1: it's very.
Speaker 1: I would almost say that that song was trite and manipulative Kind of.
Speaker 1: but anyway the point is that regardless of how you feel about the song the song became a blockbuster success because People are heard the song and remembered all the things.
Speaker 1: just to kind of brings them back to all their times in their life And all the things they've lived through.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Well, there's a video circulating to internet that is attempting to do the same thing for the internet.
Speaker 1: It is entitled internet people.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you've all seen it already.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know a lot of you in the forum said wow, that was amazing.
Speaker 1: Wow, I really felt it Wow.
Speaker 1: How cool was that?
Speaker 1: And I'm gonna say you should see it.
Speaker 1: But I'm gonna take the contrary position and say that it was pretty piss-poor and I was really disappointed with it.
Speaker 0: I think it was kind of meh.
Speaker 0: I mean that musically it was worse than we didn't start the fire lyrically nah slightly worse.
Speaker 1: and The the animation that you know what you actually see in the video was poorly done and really not that clever.
Speaker 1: It was one of those overly literal not interesting.
Speaker 1: why even bother with the video things?
Speaker 0: It's sort of one of those things where it's like I can't actually make something creative and popular.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna aggregate creative and popular things and hopefully get like a you know a second run on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's one of those.
Speaker 1: obviously the guy who did this our girl.
Speaker 1: I didn't look at who did it I don't really care had the great idea.
Speaker 1: Hey, why don't I make one of those nostalgia songs about the internet?
Speaker 1: And that'll make me famous.
Speaker 1: it kind of worked because the things super known and popular.
Speaker 1: but you really a for idea D for implementation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really didn't.
Speaker 0: I mean I watched it and I was just kind of like.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's what that is.
Speaker 1: The worst thing is it's it didn't even cover the real span of that sort of thing on the internet.
Speaker 1: It was way too recent and covered things that were so new or on Noteworthy that I didn't even I hadn't heard a lot of them.
Speaker 0: to be honest Yeah, pretty much only covered things like since the existence of dig these people whoever made it wasn't really, you know There were.
Speaker 1: there are very few things in there that weren't super recent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only old thing in there was like all your base and it's like Did you forget about like the pusher robot and the shovel robot?
Speaker 0: Did you forget about like Zumble come?
Speaker 1: Did you?
Speaker 1: yeah, and even if you don't show it you gotta say or somehow bring up goats See because they did they said goat seed like the word appeared that it.
Speaker 1: I didn't even notice that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they didn't mention the other ones though.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, or this is I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm really disappointed with that video and it surprises me that so many people like it so much because it.
Speaker 1: I Don't know if maybe my attention span is a few minutes longer than everyone else's but a lot of that stuff just wasn't that noteworthy or nostalgia worthy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like it mean someone coming up and saying hey rim, huh?
Speaker 0: The What's the the the what the Numa Numa guy?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the Numa Numa guy That's not gonna entertain me.
Speaker 0: Just someone saying hey, remember this.
Speaker 0: so saying hey, remember this about everything Not any better.
Speaker 1: at least it had Washington in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I did.
Speaker 0: it did have Washington.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the thing is Washington the real Washington despite being of similar graphic quality was actually so much better.
Speaker 0: The thing is I think for most of the stuff that was live-action, right?
Speaker 0: They did.
Speaker 0: they actually drew like they drew a Numa Numa guy who looked like King Hippo Yeah, but like they didn't draw Washington.
Speaker 0: They just copied and pasted Washington because he was already animated You know, they just it was kind of a yeah someone out there do something better.
Speaker 1: I don't have the time or the inclination right now.
Speaker 0: No, nor do I care.
Speaker 1: Plus you really got to hit the more serious things.
Speaker 1: make it actually nostalgia worthy.
Speaker 1: make it one of those.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, the you can't just say the thing and show a picture and a you know drawing of it.
Speaker 0: You got to have to like, you know, like bring it back Like you got to be like, you know And I don't just say like show like the Numa Numa guy going like my yeah
Speaker 1: Yeah, like cut to that as a musical bridge or yeah
Speaker 0: or even in real like I just sort of merge them together in a new interesting way where the Combination of the parts actually creates a new hole rather than just referring to the originals.
Speaker 1: I mean even we didn't start the fire musically it kept like the Music would build up and build down and come to climaxes when certain words were being said it was done.
Speaker 1: Well and the music and this was just really But completely.
Speaker 0: are we done talking about how sucky this is done making fun of this?
Speaker 0: So some company it's a UK defense firm called kinetic with Q's instead of K's and They made a vehicle an unmanned flying vehicle that runs on the solar power.
Speaker 0: Ooh and People have made these before but this one they say flew for 54 hours on its own.
Speaker 0: That's like the record.
Speaker 0: but they didn't get the record because the people who are allowed to you know Decide if it was the record breaker or not did not watch because it was secret
Speaker 1: huh,
Speaker 0: but now they say they're gonna do another one for like 33 hours that they'll be allowed to watch I guess.
Speaker 0: so they can get the record and they're like Yeah, we can do this forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna you know, to be honest the whole idea of world records.
Speaker 1: I just don't care about it.
Speaker 0: I don't care either.
Speaker 0: But what I do care about is Unmanned flying things that can fly really high up and really far for a really long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sadly, you know who else probably cares about that a lot.
Speaker 1: spy the military.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So while I could use one to say load up Google Maps I have a feeling that it's not gonna directly benefit me for a long time, but it could.
Speaker 0: And it's cool to look at it.
Speaker 0: Looks good.
Speaker 0: It looks like a paper airplane, but made out of solar cells.
Speaker 1: So we haven't done this in a while, but there's been a lot of tech news.
Speaker 1: so I think it's finally about time to cop out and do a Tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: it helps is the perfect day to cop out and the news Timing is perfect and just everything sort of came together for us to beat to it at its own game.
Speaker 0: I'll tweet anyway, so obviously the biggest news did we discuss this on the show yet is the?
Speaker 0: I don't believe.
Speaker 0: so All the new Apple action, all right.
Speaker 0: So first you've got the iPhone going down in price from I think what 600 to 400, right?
Speaker 0: I particularly like how there's that rebate whatever after it was two months of the iPhone at $600 and now it's $400.
Speaker 0: then Because Steve Jobs said alright Anyone who bought the iPhone for $600 gets $100 in store credit.
Speaker 0: So now that is brilliant cuz they just give them some accessories and shit for their iPhone.
Speaker 1: Not even then you know that those people are gonna spend more than $100 in the Apple store.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you know you go in the Apple store with $100 in credit.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna?
Speaker 0: Buy you could buy some accessories But like you buy one accessory is like $60 or $40 and then another one and then there's something left.
Speaker 0: Or maybe you'll buy like that $80 keyboard.
Speaker 0: then what he can do with the $20?
Speaker 0: So you're gonna buy something you know it with $100 in the Apple store or on the Apple website.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much impossible to spend all of it without going over in some way.
Speaker 1: I just wonder if this specific move wasn't pre-planned from the start.
Speaker 1: charge X Reduce price X time later now.
Speaker 1: I don't have a goodwill kind of.
Speaker 1: hey we care about our customers so much.
Speaker 0: I don't think that the it was planned from the start because He sort of You know messed up the marketing of it and that if the rebate was planned He would have mentioned it when he announced the iPhone.
Speaker 0: all right and what's happened now is because he didn't mention.
Speaker 0: Or I guess he came up with the rebate.
Speaker 0: You know later like the next day or after his you know little you know presentation is that all the news stories are?
Speaker 0: Concentrating on oh man iPhone price drop.
Speaker 0: They're totally giving the finger to all the early adopters And they didn't concentrate on all of Apple's new iPods and things and That didn't work out too Well for Apple they should have.
Speaker 0: if they had planned it in advance they would have been smart enough to mention the rebate.
Speaker 0: You know when during the presentation which would have helped them out a lot, so about those new iPods.
Speaker 0: So what they do?
Speaker 0: they I think the shuffle.
Speaker 0: does it have new colors?
Speaker 0: Maybe?
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: I didn't even look doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: the nano is now shorter and fatter, but much thinner.
Speaker 0: I guess it's stupidly thin, but it can now do videos and everything.
Speaker 1: I am excited But at the same time I'd have to buy a new mount for my car.
Speaker 0: Yeah They the iPod Classic is sort of the same as the iPod.
Speaker 0: the normal iPod has always been except It's now.
Speaker 0: I think you can get it with like a hundred and sixty gigs or something ludicrous like that.
Speaker 0: But I heard a rumor that it was sort of laggy like using it.
Speaker 0: huh and the interfaces on the nano and the classic are sort of improved to be more iPhone.
Speaker 0: ish with like the albums that go Swoosh and everything, but it's not a touchscreen.
Speaker 0: It's the same disc.
Speaker 0: We're used to.
Speaker 1: you know that's fine We're a regular iPod.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'd want the touchscreen right.
Speaker 0: just get in my way and distract and then they've got the iPod touch Which was almost I almost cared about it, so did we ever get an answer?
Speaker 1: uh?
Speaker 0: No, actually.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure the answer is no, but there's no.
Speaker 0: yet There's no abs.
Speaker 0: I have not seen any actual full-on confirmation.
Speaker 0: Basically the iPod touch is an iPhone without the phone and it's like $300.
Speaker 0: I think you can get it at 8 or 16 gigs or something like that right with flash and The news stories I keep seeing about it are oh man it.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: they took out the add Contact button.
Speaker 0: you know you know to sort of.
Speaker 0: they basically took things out of it.
Speaker 0: all right feature wise out of the software to Differentiate it from the iPhone itself.
Speaker 0: It's like there's a the device the hardware that can consists in the iPhone The not the iPhone.
Speaker 0: the iPod touch is capable of ludicrous things.
Speaker 0: it could do amazing things But it doesn't because Apple has decided to just you know put the software in there.
Speaker 0: So it only does certain things Mostly what an iPod does plus a little bit more.
Speaker 1: see the thing the one product that I've said this before I was waiting for And I would pay a lot of money for Some sort of portable mp3 player with Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the iPod touch has Wi-Fi that I could just run iTunes on and just get my podcast from wherever yep and this Touch had that I'd pay almost a thousand dollars for it possibly and it but it does.
Speaker 0: as far as we know it doesn't have That.
Speaker 0: what it does have is you can go on the iTunes store through this iTunes Wi-Fi interface they give you which is also going to be available in the iPhone and You Can buy songs you know like.
Speaker 0: you can search for an artist and then it'll show you their albums.
Speaker 0: You could touch the album with your finger and download the album But so far there is no indication that it can get podcasts.
Speaker 0: the only device I know of that is Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: that can get podcasts is the PSP which I would buy for that feature if it wasn't so goddamn Big.
Speaker 0: it's huge.
Speaker 0: Even the new thin one is still as wide said this gigantic screen.
Speaker 0: I don't need that screen to freaking listen to stuff all right.
Speaker 0: I don't need this UMD drive on there It's it's too much.
Speaker 0: It doesn't fulfill the purpose.
Speaker 1: see I think what Apple's going for here Is people are out on the go and they're in a hot spot or whatever it.
Speaker 1: suddenly They want to hear a song like they just start thinking about a song.
Speaker 1: Now they can get the impulse buy market out there and not just at home.
Speaker 0: yep And also what it does is when you get back home.
Speaker 0: If you sync with your iTunes it will take any songs you bought on your iPod touch or your iPhone and put them In your iTunes, I wouldn't be surprised if there was some sort of dual marketing thing where in major urban areas They start doing thing.
Speaker 1: I can think of a lot of ways They could.
Speaker 0: well they have a thing in Starbucks where you can buy the song that's currently playing in the Starbucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I expect a lot more things like that, and I if I were them.
Speaker 1: I'd actually go around to all sorts of businesses and Pay them to play certain songs.
Speaker 1: that I think would be I don't know impulse buys for the target demographic of said stores Maybe but just to you know reiterate again.
Speaker 0: Oh first.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's one other small thing which I'll get to but they The not supporting podcasting as much as it could be supported.
Speaker 0: We just talked about how podcasts aren't so big and they could be.
Speaker 0: the problem Is the people who make the technology that could bring podcasting into the into the fold are not making that technology.
Speaker 0: The Zune could sync up and download podcasts.
Speaker 0: it has all the hardware to do that But it doesn't just cuz no one made the software for it.
Speaker 0: the iPod touch could do it But it doesn't.
Speaker 0: a trio could do it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't.
Speaker 0: any portable device with Wi-Fi could have a podcatcher That was all slick and could just synchronize podcasts wherever you are.
Speaker 0: so a new episodes come out there They appear could even notify you that new episodes are out And you could listen to them on the device and delete them from the device and not have any Synchronizing or anything.
Speaker 0: but no no one makes such a device now.
Speaker 1: one could say this is not my opinion But this is the kind of thing that you would see some guy on slashdot write a big paragraph about.
Speaker 1: One could argue that perhaps the reason this doesn't this this is the way everything is is Simply that the current content producers are as always threatened by any sort of media or any sort of distribution method They can't control especially when said distribution method is full of free stuff made by people who aren't trying to make money.
Speaker 0: And it could be.
Speaker 1: one could say if one were a conspiracy theorist that perhaps The people who have some sort of influence over Microsoft and Apple you know people like EMI or other content Distributors or content owners might be really downplaying or keeping down.
Speaker 1: I'm not podcasting, but just any sort of open media.
Speaker 0: Or you could also say that hey You know the iPod touch right let's say it did have a podcatcher right.
Speaker 0: it had let you Synchronize your podcast on the device just like I want.
Speaker 0: How many sales would that really get them above and beyond?
Speaker 0: sure we give my say.
Speaker 0: you know what rim sale even if it got?
Speaker 1: Every listen every person in the world who listens to podcasts right now immediately went out and bought one.
Speaker 1: That's a drop in the bucket of how many people are gonna buy an iPod touch.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's really not enough for them to take that into account.
Speaker 0: when in you know making a business decision remember Apple much like Nintendo Above all else.
Speaker 1: you can't forget no matter how much you like a company that they just want your money and They both do the same kind of thing of release.
Speaker 1: just enough to get the majority of people.
Speaker 0: Why should they spend their time and money developing more software for a device?
Speaker 0: if that saw you know if they spend?
Speaker 0: $20,000 paying a guy to work on software for half his for half a year right he's a $40,000 your employee to make one more application for the iPod touch.
Speaker 0: and Then how many iPod touches they have to sell to make up for that guy's salary?
Speaker 1: yeah I mean iPods don't sell because of podcasting they sell because of iPods.
Speaker 1: Yep Right so don't get away from that unless you have anything else pertinent to say.
Speaker 0: no The only other thing is I. it's sort of a chicken and egg in a way where if they started pushing The the podcasting onto the iPhones and on to the zooms and things and he actually caught on.
Speaker 0: Then by making podcast device You know it's like they could create.
Speaker 0: they could help create the market to make more money But at the
Speaker 1: same time
Speaker 0: and saying there is no market the
Speaker 1: moment the market actually exists in Podcasting or syndicated anything like that starts to really take off
Speaker 0: then
Speaker 1: everyone else like Microsoft will just jump right in
Speaker 0: yep And the Sansa will even have Wi-Fi and let us get podcasts on and everything.
Speaker 0: so yeah Oh, and you can.
Speaker 0: you can now turn any song you buy in the iTunes music store into a ringtone.
Speaker 1: Do you see that for a dollar?
Speaker 1: that's brilliant marketing, and they're gonna make so much money off that.
Speaker 0: But you see someone hacked it all the thing is what happened was is someone realized hey if I just rename this you know M4a file or AAC file to be like M Like are something right.
Speaker 0: then it will.
Speaker 0: iTunes will think it's a ringtone And it'll just work and I won't have to pay a dollar.
Speaker 0: But then the iTunes upgrade came through you know to Matt.
Speaker 0: you know because every time they bring out new iPods They upgrade iTunes to work with the new iPods and that hack that trick didn't work anymore.
Speaker 0: So I guess they thought of that.
Speaker 1: yeah, well what I'll say very simply is that while from a money-making perspective It's brilliant to sell people their own songs again.
Speaker 0: Just to be well They're not telling you the song again is they're saying it's a. you know you add a dollar to the.
Speaker 1: yeah So you have to buy the song again for a dollar and ringtone form effectively yep That's basically paying a dollar to rename a file.
Speaker 1: the fact that the phone doesn't let you just make any file You want a ringtone is kind of shit it is.
Speaker 0: That's just a really there is no Technological reason that it couldn't just do that.
Speaker 0: for you know that it doesn't cost Apple any resources whatsoever.
Speaker 1: what it does Is it cost them the opportunity cost of the millions of people who are gonna pay a dollar to get a ringtone?
Speaker 0: That's what it does do.
Speaker 1: so I guess it's smart of Apple to do that to make money and also same time Really shitty of Apple to do technically the record companies.
Speaker 0: that the way the royalty works is they yeah charge again When a song is used for as a ringtone because it gets played in public and all sorts of crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we're not gonna get into that.
Speaker 0: It's like you buy a song and now I can't use that recording of the song that I purchased.
Speaker 0: in any way I want I can only use it in certain ways and fucking right.
Speaker 1: so an actual science news news being in quotation marks here Russia The has claimed that they have discovered a magical mythical mineral in the Arctic somewhere that just Somehow removes radiation from water-based solutions.
Speaker 0: all right all right Let's not even because I don't want to say Not even what do they mean remove?
Speaker 0: Where does it go?
Speaker 1: Let's not even get into the scientific.
Speaker 0: Oh come on.
Speaker 1: I would just like to point out that stories like this come out of Russia a lot Lately and They're almost always bullshit.
Speaker 1: There was the one a while ago about they brought those dogs back to life And it was totally fake and there was no actual thing that was Australian Yeah, but that Australian article linked to a Russian study.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure there's a bunch of crap like that And it seems like a lot of this is going hand in hand with Russia's kind of attempting to Remilitarize even though that's basically just a joke.
Speaker 1: and yeah Russia's trying to make itself look like it's very important.
Speaker 1: and this I think is just a straight-up lie on the behalf of Russia.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's definitely a lie.
Speaker 0: I mean where do they say the radiation goes?
Speaker 0: no, but I don't think this is just oh we found Because I don't want to get into that, but it's I tech day.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk about politics and in foreign stuff.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about the science and the tech.
Speaker 1: I think the science here is that in political science no the Russian government as I think that this is a straight-up hoax lie, and it's not even an accident or anything.
Speaker 1: It's just they are trying to convince the world that they are somehow still irrelevant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but now great.
Speaker 1: There's no way such a thing were true.
Speaker 1: That would revolutionize the world.
Speaker 1: that would be one of the most amazing advances in possible.
Speaker 1: because then we have a solution to the Problem of nuclear waste and yeah, we just take this mineral and like you know make a nuclear reactor out of it.
Speaker 1: And then holy crap that's all I have to say about that.
Speaker 0: It's just yeah.
Speaker 1: have such the audacity to lie openly about something like that.
Speaker 1: I'd hundred percent doubt that this is true.
Speaker 0: I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: if something absorbs or gets rid of radiation well has to go somewhere.
Speaker 0: does it go become heat?
Speaker 0: if That's the case it'll freaking start crazy fires, right?
Speaker 0: Where does it?
Speaker 0: where else could it go?
Speaker 0: it could turn into the mineral itself right.
Speaker 0: so I think it's our mineral grows as exposed.
Speaker 1: I think it turns into communism.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like as the mineral is exposed to radiation it starts to grow and turn red Matter to it.
Speaker 0: turn it Superman if something's growing like that.
Speaker 0: It's gonna become radioactive itself eventually, but it just doesn't work.
Speaker 0: It makes no sense.
Speaker 1: Like I said, I wasn't going to get into it, but I somewhat doubt the veracity of the claims of these Russian scientists.
Speaker 0: All right, so there's a bunch of AMD news here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's two big Start.
Speaker 0: well, there's like two or three, but I'm gonna start out.
Speaker 0: AMD has come out with these like quad-core Opterons right and they're supposedly not so expensive, and they're supposedly wicked fast.
Speaker 0: And you know for a while.
Speaker 0: I thought ah AMD is going down.
Speaker 0: They got there.
Speaker 0: You know the Intel's got the dual core the core two duos and AMD isn't keeping up.
Speaker 0: and even though the AMD stuff is kind of cheap It's it's not really fast enough or reliable enough.
Speaker 0: But now they've got like this Opteron.
Speaker 0: let's see what it is the Opteron two three five.
Speaker 0: Oh, which is two gigahertz quad-core for 389 ha $389 and it's supposedly wicked fast.
Speaker 0: I don't know how it heats up or any or you know it's Pat.
Speaker 0: I'll see.
Speaker 0: power efficiency I guess it's kind of average, but that's nothing to sneer at right there I mean granted a quad-core has almost no desktop uses That's true.
Speaker 1: but for the server market that Like Scott said nothing to sneeze at because the server market is actually still in flux because desktop Whatever the high-end chip market AMD and Intel still both have very good offer.
Speaker 0: But at the same time if they're whipping out you know these quad cores and the $300 $400 for the server market Right the desktop ones man.
Speaker 0: They're gonna.
Speaker 0: I think that's gonna be.
Speaker 0: it's getting really tight basically Yeah, and it's tough to call.
Speaker 1: I don't think they can.
Speaker 1: they can't make faster dual cores They're basically just making quad cores at the speed They can make them which is great for the server market.
Speaker 0: supposedly they're gonna have like four gigahertz ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah Don't forget right around then is when Intel's pen rins are gonna start coming out.
Speaker 0: isn't the pen run what we have now?
Speaker 1: No The next.
Speaker 0: the thing were that they Intel claimed that the I don't know the name I hate when people use those names.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure Henry and Scott is the next gen.
Speaker 1: I have no idea that was when it's the current core to duo technology and core to quad just twice as fast.
Speaker 0: Huh well who knows I'm not gonna bother to look up all those names right now, but yeah AMD whoa watch out it the CPU race is getting tight.
Speaker 0: I think this is not the time to buy a computer And you should probably wait until like there's a period of time perhaps After the holiday season or during it when it's like.
Speaker 1: ah yeah I mean I bought one because I had to and even then I bought my computer during a Plateau was a short plateau, but there was a plateau.
Speaker 1: right when I bought my computer There was this plateau, and I knew that there was a steep increase coming.
Speaker 1: I figured by October late November There's gonna be a gigantic change in computing technology again.
Speaker 1: I just wasn't willing to wait that much longer.
Speaker 0: in addition to that AMD.
Speaker 0: all right you might know from many people yelling is that AMD's video drivers?
Speaker 0: They kind of suck.
Speaker 0: Nvidia's video card drivers are kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: Intel's are okay.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons for that.
Speaker 1: We're not getting into it.
Speaker 0: Nvidia's Technology is closed source.
Speaker 0: It's all secret.
Speaker 0: Intel's is not so open source, but they have their specifications online.
Speaker 0: So it's pretty easy for the open source developers to make Intel video card drivers and for the most part They work really well without any sort of user Interaction.
Speaker 0: right ATI has had the problem where they were also closed source like Nvidia But the driver they made for Linux that was closed source sucked.
Speaker 0: so pretty much all Linux people were just like.
Speaker 0: alright We're pretty much only buying Nvidia and Intel cards.
Speaker 0: you know Nvidia when you need 3d Intel when you don't screw ATI and Anyone with ATI and Linux was just suffering and complaining.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, you can listen to some old episodes where we had trouble.
Speaker 0: Against everyone's predictions and anyone's wildest dreams AMD has come out and said AMD slash ATI which is the same company.
Speaker 0: now remember they came out and they said well We're gonna give you the specifications, but you get it to sign an NDA now, and they said wait actually no forget about the NDA We're just gonna put out enough specifications.
Speaker 0: So people will just be able to make open source video drivers for The ATI cards.
Speaker 0: and it's suddenly ATI.
Speaker 0: AMD in like an hour in like a second has gone from being you're the enemy of the Linux world to we love you.
Speaker 0: Fuck Nvidia ha ha.
Speaker 1: now part of the reason for that.
Speaker 1: I mean even Nvidia solution.
Speaker 1: while the drivers were closed source at least Nvidia worked Relatively well with.
Speaker 1: you know open source stuff, and they they did as well as you could expect And they did have Nvidia people.
Speaker 0: they do have Nvidia employees working on the kernel and other open source stuff to make sure that their Driver works.
Speaker 1: the issue was that right about now While generally I still I've always thought that envy like the Nvidia side of technology was generally more robust.
Speaker 1: But ATI very recently their high-end cards are a little faster than Nvidia's high-end.
Speaker 0: Well the cards have all.
Speaker 0: it's always been close You know the high-end cards versus the high-end cards and the price performance has gone back between unlike AMD Intel where Intel always sort of was down on the price performance ratio even if they were up on the performance.
Speaker 0: ATI and Nvidia have always been pretty close on the price performance ratios You know and the high-end cards from both companies have always been stupidly overpriced and no reason to buy them.
Speaker 0: But I guess just at this moment in time.
Speaker 0: I think ATI is a little up with what their HD something whatever cards and They also like the latest ATI closed source drivers Right are suddenly catching up to the performance of the Nvidia drivers and Linux like they're not quite there But they're actually not as bad as they were.
Speaker 0: they used to be useless.
Speaker 0: now They're kind of and they're open source and well They're not open sourcing But they're opening the spec for open source people to look at to be able to make better open source drivers.
Speaker 1: now I predict that Nvidia within six months is going to do something similar.
Speaker 0: They're gonna have to do something because if an open source driver for ATI cards comes out You know for you know how many Linux nerds are gonna jump on that and make it better as fast as they can.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's already some people who are working on this nouveau project Which is a project to make an Nvidia driver that is completely open source.
Speaker 1: now one step further if I was in video I would tap those people.
Speaker 0: yes, but what's happened is Nvidia is basically not going to help or hinder them in any way.
Speaker 1: I think they're gonna change their tune as time goes on.
Speaker 0: if they don't change their tune I do foresee that you know basically as soon as a driver comes out That's open source for ATI cards that works and is awesome Which I imagine will take Six to twelve months before it's.
Speaker 0: it's at a point where people are using it and it when it's included in an Ubuntu release Is the moment.
Speaker 1: basically now this is this whole market shift.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't want to go into much more detail because we could talk about this forever.
Speaker 1: I think that what we're whatever we see happen in the next six months to a year because of all this is Going to be one of the first really good indicators of just how important Linux is on the desktop scene.
Speaker 1: because if suddenly ATI sales start going up at a Noticeable rate then there's no way they can claim anything other than that's because Linux people stop buying Nvidia.
Speaker 0: yeah, because the basically the rate of buying video cards is sort of unchanging and they make their profits and all the people who keep Buying the hottest new video card no matter what constantly because they're crazy stupid gamers who don't know any better.
Speaker 1: So now we're gonna find out how many of those people do a boot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they like also to make most of their money in you know The direct sales like if Dell decides to put Nvidia cards in the chips in their computers.
Speaker 0: That's where Nvidia makes its big money.
Speaker 0: If you know I guess gateway doesn't.
Speaker 0: if Toshiba decides or HP to put ATI cards in a line of PCs.
Speaker 0: That's where ATI makes all their money.
Speaker 0: So any difference, you know that this will cause is gonna be in the in the gamer market and the nerd market.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna figure out just how much of the nerd market is Linux.
Speaker 0: people by looking at the difference in How ATI's sales increase because they will increase if ATI.
Speaker 0: if Nvidia doesn't do anything I guarantee it that over the next two years ATI will see sales go up and the Nvidia will see sales go down if the open-source ATI driver comes out and is working.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I mean there's a chance that there won't be.
Speaker 1: it'll just be a blip and no one will notice.
Speaker 1: in which case we know That no one actually cares about Linux.
Speaker 0: in which case then why doesn't Nvidia open source?
Speaker 0: It's not gonna hurt them if it sales aren't gonna change.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: I don't understand.
Speaker 1: I will I never understood.
Speaker 1: I mean, what could the driver have in it?
Speaker 1: That would be such a trade secret.
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: it is written really well, you know, and I imagine there are some algorithms or technique.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: now that I may be patented just now my my broad guess not about technology But just look at the history.
Speaker 1: for the longest time ATI's drivers for their own cards even when the cards were technologically superior Were kind of crappy and there were a lot of times where the driver alone was hindering the performance of an ATI card.
Speaker 1: Yeah, meanwhile Nvidia's always had really good drivers.
Speaker 0: I think Nvidia.
Speaker 1: the reason they stayed back from this for so long was just that they didn't want ATI to pick up any tricks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh, well I think they would.
Speaker 0: they would be really smart to do.
Speaker 0: right is if they open source their driver on Windows, too Because you know if why.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: think about how much money Nvidia spends on Making their driver.
Speaker 0: not much ATI spends on making their driver.
Speaker 0: These people out there will make your driver for you.
Speaker 0: just open source it and these random people Will keep maintaining it and they already don't give any warranty for their driver, right?
Speaker 0: All they need to do is have like a couple guys to let you know Just keep putting the spec out for the new chips so that the new features on the new chips You know will be put into the driver on time.
Speaker 0: Maybe hire a guy to make sure that the driver keeps pace with the you know the chip development features and such.
Speaker 0: but other than that why bother paying developers to maintain these drivers when people out there will do it for free and Essentially make the same product.
Speaker 0: They could save a lot of money doing that.
Speaker 1: Oh well Yeah, but regardless this is good news, and I really want to see what comes of it in the next six months.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my bike plus am I paying ATI.
Speaker 1: I might well.
Speaker 1: I just bought a high Didn't?
Speaker 0: I didn't?
Speaker 0: you didn't I didn't like so I did.
Speaker 0: I just bought an Nvidia card but in two or three years about when this thing will be set and done is the next time I'll make a move.
Speaker 0: and whoa who knows?
Speaker 1: so in somewhat less good news in fact possibly bad news from slash out here as of September 1st the free XML TV guide service at zap to it labs Has shut its doors due to misuse issues and all.
Speaker 0: Let me let me explain this to people so you understand what the story is.
Speaker 0: Let's say you use myth TV.
Speaker 0: myth TV is basically and free TiVo.
Speaker 1: yes Leave it at that.
Speaker 0: instead of getting a TiVo you get a computer you install Linux on it you install myth TV on that and Then now you have a computer that is a TiVo and you don't have to pay TiVo a monthly fee.
Speaker 1: Not only that it's better than TiVo because you can skip ads however you want.
Speaker 1: you're totally unrestricted Whatever.
Speaker 0: you're basically using a PC instead of a TiVo you own it.
Speaker 0: It only costs you the price of a PC because the software is free and there's no monthly fee and no nothing.
Speaker 1: Myth TV is pretty easy to set up that unless it doesn't work on your hardware in which case just give up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you need to be if you buy a computer knowing you're gonna do myth TV with it.
Speaker 0: It is not hard now.
Speaker 0: The only thing missing from the myth TV that the TiVo has is you need the TV listings right.
Speaker 0: let's say I want to record Seinfeld right every episode of Seinfeld.
Speaker 0: well on a TiVo I just go and I click on Seinfeld because it looks like a TV guide on the TV screen.
Speaker 0: I click on Seinfeld and I say record all the Seinfeld's.
Speaker 0: and it knows you know not to record two of the same episode of Seinfeld if it gets a rerun on the same day at like two different times.
Speaker 0: or it knows You know when Seinfeld is on.
Speaker 0: it knows Seinfeld is on this channel at this time and this channel at this time and such And such and such.
Speaker 1: I can just scroll through the directory and say I want to record that show and that show and that show And that show.
Speaker 0: I don't need to know the times of the shows beforehand.
Speaker 0: I don't need to have like a paper TV guide in front of me.
Speaker 0: I don't need to type in like you know channel six at seven because that would be what's the point then?
Speaker 1: right but The real problem is most of the services that give you this information are not free.
Speaker 0: yet There is no.
Speaker 0: if you set up a myth TV box the only thing hindering you is that how does this computer that you just set?
Speaker 0: Up know when shows are on?
Speaker 0: are you gonna type your TV guide into it?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: it needs to connect to some server somewhere that has the TV Listings and has to get the TV listings from that server and some company has to put the TV listings into that server and has To know where you live.
Speaker 0: that's you know what channels you get.
Speaker 0: it has to account for like satellite channels You know has to count for everything different time zones.
Speaker 0: It's crazy It's a lot of data, and it's hard to manage and until now there was only one place You could get that information for free and that was zap to it And they would give you this information in XML form for free if you signed up and whatever.
Speaker 0: and now they're good.
Speaker 0: So what do you do?
Speaker 0: You're gonna type in seven the hostage on channel three.
Speaker 0: That it's really bad.
Speaker 0: think about it though.
Speaker 0: all the information you can think of right is online.
Speaker 0: the weather You know the time.
Speaker 0: all the TV listings are not really online.
Speaker 0: Are the TV listings online?
Speaker 0: I've never seen them.
Speaker 0: They're fine.
Speaker 1: when was the last time you looked for a TV list?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna look right now But I remember from the times when I did try to look for TV listings very hard to find online.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, well I mean I think there's a bunch of issues here because a lot of the people on slashdot are basically railing against.
Speaker 1: this is ah That's bullshit.
Speaker 1: How dare those people giving me a free service decide to not bother giving me the free service anymore?
Speaker 1: How dare they indeed and there's this this happens with other projects, too Just because people have been providing a service for free for a long time or for a short time for any amount of time and For whatever reason they stop.
Speaker 1: a lot of people on the internet have this kind of sense of entitlement that hot it's mine.
Speaker 1: They can't stop.
Speaker 1: they got to keep giving this to me and a lot of people are really mad about this.
Speaker 1: But if someone's giving you something for free I really can't see any valid way to complain if they suddenly stop.
Speaker 0: Alright TV guy calm has TV listings, but they're kind of ad.
Speaker 0: they're not really all too useful.
Speaker 0: And well the guys are like four pages to get to see.
Speaker 1: the trick isn't getting the listings because that information is out there.
Speaker 1: The trick is getting the listings converting it into a form that myth TV can then understand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and companies like TiVo jealously guard their listings because well because they have to pay someone to provide them with a list.
Speaker 1: Well, not only that but that's one of the prime benefits you get for buying a TiVo.
Speaker 1: Is that that all just works?
Speaker 1: You don't have to worry about it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I mean your cable company doesn't even want you to have the listings.
Speaker 0: they cuz they show them on a channel that they Want you to watch because that channel has ads.
Speaker 0: yeah I don't want you They don't want you to have TV guide cuz then you're not gonna go to the channel that has the ads and the listings on It.
Speaker 0: so yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: do you think another company is gonna just show up with XML TV listings?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of people are gonna start using various hackish Scrapers that'll go to websites scrape the information turn it to XML.
Speaker 0: I just went to TV guide calm and it looks like not the trivial thing to scrape.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I was looking through some of the scrapers out there and they're just pearl monstrosities.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and apparently they break often because people notice the scraping and fix it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just.
Speaker 0: It's bad news for myth TV users.
Speaker 0: However, even if I had a myth TV, I wouldn't be using it as a DVR because I don't watch TV.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing The.
Speaker 1: the core truth is simply that this information Does not really exist out there in a useful form for these people and it's not trivial to put the information in this useful form.
Speaker 1: so the capitalist solution is to pay someone to put this information into the form for you or To do it yourself and pay for it with your own time and a lot of things.
Speaker 0: I wonder.
Speaker 0: like any of those I wonder how much the places that are non free, right?
Speaker 0: There must be non free places to get this information.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there are.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there are cuz they'd like oh the last non free one is gone, right?
Speaker 0: And I remember when I researched myth TV a year or so ago that there were non free alternatives.
Speaker 1: I do wonder how much they charge because $15 for three months and they're hoping to change it to $20 a year.
Speaker 1: Is that what it says for one run by the myth TV?
Speaker 1: devs saw www.schedulestirect.org.
Speaker 1: $20 a year.
Speaker 0: I was just about to say that if they charged outrageous prices that I would think about starting up a competitor to charge a non outrageous Price, but $15 for three months $20 a year.
Speaker 0: Those are both reasonable price.
Speaker 0: You know what thing for that service?
Speaker 0: I'd be willing to pay that if I was a TV watcher with a myth TV.
Speaker 0: $20 a year $15 to three months.
Speaker 0: You're still owning the price of a TiVo which is what like 20 a month at least probably more plus the cost of a TiVo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just the fact that a lot of people are complaining so loudly about the free thing going away when there is a perfectly reasonable Paid one out there.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like the feet like I can see people's complaints when a CD cost You know 20 bucks and a crap CD in the discount bin cost seven bucks.
Speaker 0: But it's like Skype was giving out the free phone calls, you know for a while and it's over now But you don't see anyone complaining because it was reasonable.
Speaker 1: Imagine if a CD was a dollar fifty and a song in iTunes was five cents at that point.
Speaker 1: I don't care how you know righteous and indignant you are when you start complaining and pirating stuff.
Speaker 0: I would buy so much God if it was no DRM, I'd buy so much goddamn music.
Speaker 1: But you know people would still complain because they can't get it free anymore.
Speaker 0: And then they those only people who would complain Would be people who didn't have jobs yet the college kids in the high school kids because they don't even have the nickel or the dollar Fifty.
Speaker 0: and if I wasn't still a college or high school kid I would still be getting the music for free well even if it was a nickel a song.
Speaker 1: the reason for that is simply that we went to our IT which had access to internet to And if any of you have never been on internet - it is nothing but mp3s and software stupidly fast.
Speaker 0: You can download like a gigabyte in a minute and the RIAA just can't get in there.
Speaker 0: so they get.
Speaker 0: but you know if it was a dollar fifty in album or fifty or like five cents a song.
Speaker 0: and I Now I'm a person who has a job that pays money And I don't have a lot of time.
Speaker 0: and I you know I like I have so many mp3s Just don't listen to because they've been sorted you know and it's such a pain.
Speaker 0: I don't download music just because it's such a pain.
Speaker 1: I'd probably re-buy almost my entire collection.
Speaker 0: I probably would just for the convenience of having it be sorted and correctly labeled and all that jazz I would go and buy like probably like $500 worth of music.
Speaker 1: just let's see that proves the point that the information itself the mp3 files Even though you can go out and get it free Not that useful.
Speaker 1: But people like us and I think a lot of people are willing to pay to get the information in a usable form.
Speaker 1: the the process Of making the information usable is still marketable even if the information itself can be stolen.
Speaker 0: because as free as Downloaded stealing and stealing mp3s is It's still inconvenient without even in the Napster days the Golden Age when Napster was full-on.
Speaker 0: it was still Inconvenient compared to iTunes which is more convenient.
Speaker 0: There is no doubt, and I'm willing to pay for convenience.
Speaker 0: I'm just only willing to pay about ten cents five cents.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: so you can make money Because you have the advantage of convenience on top of the product itself.
Speaker 0: You just have to make the price so low that you know it makes up for the the inconvenience of downloading for free.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I got another one here.
Speaker 1: alright rim is really hungry and wants some Chinese food.
Speaker 0: I got some more real ones right there real quick.
Speaker 1: Let's be alright Let's just do a bam bam bam because I really want to eat.
Speaker 0: okay first BAM NTP pool reaches a thousand servers needs more.
Speaker 1: all right NTP is great.
Speaker 1: I have words about implementing NTP, but that's beside the point.
Speaker 0: yep The NTP pool is basically a bunch of people who set up their computers to keep track of time so that other people can synchronize their computers to have the correct time.
Speaker 0: and I encourage people who have spare computers to join.
Speaker 0: have a computer.
Speaker 0: join the NTP pool So that more computers on the internet can have correct time for free.
Speaker 1: in fact I'm thinking of when I build my new server in the house We're gonna have an external facing server with you know SFTP and all that business or idiot friends can send us files.
Speaker 1: I'm really thinking.
Speaker 1: I'll just make it an NTP pool.
Speaker 1: doesn't hurt me.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's some guy who went missing and they're you see faucet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who is?
Speaker 0: do you know about him?
Speaker 0: I don't know about him.
Speaker 0: I just I'm missing.
Speaker 1: Here's what I know about him.
Speaker 1: He is missing and the internet cares.
Speaker 0: Yes, uh they're using amit.
Speaker 0: the interesting thing isn't me?
Speaker 0: I guess it's sad that he's missing even though I don't know anything about.
Speaker 1: at the same time It's it while that said this illustrates a point because this happened before with the other guy went missing that Geeks on the internet even if they don't know a geek they'll use technology if they can to try and help each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like imagine if you know there was just another one of those you know sensationalized missing little girls Cases.
Speaker 0: right they would not be using Amazon's mechanical Turk to find her you know because it's just.
Speaker 0: they're not.
Speaker 0: It's just the way the geek community is right now is it's you know?
Speaker 0: the geeks are helping each other out.
Speaker 0: people who are have A presence on the internet are getting helped by the internet.
Speaker 0: You know when you give to the internet it sort of gives back to you.
Speaker 0: You know you give to an internet community that community gives back.
Speaker 0: So they're using Amazon's mechanical Turk to help find this guy And I guess it's sort of helping.
Speaker 0: maybe if it actually finds the guy that'll be amazing.
Speaker 1: well what they're doing is they're looking at small images from satellite photos taken recently and People just look at one and see if they see the wreckage of a plane.
Speaker 1: Hopefully they can narrow down where he is out there.
Speaker 0: yep, and if someone says yes I think I see wreckage on this one and no I don't see any on this one then the Professionals look at the ones that people mark as yes And if they see something that they send a crew out there.
Speaker 1: So there have been a bunch of stories about you know the old Amazon one-click shopping patent and the BS around that.
Speaker 1: There's been a bunch of articles lately pointing out that the US patent and trademark office is Really starting to shape up when it comes to technology issues and one of the things they're looking at more and more closely is the possible Bullshittedness of this patent.
Speaker 0: it's the most bullshitted patent ever and it's really one of the only.
Speaker 0: I submit that the patent that may I'm just a behalf for IBM I'm just saying is that this is a pretty nefarious and infamous patent And it's one of the only evil things really there is about Amazon.
Speaker 0: It was otherwise pretty nice in terms of internet companies And if it gets turned over then that marks like a new age for patent goodness instead of patent evil.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: And also there's an article here Columnist it's on slashdot.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna bother with who wrote it, but it talks about Online relationships, and how people shouldn't just dismiss them as not being real because they're online.
Speaker 1: and all I want to say is that I?
Speaker 1: think that's pretty obvious.
Speaker 1: because regardless of if people see each other in person or whatever an Emotional relationship can happen in just about any format, and if you doubt that just go on live journal for like five minutes.
Speaker 1: yeah, and There's a lot of cases coming up where you know people are married or dating and then someone has an emotional attachment with someone online And maybe there's significant other Dismisses this as not being real and that's only gonna lead to problems down the line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've heard I know of like two or three stories of you know two people married with kids.
Speaker 0: One of the people who's married meet someone on the internet runs away, and that's the end or don't even run away.
Speaker 1: But you know if they're really into it they get married in World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: And then that relationship becomes more important than the quote unquote real relationship.
Speaker 1: and if you care more about a person that you know online than someone you're living with then How?
Speaker 1: who could say that one relationship is somehow more valid?
Speaker 1: no even though the other one is more emotion.
Speaker 0: I cannot say they're let more or less valid, but I can say that a Online relationship does have problems with it that real-world relationships do not.
Speaker 0: for example You know there was a story recently like some guy who is like oh, it was actually someone.
Speaker 1: he met the person.
Speaker 0: You know you know it's like you don't really know.
Speaker 0: it's like you got a. that's why I kind of like you know community Relationships on the internet.
Speaker 0: you got like a forum, and then you actually meet the people in real life.
Speaker 0: at some point It's like ah well at the same time.
Speaker 1: I mean we don't have to say just a romantic relationship.
Speaker 0: No, it could be.
Speaker 1: you can have an emotional relationship with someone online.
Speaker 1: I mean I back in the early days of.
Speaker 0: but the same problems can happen where you don't you think you know about the person But really you only know you're having this emotional relationship with the online persona.
Speaker 0: That is not necessarily the true person and there could be deception that does not really exist so much in Longer-term real-world relationships because it's hard for people to Put on such a fake persona unless they're like a con artist if you're actually sitting there next to them.
Speaker 1: true I guess the point I want to make is just that a lot of people dismiss The social interaction online as not being real and not being worth worrying about and a lot of times That's real case.
Speaker 0: It's real.
Speaker 0: It just has a potential for deception.
Speaker 0: Do you want to do one more?
Speaker 0: let the IBM open office?
Speaker 1: Oh?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: We should talk about that.
Speaker 0: I think that'll be the last one all right, so IBM has been supporting the open document format, which I'm not gonna talk about that.
Speaker 0: No, it's a whole show, but it's basically yay for not Microsoft.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's a whole other issue about how IBM has been going.
Speaker 1: I mean when I worked there This was a really big trend and I actually was a big part of that and we got rid of a lot of Windows PCs but pushing and pushing toward Linux and open source and Internally just not being dependent upon other people's crap
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: So they're actually what they've decided now is they're going to put some developers to start working on open office.
Speaker 0: So IBM people are gonna work in open office.
Speaker 0: the same way IBM people work on eclipse and the first thing they're gonna Do is they're gonna sort of add this I?
Speaker 0: Accessible to thing to the open document format and such.
Speaker 1: yeah, we don't have to go over the details.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically what they're gonna work on first is they're gonna make it so that if you're a blind or a debt I guess mostly blind but also deaf people.
Speaker 0: Maybe I guess I think they have a problem with documents on computers They're gonna make it easier for blind people to use Open office.
Speaker 0: so basically if this works out I see a lot of visually impaired people just drop in Microsoft Office and use open.
Speaker 1: Oh, I gotta read between the lines that I think the reason they're doing that first because that generates a lot of good PR buzz A lot of charity buzz and that sort of thing because the in the corporate culture and IBM is actually very big on Charity and community work and things like that because we go.
Speaker 1: I mean good gets done, but it also makes the company look really good.
Speaker 0: IBM donates a lot of money to charity Yeah, but technologically speaking this technology this I accessible to is actually interesting in that it's it's a technology It's not just you know helps read the screen to the to the blind person.
Speaker 0: we have that already.
Speaker 0: it helps read Text embedded in charts menus pictures pop-ups and hyperlinks, so it's actually really cool What it does and that's that's pretty advanced stuff right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but beyond that there I think the ulterior motive is that I mean IBM.
Speaker 1: internally we use like Lotus and crap but really everyone just use word and Philosophically and realistically they don't want to have to keep upgrading and dealing with word and new versions.
Speaker 0: if you're IBM Why do you want to pay Microsoft to have a word processor?
Speaker 0: You don't want to do that.
Speaker 0: That's just costing you money for nothing.
Speaker 1: and also IBM was putting a lot of money into Lotus and crap.
Speaker 1: And you know one if they put the money into open office They get the same benefits in terms of the technology getting better that they get putting it into Lotus But they also get all the open stuff and they get the goodwill of the Linux community And they can you know push their Linux on people with.
Speaker 1: look we contribute back and it's just a Situation for anyone, but Microsoft.
Speaker 0: and they can push out Microsoft who they don't like and Microsoft's not doing too.
Speaker 0: Well with their Ooxml format they're trying to push.
Speaker 0: it keeps getting voted down all over the place.
Speaker 1: There's reasons for that But we'll save that for that could be a whole show that one.
Speaker 1: so up in other news Rim stomach just started rumbling.
Speaker 0: mine's been rumbling so they got home.
Speaker 1: Let's get some Chinese food.
Speaker 0: That sounds good.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you Can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.