Speaker 0: It's Monday March 19th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We explain version control systems such as CVS and subversion in simple layman's non-technical terms.
Speaker 0: Let's do this So Friday night.
Speaker 0: Well actually Friday evening.
Speaker 0: I was trying to leave work, and I noticed that a little bit of snow a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was in the city and there was some snow coming down, but it didn't look like anything that was gonna disturb my day.
Speaker 1: You know it all melted as soon as hit the ground.
Speaker 1: Not really any trouble.
Speaker 0: so as soon as I get to my car it turns into a blizzard And I basically had to drive home in a blizzard.
Speaker 0: now I learned something interesting the taconic which is this road that for anyone who lives in New York you know about the taconic.
Speaker 0: Basically it was ground to a halt due to the fact that I don't know there were a million Accidents on it because everyone's stupid and it was snowing.
Speaker 1: it seems like every time it snows That people forgot how to drive and snow the last time.
Speaker 1: it's not like.
Speaker 1: I go and I see this accident And there's some Florida plates there.
Speaker 1: It's not like a going to see this accident, and it's teenagers It's middle-aged people from New York?
Speaker 1: Did they not drive in snow last winter or a few weeks ago?
Speaker 0: It seems like what most people react in one of two ways to there being snow on the ground.
Speaker 0: They either drive as fast as they always drive Which is already too fast in most cases and end up crashing or they go one mile an hour and don't let me pass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, though Growing up in Michigan has a lot of benefits also having a car that Doesn't really look it, but it's actually pretty high off the ground and has a pretty good suspension in terms of dealing with snow.
Speaker 0: So I decided to take the back roads.
Speaker 0: I drove off through the mountains to get home on this little road that kind of hugs the Hudson River.
Speaker 0: There was maybe one other car on.
Speaker 0: this whole road wasn't plowed, but you know what.
Speaker 0: I got home Just fine because there wasn't anyone in my way Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: yeah, I was on the train of course on the way home And I didn't really look out the window cuz I was minding some business while I was on the train And I got off the train.
Speaker 1: it was a lot more snow and beacon than there was in New York City.
Speaker 0: Now I submit to you that the beacon train station is kind of low and all of the roads out of it go uphill.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it's the train station is on the Hudson River.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if the town was lower than the river that would be trouble I imagine you know with flooding and such.
Speaker 1: so yes The it basically from the river.
Speaker 1: then there's the train station at the same level as the river and then it only goes uphill from there pretty steeply in fact and Basically they didn't plow the parking lot and they were considering that it was still snowing heavily.
Speaker 1: there really was many I and it had already snowed a lot though And they didn't plow the roads going out of the train station.
Speaker 1: So like me and my car along with I'd say five or six other cars We're unable to make it out of the train station.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I did make it out of the train station.
Speaker 1: I didn't make it up the hill like I made it about halfway up the hill And then the incline at that point was just like the limit.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: Here's the point which I couldn't go up.
Speaker 0: Here's the point at which I want to jump in because I know which road that is that road goes.
Speaker 0: You know you can turn right and it seems to go off nowhere You can turn left, and it goes up to Main Street in 90 and all that you could have turned right.
Speaker 1: no Yeah, I'm smarter than that.
Speaker 1: all right I was thinking cuz you know there's a long line of people going left And I thought I'm gonna go right.
Speaker 1: because yeah when I got up to that part where you choose between going left and right There was a little accident over to the right and some emergency vehicles, and they weren't letting anyone go that way.
Speaker 1: Wow All right, and then so I go left, and I'm in this long line of cars going left.
Speaker 1: I probably could have made it up that hill if I was all alone.
Speaker 1: You know just I had just like I got some speed when the incline wasn't there And then I rolled up the rest of the hill.
Speaker 1: you know with my existing speed I could have done that But you know it was a long line of cars basically creep creep creep creep.
Speaker 1: And if I stopped and tried to like leave a space in front of me No all the cars would come and pass me on the left and go over the WL line that no one could see.
Speaker 0: Hate to say it that but that probably would have been me.
Speaker 0: it seems like cuz I've seen.
Speaker 0: oh Yeah, it seems like Mazda 3s.
Speaker 0: Just don't handle snow.
Speaker 1: very well I think it's cuz.
Speaker 1: my tires are shot from driving in the middle of.
Speaker 0: no tires aren't that bad.
Speaker 1: They're pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I took a look at it.
Speaker 1: You know how to tell if tires are bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's little wear indicators.
Speaker 1: you take a penny and you put it in the groove and if you can't cover half the penny Then you need new time.
Speaker 1: well the
Speaker 0: actual way you tell is that they're wearing wear things and you look in the tread and if the tread is worn down to the point where it's level with the indicator then your car is now at the minimum tread level if not below it and you have to get them replaced.
Speaker 1: mmm-hmm.
Speaker 0: now if Your tires are just worn on the edges Then it's usually not that big of a deal.
Speaker 1: now my tires are.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna need new ones pretty soon.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't need tires that often.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I think they were shitty tires, and I think I drove them.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean the tires that the car came with the brand new car.
Speaker 0: Yep that one uh-huh That's an interesting hypothesis, and I can't wait to see how well this all pans out.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna get new tires.
Speaker 0: Anyway so in the news There's been this lawsuit against internet archive org Which is a really cool website that kind of archives the internet.
Speaker 0: so say you've got a website in 1997 they take a snapshot of it and then in 2007 there's another snapshot and there's snapshots all along the way.
Speaker 1: that way you can you know.
Speaker 1: see hey?
Speaker 1: What did Google look like in?
Speaker 1: 1999?
Speaker 1: and you can go find out.
Speaker 1: it's a really cool thing Google exist in.
Speaker 0: I don't think I've always played around with this site.
Speaker 0: I like going to it.
Speaker 0: well a while ago this crazy lady sued them for Cashing her crazy website, and this has suddenly been in the media.
Speaker 0: So I thought I'd talk about it as a little blurb or thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I wasn't really gonna do news about it But then I fell down the rabbit hole and there was far more to this than met the eye.
Speaker 0: So this woman has this website now before we go any further because this woman seems to be suing everyone on the planet I would like to point out that everything I am about to say is hearsay that I read on other websites on the internet.
Speaker 0: I am NOT asserting anything.
Speaker 0: I am merely pointing out things that I have read on the internet that may or may not be true.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh so with that disclaimer aside.
Speaker 0: There is a woman named Suzanne shell and she has this crazy website.
Speaker 0: I'm not really sure what it advocates because it's all over the place.
Speaker 0: It's one of those.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much just nuttiness.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know those you know those kind of websites that have a million Semi-revolutionary quotes and a whole bunch of kind of rambling text and a bunch of like Neil Adams website and the time cube website.
Speaker 0: Yeah Lots of red text and different font sizes and links and the text is all over the place and there's frames Business all over.
Speaker 0: in fact this site even has a pop-up before you can even go to it.
Speaker 0: I think it's some JavaScript thing I didn't really look.
Speaker 0: that asks you if you agree to the terms of service to view the website But it doesn't show you the terms of service.
Speaker 0: huh well it either advocates for or against child protective services.
Speaker 0: I am not sure which.
Speaker 0: Huh, it's generally nutty in my opinion.
Speaker 1: I would agree with that opinion.
Speaker 1: so I didn't even read anything on the site.
Speaker 1: I just looked at it.
Speaker 1: I said wow that's nutty.
Speaker 0: so at the bottom of this website.
Speaker 0: There is a great amount of text and this tech.
Speaker 0: you should go to the website.
Speaker 0: It's pretty funny to look at but at the bottom There's all this text and this woman has this really warped idea of how the internet works.
Speaker 0: And I'll copyright works and everything works and it goes so far as to talk about the $5,000 licensing fee for cashing or reproducing her site anywhere and how to buy a license to print it.
Speaker 0: and She has this whole crazy rant about how she disabled right-clicking and Printing and all that stuff because people were ripping her off or using her website against other people.
Speaker 1: This is like those people who say that if you go to a website and blocking ads you're stealing because looking at the ad is The price of admission.
Speaker 1: guess what have you noticed that?
Speaker 1: other websites?
Speaker 1: Don't say that crazy shit.
Speaker 1: Have you noticed other websites?
Speaker 1: don't have these crazy agreements.
Speaker 1: You know as you're the odd one out.
Speaker 1: Maybe you're not.
Speaker 1: maybe you've never seen another website in your life.
Speaker 1: if you don't want your shit to be printed or saved as or Used in other places on the internet don't put it on the internet.
Speaker 0: I'm actually of the mind that anything that is lawfully published to the internet on a public web server should.
Speaker 0: there should be some sort of safe harbor law saying that as long as it was published legally and in no violation of its own copyright or other copyrights then anyone has the right to copy and Disseminate that information with.
Speaker 0: I mean, obviously I agree with very easy to that.
Speaker 0: at least cashing should be okay.
Speaker 1: Cashing and content parsing I mean just someone visiting her website is caching it in their web browser.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not paying her five thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 1: I visited the site about five times since I read this bit and disabling right-clicking and printing with JavaScripts or whatever guess what doesn't work.
Speaker 1: someone who's smart enough.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna work on them.
Speaker 1: I can still print it if I want your.
Speaker 1: you know bullshit is not getting him.
Speaker 0: I remember in the 90s when I first went to a where site and I was trying to download stuff And I right-clicked on something and this pop-up thing appeared and said hey You can't right-click you gotta pay to get access to blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And then I turned off JavaScript and then I right-clicked and I downloaded my wares That's right.
Speaker 0: That was great.
Speaker 0: So that that alone would have just been a crazy woman.
Speaker 0: well the internet picked up on this the lawsuit and all that and dig at a story and a bunch of other sites had stories and this woman started getting a lot of hits and A lot of hate mail and there was a lot of articles all over the place talking about how crazy she is And that pushed her over the edge And she it looks like she was even posting on dig defending herself as best.
Speaker 1: this crazy woman came But she does what most crazy people do and they were react crazily.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like where a troll is usually one guy who gets a whole bunch of people to go nuts.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like the opposite where a whole bunch of people do a simultaneous Troll targeted at one person to make them go nuts and this lady went all around the internet going nuts.
Speaker 1: We basically like it was like a little bear in a cave.
Speaker 1: We poked it with a stick and ran away and everyone's sitting there watching to see what it's gonna do and they all laugh.
Speaker 0: Hahaha, so now apparently she's suing a bunch of people.
Speaker 0: I think she said she's gonna sue dig.
Speaker 0: Apparently she wrote this crazy rant on her website, which I would just recommend you go read.
Speaker 0: She's got a bunch of facts as to why she's mad and she's mad about all these iGeeks she calls and then she has a footnote Denoting that iGeek means internet geek.
Speaker 0: and oh you internet geeks have your panties all in a twat.
Speaker 0: about this blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: You just don't understand how the laws work and you guys want everything blah, but it's just it's so you're living in the year 1929.
Speaker 1: get with the times.
Speaker 1: we're gonna kick your ass.
Speaker 0: If any of you can get through her site enough to tell me what her opinion is on Anything other than this whole dig business.
Speaker 0: whatever what your stance actually is I Won't give you anything, but that'd be interesting.
Speaker 0: now the rabbit hole gets deeper.
Speaker 0: now This is all hearsay And I'm gonna start with the things that are more verifiable and go toward the things that might just be outright lies.
Speaker 0: Alright, so apparently in 2005 she demanded that the Internet Archive pay her like a hundred thousand dollars For archiving her website multiple times between 1999 and 2004.
Speaker 1: all I got to say is we know it's craziness And there's no way it's gonna happen, but if she succeeds we are loaded Cha-ching.
Speaker 0: well among other things she seems to think that spidering her website is impossible because of the safeguard She has but to even if it's not possible.
Speaker 0: It should be illegal and you should have to pay.
Speaker 0: obviously She's never heard of robots dot text.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if she has heard of robots dot text The only reason robots dot text works is because search engines decide that they are going to pay attention to it.
Speaker 1: like Google respects Robot dot text if Google comes to your site, and they want to you know put it in the Google index They first look at robots dot text and they say hey does this person want to be in Google?
Speaker 1: and if the robots dot text Says no Google is nice, and they won't put you in Google Yeah, which really only hurts you unless you're doing something shady.
Speaker 1: Yep, if I wanted to make a search engine I could just make a search engine that doesn't give it two shits about robots That text and spider you anyway.
Speaker 1: It's not a goddamn thing you could do about it besides making your website non-public.
Speaker 0: Well the just the legal system seemed to agree with archive org and threw out almost all of her claims Summarily and without any consideration.
Speaker 1: see did she not learn her lesson.
Speaker 1: Why would you ever try?
Speaker 0: Oh?
Speaker 0: Learning her lesson?
Speaker 0: well apparently now according to this in 2001 the Colorado Supreme Court charged her with unauthorized practice of law Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: and in I think 2004 maybe 2005 she was cited in another court for contempt of court for ignoring the 2001 order and then apparently in 2006 this happened again.
Speaker 1: I wonder what law she's practicing crazy law now.
Speaker 0: I would have I believe that hearsay because on her website She has this crazy rant about unauthorized practice of law and how it's unconstitutional And morally wrong for there to be any restrictions on anyone practicing law.
Speaker 0: Now I have feelings.
Speaker 1: I got a slight agreement with that, but not much.
Speaker 1: I mean you can't just have people running around being lawyers willy-nilly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I agree with the right of anyone to defend themselves in court if they feel that that is what they should do.
Speaker 1: But you cannot go for you know Representing someone else in court without proper training and skills.
Speaker 1: now You could just be you could just suck.
Speaker 1: really bad.
Speaker 1: I mean if someone decides to represent themselves And they suck at it That's their own fault.
Speaker 1: if someone chooses you to represent them in court And you suck at it Then it's sort of your fault And you shouldn't be allowed to take that fault unless you pass that bar thing.
Speaker 0: well the problem with all that is just that When it comes to more mundane things like a renters agreement, or let's say Software licenses someone techno Technological who doesn't have a law degree or isn't a paralegal and where this all varies from state to state.
Speaker 0: I don't think someone like me should be barred from giving advice on Software licenses provided that someone like me makes it clear not a lawyer.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I agree however.
Speaker 0: It seems like New York State is actually extremely down on that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: See I think you should be able to give anyone advice on anything.
Speaker 1: it's free speech.
Speaker 1: You know if it's legal advice just like if it's doctor advice.
Speaker 1: you say I'm not a doctor, but I recommend this medicine.
Speaker 1: You know I'm not a lawyer, but I recommend this law.
Speaker 0: yep Well, I'd be great with a law that says how prominently you have to point out that you're not a lawyer How often you have to say it that sort of thing?
Speaker 0: Maybe you should wear a big yellow star on your arm that says I'm not a lawyer whenever you're trying to pull that.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: so this woman's obviously according to the internet a nutjob.
Speaker 1: Hooray nutjobs.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what else I could say about this other than that.
Speaker 0: Here's the final bit and I saw this said in three different locations by apparently three different people.
Speaker 0: They claim that this woman has ties to the Church of Scientology Well that explains her legal tactics and that her website is basically a trap in order to bring about lawsuits.
Speaker 1: That could be so also.
Speaker 0: they also claim that the Church of Scientology did this with a number of front organizations throughout the years.
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 0: Do not know if this is true or not.
Speaker 1: it is entirely hearsay I find likely because it's very similar to the legal tactics of the Church of Scientology.
Speaker 0: I Find internet references to it, and I'm just going to relay it all to you because I find it hilarious.
Speaker 1: It is quite hilarious Alright, so this is guy named.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say I actually can't pronounce this name right which I'm usually very good at.
Speaker 1: it's Dilip koteta.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, I L I P K O T E CHA right?
Speaker 0: what nationality is that?
Speaker 1: I have no clue.
Speaker 1: He looks like a nice guy though.
Speaker 1: It's like an old.
Speaker 1: He's looking old man looks kind of like my grandpa only thinner I can't really tell.
Speaker 1: anyway He's a. he's basically a retired guy who used to work in the food manufacturing industry, but he's not retired anymore.
Speaker 1: Now he runs a business in instant yogurt, it's Got.
Speaker 1: it's called yo kit.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: ok it It's like an instant cup of yogurt that lasts for 12 months on the shelf And he's you know thinking about using it for all sorts.
Speaker 1: He's gonna make a lot of money from this yogurt probably if I if it tastes good.
Speaker 1: But that's not the news.
Speaker 1: a guy making yogurt who gives a shit.
Speaker 1: the news is the way he made this yogurt is He basically had a patent Donated to him from a bigger company that had figured out instant yogurt And they weren't using the patent.
Speaker 1: so they gave it to this small time entrepreneur guy And he took the patent and he went nuts.
Speaker 1: and now he's got a successful yogurt business and trepanor and trepanor entrepreneur.
Speaker 0: whatever People in the forums are gonna jump down your throat.
Speaker 0: I figured I'd preempt it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, so Now there's this big movement cuz you know 90 to 95 percent of patents are just sitting there not doing anything.
Speaker 1: You know no one's making any money off of them.
Speaker 1: they're just patents that companies collect over time in case they want to sue someone or in case they need one.
Speaker 1: and You know there's a bunch of groups of people who are trying to encourage these big companies with useless Unused patents to donate them to small businesses.
Speaker 0: I think that's cool.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing that bothers me about it, though This is sort of backwards when you think about it.
Speaker 1: the point of the patent is that the small-time guy comes up with something And then he's protected from the big guys.
Speaker 1: But now it's the small guy has to beg the big guys to let go of the idea.
Speaker 1: He came up with Already that they just happen to have a patent on because they have a million patents and he can't take you know make his money off his idea without you know a Donation a nice donation from the guy who's already got more money.
Speaker 1: He knows what to do with.
Speaker 1: The other thing is if you're a big company with a lot of unused patents And you're donating them to one guy so he can make money What the hell donate them to?
Speaker 1: like the world just give them up, so we everyone can do stuff.
Speaker 0: Maybe we need some sort of legislation that would Automatically release patents to the public domain if they're unused or under certain circumstance.
Speaker 1: I would say unused for six months.
Speaker 1: It's gone.
Speaker 1: You know it's like you're not What?
Speaker 1: well okay?
Speaker 1: If you're not it's like.
Speaker 1: you don't have to be you know making money off it right now if I patent some gizmo.
Speaker 1: You know and you know on the side I'm working on the gizmo as long as I'm still working on it You know, but if I forget about it for six months to a year that I'm done.
Speaker 1: You know it's like what the hell.
Speaker 1: if you're not making money off that invention You just made then why do you have a patent on it?
Speaker 1: You're just hurting everyone else by restricting everyone's freedom to invent and sell and make businesses around Whatever that thing crazy thing you patent it is.
Speaker 1: we shouldn't have to beg you to give it up to one small guy Who now can do whatever that thing is without competition.
Speaker 0: well a lot of companies?
Speaker 0: Just keep patents around as kind of a defensive tactic.
Speaker 0: so if someone sues them for any sort of patent thing They can usually turn around and counter sue the other person for 10 or 15 other patent things.
Speaker 1: yep There's a quote from an IBM guy.
Speaker 1: of course cuz IBM is the king of patents.
Speaker 0: God I mean, I'm still up for a patent at IBM.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're ready for this.
Speaker 1: IBM Corp has more than 40,000 patents according to company spokesman Steve Malkovich.
Speaker 0: they pushed us to get patents every day.
Speaker 0: It was like get a patent yet got anything you can patent.
Speaker 0: fill out this form will patent it.
Speaker 1: yep Rather than give away their idle patents the company keeps them But allows some groups to use this technology for free.
Speaker 1: they believe the strategy helps generate new innovation and growth.
Speaker 1: You don't help generate new innovation and growth.
Speaker 1: stop fucking patenting everything so people could just do things well because that's a lie.
Speaker 0: Obviously the real answer is we have weapons.
Speaker 0: it basically patents in the modern corporate world are not actually patents in the old way.
Speaker 0: They were effectively economic nuclear weapons Mmm.
Speaker 0: Where if anyone tries to nuke you you've got so many that you just destroy them in turn.
Speaker 0: yep And if two big companies get into a tiff I can imagine all Sorts of hilarity, and I look forward to that day with great enthusiasm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh apparently Suzanne Schell is a chicken farmer according to the internet.
Speaker 1: uh-huh yeah This whole patent situation just gets worse and worse all the time, and it's really not good.
Speaker 1: I mean it says in the Constitution Patents are there to promote like people inventing and researching and trying new things.
Speaker 1: now Patents are just hurting people from trying to invent new part of it's the patent.
Speaker 0: They had a certain term how long they would last and now technology moves so fast by the time a patent falls out of its Term.
Speaker 0: it's been obsolete for seven years already.
Speaker 1: Not only that but it's way too easy to get them and the patent office is not so good at choosing Which ones to approve and which ones not to approve?
Speaker 1: You know they pretty much let through all kinds of bullshit and don't let through good stuff.
Speaker 0: things of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you all remember at least know about the 1984 ad from Apple computers back in the day.
Speaker 0: It's probably one of the most famous video advertisements ever.
Speaker 1: yep it played during the 84 Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: It was for Macintoshes, and it's.
Speaker 0: I really like the the aesthetic of it because I generally dislike 1984 like societies I'm really not a fan of the ad like other people are like.
Speaker 1: I recognize significance, but I don't enjoy watching it.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's fun or entertaining at all.
Speaker 0: I like the ad except for the fact that it's advertising Apple and instead I don't care about what it's selling, but I ignore that in ads anyway.
Speaker 0: I just like the.
Speaker 0: I like the visuals.
Speaker 1: Oh, it has nothing to do with what it's selling.
Speaker 1: even if the ad was for like you know Scott's like you know I I Still wouldn't like it.
Speaker 0: I just don't like it all right You're entitled to your incorrect opinion.
Speaker 1: Talking about.
Speaker 0: well someone did something funny on the internet and actually NPR It's all politics did talk about this quite a bit.
Speaker 0: Someone and no one knows who as yet unless this has changed in the last few hours Took that old ad and mashed it up with Hillary Clinton and Barack Obama, and they also added an iPod to it.
Speaker 0: It's very high quality, and it's basically an anti Hillary pro-obama ad.
Speaker 0: that's pretty well done.
Speaker 0: And the thing is that alone wouldn't be news.
Speaker 0: But the fact that it got all over the internet And then it got on CNN and it's not all the major new media and everyone's talking about it and NPR I saw politics went into great detail about how they think this is the beginning of a new era in political advertising with these kind of underground Unaffiliated.
Speaker 0: no one paid for them even if they violate laws or if they're really really negative or whatever Internet advertising.
Speaker 0: if someone really likes a candidate It's their right freedom of speech to say whatever they want as long as they don't violate any laws.
Speaker 0: So as a result we're gonna see a lot of advertising for candidates That doesn't hit the mainstream media And they're speculating that this presidential election in 2008 is gonna be decided by the internet as opposed to by the traditional media.
Speaker 1: Eventually it's gonna be decided by the internet.
Speaker 1: it Thing now a large portion of it will be and perhaps years.
Speaker 1: well the whole thing will be.
Speaker 0: we've seen the trend.
Speaker 0: I mean Howard Dean's Popularity existed solely because of his grassroots hippie internet action.
Speaker 1: that is correct and Obama is more internet action going on than anyone Ever seen got.
Speaker 0: Obama does a podcast and he has a pretty good radio voice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, thing is I don't know how it's like.
Speaker 1: there's limits on how much you can spend in advertising and such.
Speaker 1: So I think a lot of people are gonna do internet advertising and pretend that they didn't pay for it.
Speaker 0: when they do obviously Especially I mean say you want to attack a candidate You don't want to be known as that candidate who attacks that other candidate.
Speaker 0: So what if some guy who happens to be a friend of some other guy who happens to be a gopher on your campaign?
Speaker 0: Makes a flash video of two Republican senator.
Speaker 0: Hopeful presidential candidates fellating each other And talking about how bad they are on whatever issue you're talking about.
Speaker 0: There's nothing illegal about that because you can't prove the connection or that any money was traded.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's real Not looking too well for the campaign finance reforms.
Speaker 0: I see I'm not so worried about campaign finance reform anymore.
Speaker 0: I'm more worried about a lot of other issues.
Speaker 1: See is the thing though in the short term it's gonna be sucky because now these people who have a lot of money are gonna Be even more likely to win and the other people can be less likely to lose because these people will afford To put like big-ass fancy ads that are you know gonna be all over the internet and get a lot of them.
Speaker 1: But at the same in a long run.
Speaker 1: now if the internet is the decider I can make shit on the internet.
Speaker 1: And now like I'd say maybe in like 12 to 16 years from now The small-time candidate can put just as many videos about him on the internet and he'll get known Without having to spend millions on TV ads.
Speaker 0: yep You can also get away with a lot more on the internet for now Because the culture on the internet as opposed to the meatspace culture that isn't on the internet Seems to be in a general way a lot more liberal not necessarily leftist But liberal in a general Libertine sense
Speaker 1: and the word the way it was meant in say 1910.
Speaker 0: so as a result you can say things on the internet to Appeal to certain kinds of voters that the voters who this wouldn't appeal to would never know.
Speaker 0: you've said it.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can say things in places where you know other people won't see.
Speaker 1: like if you say something on TV Pretty much everyone who votes is gonna see it, but if you go to say except us yes.
Speaker 1: But if you go to like the geek nights forums And you say I love computers, and then you go over to
Speaker 0: the neo-luddite forums
Speaker 1: the neo-luddite forums And you say man computers are terrible, and then you go to the pedophile forums And you say I'll let you guys slide.
Speaker 1: then you go to the chat rooms where all the police are trying to catch pedophiles And you say I'm gonna catch all these bastards no one will ever know.
Speaker 1: you said all these things.
Speaker 0: For now yeah, but it's still.
Speaker 0: it's a useful tool.
Speaker 1: yep alright.
Speaker 1: So if you haven't been paying attention The latest hotness in the web 2.0 internets is this thing called Twitter.
Speaker 0: I started listening to twit.
Speaker 0: for some reason I don't know if I like it it.
Speaker 0: just if I turn it on I end up listening to it.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's that's pretty much it kind of kind of mesmerizing their voices cuz they have more expensive microphones than us.
Speaker 1: yeah I listen to two twits today.
Speaker 1: anyway Twitter is the thing.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna tell you what it is in a second.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't know what it was But it has nothing to do with to it other than the twit.
Speaker 0: people use it and talk about it more than they show.
Speaker 1: they Talked about it recently in one episode.
Speaker 1: a lot anyway.
Speaker 1: It is made by the people who made Odeo and the people who made Odeo printers giving up Odeo and doing Twitter now.
Speaker 0: Oh, huh, so they made Odeo which didn't work and was basically useless and now they're making Twitter.
Speaker 1: Well Twitter's sort of made and done.
Speaker 1: There's really not much more.
Speaker 1: It can do so.
Speaker 0: then what are they doing?
Speaker 1: Okay, Twitter is you ready for this.
Speaker 1: This is really dumb.
Speaker 1: all you do is You can say a hundred and forty characters worth of text.
Speaker 1: that answers the question What are you doing?
Speaker 1: And you have a picture and you have a name and it also has a GPS coordinate and It says you know there are different ways to send.
Speaker 1: you can send it by SMS You can send it by instant message, or you can send it on the website.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: So let's say here's an example of Twitter usage already.
Speaker 1: I wake up in the morning I pick up my cell phone, and I say I just woke up smiley, and I push the button.
Speaker 1: now on my Twitter It says the time.
Speaker 1: it says Beacon, New York And it says Scott you know it has exactly what I typed in.
Speaker 1: I woke up hooray via SMS.
Speaker 1: then I take a shower.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna take a shower.
Speaker 1: so I go over to my computer And I log into the website, and I say I'm gonna take a shower now, and it says on Twitter I'm gonna take a shower now.
Speaker 1: Huh, and now anyone who befriends me on Twitter can see all these things that I'm saying about what I'm doing and Anyone that I befriend I can see what they're doing and I can have those things sent to me by SMS or instant message Or I can look at them on the web and some things are public.
Speaker 1: you can just go to Twitter Twi tter calm and look at what things people are saying and doing in different places around the world and how they're saying those Things via SMS or I am or whatever.
Speaker 0: so it's basically all the bad parts of myspace and LiveJournal without any of the good.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like not in a way message But like a here message.
Speaker 1: you have a constant here message that you just keep Changing only it just they keep adding on top.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna qualify everything I'm about to say about this by stating that the idea of having a Constantly updating feed of what you were doing that people you care about can look at or that you can reference later to see what You did at certain times is Interesting and I can see uses for that.
Speaker 0: this implementation I would say borders on the silly, but that's like saying that Alaska borders on the chili.
Speaker 1: well Here's the thing is that that alone.
Speaker 1: You know I could go for that.
Speaker 1: You know if it's just what are you doing?
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: people have pretty much taken this now And it's just a giant worldwide IRC.
Speaker 1: people are friending thousands of people and being befriended by thousands of people and I see messages on here like here's one At Vincent Ferrari, what if the at is at you?
Speaker 1: question mark Smiley somebody is?
Speaker 1: Talking to someone else by posting a worldwide message.
Speaker 1: That's supposed to be what are you doing right now, but there's Specifically trying to say hey Vincent Ferrari look at this message.
Speaker 0: It's for you see now that at least is a little interesting.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a global Stupid inane chat room.
Speaker 1: It's just a worldwide IRC that you can only say a hundred and forty characters at once.
Speaker 1: That's that's the opposite.
Speaker 1: It would be cool if it was what it said.
Speaker 1: it was gonna be but now it's just a worldwide IRS each.
Speaker 0: Oh now while that is silly I I posit Scott who would have So little of a life that they would watch this?
Speaker 0: the twits who would have So little going on that they have the time to constantly type 140 or so characters of what they're doing into a website?
Speaker 1: Who would have so little time in life that they can sit here watching this sending chat Messages to the whole world and chatting with the whole world?
Speaker 0: You know that's a little bit better than the original usage in my opinion.
Speaker 1: I think that's worse.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just you make an IRC channel and everyone join?
Speaker 1: it's better.
Speaker 0: Who is the bigger loser though?
Speaker 0: the person who tells the world?
Speaker 0: Constantly when they masturbate and when they take showers or the guy who watches that and feels enriched by it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: neither one is good, but anyway my thing of the day is not Twitter itself.
Speaker 1: I just wanted to let you know what Twitter was because it's something you should probably make fun of.
Speaker 1: make fun of because it's the Latest internet hotness.
Speaker 0: I have a solution to Twitter, but I'll get to that in a bit right.
Speaker 1: well The latest my thing of the day is Twitter vision.
Speaker 1: you can go to Twitter vision calm TWI TTR vision calm or Twitter Map calm slash Twitter vision.
Speaker 1: it's Twitter plus Google Maps.
Speaker 1: basically you sit here looking at Google Maps and Whenever someone twitters it puts a little dot on the map and you see what they said and then it loads up some more Twitter's and you get to sit here, and you'll see pretty much every Twitter around the world where it is what they said Constantly.
Speaker 0: so I've got like three or four ideas for Twitter pranks already.
Speaker 1: Apparently a lot of people using Twitter for marketing like it seems like in the UK somewhere There's a Twitter guy named fresh podcast.
Speaker 1: He just keeps linking to podcasts.
Speaker 1: Wow and I'm like who the hell is sitting here.
Speaker 1: Wait watching what the this guy has to say to get a new podcast.
Speaker 1: go to take podcasts and search for something.
Speaker 1: what the hell?
Speaker 0: No number one.
Speaker 0: perhaps someone sets their GPS stuff to be in the middle of North Korea, and then they post something like OMG I got internet access.
Speaker 0: help me And wait for the Internet to react to that - - - -.
Speaker 0: what if someone posts OMG?
Speaker 0: I saw a UFO and then silence or a bunch of people with the same GPS all post these UFO sightings all at once like in Montana and then silence from all of them forever more.
Speaker 0: so the conspiracy nuts have a field day Now.
Speaker 0: idea number three.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that military Engagements could end this right quick.
Speaker 0: suppose We get all the rational people on the internet together and deploy the mighty cock boat army on Twitter.
Speaker 1: Just start putting cock boats in there.
Speaker 1: cock boat 140 character long cock boats.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about entire cock boat destroyer groups.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: now of course you would have to set your GPS coordinates.
Speaker 0: So they were in fact in the Atlantic and Pacific Ocean.
Speaker 0: Now if we coordinate this properly this could be utterly hilarious.
Speaker 0: if the internet is with me We will put something together.
Speaker 1: I think I might use the Twitter for just one day and then not use it again.
Speaker 0: And then what review it?
Speaker 1: no, but that way at least you know.
Speaker 1: It's like it is an important part of internet history because this is probably gonna be something that you know comes And then dies sort of like Odeo did.
Speaker 0: and then 20 years later people say do you remember Twitter?
Speaker 1: And I'm like haha use that for one day instead of haha.
Speaker 1: I remember some people use that but I don't really remember what it was like.
Speaker 0: we've already got a lot of things like that Though I mean Kingdom of Loathing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like how it's worth it to make a myspace account Even if you don't really use it.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like how it's worth it to poke around live journal once just to know what it is.
Speaker 1: You know be on Facebook once and that's that's so I'll be on Twitter once.
Speaker 0: that ought to be interesting.
Speaker 1: It might be.
Speaker 0: you should keep a log of how many times you can't resist yours to just write an ASCII penis.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 0: I will bet that that is going to be within the first two things you post on Twitter.
Speaker 1: No, I imagine.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna basically type in what I'm doing for 24 hours whenever I do something new.
Speaker 1: Wow That's what it's supposed to be.
Speaker 1: So that's the way I'm gonna use it.
Speaker 0: I just I don't see this being the best use of your time.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm gonna try.
Speaker 1: I think what I can do is I'll try to do with SMS or I am so it doesn't take very long.
Speaker 1: So tonight plus think about it.
Speaker 1: I mean at one point.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be like I'm at work And like four hours later, I'm eating lunch.
Speaker 1: I'm done eating lunch.
Speaker 1: I'm back to work then four hours later I'm going home.
Speaker 0: So tonight lately our how computers work series has been very popular among the listeners especially all the networking stuff.
Speaker 0: and Also, we're very lazy and we haven't felt like talking about any technology topics lately.
Speaker 1: Yeah technology topics I mean while we know a lot about technology There's only so much you can say about a lot of things and sometimes we have to do some research if it's not something We've used in regular daily life.
Speaker 0: also we just generally are lazy and the fact that you guys seem to want these less technical how computers works as opposed to the.
Speaker 0: Here are the frequency bands of 802 11 V channels kind of podcast.
Speaker 1: Here's how Manchester encoding works.
Speaker 1: All right Today we're gonna talk about something that you probably aren't familiar with But you should be.
Speaker 1: we're going to talk about version control systems.
Speaker 0: Now this is a topic that generally a lot of people think only applies to coders people who write well people even know What version control systems are in the first place?
Speaker 0: but this is the kind of thing that you might not even realize.
Speaker 0: you have this problem or you might have the problem and Not realize that there's a solution or you might not even Care.
Speaker 0: yeah, you might not.
Speaker 0: but in general This is something that many people could be using to great effect to make their productivity and their lives Generally better and easier to manage.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It is also something that is on slashdot.
Speaker 0: recently people were talking about.
Speaker 0: I think that our Congress the United States Congress should be by law required to use something like this.
Speaker 0: I agree, but anyway version control is actually something very very simple.
Speaker 1: Yes, basically you have some sort of information that one or more people is working on.
Speaker 1: However, this you know, let's pretend it's a document.
Speaker 1: It's it's a word document.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're writing a guide on how to cook a goat.
Speaker 1: All right a guide on how to cook a goat, right?
Speaker 1: so I write up the guide on how to cook a goat and Now rim wants to make some changes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, obviously you're thinking about wiki's already.
Speaker 1: you people I know you are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but you know Rim make some changes to it and then I make some changes and then Someone else make some changes and we keep updating and working on this guide to how to make a goat together or maybe just alone.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the thing is we're doing this by a traditional methods, you know, download the file edit it put it back up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And now if someone rim does that what if you're accidentally erased one of my paragraphs or he changed something?
Speaker 1: I did and I forget just how I said it.
Speaker 1: Well the old versions unless we you know We could just keep a whole bunch of files and every time there's a new version of the document We make a whole new file and we've got all these files just lined up.
Speaker 1: And now if I want to see what the difference is between version the newest version and the oldest version It's like a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: And if I want to replace a part of the new version with a part of two versions ago It's also a pain in the ass and it basically is a pain in the ass and a lot of manual labor and it sucks.
Speaker 0: and also it doesn't deal with a very Maybe not obvious problem, but a problem that comes up quite a bit whenever multiple people are working on any sort of project Especially in computers.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a race condition where the time that you start to edit something can matter.
Speaker 0: Well, let's say I start I download it and start editing I start adding a paragraph and then
Speaker 1: I downloaded it and I start deleting something
Speaker 0: and then I put my version up which has my New paragraph and then Scott puts his version up that doesn't have my new paragraph But it has the things he took out and now
Speaker 1: rims.
Speaker 1: work is gone.
Speaker 0: My work is gone.
Speaker 0: Scott's work hasn't taken mine into account.
Speaker 0: Maybe a third person was trying to edit but Scott didn't download the file.
Speaker 0: He was working on the one on the server.
Speaker 0: So the guy couldn't even write it back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now we've lost information.
Speaker 0: Everything's chaotic.
Speaker 0: Everything's done.
Speaker 1: So the solution is to have a version control system.
Speaker 1: You know how when you get software and software says it's version 1.0 or 1.1 or 2.3 or whatever Those numbers come from version control systems.
Speaker 1: people didn't.
Speaker 1: just you know make.
Speaker 1: I mean everyone has a different system for how the numbers work.
Speaker 1: like the Linux kernel does the numbers by.
Speaker 1: you know 2.6 is the series and then like dot 25 is the 25th kernel and the 2.6 series and Ubuntu does it by the date?
Speaker 1: So edgy is 610 because it came out on June, you know 10. or it was like No, it came out in October of 06. that's why it's a lot of programs.
Speaker 0: just do the major-minor.
Speaker 0: So version 1.0 is the first major release.
Speaker 0: 1.1 is a minor update.
Speaker 0: 1.2 is another minor update.
Speaker 0: 2.0 is the second major release.
Speaker 0: Yeah sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Everyone uses a different system of numbering but those numberings come from the version control systems.
Speaker 0: Now there are a lot of ways to do this and we're really not going to go into technical depth But you might have heard of terms like CVS or subversion or RCS.
Speaker 1: Those are pretty much the big three.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's a lot of people do it manually partly because they might not know that there are content management systems out there That'll do this for them and version things for them or two.
Speaker 0: They might just not Understand that this is a good thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're crazy Luddites and maybe they don't like CVS.
Speaker 1: Well, some people use like the stuff that's built into Microsoft Office and Word But that stuff really sucks compared to what CVS and others already do.
Speaker 1: Basically how these version control systems work is not too complicated.
Speaker 1: you have some sort of Repository where all of the stuff that is being all the stuff everyone is working on sits there.
Speaker 0: now This could be a database.
Speaker 0: It could be a file.
Speaker 0: It could be a directory with just all the version files in it.
Speaker 1: It could be on your computer.
Speaker 1: It could be on a server somewhere else.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: It could be a safe deposit box in a bank.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's a place where all the information Sits about everything that has ever been done to the things you are working on from the oldest version to the newest version and It just sits there.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: the way it works is when you want to work on something you check it out.
Speaker 1: So let's say there's a project me and rim are working on say the latest episode of geek night.
Speaker 1: It's in there.
Speaker 1: It's in the repository.
Speaker 1: the work that's already been done is in there.
Speaker 1: I'm just sitting at a computer.
Speaker 1: That's brand new.
Speaker 1: So I connect to the repository.
Speaker 1: However, you connect to it network hard drive, whatever.
Speaker 1: I check it out.
Speaker 1: now I've got the version of the work the newest one that was in the repository because I checked out the newest one.
Speaker 1: I could have checked out an older one.
Speaker 1: I start working on it.
Speaker 1: I edit the copy that I checked out.
Speaker 1: now rim.
Speaker 1: he checks out and he's working on it.
Speaker 1: now There are two other things I can do.
Speaker 1: well major.
Speaker 1: there are lots of things you can do But the major ones are update.
Speaker 1: update says alright, I've got what I've the work I've done it right in front of me.
Speaker 1: go look on that repository And if there's anything newer there that was changed since I checked out Bring that down to me so I can incorporate it into what I've just done.
Speaker 1: That's update.
Speaker 1: The other thing you can do is commit which says take what I've got right here and put it in as the next version.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: rim starts working on it.
Speaker 1: I start working on it.
Speaker 1: rim updates.
Speaker 1: He sees that nothing happened as so he commits.
Speaker 1: now rims version is in there.
Speaker 1: It's in the repository But I'm working on the previous version to what rim is done.
Speaker 1: before I commit my work right on top of rims work I update now rims changes that he just did come down and I look at what I've done and I look at what rims done.
Speaker 1: I mix them together, which is real easy And then I commit and now our work isn't lost.
Speaker 1: it's in there and everything's cool plus I can go in and I can say all kinds of cool stuff like show me the difference between this version and the last version.
Speaker 1: Give me the older version because the new version sucks all kinds of cool stuff like that.
Speaker 1: It's nice and easy and everything's awesome.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: You can see how this is a great advantage.
Speaker 0: I mean without version control you're eventually gonna have a mess and you're very much limited in the number of people who can be working on one project or the Number of people who can collaborate simultaneously.
Speaker 1: You're also much more likely to lose lots of data and have a pain in the ass time, especially if you're working on software.
Speaker 0: Yep, now to with simple primitive version control the most primitive forms Generally just involved.
Speaker 0: if I check a file out like before any of this or I just I'm using a file and someone else tries To edit it.
Speaker 0: It says hey someone else is editing this.
Speaker 0: don't fuck with it.
Speaker 0: That's what RCS does Yep, and while that's not great at least you don't lose data anymore.
Speaker 0: It slows down productivity because now if Scott's working I can't work and if I'm working Scott can't work But at the same time at least you're not gonna lose anything
Speaker 1: and at least you can still keep track of different versions of something
Speaker 0: Yep, which is very important because then you can track back who added what when you can figure out when problems appeared.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone likes an old version and you want to incorporate that into a newer version.
Speaker 0: Maybe you want to split off and fork but we'll talk about that in a second Yep, and really in general you can just get a lot more done a lot more quickly.
Speaker 0: people can collaborate Simultaneously on single projects.
Speaker 1: you think about what it'd be like if say you were trying to write a book a big instruction manual For something and there were like a hundred people on the team.
Speaker 1: It's basically impossible without a version control system of some sort.
Speaker 1: It's as essential as the hammer.
Speaker 1: without this tool You couldn't hammer a goddamn nail But because of the tool we can do amazing things.
Speaker 0: now to look at a very practical semi non technical application.
Speaker 0: I said a bit before about the Congress of the United States.
Speaker 0: for those of you who aren't American Which is a good number of you the way laws work in America basically boils down to the fact that very few of our elected representatives actually read any laws that they vote for or against Partly because there's so many laws Partly because the laws are long and all sorts of problems.
Speaker 0: as a result a lot of AIDS end up doing the work.
Speaker 0: It's not that difficult for someone to just change a law and not tell anyone and then no one will notice and they'll vote on It.
Speaker 0: it happened recently pretty spectacularly actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also lots of laws like a law will be like the funding of the something-something act of 2007.
Speaker 1: But when you look at the law like the beginning part of it might have something to do with funding the something-something.
Speaker 1: But then after that it says oh and by the way give money to rim.
Speaker 1: Oh and by the way, you can't Build a school in Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Oh and by the way You can build a bridge in Alaska all in favor of the Springfield slash pervert act I.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so how would you deal with this?
Speaker 0: Well Congress has tried to deal with it in various ineffective ways Even though something like CVS or any sort of version control system would all but eliminate this problem.
Speaker 1: Plus the other problem we have in the US government is we got these two branches of the legislative branch, you know two legislative branches
Speaker 0: yeah, and
Speaker 1: like the house will have one version of a bill and then the Senate will have a different version of the same bill and They vote on them separately and then they go to this conference committee Which mixes them together.
Speaker 1: it like if they pass both houses the two different laws Two different bills in both houses then they go to a conference committee and they mix them together to get the same one And then they vote on them again.
Speaker 0: It's really kind of silly and I just did.
Speaker 0: this is one of the things that bothers me in general about the world.
Speaker 0: Is that there are solutions?
Speaker 0: relatively simple solutions to Long-standing problems with society culture technology everything and for various reasons the people who have Much to gain or actually in this case possibly much to lose A lot of their you know shortcuts and tricks and shenanigans.
Speaker 0: These solutions aren't adopted aren't even looked at.
Speaker 0: the people who have the problems don't even understand that these solutions exist.
Speaker 1: People don't understand technology.
Speaker 1: So any technology solutions, they're not even gonna.
Speaker 1: it's like there are people who like it's sort of like regular expressions like people will be editing some file and they'll need to like Find and replace something or they need to do something clever and you know what they'll do.
Speaker 1: they'll copy and they'll go paste paste paste paste paste paste paste and then they'll edit every single line by hand and that they Won't even realize they'll be like that's just the way it's done.
Speaker 0: They won't even think if only there was a way that this could be done easier If there is a way if only there was some sort of machine that could do large numbers of menial calculations over and over again as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: if Yeah, it's like people don't even know they have the problems to even think if like if there was a solution now There is there are solutions to problems that you have that you don't know you have.
Speaker 0: obviously the Congress example is Somewhat more complicated than we might have made it out to be but the fact remains that well one We've thought about this a lot and I could go into great detail as to the more specific ideas have I have regarding that.
Speaker 0: Yep, but in general, I think the idea stands that there are problems that can be solved trivially by technology That are not solved by technology for no good reason.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Alright, you want to talk about some specific version control type topic?
Speaker 0: Alright, well very I'd like to talk about forking because a lot Of people don't seem to know what forking means and it's kind of related or branching.
Speaker 1: Ah Hmm.
Speaker 0: Alright, so let's say I'm working on my how to cook a goat thing and Scott's working on it with me.
Speaker 0: And we get to version 2.1 and everything's going fine and suddenly Scott says, you know what?
Speaker 0: We're going about this all wrong.
Speaker 0: you're supposed to cook goats on grills and we've been talking about cooking them in ovens and I'm done with this business and I'm Gonna write my own guide and I'm gonna take all the data we got and do my own thing.
Speaker 0: and I say, you know What screw your idea?
Speaker 0: I'm sticking with what we've got now.
Speaker 0: We've got a problem.
Speaker 0: We've got one document and two different philosophies as to where to go forward from here.
Speaker 1: No We could just keep making versions where we go back and forth and back and forth and back before.
Speaker 1: that is silly.
Speaker 1: That is very silly.
Speaker 0: that happens on Wikipedia often.
Speaker 0: luckily they're safeguards to stop that.
Speaker 1: luckily.
Speaker 0: Yes, luckily he died.
Speaker 1: Forks or when you break off and you split it two ways or possibly more than two ways.
Speaker 1: So now we've got the oven methodology fork and the grill methodology fork.
Speaker 1: So I've started a whole new chain of updates going that way and rim has started a whole new chain of updates going that way.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like evolution where two species break off from a common ancestor species.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much exactly what it's like.
Speaker 1: Yeah and you'll often see people talking about forks when in open source projects like when x free 86. right They x free 86 was the x server that people used on Unix and Linux systems and to make the GUI show up And it's still what they use.
Speaker 1: However, people used to use x free 86. now people use xorg.
Speaker 1: What happened was at a certain point the people who do x free 86?
Speaker 1: Made some stupid changes to their license and they did some stuff that no one liked And people are very upset with them.
Speaker 1: So they went to the previous version of x free 86 before the bullshit happened and they forked it and do a new thing Called x org which now you pretty much should be using.
Speaker 1: you don't really want to be using No one's using x free 86 anymore, except people with old computers.
Speaker 1: They can't be updated.
Speaker 1: but X free 86 continued along its merry stupid way.
Speaker 1: At least I'm.
Speaker 1: I don't know is it still continuing.
Speaker 0: I've never looked.
Speaker 1: I don't even know if anyone's still working on it.
Speaker 1: That's how much it died.
Speaker 1: But the fork of x free 86 x org is going along quite nicely and it is the very awesome.
Speaker 0: So now if you ever wondered what people like us mean when we say hey blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: He forked the Linux kernel.
Speaker 0: now That's that's it.
Speaker 0: That's all it is.
Speaker 0: you fork off into two separate paths going in usually separate directions or at least different directions.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now here's a funny one.
Speaker 1: There is a fork of CVS the concurrent very the.
Speaker 1: What's a CVS?
Speaker 1: it's like concurrent version system something like that.
Speaker 1: I don't actually remember current version control system.
Speaker 0: I'm not even sure It's one of those things that you use so often.
Speaker 0: You never really care what the accurate current versioning system.
Speaker 0: Maybe we have the internet at our disposal.
Speaker 1: I know but I closed my laptop.
Speaker 1: Ah, but anyway, there's a fork of CVS itself Which is quite ironic called subversion and the main difference there.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of differences and you know Basically, it's not like we just talked about where xorg was great and x free 86 sucked and everyone uses xorgs.
Speaker 1: Now people still use CVS and people use subversion because they're both good in their own way.
Speaker 1: That is different philosophies on versioning control concurrent versions system.
Speaker 1: I was close.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the difference between.
Speaker 1: the main difference between CVS and subversion is that CVS has every single file in a repository Is separate.
Speaker 1: so let's say I'm working on a book with rim and we put each chapter in a separate document and I edit one Chapter.
Speaker 1: that you then with the first version was point one and I edit one chapter.
Speaker 1: now that chapter is version point two And all the other chapters are still point one because they haven't been.
Speaker 1: they're still on their first version.
Speaker 1: That's how CVS works.
Speaker 1: so in CVS every single file is gonna have a current version and That's that's good for a lot of things.
Speaker 1: sometimes you want to have every different file have a different version.
Speaker 1: in Subversion you have what is called atomic commits.
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 1: Every single file goes with the same version.
Speaker 1: So let's say we're working on like we put the initial version of the book in there.
Speaker 1: Then I edit one chapter and I commit.
Speaker 1: now Even if those other chapters aren't updated they got it.
Speaker 1: the next version of the chapter is exactly that.
Speaker 1: it makes a new version.
Speaker 1: So point two there's a new version of the other chapters.
Speaker 1: They're just the same as the older version.
Speaker 1: This is good for software for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: For example, I'm working on a software project, right?
Speaker 1: I make some changes to one source file and another source file.
Speaker 1: If you don't have the right versions of every source file the program probably won't work, you know.
Speaker 1: So, how do you know if you need like version 1.5 of this and 1.7 of that and 2.3 of that in order to make?
Speaker 1: It work.
Speaker 0: It's tough.
Speaker 0: Yep Now you can't control the version numbers of external programs or external libraries or external sources.
Speaker 0: You happen to be using But at the same time you can at least control all the things that you were working on To be the same version to make it at least a little bit easier.
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: so with subversion if someone's doing software with subversion and you only commit when the software works You know that whatever version you check out of subversion You're gonna get something that probably works and not you know This version of that file and this version of that file in order to go to the previous version of the software.
Speaker 1: so for certain types of projects the atomic commits of subversion are pretty awesome and For certain other kinds of things the non atomic commits of CVS are awesome.
Speaker 1: So you gotta you know choose which one you like sometimes depending on your philosophy Maybe choose the one that's better for whatever project you're working on Etc.
Speaker 1: now, here's something really cool.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it's called a tinderbox, but I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 1: And basically what a tinderbox does?
Speaker 1: it's a specific software tool.
Speaker 1: You have a version control system.
Speaker 1: the tinderbox will look at the latest version of the software in the version control system and Make sure that it works.
Speaker 1: sort of it'll run some tests on it.
Speaker 1: You know, does it compile?
Speaker 1: does it run without core dumping whatever?
Speaker 1: and if it you know Breaks the software by committing say something with a syntax error the tinderbox will go.
Speaker 1: Oh fucks someone messed up.
Speaker 1: So now you know that.
Speaker 1: oh, you know who messed up because you can see who committed the change.
Speaker 0: You can see what version.
Speaker 1: you can go back to the previous version that you know that works.
Speaker 1: You can go and look at the difference between the broken version and the previous version You know is working and see where they screwed up and then you can get the tinderbox to turn green again And then people can get back to work because they know they won't screw it up.
Speaker 1: Huh, and this helps you develop software not only with all the advantages of version control But keeping a working product the whole time and never, you know, totally screwing up all the code.
Speaker 1: now You don't know where the problem is.
Speaker 1: That's making it not go.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: just in general the best thing about something like CVS is that from my standpoint as a guy who would maintain the server but Has nothing to do with the code because I the code I write is dubious at best and usually relegated to the script category.
Speaker 0: I'm an IT guy, but I've managed CVS servers.
Speaker 0: It's so trivial to take care of a CVS server.
Speaker 1: You just kind of turn it on and let people set the permission.
Speaker 0: We got to turn it on until you get a back up the data.
Speaker 1: Oh backing up the so important Yeah, but that's it.
Speaker 0: That's all you got to do.
Speaker 0: I mean if it breaks It's not gonna break.
Speaker 0: the server is gonna break before CVS is gonna break.
Speaker 0: CVS is pretty tried and true.
Speaker 1: It's real old and even subversion which is much newer than CVS is tried and true and you can totally trust it for whatever You're doing.
Speaker 1: there are other ones like git which is the one I think that I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: Linus Torvalds developed it when he stopped Using bitkeeper because bitkeeper did something weird.
Speaker 1: There's a whole story about that.
Speaker 1: You can go research it on the internet if you want.
Speaker 0: You probably don't care.
Speaker 0: In fact, I'll bet that we've already gone into more technical depth than any of you care about.
Speaker 1: There's not really much more to say that isn't technically deep.
Speaker 1: Well here let's think of some interesting uses for version control systems that are out of the ordinary.
Speaker 1: I got one.
Speaker 1: the one that I say is if you've got say my documents folder Put the whole thing in a version control system.
Speaker 1: Then you got.
Speaker 1: you got a backup because it's you know Hopefully on some other server somewhere and if you ever change any of your documents Well now you can go back and get old versions.
Speaker 1: You can see what your my documents folder was like in 2003 or 2002.
Speaker 1: You can see what your my documents folder is like today.
Speaker 1: if you have Multiple computers and your version control system is on a server You can be at home.
Speaker 1: check out your my documents folder make some changes check them in Go to work check out your new my documents folder.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like your stuff is stored on a server But you can kind of mix and match the versions.
Speaker 1: work on something at home work at something at work.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 0: you could do that almost as easily with roaming profiles or remote home directory or all that sort of a lot.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of scary people who put their whole home directories in CVS.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't recommend that I'll put my home directory on a separate hard drive mounted, but I put my Configuration files for my computer in CVS.
Speaker 1: that way you go to a new computer.
Speaker 1: you want to set it up Just like the one at home.
Speaker 1: Check out all the configuration files.
Speaker 1: You're done.
Speaker 0: Yep I actually did that for a DNS DHCP server combo when I was an RIT working in labs because it was just BAM And I had it there exactly the way I wanted it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then say one day one of your settings is bothering you so you change it on one machine Yep, then it's changed on all your other machines because you check out the same settings from the same repository.
Speaker 0: Also, I'd recommend anyone learning about computers do this sort of thing because even if you don't need the version control It's something you should know about and unlike a lot of other things that you should know about on the internet and with computers It's really easy to learn how to use CVS.
Speaker 0: Like I'm not kidding.
Speaker 1: There's basically three commands.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of advanced commands like the command to fork is a little complicated But the basic commands of check in check out update a real simple.
Speaker 0: Yes I mean, we're not just saying this as two guys who are technologically proficient seriously Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: The one last thing you're gonna want to learn CVS or subversion for is that there's a lot of open source software out there that you know.
Speaker 1: You want to get the newest newest newest version.
Speaker 1: and of course the open source people, you know They have people around the world working on one piece of software.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: They keep all that source code in a CVS or subversion.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean, let's say you're using redhead or whatever.
Speaker 0: You have to wait for the people doing the project or their friends to make your RPM file Which is probably a few little tiny versions behind.
Speaker 0: maybe it comes out late.
Speaker 0: Maybe you need the newest version now.
Speaker 1: Maybe you want to try out, you know the version that people are working on.
Speaker 1: Maybe you want to work on the newest version of an open source project.
Speaker 0: You're probably gonna have to go into CVS to get it because they're not gonna make binaries of every little release just for you
Speaker 1: yes, and you can also a lot of times get a much newer version of Software then is easily available By going through the slight trouble of checking out the absolute up-to-the-minute newest version of the source code from CVS and then compiling it Yourself,
Speaker 0: I mean even gen 2 which generally has very up-to-date sources in its update tree.
Speaker 0: There are times when there will be stuff you want that for whatever reason isn't in there.
Speaker 0: Even then granted many of you aren't even gonna ever use gen 2 so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: But CVS is usually the way to get the bleeding is bleeding ist edge of any given software Because people are working on it.
Speaker 1: Like if a guy was working on something five minutes ago, and he submits his updates You can grab those and take advantage of those new feature.
Speaker 1: He just coded five minutes ago.
Speaker 0: this is especially great when you've got new hardware or new something and Support for that new something is in the newest newest newest alpha alpha alpha stage of some program that you need.
Speaker 1: or say if You have a piece of software that you rely heavily on But it's still in super development or there's a lot of people working on it But it's not quite there yet like a lot of people will check out the newest versions of Firefox from CVS's or get the nightly builds and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: just to get you know The Firefox 3 features before Firefox 3 comes out even though it's sort of unstable and still being worked on you can get it It's there.
Speaker 0: so I suppose that's that even though it's not the night for it.
Speaker 0: I would like to point out that we have contests running both Wednesday night and Thursday night and the deadlines are Wednesday and Thursday.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is the final week.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna remind everyone.
Speaker 0: I think I'll extend the deadline one day because one person on one of the contests said they had a good entry and they emailed Me personally, so I might accept a few late.
Speaker 0: But we've gotten some pretty good entries on both.
Speaker 0: So I'm not too worried here.
Speaker 1: And if you want to enter those you're gonna have to listen on Wednesday or Thursday because we're not gonna tell you what they are right now.
Speaker 0: Oh knows This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.