Speaker 1: It's Tuesday March 20th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talked about two old PC games that are super awesome Xcom UFO defense and star control - Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So despite the fact that we own all of these games multiple times over never mind the fact that we have emulators We keep buying virtual console games about a virtual console game in a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, however, we've been playing Super Mario World and I'm happy that I remember as a kid there was that star world.
Speaker 0: that was crazy hard and you know when he got to the end of it it totally changed the game and Changed all the graphics and all the turtles started wearing Mario heads and it was kind of weird.
Speaker 0: And I remember as a kid it being this impossible dream.
Speaker 0: to defeat that it took me days and days and days.
Speaker 1: Well, at least you could save.
Speaker 1: so it wasn't an impossible dream.
Speaker 1: It was just pretty hard, especially for a kid without any help.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember as a kid especially funky at the end just banging my head against that level over and over and over again Unable to beat it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I like that because Mario games too often You know while it might be a little tricky to figure out where the secrets are or where the alternate exit is.
Speaker 1: It's never really hard to beat a Mario level without dying not since Mario 3 Yeah, and parts of Mario World.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So when there's Mario levels in a 2d Mario side-scroller They just can't be beaten.
Speaker 1: That's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Cuz you know new Mario Brothers didn't have much of that.
Speaker 0: God I'd be new Mario Brothers in like two days.
Speaker 1: I beat it so fast.
Speaker 1: I think one of these days I go back and finish getting all the coins.
Speaker 1: I think I've been the big coins cuz.
Speaker 1: I think I got all the big coins and like the first three or four worlds Yeah, I got most of them and then I just stopped caring.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I also stopped caring.
Speaker 0: It's like I stopped carrying in the Mario to one where you can get the Yoshi eggs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was going after those for like a week and then one day I realized that you know I wonder what I get for this.
Speaker 0: I looked online and apparently it I think they change one graphic on the start screen.
Speaker 1: Wow Yeah, yeah, they really have to make some like a if they should make another new Mario Brothers.
Speaker 1: But they should make it actually get hard instead of just get interesting.
Speaker 0: Well the thing.
Speaker 0: my point here the thing that I found way interesting was that now as an adult I played those worlds again And it wasn't trivial to beat them, but I beat them in fairly short order without much difficulty.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I also didn't have much problem.
Speaker 1: The only reason I haven't gotten as far as rim because he's gonna be all like hey you suck is cuz I haven't.
Speaker 1: I really Haven't played it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll say like a week or two.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: you didn't know where some of the secrets were.
Speaker 1: That's cuz.
Speaker 1: I never owned the game.
Speaker 1: I only remember we're like the first.
Speaker 0: it's no excuse 75% of the secrets.
Speaker 0: I didn't own the game.
Speaker 1: Oh, I should know all the secrets in a game.
Speaker 1: I never owned it.
Speaker 1: Yes read a fact.
Speaker 0: for yes I mean if you don't know where currybo's shoe is even if you've never heard of mario 3 that's not cool.
Speaker 0: But I've realized I was thinking back after this when I beat this pretty handily that a lot of these games that as a kid I guess I wasn't good at video games when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm just a better gamer now.
Speaker 0: But when I played bionic commando, I'm I'm a god at that game compared to what I was as a kid.
Speaker 0: I remember it was so hard to get even to the second half of that game And I always died.
Speaker 0: I continued all the time and now I can just beat bionic commando without blinking.
Speaker 1: yet We still can't get anywhere in silver surfer.
Speaker 0: You know, I haven't tried.
Speaker 1: I tried it.
Speaker 1: You can't get anywhere.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should get some emulation going on that Mac and try.
Speaker 0: it's all you First one of us.
Speaker 0: we should have a bet first one of us to get to the third stage.
Speaker 1: If there isn't really a third stage to beat two stages, okay to beat two stages.
Speaker 0: Let's put like 500 bucks on the line.
Speaker 1: No, that's all right.
Speaker 1: I don't have 500 bucks right now And have money troubles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've realized that I really like Mario world and it's probably my second favorite Mario.
Speaker 0: But I'm also remembering that I think I like Mario 3 a little bit more just because Mario 3 is still harder than I can Deal with easily.
Speaker 1: I also well, I'm not sure if Mario 3 actually has more levels.
Speaker 1: It feels like it has more levels.
Speaker 0: The levels are a lot shorter though.
Speaker 1: They are but they're also Sort of more interesting and because you can't go back to them I've played a lot of them a lot less.
Speaker 1: So they're more fun to play.
Speaker 1: levels I've barely played especially curry boshu type levels.
Speaker 0: Well, there's just more kinds of things and more kinds of levels.
Speaker 0: and Mario world.
Speaker 0: The worlds aren't that different.
Speaker 0: I mean the mystic forest is a lot different from everything else.
Speaker 0: But other than that, there's not any really real sense of wonder.
Speaker 0: Nothing really changes between the worlds.
Speaker 0: other than that It gets hard.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: I just realized it feels like in Mario world.
Speaker 1: You can a lot of levels you can burn through.
Speaker 1: you just go and write
Speaker 0: Oh if you got a Mario and a blue Yoshi Yeah fly
Speaker 1: over the top and Mario 3 while you can fly over a lot of the levels actually force you to progress through each and every part one You know all slowly and carefully like yep
Speaker 0: Plus even if you want to fly over it without a p-wing you can't fly forever.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right Mario world You can fly forever without a p-wing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as long as you've got I don't know some level of motor control.
Speaker 1: Well, there's the level early on in the game where you can just practice to your heart's content.
Speaker 1: Yeah Alright, this is turning into like the episode from a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Alright, this isn't really news.
Speaker 0: I'm sure everyone's aware But I just have to mention the fact that splatter house has been released on the virtual console for the Wii woot.
Speaker 0: The game's not that good.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't recommend anyone actually buy.
Speaker 1: it depends how much it is.
Speaker 1: I would pay three dollars for splatter house.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it's not three dollars.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's 800.
Speaker 0: That seems to be the going travelers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, eight hundred points eight dollars.
Speaker 0: You mean eight hundred point?
Speaker 1: No, I mean eight dollars.
Speaker 0: There are no dollars and we land.
Speaker 0: there's points.
Speaker 0: Yeah You keep telling yourself that a splatter house really it's more a nostalgia thing than anything and I never even really played the game.
Speaker 0: I just knew about it.
Speaker 0: every kid knew about it because in every gaming magazine there were these horribly violent Advertisements for this horribly violent game and the game was marketed on the sole premise that it's horribly violent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, splatter house is sort of the over fiend of video games, you know All your.
Speaker 1: you're a guy who's basically Jason.
Speaker 1: you had a hockey mask that possessed you with evil and gave you powers and a chainsaw.
Speaker 1: Or what a baseball bat.
Speaker 1: or two by four usually or what other sort of weapon maybe your fist if you sucked And you walked around a house full of nasty monsters and when you hit them they went splat and they made a big gooey mess everywhere.
Speaker 1: Usually that was all gory and nasty and you were just trying to save your girlfriend from this haunted house And then all the bosses were crazy as brain things or whatever and it was just a big mess of gold.
Speaker 0: I don't remember if it was splatter house 2 or 1 or which one it was But one of the bosses and one of them I remember was a bunch of bloody fetuses that were just kind of dangle from the ceiling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not so good.
Speaker 1: That's like it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if you like just walking around hitting things and watching them go splat.
Speaker 1: This is the game for you.
Speaker 0: However, you should at least be aware that this game existed because
Speaker 1: we have
Speaker 0: a lot of problems now with people blaming video games for violence Or whatever and I think a lot of this at least has its earliest Basis origins and the fact that there was an era where a lot of video games were marketed solely on the level of violence in Them.
Speaker 0: and this isn't a new debate.
Speaker 0: It's just been a mortal combat Mortal combat.
Speaker 0: All right That was the one moment in my entire life where as a kid there were people who had a Sega system Who had a 1-up on me because my version of Mortal Kombat didn't have blood.
Speaker 1: It was actually a better version though It was.
Speaker 0: it was But it didn't have blood and unlike the Sega kids.
Speaker 0: There was no blood code.
Speaker 0: Yep, not that Mortal Kombat was a good game by any stretch.
Speaker 1: Mortal Kombat 1.
Speaker 0: Mortal Kombat 1 was a mediocre fight.
Speaker 1: It was an okay game.
Speaker 1: mortal Kombat 2 was actually a good fighting game.
Speaker 1: Mortal Kombat 3 is just bad and and any Mortal Kombat greater than 2 is pretty much as bad.
Speaker 0: see by the time we had Mortal Kombat 2 which was an okay fighting game.
Speaker 0: We could just play Street Fighter 2.
Speaker 1: So I bought a fighter 2 and we had Mortal Kombat 1.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Street Fighter 2 was better than Mortal Kombat 2.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 1: I think super Street Fighter 2 was better than Mortal Kombat 2.
Speaker 0: Mortal Kombat 2 wasn't that great.
Speaker 1: Mortal Kombat 2 was alright.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so there's a guy out there named Eli Tomlinson and he's done something that a lot of people have had the idea to do for a long time.
Speaker 1: he took some Linux and put it on a CD and he put a game on the CD and You put the CD in your computer and you boot your computer and the game just plays as if your computer was a console.
Speaker 0: Now many of you might be too young to remember this but there was a time a long time ago Where you would buy computer games and your computer probably was not able to run windows or Your mouse driver and still play the game.
Speaker 1: it just if you only had say 8 megabytes of RAM and the game required 6 megabytes of RAM and All your drivers for your hardware required one and a half megabytes of RAM, you know You're running out of RAM pretty quickly there.
Speaker 1: So what you've got to do you had to in those days was boot your computer with a boot disk that wouldn't load All the things that are normally loaded.
Speaker 1: like you're operating all your you know, you would load less of your operating system.
Speaker 0: Well, what actually happened was a lot of games came with a boot disk So they come with the install disks and the boot disk and they just assume that your computer was too slow.
Speaker 0: So whenever you wanted to play the game you put the boot disk in Rebooted.
Speaker 0: or if you were uber-leet and you knew about DOS you held f5 when it booted and then you manually loaded your mouse Drivers and your high mem stuff and you shuffled your RAM around and then you started the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean when you really think about it your computer Oh, I assume it's pretty damn powerful and you look at the system specifications of something like the Xbox 360.
Speaker 1: And then you look at the specifications of your computer and you say way my computer is way better than the 360.
Speaker 1: Why do the 360 games look better than the ones on my computer?
Speaker 0: because the 360 isn't run in Linux or Windows and I am And I CQ and Firefox and Photoshop.
Speaker 1: It's just you know, if you get your computer to run the game and nothing else It'll be pretty damn awesome.
Speaker 1: Now this guy isn't actually doing that.
Speaker 1: He's not putting out awesome games that Are using your computer to its fullest potential and getting those extra 30 FPS that are being eaten up by CPU time on other programs.
Speaker 1: He's just taking open-source games putting them on discs and selling them for 20 bucks, huh?
Speaker 1: Which is perfectly legal.
Speaker 1: you're allowed to do that.
Speaker 1: If you take the gimp you can put the gimp on a CD and sell that CD.
Speaker 1: this is that.
Speaker 1: that's okay thumbs up Open-source people have no problem with that.
Speaker 0: Well most open-source people.
Speaker 1: if they do they're crazy because the GPL lets you do that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, specifically what if there's all those nutjobs?
Speaker 1: you use things other than GPL like the a FPL and it's like that time That's someone in Britain was selling copies of Firefox rebranded I remember that and they called up the Firefox guys.
Speaker 1: the the Britain piracy people called up Firefox And they were like people are doing this and they're like, yeah, so they can do that.
Speaker 1: But but we can't.
Speaker 1: that messes up our whole system here catching pirates.
Speaker 1: We can't.
Speaker 0: but uh, man I remember just one of the greatest days in my life was when I bought four megabytes of RAM to bring my 486 up from four megabytes to eight megabytes and then I could play doom without having to boot f5.
Speaker 1: Yep, the interesting thing about what this guy is doing is that he's not selling it as like hey, here's a Linux game That's a boot CD.
Speaker 1: He's saying this is a game for the gamix console G a mi X and he's distributing them in blue cases as if they were for a console.
Speaker 1: and he says if your computer meets these Specifications then it is a gamix console and it can play these games.
Speaker 0: You know, I see the primary market for this sort of thing especially with simple games or open-source games or whatever being Parents who don't know about computers who have younger kids and want to get games for the younger kids.
Speaker 0: But don't understand any of this business.
Speaker 0: don't want to install software Don't want to deal with that.
Speaker 0: buy a CD boot it kid plays take the CD out.
Speaker 0: now You're back to doing your businessman things.
Speaker 1: I could actually almost see like actual PC games going to be a sort of gamix type format, you know, why?
Speaker 1: why can't the next big?
Speaker 1: FPS be a gamix game?
Speaker 1: Well, the only reason that I can see it won't be is because people need to keep their IMS open.
Speaker 0: That's what I was about to say.
Speaker 1: need to keep their team speaks open.
Speaker 0: rebooting computers is a gigantic pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: It is indeed.
Speaker 0: I mean the Mac downstairs.
Speaker 0: we reboot it pretty much never.
Speaker 0: so when I have to reboot it It's this huge annoyance and the only reason I avoid rooting the primary computer.
Speaker 0: I use the you know, geek night's computer because every time I boot it there's a chance it won't come back up It.
Speaker 0: it has some trouble recently.
Speaker 0: So lately I'm just leaving it on.
Speaker 1: are you gonna buy a new house soon?
Speaker 1: Are you gonna buy a new one if you change your plan April 22nd?
Speaker 0: I'm holding out for that possibility that the memo leaked from Intel was true and that in April They're gonna announce all the new chips and the price cuts.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, and if that happens, I'm gonna buy a new computer pretty much that day.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're changing all your plans I see.
Speaker 0: actually this has been my plan for like two and a half.
Speaker 0: three.
Speaker 1: plan was like summer.
Speaker 1: you're gonna buy.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, my original plan was the week before Team Fortress 2 came out.
Speaker 1: See you're changing the plan.
Speaker 0: I changed the plan months and months and months ago when I found out they were gonna delay Team Fortress 2 way beyond what?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh All right, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I've talked about this on the show a couple times and in the forums.
Speaker 0: It's not new news.
Speaker 0: I changed my plans a long time ago big Flip-flop for.
Speaker 0: well originally they said that Team Fortress 2 was gonna come out in spring of this year and that ain't happening.
Speaker 1: So it's not so.
Speaker 1: you're saying it's not okay for them to change their plan.
Speaker 1: So it's not okay for you to change your plans.
Speaker 0: No I'm saying because they changed their plan.
Speaker 0: I changed my plan and that was a while ago and you knew about this.
Speaker 0: and now you're Acting like you didn't know.
Speaker 1: so you can make a deal about it on the show when you change when they announced that they were Changing those dates.
Speaker 1: You didn't change your plan to buy a computer in April.
Speaker 1: You changed your plan to buy a computer Earlier.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I said ah shits.
Speaker 0: What am I gonna do now?
Speaker 0: I don't have to buy it as soon as I thought.
Speaker 0: how long can I hold out?
Speaker 0: and the answer is not as long as I hoped.
Speaker 1: no Whatever.
Speaker 0: and that was a couple weeks ago when I saw that that was the date supposedly that Intel's gonna release the new chips.
Speaker 1: Alright, alright big big plan changing.
Speaker 1: So what see you got any news over there?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got some news And this is kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: It looks like news that rim, but yeah since about that virtual console thing isn't news I'm not gonna make my news every week.
Speaker 0: view whatever the Wii has on the virtual console.
Speaker 0: But in actual news the ps3 lost another exclusive.
Speaker 0: It looks like Devil May Cry 4 which I care so little about.
Speaker 1: I care about it less than pretty much almost everything.
Speaker 0: Here's my experience with the Devil May Cry franchise because we didn't have a ps2, but our friend Luke did.
Speaker 0: So we went over to his house.
Speaker 0: He said check out this game.
Speaker 1: This is a Devil May Cry was brand new like the new hotness.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like two days after it came out We're sitting in his apartment.
Speaker 0: Yep, and he's playing and he's having a great time and the graphics look great.
Speaker 0: So he hands me the controller and for like a half hour I'd hit a thing with a sword and then I jump and shoot while I fell through the air in slow motion And I just did that over and over again.
Speaker 0: It was so awesome to jump in the air and shoot in slow motion and Another hour went by and we all took turns shooting things in slow motion in the air And then eventually the next day we realized that there really wasn't anything else to that game And we stopped playing.
Speaker 1: all we did was walk around this castle and whenever there was a monster You would kill it in some way.
Speaker 1: that looked really cool But was the same thing every time and then eventually the game was over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then we read on the internet about all the people talking about the various difficulties or annoying things later in this game.
Speaker 0: And then I stopped caring about Devil May Cry and I didn't even know that there was a three.
Speaker 0: So the fact that there's a four here means I'm kind of out of the loop.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's not a ps3 exclusive anymore and there's rumors going around that Metal Gear might be going the same route.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean if you're a game developer if you're gonna really decide to make your game ps3 exclusive You're pretty much asking to lose money.
Speaker 1: I mean you just you can't do it business wise.
Speaker 1: You're paying how much money to develop Metal Gear Solid for millions of dollars.
Speaker 1: if you choose to sell it on only the ps3 Pretty much almost nobody is gonna buy it.
Speaker 1: I mean sure You'll some people will buy ps3 is just to get your game because your game is that good or that popular.
Speaker 1: It's such a big franchise and people with ps3s will almost all definitely buy the game sort of like everyone with the GameCube will buy Wind Waker and everyone with a Wii will buy a Twilight Princess, right?
Speaker 1: But it's still not enough to make back the millions you spent to die metal get.
Speaker 1: make Metal Gear Solid 4.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is I can only see two situations where a game developer would ever make a game exclusive.
Speaker 0: Number one is if whatever you're doing with your game requires something that is only on a particular console.
Speaker 0: if you want Xbox Live You gotta be on the Xbox.
Speaker 0: Yes, you want the remote you got to be on the Wii.
Speaker 0: If you don't want to sell your game, you got to be on the ps3.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is the ps3 doesn't have a lot to offer so far.
Speaker 0: I mean even it, you know, it's supposed to be so much more powerful.
Speaker 0: yet a lot of games are having some trouble Capitalizing on that power and I haven't really seen any games that look like they really push the ps3 to its limit.
Speaker 1: Even if they do push the ps3 to the limit, they got to be good girls.
Speaker 1: I mean I could go and make a game that pushes the graphics of the ps3 the limit.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's all just be a double dodecahedron raytracer.
Speaker 1: That's what it is.
Speaker 1: It draws a really cool double dodecahedron and you can look at it from different angles by controlling it with your six axis
Speaker 0: And then it draws a thousand of them and they bounce against each other in a real-time Physics engine
Speaker 1: and then it fills the thing with water and you can see the fishes go out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the only other reason would be if the people who control a console decided to pay a developer X amount of money To make the game exclusive.
Speaker 0: now I don't think that Sony has enough money to pay the people who make these games To release their games only on the ps3 at least now when there aren't so many ps3s in the world in people's hands.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean like you got to assume All right What if they made Metal Gear Solid 4 at for the Xbox?
Speaker 1: 360?
Speaker 1: right and it would cost them X much to make the game.
Speaker 1: and then the end they would make X profit if they Sell it on the ps3.
Speaker 1: they would only.
Speaker 1: they would only get X dollars.
Speaker 1: They might not even profit.
Speaker 1: So they're basically Sony would have to pay them the difference for it to be worth it for them to make it a Sony Exclusive.
Speaker 0: Yep and game developers.
Speaker 0: It's not like they have loyalty to a console for any reason other than money.
Speaker 0: I mean square there was.
Speaker 0: they used to be buddy buddy with Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Everyone always forgets that Final Fantasy started in Nintendo and stayed on Nintendo for a long time.
Speaker 0: A lot of people would say through the best of Final Fantasy, but I'm not gonna get into that.
Speaker 1: In fact if Nintendo didn't you know have troubles with square soft the PlayStation would never would have been anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean square had an actual not personal falling out with Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Yeah In addition to the non personal issues and whether you realize it or not if that falling out did not occur then Final Fantasy 7 Would have not come out for the PlayStation.
Speaker 1: it would have coming out for the n64 or something else and then no one would have Bought a PlayStation or at least Sony would be nothing.
Speaker 0: right now You know what.
Speaker 0: there's a chance that if that had happened the Dreamcast might have done better.
Speaker 0: That is true, and that would have been a great god.
Speaker 0: We got to go back in time and kill also the Saturn.
Speaker 1: the Saturn would have done better.
Speaker 0: We got to go back in time and fix this.
Speaker 0: yeah, okay?
Speaker 0: There's a disturbance.
Speaker 0: if we correct this then the Saturn becomes a viable console.
Speaker 1: No, the only the real solution is to make sure mist is never released.
Speaker 1: ah Released many years later.
Speaker 0: We got to do a show on mist so I can complain about it.
Speaker 0: Okay, and Riven I never played the other ones me either, but I know about them because I knew people who played them all right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this isn't big news in and of itself.
Speaker 0: But if Metal Gear and other franchises start dropping from the ps3 exclusive visit II
Speaker 1: exclusivity
Speaker 0: yeah Then that's not really a good thing for Sony because pretty
Speaker 1: much
Speaker 0: the only reason to buy one Console over the other if you ignore things like how much they cost is The game library on it.
Speaker 0: and if a game is released equivalently on all three consoles or on two different consoles You don't need both consoles.
Speaker 0: if you like that game you only need a console.
Speaker 0: if you want a game That's only gonna be on that console.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean no one goes out and buys an Xbox 360 for Madden or something like that because Madden's on every console.
Speaker 1: so as long as you got one You don't need it doesn't matter which one you've got.
Speaker 1: you've got Madden.
Speaker 1: It's there It's gonna be there.
Speaker 1: yep, but you buy a Wii to get Twilight Princess cuz you can't get it anywhere else.
Speaker 0: But if you have a Wii and Madden comes out on the Wii and say an identical Madden came out on the Xbox There's no reason to buy an Xbox to get that Madden.
Speaker 0: well the only reason is Sometimes people I said identical if it's not identical yeah some.
Speaker 1: well even if it is identical.
Speaker 1: sometimes people are super fans And they'll want to get you know the games for different consoles also, but if they're identical Well it's also.
Speaker 1: sometimes You know let's say you have a Wii a PS 3 and a 360 and a game comes out for all three And it's the same game on all systems.
Speaker 1: You still might you know you if even if you only buy one you might choose to get say the ps3 one because you like That controller or you might choose to get the Xbox one because you use your Xbox more than use your other consoles.
Speaker 1: So it's easier for you.
Speaker 0: well like the case of Soulcalibur 2 if you had a GameCube You're pretty much an idiot if you bought that game for something other than the GameCube because it was Really, it's best on the GameCube.
Speaker 1: Well you might have been a fan of those other care.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you might have been a fan of the characters, but in terms of the game itself It was better on the GameCube.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least it was better on the GameCube and the Xbox than it was on the PlayStation.
Speaker 1: no No the PlayStation 2 one was actually the second best.
Speaker 1: Soulcalibur 2 I don't know anyone who bought the Xbox one Soulcalibur 2. who bought that?
Speaker 0: I've read forums where people were talking about the one with spawn.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: they prefer the Xbox one.
Speaker 0: they've complained that the ps2 one was slow And they're not really slow, but that didn't look good.
Speaker 1: I don't cares what it looks like it's it's a fighting game You fight.
Speaker 0: no I care a little bit about prettiness in a fighting game because otherwise why not just have stick figures?
Speaker 1: Why not just have stick figures?
Speaker 1: you can make a badass stick figure fighting game if you had really good stick figures.
Speaker 0: things of the day.
Speaker 0: So doom 2 is probably one of my favorite FPS is ever in terms of single-player.
Speaker 0: I really really like it that in half-life 1 or together is the best games.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's not the best FPS ever now considering we have half-life 1 & 2 and system shock 2 which I still haven't played and some others.
Speaker 1: But it's a classic, and it's still awesome.
Speaker 0: I think it holds its own even today.
Speaker 0: I mean serious Sam is the only game that's even tried.
Speaker 1: I think it's fine.
Speaker 1: I think the problem is it had yeah It's a different style than the FPS is of today And I like that style less than I like these.
Speaker 1: you know current half-life style of single-player FPS But in its style it might be the best one.
Speaker 0: well the thing is the current.
Speaker 0: well You call it the current style.
Speaker 0: not many FPS has really pulled that off well at all.
Speaker 1: I know that's.
Speaker 1: the thing is that when it's pulled off It's the best, but it's only pulled off like maybe five or six times in history.
Speaker 0: Well anyway I used to make a lot of doom 2 mods when I was a kid and I made some fun ones and some clever ones And some stupid ones, but this one here is probably the most hilarious one.
Speaker 0: I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: no I didn't make it.
Speaker 0: according to YouTube it was made in Peru.
Speaker 0: it is Super Mario Doom Brothers.
Speaker 0: You might think this is gonna be stupid.
Speaker 0: I'd recommend you watch it.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty hilarious.
Speaker 1: I remember back in the day the first doom mod ever was Barney doom because in those times Barney You know the big purple dinosaur was.
Speaker 1: everyone loved to make fun of it and say how stupid it was and Everyone hated it in the stupid songs that it sang in the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So they made Barney doom where you could kill Barney with the doom weapons And there would be Barney bad guys And you'd kill them while it's saying it's terrible song, and it was great.
Speaker 0: We had a project in middle school where we had there's like this cross Curriculum BS where he had to get into teams and do all these parts of a project and involve designing a candy factory.
Speaker 0: You might wonder why this is relevant.
Speaker 0: me being all clever decided that what I would do for part of this was make a virtual Reality mock-up of our factory and all I did was open up wadded and windy and all those things make a little Semi crappy.
Speaker 0: doom level with the right textures to look vaguely like a candy factory was basically just a doom level without any monsters In it.
Speaker 0: I got rid of the gun and replaced it with like a spatula.
Speaker 0: I put a chef hat on the doom guy and I got an A because that was the most amazing thing.
Speaker 0: my teachers couldn't believe That.
Speaker 0: I made this virtual reality world for a project in school.
Speaker 0: I Even left to some of the monsters in and one of the rooms.
Speaker 0: like workers I just took away their shoot animations.
Speaker 0: all they did was wander around and stare at you And they were still zombies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so here's another video from doom - and it's this punk kid Definitely a punk kid.
Speaker 1: There's no doubt.
Speaker 1: and he's like hey everyone check this out.
Speaker 1: This is a secret level in doom - the secret level that is Straight out of Wolfenstein 3d the secret level that anyone who's ever played doom - knows about.
Speaker 0: well kid I got this to say to you and that is welcome to the internet.
Speaker 1: I mean this kid.
Speaker 1: this video would the only equivalents that I can think of would be if someone Like made a video and said hey, here's how you get the whistle in mario 3.
Speaker 1: Hey, here's how you do the Konami code.
Speaker 1: Do you know that it works in Contra and Gradius?
Speaker 1: No, holy shit.
Speaker 0: I think it's even a step beyond that.
Speaker 0: cuz this kid I don't know where to begin first off before we even go any further.
Speaker 1: Hey guys, I found this great movie Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Have you ever seen it?
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Well one the kid has to cheat to beat the cyberdemon.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: Yeah, he says.
Speaker 1: when he opens the door and the cyberdemon comes out He says in the video luckily I got some cheats I Can beat the cyberdemon with the pistol.
Speaker 1: anyone with any amount of skill can beat the cyberdemon with the pistol without getting hit.
Speaker 0: I punched a cyberdemon to death just to see if I could.
Speaker 1: as long as it's only one Cyberdemon if there's two at the same time and you can't get them to kill each other then it could be a little tough.
Speaker 0: Actually a map that I always had a lot of fun.
Speaker 0: I was a custom one.
Speaker 0: I don't know who made it, but I had it.
Speaker 0: It was basically this arena like a gladiatorial arena.
Speaker 0: It was you and three cyberdemons, and that's it.
Speaker 1: the trick is to get them to kill each other.
Speaker 1: They won't till there's just one left.
Speaker 0: They won't.
Speaker 0: I fought them all.
Speaker 1: It sucks as long as I can do it one at a time.
Speaker 0: Not really, uh, hey, that's how I trained.
Speaker 1: yes, I did I can do that, but I couldn't do it with the pistol.
Speaker 0: I defy anyone who has ever listened to geek nights to beat me in a doom tube deathmatch.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it gets even worse because after he beats the cyber team with his cheats He goes into the next room.
Speaker 1: if you play doom - you know, what's in the next room of the secret level?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's and commander keen there's four commander Kean's.
Speaker 1: hang in there and you shoot them and then you flick the switch and the game's over.
Speaker 1: He says all right, can someone please tell me why this is the kid the kid says in the video.
Speaker 1: Can someone tell me why there's a football player dead hanging on ropes at the end of doom - it's?
Speaker 1: Commander keen what the?
Speaker 1: can someone tell me why there's a plumber going down pipes in Mario 1 I don't know - is commander keen to his credit.
Speaker 0: He was probably not born when commander keen was popular.
Speaker 0: I'll bet half of our listeners have never played a commander keen game and they're just as bad as this kid for not knowing Just as bad Scott commander keen was old hat when we were in middle school.
Speaker 1: That's the point, but I know about it.
Speaker 1: It's like oh gee, what's this game?
Speaker 1: It's dig duck.
Speaker 0: You gotta know commander keen.
Speaker 0: I don't think the vast majority of people in the world today have any idea who commander keen is ready.
Speaker 0: Okay ID these are the same people who don't realize that Duke Nukem was a fun 2d platformer long before it was an FPS Id software.
Speaker 1: the people who made doom and Wolfenstein and everything and quake Before they made those games.
Speaker 1: They made a game called commander keen and there were actually quite a few commander keen games.
Speaker 1: It was a platform game kind of like Mario you jump around and you know, you do stuff you pick up items.
Speaker 1: You would kill bad guys with this laser gun.
Speaker 1: Basically you're on an alien world.
Speaker 1: you collected treasures you found secret exits But it wasn't platform.
Speaker 1: like Mario gets at the end of the level even though there was some of that.
Speaker 1: It was sort of platform.
Speaker 1: figure out your way around the level.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a little bit of a maze a little bit exploring a little bit.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: Do you want to take the risk and go for that extra goody if you want to miss the spikes that sort of thing?
Speaker 0: Kinds of games that aren't around so much anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and The thing about commander keen that was awesome was that you had this pogo stick and it was all about the pogo stick.
Speaker 1: and The plot was you were like.
Speaker 1: you were a kid And you were like in your pair.
Speaker 1: you're in your bedroom and then suddenly you were needed on a planet far away to save like the universe from aliens or something and you would get in your little UFO with your football helmet and your ray gun Or your pogo stick and you go to another planet and save the day.
Speaker 0: now The best part about this kid's little internet video where he shows us His voice.
Speaker 0: this kid has such the nerdly punk kid voice that it was almost painful to hear it And he doesn't know crap about video games.
Speaker 0: I do however salute this kid because he has shown me that no matter how connected the world is There are always going to be nubs and the nubs don't know that they're nubs.
Speaker 1: You know, there was a baby born just now and it doesn't know anything.
Speaker 1: It doesn't even know who Mickey Mouse is who Mario is.
Speaker 1: it doesn't know nothing Scott.
Speaker 0: there are probably a lot of kids who are gonna play Twilight Princess and they don't even know that there was this other Zelda game for this archaic Gray box that came out when their parents were younger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they will cuz the virtual console will show them the way.
Speaker 0: no Maybe maybe their parents aren't gonna give him the credit card.
Speaker 0: Let him buy games.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, but they'll see in there in the virtual console.
Speaker 1: They'll see these games that they're still there.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's the true power of the virtual console that it will show.
Speaker 0: it'll force kids to at least know that they used to be something else.
Speaker 1: I Think eventually one day, you know how we have sort of have classic books, you know and they're like there's a special section in the bookstore for the classics, you know, like Moby Dick and Shakespeare and all all those the classics.
Speaker 1: and there's movies that are the classics.
Speaker 1: It's a whole TV channel that just shows them all day long.
Speaker 1: We're gonna have the all-time classics of video games one day and they'll be in every store.
Speaker 0: You know on that special section the classics interestingly to me and not to belie any sort of fanboy and ishness or anything.
Speaker 0: But if I think about games that I would consider classic the vast majority of them are Nintendo games Pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that might just be due to the fact that Nintendo had a virtual monopoly on the gaming market for a long Time longer than anyone else and possibly at the present time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't.
Speaker 0: I honestly didn't think Nintendo would come back so strong until the we came out and did.
Speaker 1: gangbusters Not the DS stills is better.
Speaker 1: Alright, so what are we talking about today?
Speaker 0: Well, I really wanted to do a show on xcom mission UFO also known as xcom enemy unknown or xcom UFO defense.
Speaker 0: But Scott sucked at the game and never played it.
Speaker 1: I barely played this game.
Speaker 1: I never had it Barely even knew much about xcom until way later and You know while I recognize that it is a great classic awesome game, and I know about it.
Speaker 0: I didn't play it enough to really do a whole episode But at the same time Scott had a game that he wanted to talk about.
Speaker 1: Yes, perhaps one of the best games ever if not the best game ever maybe the best PC game ever You couldn't argue.
Speaker 1: it is no worse than the second greatest PC game ever Star control 2 which rim has never played and I think a lot of people I've turned it on and poked at it I've just never played it for more than a Trivial amount.
Speaker 1: and a lot of people who didn't have you know, DOS computers don't even know about this game.
Speaker 1: They ever played it yet.
Speaker 1: It is no worse than the second best PC game ever.
Speaker 0: See now I would say the exact same thing about xcom mission UFO.
Speaker 0: I consider it to be one of the greatest bar none PC games ever made.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like them and tie fighter.
Speaker 0: Well tie fighters the number one and save - there's no question.
Speaker 0: tie fighter got the same city.
Speaker 1: Do that.
Speaker 0: I remember back in the day when tie fighter got the highest score PC gamer which used to be a fairly legitimate reviewer of games had ever given a 97% and then years later a game beat tie fighter with 98% and the only game that was ever good enough to beat tie fighter was tie fighter re-released on CD.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, it's a good thing.
Speaker 1: It's a good.
Speaker 1: I think we'll do well combining these two games into one show where we sort of have a similar experience with each great old PC games For DOS that you played one and I played one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one seems to know about them anymore.
Speaker 0: care now.
Speaker 0: There's also a lot of things that you should take away from this episode.
Speaker 0: One that I think is interesting is that both of these are kinds of games that not only aren't made anymore But have almost never been made.
Speaker 0: There are so few games that are like this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's.
Speaker 1: there's not many games like star control except star control and xcom.
Speaker 0: there were sequels that were ass and there Have been a lot of people.
Speaker 0: xcom was so good back in the day that even to this day There are a lot of people trying to make xcom clones or trying to recreate xcom and they all suck.
Speaker 1: Yes, good God I mean it would be trivial like I could imagine easily a game in the same genre as xcom Had a better interface than xcom and was a better game than xcom UFO defense.
Speaker 1: not any the other xcoms.
Speaker 1: yet No one has made them despite trying even though it's just you can.
Speaker 1: I can think of it right now.
Speaker 1: It's in my brain There it is.
Speaker 0: It's definitely feasible Yeah but it ends up being.
Speaker 0: these are both fairly unique games and what I really want you to come out of this is that you Can get a hold of these games?
Speaker 0: They're not lost to the star.
Speaker 1: control is much easier to get a hold of.
Speaker 1: the next combat Is not impossible is trivial to get a hold of.
Speaker 0: I'm going to link to the underdogs download of xcom.
Speaker 0: Oh snap, you can just play it.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: I have I own two legitimate copies of xcom.
Speaker 0: I also have a third.
Speaker 0: the first xcom is the first game I ever got.
Speaker 0: that wasn't just a shareware game Or some sort of crap puzzle game for a computer.
Speaker 0: Mmm, also I pirated it cuz I didn't know that there was such a thing as software you could buy.
Speaker 0: Haha But anyway You can get these games and I cannot recommend enough that you play both of these games.
Speaker 0: if you consider yourself a gamer by any stretch at least try to play these games and look at them and Examine them and I guarantee that you will like at least one of them a lot.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much impossible.
Speaker 1: It's like if you're a movie person you can't just like not watch citizen Kane.
Speaker 0: awesome Blanca You have to watch him biodome.
Speaker 1: So if you have to watch those and you got to play these.
Speaker 0: So in 1993 microfroze released this game called UFO enemy unknown in Europe And it was then released in America titled xcom UFO defense.
Speaker 0: There was also xcom mission UFO, which was the same game.
Speaker 0: I don't know why but I saw boxes of it that said xcom mission UFO, but it was the exact same game.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like when they put out a comic book with two covers and then you buy both.
Speaker 1: They're trying to scam you and to find the same game twice.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think there might have been issues with it being released in different places and things getting knocked around.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter because the game is xcom people called by all these names, but xcom is basically the name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are other xcom games that came later like Xcom apocalypse xcom terror from the deep.
Speaker 0: They're all garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only one you care about is the original xcom UFO something something.
Speaker 0: Yeah UFO defense.
Speaker 0: We'll go with that.
Speaker 0: That's the easiest way to nominate Hereby known as xcom.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Now this game were for the PC right out of 486.
Speaker 0: It was fairly high for the time.
Speaker 0: my computer had to be booted specially to run it because my computer was really slow.
Speaker 0: it barely met the requirements and To say what genre the game is in would be very difficult to do because it has it's kind of remember how act razor for The SNES had basically two entirely different games within itself and they interacted with each other Xcoms kind of the same way.
Speaker 0: the plot of xcom nominally is that aliens?
Speaker 0: Exists there.
Speaker 0: We see them.
Speaker 0: They're out there.
Speaker 0: They are gray men and they have UFOs and they have started causing trouble on earth.
Speaker 0: They start abducting people and mutilating cattle and then they start attacking people straight up.
Speaker 1: They start just invading earth flat out.
Speaker 1: We are going to take over earth and kill you all and we're not just gray aliens.
Speaker 0: Well, we don't actually know their motivations other than that they are attacking earth for some reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah And attacking earth means literally coming into a city suddenly and trying to kill everyone there in Horrible ways and harvest their organs and ways they get more horrible as the game goes on.
Speaker 0: So the governments of the world all try to fight this on.
Speaker 0: there's actually an extensive backstory to xcom where the Japanese Created this group that tried to fight him and failed and other people got together and eventually the United Nations Creates what is effectively nerve from Evangelion xcom the secret organization funded by the world governments that Basically exists in these underground bunker bases much like nerve and your goal is to identify the threat Defend the earth from it and eventually eliminate the threat entirely.
Speaker 0: You don't know what the threat is.
Speaker 0: You really have no idea what's going on other than that.
Speaker 0: These alien attacks are occurring.
Speaker 0: you start with almost nothing.
Speaker 0: UN gives you a pile of money.
Speaker 0: You've got conventional weapons that the earthlings have.
Speaker 0: the aliens meanwhile have horrible alien Technology and plasma rifles and psychic powers.
Speaker 1: yeah, you basically start the game with a few guys that have machine guns maybe a rocket launcher a grenade or a pistol and Like one shit one fighter jet.
Speaker 1: basically.
Speaker 0: now the general gist of the game is that you've got to Somehow fight off this alien threat and it caused money to do this.
Speaker 0: you get money from the UN and all the UN member states.
Speaker 0: Every year the UN evaluates your performance and decides whether or not to increase your budget.
Speaker 0: if you do really poorly Nations might back out of the treaty altogether and stop funding you.
Speaker 0: Let's say all your bases around North America.
Speaker 0: Maybe Russia eventually is sick of this and pulls out and tries to fight the aliens on their own Meaning you lose funding.
Speaker 0: if you do really horribly the UN will drop the project altogether and abandon it in which case you get Probably one of the best endings to a video game ever where the game basically says yes over the years the aliens Completely enslave humanity and destroy everything.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Good job You're the MVP of the alien team.
Speaker 0: So the way the game actually starts in terms of gameplay is you pick a spot on the globe.
Speaker 0: It can be anywhere on the globe.
Speaker 1: You've got a 3d globe even in the water.
Speaker 0: Well, not in the water anywhere in the land Antarctica.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can put.
Speaker 0: you can put a base there All right.
Speaker 0: I have put bases there.
Speaker 0: Okay, and you stick it somewhere now.
Speaker 0: Obviously you probably want to stick it near countries that have more money.
Speaker 0: So you keep them happy So they keep giving you more money.
Speaker 0: But aside from that you put a base down and now the game suddenly starts in real time.
Speaker 0: Time is ticking away in five second intervals 24/7.
Speaker 0: Well, can't you change the speed?
Speaker 0: I'll get to that.
Speaker 0: So you can watch the shadow of the of the Sun and the earth going around and you just watch the earth in real time.
Speaker 0: You can spin it around zoom in zoom out.
Speaker 1: Now remember, even though rim is saying it's 3d.
Speaker 1: This is old DOS Pixelated graphics doing this.
Speaker 1: This is not a 3d card with your DirectX's go.
Speaker 0: No, it's polygons.
Speaker 0: But the graphics are actually very good for the time and they're passable even for modern games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're good enough to make the game work, but they are not like, you know, don't don't Think incorrectly about them.
Speaker 0: Well, they're actually they're very good.
Speaker 0: And I think they're better than almost every open-source game out today.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, pretty much just because they're really clean.
Speaker 1: It's like they did the best they could with the technology they had.
Speaker 0: Yes, so time progresses in real time constantly.
Speaker 0: You can alter the rate.
Speaker 0: the time passes.
Speaker 0: ranging from every interval is 5 seconds to every interval is 24 hours.
Speaker 1: That's dangerous.
Speaker 0: Yes well the nice thing is you've got your base and you're sitting there and you're waiting and whatever you can click on your base and There's a billion options.
Speaker 0: You've got an actual base with a grid.
Speaker 0: you can build hangers in it or alien containment things or Armories or all the stuff you would need to man a base.
Speaker 0: you got to manage your scientists.
Speaker 0: You're doing research.
Speaker 0: your engineers will build stuff for you.
Speaker 0: You've got a higher troops.
Speaker 0: Every single person you hire gets a name and a individual stats.
Speaker 1: You have to pay them a salary and you out you equip them with individual weapons Like you're like, okay This guy has a clip of ammo in his right pocket and he carries a pistol and there's a rocket launcher in his backpack.
Speaker 0: Yes, luckily a lot of those things are automated.
Speaker 0: You really don't have to worry about them other than tweaking a few things here and there.
Speaker 0: but they're there.
Speaker 0: Yes, they're there.
Speaker 0: the game Basically, you're managing the entire UFO defense.
Speaker 0: You are the CEO of the secret company that is fighting the aliens.
Speaker 0: You have to manage the salaries of everyone.
Speaker 0: you have to manage the politics of when to shoot down aliens Where you have to decide on the science every single thing?
Speaker 0: You've got to manage.
Speaker 0: as a result There's a fairly fantastic interface where you look at this globe and you've got your base and you've got radar installations.
Speaker 0: Whatever whenever an alien UFO is picked up or whatever anything's going on It'll stop time and pop up a warning saying hey UFO designation 001 has been spotted and depending on what technology you have Maybe you'll learn more about it.
Speaker 0: and then the game just continues at five-second intervals.
Speaker 0: It always drops to five seconds whenever there's trouble and you have to decide how to respond.
Speaker 0: So you'll have interceptor craft and the sky Ranger which is kind of your bus full of troops.
Speaker 1: Yeah Typically your first response is send out a ship that to shoot down the alien UFO because if you can do that You're gonna be a lot better off than if you just let it go about its business and it's gonna start killing people.
Speaker 0: Yes, the UFO is actually.
Speaker 0: it's fairly complex.
Speaker 0: Once you learn to decode the aliens encryption and read their communication you start to find out exactly what each of these ships are doing.
Speaker 0: and it gets really interesting like say you see a Terror ship and you know, it's on its way to a city to do some sort of terrorist mission.
Speaker 0: or very interestingly later in the game You might start seeing supply ships and they're big and fat and they're full of goodies and say you wonder why are there supply ships?
Speaker 0: Where are they going?
Speaker 0: So then, you know say you see hey, these supply ships are always going to run Antarctica.
Speaker 0: so you fly over to Antarctica with one of your interceptors and tell it to Patrol around and you find an alien fucking base in the middle of the Antarctic.
Speaker 0: Oh shit and all sorts of things like that.
Speaker 0: or They build alien bases in Russia and then they infiltrate the Russian government And then they force the Russian government to pull out of the treaty and stop funding you.
Speaker 1: Yep, now remember rim said it was kind of like Actraiser where there's two parts the city building part.
Speaker 1: and then yes
Speaker 0: you know, well in this case the two parts are one the strategic manageable the tactical and strategic management of this entire enterprise from the bottom up from the hiring and firing of Individual people working for your program to the budget to the technology to making sure all your equipment is in but melt maintained Well fueled you have bases with radar coverage everywhere Reacting to multiple UFO threats simultaneously.
Speaker 0: Yeah prioritization all that fun stuff that alone would be a fantastic fucking game.
Speaker 0: I mean when you send ships out to fight you don't actually have to sit and fight There's no sort of.
Speaker 0: now you pull out the joystick and fight.
Speaker 0: You're more like the commander.
Speaker 0: You told the ships to go out.
Speaker 0: you told him where to go.
Speaker 0: you watch on your display as they fight the UFOs.
Speaker 0: you can give them orders like stand down or Maintain a safe distance or destroy the UFO at all cost.
Speaker 0: But otherwise, they act pretty much on their own and you're the commander.
Speaker 0: You're not the person doing the dirty work Until until the other hand land on the ground.
Speaker 0: Well, let's say you shoot down a UFO.
Speaker 0: what you're gonna do at some point I hope unless you're really bad at this game.
Speaker 0: Now you take all your troops.
Speaker 0: you equip them with your technology you equip them with rifles and whatever.
Speaker 0: you load out your thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe you buy a tank to go with you and you send your sky ranger out and you land at the UFO site.
Speaker 1: Sky ranger is a ship that's full of soldiers and it lands on the ground Whereas the interceptor is a ship that flies around shooting alien ships.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now you can get other ships in the game, especially later when you start getting alien technology.
Speaker 0: See, you don't know what the threat is.
Speaker 0: That's the best part about this game.
Speaker 0: You don't know anything.
Speaker 0: when the first UFO comes up, you know, nothing.
Speaker 0: you have no idea what this what's going on.
Speaker 0: So you shoot it down then you land.
Speaker 0: you don't know what to expect.
Speaker 0: it now turns into this kind of top-down Isometric kind of view of a gridded battlefield a three-dimensional battlefield and you control individual troops in a direct turn-based tactical strategic game.
Speaker 1: you control them.
Speaker 1: so micro II like you say you duck now and you Turn and face in that direction and look around and you walk three spaces that way Crouch and aim at the door and if anyone opens that door you shoot them.
Speaker 0: Now the system is based on time units.
Speaker 0: so a troop will have say 70 time units and they can use time units to do actions and Say every step you take uses X time units.
Speaker 0: drawing a weapon uses X time units But you can just have weapons drawn.
Speaker 0: you can set people up ahead of time Loading and unloading weapons ducking standing back up take different amounts of time units shooting takes time units And the thing is you can use all your time units to move around and then when you've moved all your units you end the turn And then the aliens go.
Speaker 0: that alone would have been an okay game, but it's semi real-time even though it's turn-based.
Speaker 0: So let's say I am walking one of my troops out and there is an alien who sees where I troop.
Speaker 0: So I'm walking and my troop walks into the aliens line of sight.
Speaker 0: The alien if he has enough time units and his reaction speed is high enough compared to that troop might get to open fire During my turn.
Speaker 1: yet The thing is while you're you know normally in a game With sort of with the turn-based grid military combat if a guy has X movement points You usually use a lot of those movement points.
Speaker 1: You don't care about saving any of them.
Speaker 1: in this game if a guy has 10 movement 10 time units You're only gonna want to use maybe five.
Speaker 1: that way, you know, wherever he stops if an alien jumps out at him He'll have a chance to shoot at the alien maybe or run away or some.
Speaker 0: it'll take say 23 time units to fire a weapon on Automatic fully automatic weapon.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So well a lot of strategy involves like say you've got to go into a building You'll get all your troops lined up outside in their proper positions.
Speaker 0: wait around.
Speaker 0: then the next round You'll have like three people storm in duck and sit there in defensive positions Covering the rest of your troops who storm into the next door and get ready to toss a grenade through.
Speaker 0: Yep You really have to play it to see the full extent of this and I don't.
Speaker 0: I can't go into great detail since Scott has to talk about his game, but suffice to say this style of combat is Incredibly fun.
Speaker 0: It is also incredibly difficult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I basically just die whenever I try it even though I Understand the general principles and strategies.
Speaker 1: I just can't seem to do it without just getting killed.
Speaker 0: See, I actually have no trouble at all and I I can blow through xcom even on very difficult settings with relative ease.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't know what I'm doing wrong.
Speaker 1: I just can't ever kill any aliens.
Speaker 1: Really, maybe I'll play the first mission and maybe I'll beat it, but I'll lose some of my guys.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: The game is one.
Speaker 0: the difficulty scaling of this game is very good.
Speaker 0: the difficulty options you have when you start a game range in good granularity from Trivially easy to absolutely fucking impossible.
Speaker 0: Haha But even in general the game itself even on an average difficulty in the early game You'll you don't realize it but you're gonna take 50% casualties If not more your troops are gonna get slaughtered.
Speaker 0: you have no armor.
Speaker 0: You've got conventional weapons.
Speaker 0: the aliens have their crazy alien technology.
Speaker 0: I think Scott your problem was that you weren't willing to accept high casualties early in the game.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what it was is if I lost stuff then I would go back to that base You know the other part of the game and I wouldn't have anything and aliens would come and I'd be like, oh shit I have no money.
Speaker 1: I have nothing.
Speaker 1: it just all got blown up by aliens.
Speaker 0: That's part of the game.
Speaker 0: the best way to enjoy this game is to not do the.
Speaker 0: Save your game every single turn and make sure you always play the game perfectly optimally.
Speaker 0: It's more fun If say one of your missions gets wrecked and now you've got the three Surviving troops one of whom is carrying the fourth surviving troop who is wounded and can't walk anymore.
Speaker 0: Two of them are covering your retreat as you desperately try to drag the little bit of alien technology in the one alien corpse You recovered back to the sky Rangers.
Speaker 1: I never recovered alien corpses.
Speaker 0: Well, the nice thing is the game automates a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: Like if you defeat all the aliens in a crash site, it says all right You've completed them all and it automatically assumes that you take everything from the site.
Speaker 0: Yep There's a lot more to the game than this.
Speaker 0: Obviously, I've gone over it in the briefest and briefest of detail.
Speaker 0: But the only other thing I want to talk about aside from the fact that there's the one game Which is awesome and then the other kind of mini fighting game inside of it That's equally awesome Both of which would be great standalone games in and of themselves is that there is this ufopedia Which is a lot like the encyclopedia in civilization -
Speaker 1: the civil opedia.
Speaker 0: Yes The way it works is you don't know anything about the UFO threat but you have scientists and you can allocate their time to studying alien resources or Alien corpses or alien technology or maybe you capture a live alien and you try to interrogate him.
Speaker 0: as you learn about this threat you start filling out this encyclopedia and learning about what's going on.
Speaker 0: and Part of the game is that the first time playing through the game is probably the best experience you'll ever get Because you're learning about the game and you're trying to figure out what's going on so you can deal with this alien threat and you'll learn interesting things about the aliens and Eventually start to figure out what the actual plot of the game is and start taking action from there.
Speaker 0: The plot is also incredibly well put together very solid.
Speaker 0: The game is just so solid and so tight and the only problems it has are problems.
Speaker 1: They're just inherent with the fact that this game was made in 1993 And no one's even tried to make you in recent years to make this kind of game anymore.
Speaker 0: Yes, I won't talk about the sequels because they're terrible.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna review this game more fully someday.
Speaker 0: Maybe when Scott's not around.
Speaker 0: but suffice to say xcom is without question one of my favorite games ever definitely top two.
Speaker 1: All right, so in 1990 a game developer known as Toys for Bob made a game called Star Control famous battles of the Urquan conflict volume 4.
Speaker 1: This is Star Control 1.
Speaker 1: Basically all Star Control 1 was was a game where you controlled in real time in a 2d top-down view Spaceships big giant spaceships, even though they weren't so giant on the screen They really were giant in outer space shooting at other spaceships in Spaceship melee, even though it's not actual melee because they all projectile weapons But it's melee.
Speaker 1: and the way it works is each ship has a main weapon which when you fire it reduces your energy meter but then your energy refills at a rate dependent on which ship you have selected and You have a crew and the crew in your ship.
Speaker 1: when you get hit that some of them die and when they all die your Ship explodes and the other guy has the ship and you shoot at each other and you have also have a secondary attack Which is different for every ship.
Speaker 1: that might you know do something weird.
Speaker 1: And what eventually?
Speaker 1: the other guy blows up or you blow up and then if you're you know You have a fleet of ships you pick another ship from your fleet and you fight again and there's different ships for all the different Races, even though you don't know what the races are.
Speaker 1: You don't know anything about the Urquan conflict volume 4.
Speaker 1: You don't know why these battles are famous battles of the Urquan conflict unless you you know.
Speaker 1: read some text in the instruction manual Which is not really a help.
Speaker 1: It's just a real-time 2d space combat game.
Speaker 1: That's kind of interesting with lots of different ships that have funny abilities, but there's not much to it.
Speaker 1: So what happened is people said hey, what about this?
Speaker 1: Urquan conflict thing you guys are talking about and star control 1 was popular enough that they were able to make star control 2 the Urquan masters in 1992 Star control 2 in a lot of ways like XCOM is two different games.
Speaker 1: one game is The game I just described star control 1. even though it the the combat and star control 2 It's pretty much the same thing as the combat and star control 1.
Speaker 1: It's better in a lot of ways that the graphics aren't shit cuz.
Speaker 1: star control 1 was like a crap game for old ass computers like DOS Amiga Commodore.
Speaker 1: I think there was a Genesis version but it sucked.
Speaker 1: star control 2 was for the DOS and also the 3do and It was had a lot better graphics, and it was actually playable, and it was way cool.
Speaker 1: and Basically you had the same combat action of you know shooting each other.
Speaker 1: you could actually choose to just play a combat game Like it was star control 1. use the ships from star control 2 and just fight each other.
Speaker 0: I remember there was a lot of that action at RIT and colony when people were bored.
Speaker 1: yep But the combat and star control 2 is not as great as say the tactical walking around guys in XCOM.
Speaker 1: It's just there.
Speaker 1: and the real game is the space adventure if you've ever read hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy or any sort of similar Sci-fi stories where there's lots of different alien races that have funny personalities.
Speaker 1: That's what star control 2 is all about.
Speaker 1: here's the story of star control 2. you are an earth Human scientist of some sort.
Speaker 1: you were out researching Lost ancient space traveling technologies.
Speaker 1: you come back to earth only to find that has been surrounded By a shield and you cannot get to earth in any way possible, and it's really strange.
Speaker 1: And this is where the game begins.
Speaker 1: you are in your precursor battleship.
Speaker 1: This is a big giant awesome spaceship that you just researched and recovered.
Speaker 1: Imagine like if the best fighter jet in the world was actually like deep underground.
Speaker 1: We dug it up and rebuilt it.
Speaker 1: Yeah The Romans made it and they buried it and you just found it and now you fly it back to earth And you can't get to earth and the game begins.
Speaker 1: You've got this spaceship.
Speaker 1: You've got a galaxy, and you don't know what stars are which it's just a galaxy full of stars And you don't know what the hell's going on.
Speaker 1: you're in your ship.
Speaker 1: your ship has fuel and some other resources.
Speaker 1: You can spend those resources to do things like upgrade your ship outfit it with new weapons etc.
Speaker 1: etc.
Speaker 1: That's not so important.
Speaker 1: you've got this ship.
Speaker 1: you're in space.
Speaker 1: you came back to earth after your scientific mission.
Speaker 1: You can't go to earth what the fuck.
Speaker 1: so you go to the moon, and there's a guy there on the moon.
Speaker 1: you will just you basically go to that.
Speaker 1: you fly your ship to the moon and You land there, and you can send this little.
Speaker 1: every time you go to a planet You can drop this little guy onto the planet and drive it around the surface of the planet usually to collect resources but also to find things.
Speaker 1: and on this planet you find a Spathy.
Speaker 1: a spathy is one of the alien races that is so humorous in this game that you will lull ten times a spathy.
Speaker 1: Yes, spathy the spathy are this really really funny alien race that has like one big eyeball and They all have these great personalities and voices.
Speaker 1: and basically the spathy are cowards.
Speaker 1: They run away and the spaceships that they have have these BUTT missiles the backward utilized tracking torpedoes, uh-huh yes, that you fly the spathy ship you fire your secondary weapon and it goes and A missile comes out the back of the ship and then homes in on the enemy.
Speaker 0: that sounds utterly hilarious.
Speaker 1: It is hilarious.
Speaker 0: I'm sure
Speaker 1: Trust me,
Speaker 0: okay
Speaker 1: And he tells you this whole story and you come to realize by traveling around the galaxy and meeting alien races That there are these earthquake guys who have basically gone around To the different races in the galaxy and said you have two choices You can either be enslaved by the earthquake or we will surround your planet with a slave shield
Speaker 0: Surround planet to stay alive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Supposedly the earthquake are doing this to save all the alien the different races of the galaxy from some unknown threat of evil When really they're just being evil.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna reveal the whole plot of how you eventually save the galaxy or not But this game is really awesome because at one hand you're going around the galaxy Meeting alien races being diplomatic with them trying to figure out where to go to get the next thing to maybe get this one more alien race to join your side or give you some ships to help you fight or To you know fight against the earthquake to free all the other good races in the galaxy.
Speaker 1: at the same time You're trying not to die in the horrible loneliness and quietness of space.
Speaker 1: You're constantly trying to scavenge for resources to keep your ship fueled or else you can't make it to the next star system.
Speaker 1: You're constantly trying to you know Get one more bit of plutonium so you can build another ship so that you can go and destroy those evil aliens over there.
Speaker 1: You're trying to figure out where the hell do these aliens live?
Speaker 1: There's all these stars and it's completely unmapped galaxy.
Speaker 1: you're just exploring this big giant unknown place and you'll go to some.
Speaker 1: you go to a new star system and All the planets will just be gas giants with nothing on them.
Speaker 1: and you go to another star system and all the planets are gas Giants with nothing on them and it the whole atmosphere of the game.
Speaker 1: It's like comedic and Incredibly entertaining different personalities of aliens that when you actually meet them but also the cold reality of space and the Epic plot of a giant war and when you actually have combat you whip it out and do it.
Speaker 1: star control one style.
Speaker 0: It seems like both of these games Have one thing in common in that while they definitely have some replay value probably xcom more than your game Yeah, the thing with star control 2 is that once you know?
Speaker 1: Basically what order to do things in like, okay This is how you beat the game.
Speaker 1: you go to this planet.
Speaker 1: talk to those people.
Speaker 1: go to that planet.
Speaker 1: Talk to those people.
Speaker 1: go collect resources on these planets because you know where the resource.
Speaker 1: good resources are.
Speaker 1: Build this and this and this.
Speaker 1: go there once you know it and you've memorized it.
Speaker 1: the whole Exploration of space aspect which is what makes the game so great It's kind of gone because you're not exploring.
Speaker 1: you already know where everything is star control - you really have to go into it cold Not read any facts not do any tricks.
Speaker 1: just go into it and pretend That you are this human scientist who came back from a mission Totally found earth surrounded by a slave shield.
Speaker 1: You have no clue what's going on.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean while xcom is a lot more replay value just due to the nature of the game It still seems like both of these games have a lot to be gained by playing them from a completely ignorant standpoint.
Speaker 0: Don't go to game facts Don't read anything other than the instruction book and just play these games Like an ignorant person and learn from the game as you go, and I think they're much more rewarding that way.
Speaker 1: absolutely Another thing after star control 2 which is pretty much the only star control worth playing It's the most popular and the most everything there was a star control 3 Developed developed by a different company, but still published by accolade.
Speaker 1: I kind of like star control 3 a lot more than most of the star control.
Speaker 1: people like it because it still has sort of That explore the galaxy, you know talk to alien stuff and it still has the same combat only a little upped in the graphics.
Speaker 1: But it's really not quite the same.
Speaker 1: instead of collecting resources you sort of Have these Master of Orion style colony building things.
Speaker 1: It's not it's not really so great.
Speaker 1: But star control 3 it.
Speaker 1: they've also replaced the pixelated Animations of the different aliens with actual like live puppets of the aliens Which are actually high quality better than Muppets almost and they have really good voice acting in star control 3 also.
Speaker 1: So it's worth playing for those two things.
Speaker 1: but basically star control 4 never came out and Star control all the games became unplayable on modern systems.
Speaker 1: So the original people who made star control to those in star control one those toys for Bob guys.
Speaker 1: They took the 3do code the code for the 3do version of star control 2.
Speaker 1: They open sourced it under the GPL and now you can download for free legally a game called Simply the earthquake masters.
Speaker 1: It is absolutely free.
Speaker 1: It runs on Windows Linux Mac OS X and BSD and that is what you are going to play.
Speaker 0: if you're listening to this podcast Yep, and I know a lot of you use Windows So I'm just gonna link to the download for xcom.
Speaker 0: you can just play it cuz you're not gonna find this game for sale anywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll link to the website for our quan masters, which you can download a hundred percent legally instead of gray area legally.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm going to find out Somewhat shortly whether or not xcom works in wine Because I suddenly have this burning desire to play that game again, and I'm going to app get installed UQM to play some earthquake.
Speaker 0: masters god This might be a problem if we ever keep reviewing old things We like because it kind of forces us to play those games again.
Speaker 1: as we're reminded about him I'm gonna put it on my laptop and play it on the tree.
Speaker 1: the whole
Speaker 0: time you were talking I was mostly ignoring you and thinking about all the stuff that made xcom great and thinking about how much I wanted to get some heavy plasma and some flying armor and Just fly around lighting up the goddamn city
Speaker 1: You know we should do is you should install our quad masters and I should get xcom to work in wine.
Speaker 0: I think I should play through both xcom and our quan masters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you suck.
Speaker 1: Yes great old PC games you probably never played if you are not super old-school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is definitely where a lot of our complaints about modern PC games come from where there are good PC games now.
Speaker 0: But very few games these days live up to the games that I played as a kid and it shouldn't be that way.
Speaker 0: Why aren't people making games as good as games back then?
Speaker 1: well I think it's because the PC has always been a platform where there was a high potential for Innovation and game development because anyone could make a PC game.
Speaker 1: I mean look star control is made by toys for Bob.
Speaker 1: who the hell are they?
Speaker 1: they're just two guys.
Speaker 1: And in the early days when it was easy to make PC games and there wasn't a big business around it People making PC games are all trying cool stuff like the people who made hero quest.
Speaker 1: and if you've made xcom And all that, you know all that people made the guy a person made mule all that stuff.
Speaker 0: I think you meant quest for glory.
Speaker 1: All right quest for glory right?
Speaker 0: I was like hero quest hero quest.
Speaker 0: All right That's the board game.
Speaker 1: No, no, not hero quest quest for glory or police quest all that stuff all that stuff.
Speaker 1: You had all these people making really interesting games of the PC because you can make any PC game you want it Unlike a Nintendo or an Atari game where you couldn't make any game you wanted.
Speaker 1: and then eventually the PC games Just started to fall into these genres, you know, like Warcraft 1 was crazy.
Speaker 1: It was like holy crap an RTS It's insane.
Speaker 1: and then you know, holy crap Wolfenstein an FPS that's insane.
Speaker 1: and then a few genres eventually stuck out from the rest and carried on.
Speaker 1: and All the other really interesting unique PC games were like one hits like yep There's start control - no one could ever make game like that again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or even some genres that used to exist don't exist anymore, where are my free space?
Speaker 0: flight sims?
Speaker 1: I know tell me about it.
Speaker 1: There was a. it was TIE fighter and wing commander x-wing Alliance Yep, and there was free space.
Speaker 1: I think free space - was the last free space fly-around shooting game.
Speaker 0: He's the last good one partly because there's no more joysticks.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's sort of joystick I bought in 1994 was superior to any joystick I've seen in a Best Buy since.
Speaker 1: yeah I think it's sort of a catch-22 where there are no joysticks because there are no flight sims that require joysticks But at the same time there are no flight sims because there are no joysticks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if anyone sees a flight stick pro from back in the day, let me know cuz I got one But I finally broke it.
Speaker 1: I was actually always a fan of the separate it like throttle and joystick combos But there was only one good one of those ever and the modern version of it sucks cuz it's all flimsy.
Speaker 0: God, not only did I convince my dad to shell out 70 bucks for a flight stick Pro But I then opened it up and modded it with much thicker springs.
Speaker 1: It's very important.
Speaker 1: I have a joystick that is difficult to move around.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.