Speaker 1: It's Monday April 16th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we talk a bit in entirely layman's terms about the history of CPUs and the battles between AMD and Intel.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: It.
Speaker 1: uh, it rained a little bit a little a little still raining though, yeah Yeah, you see I was all excited.
Speaker 1: It was summer.
Speaker 1: Everything is beautiful.
Speaker 1: I was climbing the mountain.
Speaker 0: summary.
Speaker 0: It's still spring.
Speaker 1: It's effectively summer.
Speaker 1: remember as far as I'm concerned there are two seasons Warm enough to run outside in shorts and not warm enough to run outside.
Speaker 0: in short yeah rim Just sort of decides things for himself and acts like you know.
Speaker 0: the rest of the world doesn't exist.
Speaker 1: I'm just generally indifferent to spring.
Speaker 1: spring is just in my way to summer and fall is just the last Lingerings of summer.
Speaker 1: so pretty much.
Speaker 0: I'm actually a fan more of real spring.
Speaker 0: I wish real spring would let you be real spring real spring.
Speaker 1: it rains all the time.
Speaker 1: It's muddy Everything's mucky.
Speaker 1: you see all the leaves from the previous autumn that didn't rot yet see a real spring.
Speaker 0: It's not cold, and it's warm, but it's not so warm that you sweat all over the place, which is perfect.
Speaker 0: It's like 65 degrees all the time, but of course we don't have real spring.
Speaker 0: We've got shit.
Speaker 1: I don't know really what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: It's spring.
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 0: when did real spring happen when I was a kid?
Speaker 1: I don't think spring was much different when you were a kid than it is now.
Speaker 0: plus I like rain as long as it's not constant insane or you know like this because this rain sucks where I go down to the train station in the morning and there's water burbling out Of the sewer.
Speaker 1: except this rain really isn't too out of the norm for this area and in fact we had similar rainstorms last year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it sucked then too, and I lived here the year before.
Speaker 1: you know what same kind of rain storms suck then also.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not anything special.
Speaker 1: The interesting thing here is that it took me almost four hours to get to work.
Speaker 0: well I mean I can understand snow making it take four hours to get to work.
Speaker 1: No during that crazy crazy blizzard where everyone was stranded on the highways all over around here and all the parkways were just covered in Snow I got home in an hour and a half.
Speaker 1: I just took the mountain back roads.
Speaker 1: There was no one on him just drove right through, but no a little bit of rain.
Speaker 1: first There's a rock slide on the road I normally take to work the walking like those metal things up to keep the rocks from falling down.
Speaker 0: yes Good job.
Speaker 1: It was one hell of a little mudslide rock slide, and it covered the road.
Speaker 1: so whatever.
Speaker 1: Well I sat there for an hour while they removed it and in that hour every single road to New York City flooded.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was at work And I saw news that said the taconic was flooded and closed at a bunch of places And I tried to tell you but you were not able to be talked to.
Speaker 0: and then I checked the trains And they were like yeah, there's some flooding at the Beacon train station.
Speaker 0: I'm like shit.
Speaker 1: Beacon train station floods once a year, and it's only that back park.
Speaker 0: I was saying I parked in the front parking lot, and I was like oh It's probably only the back parking lot.
Speaker 0: sure enough the back parking lot must have flooded and unflooded during the days.
Speaker 1: I'm the only suckers parking that back parking lot.
Speaker 0: well It's I think the people who parked back there are People who were like been here for a long time because they used to be the only parking lot And it's people with permits.
Speaker 0: So I think the people who have permits and they've had them for a long time are the people who parked back there Which I don't know why you think they'd be smart enough by now to park somewhere else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they closed.
Speaker 0: I think they were pretty smart though because they closed off the most flooded part of the parking lot this morning Because no one was parked there, and there was yellow tape saying don't park you.
Speaker 1: yeah luckily with my works policy I pretty much just left work at the normal time and it counts as a full day, but on the way home I'm driving back, and I think I'm gonna stop and get some ice cream or something.
Speaker 1: But I see this huge crowd of people standing by the old dam the turn of the century Dam with the old mill connected to it on the little creek that goes through Beacon and this giant crowd of people just Looking around.
Speaker 1: a bunch of have cameras.
Speaker 1: So I stopped the car and I get out.
Speaker 1: cuz what they find?
Speaker 1: a body.
Speaker 1: what's going on?
Speaker 1: I got to see what's going on here And I have to have my camera with me And I hear a roar and I look and the creek has become a torrential Horrible river that is completely covered and is blasting across this dam an incredible velocity of volume.
Speaker 0: You just seen out the window of the train because the train is basically in between the Hudson River and the land And all the water coming down the sides of the land into the river.
Speaker 0: There was quite a lot of it especially when the train went like by some rocks.
Speaker 0: They're just water like flying off the rocks And there was like whitewater rapids only very small ones so only mice and their little boats could go and have fun.
Speaker 0: but They were like maybe like three feet wide, but they were rushing down that mountain real quick.
Speaker 0: It's pretty fun.
Speaker 1: Anyway in tech news I was nominally gonna talk about this idea that Firefox looks like it's reaching the 25% mark in Europe And it's almost at 50% in a bunch of countries like Finland.
Speaker 1: But I've got something much more important here because I'm slashed out.
Speaker 1: there was some stupid article Entitled is Dvorak gaining traction among coders?
Speaker 1: the answer is no.
Speaker 0: well when I was in college there were nominally You know those Dvorak guys.
Speaker 0: I know some of them, so I do one Steve.
Speaker 0: well some of them were good guys.
Speaker 0: Some of them are bad guys But you know there were always a few guys in the code especially in the CS department was pretty is the only place to find These people and they were like yeah, Dvorak's the way to go.
Speaker 1: well you see most people's keyboards I don't think a lot of people know what Dvorak is are QWERTY.
Speaker 1: if you wonder why it's called QWERTY look at your keyboard and look at the the second row from the top right under The numbers and it should become apparent rather quickly Why it is called QWERTY?
Speaker 1: Dvorak is called Dvorak for pretty much the same reason.
Speaker 0: no Dvorak is called Dvorak because the guy named Dvorak all right I've never actually seen a Dvorak keyboard.
Speaker 0: all the vowels are generally like right under your fingers And what it the.
Speaker 0: the logic behind a Dvorak layout is that the most commonly used letters are all hit with the mate your Index fingers and then your middle finger and the least used letters are out by the pinkies and things like that.
Speaker 0: so it's Technically.
Speaker 0: you should have to move your fingers the least distance possible to type any Random text.
Speaker 1: well the issue is that while a lot of people say oh Dvorak is more efficient or oh look It's based on science and QWERTY was made to slow down typist back when typewriters used to jam and almost everyone I've ever met who uses Dvorak makes those two arguments well in terms of the latter.
Speaker 1: That's complete horseshit.
Speaker 1: I'll get that out right now.
Speaker 1: QWERTY was designed for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 1: none of them at all had to do with slowing typist down.
Speaker 0: Number one the reason that QWERTY was designed the way it was is that you didn't have to because on a typewriter You know there's you can't have two hammers from the same side come at once.
Speaker 0: So it was to alternate as much as possible while typing.
Speaker 0: that way you could actually go faster.
Speaker 0: And you know what alternating is sort of faster when you type whether you have Mechanical typewriters or not because you're going left right left right left right left right left right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of people claim that oh QWERTY was made to slow people down to Dvorak is faster blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: But it turns out that QWERTY is actually a very very efficient system of typing.
Speaker 0: I mean think about all the different possible ways you could lay out the letters without changing the way the keys are oriented.
Speaker 0: You know just moving the letters around on the existing keys.
Speaker 0: There are like a zillion jajillion ways you could possibly arrange those letters And if you calculated the efficiency of typing and all possible layouts.
Speaker 0: QWERTY is one of the most efficient layouts possible.
Speaker 0: It's nowhere near the bottom.
Speaker 1: now two people say oh There's all these studies saying that Dvorak is X percentage more efficient or X percentage more.
Speaker 1: You can type faster on average and there has never actually been a real Valid scientific study of any merit.
Speaker 1: and almost all those numbers are either made up or based on studies that are Let's say have a dubious and tenuous grasp on science at best.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Dvorak really isn't bad.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not any worse thing.
Speaker 1: now I submit that it is bad and the reason it's bad is that one QWERTY is the standard the world over.
Speaker 1: so Choosing to use Dvorak is basically saying I am going to choose to use a very Rarely used method of inputting data into a computer.
Speaker 1: that will often cause me Difficulty and will also cause difficulty to anyone else who attempts to use my computer.
Speaker 0: Well, that's true.
Speaker 0: However, a lot of people have real easy ways to just switch their keyboard from QWERTY to Dvorak with like the push of a button.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much anyone using Dvorak has a key combination.
Speaker 0: That'll do that.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah in the software, but keyboard still looks wrong.
Speaker 0: That's true But you don't if you see if you're looking at the keyboard you suck anyway, and it doesn't matter Dvorak or QWERTY.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is all the Dvorak people also buy the expensive Dvorak.
Speaker 0: No, I noticed most Dvorak people just use a QWERTY keyboard or a blank keyboard.
Speaker 0: They don't even bother to get it.
Speaker 1: now a lot of the ones I knew at RIT actually bought old IBM keyboards.
Speaker 0: We can switch the keys around When I actually do that and I've only actually seen maybe two keyboards you can actually buy that had the letters laid out.
Speaker 1: In fact a guy in one of my IT remember we had all those key AT keyboards we found And we kept him for a while.
Speaker 1: then we threw him away.
Speaker 1: Someone asked me for one when he found out I had one because he wanted to make a Dvorak keyboard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well most of the people I knew no one ever real actually cared about the letters being laid out that way.
Speaker 0: but even so some people who use the Dvorak they claim they can just switch back to QWERTY like ah and Some people when they actually do.
Speaker 0: I've actually seen them struggle going back to QWERTY.
Speaker 0: So I guess it comes down to are you actually gonna be able to avoid QWERTY?
Speaker 0: If not, can you just switch back and forth or can you not?
Speaker 0: and I imagine some people can and some people can't.
Speaker 1: Yep, especially considering that touch typing is mostly muscle memory and that sort of thing I can't imagine it being efficient to have two entirely different systems that are mostly Instinctual that you have to work with on a regular basis.
Speaker 1: Yeah that the main reason I bring this up is that this seems to come into the news cyclically like every six months or so where All the people who use Dvorak like yeah Dvorak's better blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: And I found that the vast majority of people use Dvorak are twats they just are posers.
Speaker 1: They use it because it's cool and hip to use or check it out.
Speaker 1: I use Dvorak which is far superior to your commoner QWERTY.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only way I can respect someone who uses Dvorak is if they say yeah, I just like it better Whatever because some people just it's a matter of taste.
Speaker 0: It's not you know more or less efficient really.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, and if it is we can't really tell it.
Speaker 0: But for some people it's more comfortable for them.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, the thing is kids I'm not gonna say that they're lying about something like that.
Speaker 1: I've only ever met one person who wasn't just a pretentious twat about it.
Speaker 1: And that was our friend Steve.
Speaker 1: Yep He's seriously the only person I've ever met as far as I know Because there might be some closet Dvorak users out there who actually uses it and isn't pretentious about it.
Speaker 1: And in fact all the people other than Steve who use it always seem to bring it up more often than would be Normally expect expected in a conversation.
Speaker 0: actually You know what the best Dvorak user would be someone who keeps it a secret like before you use that.
Speaker 0: They can have a QWERTY keyboard before you use their keyboard.
Speaker 0: They switch it so you don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would be the best Dvorak user.
Speaker 1: So I guess Dvorak's got to be a lot like religion.
Speaker 0: It sort of is in a way yeah because it's not based on fags.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what do you got?
Speaker 0: So is this big news story going around about how Adobe's putting DRMs and ads or something in flash and a lot of people didn't read the story and don't understand what is actually saying.
Speaker 1: Yep, there was a lot of fun.
Speaker 0: A lot of people are like, oh no is youtubes will be full of ads in DRM.
Speaker 0: It's over and I'm like, uh, dude, what did you.
Speaker 0: did you read?
Speaker 0: Did you even read this article?
Speaker 1: Well, you didn't read nothing for the benefit of all of the people out there.
Speaker 1: What is the actual story here?
Speaker 0: Well Adobe is check this out.
Speaker 0: You got flash right.
Speaker 0: flash does animations and things but there's also flash video Which is what makes it things like YouTube and such possible.
Speaker 0: It's a way to put videos in Flash where you can download them pretty quick and watch them in your browser and everything's happy as long as your browser is flash.
Speaker 1: Don't have to worry about codecs or all the business.
Speaker 1: We used to have to worry about Yep, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: to plug your media player into your browser is an embeddable whatever and then get codecs.
Speaker 0: It's just flash video and if you have flash it plays.
Speaker 0: YouTube uses it everyone use it.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 0: Adobe is gonna add some features to the flash video.
Speaker 0: the features They're gonna add are as follows if you're making a flash video You will be able to make the video in such a way that you can force the person watching it to watch some ads.
Speaker 0: It doesn't mean every flash videos gonna be that way.
Speaker 0: It's just someone making a flash video can choose to put some ads in it or anything else.
Speaker 1: They can show you the meat-spinning goat see for 10 seconds before you get to see your content.
Speaker 0: Imagine they could.
Speaker 0: I imagine people will yep They're also adding a DRM feature.
Speaker 0: However, the DRM feature isn't gonna keep you from watching flash videos in a website.
Speaker 0: That's not what is there for.
Speaker 0: it's there to cover for another feature They're adding which is that you're gonna be able to download flash videos and then play them off your computer without having to be online Or anything.
Speaker 0: so you could go.
Speaker 0: let's say YouTube implemented this feature.
Speaker 0: You could go onto YouTube download a bunch of YouTube videos without having to use all the crazy Firefox plugins or whatever people are using to do it these days Download them and watch them later And if YouTube wants they could make it so that when you download videos from YouTube those videos have some DRM So that you can't go copying them all over the internet, but it's only if YouTube wants.
Speaker 0: basically It's three features added to flash that people who make flash video can choose whether they use or not use and I don't think YouTube's gonna use it considering they're still using the flash 7.
Speaker 1: Yeah, YouTube seems to be doing okay.
Speaker 0: so far I don't know what.
Speaker 0: I don't see Google video using this either.
Speaker 0: the only people I see using this are people who run other flash video sites that already have ads in some way and Media old-school media companies who have videos on their sites like, you know, you go to Comedy Central calm They'll make you watch an ad and maybe if you're lucky They'll let you download something to watch later with a DRM if
Speaker 1: anything.
Speaker 1: I expect
Speaker 0: all your
Speaker 1: friends I expect this to actually make YouTube more used or more popular because YouTube is gonna do it right and most likely either not implement this sort of thing at all or Do it in a tasteful or sparing manner while plays like meta cafe or all those other?
Speaker 1: Wannabe youtubes are probably just gonna go whole hog with the ads.
Speaker 0: I imagine most people go haul hog with the ads.
Speaker 0: Especially the people who you're trying to make a lot of money as opposed to being owned by Google don't need to make money.
Speaker 0: So Yes, that clears that up for everyone.
Speaker 0: I hope there are going to be bad features added to flash video But no one's forcing anyone to use them and it's up to the people who put the videos online whether they use them or not.
Speaker 1: So my suggestion to everyone out there is whenever you see a story particularly on slashdot or Fark or dig.
Speaker 1: in fact the more inflammatory inflammatory or Frightening to you the headline is the more dubious of it You should be in the more you should probably I don't know read the article see what it actually says as opposed to OMG ads onto youtubes.
Speaker 0: Yep, and if you're like me sometimes you read an article that you don't understand.
Speaker 0: Like I'll read an article about some new medicine and I'll say I don't understand the fuck shit this article saying even though I read It and then I ask someone who knows because I don't know.
Speaker 1: granted unlike you people out there We have our resident scientists.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: So if you read an article about something computer II and you don't understand it or you're skeptical and even though you read it You're not sure you're 100% right.
Speaker 0: Don't go saying stuff.
Speaker 0: Ask me first cuz I know Things of the day.
Speaker 1: I hate to take something that's on the front page of dig Especially when it's on the front page of dig the day I do it.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: I'm taking something from big videos.
Speaker 0: It's a lazy day.
Speaker 1: I had to go with this one because again there wasn't much exciting on the internet and to I want to point out This kind of person because this is one of those kinds of people that I really dislike and I run afoul of often.
Speaker 1: See Quentin Tarantino is my man.
Speaker 1: He makes those kinds of movies that I like.
Speaker 0: He hasn't made a movie I don't like.
Speaker 0: not one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't think of a Tarantino movie that I've seen that I did not enjoy sort of like Satoshi khan in a way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, can't go wrong for now.
Speaker 1: One day he'll turn on us.
Speaker 0: if he turns on us.
Speaker 0: I'll just be the end.
Speaker 0: I won't watch movies anymore.
Speaker 0: I'll just watch the same ones over and over.
Speaker 1: just watch snatch and boondock Saints over and over until you die.
Speaker 0: I guess I think about it.
Speaker 0: all the old people like our parents our parents didn't catch on to new music.
Speaker 0: They just listen to music they listen to in the 70s and the 60s over and over again until today And they're still listening to it.
Speaker 0: Why can't I watch the same movies from?
Speaker 0: well?
Speaker 1: I think part of that is that our parents listen to the Beatles and Led Zeppelin and they're still the some of the best.
Speaker 0: You don't see.
Speaker 0: it's not the point.
Speaker 0: you understand what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah But way back after kill bill came out.
Speaker 1: I don't know if this is one or two.
Speaker 1: I just watched this clip and I did not do any research.
Speaker 0: pretty sure they're talking about one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this kind of fugly looking Movie reviewer gets Quentin Tarantino on her show to talk about kill bill now.
Speaker 1: This is that kind of person.
Speaker 1: I just like Lady.
Speaker 1: she's fat and indignant but more importantly she does this exact thing that I have had so many people do to me in my day.
Speaker 1: and While it's infuriating at the same time It's hilarious because whenever someone does this to you and remember take heed Anytime someone acts this way towards you you have already won because what you were saying is making them so uncomfortable That they will still be thinking about it tonight when they try to go to sleep and you'll have already forgotten
Speaker 0: or be laughing.
Speaker 0: Yes, if someone actually brings it up again, you'll be like, oh, that's still around.
Speaker 1: So she gets him on the show and she's nominally talking about kill bill But she obviously has an agenda.
Speaker 1: she obviously is going to corner him about some issue that got crawled off her butt and She's gonna make a stink about it and make him feel bad and make him look bad.
Speaker 1: Luckily Quentin Tarantino is the man.
Speaker 0: So he's a little bit crazy, but doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: He's sitting there and he's like, yeah I made kill bill.
Speaker 1: I like to run a hockey jersey.
Speaker 0: Yes Everything's excused when you're wearing a hockey jersey.
Speaker 1: I was gonna point that out at the end.
Speaker 1: I was like and he was wearing a hockey jersey.
Speaker 1: Yep, but so he's all again kill bills.
Speaker 1: Awesome blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: and then the woman after a little bit of small talk Looks at a piece of paper and looks up and says now, uh, I want to make sure that you weren't misquoted here.
Speaker 1: So could you clarify?
Speaker 1: did you actually say this?
Speaker 0: Twelve year olds should see kill bill and he's like, yeah twelve year old should see it.
Speaker 0: At least the ones with the cool parents.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: that's the kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I would say like yeah, what of it?
Speaker 1: He's like, yeah, if a parent wants to bring their 12 year old kid to see kill bill I say great I grew up watching violent movies.
Speaker 1: I grew up to make violent movies.
Speaker 1: I never heard anybody.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of fun.
Speaker 0: It's entertaining.
Speaker 0: It's not the real world It's the fake world.
Speaker 1: the woman thinks that she has won the argument and she gives that look of.
Speaker 1: haha You have fallen into my clever trap.
Speaker 1: watch as I humiliate you before the masses.
Speaker 1: For she thinks that now that he's admitted that yes He thinks 12 year olds should watch kill bill that somehow he is admitted something wrong or that somehow she is now won this argument And it couldn't be further from the truth because she gets all indignant.
Speaker 1: And so you're saying that kids should watch violent movies and she expected him to go.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe yeah, but instead he goes.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: What you gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: And she starts getting really really really indignant and she does that thing where she sits back Folds her arms and does that smile of.
Speaker 1: I already won this argument.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna sit here and let you talk But I'm ignoring everything you say.
Speaker 1: cuz I know that the people are on my side and the deep down in my bitter little heart I'm right and these doubts I'm feeling don't exist and you're not making me uncomfortable You're not touching a sore spot.
Speaker 1: Please stop talking.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, she's a fat indignant lady and Quentin Tarantino is as she even admits a really rich Famous movie guy wearing a hockey jersey.
Speaker 0: and we people like him and they don't like her.
Speaker 1: So the next time you see people like this remember this video and remember that the moment someone gets that way You've already won far and away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all you can do because you're never gonna like beat them to where they'll be like.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're right.
Speaker 0: That's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: All you can do is make them as in comfort as uncomfortable as humanly possible.
Speaker 1: And the funny thing is maybe they'll explode which is the best outcome because this happens all the time.
Speaker 1: Remember back with that Frank Zappa thing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, where the guys like are you saying that blah blah blah blah blah and zap is like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah That's exactly what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: You were correct.
Speaker 1: That is my stance.
Speaker 1: What of it?
Speaker 1: and that always takes the thunder out of anyone who's trying to argue with you?
Speaker 0: Well generally that happens when people have a stance That other people like like.
Speaker 0: they view the stance itself as inherently wrong And there's no evidence on the outside of it.
Speaker 0: It's like they look at the stance itself.
Speaker 0: Like this lady says children shouldn't be watching violent movies and she does this.
Speaker 0: she doesn't have any evidence either way But she takes that statement in and of itself to be a wrong thing as if I had said the sky was green.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 1: so this isn't a contest for a prize or anything.
Speaker 1: But uh, you all your listeners out there.
Speaker 1: that is in fact a fairly specific logical fallacy And I'd like to see who posted in the forum.
Speaker 0: Let's see logical fallacy of no evidence.
Speaker 1: No No, there's a logical fallacy of taking an unfounded statement or taking what would be an argument Making it as a statement and then using that as the basis for further argumentation.
Speaker 0: That's not quite what this is.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it is her statement.
Speaker 1: She's taking as truth.
Speaker 1: She's not saying if blah blah blah then blah.
Speaker 1: She's saying blah blah blah unfounded assertion.
Speaker 1: Therefore you're wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I Saw this cool thing on dig video today.
Speaker 0: You remember back at RIT There was always those guys who were really into juggling and really into unicycling.
Speaker 1: Yep, there was a lot of overlap in those two clubs.
Speaker 0: There was there was a juggling club and I don't know if it was unicycling club But there were some guys who were just geeks total geeks for juggling and total geeks for you.
Speaker 1: actually as far as I recall I forget if it was the Unicycling club and there was a club or the juggling club, but in terms of the sizes of clubs at RIT It was pretty much the anime club was the biggest.
Speaker 1: the gaming club was the second biggest right there.
Speaker 1: It was like the juggling club.
Speaker 0: Well, no, there was the formula SAE guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah Formula SAE is a special case.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz all the people who raced cars at RIT.
Speaker 1: a lot of people joined because they wanted to race the cars But Scott and I were smart and Scott was the one who asked.
Speaker 1: so what are the chances that I will ever?
Speaker 0: that's the thing.
Speaker 0: When I went to RIT, you know Well, I didn't go there for the race car thing because it was mostly an engineering building a car thing Which has nothing to do with computer science not much anyway So but I knew it was there and I said, you know what if I don't bother to ask It's not gonna happen?
Speaker 0: and if it doesn't happen, I don't care because I wasn't expecting it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I went when I was a freshman and I knew they had this program of formula SAE and I said Is there a chance I will ever race that car?
Speaker 0: because it's the only thing I want to do.
Speaker 0: I don't know shit about engineering.
Speaker 0: I don't know shit about cars.
Speaker 0: I want to race the car because I know a lot about driving and it's fun.
Speaker 0: and they said no There is no chance you will ever drive this car freshman and I said, thank you.
Speaker 1: Goodbye.
Speaker 1: Yep You'll never see me again, but a lot of the people who join the club heads these aspirations.
Speaker 1: They would somehow get to drive the car and I know for a fact that a very small percentage of people in that club Ever got to even sit in that seat.
Speaker 0: Yep, very few people actually drive that car.
Speaker 0: I've seen it driving around.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty fast.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, cuz I'd always for club crap on the weekends.
Speaker 1: I'd go over to campus on like Sunday morning when no one's there and then I walk off a parking lot.
Speaker 1: They put cones out Yeah, and they just be racing it around doing times.
Speaker 1: Fitz Hudson with it put different tires on.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, never got to race that car.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there were unicycling guys at RIT.
Speaker 0: They unicycle to class the unicycle around when it was like spring And everyone was hanging out outside.
Speaker 0: They were unicycle tricks in the quarter mile.
Speaker 1: It was not an uncommon sight to be walking to class and to be passed by someone who was also going to class and has A backpack on but who was on a unicycle and juggling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they're not doing it like for entertainment like they're trying to entertain you.
Speaker 0: They're just unicycling the class just as normally.
Speaker 0: as someone who's like the class
Speaker 1: I just realize
Speaker 0: the class
Speaker 1: thinking back and looking at the things I saw on a daily basis Just walk into class at RIT or looking out my window of my apartment Really make RIT look like this kind of bedlam carnaval Weird place where weird things happen.
Speaker 0: So I was a great place to live it was.
Speaker 0: but Those guys I realize now we're shitty unicycling.
Speaker 0: They sucked at unicycling.
Speaker 0: I mean in terms of transportation They were better unicycling than say me who can't stand up on a unicycle at all.
Speaker 1: But I didn't end up for about four seconds.
Speaker 0: I I unicycled for about like five feet once.
Speaker 0: but they were not so good at the unicycling tricks.
Speaker 0: You mean they can maybe spin around on the unicycle a couple times.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't say that they suck because even if you can't do a unicycle trick being able to unicycle for any Reasonable distance is a pretty cool feat.
Speaker 0: in my opinion that that is the case.
Speaker 0: They're definitely have the unicycling skills, but on the grand scale of unicycling skills.
Speaker 0: They were in the you know amateur rank and file of unicyclers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even the best of it's the difference between in D&D a level one character and level zero character.
Speaker 0: It's a difference between the kid in your high school who's really good at baseball and the major league stars?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you're looking for the major league stars of unicycling.
Speaker 0: Where do you go?
Speaker 1: Well, I think Michael Godot the circus.
Speaker 0: No, no, I'm pretty sure the answer is China.
Speaker 0: cuz it looks Chinese to me I can't tell don't yell at me if I'm wrong and it's some other Asian country.
Speaker 0: But here is a woman who I think is a Chinese woman Unicycling better than I've seen anyone unicycle before and she's doing a lot of fancy stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean she falls off twice, but I can't tell if it's on purpose or not.
Speaker 0: So she wins.
Speaker 0: watch this video and you will see possibly the world's best unicycling or close to it.
Speaker 1: I was actually doing my taxes this time, but I looked up for a few seconds near the end and I was duly impressed.
Speaker 0: It's some crazy-ass unicycling going on.
Speaker 1: So this should be short and sweet because it's coming on to computer buying season here at geek nights And Scott and I are both looking at buying new computers.
Speaker 0: I'm looking a little later than rim, but that's alright.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you're starting the process because in my whole life and Scott's been mostly the same way I don't constantly keep abreast of exactly what is going on in like down-low Processor technology.
Speaker 1: is this processor faster than this one?
Speaker 1: What motherboard chipset is currently the best one?
Speaker 1: what's going on with motherboards?
Speaker 0: There are some people, you know, they subscribe to maximum PC and they read Tom's hardware.
Speaker 1: Maximum PC was a great magazine in like 1997.
Speaker 0: you know, there are those guys and they pay attention to overclocking and every time a new chip and a new video card or A new anything comes out.
Speaker 0: They're on top of it.
Speaker 0: They know Every single change in computer personal computer technology and they're always on top and they're always in the in the lead.
Speaker 0: now I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't have time for that either.
Speaker 0: So I only really pay attention when I need to build a computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's time to build a computer again.
Speaker 0: I go and I look and maybe if like a six months has gone by and I haven't looked I'll take a look just to see What's going on, you know go a new egg.
Speaker 0: I'll put a computer together.
Speaker 1: see, you know, what new technologies there are and like we'll know Intel's making new chips or AMD has a new process.
Speaker 1: all the news, but we won't we won't remember.
Speaker 1: Well, there's actually two different cores on the new Intel block chip One of which has four megabytes of level 2 cache and what it will.
Speaker 0: sometimes this bites me in the ass because like they switched The ATX motherboard connectors to have four more pins to your credit.
Speaker 1: They hadn't changed that in a long time I know.
Speaker 0: how would I think that was gonna change?
Speaker 1: But anyway I remember when there was a sudden unexpected jump in the wattage required from a power supply to boot a modern motherboard.
Speaker 0: Yep, that bit us again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seems to be power supplies to bite you because they have the least news anyway.
Speaker 1: But the only time it ever bit us was when we weren't looking for a computer.
Speaker 1: because whenever it gets to that time You know that time in a young man's life when he starts to notice the micro processors and realize that perhaps he needs a bigger one.
Speaker 1: Yes, perhaps a faster one perhaps one that does not overheat perhaps one that is bigger and faster than his friend.
Speaker 1: And Generally what I do and I know a lot of people you can measure up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically Three to four months before like, you know, I'm gonna be building a computer sometime in the spring.
Speaker 1: So months before you start researching a little bit you start looking at Tom's Hardware You look at the most recent benchmark.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: We just got bought for a lot of money.
Speaker 1: We didn't talk about that did we?
Speaker 0: it's not really that important.
Speaker 1: no, I didn't even pay attention to who bought it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, me either watch.
Speaker 1: It's like Intel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but millions of dollars say go Yeah, yeah, Tom's run a pretty good generally reliable site for a long time and I've often relied on his benchmarks.
Speaker 1: Yep, granted benchmarks aren't what they used to be, but that's a whole other show.
Speaker 1: Benchmarks used to work.
Speaker 1: if you look into benchmarks It was like that chip is clearly 40% faster than that chip nowadays.
Speaker 0: Not so much now.
Speaker 1: It's too complicated, but we're not gonna talk.
Speaker 1: I mean we've talked about how to build a computer before but in terms of Processors just processors and I guess as an extension of that Motherboards and motherboard chipsets only because they're directly related to process sockets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and all that stuff We're gonna do because these layman's terms computer shows have been really popular.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about Microprocessors for consumers in layman's terms from the perspective of the consumer of these goods.
Speaker 1: So people like us and people like you who build your own computers Through the years what the market has been like and how it's evolved because it's actually kind of an interesting story.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna talk about like, you know the history behind them.
Speaker 0: Like what was going on at the companies.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna talk about the specific technologies that were added or how they work.
Speaker 0: Yeah We're not gonna talk about Risk or say now or any of those complicated processor things that you don't need to know.
Speaker 0: we're gonna talk about what it was Like to be someone building computers in the years Like the late 90s through the current day So the past decade what it's been like as a nerd building computers in terms of processors
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: and how it's changed
Speaker 1: because I mean brief brief brief history of the time up till that 386 486. you just bought a computer.
Speaker 1: They were all the same.
Speaker 0: You bought a computer and well if you were building you weren't buying a Mac.
Speaker 0: you were buying an IBM and the first IBM that You would buy.
Speaker 0: the first chip that was in the IBM PCs You know was the 8086 and they just kept making it better.
Speaker 0: they came with the 286 and the 386 and the 486 Yep.
Speaker 1: Now they're all 86 long story short.
Speaker 1: They're all based on the same original core set of instructions.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna get into exactly what that that's a whole nother show.
Speaker 1: but every chip every generation beyond that has been mostly to put it simply an Extension upon that instruction set or some sort of modification to it But for the most part retaining backwards compatibility.
Speaker 0: Yep, so a program written for a 386 will run on your current chip Which in all likelihood is a 686 if you have a computer that's modern, of course They've added instructions instead of going to 786 or 886 or anything like that.
Speaker 0: the way they've added instructions They these days is to add things like MMX or 3d now or mx2 or SSE.
Speaker 0: That's how they add instruction.
Speaker 1: Yes now again super oversimplifying.
Speaker 1: It's a really cool interesting thing that we'll talk about some other day.
Speaker 1: Yes, yes But right after the 486 era that was pretty much as far as we were concerned.
Speaker 1: as far as geeks like us That was about the point when it became feasible and in fact cost-effective to build your own computer Instead of buying just a computer that came with a chip.
Speaker 0: It also became the time where your chip actually sort of mattered like.
Speaker 0: up until then you just got the highest number at 86.
Speaker 0: I mean, no one said oh look I have a better 386 than you do It was.
Speaker 0: there was so few choices.
Speaker 0: It was like a 386 66 or a 486 a hundred And pretty much like once.
Speaker 1: the 486 came out and became reasonably priced.
Speaker 1: You didn't buy 386.
Speaker 1: They just disappeared.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when a 386 came out 286 has just disappeared.
Speaker 1: and the 486. it was so clear What was faster the 486?
Speaker 1: Sx2 was slower than the 486 sx4.
Speaker 0: I had the 486 DX for it was a hundred megahertz.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: Yep, and DX was just better than SX for it had to do with God, I can't get into that.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Everything changed when Intel came out with the Pentium one at I think it was at 60 megahertz or 75.
Speaker 1: I don't even remember because I still had a 486 sx2.
Speaker 0: I still had a 486 DX for because it was still better than some of the earliest Pentium ones.
Speaker 0: But when the Pentium one came out, it was a big deal.
Speaker 0: people actually started paying attention to chips.
Speaker 0: They were like, oh the megahertz matter now because that's what Intel advertised with the Pentium one because before then it was just by 486 or a 386.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the store man might explain DX is faster, but cost a lot more money.
Speaker 1: SX is slower But you won't notice the difference.
Speaker 0: hence I bought an SX because I was when the Pentium one came out is when they started saying hey This is X megahertz.
Speaker 1: You see before then better people didn't know what megahertz were there.
Speaker 1: No one would say what's your clock speed except super nerds?
Speaker 0: Super nerds, there was no overclocking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people just didn't.
Speaker 1: well there was.
Speaker 1: there was overclocking that the company.
Speaker 0: let you do The turbo buttons on the case.
Speaker 1: Oh god the turbo button the turbo buttons.
Speaker 1: All right, I could do a whole show on the turbo.
Speaker 1: Yeah computers used to have a button called turbo and that's all I'm gonna say.
Speaker 1: so pretty much always left it pushed in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it even actually worked it wasn't just for show.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I un-pushed it once and it immediately crashed.
Speaker 1: But even then now the only metric you had to go on was megahertz and again it was a direct relationship.
Speaker 1: the more megahertz the faster your chip was.
Speaker 1: and Also, there was really only one company making chips and that was Intel.
Speaker 0: Yep You would get an Intel Pentium chip as soon as the Intel beat out the plain old for I mean Intel made a lot of The 486 is - but as soon as the Pentiums were out, you're pretty much Pentium was released in 1993.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they sort of had a monopoly.
Speaker 0: it was like which Pentium chip are you gonna get?
Speaker 0: you didn't have much of a choice.
Speaker 0: I mean you could get a Cyrix like, you know 586 but it was basically just crap for any.
Speaker 0: you would only get it if you were super nerdy or Poor or I don't know but everyone just got a Pentium chip.
Speaker 0: That was it.
Speaker 1: Pentium was the way Yep, and while there were other chips available like the k5 you see we're AMD and we're talking.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be Intel and AMD and kind of the evolution here.
Speaker 1: back then while AMD existed and in fact AMD had made 386's 46 all that stuff as far as consumers were concerned.
Speaker 1: They didn't exist.
Speaker 1: No one had a k5.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't even know what a k5 was.
Speaker 0: and the k6 came.
Speaker 0: I had never heard of AMD until the k6 - yeah me either and somehow there was a k1 through k5 K61.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's actually a really interesting story about how AMD which is advanced micro devices Came to be and how they competed with Intel how they constantly sued Intel for antitrust and how they won in a bunch of places like Japan and
Speaker 0: how now somehow against this seeming Monopoly of desktop PC processors at least in the United States where we lived by Intel and their Pentium chip.
Speaker 0: AMD did really well and is still doing relatively well.
Speaker 0: So and of amazing.
Speaker 1: but even that back then if you built a computer yourself, you got an Intel Pentium Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It wasn't until the mid and late 90s like the middling late 90s that Building computers became more than just buy the chip you can afford put it in a motherboard you can afford.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean in 1999, I think I built the Pentium 3 450.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had a Pentium 200 and then right before I went to RIT.
Speaker 1: I built a k7 system.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the Pentium one was the hot shit when it was out, but it just basically kept trucking on.
Speaker 0: It was the Pentium 2 was just more and better.
Speaker 0: They added MMX.
Speaker 0: It was just more and better.
Speaker 0: you had to you know.
Speaker 0: Now the chips just kept getting crazy faster crazy faster and your only choice was the newest best Pentium.
Speaker 0: I mean by the time the Pentium 3 was out.
Speaker 0: when I bought that 450 the choices are basically Pentium 3 350 Pentium 3 450 Pentium 3 500. that was the choice.
Speaker 1: So in AMD released the k6 which had somewhat comparable performance to the to the Pentium chips that would have been put at the same level and they weren't as fast as Pentium chips.
Speaker 1: I mean while I say similar performance, they were definitely nowhere near as fast as Pentium chips.
Speaker 1: However, they were Substantially cheaper.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean it wasn't as fast But for a lot less money.
Speaker 0: if you were building the computer because no one sold a computer with a k6 in it forget About that.
Speaker 0: you could get a computer working that could do some stuff For a lot less money and you wouldn't have to buy a Pentium chip.
Speaker 1: and I knew a few people.
Speaker 1: I started to read.
Speaker 1: People were using these k6.
Speaker 1: is the k6 to the case?
Speaker 0: I didn't really pay attention to them until when I bought my computer in 99 and you know I got.
Speaker 0: I subscribed a computer shopper for a year.
Speaker 0: we could do a whole episode of computer shop God, but it had.
Speaker 0: it's a big.
Speaker 0: it used to be this big phone book.
Speaker 0: It's a magazine that still exists now as an old magazine, but a computer shopper used to be this inch thick gigantic thing.
Speaker 0: that cost like a dollar two dollars and It would have basically half of it was article not even half of it like 20 pages as articles and the rest was ads for computer stuff because you didn't have Newegg to go to.
Speaker 0: so you'd go in there and some people were advertising the k6 - and the k6 - was Almost as good as the Pentium threes of the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yep while they weren't as fast They were definitely budget processors and they had some problems.
Speaker 1: I'd had a lot of people who'd used them.
Speaker 1: they had problems overheating or compatibility occasionally.
Speaker 1: Sometimes the motherboards weren't so great.
Speaker 1: There were all sorts of issues with them, but in terms of dollars per unit performance They beat Intel by some stupid amount.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the k6 - you know, it wasn't stupidly popular anything but a lot of people actually bought it.
Speaker 0: and there I kept seeing more and more ads for it and Someone must have been buying these things Me because I was still using my Pentium three because you could build a computer that was almost as fast as an equivalent Pentium computer For hundreds and hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 1: less money dollars less money.
Speaker 1: That was a wonderful construction.
Speaker 0: I mean I paid like hundreds of dollars to that Pentium three in the k6 - was like a hundred.
Speaker 1: and god I paid some stupid amount of money for that Pentium 200.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Pentium - 200 so Athlon k7.
Speaker 1: This is the error that a lot of people are familiar with because this is when there was actually a choice.
Speaker 1: in fact, this is when the industry really got turned upside down and AMD started doing better than in town.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically what happened?
Speaker 0: I remember the summer before.
Speaker 0: all right Was it the summer before?
Speaker 0: it was when I went to RIT for college and careers.
Speaker 0: the first time I went to RIT I wasn't a student.
Speaker 0: It was August 1999.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about being a student and the my roommate of two days.
Speaker 0: I forget who the guy was who?
Speaker 0: just some guy but he liked computers.
Speaker 0: and we talked about computers.
Speaker 0: and he was talking about the K7 which was the Athlon the first Athlon and how all indicators showed that it was probably going to be badass and Not suck like the k62 sucked and it still be cheaper than the Pentium 3 of the time.
Speaker 1: in fact, then all the compatibility issues were gone.
Speaker 1: the chip was just a badass chip and For the same performance.
Speaker 1: take an Intel chip and the AMD chip that perform Identically.
Speaker 1: the AMD chip was so much less money that only an idiot would have bought the Intel chip.
Speaker 1: There was absolutely no reason for someone building in their own computer back then to buy an Intel chip And this was a complete reversal from the way computers had been forever before.
Speaker 0: that I mean the Athlon was coming and it was hyped up.
Speaker 0: and you know A lot of people didn't believe the hype.
Speaker 0: and then it came and the people who believe the hype bought it.
Speaker 0: And then of course, it was the real deal and it just caught on and kept catching on.
Speaker 1: one year later I built the $4,000 computer using an Athlon K7 800 megahertz processor Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I used that computer up until near the end of our IT where the motherboard exploded.
Speaker 1: I still have the chip and the chip is still fine.
Speaker 1: The motherboard exploded.
Speaker 1: I had to buy a replacement motherboard.
Speaker 1: They didn't sell motherboards that took that chip.
Speaker 0: So I Explain why.
Speaker 1: yes.
Speaker 1: Well, you see chips for the longest time took sockets.
Speaker 0: Well, they went into sockets.
Speaker 0: You know you look at a motherboard and there's the part where the the processor goes.
Speaker 0: now It's a little flat thing and it's sort of a square with a square in the middle and you the chip has a bunch of Pins on the bottom of it and you drop it in and you pull the lever and your chip is now in the motherboard.
Speaker 1: Chips were like that from the dawn of time up until this one little stint and then they went back to that pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the way chips are now.
Speaker 0: That's the way they used to be but in this one period of time the Pentium threes and the original Athlons They went into slots.
Speaker 0: It looked a lot.
Speaker 0: the place where your chip went looked like a PCI slot.
Speaker 0: only your chip went in there and your chip was on this board and the board was surrounded by plastic.
Speaker 0: and that piece of plastic went into this Thing.
Speaker 0: that looked like a PCI slot and it was called for an Athlon It was slot a and for a Pentium it was slot one.
Speaker 1: Yep, and they were mostly identical.
Speaker 1: However, they were not compatible at all.
Speaker 0: No, you couldn't put a slot a chip in a slot one motherboard.
Speaker 1: now there was also slot two and slot B. slot two was for server special chips from Intel and slot B was nominally for server chips from AMD, but What we're talking about?
Speaker 1: the consumer side?
Speaker 1: suffice to say industry.
Speaker 1: people Ignored AMD up until very very recent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much because Intel had a separate line of chips the Xeon which they still have now back there is server ring.
Speaker 0: That's what you bought back.
Speaker 1: Then a Xeon chip was Amazingly Incredibly faster than anything else on the mark also incredibly amazingly expensive.
Speaker 1: They were thousands of dollars.
Speaker 0: The main reason the Xeon was and still is really stupidly powerful is because it has so much cash on the chip.
Speaker 0: It had megabytes of cash on the chip.
Speaker 1: This is back in the days when having like 256 K of a tiny little cash was huge Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Now the reason they moved to this slot design was twofold.
Speaker 1: one It was thought that you could cool chips better because chips were getting really really hot around this time.
Speaker 1: This is when chips there was this huge cuz.
Speaker 1: remember right around the Pentium 400 450 500 550 megahertz times there was this long plateau where chips really weren't getting faster and they weren't getting cheaper either and everything just kind of Stagnated for a while.
Speaker 1: and then suddenly there was this rush with the k7 700 800 megahertz a gigahertz.
Speaker 0: Well, the Pentium 3 got up to that fast also, but yeah, it did but the AMD actually got there first.
Speaker 1: Yep, but they started getting really hot as a result.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: This is also when people started overclocking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people had a Pentium 3 500 and someone else had something else 800.
Speaker 0: They said I can get this up to 800 and they could.
Speaker 0: they could get the motherboard to go from 100 megahertz to 133.
Speaker 0: They could up the multiplier by one and people were trying to get more and more out of their chips And thus they were get started.
Speaker 0: This is where all the people started getting crazy cooling devices and water cooling and this is the era where all those things began.
Speaker 1: Everywhere overclock because back then you got substantial performance increase.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I overclocked that Pentium 3.
Speaker 0: I basically upped it by one bit one bit one bit one bit at a time until it crashed and then I went back down One bit and I was able to make that computer last a lot longer than it would have lasted Otherwise, yes,
Speaker 1: I overclocked my 800 megahertz pretty much at to the limit I could overclock it without losing stability.
Speaker 0: It helped that at the time I was using the a bit bx6 r2 motherboards days one of the most stable motherboard ever Regardless if now it's too slow to do anything.
Speaker 0: But the Intel BX motherboard chipset is the greatest motherboard chipset to ever exist.
Speaker 0: You could do anything to it and it would just keep working.
Speaker 0: It still works now.
Speaker 0: I've still got it.
Speaker 0: I'm never getting rid of that thing.
Speaker 0: I think I still got it.
Speaker 1: but Remember we talked about how suddenly megahertz became the issue.
Speaker 1: way back people realized that oh the higher that number is the faster the chip is.
Speaker 1: well AMD and Intel kind of got into this megahertz race where they were both tracked kind of fighting to see who got to Gigahertz first and also to try to win the public over with.
Speaker 1: look our chips are faster.
Speaker 1: No, look our chips are faster Mm-hmm, and this is pretty much as a result of this.
Speaker 1: They weren't streamlining things.
Speaker 1: They weren't worried about power.
Speaker 1: They're worried about speed raw Unbridled speed.
Speaker 1: so chips got hotter and hotter and hotter and use more and more.
Speaker 1: power needed more and more cooling.
Speaker 1: You could put cooling on both sides with these slots also, and this is probably the more important reason.
Speaker 1: This is when RAM and registers started getting a lot cheaper.
Speaker 1: like there was this huge dropout in the RAM market around this time and Suddenly it went from having some little amount of RAM to you Just buy as much RAM as your motherboard could take and it was so cheap.
Speaker 1: You didn't even care.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think it's because the RAM speeds didn't really go up.
Speaker 0: I know is PC 100 and PC 133 for the longest time and DDR wasn't there yet and People had just they.
Speaker 0: you know They had not changed the RAM technology and so long so long like a year so that they had just met Factories churning this stuff out like crazy and the price went down.
Speaker 1: RAM was dirt cheap.
Speaker 1: In fact, I had.
Speaker 1: we have like four gigabytes worth of that old RAM just like a lot of PC 100 and PC 133 RAM.
Speaker 0: I don't know what sticks work and which ones don't.
Speaker 1: I have a full two gigs from my old computer because when I got the New motherboard to replace the busted one I had to get a DDR motherboard because they didn't make motherboards.
Speaker 1: that took the old stuff and took the chip I wanted.
Speaker 1: so I had all this RAM laid around by all new RAM, but because this was cheaper They started putting a lot more cash on processors.
Speaker 1: And in fact, they had level 1 level 2 and in many cases level 3 caches.
Speaker 1: not gonna get it 486.
Speaker 0: the the l2 cache was little chips 128 K little bug ships you would put in the motherboard.
Speaker 0: Yep I was crazy.
Speaker 1: They started putting these extra caches on boards that were connected that were in this slot thing.
Speaker 1: There wouldn't be room in a socket.
Speaker 1: Inside of that plastic slot was a little board that had a bunch of caches on it and all sorts of circuitry.
Speaker 1: now technology marched on and Very rapidly.
Speaker 1: it became more cost-effective more feasible and better to just put that RAM Right on the die or near the die and you didn't have to bother with these boards anymore and slots just disappeared.
Speaker 1: They'll probably never come back.
Speaker 0: No, I think the slot is pretty much dead.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much sockets forever.
Speaker 1: Yep In fact, I bought one slot and by the time my computer died There were no more slots and I had to buy a socket.
Speaker 0: That's the same way It was for me.
Speaker 1: Now people sold these things where you could connect a slot into a socket and those things never fucking.
Speaker 0: people also sold things Sockets into slots.
Speaker 0: those didn't work either but they were just stupid and Unnecessary because a motherboard was cheap.
Speaker 1: now This was the last time I paid attention because back then it was just duh by the highest megahertz AMD k7 that you can afford the bed like you.
Speaker 1: try to get the optimal performance price ratio and that was it.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what happened next was you sort of had the Athlon and the Pentium 4 and they just kept fighting each other For years and years and years getting faster and faster with not much changing.
Speaker 0: I mean the Pentium 4 added the hyper threading which is just bullshit.
Speaker 0: It didn't really help you that much.
Speaker 0: The Athlon just kept getting faster and faster.
Speaker 0: They add you know The Pentium would add a feature like SSE and then the Athlon would add the 3d.
Speaker 1: now now This is what I find really interesting.
Speaker 1: for the longest time AMD chips had the percent there's the perception that they weren't as elegant or efficient.
Speaker 1: They were just raw power and a lot faster while and they just plugged through.
Speaker 1: well Intel's were slower But more elegant and as a result were much more powerful.
Speaker 1: and this really started coming to play with the Pentium 4 era When suddenly it got reversed and the Pentium 4's were just higher megahertz higher megahertz but the AMD's got equivalent performance with less megahertz and AMD actually started naming their chips no longer based on megahertz but based on the number that they made up.
Speaker 1: It was like the equivalent clock speed.
Speaker 0: like for example, my chip and my computer right now is an Athlon XP 2500. supposedly that means according to AMD at least in their marketing that that is roughly equivalent in speed to a 2.5 gigahertz Pentium 4 as where it's actually only a 1.8 gigahertz chip.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they never said that straight up to not get in trouble.
Speaker 0: But that's heavily.
Speaker 0: that's what they meant.
Speaker 0: That's the reason they did it?
Speaker 0: because they didn't want people to think hey this AMD is 1.8 Gigahertz and this Pentium 4 is 2.5 gigahertz.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and in reality, okay, if you do the math The Athlon was actually a faster chip.
Speaker 0: So putting the lower number on it is bad for marketing because people think it's slower who were stupid when it's actually faster.
Speaker 1: See the chip companies have put so much marketing power into getting people to understand Megahertz equals speed that suddenly this was no longer the case.
Speaker 0: Well, no longer the case for Intel across different chips.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know when they when they did when Intel originally had that marketing It was so people would know that the higher megahertz Pentiums that cost more were better than the lower.
Speaker 0: her better It's Pentiums.
Speaker 1: and then it was true.
Speaker 1: because they were the same chip just one was faster And he took advantage of that by making chips that were higher megahertz than Intel and then winning out in terms of the geek market.
Speaker 0: Yep, it didn't help that the general architecture of the Pentium 4 was black.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Pentium 4 suffice to say was not a terribly great leap.
Speaker 1: Yes in performance or power.
Speaker 0: so that era is now ended in the past year or so.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think for most of the time that people who I guess listen to five last like three or four years built computers Like that golden era of building computers from back in our young days.
Speaker 0: AMD was like 2001 through 2005.
Speaker 1: AMD was the undisputed king of building your own PC.
Speaker 1: There was no reason to get an Intel chip.
Speaker 0: well people got Intel chips.
Speaker 0: if they bought a pre-built computer like a Dell yeah couldn't.
Speaker 0: sometimes you can get an AMD but not often.
Speaker 0: and Some people got an Intel because it is true.
Speaker 0: Remember that demo video we watched.
Speaker 0: It's absolutely true.
Speaker 0: If you had an Intel chip and you took the heatsink off right it would just Stop working and then you put the heatsink back on.
Speaker 0: it would start working again.
Speaker 1: If you took the heatsink off an AMD, it would just set on fire.
Speaker 1: literally literally it would catch fire.
Speaker 0: Smoke would just come out.
Speaker 1: In fact, if you bumped your heatsink somehow while you're using an AMD and it was at all loaded the processor in terms of use Your processor would be broken and irreparably destroyed within seconds.
Speaker 0: There's a famous video that we the one I'm just talking about where they were playing Quake 3 on a Pentium 4.
Speaker 0: They take the heatsink off.
Speaker 0: Quake 3 slows down to zero FPS.
Speaker 0: They put the heatsink back on while the computer's running and Quake 3 jumps back up to full FPS.
Speaker 0: They do the same thing to the AMD windows crashes.
Speaker 0: The screen goes blank and the chip sets on fire.
Speaker 0: So the Pentium 4 while being less efficient costing more money Not being quite as fast as the AMD per dollar spent generally a bad purchasing decision when building a computer did have some advantages in some areas such as like power consumption and Not setting on fire when you take the heatsink off
Speaker 1: because you see the brief history of these two companies.
Speaker 1: Is that?
Speaker 1: AMD was the underdog crap little company that kind of pulled through and made chips as best it could and They generally didn't have a lot of R&D money and they had to use other relatively less.
Speaker 1: They're making lots of money Yeah, but for an up until the k7 days They didn't make a lot of money and they didn't have a lot of money to invest into R&D and any investment They made was a huge risk.
Speaker 1: Intel meanwhile was the world powerhouse Monopoly of chip making.
Speaker 1: yeah Intel had more money to put into R&D than AMD and all the Intel Competitors can.
Speaker 0: it's why it was so amazing that when AMD came up in the first place as actually seriously competing.
Speaker 0: It was so amazing.
Speaker 0: It would be like if some other operating system came up and seriously competed with Windows and actually beat it for a time.
Speaker 0: I mean as opposed to just you know, Mac and Linux which are still while they have You know market presence in terms of visual.
Speaker 0: this there's still.
Speaker 1: they got nothing in the case seven days At least and it was my perspective too because I didn't know a lot about Intel back then.
Speaker 1: now that I've worked for IBM And I'm older and wiser.
Speaker 1: I know a lot more about this and I see how my My optimism was misguided.
Speaker 1: AMD was beating Intel as far as any geek could see.
Speaker 0: their chips were better and cheaper in terms of geeks building computers Home PCs, etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 1: now even for OEM stuff the chips were better and cheaper and the a lot of people thought that people didn't use AMD and OEMs because it deals with Intel which was partly true.
Speaker 1: Intel has been caught doing Trust-like things many times.
Speaker 1: Intel is not your friends.
Speaker 1: No, not really to put it very But neither is AMD even though they really like to pretend they are yep, but kind of like Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're your friend.
Speaker 1: Give us the money for the Wii.
Speaker 1: games come next week.
Speaker 0: Games come next week year.
Speaker 0: We clean air in Japanese.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes But AMD in terms of I mean you could buy the chips were awesome and stupid.
Speaker 1: awesome But AMD was not a mature company.
Speaker 1: They didn't have this tradition of engineering quality and they didn't have the R&D and they didn't have the massive fabs that they own.
Speaker 1: They couldn't put out enough chips to meet the demand of the OEMs for one and two.
Speaker 1: while we thought that AMD had won the war and Intel wasn't doing well Intel was actually losing money on their Pentium 4s for a while and things weren't looking so great for it.
Speaker 1: They really lose money in the Pentium 4s in terms of R&D versus money made in the early days.
Speaker 0: yeah, well what?
Speaker 0: eventually?
Speaker 0: what ended up happening is Intel has a lot of R&D teams and they had an R&D team in Israel.
Speaker 1: And those guys are real smart because they basically saved Intel from doom Yep, because Intel kind of disappeared from the face of geeks making computers and everyone just ignored him.
Speaker 0: Well, it didn't completely disappear was still there But it just it wasn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't smart.
Speaker 0: now to get like if you looked at the like steam always does that thing where they?
Speaker 0: See what hardware you're running and they do a survey and they show you the results.
Speaker 0: and I remember at the time it was like 60/40 AMD Intel or something like that and AMD usage was going up and going up and going up.
Speaker 1: But these Israeli engineers were very quietly just developing new architectures and new chips.
Speaker 0: yep, they took what is essentially the architecture of the Pentium 3 and they brought it up to speed and they made the core the core solo and the core duo that you're using right now.
Speaker 1: and When those were announced and then when they came out it Really kind of flipped everything back around because these chips are in terms of megahertz a lot slower than AMD chips.
Speaker 0: My work.
Speaker 0: I have this Dell Optiplex something.
Speaker 0: something has a core to duo in it.
Speaker 0: It's it's it's almost as good as it gets.
Speaker 0: each of those two cores are 1.8 gigahertz each the same as my AMD XP 2500 the same exact clock speed.
Speaker 0: Yep yet Comparatively my computer is slow as shit and the thing at work is stupid fast.
Speaker 1: The core twos are Faster in terms of getting work done than the intent in the AMD chips megahertz per megahertz.
Speaker 1: in addition They're a lot cleaner a lot more efficient.
Speaker 1: They use a lot less power.
Speaker 1: They're a lot cooler They're a lot more reliable and the kicker they're not really that much more expensive.
Speaker 0: See they are still more expensive.
Speaker 0: AMD has a line of also.
Speaker 0: You know their AMD has been keeping pace as best they can.
Speaker 0: they have the x2 chips Which are dual core AMD's.
Speaker 0: they came out with all their 64-bit stuff, which is Sort of good sort of bad.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about 64-bit stuff now, but it the AMD is ahead in the 64-bit race Needless to say but it's not that important.
Speaker 0: And they have their FX line, which is the stupid fast AMD's, but those are expensive.
Speaker 0: So you're not really making the price performance win.
Speaker 1: They're not really that expensive.
Speaker 1: The thing is up until very recently and this is why I keep oscillating back and forth between Intel and AMD And I'm still not sure what I'm gonna end up with though I want a core to.
Speaker 1: the core twos were still a lot more expensive But AMD has recently been slashing their prices repeatedly and AMD chips are so cheap now That it's harkening back to the old days where while the core two is a far superior chip in almost all respects You can get a chip that's almost as fast for a ludicrously Cheaper price.
Speaker 0: it's like right now.
Speaker 0: You can get a core to do it for like what 300 bucks something like that.
Speaker 1: Well it currently and it has been for the last week and a half the E6600 core 2 which is the sweet spot.
Speaker 1: That is the best chip on the curve of performance of the core tube right now in terms of price is three hundred and eight Dollars.
Speaker 0: all right how much is the roughly equivalent AMD x2?
Speaker 1: it was at least $120 less.
Speaker 0: See it's like two-thirds the cost.
Speaker 0: is it a third slower?
Speaker 1: Well they hit.
Speaker 1: it also gets complicated in that the AMD FX's and these new to AMD chips do outperform the core twos on certain specific tasks.
Speaker 1: yeah, however usually these are very computationally intensive benchmark kind of things and Real world use cases like running a game like supreme commander the core twos kick the AMD's asses.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't have a lot of experience with new AMD chips But I have experience with the core to do at work, and it's plenty fast.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be upset if I had one.
Speaker 1: the core solo.
Speaker 1: That's in our Mac mini megahertz wise is pathetically slow.
Speaker 1: however It's really fast.
Speaker 1: all these video without skipping.
Speaker 0: I mean I have a core.
Speaker 0: I have the slowest core solo imaginable in my new laptop.
Speaker 0: It's a core solo u1400.
Speaker 0: It's one point two gigahertz ultra low voltage.
Speaker 0: It's the weakest possible core solo and It gets the job done.
Speaker 0: I mean I can't play 3d games on it.
Speaker 0: that well.
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe I could play half-life 1.
Speaker 0: I haven't tried But it can play a video without skipping.
Speaker 0: it can web browse it can word process and the CPU is never the bottleneck in any of those cases.
Speaker 1: So basically the market has gone back and forth and now I'm not sure where I should be Because everything is still in flux.
Speaker 1: April 22nd according to various sources is the day that Intel is supposed to announce new chips and Lower the prices of current chips.
Speaker 1: a day is coming soon, and if those announcements happen.
Speaker 1: I might just buy a computer immediately.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was based on a leaked memo, so we'll see what actually happens.
Speaker 0: Just let it be known everyone out there who you know didn't live through all this.
Speaker 0: Pentium Intel AMD Athlon BS.
Speaker 0: it's been a back and forth over the years and Things are getting interesting right about now, and you should probably pay attention if you plan on buying computers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because pretty much the chip industry it seems to go a whole bunch of building and then it'll hit a sweet spot and Sit there for a while, and it's like the perfect time to buy a new computer.
Speaker 1: You'll get the most bang for your buck, and then it'll be stable for a while.
Speaker 1: And then suddenly there'll be this new rush and the current rush is just about to end and there's no new rush coming.
Speaker 1: until Intel is announced and if these come to fruition The next round of chip advancements are going to be more than like the previous several chip advancement.
Speaker 0: Well, they keep talking about some stuff That's kind of silly.
Speaker 0: like they talk about these quad core things Then it's like all right now You're you know they get into this realm where they talk about chips that is so expensive and so crazy that they're not Practical for a personal computer.
Speaker 0: It's like no one at home is well.
Speaker 0: That's a quad core.
Speaker 1: That's only because not only most software does not take advantage of multiple cores.
Speaker 1: very well I mean supreme commander, which is a very computationally intensive game uses two cores at best.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the quad core is not necessary for home, but that's not what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: Intel is basically Theoretically going to be able to push the clock speeds of the current type of chips the current core twos that are already Wickedly fast at like two gigahertz up to three and four gigahertz with just a snap of a fingers.
Speaker 1: We'll see about that that these announcements are coming, and it doesn't look like this.
Speaker 1: technology is going to be available until December January.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's so up in the air.
Speaker 1: I can't really say a date But there's gonna be a long sweet spot because things are starting to level out and I think in the next few weeks in fact There's going to be a sweet spot buying time And I think the next sweet spot is gonna be next year on February.
Speaker 1: well That's total speculation based on rim reading a bunch of articles for the past month.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if AMD doesn't come out with some sort of new chip soon they might It might be over.
Speaker 0: because see that's really.
Speaker 0: what's going on here is if any company ever gets Enough of a lead.
Speaker 0: see the only reason AMD was able to get in in the first place is because Intel was lagging.
Speaker 0: They didn't you know advance the technology fast enough and AMD was able to go faster with them.
Speaker 0: It's all an R&D race Yep.
Speaker 1: So Intel always has the advantage in R&D and they just sat pet Made something amazing and then threw it out to muck up everyone's world Plan on the head.
Speaker 0: coming out with these core duos and things it was sort of hooray.
Speaker 1: they saved us Yep, but now they're putting a lot of research into making the core twos faster and better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I don't know what AMD is doing.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen any major press releases from them that interested me in a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of the things I see from AMD now our prices are going down.
Speaker 1: They're always dropping their prices while Intel is up in their performance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're doing stuff with ATI but not much stuff with the the main Athlon action.
Speaker 0: But uh, it's always a big race because as soon as one company gets ahead enough of the other company, that'll be it.
Speaker 0: It's over.
Speaker 0: because if you can't can't keep up in the R&D race, you're done.
Speaker 0: You can never catch up because everything's patented and if there's no way for you to make a chip fast enough to compete It's just game over.
Speaker 0: you're done.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is why I like China always talked about making the dragon CPU their own Independently developed CPU.
Speaker 1: that wasn't beholden any patents or anything and as far as I've seen that never came to fruition.
Speaker 0: Well, I think they made it but it's really slow and useless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, because there was a flood I'm gonna go to bed because I have to get up early enough to check the weather and see if I can actually get to Work tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I just not even bother.
Speaker 1: I might just not go to work.
Speaker 0: I was half asleep all day at work And so I need to go to bed so I don't sleep at work anymore.
Speaker 1: was yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.