Speaker 0: It's Wednesday August 29th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek night.
Speaker 0: Tonight I regret to inform you we will be discussing the new anime of buzzer beater.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So today I ran a foul of a mendicant a what a beggar.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it was one of those.
Speaker 0: what variety of beggar was it?
Speaker 0: because you know there are many different types.
Speaker 1: It was a kind of beggar that I've never really encountered before because he he took several different types of beggar and kind of molded them together.
Speaker 0: so he was a sort of like a.
Speaker 1: He was a million beggar.
Speaker 1: He was a multi-classed beggar.
Speaker 1: He had like three different beggars all shoved into one all right for one.
Speaker 1: He was a crazy beggar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, crazy going for him, okay, but for two he had the.
Speaker 1: get mad at you If you don't give him money or ignore him.
Speaker 1: hey, I'm talking to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you sir Hey, don't don't ignore me.
Speaker 1: get over here.
Speaker 1: Hey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, get over here asshole Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: and three he was going after people who were driving by.
Speaker 0: Okay,
Speaker 1: so he's like I'm driving up and I see this guy in the middle of the street just kind of yelling at cars and going up to him and every now and then someone stops and he kind of leans in their window and then they kind of drive away and I Get up there and keep
Speaker 0: your window closed.
Speaker 1: It's hot.
Speaker 1: I got my window open.
Speaker 1: I stopped at the stop sign and the old man comes over and he yells like hey So I look at him for a second thinking all right.
Speaker 1: Maybe this guy needs something.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: I didn't think he was a beggar.
Speaker 1: I thought all right this guy might need help whatever.
Speaker 1: and he yells.
Speaker 1: Give me some change.
Speaker 1: So I think oh, okay that answers that and I turn to the right and I Start to drive through the stop sign and then he yells no don't ignore me get over here.
Speaker 1: I know you got money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm still gonna ignore you now.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Here's the trick.
Speaker 1: I was about to park on the street like right there.
Speaker 0: Ah, so just keep going but there's nowhere else to park.
Speaker 1: So so I pull into it.
Speaker 1: there's one spot left, you know, this is a part of the Bronx.
Speaker 1: There's no goddamn parking.
Speaker 1: So I pull into a spot like maybe 50 feet away from him.
Speaker 1: Luckily, he's engaged in yelling at some other car at this time.
Speaker 1: All right, but I'm in my car and the engines run him in this spot and I'm thinking if I leave is he gonna pee on my car?
Speaker 1: What should I do?
Speaker 1: I Gotta go do work.
Speaker 0: Chances are not zero.
Speaker 1: I was kind of worried about this.
Speaker 0: I eventually just your work should ensure you against that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: No work is gonna ensure you against that sort of.
Speaker 0: they make you drive around the Bronx and deal with these people.
Speaker 1: then I Just drove somewhere else.
Speaker 0: I'm not a fan of insurance, but I would buy crazy bum insurance.
Speaker 1: So I drove like two blocks away.
Speaker 1: then I stopped it a really shitty scuzzy looking Chinese place But it was actually pretty good Chinese food But the secret poison sauce in me, but it was good.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good.
Speaker 1: I ate it.
Speaker 1: I had a shrimp roll.
Speaker 1: It was it was acceptable.
Speaker 1: Hey And the bum didn't find my car because it didn't look like anyone had peed on it.
Speaker 1: when I got back Did it smell like being not any more so than my car does just from being in certain parts of you?
Speaker 1: Well that too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, I only attempted that once on a long road trip and all I want to say is My don't pee your pants reflex is a lot stronger than my pee into a jug attempts.
Speaker 1: So my brain said just peeing it then I don't have to pull over and the body said I'm not in a bathroom.
Speaker 0: One time I went to the doctor and you know you go to the doctor you get a urine and you know urine test You know to make sure you don't have problems.
Speaker 1: I can only do that if I'm standing over a toilet.
Speaker 1: I just got a whole no.
Speaker 0: No, I can do it standing up even if there's no toilet.
Speaker 1: One cuz I'll feel.
Speaker 0: they did the test and they said there's something funny, but it might not be anything serious.
Speaker 0: What you have to do is you have to do the urine test as soon as you wake up.
Speaker 1: I know exactly what that was.
Speaker 1: They found protein in it maybe and they're like, alright You either were walking around a lot or you have kidney problems, right?
Speaker 0: See you to do it as soon as you wake up in the morning before doing anything without even standing up and then they can Know.
Speaker 0: so I had to lay down in bed sideways and pee into a cup and I just couldn't pee Laying down, you know, I because my don't wet the bed reflex is so strong strong reflex.
Speaker 1: It is every now and then I've had those dreams for not so much lately But when I was a kid, especially where you know, I got a pee.
Speaker 1: cuz you know in the real world Rims body that's laying there has to pee and in the dream I got a pee and I had to be pretty bad too.
Speaker 1: and the brain smart It always just doesn't let you find a bathroom.
Speaker 1: You know in your dream, you can't find a bathroom ever if you got a pee because your pains like alright I know what'll happen if I let him find a bathroom.
Speaker 1: There's no bathrooms in this world.
Speaker 1: But every now and then I'd will myself into a bathroom And then I just couldn't pee or even worse.
Speaker 1: It'd be the Adam Sandler syndrome.
Speaker 1: I'm peeing and peeing and peeing and peeing and peeing and peeing and peeing.
Speaker 1: But I'm not getting any relief and it just keeps coming and eventually I wake up and I'm laying in bed.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh I gotta go pee and then I get up and go pee.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the brain's really clever about that.
Speaker 0: I got to say well, you have to train it when you're a kid.
Speaker 0: It's not so clever It's really kind of stupid.
Speaker 0: Hey, I gotta be let's be right away.
Speaker 1: Well, that is the natural state.
Speaker 0: I think the problem is is that you know when you start out, you know, you're a little baby You just pee and then they give you a diaper.
Speaker 1: So you keep just peeing and I didn't just keep the moment.
Speaker 1: I remember the like one of my earliest memories.
Speaker 1: I had a diaper on and I peed and then I thought ah I paid and I think that was the moment.
Speaker 1: I attained.
Speaker 0: sentience Sounds like a good time as any.
Speaker 1: well you had your moment when you realized the lines.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz people always said, you know color in the lines.
Speaker 0: I remember people saying color in the lines and I didn't really like.
Speaker 1: you took a crane and we're like scribble scribble scribble Yeah, I didn't really think about it or anything.
Speaker 0: just people that was just something people said.
Speaker 0: whenever I colored I didn't Understand that they were telling me to do something.
Speaker 0: and then I remember it must have been like some kids birthday party or something.
Speaker 0: and I was sitting there the coloring book and the crayons and I'm like, oh the lines.
Speaker 0: And then I call it in the lines and I kind of want a coloring book.
Speaker 1: all of a sudden, you know There's gotta be some coloring books, you know, if no one's made him, I think we should make him some sort of Cthulhu coloring book.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it exists.
Speaker 0: Let me search for it right?
Speaker 1: Yeah while you search for that.
Speaker 0: I've actually seen it before.
Speaker 1: So, uh speaking of kids and being kids There's some pretty bad news in the anime world.
Speaker 1: like every now and then there's something happens Like, you know a famous animator dies or a great show gets cancelled and you just gotta have the moment of silence.
Speaker 1: It is as if all of the good taste on the internet was suddenly silenced.
Speaker 0: Oh, but there is no good taste on the internet.
Speaker 1: So nothing about the good parts of the internet.
Speaker 1: So basically our forums and Like some parts of slash shot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, right.
Speaker 1: So, uh, they're making a second gunslinger girl and it's gonna air in the spring.
Speaker 1: now I don't know if you're familiar with gunslinger.
Speaker 0: It's not the worst show.
Speaker 0: nice pretty bad.
Speaker 1: it's not the worst show because the worst show is the show that we're gonna do a show on at some point because Anime world order and fast karate think they're all cool talking about like demon city or angel cop.
Speaker 1: But there's a show they've never talked about and we're gonna talk about it.
Speaker 0: It's real.
Speaker 0: Oh you we should talk about it today.
Speaker 1: No, because I want to do the thing.
Speaker 1: I want to watch the show again.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I want to waste my time.
Speaker 1: Here's the reason.
Speaker 1: if you talk about a show like this and you don't give like all the pertinent details of the show and Kind of take people through the plot semi chronologically They're gonna be curious and they're gonna watch the show and that's a bad idea.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: You got to take.
Speaker 1: give them enough info to where.
Speaker 1: not only do they get how bad the show is But they no longer need to watch.
Speaker 1: the curiosity is sated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would not inflict this show upon anyone.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe that could be fun to inflict the show upon everyone.
Speaker 1: If that were the case I'd review it like.
Speaker 1: it's awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh my god starts out really bad.
Speaker 1: But then the last 20 minutes make up a story like they ran out of money.
Speaker 1: So they just went crazy.
Speaker 1: go nuts and it's super awesome And you just gotta wait for it.
Speaker 0: too bad in the anime.
Speaker 0: That's the last second.
Speaker 0: It's the worst thing ever I know.
Speaker 1: I mean the show.
Speaker 1: she's going downhill downhill and then we get our ID It's the end and then it goes off a cliff if that's possible.
Speaker 0: It's so far underground I don't know how but I guess they come out the other side of the world.
Speaker 0: No, that would be better.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like I'm Caesar and I've already been stabbed and I'm laying on the ground slowly bleeding to death.
Speaker 0: No, you're laying on the ground already dead and it still gets worse.
Speaker 0: Yeah You're already in hell.
Speaker 0: if there is a hell doing the worst thing possible and it still gets worse at the end.
Speaker 1: All right, right.
Speaker 1: So, uh gunslinger girls is basically Pedophile moe bullshit plus gun porn.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now that wouldn't.
Speaker 1: I mean it could have been a good show.
Speaker 1: You could have taken this concept and made a really creepy really Scary show.
Speaker 1: but no that's not my gripe because you can make a show like this.
Speaker 1: But despite the fact that they spent all this money on the show and they made it the kind of show that it is It's really shittily done and the director just didn't know what he was doing and it was slow and the gunfights were crap.
Speaker 1: You'd think all right.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get to see a nine-year-old girl take a p90 and kill like a thousand gangsters.
Speaker 1: How could that not be awesome?
Speaker 1: Well gunslinger girls found a way fuck that show.
Speaker 0: The fact I've only watched one episode of it.
Speaker 1: I watched all of it.
Speaker 1: Wow Don't watch that show.
Speaker 1: the moment There's a moment when I decided I wasn't gonna watch the rest of it and the only thing that made me watch the rest of it was the fact that I didn't have an internet connection and I was really bored and my cell phone didn't work.
Speaker 1: So I was living in the mountains and I'd already read every book I had and I already beaten half-life 1 again And I've already beaten XCOM again.
Speaker 0: I've noticed this trend lately that a lot more anime shows are getting second and third seasons than they were previously.
Speaker 0: I mean few.
Speaker 0: just years ago like less than a decade ago shows were getting cut to 13 episodes.
Speaker 0: You know not getting their full 26.
Speaker 0: Yeah Of course that happened back in the day.
Speaker 0: Episode shows are getting cut to 26.
Speaker 1: how many of the great shows from back in the day were originally 39 and got cut back?
Speaker 1: Well, that's
Speaker 0: that's part of what I like so much about anime at least television anime was that they're all limited series usually 26 episodes that you could digest pretty quickly and if they keep coming out with multiple seasons of all these stupid shows I just don't know if I'm up to watching them no matter how good they are.
Speaker 0: I mean That's a major reason.
Speaker 0: I don't watch things like Naruto and bleach despite not liking them because all the fighting is just too many goddamn Episodes, you know, it's 39 or less.
Speaker 0: I mean Gundam seed was 50 and that was still a little too much.
Speaker 1: Right, I don't have any more to say about this.
Speaker 1: if you haven't seen gunslinger girls Don't watch it.
Speaker 1: It's not cool.
Speaker 1: Not even an ironic sense.
Speaker 1: It's just there was nothing redeeming about it.
Speaker 1: It is not interesting in any way and the end is just.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into it All right.
Speaker 0: So this news might seem Counterintuitive to a rant I had in recent weeks about this kind of news But I am not concentrating on the aspects of this news.
Speaker 1: hypocrite.
Speaker 1: Yeah hypocrite That's it.
Speaker 1: we're past that Scott's hypocrite.
Speaker 1: get on with it.
Speaker 0: All right, so the headline of this story?
Speaker 0: Well, it's talking about the speed racer movie that the matrix guys are making.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think I know tricks guy and transsexual.
Speaker 0: I think I know what you're gonna talk about because I have that article open and it was almost my news and this Actual article is like an interview with Susan Sarandon who's gonna be in the movie or I guess Tommy Lee Jones is giving the interview.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: The point is is that in this little article here They they talk about that in the speed race or live-action movie that they are making that I naturally have low expectations for.
Speaker 0: they're going to have a camera in which everything that the camera sees is in focus much like an animation where everything is in focus all the time.
Speaker 0: and That gives me a tiny speck of hope that hey, they're gonna make it a live-action speed racer But they're gonna make it definitely in the style of the animation.
Speaker 1: So really really choppy and hard to follow and everything off model all the time.
Speaker 1: That's exactly what I want.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to go off model with actors I guess unless you.
Speaker 0: The thing is they gotta have the monkey they need the monkey or else bits.
Speaker 0: It's worth it.
Speaker 0: It's worthless.
Speaker 0: There's no point without the monkey.
Speaker 1: You know, it would make it great if they just got some untrained non-circus non-film monkey And it was just always there causing trouble in the pit.
Speaker 0: It was just monkey loose in the pits just constantly and then like the monkey would get into the other people's cars and this Avotage them.
Speaker 0: but it wouldn't be purposeful.
Speaker 0: It would just be random act of monkey does nothing about poop and mall people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you made like the speed racer movie in the style of the original speed racer But like with this dose of parody reality in there That could be actually really good.
Speaker 1: I'd watch that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wish they do that with a lot of things.
Speaker 1: I mean we talked about it before.
Speaker 1: remember the live-action initial d-movie and how much it sucked sucked ass.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, I got nothing else to say about that.
Speaker 0: No, but I'm looking forward to the trailers for this movie just to see what it looks like.
Speaker 1: That's a pretty strong endorsement from the Scotty.
Speaker 1: There you go Things of the day.
Speaker 1: so as you all know I'm a big fan of pranks and this prank Was very near and dear to me because I attempted something similar as a child in high school.
Speaker 1: that didn't quite go.
Speaker 0: so well Oh, he didn't succeed the way these people did.
Speaker 1: Oh, not at all, but I had the idea I was thwarted.
Speaker 1: but I'll get to that.
Speaker 1: basically these kids there's a crosswalk, you know, and I don't know what state it was And I didn't read or pay attention to anything.
Speaker 1: But in a lot of states in the US if there's a marked crosswalk by law.
Speaker 1: if it's uncontrolled Pedestrians have the right-of-way no matter what.
Speaker 1: Yep, as long as they're within the boundaries of the crosswalk.
Speaker 0: Usually they only put crosswalks like this that are uncontrolled, you know in places where there isn't a great deal of pedestrian traffic If there's a lot of pedestrian traffic, they usually have you know lights that say okay cars go.
Speaker 0: Okay, people go.
Speaker 1: Okay Okay, people go but this one place they often put them is right in front of schools because there's a bunch of pedestrian traffic all At once when the kids need to go and other than that, there's nothing.
Speaker 0: Yep So why have lights there all the time for go and not go and really only have kids there?
Speaker 0: in the morning Everyone stops and then at night everyone, you know, everyone goes again.
Speaker 1: Well these juniors Realized that there was a tunnel or something going underneath the street between these two buildings and the crosswalk went across between the two buildings.
Speaker 1: So they got a whole bunch of people together and at a specified time in a semi single file kind of casual line People just started crossing the street and they didn't stop ever.
Speaker 1: And cars started backing up and the speed was just blocked and it just keeps going and go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, while they may not seem illegal, you know, we're just crossing the crosswalk.
Speaker 0: if they do discover which will be pretty obvious You know when they see the guy in the cow costume walk by more than once and the chicken costume walk by more than once They'll realize that you are blocking traffic on purpose, you know in an organized and intended way Which is as illegal as say parking on the sidewalk,
Speaker 1: but regardless of that It's quite hilarious.
Speaker 1: and I give these kids props.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's super hilarious.
Speaker 0: This is an awesome prank.
Speaker 1: I give these kids props for the very hilarious and non-destructive prank.
Speaker 1: Yep Now when I was in high school I was a member of the Ford to Falcon marching band and we fielded over 200 people at one point.
Speaker 1: so Partly because we were gigantic jerks whenever we marched to a parade ground like two for a competition from the staging area we would often do it single file partly because it was kind of intimidating to the other competition bands when We would march by for like five solid minutes because we were twice as big as all of them.
Speaker 1: So one day we're marching out of the school in a little break room We had.
Speaker 1: we're marching down to a parade ground for a practice and we're going past all these bands and I realized and I was Pretty sure that if we had just taken the front of the band and looped it around through the school We could have made a never-ending loop passing this band that was a particularly a bad rival of ours
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So and of course, there are all these other people in some minor local reporters around.
Speaker 1: So we thought it'd be really cool If the band just kept walking past in the background and all this reporter stuff and all these people.
Speaker 1: and I was down with this.
Speaker 1: So I go up to mr.
Speaker 1: Knitter house the somewhat ornery band director and I explain or attempt to explain my plan to him and He just kind of stares at me.
Speaker 1: He doesn't react at all doesn't even raise an eyebrow and just stares at me.
Speaker 1: and I'm talking, you know well what we got to do is get the front part of the band right and get him to come around like this and meet up With the back half and then we get the drummers to go ahead but not go past the second time otherwise, they'll catch on.
Speaker 1: and And finally I stopped and I'm like, so what do you think?
Speaker 1: and he just looks at me and then he just kind of says You know, you don't really like living on this planet very much.
Speaker 1: Do you?
Speaker 1: Get back in line.
Speaker 0: Oh I was spoils for it.
Speaker 1: I was sad.
Speaker 1: I really think we could have done it and I would have been very happy with that.
Speaker 0: Oh So my thing today when I was a kid There were these movies that called gremlins and then gremlins 2 and I never saw gremlins 1 actually, but I saw.
Speaker 0: One is great I know but I saw gremlins 2 in the movie theater.
Speaker 0: and the premise of these movies that there's this cute furball thing and If it gets wet between a certain amount of time or if it eats at the wrong times during the time You don't remember at all.
Speaker 0: All right, something like so like after midnight or something.
Speaker 1: if you get the little cute fuzzy creature wet He spawns like five or six more little gremlins But they're also really cute.
Speaker 1: and if you let him eat meat after midnight They turn into horrible evil deadly things that go around killing old ladies, right?
Speaker 1: Now I always wondered you can't feed a meat after midnight, right?
Speaker 0: So when can you feed him again?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's the deadline?
Speaker 0: I mean they never explained that.
Speaker 1: is it from midnight on is just once it hits midnight They can never eat meat again.
Speaker 1: that that pissed me off as a kid and to this day Pissed me off as a kid.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: So after midnight well 1159 p.m.
Speaker 0: Is after midnight of the previous day.
Speaker 1: also How come?
Speaker 1: the main character gremlin is really nice and doesn't do all the bad things, but everyone else does.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it made no sense to me but gremlins 2 was actually a comedic parody movie that was not quite the same as gremlins 1 but still kind of the same and I Saw it as a kid in the theaters and it was pretty funny and I like it even though it's not the greatest movie ever.
Speaker 0: The point is that in the middle of the movie at some point It was sort of this fake intermission thing that involved Hulk Hogan Hulkamania yeah, and When they put this movie out on VHS slash DVD whatever the scene with Hulk Hogan and the fake intermission was removed.
Speaker 0: for who knows what reason we don't know.
Speaker 0: and Here is that scene on YouTube?
Speaker 0: So if you're watching the gremlins 2 which you probably should sometime in your life and also the one Here's the missing scene from the second one.
Speaker 1: You know when I was a kid with Hulk Hogan.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Wait, that's Randy Randy Savage that goes.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Yeah I had the audio drama of gremlins on a little record that I played That I played on my Big Bird record player.
Speaker 0: I had a Big Bird record player.
Speaker 1: I think everyone did.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that was the best turntable ever had now.
Speaker 1: I know that Hulk Hogan gives the gremlins the double-deuce.
Speaker 1: It's funny cuz Scott's sitting there.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: he sends me the video so I watch it.
Speaker 1: I'm laughing But then I just keep watching it like this one part.
Speaker 1: over and over and over and over again Scott's like what the fuck you doing?
Speaker 1: I Was pretty sure he flipped the gremlins off, but I couldn't tell.
Speaker 1: and it's really hard to go frame by frame in a YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: But it does appear that Hulk Hogan gives two middle fingers to the gremlins that are off-screen.
Speaker 1: I got to the exact frame and unless it's just really blurry and he's actually just kind of pointing at him I'm pretty sure that he flipped him off.
Speaker 0: It is a good 75/25 chance.
Speaker 0: He is flipping them off.
Speaker 1: I'm proud of the fact that I found that out that I wasted a good part of my day.
Speaker 1: Not a good part, but actually yeah If you take my commute and everything into consideration a good part of the free time I have I spent trying to figure out if Hulk Hogan flipped off some gremlins in a special feature in a movie that was never Put on a DVD.
Speaker 0: doesn't matter Hulk Hogan.
Speaker 0: Awesome gremlins.
Speaker 0: Awesome video.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: So apparently in the future of all the human achievements of all the sports of all the games Of all the culture of all the art The thing that spreads across the universe the thing that humans bring to the collective intelligence of all known I almost said creation because that's a poetic word but intergalactic.
Speaker 1: I don't want to use that word entertainment Whatever, I don't know.
Speaker 1: apparently Basketball is the thing that we bring to the universe.
Speaker 0: Oh, you think of all the art and all the things that we've created the one that would catch on through all intelligent species podcasting would be Podcasting.
Speaker 1: yeah basketball now, not only that.
Speaker 1: but turns out that in all the universe there are in fact species of Animals, well, maybe not speech.
Speaker 0: Well, they're an alien species alien races.
Speaker 0: I'd say there's a Humanoid alien race.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I wouldn't say that to be humanoid.
Speaker 1: I mean odds are out there.
Speaker 1: There is some form of being that would be better at basketball than us humans.
Speaker 1: Maybe some sort of psychic blob that just moves the ball with its mental powers?
Speaker 1: or maybe just a Giant stick that just puts the ball on top of itself and then slams it every time.
Speaker 0: maybe a race of living basketballs.
Speaker 0: they confuse you and put themselves in the net.
Speaker 1: but no apparently.
Speaker 1: First all the aliens and all the multiverse are humanoid.
Speaker 1: They're just different colors like green or purple and they have horns.
Speaker 0: They're otherwise.
Speaker 0: only one species of them has horns the Goran.
Speaker 1: But they didn't show us any other alien species.
Speaker 1: so I can assume that that is the only species of alien in the universe except for humans.
Speaker 0: So as humans and Goran's and Goran's are way better at basketball than human It must be those horns.
Speaker 1: I don't know that green skin.
Speaker 0: apparently They're not so much better that humans can't.
Speaker 0: can you know can still score?
Speaker 1: They're just like 12 feet tall and twice as fast yeah, but they're not so much better.
Speaker 0: the humans can't score at all.
Speaker 0: They're just so much better.
Speaker 0: the humans can't win and apparently they don't cheat or kick you while you're down or anything evil like that.
Speaker 1: They're just way better and evil looking but not evil at heart though up in the minor leagues One of the teams that was the champion has a really evil looking coach.
Speaker 0: It does it does yeah.
Speaker 1: So we're talking about some shit.
Speaker 1: anime that we watched.
Speaker 0: well We didn't have any.
Speaker 0: well rim again did not read a comic.
Speaker 1: And well because we cancelled last week when I was gonna do read a comic and this week I thought I'm gonna read that Batman comic that katsu head out, and I don't know where he put it And I didn't put any effort.
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 1: I didn't look in there.
Speaker 0: He left it down where the comics are.
Speaker 1: he left it downstairs.
Speaker 1: I figured I'd still be there.
Speaker 1: you put something away.
Speaker 1: I put wait wait wait a minute.
Speaker 0: I think the problem here is that I put shit away all the time, and you seem to think I don't put shit away.
Speaker 1: Well you don't put your shoes away every day shoes.
Speaker 0: I use them constantly.
Speaker 1: No you don't you leave them.
Speaker 0: Every day I use them.
Speaker 1: Scott leaves his shoes sprawled out Directly in front of the front door where I have to walk.
Speaker 0: I come in the house.
Speaker 1: I take them off Yeah, and you leave them there.
Speaker 1: You don't put them away.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 0: What am I gonna put them?
Speaker 0: I'm using them again real soon, but with all I wasn't gonna use my shoes like my dress shoes.
Speaker 0: They're away cuz you know what I don't use them.
Speaker 1: you have several pairs of shoes laying around downstairs.
Speaker 1: They're only away because I put them away.
Speaker 0: whatever.
Speaker 1: anyway This shit anime called buzzer beaters or buzzer beaters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had watched this show previously And I went downstairs to look and see what anime we had to watch you know because we needed to watch something quick.
Speaker 0: There just be an episode that we can make a show about and we wanted Something kind of recent and I saw this in the bin, and I said well, that's terrible, but we can talk about it.
Speaker 1: So uh everything we said just before we brought this up.
Speaker 1: That's the plot.
Speaker 1: basically the gore ends are better than humans at basketball But the humans got to show them up.
Speaker 1: let their homies know who done it.
Speaker 0: so the humans make an earth team of the best Players on earth.
Speaker 1: no they don't they?
Speaker 1: there's a montage where it's like check it out a quick shot of all the Not so great players on earth because they're all really stupid and divisive And they argue with each other.
Speaker 1: and then the main character the show is like the shittiest of all of them.
Speaker 0: the main character.
Speaker 0: The show is like Edward Elric only he's annoying all the time instead of occasionally not being you know.
Speaker 1: imagine if you take you know Full metal alchemist if Edward Elric, and he goes into that who are you calling short?
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: you're sure I'm gonna kick your ass bla bla bla bla.
Speaker 1: Who you calling a bean sprout and you just leave him in that mode for the entire show and not only that.
Speaker 0: but he's so immature like like.
Speaker 0: I've never seen someone so immature.
Speaker 0: I mean Usually when you have a a show like a sports show especially like a basketball show.
Speaker 0: What's the obvious thing in a basketball show?
Speaker 0: for there to be drama you don't pass me the ball?
Speaker 0: I'm a ball hog.
Speaker 0: That's the obvious immature crap that good sports anime and manga just go beyond.
Speaker 0: like initial D Doesn't get the.
Speaker 0: oh you crashed into me crap.
Speaker 0: I mean well once once, but it doesn't do it in that immature way.
Speaker 1: No, it does.
Speaker 0: It's just this show goes down to the lowest common denominator.
Speaker 1: You don't pass me the ball.
Speaker 0: Hey, why'd you pass me the ball, and I hate you.
Speaker 0: you suck screw this earth team now.
Speaker 1: beyond that I would like to note that the animation is It's it's.
Speaker 1: it's a little better than size.
Speaker 1: and Joe.
Speaker 0: well the thing is the animation is deceptive and that the actual colors are bright and The.
Speaker 0: the way things are done with CG everything looks really shiny and new But kind of like Ziza and Jotaro.
Speaker 1: no no you look at it still and you think it looks awesome.
Speaker 1: You look at it still.
Speaker 1: It's like wow.
Speaker 1: That's really cool.
Speaker 0: You know the style of art is sort of like this weird muscliness But it actually is sort of a basketball muscliness, so yeah kind of makes sense.
Speaker 0: and when they play basketball They do this weird thing where they have 2d Basketball players right and normal anime on top of this big CG 3d basketball court that sort of bounces up and down.
Speaker 1: It almost looks like they kind of Protoscoped it or something.
Speaker 0: it looks like you're.
Speaker 0: it looks like you're playing a basketball video game where the camera is going all over the place except it there's not a lot of good continuity between Like.
Speaker 1: they'll show like up zooming in shaky cam whatever and it shows like a move.
Speaker 1: or one guy passes the ball to another guy Who tries to do a layup, but all the individual scenes don't really link up into a contiguous game?
Speaker 0: Well, I think the thing is they didn't show us a basketball game Which is what I want in a sports anime.
Speaker 0: I want to see the sport itself unfold and the drama of even when they were playing basketball They started with.
Speaker 1: they started a game.
Speaker 1: Game lasted like 30 seconds, but even when the game was going the they don't really show basketball.
Speaker 1: They show these kind of oddly animated jerky Someone's playing basketball over there And then it cuts to a still of all these people watching and then they cover up their mouths.
Speaker 1: don't have to animate their mouths moving This show.
Speaker 0: if you actually pay attention to what's going on they avoid animating mouths at all costs.
Speaker 0: They don't show you anything.
Speaker 0: They will show you the character who is being talked to so they don't have to draw the character talking.
Speaker 1: It's like I started to anticipate.
Speaker 1: it's like alright that character is about to talk.
Speaker 1: I'll bet as soon as they start to talk it's gonna cut to the reaction shot and sure enough And they'll show freaking the backs of characters.
Speaker 0: They'll have characters think to themselves to avoid having them talk.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of top-down so they don't have to show my have people like.
Speaker 0: they'll have characters narrate other characters playing basketball.
Speaker 0: Love characters go as D and start screaming so they want to animate the mouth.
Speaker 0: They do every trick in the book to avoid animating as much as possible.
Speaker 1: now Yeah, it's even worse than that.
Speaker 1: almost every shot outside the basketball Which is 90% of this show is you know when an anime when they're cutting corners?
Speaker 1: It'll be like moving moving moving and suddenly an entire character locks into a rigid Obviously not changing cell or not changing like set or pose and then like just one arm is animated.
Speaker 1: It looks really weird.
Speaker 1: the show does that all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like there's a time when a character is standing there But their arms and the basketball are moving and nothing else and it they stay at that for like at least 10 seconds.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird and even it just keeps getting worse.
Speaker 1: There's so many you know what.
Speaker 1: sometimes you pan across the scene for dramatic effect or whatever.
Speaker 1: This show pans like every single shot to try to distract you from the fact that it's just a still That they're all just stills.
Speaker 1: the show is just stills pretty much.
Speaker 1: It's even worse than that.
Speaker 1: The characters don't stay on model at all.
Speaker 1: I have no idea how tall the main character is.
Speaker 1: sometimes She's like eight feet tall.
Speaker 1: sometimes He's like four feet tall.
Speaker 0: hard to tell how old he is too because he's SD a lot And then he'll suddenly be sort of non SD, and then it he'll be shorter and taller and and wider.
Speaker 0: and God it sometimes will be better basketball than is at other times, and I don't fucking know.
Speaker 1: so The character designs are muscly and weird, but they kind of fit the sports anime whatever.
Speaker 1: So I'm not really gonna complain about that though a lot of shots and a lot of angles the muscles look Broken like muscles that should be there aren't and muscles that shouldn't be there Just kind of hanging on and limbs move in ways that they shouldn't move.
Speaker 0: And it's like whoa did your shoulder just detach what the hell?
Speaker 1: and people's arms are just way too long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess that's part of basketball those you need the really long arms that you can animate the basketball maneuvers It's just.
Speaker 0: ah.
Speaker 0: so regardless of the terrible animation buzzer beater has a show I Guess supposed to be about basketball and it's based on a manga called buzzer beater Which is by the same guy who did the manga called slam dunk.
Speaker 0: now I?
Speaker 0: Was previously under the impression that since slam dunk is a famous Basketball manga that is popular all around the world except in the US that it was good.
Speaker 0: I had done some research and checked with some sources And I can say slam dunk is not good slam dunk is terrible and buzzer beater is Sort of more slam dunk with aliens by the same guy.
Speaker 1: I keep forgetting that when I'm talking about it that it's about fucking aliens with horns And there's the one ring guy if it's.
Speaker 0: if it's worse than slam dunk it five that's possible.
Speaker 1: There's the one.
Speaker 1: There's one cool alien.
Speaker 1: He's green.
Speaker 0: He's got horns and a fro.
Speaker 1: That's the best care.
Speaker 1: now all right There is one good scene in this entire first episode of this show.
Speaker 0: is it the same the same scene that I thought was the Good scene?
Speaker 1: well for me.
Speaker 1: It's the guy who the guy named zucchini who's like the paparazzi that one and The characters just crap.
Speaker 1: But he pulls out his business card and the business card has this like logo of him.
Speaker 1: And if I were that guy that would be my business card.
Speaker 1: if if I looked like that at all That would be the logo for geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's it's perfect.
Speaker 0: My favorite scene was when one of the players walks On the earth team walks is walking down the hallway, and he there's a bin of fan mail And he looks at it and all right.
Speaker 0: And he picks up this one letter completely randomly and completely unrelated to everything else in the episode.
Speaker 0: and the letter says you know I'm a kid who's in a Goron Goran slave can't you know?
Speaker 0: I am a slave.
Speaker 0: It's in English, too.
Speaker 0: It's like I am slave of Goran.
Speaker 0: I pray for you to win at basketball.
Speaker 1: It's a secret to everybody.
Speaker 0: yeah, just and the guy is all like touched by this letter.
Speaker 0: and Frickin make the show.
Speaker 0: if you the show is about that kind of drama of you know the humans versus the Gorons and the Cool, they just.
Speaker 1: I mean there's a scene where the Gorons.
Speaker 1: There's one with a couple of goils hanging out at a movie theater.
Speaker 1: He just seems like a cool guy.
Speaker 1: They're not evil.
Speaker 1: They're just good at basketball Apparently makes them evil.
Speaker 0: yeah But it's so.
Speaker 0: if the show is concentrating on all the wrong things the worst character on the entire earth team is Concentrated on the most while the cool captain either team barely gets any time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can go over the characters briefly.
Speaker 1: I don't remember their names.
Speaker 1: It doesn't fucking matter It's.
Speaker 1: it's a typical harem show school whatever.
Speaker 1: They're all just this area.
Speaker 0: Ready, there's the old guy who owns the team who's sort of yelling and screaming even though he should be kind of more serious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's the female coach who's all business.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's the Female player who's sort of bratty, but she's obviously like you know the girl you end up with type.
Speaker 1: There's the main character who we've talked about.
Speaker 0: there's the captain who's calm cool and collected like Takahashi Rios, okay?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that guy's the only smart guy.
Speaker 0: There's the guy who's kind of like Katani Toga who's sort of like driving his convertible and being all badass with the ladies.
Speaker 0: There's the muscly guy who's a lot like Armstrong.
Speaker 0: He's the guy who looking at the fan letter where he's a softy But he's huge and muscly.
Speaker 0: there's the token black guy Who's acts like a token black guy?
Speaker 0: It's all stir, but he's not really that black.
Speaker 0: It's sort of.
Speaker 0: it's sort of weird that you have this all-earth basketball team with so few black people on it.
Speaker 0: It seems kind of wrong and sort of racist in a way.
Speaker 1: You know I'm not gonna Pick with this show because I would like to point out that buzzer beater is directed by none other than the famous wonderful Shigeyuki mia.
Speaker 1: now this person is responsible for jack all so he's directed buzzer beater some other buzzer beater and The pawn the third angel tactic special and that's it now.
Speaker 1: he did animation for x-driver Which was also a crap show.
Speaker 1: just happened to have a good character designer.
Speaker 0: extra x-driver was shit.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 0: I was like about it though the thing is I was excited about it.
Speaker 1: I really thought it was gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: I get another show with a good premise.
Speaker 0: I mean like.
Speaker 0: I could write.
Speaker 0: I can't write fiction for shit But I could write or at least come up with in my mind a story involving aliens in basketball.
Speaker 0: That would kind of be an average to middling and it was that movie with Bugs Bunny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're right That was a lot better than this crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah buzzer beater is just bad space jam in a way.
Speaker 0: It didn't have Michael Jordan.
Speaker 0: it didn't have Looney Tunes.
Speaker 0: it didn't have cool aliens that are actually characters.
Speaker 0: it There's nothing.
Speaker 0: it just has annoying Edward Elric guy.
Speaker 1: I Really don't like this show and I'm just not just I mean, I don't really like a lot of sports anime.
Speaker 1: But forget that This show is bad.
Speaker 0: If you like sports anime watch anything else is like so bad.
Speaker 1: It's watch I shield 21 or something.
Speaker 0: Maybe if you watch this show with a large group of people.
Speaker 1: Oh, this show would be great to show to an anime club.
Speaker 0: Maybe it depends because it while there are many parts that are good to show to a large group of people You know certain scenes where everyone would laugh and get a good time a lot of it.
Speaker 0: They just be sitting there going.
Speaker 1: Here's how you show the show to an anime club.
Speaker 1: You show four episodes of four different shows.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah first episode this second episode some other crappy show.
Speaker 1: third episode some other crappy show.
Speaker 1: fourth one size and Jotaro I.
Speaker 0: that would work if you showed it with other shows, but I think just watching this alone at an anime club There are scenes that everyone would get a laugh from but overall most people just be like wow I really don't like this show.
Speaker 0: So it's just bad.
Speaker 1: I don't know Why this is the kind of show that Dave and Joel need to make fun of.
Speaker 0: I guess it's just bad.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there are the words besides bad sad mad glad.
Speaker 0: no Glad is not a good word for this plaid terrible horrendous Vomitation.
Speaker 0: very bad very sad Even if you're the biggest Basketball anime fan like your two things in life are basketball and anime.
Speaker 0: stay away from this.
Speaker 0: do not go Active not watch Geiger counter off the charts.
Speaker 0: You will die.
Speaker 1: Do not touch You know, I think we're done with that show.
Speaker 1: But Scott pointed out a little while ago and we've realized that we really only review shows that we really like or we really don't Like.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm gonna try to find some middle-of-the-road shows that we don't that we either don't like a whole lot or don't hate a whole Completely or I'm gonna try to find some shows where we disagree.
Speaker 0: That's kind of hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can think of a few like tenchi muyo.
Speaker 1: We kind of disagree a lot.
Speaker 1: Yes, you know, I really like Some of tenchi muyo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've only seen some of tenchi muyo and what I've seen I did not like.
Speaker 1: See how the first OAV is good.
Speaker 1: The first movie is good.
Speaker 1: The second movie is not so bad.
Speaker 0: I've seen some stuff on Cartoon Network and I did not like that doesn't?
Speaker 0: I don't know what it was And it was.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you real quick the story about tenchi.
Speaker 1: They made a tenchi show and it was really good and it was kind was really funny and I liked it.
Speaker 1: And then the guy who made tenchi Saw liked what he did and decided that he wanted to recapture that magic Forever and he has failed in every attempt from this from that day forward.
Speaker 0: I also saw tenchi muyo GXP, but I just read as far as I had a great opening song though That's see there's.
Speaker 1: that's a show we could do Anime that has music that was wasted on that show.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of those XP.
Speaker 1: Pac-sign Are El Cazador?
Speaker 0: Okay music.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was pretty good.
Speaker 1: But when it comes to tenchi muyo GXP pretend that I Can somehow give birth to an anime and that my child was tenchi muyo GXP.
Speaker 1: I have no son.
Speaker 0: So tenchi muyo and buzzer beater have a baby and that's tenchi muyo GXP.
Speaker 1: well in that case I would have to murder them and be a serial killer and go to jail because But have a great opening song to it.
Speaker 1: See, there's the other thing buzzer beater not so good on the music from nothing in.
Speaker 0: buzzer beater is good the music.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no, you're forgetting.
Speaker 1: you're forgetting.
Speaker 1: There's that business card.
Speaker 1: That's about that business card is great.
Speaker 0: Oh Only thought we only talked about it because we really needed something to do an episode on tonight and the show's really bad.
Speaker 1: I think Scott it's kind of like in with those like dramatic samurai movies where the guy Stabs through himself to stab the bad guy and self-sacrifice and all that.
Speaker 1: I almost feel like Scott did that to me maliciously.
Speaker 1: He watched this show again just to force me to watch it.
Speaker 0: Well, you know I went through the like.
Speaker 0: I said I went through the bin of shows we had available to watch that were new and That was the only one and we should have watched the show with the bunny girls.
Speaker 1: I'd rather watch some bunny girl show watch it while we eat.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's actually kind of funny.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to watch the rest of gonkotsu.
Speaker 0: Hope to watch that later.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I think we're done.
Speaker 1: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.