Speaker 1: It's Monday, May 28th.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: We're sick, and this is geek night Tonight.
Speaker 1: we're gonna continue getting into it week Which we stopped prematurely last week with how to get into computer programming.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So as I'm sure you all noticed we missed two shows last week.
Speaker 0: I wonder why that was well.
Speaker 1: I got actually pretty sick and Sadly it's a sickness that was going through much of my work and many of us got sick with it.
Speaker 1: And it seems I brought it home because now that I'm back from my trip Scott seems to be just having the beginning of the exact same sickness.
Speaker 0: Yes, but meanwhile Well, you were sick.
Speaker 0: We had to cancel the show when I'm sick.
Speaker 0: That's just fine.
Speaker 0: We'll do the show anyway because I'm not a wuss.
Speaker 1: see now I will point out that well Wednesday I pretty much came home from work chugged some NyQuil and went directly to bed And I was really sick mostly due to the secondary bacterial infection that I gained in my sinuses and the sore throat and such.
Speaker 1: but Thursday I was actually feeling a lot better, and I was 50/50 on doing the show and I could have done it.
Speaker 1: But I'll point out that always said Scott I think I'm up for doing the show.
Speaker 1: Scott basically looked at me and said I don't think you are and I think his ulterior Motive was that he really didn't want to do the show.
Speaker 1: He wanted to just I don't know cop out.
Speaker 0: well if you were so badass as I am to do the show when sick Why didn't you just do the show alone?
Speaker 0: so on Thursday?
Speaker 0: We got to share the responsibility for the show Wednesday a hundred percent of the responsibility goes to your wussiness for not doing the show.
Speaker 0: I will now.
Speaker 0: hey We're doing the show which and I'm sick, so I guess I'm a badass and you're a wuss.
Speaker 1: We'll see because you're in day one of the sickness and day two is the bad day.
Speaker 0: I was kind of sick yesterday.
Speaker 1: No, that's like the precursor day.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I was sick yesterday.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: I think that really comes down to if you get the secondary bacterial infection.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but actually I'm not gonna talk about this in any great detail But it was quite an eventful four-day weekend because we obviously didn't go to work today.
Speaker 0: I thought it was gonna be a lot less eventful But it turned out to be too eventful, and I didn't get done a lot of things.
Speaker 0: I wanted to get done, but I also got done things.
Speaker 0: I wanted to get done so yeah.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: It was pretty great.
Speaker 1: I mean first off.
Speaker 1: I think I mentioned that I was going hiking.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I did or not in the show because I got sick, but We plan to go hiking with our friend James.
Speaker 1: not by we I mean all of us other than Scott who thinks hiking is stupid Wasn't all of us.
Speaker 1: It was like you and Scott Johnson and James and his whole family and Laura.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: And I think Alex would have gone And I'm pretty sure Pete and all them would have gone if they could know Alex had stuff to do like me Yeah, but he probably would have wanted to go.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: maybe you're the one who doesn't like hiking Yeah, why walk around and do nothing when you could do stuff?
Speaker 1: well the thing is when we first said Oh, we're gonna go up to the Adirondacks Lake Placid and go hiking Scott Johnson, and I like oh alright.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna get our gear gonna do some camping and then James tells us that no we're just gonna stay in a hotel.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be a day hike and I guess I didn't really think about the way his family is now seriously they take hiking.
Speaker 1: so I immediately thought oh, well, this is gonna be easy.
Speaker 1: and After I got to the top of the fourth mountain After trudging through snow banks at the top and stood at an elevation of cold up there.
Speaker 1: little shit It wasn't too cold because it was stupidly hot on the bottom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it by the time we got to the top It was warm enough that even with the wind I was okay up there, which is good.
Speaker 1: Low air pressure yeah at the lower air pressure I didn't really notice it except that I was breathing a bit more heavily than I expected.
Speaker 1: and I really noticed it when we're going back down the mountain quickly and my ears started popping.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what goes on Yep, but standing on the top of the 4,000.
Speaker 1: Whatever foot mountain gothic up there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we climbed a lower.
Speaker 0: Well, that's an actual mountain not some hill.
Speaker 1: well the thing is Mount beacon is classified a mountain by all the local law.
Speaker 0: It's a yeah, no no it's a mountain It's a hill.
Speaker 1: the thing is because a lot of mountains up there are really small too But the 46 high peaks are the ones that are over 4,000 feet.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's called a mountain.
Speaker 1: well see There's no law or anything.
Speaker 1: There's no official standard.
Speaker 0: Oh there isn't but it's this is a hill.
Speaker 0: all right regardless.
Speaker 1: I can now say pretty straightforward that I'm a mountain climber because I've now climbed several very tall mountains.
Speaker 0: All right, I guess you can.
Speaker 1: I guess the biggest thing was that we climbed them all in one day and we went well over 20 miles up and down and up and down and Walking out after we got back to the lodge refilled in water And then had to walk a further three miles at night to get out to the cars.
Speaker 1: I felt like Sam.
Speaker 0: why don't they put the cars next to the lodge?
Speaker 1: Because the lodge is in the middle of the wilderness.
Speaker 1: That's where you stop to camp and refill your water.
Speaker 0: Put a parking lot out there.
Speaker 1: There's no roads.
Speaker 1: There's no way to put a road.
Speaker 0: gotta put a road you can't All right, Scott.
Speaker 1: anyway
Speaker 0: Yeah, so for those of you who do not live in the United States or are not familiar with the customs the United States today is The day we observe Memorial Day Which is supposed to be a day where like you remember veterans from all the American Wars and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But really all it means is that everyone in the whole country doesn't go to work except people who work retail.
Speaker 1: Well what it actually means is that pretty much.
Speaker 1: It's gonna rain.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: This is probably the first year in my life I can remember where it didn't rain on Memorial Though I guess technically it did because it rained at about midnight for about an hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah it means people will go to bars and get drunk people will barbecue people will hang out with each other and They generally won't work, and it's kind of fun.
Speaker 0: and people have parades.
Speaker 0: also parades lots of parades.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the really fun thing was we're gonna do a whole show on this now but we got back from Lake Placid early because after the one day of Excruciating hiking where I can say was certainty that the final trudge out and all that by the time we were done That was the second worst pain.
Speaker 1: I've ever experienced in my life.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh very clearly the second worst pain.
Speaker 1: I definitively put it on the list at number two Uh-huh number one being the food poisoning that resulted in a not the bicycle spoke through the leg.
Speaker 1: No, that was like number five or six.
Speaker 1: that wasn't that bad.
Speaker 1: It didn't hurt so much as it was disgusting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty disgusting.
Speaker 1: right there I'm trying to explain to the doctor.
Speaker 1: No, it's fine It's just a little dud.
Speaker 1: and he says uh because you turn around and I turn around and he pulls the q-tip all the way Out of my leg, and I'm like oh, I guess it's deeper than I thought and he's like yeah You're gonna need some stitches.
Speaker 0: Yeah speaking of disgusting.
Speaker 1: Oh god.
Speaker 1: I know what you're gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if everyone listening is aware of what a tonsilis is.
Speaker 1: well is a tonsilis or tonsilis?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: the internet sort of doesn't have a definite answer, but I've seen tonsilis more often.
Speaker 1: I believe.
Speaker 1: these scientific term are those white rocks that occasionally appear in your tonsils.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically the tonsils you have tonsils that are these things in the back of your throat way back there.
Speaker 1: Well, unless you're one of those sorry folks who had them cut out for no good reason before doctors realized that they're actually kind of Useful yeah, and basically what they do is they clean shit that goes down your throat.
Speaker 0: You know what they do.
Speaker 1: is they?
Speaker 1: as far as I've been able to read there are crypts in them which are like these folds of skin yeah, and there's little crevices in there and Bacteria that you're gonna be infected with will often come in through the eye nose throat area first.
Speaker 1: So there's a decent chance they'll get in there and colonize before they begin to infect the rest of you.
Speaker 0: So basically your tonsils are like this little house that attracts all the nasty things coming in through your head And you hope that stuff gets caught in there instead of going into your body and infecting you now.
Speaker 1: Well more that it gets caught there.
Speaker 1: Then your body recognizes it and develops an immune response before it starts infecting the rest of your body.
Speaker 1: It's like an early warning system.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good now.
Speaker 1: I'm sure a doctor can get going to better detail Or tell us where we were wrong about that description, but of course that's all we know.
Speaker 0: we're computer people.
Speaker 0: What do you want from us, but on occasion your tonsils will have these lifts basically?
Speaker 0: In those crevices where the bacteria grow they will grow and grow and grow and you'll get like these white rocks that That are like sticking out of your tonsils and like if you have.
Speaker 0: really if you don't you know If you have a dirty mouth and you take a flashlight and look at the back of your mouth or your tonsils are You'll probably see a lot of white rocks grow in there, which is kind of disgusting.
Speaker 1: It's not so much a dirty mouth It's just your lifestyle and your what your tonsils are set up like.
Speaker 1: I mean you might happen to have big crypts or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, our friend are one of our friends.
Speaker 1: I'd realize not to mention the name has pretty big tonsillets and if I were this person I would have a doctor cut them out.
Speaker 0: Well, the doctor doesn't cut them out.
Speaker 0: I actually found out there.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I mean I cut out his tonsils.
Speaker 0: No, maybe but doctors have a tool called a curette which and they buy a process known as curette age.
Speaker 0: I guarantee that's exactly what the internet said curette age.
Speaker 0: They will can remove them.
Speaker 0: Granted it's like thanks.
Speaker 0: You have a screwdriver.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna apply some screwdriver II.
Speaker 1: Believe the term is screwdriver II.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, but you don't know before.
Speaker 1: you're not supposed to pick them out unless they become a problem.
Speaker 1: Just let him sit there Gouging at your tonsils with a piece of metal and you're not a doctor that you can hurt yourself.
Speaker 1: That's a recipe for not good things.
Speaker 0: Yes, basically what will happen on occasion is you'll cough out a tonsillets because that's what happens.
Speaker 0: you cough them out.
Speaker 1: They're easily identified.
Speaker 0: They're little white rocks and they smell really bad.
Speaker 1: They smell like the worst bad breath imaginable.
Speaker 0: That's basically what they smell like.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I would cough these out on occasion Yeah, and I would ignore them mostly.
Speaker 0: I'd be like hey, why am I coughing up weird rocks?
Speaker 0: And then I found out oh, it's tonsillets that I'm supposed to cough those out.
Speaker 0: Nothing wrong here.
Speaker 0: But I think it was like a month ago.
Speaker 0: I felt something in the back of my throat like something was living there and it was kind of bothering me like it was as If a rock was stuck back there and I actually felt it.
Speaker 0: Usually you don't feel tonsillets because you don't have feeling receptors in your tonsils.
Speaker 0: So if you can feel one that means it's so big it's touching other parts back there.
Speaker 0: So I tried to get it out and I thought I was successful.
Speaker 0: I poked back there.
Speaker 0: I figured out a method with a flashlight and a Toothpick.
Speaker 1: that was now I point out from my perspective Scott out of the blue kind of says I'm gonna go get this thing out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it goes upstairs.
Speaker 1: I've been a minute later.
Speaker 0: I hear Yeah, I figured out how to poke around back there without gagging myself and vomiting which is a useful skill I imagine in case you get something stuck back there that could be dangerous.
Speaker 0: But yeah, and I thought I removed it, you know, I didn't feel it anymore and I didn't see any white rocks.
Speaker 0: So I thought I was done today.
Speaker 0: I felt one back there and it was so bad.
Speaker 0: So I said I got up and I said, alright, I learned how to do this before I will do it again I will remove this tonsil it and I looked back there and I couldn't really find it And I saw a little white bump for a second and then it was gone, but I still felt it.
Speaker 0: So I went at it and I went at it and I basically Discovered there's a crevice in my tonsil on the right side.
Speaker 0: and it's so strange because if you look at it the wrong way It looks just like flat skin completely flat.
Speaker 0: But if you poke it just right it opens up and there's basically this Grand Canyon back there And all I saw with the flashlight was a tiny white bump like blue I got it wasn't even sure that it was like wasn't just a white bump on the skin itself as Opposed to a tonsil.
Speaker 0: it that just touching the skin.
Speaker 0: But I figured out how to get it out of there and what came out was the largest.
Speaker 1: most hideous in this game was like Crazy the fact that Scott decided to come downstairs and show it to everyone.
Speaker 0: It was just so crazy And even though it was disgusting it had to be shared with the world that it was so large.
Speaker 1: You didn't take a picture of it.
Speaker 1: Ah shit cuz.
Speaker 1: then that could have been your thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I never I always forget to take a picture.
Speaker 0: like I've been taking a picture of my tomato plant every day I forgot to do it today.
Speaker 1: you go do it right now.
Speaker 0: No, cuz it doesn't help because then it's not gonna be that different from the tomorrow morning picture.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's got to be like 24 hours to keep it.
Speaker 0: even so I'll just skip one and it'll be better.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be one sudden burst of growth in your animation.
Speaker 0: tomato plant grows frickin quick.
Speaker 0: I gotta tell you Like it was really small few days ago, and now it's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Yep I guess suffice to say I'm still.
Speaker 1: I mean I was starting to recover from my sickness And then I hiked a long way.
Speaker 1: it probably the most physical exertion I've ever put myself to and I think as a result.
Speaker 1: It's lingering a little bit.
Speaker 1: So I'm like just getting better and Scott is just getting sick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm illin I got some Sudafed in me right now, and I'll probably take Nyquil and go to bed.
Speaker 1: Scott hates to take medicine so the fact that I convinced him to take a pill because he hates pills I don't take medicine unless absolutely necessary.
Speaker 1: the fact that he took a pill is when I realized.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's really sick He's not just complaining.
Speaker 1: Ah yep back up a little bit.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be some Sniffling in this show there's gonna be some Nyquil and tonight.
Speaker 1: I met well Nick home Nick.
Speaker 0: well whatever you bought instead of the actual No, you know get the real deal with Sudafed in it and not the BS can't make meth out of it Nyquil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those laws.
Speaker 1: I can't see in America here.
Speaker 1: There's a problem in rural places with methamphetamines which are made by some people by buying drugs that contain Sudafed erin and basically an illegal drug that you can produce By using a chemical process on over-the-counter drugs.
Speaker 1: now It just so happens that the drug they use to make this bad drug is probably the best decongestant known to man.
Speaker 0: So if you want to buy it at the store just to decongest yourself and your sinuses.
Speaker 0: you have to sign For it, and it's not easy.
Speaker 1: to get even worse all the good brands of medicine started Just not selling it anymore because they didn't want to deal with that.
Speaker 1: Because a lot of people aren't gonna go through the trouble of going and showing ID and signing a logbook Just to buy some cold medicine.
Speaker 1: They'll just buy some other cold medicine not knowing that it doesn't work as well.
Speaker 0: Yep so it generally sucks for people with colds here because your choices are do a bunch of bullshit to get the real medicine that works or Buy bullshit medicine, but I was gonna say what about homeopathy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just said or buy bullshit medicine That zinc I won't even I won't even give it the the honor of calling it medicine.
Speaker 0: buy bullshit bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, we're still a shade better than Japan where it's basically illegal to sell any kind of Decongestant actual drug.
Speaker 1: working drugs any kind of allergies and suffering like that'd be.
Speaker 1: the biggest reason I couldn't move to Japan is that I couldn't take my allergy medicine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and what the fuck is wrong with those people?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I've heard a lot of explanations about that and it just it really kind of bothers me because Japan is one of the most modern scientifically advanced industrialized nations When it comes to medicine except when it comes to allergy and cold medicine.
Speaker 0: So the thing is there are a lot of like Japanese doctors who are like the world's foremost leading expert on some kind of crazy Kidney surgery or so.
Speaker 0: I just picked something.
Speaker 0: I have no idea But you know, they have all that kind of high-end medicine like surgeries and things like that.
Speaker 0: How come you can't wait a day-to-day over-the-counter medicine?
Speaker 0: They just don't let you have it because they're all Something I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean, what are they afraid?
Speaker 1: that if the Japanese man takes lorata Dean?
Speaker 1: He'll suddenly become a serial killer?
Speaker 0: and maybe they're right that maybe yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, some news besides us.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: so there's been a lot of news for a long time about the issues between Google News and the rest of the news industry combined.
Speaker 1: There have been some recent developments.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna get into any of them because It's really not worth it to go about the intricate details of all this.
Speaker 1: but suffice to say The mainstream media don't really like Google News.
Speaker 0: No, because they want people like if you live in I don't know, Kansas They want you to read the Kansas newspaper and whether it's not they want you to read it online.
Speaker 0: They want you to read the actual paper, you know, they don't want you going to Google News.
Speaker 0: then Then ending up at the Kansas News or maybe if you live in Kansas you end up reading like the Missouri News or something.
Speaker 0: Well, the main issue the Mississippi News.
Speaker 1: Here's the issue as it boils down Google Indexes news that is publicly and freely available all over the internet like they do with everything else.
Speaker 1: They index Yeah, and they don't even really copy it.
Speaker 1: They just link to it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: However Almost every source of news in the United States every single one Gets almost all of its news from the wire services.
Speaker 0: You have the AP wire the UPI Reuters.
Speaker 0: Is there Reuters and I think there's one more.
Speaker 0: I forget but those are the big ones.
Speaker 1: So those people actually go out and make the news.
Speaker 1: well not make the news.
Speaker 0: Make the local news like the Kansas newspaper gets news from Kansas.
Speaker 0: But you know some of them.
Speaker 0: they put on the AP wire I guess and I'm sure eight people but but a lot of the news out there.
Speaker 1: if you go to 20 different newspapers They're running the same story.
Speaker 0: They all got the base story from the wire and then they might have someone edit it and write it differently.
Speaker 1: You know, but it's the exact same facts the exact same news a lot of times.
Speaker 1: They just publish it verbatim
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: and they pay for this privilege hoping that they'll make the money back in the ads They show you on their free newspaper site,
Speaker 0: but or in their newspaper that you pay for
Speaker 1: but with Google News Say the news is I don't know president watching McCall it of Tasmania Shot someone and there was a coup.
Speaker 1: something like that.
Speaker 1: the AP wire reports on it and Rogers reports on it and Every other newspaper in America just runs that exact same story.
Speaker 1: The facts are known freely available and the same no matter where you get the facts from.
Speaker 0: you have c8 the wet.
Speaker 0: the wire Services make their money because the newspapers pay them so they don't really care who sees the news.
Speaker 0: they don't care if the news is all over the internet.
Speaker 0: that doesn't bother them because Newspapers can't print that news unless they pay.
Speaker 0: and if they do print it without paying they get sued and they make their money anyway.
Speaker 0: So the wire or if they get the news independently Yeah, the wire service just doesn't give a shit.
Speaker 0: who sees the news they want?
Speaker 0: they just don't care.
Speaker 1: So if I'm looking for that news, you know, they want newspapers want us to do is anytime I want news They want me to go to the Sun or the Times or whatever and always look at the news there because then I see all The news and I see their ads and everything's great for them.
Speaker 1: But if all the newspapers have the same news if I go to Google News and they just show one of the thousand papers That all have the same news and I click on it.
Speaker 1: Every time I look at a news article I go to a different paper.
Speaker 1: I never stay on one paper because there's no point is the same as every other paper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a Google News is so smart.
Speaker 0: What it does is it sort of figures out which stories are the same.
Speaker 0: so it groups together.
Speaker 0: like I found a story.
Speaker 0: I found the same story in this other paper I found the same story in this other paper and it groups them all into one unit and you can just click on that one Unit and bet that you're all good.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: The newspapers obviously don't like this.
Speaker 1: Here's a quote from Sam Zell than the owner of tribune company.
Speaker 1: This is from the article.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna link to a quote.
Speaker 1: if all the newspapers in America did not allow Google to steal their content How profitable would Google be?
Speaker 1: the answer not very?
Speaker 0: How much money does Google make from Google News?
Speaker 0: not much well go makes its money from elsewhere.
Speaker 1: Yes notice that Google doesn't put ads on Google News.
Speaker 1: part of that is because there's been a lot of lawsuits a lot of threats of lawsuits and The funny thing is it goes both ways.
Speaker 1: because early on a few newspapers said hey Google don't index our stuff and Google Being Google said alright fine.
Speaker 1: We will remove you from the Google News database.
Speaker 1: We will not track your site We will not link to you in any way.
Speaker 1: How's that?
Speaker 1: That's exactly what you asked for.
Speaker 1: and then those sites realize that Most of their traffic comes from Google and no one got to their site anymore and no one looked at their ads.
Speaker 1: Yep so now these newspapers.
Speaker 1: the news now is that a lot of them are starting to realize that they can't just Pretend that Google is somehow the enemy.
Speaker 1: they can't just fight or ignore Google because Google Much like the people who make Starcraft when it comes to Korea have them by the balls.
Speaker 0: And all that tells me is that in within the next 10 to 20 years I think Google is just gonna buy every goddamn newspaper.
Speaker 0: That doesn't go out of business.
Speaker 1: Why even buy?
Speaker 0: they might even buy just the wire service and then all the newspapers to go out of business.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't even need to because the thing is most of these wire news services.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna very much get on some sort of soapbox But I think the future of news reporting is going to be straight-up citizen self-organized.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think the thing is though is that you still need people who are career reporters because oh Yeah, citizens are not gonna go to some crazy war zone and report.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not gonna fly around the world.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna get information.
Speaker 0: that citizen they're getting information citizens can't get but yes, they get press passes to things.
Speaker 1: Yes, they will because if the mainstream media is so unprofitable which when it comes to news they are they're not doing well and a lot of newspapers are going out of business every single day and For the last several years every year the median age of the people who read newspapers has gone up by exactly one year
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: which says a lot.
Speaker 1: Mmm, and also I mean we do this podcast Completely on our own and pay for it for fun if we didn't have this.
Speaker 1: I know there are a lot of people who would as a hobby just be reporters.
Speaker 1: the problem also also there are Professional organizations that would step in and fill the void By providing professional news and either pay for content like a lot of places do.
Speaker 1: now a lot of the specialty places Some newspapers are doing very well because instead of just reporting on the wire They actually go out investigate on their own and have stories that only they have.
Speaker 0: Yep, the thing is, you know when it comes to reporting on some topics most topics, that's just fine.
Speaker 0: But there's certain things where you know, we don't even know if the real news is true.
Speaker 0: How are you gonna trust, you know, you see what comes on dig?
Speaker 0: they can't even report on video games without lying.
Speaker 0: How are they gonna report on politics in the war and stuff like that without?
Speaker 1: well, you know how you know currently people For some reason because it used to be the case where you'd have to trust the gatekeepers Which were the newspapers to filter out what was and wasn't true.
Speaker 1: you expected that once the story got into the newspaper It had already been checked by multiple sources and was guaranteed to be true.
Speaker 1: Nowadays, not only do the newspapers really report shittily and don't even get me into how absolutely atrocious The writing is in almost every newspaper in the world these days.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, they got a appeal to the lowest common denominator to get more readers.
Speaker 0: if they wrote it Well, most people wouldn't understand what it was saying and it wouldn't sell.
Speaker 0: They write to a fifth grade level in the newspapers.
Speaker 1: Usually I mean when I see in an actual printed newspaper misspelled words.
Speaker 1: That's really bothersome to me.
Speaker 1: But nowadays with the internet the new all the information is out there from many many many sources and you can't trust any one source and a lot of people.
Speaker 1: You have to be intelligent.
Speaker 1: all the people who say Oh Wikipedia or the internet are unreliable are just too dumb To filter information on their own.
Speaker 1: if I see a news story from any source these days I really don't trust it until I personally verify it from multiple other source and those sources can't just be a blog that links to The original story.
Speaker 0: Yeah to make sure these are people who got it independently of the first piece And that's why Google News is so great because it'll lump them together.
Speaker 1: So like say I see a story about something in a high school that outrages me.
Speaker 1: Well, if I go on Google News, and there's only one other reference to it probably not true Yeah, because if it's true, there's gonna be like 400 references to it.
Speaker 0: The other thing is you got to be able to interpret stories correctly.
Speaker 0: that don't say things accurately.
Speaker 0: Like if some story says guy in Britain invents Like perfect free energy device you have to say Oh, this doesn't news.
Speaker 0: story doesn't say a guy in Britain made a free energy device.
Speaker 0: The story is some guy in Britain says he made a free energy device.
Speaker 0: That's the actual story.
Speaker 1: I guess my long point is that Google is basically showing us the future of news.
Speaker 1: and the future of news Is that you can't trust the gatekeepers to accurately report news to you because that makes you effectively their slave.
Speaker 1: I mean, what's the old saying?
Speaker 1: any man who withholds you information wishes to be your master or something like that?
Speaker 0: The only thing I disagree with is I think the news wire and professionally paid journalists will continue to exist for a long time.
Speaker 1: Well, how are they going to make money?
Speaker 0: Because people I mean they're.
Speaker 1: hey to get the information most people aren't most people With few exceptions and those exceptions are things like the Wall Street Journal.
Speaker 1: People won't pay for the news if they can get it free and most people don't care about the news enough to even seek it out.
Speaker 0: regardless Someone's gonna pay at some point.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, even if Google's got to get to pay for them to something who knows Whatever.
Speaker 0: We still need that people to do that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah Pay for it or not.
Speaker 0: We need people to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean maybe governments will step in.
Speaker 1: Maybe people will just do it for the hell of it.
Speaker 1: Maybe nonprofit organizations will spring up and do.
Speaker 0: I don't see like TV news going anywhere because TV news is just trash.
Speaker 1: It's not new.
Speaker 0: I know but they still they're gonna hire people to go make that trash news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then again with YouTube as video becomes more and more accessible on the internet It's gonna be the same thing all over again.
Speaker 0: I know but not for a while.
Speaker 1: No, not for at least three or four more years.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know if people out there use many of the social networks sites on the internets.
Speaker 0: You know, we use the Orcutt way back and then we stopped when Brazil took it over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know and since then there have been many other comers and you know There's big popular ones like the live journals and the Facebook's in the my spaces.
Speaker 0: Well Facebook has just done something quite extraordinary And I don't think any other site has done this and it's gonna be pretty interesting how this turns out.
Speaker 0: Basically what they've done is they've opened up Facebook.
Speaker 0: They told people how it works not how it works 100% but they gave out enough information that you can make and enough You know openness so that you can make Applications within Facebook.
Speaker 0: so like I can make a Facebook Clock and now you can add it to your Facebook and now you have a clock there.
Speaker 0: or I know Facebook has a photo feature.
Speaker 0: I could go out and make Scott's special Facebook photo manager and it would replace your existing Facebook photo manager with my Better Facebook photo manager.
Speaker 1: now think about this.
Speaker 1: This is pretty revolutionary.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Facebook is basically gone for being just an applique a website that allows people to connect with each other to an Applications platform.
Speaker 0: like you could make things on Facebook the same way you make things on Windows or Firefox or any other platform and What's gonna end up happening?
Speaker 0: Is that see Facebook?
Speaker 0: They're just letting people do this.
Speaker 0: They weren't charging them any money.
Speaker 0: They're not putting really any restrictions on what you do.
Speaker 0: Like I could make a special geek nights thing for Facebook.
Speaker 0: that is like ads in it that I sell and make money off of and the more people who Add it to Facebook the more money to their Facebook's the more money I get and the more advertising I do for geek nights and Whatever.
Speaker 0: and Facebook just doesn't care because they know that this sort of thing is what's gonna bring a lot of people to Facebook And it also means they're not going to have to do as much work as they were doing.
Speaker 0: Because now oh if the Facebook photo feature sucks, that's fine.
Speaker 0: Someone will make a better one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if the Facebook this feature sucks, someone else will make a better one if people use that.
Speaker 0: so they basically cut their costs.
Speaker 0: they brought in a whole bunch of users who are going to be attracted by all the things that Facebook can do and Someone else is doing all the work and Facebook is also actually a decent site.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile myspace is a cesspool.
Speaker 1: myspace is what the internet was if you looked at geocities over a decade ago.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I really think that this is the sort of thing that's gonna.
Speaker 0: you know myspace right now It's like a hundred million people and Facebook is like 20 million.
Speaker 0: But I really think that at least in the US with this if myspace doesn't make a move Facebook's gonna do them in well in the very least over time anyone with sense is gonna be on Facebook.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Facebook has basically said Well, we're just gonna make ours the best and suddenly the best end of story.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's a far cry from the days when we used or cuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just want to see what kind of interesting Facebook applications show up like.
Speaker 0: I mean someone might make a Facebook application somehow.
Speaker 0: That's just doesn't exist elsewhere on the web on its own and you might be worth it just to get Facebook accounts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just to use some of the applications people make on Facebook.
Speaker 1: I'm I'm honestly not that far if this goes as we're hoping it will from just getting a geek nights Facebook.
Speaker 0: Geek nights Facebook is good Cuz I. I mean like this geek nights myspace that I registered just to save it.
Speaker 0: But I don't know how to use fucking myspace and the interface is so shitty.
Speaker 0: It wasn't even worth my time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I looked at it and if any of you out there use myspace.
Speaker 1: I'd like to know so I can track you down and get rid of you.
Speaker 0: Good God Yeah, but you know, I had a Facebook since I was at RIT, but I just barely used it.
Speaker 0: but now I see that like, you know the one generation behind us like my brother and My cousins and they all use the Facebook crazily.
Speaker 0: and I imagine that if I went to college like three years later than I did I would also be using the Facebook crazily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean It was either that or Napster.
Speaker 0: So I'll take Napster.
Speaker 1: I Wow, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Napster came and went and most people today I've never actually seen what Napster used to be it be every song ever available instantly No waiting, it just downloaded.
Speaker 0: you could find everything.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean at least everything popular.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everything that was like released by a record label in the United States was there.
Speaker 0: everything else maybe there but it was off course.
Speaker 1: Remember the win MX and the open nap days right after that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those were also good days.
Speaker 0: They're also good days, but Facebook the new hotness.
Speaker 0: I barely use my Facebook now like I Recently went on to it because it was my birthday and a bunch of people messaged me because I guess Facebook tells them that It's my birthday, but like I went in and I like oh, it's pretty nice, but I have no use for it.
Speaker 0: But if people make the right applications, well, I point out I'd suddenly have a use.
Speaker 1: I think one of the main reasons that we Personally and our group do not have a use for social networking software is that we have our own private Widely trafficked forum on the internet and that is true.
Speaker 1: We don't need anything to coordinate our social activities because we already do so actively.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the thing is the social networking sites do things besides.
Speaker 0: Coordinate social activities like.
Speaker 0: you can meet new people with similar interests in your same area and you can find people who are like Oh my god, randomly.
Speaker 0: There's a person very similar to myself that I did not know about.
Speaker 0: look at that true And that's really what the point of them is.
Speaker 0: plus I think there was a great article a long time ago That was like why social networking sites are really popular and it's because there's a you know While they probably don't do this quite often Basically the deep psychological instinct of using them is you think you're gonna get laid using them?
Speaker 0: Ah, and it the K had a pretty good case for that so well
Speaker 1: I think equally important is the idea that Culture at least when it comes to these current generations of people who are less and less tied to Localities that culture and locality are becoming very distinct from one another.
Speaker 1: I mean, I am culturally similar to all of you out there listening and all the geeks of the world.
Speaker 1: I have more in common with some D&D playing video game or geek in Norway or Japan or Australia.
Speaker 1: Then I do with 99% of the people who live within five miles of me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, think about it.
Speaker 0: ten years ago It culture was mostly at least for people who you know.
Speaker 0: I mean now it's still true for people who aren't connected.
Speaker 0: but back in the day before there was a Possibility of being connected.
Speaker 0: there were no cell phones or internets or anything commonly available.
Speaker 0: Yeah, your culture was Ninety-nine percent of the time determined by where you lived.
Speaker 0: if you lived in Argentina your culture was Argentinian.
Speaker 0: now, that's true.
Speaker 0: Still, you know most people in Argentina are probably still Argentinian in the culture.
Speaker 0: But there are people in Argentina who are so connected to the world or technology that their culture is not Argentinian.
Speaker 0: it is geek internet dig whatever.
Speaker 0: It's something else.
Speaker 1: I would say geek because we you know.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it could be anything, you know, they're not.
Speaker 0: there are other cultures that are coming into being on the internet.
Speaker 0: besides geek You know There are all sorts of other groups of people out on this internet doing things that we don't really pay attention to.
Speaker 1: well Like there's Brazilians and then there's the Orcut Brazilians.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like we have dig which is like our cultural center, I guess right now, but there are other sites like this.
Speaker 1: Well, there's the corrosion community.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's those kinds of people out there.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 1: there's all sorts of different new cultures coming into existence And I think it's wonderful these cultures couldn't have existed before.
Speaker 1: and think about how many it's kind of some internet anthropologists coming on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I
Speaker 1: mean not to draw upon this too heavily or make too many comparisons But back it during the early days of the feminist movement and the idea of the feminine mystique that a lot of people were unhappy With their lot, but they couldn't act like they were unhappy because they couldn't see any way to be happy.
Speaker 1: You see everyone else around you appears to be happy.
Speaker 1: You're the odd one out.
Speaker 1: You can't know that everyone else feels the same way you do or that there are people out there There's just like you.
Speaker 1: if you were a nerd who is into gaming and you lived in some backwater community in the 20s How are you going to be happy and find other people with similar interests or similar culture or anything?
Speaker 0: You're not going to.
Speaker 1: nowadays You can find that easily no matter where you live.
Speaker 1: if you can get on the internet You are now connected to other people who are just like you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and for better or for worse, you know, it allows the geeks to connect as well as the pedophiles.
Speaker 0: But you know, I wouldn't while that's bad.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't trade it away just to stop those people.
Speaker 1: Well, every advance has its costs and his benefits.
Speaker 1: I mean we got the printing press and we lost peasants And we gained pornography Things of the day.
Speaker 0: So how am I doing the show?
Speaker 0: pretty sick is it?
Speaker 0: is it going good?
Speaker 1: It's going okay.
Speaker 0: Okay, far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: see I'm kind of tired.
Speaker 1: I'm still also a little sick plus my RMA'd motherboard which new egg did in fact admit was broken is gonna be here tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Sounds good.
Speaker 1: So I'm not.
Speaker 1: I don't really care because I'm gonna redo all the audio and everything Prob.
Speaker 1: tomorrow's show is gonna be the last show recorded on this busted old computer.
Speaker 1: unless I have trouble setting up the new computer
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: Might even if even if all the hardware works I got to install windows and then I got to install Ubuntu and then I got to get everything working the way I want it And then I got to make sure the new sound card works.
Speaker 1: decide if I want to use the old side It's fine.
Speaker 1: all that crap.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Well people always talk about how geek nights is super egotistical and I don't really.
Speaker 0: I always ask them Well, what part of the show is egotistical?
Speaker 0: and they always don't say anything and they don't have an answer for me.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm gonna say something.
Speaker 0: egotistical you ready?
Speaker 0: You're listening to geek nights right now.
Speaker 0: this episode This is an episode.
Speaker 0: We're doing while gravely ill.
Speaker 0: not gravely ill but but ill.
Speaker 0: think about how good the show is.
Speaker 0: This is what we do and we're sick.
Speaker 0: think about what it's like when we're not sick.
Speaker 0: That's how badass we are.
Speaker 0: Everyone else sucks.
Speaker 1: now I picture our good friend Scott Johnson who is one of the.
Speaker 1: he's not a king of insults, but he's definitely a prince and He likes to say your mom a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is when other people say your mom.
Speaker 1: It's just stupid but he says it with such frequency and in such a way with such impeccable.
Speaker 0: Dick is just saying your mom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he would say I know what he would have said to what you just said.
Speaker 1: He would said something along the lines of well, I guess you've never been healthy.
Speaker 0: Oh Like a little Statler and Waldorf action something like that.
Speaker 1: All right, so that's a good thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna use it.
Speaker 0: Okay later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one no one knows about it.
Speaker 0: You didn't hear what he just said.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, you think I'm editing tonight?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So Today's Memorial Day and last Friday was actually two different holidays.
Speaker 0: It was towel day and the day of New Hope simultaneously.
Speaker 0: now You might be like what the fuck holidays are they?
Speaker 0: what kind of holidays towel day or day of New Hope?
Speaker 1: Well, it's a perfectly cromulant holiday.
Speaker 0: Absolutely cromulant.
Speaker 0: Basically one holiday is a holiday that celebrates Star Wars.
Speaker 0: cuz on Friday the 25th.
Speaker 0: not Friday But May 25th in 1977 was the day that Star Wars a New Hope opened in theaters.
Speaker 1: now for those of you who saw Star Wars in the theater When it came out, don't you feel old?
Speaker 0: You're super old.
Speaker 1: You're older than me.
Speaker 0: I wasn't alive then I wasn't.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be bored yet for five years.
Speaker 0: I wasn't even a twinkle in my daddy's eye Wasn't even not even a sperm yet.
Speaker 1: Well, you might have been a twinkle in Ron Jeremy's.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: And Also, it is towel day a day set where you must carry around a towel in celebration of Douglas Adams affinity for towels.
Speaker 1: Yes, I actually did because I was cleaning my room anyway And when I left the house, I had my tiger towel from the RIT hockey games and I brought that with me in the car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was gonna take a towel but all of my towels are too large.
Speaker 0: I needed a smaller.
Speaker 1: Well, you don't own towels you own basically bath sheets.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta get me some small towels.
Speaker 1: No, you don't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: But yeah, basically my thing of the day is I use Google Calendar Like I've never actually successfully used a calendar application in my life.
Speaker 0: Like I kept trying and none of them like stuck.
Speaker 0: like I tried to use that Mozilla Sunbird and it just I tried to use it and then I just stopped using it.
Speaker 0: but Google Calendar I'm actually using and continuing to use it's amazing.
Speaker 1: We even use it for the show And we have a Google Calendar full of every show we're doing for like the next two months.
Speaker 0: Yep But what one feature of Google Calendar is that you can find you can share your calendars.
Speaker 0: I mean if someone else has shared a calendar you can add it to your calendar view.
Speaker 1: No, we're not sharing the future of geek nights calendar.
Speaker 1: No, don't ask.
Speaker 0: Yes But for example, I have the the Scott Rubin calendar, which is the things I'm doing personally and that's sort of hidden.
Speaker 0: I have the front row crew calendar, which is like what conventions we're going to.
Speaker 0: that's public.
Speaker 0: I have the Jewish holiday calendar.
Speaker 0: just so I know even though I'm not really super Jewish I have the US holiday calendar for obvious reasons and I have the geek holiday Calendar and that is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: It is a geek holiday calendar.
Speaker 0: It will tell you every geek holiday and It's pretty useful.
Speaker 0: I mean the 27th which was yesterday was WordPress day and the next geek holiday coming up is happy ripping day on July 14th followed by Firefox day on the 15th.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So geek holidays, are you a geek?
Speaker 0: I'll break that shit.
Speaker 1: I can say I celebrate more geeky holidays than I do.
Speaker 1: I guess quote unquote real holidays.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I don't really celebrate more than any other is September 19th Of course, of course granted shouted the sky day was always a favorite, but that's a very very small Internal somewhat inside holiday.
Speaker 0: Yes, we should Dedicate we should figure out what day that is and put it on.
Speaker 1: it was hard to say because in Rochester it felt like every day Actually my second favorite sadly out of the sky day, it's every day but only in Rochester, New York.
Speaker 0: I might possibly live to see another one, but International Day of Slayer Yeah, that's a great holiday right there Sadly one of the top five holidays of the year.
Speaker 1: sadly I was unable to celebrate International Day of Slayer in the manner so prescribed by the people who invented it.
Speaker 1: I was not able to play Slayer at full volume 24/7 whilst I went about my business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would go deaf if I did that.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't think my co-workers would have liked it.
Speaker 1: I probably would have been fired and possibly killed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I did.
Speaker 0: I did play some and listen to some Slayer.
Speaker 1: on the International Day of Slayer I actually just put all of my Slayer on a loop and just played it all day and my computer whether or not I was Talking about a way to market.
Speaker 0: All right people Let's figure out which day of the year has the least geek nights listening action and make that international day of geek nights.
Speaker 0: I've asked listen to geek nights all day at full volume.
Speaker 0: So everyone else can hear it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it sounds good to me.
Speaker 0: Ram you're working on the station identifications, right?
Speaker 0: We got to put those wacky Wwek radio.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh that actually really hurt with my throat.
Speaker 1: I couldn't do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my throat was like I was sick with the throat a little bit yesterday the day before like a tiny bit But now it's gone and it's just head congestion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had a bad throat thing going.
Speaker 1: I still got a little touch of it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I have a pretty dodgy throat.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, your throat is way dodgy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're actually kind of worried.
Speaker 0: You're not sick.
Speaker 0: You're like coughing up phlegm and shit.
Speaker 1: We're actually kind of worried because we're doing a lot of live shows this summer at a couple of conventions.
Speaker 1: We're doing like three conventions in the month of July alone and we're doing like 10 or 11 December at one of these conventions.
Speaker 0: we're doing a lot of shit.
Speaker 1: now I point out that we both lost our voices at one convention where we did One live show.
Speaker 0: Well, we lost it before the live show.
Speaker 1: Yes the live show was when we went into Overdrive and kicked it up to 11 by drugging ourselves so that we could actually make our live appearance Thanks to the halls of medicine.
Speaker 0: Yeah next year though.
Speaker 0: We should use Rico.
Speaker 1: Actually, I think joke about it We should find because there are a lot of experts in the area find professional speech therapists and get vocal training.
Speaker 0: It's a little bit of money and time.
Speaker 1: It's not that expensive.
Speaker 0: I don't have that right now.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna look into it because we could probably learn how to do this better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll look at to the SSR first then then we'll talk.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway, uh We were sick and all that and I realized that nothing makes a sickness or a bad day feel somewhat mitigated Better than making someone else feel just as bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and thus my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Emily showed this to me and she wasn't quite sure what to make of it other than she was laughing hysterically And I watched it and I'm also not sure what to make.
Speaker 0: I was laughing hysterically.
Speaker 1: I was laughing but more in that Like you know when the Joker kills you with this horrible gas and you laugh just before you die.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is that is how I was laughing but only on the inside.
Speaker 1: It's just watch the video.
Speaker 1: I linked to.
Speaker 1: it's about Willow and when I say willow, I don't mean hot willow from that vampire Buffy whatever show I mean Lucas Arts will Teeny baby.
Speaker 1: Yes, that willow the best willow as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: If you haven't seen that movie go get it now.
Speaker 1: the little peckers gonna throw an acorn at me.
Speaker 0: I barely remember it, but I remember it.
Speaker 1: Oh god, I could do a show about that.
Speaker 1: I got to see it again But then I could do a show but put it in the Netflix queue and we'll do a show whenever we get to that point In the queue.
Speaker 0: All right, also ten years from now when it comes up We'll realize how long and you know Because think about it in like I don't know maybe five years they'll be like up.
Speaker 0: It's the 25th anniversary of willow special edition DVD.
Speaker 1: That'll do it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's what's gonna get us.
Speaker 1: So, uh, all right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no last week on the show.
Speaker 0: Oh, did you do your thing of the day?
Speaker 1: I was in the middle.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow, you didn't.
Speaker 0: I was trying to jump ahead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you were.
Speaker 0: oh that's apples when I'm sick.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 1: Okay, I wasn't gonna say much more other than I'm not sure what to make of this.
Speaker 0: There are some things I know about it and that these are the kind of people I see at gaming conventions.
Speaker 0: They're scary and I don't like them But at the same time they are geeks and they are sort of like our distant cousins.
Speaker 1: I could get the sense that it was done in jest.
Speaker 1: However, the fact that I am not 100% certain that this was done entirely in jest is what Confuses and disturbs me.
Speaker 0: and even if it was done in jest it doesn't jest me it disturbs me.
Speaker 1: So granted I watched the whole thing I did.
Speaker 1: I was somewhat entertained because rim didn't close the window Yeah, but I noticed that you didn't violently protest.
Speaker 0: I somewhat protested.
Speaker 0: I said why are we still watching this like three times as you kept watching?
Speaker 1: you could have averted your eyes But you didn't.
Speaker 0: it was.
Speaker 0: it was like it wasn't like goat see where I have to or tub girl Where I have to avert my eyes, it was kind of like looking into the Ark of the Covenant Kind of kind of.
Speaker 1: uh, I I now I did a little bit of research I found I tracked down more about who did it, but I haven't really tracked down why and If any of you feel like figuring out the whole story and telling us exactly what this is all about I would be I guess grateful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, watch the video and you'll see what I mean.
Speaker 1: And in the very least I know you're gonna say and try to stop watching and it's not sick or anything.
Speaker 1: Don't worry about that It's just about willow to music video.
Speaker 1: Don't stop watching until you've at least seen some of the music video part because the first bit is just lead up to the music Video, I don't understand how it was lead up.
Speaker 0: as far as I was concerned It was just the stuff that happened before the music video part.
Speaker 0: It had no meaning or relation to the music video whatsoever as far as I could tell.
Speaker 1: but oh she shall sing.
Speaker 0: Yes, all right.
Speaker 0: So last week we were trying to do a theme week the how to get into it week where we told you how to get Into various geekeries if you are not into them, unfortunately starting starting on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: It was how to get into throat infections Yeah, so as a result it was a theme half-week.
Speaker 0: well That's good for us because that's actually a theme week with I think we have more than four ideas for.
Speaker 0: Therefore we have decided to go easy on ourselves and hopefully entertaining for you and continue it to make it a theme week and a half.
Speaker 0: And today we will talk about something people have clamored for quite a bit how to get into Computer programming.
Speaker 0: now, I am a computer programmer.
Speaker 0: I am NOT rim is not so I'm a best computer scripter Yes, so I think the best way to start out is.
Speaker 0: a lot of people out there They they talk about coding and programming this but they don't really know what programming is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean a lot of people say things like yeah, I was coding HTML the other day and that's not really coding it It's a really it's a different thing.
Speaker 0: Yes Basically you have a chip in your computer and it's a Pentium or a. what a cord to or an AMD whatever it is.
Speaker 0: It's a freaking I don't know.
Speaker 1: Apple - it's an x86.
Speaker 0: Yeah it's some chip of some sort and that chip has a bunch of wires going into it.
Speaker 0: a lot of them like hundreds of them and They're the in wires.
Speaker 0: They're also out wires, but don't worry about those and You can either on any of those wires.
Speaker 0: You can choose to send electricity or not send electricity.
Speaker 0: and let's say you have I don't know a three gigahertz Processor.
Speaker 0: every second the chip will look at those wires Three three billion times to see what's there?
Speaker 0: So you basically have to change what the what whether those wires have electricity or not.
Speaker 0: three billion times a second the chip will depending on which wires are on and which wires are off do something inside of itself and then output something on the other end on the output wires, which are many and Computer programming in as best as I can tell you is Controlling the what whether those wires are on or off.
Speaker 0: Does that sound exciting to you now luckily?
Speaker 1: programming has advanced a long way and there are many layers of Programming between the physical chip and you and your application.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you can roughly break it up into low level and high level.
Speaker 0: yes, when people talk about people talk about things like assembly language and Basically what because we have modern technology.
Speaker 0: back in the day people really did like an ENIAC.
Speaker 0: They would literally turn all these inputs on and off and then push a button then turn them all on switch them all again Push a button and repeat that process many times.
Speaker 0: then they had punch cards or basically you would punch the cards Which switches you want switched at which times you fed the cards into the machine and depending on what you punched It would turn them on and off.
Speaker 1: I mean now at the bottom you've got machine code, which is literally just ones and zeros.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll just in a row but now thanks to modern technology you can type on a computer things that look almost like English words or sometimes our English words and That will be translated for you by existing programs into the sequence of turning the switches on and off.
Speaker 0: So programming is typing in the words Or whatever depending on which language you choose into the computer that tell the computer what to do and That is how you make software.
Speaker 0: It's how Microsoft Word is made.
Speaker 0: It's how Firefox is made.
Speaker 0: That's how Pokemon is made.
Speaker 0: So World of Warcraft is made.
Speaker 0: all those things are made By someone typing words into the computer that tell it which switches to turn on and off when to and then that's it.
Speaker 1: Now we're not gonna go into a lot more detail than that about how programming works or different languages because that is not the show We're not talking about to it.
Speaker 1: What programming is?
Speaker 1: we're talking about how to become a programmer.
Speaker 0: Yep Well becoming a programmer is sort of tricky because a lot of people say ah, what language should I learn?
Speaker 0: I learn this language.
Speaker 0: I learn that language and I always tell them you shouldn't learn a language.
Speaker 0: Don't learn a language because when you learn a language, you don't learn anything about languages.
Speaker 0: It's like if you learn say French right you learn French specifically You're not gonna also know Spanish or also know Italian by magic.
Speaker 0: But if you learn Latin languages, you will know French Spanish Italian and all other similar Latin based languages Very easily if you learn the more generic concepts behind Latin based languages.
Speaker 1: also to extend the analogy in America the United States when people learn English Part of this is because the American educational system people don't actually learn a lot of the finer finer points of grammar or why things Are the way they are.
Speaker 1: they just learn English because they use it all the time.
Speaker 1: so people have a working knowledge of English, but they don't really understand the hows and whys.
Speaker 1: and I can say that I learned a lot more about English language when I studied French than I ever did in any English class.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because by learning and learning about things like conjugation which they don't teach you about English conjugation But they taught me about Spanish conjugation when I took it for like in middle school in high school And then I said hey English has conjugation - look at that.
Speaker 1: And I guess much more important in programming as with language then learning how to do a specific thing in a specific language is Learning what things there are to do what generic ways there are to do them and just the basics of how programming works.
Speaker 0: Yep Okay, so there are many different ideas for how programming languages should work.
Speaker 0: there are procedural languages There are functional languages there assembly languages, whatever.
Speaker 1: what about those semi vs?
Speaker 1: Yeah, aspect oriented programming language?
Speaker 0: There are lots of different theories as to how a language should work, and I'm not going to talk about language theory But there are languages that work on different principles from others.
Speaker 0: now for example C is a functional language.
Speaker 0: So is Pascal?
Speaker 0: if you learn just see you'll know.
Speaker 0: see if you learn Pascal you'll know Pascal.
Speaker 0: But if you learn the concepts of functional programming languages It won't be very difficult for you to make programs in C or Pascal.
Speaker 0: if you have a book that tells you the syntax Which is just which words do you type which is not nothing you need to remember?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you know a book or the internet to tell you if you know what you want to do And you know what language you're using you have a reference no matter who you are.
Speaker 1: You can just follow the book and make it do what you wanted it to do But you're not gonna learn a lot from doing that.
Speaker 0: yep in the modern world we have developed a new relatively new like in the 90s Theory of computer programming languages that allows for a type of language called the object oriented language.
Speaker 0: I could talk a whole show about object oriented languages and someday.
Speaker 0: I will if someone posted in the forums, but Object oriented languages?
Speaker 0: they thought it was a fad.
Speaker 0: And it's not.
Speaker 0: object orientation is the way that most programming languages work.
Speaker 0: It is the proper way to write programs these days.
Speaker 0: It is the.
Speaker 0: an object oriented language is the is the language of choice for most applications.
Speaker 0: It is the prevailing Everything and what you should.
Speaker 0: if you go to any school object orientation is the first thing they will teach you is the first thing They taught me at RIT.
Speaker 0: This is what they taught me in high school.
Speaker 0: This is what they teach.
Speaker 0: It's what people use.
Speaker 0: So if you want to become a computer programmer and first decide if some programming is something you really want to do based on what?
Speaker 0: I said before and then learn the fundamental principles of object oriented design Like what is an object?
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: What is an object method?
Speaker 0: How do you private and public in?
Speaker 0: Polymorphism Instantiation yeah all those.
Speaker 0: when you learn those concepts of Object how oriented laying object orientation works?
Speaker 0: You will be able to pick up any object oriented language and use it like.
Speaker 0: I had to do a job once and I need To learn Ruby.
Speaker 0: I didn't know Ruby.
Speaker 0: I picked up a book and the book had the syntax of Ruby in.
Speaker 0: it was actually online.
Speaker 0: I learned Ruby in a week because I already knew how object oriented languages worked and this is an object oriented language, so I just looked at it, and I drew on what I already knew.
Speaker 0: and There you go.
Speaker 0: I know Ruby.
Speaker 0: if you give me a book on any object oriented language I can pretty much write a program in it almost immediately.
Speaker 0: And if you want to be able to do that don't learn like I'm gonna learn PHP or I'm gonna learn C++.
Speaker 0: don't do that.
Speaker 0: That's that's basically.
Speaker 0: It's like learning how to use one tool.
Speaker 0: That's like saying I'm gonna be a carpenter I'm gonna learn how to use a screwdriver.
Speaker 0: You don't learn how to use a screwdriver.
Speaker 0: you learn how to use tools in general and then you can pick up any tool And you know how to use it.
Speaker 0: and then depending on what job you have Let's say you come up to a job and the job is to hammer a nail into the wall.
Speaker 0: Well, I only learned how to use a screwdriver.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: I guess you could get a nail into a wall with a screwdriver.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and by the same token you can write whatever you want to write in Visual Basic if you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you could write a website in Visual Basic.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be pleasant for you.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be like hammering a nail into the wall with a screwdriver.
Speaker 1: I have done both yep.
Speaker 0: So if you know the correct a bunch of languages and the generic concepts of languages You can pick the right tool for the job.
Speaker 0: if you need to write a big production website You can learn.
Speaker 0: you know PHP or Python inside a day.
Speaker 0: if you need to make some like Linux kernel module you can learn C pretty quick even though C is an object oriented.
Speaker 0: But you know you can learn these things very quickly once you understand the fundamentals.
Speaker 1: So I guess along those lines don't just think of.
Speaker 1: you know you want to learn the fundamentals of programming.
Speaker 1: basically Which kind of is easier to say than to do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you don't learn how to drive a Ford Taurus.
Speaker 0: you learn how to drive, and then you can drive anything.
Speaker 0: That's how programming languages are.
Speaker 1: well see almost anything because you still can't drive the semi-truck cuz that's okay I drive the semi-truck.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: and some programming languages in the same way.
Speaker 0: yep I can't just suddenly write assembly if you can do Python and PHP.
Speaker 0: But anyway if you want to learn these things there is actually one place I recommend you go to start out and determine if you actually are going to like programming.
Speaker 0: don't do it.
Speaker 0: Don't continue to do it if you don't like it, but there is a book.
Speaker 0: you can read it online for free.
Speaker 0: It is distributed with the GNU free documentation license And it is called how to think like a computer scientist.
Speaker 0: if you just search Google for how to think like a computer scientist You'll find it right away.
Speaker 0: I'll link to it in the forum or on the site or something and it uses Python Which is pretty easy to get and it works on Mac and Linux and Windows.
Speaker 0: just fine.
Speaker 1: Python is great.
Speaker 0: I gotta say it's really good for learners because you can just type Python on the command line and then type in Python code And it'll immediately be interpreted and executed.
Speaker 0: Yep You'll be able to learn how different Python commands work very easily with that.
Speaker 0: so that
Speaker 1: was a big Frustration a lot of people I remember had in IT when I was taking Java classes because I was one of the last classes where All the programming we did just by the Institute policy Was visual basic and then they turned it into Java right after I'd finished all that crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I took a Java class just to learn Java and force myself to because I wouldn't have learned it on my own I wouldn't have bothered and a lot of people had trouble Because you actually have to do a lot to make Java do some pretty basic things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Java is really a language.
Speaker 0: It's object oriented, but it's designed for large enterprise applications.
Speaker 0: So if you're not making a large enterprise application with it, it's sort of cumbersome.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean like trying to chop like cut down your tomato plant with a chainsaw Like my experience of using Java would say you want to make a big GUI interface for something in Java.
Speaker 1: The amount of effort it took to make one button in the upper like just one button that you clicked on Versus the effort to make an entire GUI It was practically the same because once you put up you had you spent more time doing the framework than the actual bits inside Of the framework.
Speaker 0: So if you want to get into computer programming I recommend if you're still like a high school kid take every high school class that your school has available.
Speaker 0: I don't care how shitty it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because they still shitty but you'll learn something.
Speaker 1: Also, you might meet the smart computer instructor who will give you a little help on the side.
Speaker 1: Yep Learn
Speaker 0: take this book that I just linked to the how to think like a computer scientist and just go through it from beginning to end and as long as you're still interested in having fun, you know that you're gonna like this business and That'll learn you a whole lot like a lot more than most people who graduate from college.
Speaker 0: No It's kind of sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Then if you really like it, of course going to college even like a community college is not a bad idea.
Speaker 0: And of course if you go to the bookstore, there are books with animals on them.
Speaker 0: They're the O'Reilly books.
Speaker 0: Oh really by O'Reilly?
Speaker 0: Yes, don't buy books.
Speaker 0: pretty much I mean there are good books published by other companies.
Speaker 0: But you really can't go wrong with an O'Reilly book like I. own many of them and they're all awesome as references or as learning tools or whatever.
Speaker 0: and If you give me an O'Reilly book on anything the computer related because I think most of them are computer related I will learn that thing as fast as I can read that book if not faster.
Speaker 0: So if you want to learn say I don't know pearl.
Speaker 0: go out and there's a book called learning pearl or like programming pearl and has a picture of like a camel on it.
Speaker 0: and that book if you read it will learn you pearl and It's well worth like the 30 or whatever dollars.
Speaker 0: They charge for the thing buy it on Amazon to get a discount.
Speaker 1: And I think on that note just because we're tired and sick and I gotta go to bed Hey, we have work tomorrow and such that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's because it's really that's all you need to do to get into programming.
Speaker 0: There's so much free information on the internet because of open source stuff that you could just learn it.
Speaker 0: if you want to everything you need is out there all The tools all the software all the everything.
Speaker 1: I guess the only other tips are one have some sort of goal in mind like we've said with a lot of young.
Speaker 1: Otherwise you just you'll stop putting the effort in.
Speaker 0: Yep That's I always find that even though I know how to write software If I don't have a specific goal in mind like if I sit down and say I'm gonna learn Pearl down I can't actually learn it.
Speaker 0: I just don't do it.
Speaker 0: You know, I just play a game or something.
Speaker 0: instead if I actually have a goal like I am going to make this thing Using this then I will actually end up learning the thing in the act of accomplishing the goal and it has to be a goal I really want.
Speaker 0: though if it's a goal I don't really want I'll just give up because I don't want to do it.
Speaker 0: so find something software or something you actually want to make badly and then Figure out what the best tool for the job is and just do it and you'll learn in the process of the doing.
Speaker 0: I think that's all I got.
Speaker 0: I gotta go to bed.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.