Speaker 1: Well, it's that time again.
Speaker 1: We way back at some point in the past did a week of questions.
Speaker 1: You asked your questions, we answered them.
Speaker 1: And it went really well.
Speaker 1: We got a lot of feedback.
Speaker 1: People seemed to really enjoy that.
Speaker 1: But another interesting thing was that we got way more questions than we could answer in about an hour for every single day.
Speaker 0: And rather than filter out some of the questions, we just decided to answer a lot of them at some point in the future and then save those up for other episodes.
Speaker 0: This way, answering questions is basically a piece of cake.
Speaker 0: So making more than one episode, hey, less work for us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, every time we appear on someone else's show or we get interviewed by anyone, it's super fun.
Speaker 1: And I guess basically our ulterior motive was we tricked all of you into interviewing us.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, just so anyone knows, if this is the first time listening to Geek Nights, I don't know if you might be entertained by this episode, but it's not our typical format.
Speaker 0: Try listening to a different show and you will hear the news and the things of the day and all the other things we usually put in an episode when we don't cop out.
Speaker 1: This is totally a cop out.
Speaker 1: We're recording this on a very sad day.
Speaker 1: If you knew what night we were recording this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but basically we're just going to read these questions and then answer them in any way we feel like.
Speaker 0: We can also opt not to answer them or do whatever the hell we want.
Speaker 0: We're not going to give anyone credit for asking the questions, because if you ask the question, you know who you are.
Speaker 0: And if you didn't ask the question, you don't care who asked it because not you.
Speaker 1: So the only final thing I'll say is that we didn't look at these questions ahead of time.
Speaker 1: So we have no idea what's coming here and we have no sort of research ready.
Speaker 1: So here we go.
Speaker 0: As the first question.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: You have a one shot time machine.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: It will irreparably break once used.
Speaker 1: When will you go?
Speaker 1: If any time?
Speaker 0: now I got the answer.
Speaker 1: I have a very clever answer.
Speaker 0: I have the most.
Speaker 0: I have the same maybe the same answer as you.
Speaker 1: is your answer.
Speaker 1: I would go back in time exactly one year and win a million lotteries.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: Is that your answer?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: My answer is go into the future to wear.
Speaker 0: non one shot time machines exist so I can get the hell back.
Speaker 0: Because if a one shot time machine is.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's fine.
Speaker 1: And how are you going to buy it?
Speaker 1: You don't have any future money.
Speaker 1: You don't have any space dollars.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I have this antique first ever one shot time machine I can sell to a museum.
Speaker 1: And you know what they'll say?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got a million of these.
Speaker 1: Everyone had the same idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The four other hundred scots that showed up.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 1: That would be horrible future.
Speaker 1: There is zero risk with my option, which is become infinitely wealthy beyond your wildest dreams.
Speaker 1: Be the count of Monte Cristo, but not have to engage in horrible revenge.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess I just feel like going to the future, even though there's a risk of a horrible future, the benefits, if it works out, are so much better than the boring known past, because most of the interesting interesting things in life are discovering previously unknown things or new experiences in the past holds far less new things than the future.
Speaker 1: Well, but the immediate.
Speaker 1: basically, instead of traveling through time, what you do is travel through money on the money scale.
Speaker 1: You become more money and then you can use that money to do great things in your normal life and you can hang out with yourself in the past and cause some sort of paradise.
Speaker 0: See all the money in the world doesn't help me if all the cell phones suck.
Speaker 0: If I go one hundred years in the future to when we have brain phones, I'll just get a normal job and a brain phone.
Speaker 0: I'll actually be better off because think about it.
Speaker 0: Us in this current time with our normal amount of money are just about.
Speaker 0: I mean, we're maybe not as comfortable as the Roman emperor was more comfortable than many wealthy Romans were.
Speaker 0: So going into the future, I could probably be have an average income, but live better than Bill Gates does now are.
Speaker 1: The only problem is that you don't have any resources.
Speaker 1: You'll basically be like a job.
Speaker 1: How you'll be like the Terminator when he came back in time, naked and alone.
Speaker 0: The Terminator did pretty well for himself.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: After he killed that guy, I got to have a job.
Speaker 0: Your job is assassinating.
Speaker 0: My job would be guy from the past at the freak show.
Speaker 1: Clothes.
Speaker 1: Give them to me.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So what do you think about this next question?
Speaker 0: Oh, what do I think about the next professional Korean Starcraft league?
Speaker 0: I guess if you really like Starcraft, it's cool.
Speaker 1: I foresee a future where video games are pretty much considered the same as sports are now in popular culture.
Speaker 1: I just foresee that being a long ways out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I like how they respect video games as a worthwhile endeavor.
Speaker 0: that and how they you know, they can show the video games can be a good spectator activity as well as a player activity.
Speaker 0: But personally, I'm just not interested in Starcraft or real time strategy games in general.
Speaker 0: So I'm not all into it, but I respect it.
Speaker 1: I'm very interested in RTS is the problem is I don't think anyone has made a truly good one yet.
Speaker 0: That's that's what I mean.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now you might say, oh, but such and such is good.
Speaker 1: And yeah, it is good, but it's not at that level where it would be something transcendent.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: RTS is of a long way to go.
Speaker 0: I think also personally, like, well, I do think there is some video games where spectating is awesome, as is verified by watching, like, you know, people, videos of people playing video games on YouTube.
Speaker 0: And it's awesome.
Speaker 0: I personally don't.
Speaker 0: I tried to watch like like a championship round.
Speaker 1: It was a Starcraft game.
Speaker 0: I watched like two Korean champions play Starcraft in the championship round on YouTube at some tournament.
Speaker 0: And I didn't get the hell what was going on at all.
Speaker 0: And it made no sense to me.
Speaker 0: And it was not interesting.
Speaker 0: But if I understood Starcraft, it might be a lot more interesting.
Speaker 1: Oh, you mentioned you do audio filters on your podcast.
Speaker 1: Which do you use?
Speaker 1: How does the script that you use to publish your podcast look like?
Speaker 0: That was how does it look?
Speaker 0: It doesn't have eyes, so it doesn't look like anything.
Speaker 0: It looks a lot like a car does not at all.
Speaker 1: It's it's funny that we got this question now, because, you see, up until about three nights ago, we recorded the show a certain way.
Speaker 1: And now that I have this brand new mixer and all this new equipment and I'm doing everything completely differently, I can answer this kind of briefly and vaguely.
Speaker 1: The thing is, every time people ask me this, I give an answer and then they say, no, but specifically, what settings do you use?
Speaker 1: So I have to preface this by saying that telling anyone what specific settings you use is not going to help anyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone's like, you know, they want to say, OK, they want us to tell them set this knob at one point five.
Speaker 0: Now said this knob at two point five, like there's some sort of magic setting where everything will sound great.
Speaker 0: Listen up.
Speaker 0: If there was some magic setting where you could I could tell you set this knob at this is knob at that and it'll sound great, then we wouldn't need the knobs.
Speaker 0: They would just sell a little box where audio crap audio comes in and great audio comes out and the knob settings already be set.
Speaker 0: The reason there are knobs is because everyone needs to put the knobs in a different place.
Speaker 0: So you need to learn what the knobs do and learn how to figure out where to put the knobs and what to set the settings at.
Speaker 0: It's different for everybody.
Speaker 1: Wow, Scott, you suddenly have a lot more knob respect than you did before when you were yelling at me for fiddling with knobs.
Speaker 0: OK, but you should not sit there yelling late into the night into your microphone at the top of your voice, fiddling with knobs while people are trying to sleep.
Speaker 1: Your light was on.
Speaker 1: You were definitely not trying to sleep.
Speaker 0: I would have read a lot less comics if you were yelling less.
Speaker 1: But basically we record geek nights through our microphones and pre amplifiers and all that.
Speaker 1: And then actually, I'm just going to tell you how we do it now with the new set up.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So then through the inserts that goes through a compressor, Scott and I each have our own noise gate and compressor.
Speaker 1: that right now are set the same, but I'm going to tweak them over time as I get more data as to how to make it sound better.
Speaker 1: And then it pretty much just gets recorded by our USB sound card into Audacity now instead of Resound.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: I feel bad about that because Resound is a thousand times the program Audacity will ever even pretend to be.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, Resound doesn't fucking work half the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What can we do?
Speaker 1: Mainly it's that Resound can't deal with most kinds of audio input.
Speaker 1: But regardless, I take the audio and I open it up in Resound after I've recorded it.
Speaker 1: And basically Resound has this facility that lets you make the equivalent of like the macros you used to make in the windows three one days.
Speaker 1: So I tell it, you know, I have.
Speaker 1: first I open all the files.
Speaker 1: So all the music, intro, exit bits, everything, the opener, the closer, the thing, everything we recorded by a script.
Speaker 1: And then I run another script that takes all these WAV files, puts them together exactly as they need to go in the right order, and then runs all the right filters on them.
Speaker 1: The filters are as follows.
Speaker 1: First, I use a low pass filter, sorry, a low cut filter, which gets rid of, you know, bumps and clicks and some breathing noise and any sort of hum or anything like that noise that no human voice is making.
Speaker 1: So you're not missing anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like human voices are between this frequency and that frequency.
Speaker 0: So if you remove all noise below the low frequency, there's no there.
Speaker 0: if there's noise down there, it can't possibly be human voice.
Speaker 0: So it's just gone.
Speaker 0: And it, you know, if there's happens to be a bad noise down there, it's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: Now I'm experimenting, experimenting with hardware low cut instead of software.
Speaker 1: But anyway, just to do it before the compressor and everything.
Speaker 1: Then I run a low pass filter, which gets rid of the high end hissy stuff that you wouldn't hear again or care about anyway.
Speaker 0: Same thing, only high up.
Speaker 0: As long as no one goes, it'll be fine.
Speaker 1: Then I run another compressor.
Speaker 1: The compressor on the recording is just to keep the peaks down so I can record a really hot signal.
Speaker 1: I run a second gentler compressor just to kind of even out the volume.
Speaker 1: So if I get a little quieter or louder or Scott gets a little quieter or louder or we yell, the volume is all kind of the same.
Speaker 1: So it's not like some podcast where you just can't hear what people are saying
Speaker 0: or some podcast where the music is really loud and then you get to turn the volume up and it's changed the volume all the time while you listen to the show and this podcast, you set your volume once and you're all good.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And then after that, I run my make room and Scott sound smarter filter, which I've explained this before, but basically it just goes through the audio and removes very tiny amounts of silence between words and phrases in just a little bit to make it sound like we're a lot more on top of things than we otherwise might be.
Speaker 1: It's very, very subtle.
Speaker 1: You'd be hard pressed to tell if I ran it or not.
Speaker 0: I think it really helps to keep the attention of all those YouTube generation audience people.
Speaker 1: You know, what it really helps for is when we interview people, because people who aren't used to being on the radio are not often the best at just keeping their train of thought going and that sort of filter.
Speaker 1: As Jeff to Terryk said to me after we interviewed him, wow, I sounded a lot smarter in that show than I do in real life.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: We're done.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Beyond that, whatever.
Speaker 1: You don't care.
Speaker 0: What bands and music do you listen to?
Speaker 0: Lots.
Speaker 1: I think there's an easier way to answer this.
Speaker 0: What don't we listen to?
Speaker 1: I don't like a lot of modern gangsta style hip hop.
Speaker 0: I like hip hop and rap and such, but most of the modern, you know, gangsta stuff that you see on MTV and whatever I do not like.
Speaker 1: However, I like French gangster rap.
Speaker 1: I do maybe because I don't understand all of what they're saying.
Speaker 0: I do not like country music, but I like Western music.
Speaker 1: I really like Western music, but I don't dislike country music.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm also, I don't think you like folk.
Speaker 0: No, not really a fan of folk, but I like some.
Speaker 0: I like folk rock, but I don't like folk so much.
Speaker 0: Uh, and I guess I'm not really the biggest fan of like old contemporary kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: But other than that, what do you mean?
Speaker 1: old contemporary?
Speaker 1: That doesn't mean anything.
Speaker 0: Like if you turn on, you know, this is the oldies station, but nowadays the oldies station plays the Beatles.
Speaker 0: If you put on the double oldies station, which plays Elvis, right.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: If you put in the triple oldies station that my grandma listens to that I do not like.
Speaker 1: Well, how much is that doggy in the window?
Speaker 0: Well, a little after that, but before Sinatra, sort of that in between stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: That didn't really describe a genre of music to me.
Speaker 0: I know it's, it's, it, I don't know what to call it except contemporary.
Speaker 0: Cause that's what it's called.
Speaker 1: I really like most classical and I really, really like Baroque music and I fugues anything with organs.
Speaker 1: I just love.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't know the different genres of the classical musics, like the, the Baroques and the, I can tell you this classical music is a sub genre, not a genre.
Speaker 0: I romanticism impressionism impressionisms.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure which ones I like.
Speaker 0: tone poems like Franz Liszt, but I like lots of them.
Speaker 0: I like Dvorak.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no.
Speaker 0: And I like Tchaikovsky.
Speaker 1: What about, what about my man Rimsky-Korsakov?
Speaker 0: I don't know who that is.
Speaker 0: I like Bach, the, the famous one, not the other one.
Speaker 1: The other one's also famous.
Speaker 1: The third and fourth ones aren't famous.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: And, uh, I like the Choppin.
Speaker 0: I like the Choppin.
Speaker 1: And some S. Kargatne Chablis.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: The Choppin and you know, all those guys.
Speaker 0: I like lots of music.
Speaker 1: What about, uh, what's his name?
Speaker 1: Mussorgsky?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: He did, uh, I think you know, I think you know him quite well.
Speaker 0: I guess if you really want to see the music I listen to like a percentage wise, just go to last.fm and look at what I listen to.
Speaker 1: I mean, right now, what I listen to, I listen to a lot of Ska.
Speaker 1: I've been listening to a lot of seventies disco because I really like disco.
Speaker 0: I like disco too.
Speaker 1: I got some Boney M. I've been rocking it up with Boney M.
Speaker 0: Lately.
Speaker 0: I've been listening to the Who and the Beastie Boys lately.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I've also been listening to a lot of Queen.
Speaker 0: It's hard not to listen to Queen.
Speaker 1: And the Ghost in the Shell soundtrack just because it's great.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's really great.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Can you pick a favorite song of all time?
Speaker 0: No, I can pick a favorite song of like the moment.
Speaker 1: I really, really, really like Fly High by Ayumi Hamasaki.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Some of her songs I like a lot too, but I don't think any of them would be even close to favorite status.
Speaker 1: That one in particular, it's one of those rare songs where the lyrics, I mean, the song's really good, but then I read the lyrics and they were actually surprisingly kind of meaningful.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's weird because there's a lot of, there's no song.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is a few songs, but Stairway, you know, but it's like, you know, you listen to songs and there's certain parts of the song that make you go like, yeah, but some parts of some songs don't make you go.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: And it seems like all those yes.
Speaker 0: It's sort of equally maximize.
Speaker 0: So the best song ever would just be all those amazing parts.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The thing is, we're not saying best song, we're saying our favorites.
Speaker 1: I guess we get the songs.
Speaker 1: We really like painted black.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, like for me to make a favorite song thing to be like, if I had a top 100 list, it would be a hundred songs all tied for number one.
Speaker 1: Pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: If you wrote a novel song, play movie, what would be the theme?
Speaker 0: What would be the theme?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I think they meant theme and in some sort of colloquial sense, but I'm gonna use theme in a more literary sense.
Speaker 1: I would probably make something that shows the dangers of anti-intellectualism.
Speaker 0: Oh, you stole my idea.
Speaker 1: I would just pick something that I was like, you know, or something along the lines of one man can walk forward on his own two legs.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Something like I would just pick something that was like bothering me lately and then try to get that message across and then make some and then something else bothering me.
Speaker 0: I try to get that message across and so on.
Speaker 1: I thought I've always I have a couple ideas for stories.
Speaker 1: I've thought about a lot of times and every time I sit down to write him, I decide I can't write and I give up.
Speaker 0: I can't write.
Speaker 1: Oh, speaking of which, this next one's kind of relevant.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What do you think a fan fiction ever write?
Speaker 0: one?
Speaker 1: Well, to the latter, no, actually.
Speaker 0: Oh, huh.
Speaker 1: Ready for this?
Speaker 1: I'm ready.
Speaker 0: When I was like a kid, right?
Speaker 0: Like way kid, like, I don't know, 12, maybe.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember.
Speaker 0: Maybe 10.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: 10 months ago.
Speaker 0: I think that's 10 years when I was 10 years old.
Speaker 0: So like 1992.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I like.
Speaker 0: I didn't even understand.
Speaker 0: I didn't even realize fan fiction existed or was a thing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But I had like school supplies and I like school supplies and I like using them, you know, so I had some paper and had a binder and I thought I kind of wanted to use it.
Speaker 0: I had a nice new pen.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, all right, something.
Speaker 0: And since I can't write, you know, whatever, I said, oh, I have a genius idea.
Speaker 0: I'll write a story about the Transformers.
Speaker 1: But this I did not know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this has been hidden secret for many years.
Speaker 0: It's not like a secret or anything.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway, it's a secret to everyone to make it even funnier.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I I hadn't even like seen Transformers in like eight years at that point.
Speaker 0: So I barely remembered anything except like Megatron was a god.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: So you were 10 and you hadn't seen Transformers in like eight years.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So you had watched Transformers when you were two.
Speaker 0: And I must say, I watched it long enough ago that I didn't remember.
Speaker 0: OK, at that time, I remember it more now than I remember that.
Speaker 1: And if that's I'm just doing some police work here to figure out when this actually happened, I was to check it out.
Speaker 0: So like one day I was sitting there and I wrote like two pages and it was basically like there was an evil secret lab.
Speaker 0: Megatron told the scientists to make something evil, but he didn't want to.
Speaker 0: But then he did that.
Speaker 0: Then I stopped.
Speaker 0: And then that was it.
Speaker 1: That's kind of saga.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think saga.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then I stopped writing and then I never started doing it again.
Speaker 0: because what do you mean?
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to.
Speaker 0: And I sucked at writing.
Speaker 0: I didn't care.
Speaker 0: I didn't remember anything about Transformers.
Speaker 0: I friend.
Speaker 0: And then later when fan fiction came around, I thought back to that and said, oh, I was not an original idea to use someone else's make a story.
Speaker 1: See, frankly, fan fiction doesn't bother me at all.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's easy to make fun of, but people can do whatever they want.
Speaker 0: It's cool.
Speaker 0: You can it's creative endeavors.
Speaker 0: You're just borrowing someone's characters.
Speaker 0: It's like doujinshi.
Speaker 0: It's cool.
Speaker 0: I think she has drawing also.
Speaker 1: The reason fan fiction is so maligned is that to be perfectly blunt, ninety nine percent of it is is so vile.
Speaker 1: And I'm not even talking about the erotic fan fiction, just beyond the tail.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not so much the content, right, that it happens to be sexual or violent.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's written poorly.
Speaker 0: Oh, and that it's written poorly.
Speaker 0: The thing that bothers me the most about most fan fiction is that it's not actually someone trying to write a story to entertain others.
Speaker 0: It's someone else who has some sort of fantasy about fictional characters like living out their fantasy and putting a dot on paper for the world to see.
Speaker 0: And I guess I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's sort of disturbing.
Speaker 0: It's it's like, why are you showing me your horrible fantasy?
Speaker 0: And then why is your fantasy horrible?
Speaker 0: Why isn't your fantasy nice?
Speaker 1: See, now, that doesn't bother me either.
Speaker 1: I mean, people.
Speaker 1: I think it's cool that people have that, you know, have things like that.
Speaker 1: I think the only problem with fan fiction is that most fan fiction isn't really fan fiction like.
Speaker 1: it'll have cloud and Sephiroth in it, but they don't act like cloud or Sephiroth.
Speaker 1: They have nothing to do with fun.
Speaker 1: It might as well be two other people with different names.
Speaker 1: It's like they write a story that has nothing to do with the thing they're so supposedly writing a fan work about.
Speaker 1: And then they say it's about this fan work.
Speaker 1: It's it's like, why not just write your own story if it has nothing to do with your source material to begin with?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, moving on.
Speaker 1: You might have already talked about this in passing episodes, so I can't that blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's a long question.
Speaker 1: In your opinions, at what point does a work move from being derivative to something being in the same genre of something, i.e.
Speaker 1: when does something stop being a clone of Lensman, Lord of the Rings, Resident Evil and start being space opera sort of?
Speaker 1: Is it shameless copy?
Speaker 0: I'm saying, you know, because you have two pieces of art, right?
Speaker 0: And they have things in common.
Speaker 1: I can actually I can answer this pretty simply.
Speaker 1: When a genre is defined by a work, do other works become derivative or are they in that genre?
Speaker 1: I think that's a better question to answer.
Speaker 0: I think that is a better question than the question he asked.
Speaker 0: The thing is this right.
Speaker 0: The fundamental problem here is you have works of art and certain works of art have things in common and usually when they have things in common, if you like one, you might like the other.
Speaker 0: So what we do is we put labels on these things and like we say these are fantasy and you can be pretty sure if you like one, there's a good chance you like others because they're in the same genre.
Speaker 0: They have a lot in common, be it settings or, you know, the narrative themes and such and such and such.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The thing is, sometimes someone comes along and creates a work of art that doesn't have a lot in common with other works of art.
Speaker 0: And of course, everything anyone ever makes borrows things from other things.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much nothing is original.
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Sometimes someone just copies something else, like someone just writes a story.
Speaker 0: It's exactly the same as Star Wars.
Speaker 0: And they change the names of the characters.
Speaker 0: That's derivative.
Speaker 0: Sometimes someone writes something that has some similarities.
Speaker 0: And this is giant grayscale from exactly the same to not the same at all.
Speaker 0: And some everything is somewhere on that grayscale.
Speaker 0: And if you want to label something as derivative instead of just being in the same genre or whatever, well, that's it's up to you, whatever you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Plus, I mean, it is tricky when something like Cowboy Bebop basically made a new genre of show it by borrowing something from everything.
Speaker 0: It there's nothing you can really put in the same genre as Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 0: It has not a lot in common with anything.
Speaker 0: So I guess it borrows from anything.
Speaker 1: But because it defined the genre by definition, everything that is in that genre will be derivative.
Speaker 1: that not so much for any useful demarcation, just simply because the genre is defined by that.
Speaker 0: I mean, it doesn't even mean that they're copying Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 0: Someone could, by chance, create a work of art that is in the same genre as Cowboy Bebop and has many similarities to it.
Speaker 0: Yet they might have never even seen Cowboy Bebop or known it existed.
Speaker 0: But, you know, so you just sort of have to investigate and figure out.
Speaker 0: And it's it's really not hard to tell when someone just copied something else or when someone actually created something new.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I guess you can ask the next one.
Speaker 0: Top five movies of all time.
Speaker 0: Most of these people, they've tried to ask these questions like, pick your favorite song.
Speaker 0: It's not possible.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe they want, you know, best movies, top five, maybe the movies that are best done overall.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know, the sort of it's sort of tough because if you want if you ask me what my favorite movies are, I'll probably be like Star Wars, Such and Such, Matrix, I don't know, Miyazaki movies of some kind, some Satoshi Kann's got to be up there somewhere.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But if you ask me what the best star, I'll probably be like Citizen Kane, City of God.
Speaker 1: Oh, City of God.
Speaker 1: I want to watch that again right now.
Speaker 0: City of God.
Speaker 0: That movie, Reservoir Dogs, maybe Godfather, definitely.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The first one, at least.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We could just randomly name movies we like, but that I'm sort of doing that already, but it's sort of lame.
Speaker 0: That's why I tried to avoid doing that in the favorite song question, because it's lame.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Let's just move on.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You have from a practical standpoint, unlimited money.
Speaker 1: I think you were misappraised as to how much money I have.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what do you buy?
Speaker 1: Commission create.
Speaker 1: Don't give me investing crap.
Speaker 1: You already have more De Niro than you can possibly spend.
Speaker 1: I think the answer is pretty obvious.
Speaker 0: You see.
Speaker 0: Oh, let's see how obvious your answer is.
Speaker 1: I met a traveler from an antique land who said two vast and trunkless legs of stone stand in the desert.
Speaker 1: near them on the sand, have sunk a shattered visage lies whose frown and snare of cold command.
Speaker 1: Did you bring this?
Speaker 1: Did you let it sculptor?
Speaker 1: Well, those passions read, which gets survived, stamped on these lifeless things, the hand that mocked them in the heart that fed and on one pedestal, these words appear.
Speaker 1: My name is Ozymandias, King of Kings.
Speaker 1: Look upon my work, see mighty and despair.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I read the question while you were answering the previous one.
Speaker 1: And there is only one answer I could give to that.
Speaker 0: Well, I'd have to say, actually, my clever answer to that is not as clever as Rem's answer.
Speaker 0: But basically, if I had from a practical standpoint, unlimited money, I would buy commission and create very little because I don't want to ruin the world's economy with horrible inflation because I'm not that dumb.
Speaker 0: If I started spending my money like a nutcase, the world would probably fall to shit and the money wouldn't be worth anything.
Speaker 1: Now, if it were simply the matter that I have a lot of power in the world to commission great works, then look mighty.
Speaker 1: Well, seriously, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I do great things, change the world, that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Trains, buildings.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think the next question will answer this.
Speaker 1: The next question is secret moon base or secret volcano layer.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't have any other choices because I really like secret undersea city.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Full of Chrysler buildings.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But a floating castle in the sky.
Speaker 0: I really don't like moon base or volcano layer because volcano layer has a stupid lava all the time and moon base.
Speaker 0: Where am I going to eat?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it is a pain in the ass of maintaining the moon base and the volcano layer is too dangerous.
Speaker 0: So I like.
Speaker 0: I like.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: The volcano layer is so much more dangerous than the moon.
Speaker 0: They're both dangerous.
Speaker 0: That's why I don't like either one.
Speaker 0: They're both bad.
Speaker 1: Why can't I position?
Speaker 1: Why can't my secret base just be all Batman style just under my mansion?
Speaker 0: See, that's a nice defensible position.
Speaker 0: A volcano and the moon are not defensible.
Speaker 1: Well, the moon is very defensible.
Speaker 1: You've got the biggest fucking mode in the world.
Speaker 0: I'm cheating on this question.
Speaker 0: Floating castle in the sky.
Speaker 0: I win.
Speaker 0: La, la, la, la, la.
Speaker 1: We know that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's still cool.
Speaker 1: If you could this is a tough one.
Speaker 1: If you could choose to have the ability to never need sleep again, would you?
Speaker 1: You could not sleep even if you wanted to.
Speaker 1: You would never feel sleepy or tired and everyone else would sleep as normal.
Speaker 0: Oh, if I never felt sleepy or tired.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the problem.
Speaker 0: It's, you know, sleepy and tiredness is sort of this gradual thing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, I mean, you could feel really energized and really go get them.
Speaker 0: You could also feel kind of a right.
Speaker 0: And sometimes I'm kind of a but not really tired.
Speaker 0: I might want to sleep.
Speaker 1: I'll just masturbate.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: But that makes me sleepy.
Speaker 0: If I could stay kind of energized, like if Red Bull wouldn't destroy my heart or anything like that, you know, I could really feel like go get them all the time.
Speaker 0: You know, like I could actually be really productive being awake all the time.
Speaker 0: Then, yes, I would not want to sleep.
Speaker 0: But if there were going to be times where I'd feel and just kind of sit there bored, then no, I'd probably rather sleep.
Speaker 1: Well, you see, this is the reason I think this is an interesting question is that it's basically as it's transhumanism.
Speaker 1: It's asking if given the opportunity, would you give up your humanity?
Speaker 1: Because part of being human is that we're these biological organisms and we have.
Speaker 1: there's only so much we can do in a day.
Speaker 1: And philosophically, you have to decide what kind of being you are.
Speaker 1: Do you what is more important to you, your human happiness or the ability to do great things?
Speaker 1: I mean, by giving up sleep, you're giving up something that makes you human.
Speaker 1: I mean, I really enjoy sleep.
Speaker 1: Sleep.
Speaker 1: Being tired is part of the human experience.
Speaker 1: And you're falling asleep and waking up.
Speaker 0: Even in Ghost in the Shell, you always see the cyborgs like going to sleep and stuff, even if they don't have to.
Speaker 1: It's just or like Batos lifting the weights, even though he doesn't have to.
Speaker 1: And.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: But it's kind of this.
Speaker 1: sleep is wonderful.
Speaker 1: It's this kind of I like sleeping.
Speaker 1: I like dreaming.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, I feel like I could do a lot for this world if I only had more time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And I think in the end, I would probably give up my humanity in order to accomplish more great work, I think, and then say into the world that lucky might.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of works.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of the problems with these questions is that I basically I need to guarantee that when I give up my humanity, I'm actually making a step forward and not a step backwards.
Speaker 0: For example, if I could stay up all night, but then if I still if I died earlier because I was I only had so many waking hours in my life and then I died, then it's not a step forward.
Speaker 0: It's really sort of a step backwards.
Speaker 1: But if you died earlier, but you got to live all of your life in your prime youth.
Speaker 0: I know it's it's a tough question.
Speaker 0: I need basically I need a guarantee that I'm actually, you know, it's actually going to be better.
Speaker 0: if it's if I can't guarantee that I'm actually doing better than I was doing before, then I'm not going to make a permanent decision like this.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Why is the show called Rim and Scott and not Scott and Rim?
Speaker 0: Because Rim and Scott sounds better.
Speaker 1: We tried them both.
Speaker 1: One sounded better.
Speaker 1: It was totally arbitrary.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Why is Scott known as my screen?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So have I told the story of the show before?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess I'll tell it again, even if I have told it before.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: So it's put yourself back in time to nineteen ninety seven or eight.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: AOL, AOL days.
Speaker 0: I need an AOL account.
Speaker 0: I need a screen name.
Speaker 0: I chose Taser and AOL decided to put three one four six.
Speaker 0: So at the end of that, because someone else already had Taser and I chose Taser because there was an old DOS game where you couldn't actually type in your own name.
Speaker 0: You had to choose one of the names from a list.
Speaker 0: And I always chose Taser from the list because that one was green.
Speaker 0: So I used Taser and someone else put numbers at the end of it.
Speaker 0: So on AOL, there was a game called Gemstone three.
Speaker 0: It was a mud.
Speaker 0: I didn't know was a mud at the time, but it was a mud and it was pretty good mud.
Speaker 0: And now then they eventually charged money for it instead of making it free.
Speaker 0: So I stopped playing.
Speaker 0: But when I did play Gemstone three, the first mod I ever played, not knowing it was a mud, I need a screen name for that.
Speaker 0: That was separate from my AOL name.
Speaker 0: So I tried Taser and he wanted it wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: And I didn't want to put numbers at the end of this role playing name.
Speaker 0: You know, I wanted to have it just be a name like everyone else.
Speaker 0: So that didn't work.
Speaker 0: So I started trying names like Frodo, Gandalf, Luke Skywalker, Vader, all sorts of Lord of the Rings, Star Wars names, Transformers names, Thundercats names.
Speaker 0: None of the names work.
Speaker 0: They were all taken.
Speaker 0: Of course, I was a naive 13 year old kid.
Speaker 0: What do I know?
Speaker 0: So what do I do?
Speaker 0: I tried.
Speaker 0: I was thinking because I just came back from summer camp recently and we did the Apache relay.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, oh, Apache is not too bad.
Speaker 0: So try Apache taken.
Speaker 0: I accidentally misspelled Apache slightly and it totally works.
Speaker 0: And I had a name that looked like a name.
Speaker 0: that was a fantasy kind of name that worked.
Speaker 0: Didn't need any numbers at the end of it.
Speaker 0: Wasn't a real word in any language that I could find or nor a conjugation of any word that I could find on the Internet.
Speaker 0: Search for it on Altavista.
Speaker 0: Nothing came up.
Speaker 0: And I said, hey, I sort of have this like unique name.
Speaker 0: Who knows how to pronounce it?
Speaker 0: Who cares?
Speaker 0: Because I was only ever going to type it.
Speaker 0: And to this day, I think I'm the only one using that name and it works.
Speaker 0: I get this name I want on every website and I don't need to put numbers at the end.
Speaker 0: And it it's just a practical username on the Internet.
Speaker 0: And I don't go by the name like some people.
Speaker 0: And I don't know how to pronounce it.
Speaker 0: It's up to you.
Speaker 0: And nor do I care.
Speaker 0: People know what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: It's interesting.
Speaker 1: I mean, my first Internet name was origins, and that's because I was sitting there and I had to log into Prodigy Classic for the first time.
Speaker 1: I'm all excited.
Speaker 1: I needed a screen name and I look up there's a big old copy of Origin of Species.
Speaker 0: Ah, good one.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Raymond Scott, if I have a project I want to do, how do I best go about planning and executing it?
Speaker 1: Well, first you plan it and then you do it.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: I think we did a show on how to not suck at doing things way, way back.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Let's skip this stupid question.
Speaker 1: It's a good question, but that would be a whole show.
Speaker 0: So it's so generic.
Speaker 1: It's basically how do you live?
Speaker 0: How do you do things?
Speaker 0: You set a goal.
Speaker 0: You make a plan.
Speaker 0: You do research.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you this.
Speaker 1: I got a good piece of advice.
Speaker 1: Whenever you try really hard, whenever you get motivated, planning to do something and especially if other people rely on you, you've got to think from the perspective of what if everything goes wrong?
Speaker 1: What is my contingency plan?
Speaker 1: If for every possible thing I can think of.
Speaker 1: So you're ready whenever anything happens.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Think of every possibility.
Speaker 1: And yeah, like you're going on a trip.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Do everything.
Speaker 0: I got the whole power into it.
Speaker 1: I got the hotel.
Speaker 1: I called the hotel the night before.
Speaker 1: They said they have the reservation.
Speaker 1: What will I do if I get there and they still don't have the reservation?
Speaker 1: What do I do if I get there and I don't have my wallet anymore?
Speaker 1: What if my car breaks down?
Speaker 1: And a lot of these plans are generic and multipurpose.
Speaker 1: So once you have them, much like the US, you don't need to update them until things change.
Speaker 1: I mean, we didn't need to change our Canada invasion plans until cars were invented.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is a tough one.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: If you were trapped in a small town in the middle of the desert, would your chances of survival be greater if, A, you were being hunted by a gang of 10 vampires flying, vulnerable to stakes, fire, sunlight and silver?
Speaker 1: only turn you into one if they want to?
Speaker 1: Or if you were one of 10 people left alive in a town full of zombies.
Speaker 1: These are slow, mindless, flesh hungry, turn you into one once bitten zombies.
Speaker 1: Assume average man on the street.
Speaker 1: intelligence for all other sentient individuals involved.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm fucked because normal people can't deal with this.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So what do you much kill?
Speaker 1: all the other people?
Speaker 1: And then I can survive both situations.
Speaker 0: It depends on because he doesn't make any suggestion indication.
Speaker 0: Small town in the middle of the desert.
Speaker 0: But I mean, I mean, is this like a ghost town?
Speaker 0: Just a few wooden buildings that are full of nothing.
Speaker 0: It depends a lot on the tools I have because he says vulnerable to stakes.
Speaker 0: So I can probably get some stakes, right?
Speaker 1: The stakes aren't going to help because they can kill you when they're awake.
Speaker 0: It says they're vulnerable to fire, though.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And actually, no, I'm picking the vampires and here's why.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Okay, here is why.
Speaker 1: Alright, it's daylight.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: It's daylight.
Speaker 1: Where are they?
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 1: Didn't you ever see the Lost Boys?
Speaker 1: They got to find the vampires first.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter because with the vampires, there's no other.
Speaker 0: See, with the zombies, there's 10 people left alive in the town with me who are going to cause me shit with the vampires.
Speaker 0: There aren't.
Speaker 0: And with the vampires, if I can survive until daylight, I can just get the fuck out of there.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's assume that you are more than a day's drive from the next civilization center.
Speaker 1: Or even if you get somewhere, you're being hunted.
Speaker 1: That means that the vampires are going to follow you.
Speaker 0: even so, even so the vampires are vulnerable to fire and silver.
Speaker 0: So it's really easy to get lots of fire and lots of silver.
Speaker 0: I can just set the town on fire.
Speaker 0: I'll just burn the whole place down.
Speaker 0: Then what the vampire is going to fucking do?
Speaker 1: Well, you didn't get their coffins probably because they're not stupid.
Speaker 0: That doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: The whole place is on fire.
Speaker 0: I can survive for a fucking long time.
Speaker 0: Those vampires aren't coming anywhere near.
Speaker 1: The fire goes out in a couple of hours.
Speaker 0: And then it's daylight and I get the hell out of there.
Speaker 1: Alright, and then you go to sleep in a hotel the next night and then the vampires kill you.
Speaker 0: It says the vampires are in the small town.
Speaker 1: Obviously, you're being hunted.
Speaker 1: They'll follow you out of the town.
Speaker 0: I can get to somewhere safer, like a city.
Speaker 1: Nowhere is safe from vampires.
Speaker 1: It's not like vampires can't go into Manhattan.
Speaker 0: I can get, if I can get out of the small town in the middle of the desert to a real civilization where there's lots of people and lots of things, I can take on pretty much any vampires or zombies or whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't think you could.
Speaker 0: The only reason it's dangerous is because it's a small town in the desert.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I'll bet I could reason with the vampires a lot better.
Speaker 0: That's also true.
Speaker 1: Then I could reason with the 10 non-zombies in the zombie town.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Even if I couldn't get away from the vampires, if I had the fire and the silver and the stakes, the silver would be easy to come by, but the fire, the sunlight and the stakes and the whatnot, I could probably have some sort of reasoning with the vampires, maybe get them to turn me into a vampire.
Speaker 0: Then I'd be all set.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, you could always just turn.
Speaker 1: See, that's why Scott Johnson always says that if it's ever discovered that dark powers exist, he's probably going to come and kill us.
Speaker 1: because you just said, "All right, I could just become a
Speaker 1: vampire.".
Speaker 1: I have often said, "Well, I could always use evil to fight
Speaker 1: evil.".
Speaker 0: Becoming a zombie sucks.
Speaker 0: Becoming a vampire is great.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll just leave that one at that.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So what's the worst injury, pain-wise, after-effect-wise, et cetera, either of you has ever received?
Speaker 1: Pain-wise, number one was when I got food poisoning.
Speaker 0: I never really had such a pain.
Speaker 1: Number two was when I cut my finger off.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Number three was when I had that bicycle spoke go through my leg.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Let's see, the only injuries I've had... I guess the worst injury I've had is when I fell on the side of my face when I had braces and one of the braces went into my lip and I had to go and get stitches in the lip.
Speaker 1: Oh wait, there was that time when I was a little kid and I got punched in the balls by fucking Steve.
Speaker 0: Yeah, stitches in the lip, that pretty much that whole experience I'd say was sort of the worst.
Speaker 0: I still have a lump there in my lip.
Speaker 0: You can feel it in there.
Speaker 1: When I had that bicycle spoke go through, I only got two stitches.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my lip was much worse than that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the worst pain I've ever experienced in my whole life was when I got food poisoning.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I guess the only other time I really hurt myself was when I fell off the swing set and broke my collarbone, but that was just eh.
Speaker 0: I didn't even really bother me at all.
Speaker 0: It was eh.
Speaker 0: I never really had much pain in my life.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess I've had pretty bad pains from occasional stomach bugs, which are pretty painful and vomiting and such.
Speaker 0: It's not really painful, but it's unpleasant and that's really it.
Speaker 1: Ah, the next one is kind of related.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: What's the closest to dying that either of you have been?
Speaker 0: Well, I'm pretty sure, right?
Speaker 0: There was this one time I was on an airplane and usually I'm flying.
Speaker 0: I'm just fine, whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm not afraid of flying.
Speaker 0: I don't get, you know, sick of the turbulence or anything, but just I was on this plane and I think it was a JetBlue plane to Rochester or Florida.
Speaker 0: I think it was to Florida.
Speaker 0: I don't remember, but I was on it alone.
Speaker 0: No one else I knew was with me.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I just felt really, really shitty, like horribly shitty, shittier than ever felt in my life, like passing out shitty.
Speaker 0: And I was just randomly, I don't know why I felt this way.
Speaker 0: I was thinking, you know, and I felt so shitty.
Speaker 0: I just didn't care.
Speaker 0: I was like, if someone's poison gassing the plane, I just don't care anymore.
Speaker 0: And I felt really, really shitty.
Speaker 0: And then the plane landed in like five, about a few minutes later, I recomposed myself and I was fine.
Speaker 0: And I didn't really know what the hell that was, but I assume I was pretty close to dying because even if I wasn't actually going to die, I had maybe given up on life almost.
Speaker 1: I know that feeling.
Speaker 1: There was a time where I had Lyme disease way back and I didn't know I had Lyme disease and doctors are kind of stupid about Lyme disease.
Speaker 1: So I went to the doctor.
Speaker 1: He was like, yeah, take some aspirin, come back in a week.
Speaker 1: And then when I came back in a week, I came back to a go home and take this.
Speaker 1: But in that interim, I remember one time I had a fever kind of going the whole week and I woke up and I'm, I'm alone.
Speaker 1: I'm living in someone's condo in Poughkeepsie working at IBM on co-op.
Speaker 1: And I woke up and I had like 104 fever and I had like, and I was kind of delirious from the fever.
Speaker 1: So I'm laying there and I've got like this damp cloth that I don't remember getting, but it was on me.
Speaker 1: It was on my forehead.
Speaker 1: and I'm laying there thinking, I wonder if I'm going to die before the sun comes up and I go to the doctor and my brain couldn't get to the point of maybe you should just call an ambulance now.
Speaker 1: That would save you no matter what.
Speaker 1: No, my brain just thought, well, probably going to die.
Speaker 0: It's like that guy said, he was talking about, you know, uh, patient autonomy.
Speaker 0: And he's like this person who may not be in the best position to make a decision is forced to make a decision.
Speaker 1: Fever dreams are weird in that way.
Speaker 1: Uh, there's also the time there's a long story as to the lead up to this, but I was driving a friend back from Long Island to Rochester and I was going about 90 give or take.
Speaker 1: And my rear left wheel exploded and she was asleep at the time.
Speaker 1: So basically car comes to stops on the side of the road.
Speaker 1: I miraculously avoided hitting anything.
Speaker 1: And right about then is when she woke up screaming.
Speaker 1: No, but yeah, I didn't hit anything.
Speaker 1: I survived.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Have you ever gotten caught?
Speaker 0: Could be doing anything.
Speaker 0: Not yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I, uh, I had some close calls, but the police have never actually physically gotten.
Speaker 0: I guess I've gotten caught speeding.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: A couple of times.
Speaker 1: Uh, you have to, yeah, I've only ever gotten two speeding tickets in my whole life.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Three, three, three.
Speaker 1: I forgot about.
Speaker 0: So we're tied.
Speaker 0: I guess I've been pulled over like 12 times though.
Speaker 0: I've never been.
Speaker 0: I've all, uh, all right.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: Well, I've run away from the police a lot in various instances where the statute of limitations is clearly up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Did Scott ever find a pair of shoes to match a sundress?
Speaker 0: Well, I don't have a sundress.
Speaker 1: That's why he's having so much trouble finding a pair of shoes to match it.
Speaker 1: Why we took so long to get out of that stupid mall in Baltimore.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What are some of your favorite comedians?
Speaker 1: Louis black, Stephen, right.
Speaker 1: Uh, George Carlin before he got extra angry and old.
Speaker 1: I like Seinfeld a lot.
Speaker 0: Uh, uh, Dennis Leary.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Um, uh, you know, it's weird.
Speaker 1: I Eddie Izzard.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Monty Python.
Speaker 0: The whole group.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Eddie Izzard is particularly great.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I like a lot of standup comedians.
Speaker 1: It's really hard.
Speaker 0: It's hard to find a bad, I mean, you know, pretty much anyone that's famous is probably funny.
Speaker 0: Otherwise they wouldn't have gotten famous.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, all right.
Speaker 0: Uh, what do you think about long distance relationships?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Thing isn't a verb.
Speaker 0: This is very hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't think we can answer that one.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I've seen some people who are in really stupid ones and I often wondered why.
Speaker 1: sometimes I ask these people why, but at the same time I was in one off and on for a while and you know what?
Speaker 1: It worked out pretty well in the end.
Speaker 0: I mean, I see some people and it's just sort of like they meet someone on the internet or something and they decide they're in a relationship.
Speaker 0: I guess on paper they say, yeah, that's my girlfriend.
Speaker 0: That's my boyfriend.
Speaker 1: That's just like when you're in second grade and yeah, we're dating now.
Speaker 1: We're go.
Speaker 1: or in middle school when people didn't go on dates, but they went out, which meant they were dating, but they don't actually go on dates.
Speaker 0: They just went out, but they don't have a real relationship.
Speaker 0: So, but I see other people where they do have a real relationship and then eventually like they come together or maybe they were together and now they're apart, but they use long distance to sort of keep it together and then they come back together again.
Speaker 0: I guess it's like long distance is okay as long as it's not long distance forever, you know?
Speaker 0: Cause it's like a long distance relationship.
Speaker 0: Either if it starts long distance, it's probably just going to end long distance, but I feel like if it starts together or ends together, then it's, it's okay.
Speaker 1: I do have one piece of advice for all our listeners out there.
Speaker 1: I know we have a lot of high school listeners.
Speaker 1: Um, if you go to college, first of all, you're high school, you can't really pick your friends because you're limited to the geographic area.
Speaker 1: Part of the reason you go to college is that now you have kind of self-selected a great, you have a group of people who are self-selected to have somewhat similar interests to be at the same school.
Speaker 1: And you're more likely to meet people you're actually going to want to be in a relationship with.
Speaker 1: So my general advice to everyone out there is if you're dating someone in high school, long distance or short, and you go to college, do not try to hold onto that relationship.
Speaker 1: It's totally not worth it.
Speaker 1: It's not going to work.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess what I'm trying to say is you, maybe your relationship can still work depending, but whatever you do, do not pick a college to go to or pick, just don't make a decision about what you're going to do with the rest of your life based on the relationship you may have in high school.
Speaker 0: Like for example, if the person you're in a relationship with says they're going to school X, don't go to school X because they're going there.
Speaker 0: Don't even take them into consideration when deciding what you're going to do with the rest of your life.
Speaker 0: That's what you have to do.
Speaker 0: The relationship might work.
Speaker 0: Plenty of people are married happily to their high school sweethearts or whatever because it worked out that way.
Speaker 0: But don't decide your college.
Speaker 0: Don't decide your job.
Speaker 0: Don't bet your future on your high school girlfriend or boyfriend.
Speaker 1: Now, right along those lines, if you go to college and you were dating someone who stayed in your hometown or went somewhere else, odds are you're going to meet better people in your college.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not 100% true, but I'm just giving, I'm warning you, you're going to meet better people.
Speaker 1: Don't forgo what you might, what might be better for you for a lame high school relationship that's going to end poorly anyway.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: You want to read this next one?
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Skip it.
Speaker 0: How about this German Scott?
Speaker 0: Why are you so abnormal to unable to enjoy a damn grilled cheese sandwich?
Speaker 0: Why do you have your fancy cheeses?
Speaker 0: Why do you throw fruity as herbs on them?
Speaker 0: Why can't be normal people enjoy grilled cheese sandwich?
Speaker 0: It's American classic.
Speaker 0: Why do you hate America so much?
Speaker 0: Why can't you eat a regular grilled cheese sandwich and can be happy?
Speaker 0: What the hell people?
Speaker 0: Well, I just want to say rim is the one who can't eat a plain grilled cheese sandwich.
Speaker 0: I prefer the plain grilled cheese sandwich.
Speaker 0: See, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: As long as it's nicely toasted and buttered.
Speaker 1: If I'm making a grilled cheese sandwich and I know how to make it better and taste better, why not make it taste better?
Speaker 0: Because you're making it taste different, not better, but it tastes better.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 1: It's got people like different things.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Some people are bad.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's a bad taste.
Speaker 1: I mean, I just I like.
Speaker 1: why would I make a grilled cheese sandwich with American cheese if I can have some moderate jack?
Speaker 0: Uh, because it does not good for grilled cheese.
Speaker 1: Actually, moderate jack is probably the best cheese for grilled cheese sandwich.
Speaker 1: It melts the exact right amount.
Speaker 0: Anyway, mostly messing with you, but honestly, why can't you enjoy just fine?
Speaker 0: Rim can't.
Speaker 1: Uh, I can.
Speaker 1: It's just some things taste better.
Speaker 1: I mean, I remember when I went to this hors d'oeuvre thing at the yacht club with Emily in the city, and I saw a bunch of cheese.
Speaker 1: and I look and I go, Oh, I know all those cheeses.
Speaker 1: Then I get over there and I eat one.
Speaker 1: It tastes really good, like better than I expected.
Speaker 1: Then I look and there's a little sign and it says the name of the cheese, and it's not the name I expected.
Speaker 1: It was some different cheese.
Speaker 1: Then I learned that every kind of cheese has a richer, better equivalent.
Speaker 1: that does taste better.
Speaker 1: However, however, while it did taste better, I ate this cheese.
Speaker 1: I thought, wow, this tastes 10 times better than the normal equivalent of this kind of cheese.
Speaker 1: I know how much that cheese costs.
Speaker 1: It is not worth that much money for me to eat that cheese.
Speaker 1: I would never buy that cheese because it's way too much money for what little better it is, but it is better.
Speaker 1: So if someone gives it to me, I'm going to eat it in general.
Speaker 0: I think that, you know, there are things in this world and it's all about perception.
Speaker 0: It's like some things are perceived to be fancified.
Speaker 0: I mean, what if, you know, Jack cheese was like the default cheese instead of American cheese being the default cheese.
Speaker 0: It's only a matter of, you know, human perception, marketing, culture and society that dictates, you know, what's stupidly fancified and what's not.
Speaker 1: If you're in the poor part of Ethiopia, a plain grilled cheese sandwich is like hoity toity food that you're not going to get.
Speaker 0: And, you know, in reality, stuff that costs more like the fancy cheeses at that place, you know, at the yacht club, they probably taste better on average is the reason they're so expensive and sought after.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's for bullshit reasons, but sometimes it's for real reasons.
Speaker 0: And in general, some things are stupidly fancified because there's a reason for it, because they actually are better and rare and more difficult and more expensive, like foie gras.
Speaker 0: And it tastes really good.
Speaker 0: And some things are stupidly fancified, but they don't actually taste very good at all.
Speaker 0: Like champagne.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll put it this way.
Speaker 1: Very expensive champagne is very good.
Speaker 1: Very cheap champagne is also very good.
Speaker 1: You want to avoid moderately priced champagne and you never want to buy expensive champagne.
Speaker 1: You want it to be given to you by someone else.
Speaker 1: Never turn down fancy champagne.
Speaker 1: But if you're buying champagne for your wedding, cheaper will taste better.
Speaker 1: No one will know.
Speaker 1: Get the cheapest champagne you can.
Speaker 1: It'll taste so much better.
Speaker 0: And a bottle will explode better.
Speaker 0: Go poof.
Speaker 1: Actually, if it explodes, then you did it wrong.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: But if you're supposed to party, you're supposed to make it explode for fun.
Speaker 1: Damn.
Speaker 1: Now I'm hungry again.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going to go eat some Chinese.
Speaker 1: That is not a question.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: We've gone on for about an hour.
Speaker 1: I think we should answer one or two more and you don't want to do the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I thought we were gonna do the whole thing and just split it up.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's do one more then.
Speaker 0: Where is the forum thread for Episode 071011?
Speaker 0: Well, it requires extra effort to make the forum threads for those episodes.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, some things are automatic and some things are manual labor.
Speaker 0: So sometimes you don't do the manual labor and a forum thread doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: If you want one, go make one.
Speaker 0: No one's stopping you.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: And we'll end on that anticlimax.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Luckily, we have another hour or so of these questions left, so there will probably be a third questions day at some point in the future.
Speaker 1: I enjoy doing this, so I'm not really going to complain.
Speaker 0: No, but it's almost interminable.
Speaker 1: I see some questions in the future.
Speaker 0: By the time the three questions episodes will be out, we'll be taking new questions next year.
Speaker 1: I see a bunch of interesting questions coming up.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: We'll have to save those for the future.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share-a-like 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.