Speaker 1: It's Tuesday June 26th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we discuss why video games are currently out of season.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well Scott refuses to let me turn off the AC.
Speaker 0: so if you hear any humming in the background.
Speaker 0: It's all him.
Speaker 1: I didn't refuse to turn it off.
Speaker 0: I just asked if you would turn it off and I said no and then you bitched about it And you had bitch.
Speaker 1: all I did is said hey Why don't we leave it on?
Speaker 1: and you know why don't we do a little test to see just how much noise it makes?
Speaker 1: And you didn't say anything.
Speaker 1: after that I said, I guess it's still on you I'm gonna turn it off turn it off turn it off.
Speaker 1: I'll turn it off all right Did anyone hear a difference?
Speaker 1: I just turned the air conditioner off.
Speaker 1: does it?
Speaker 1: does it sound any different now?
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz I didn't really bother testing partly because I had to turn the air conditioner off to do that and partly because I can't know It'll really sound until I do all the processing and the filtering and it's just not worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have a feeling that it won't be that much sound.
Speaker 1: of course the air conditioner is right behind me.
Speaker 1: So it would be more than if say the air conditioner on the other side of the room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is also the issue that with the compressor whenever we're not talking It would just get rid of the air conditioner, but then it would come back as we talked.
Speaker 1: It's it's tough call But well you have a small sample of air conditioner geek nights to listen to and tell us how it sounds because if you can't Hear it I'm keeping that bitch on.
Speaker 1: cuz it is warm today.
Speaker 0: God damn.
Speaker 0: Yeah warmer than yesterday, so You Didn't do this typical.
Speaker 1: run through it.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: I didn't cuz otherwise we would get predictable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right, so it's a gaming day isn't it?
Speaker 1: and I've been playing too many games lately.
Speaker 1: So this is gonna be kind of weird me either.
Speaker 0: luckily that gave us something to talk about.
Speaker 0: see originally We're gonna talk about sieve - then I realized we already talked about sieve - I think I don't really remember talking about sieve - it's Listed as the primary thing of a show from a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I have to go listen to that show to see what the deal was.
Speaker 0: yeah Cuz you're gonna go back.
Speaker 0: you have time to go back and listen to that.
Speaker 1: I actually today I was sitting at work And I listened to the podcast on my iPod except for the ones that didn't feel like listening to and I actually went around to pod websites of podcasts downloaded mp3s Directly and then listen to them with my headphones plugged into my work PC.
Speaker 0: I've tried to do that several times, and I still can't find any podcast worth listening to.
Speaker 1: I mostly did it for Episodes of podcasts I do listen to.
Speaker 1: that came out after I left to go to work.
Speaker 1: wow That's kinda cuz I was out.
Speaker 1: I needed something to listen to.
Speaker 0: what was I gonna do I guess cuz I only listen in the car.
Speaker 0: I only update my iPod like once a week, and then I pretty much just listen to Dave and Joel and NPR.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I listen at work, so I need I need some more content cuz the awo hasn't been updating so much.
Speaker 1: I actually went around.
Speaker 1: you know all the the anime type podcast that we're friendly with and how they all have all the links on The side you know like animal door links to Ninja consultant links Dave and Joel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah And I clicked on every single one of those on all of the sites to actually get the whole picture.
Speaker 1: I had a whole row of tabs for every single one.
Speaker 0: I didn't listen any of them Right, but there's video game day, so I'm sure you've heard about all this crap with the ESRB, and how they've rated this game Adults only and how the albionic people decided they don't want this game to come out.
Speaker 0: and then I'll Sony Nintendo said yeah We don't want it to come out either.
Speaker 0: change it Take two.
Speaker 0: basically said all right We're not gonna change the game Because that goes against everything we stand for.
Speaker 1: oh do they really?
Speaker 0: I thought they were gonna change delay it and make it m Well what they said is they're just gonna shelve it and for now and that's it They're not gonna release it.
Speaker 0: And I don't think they're sure what they're gonna do yet unless there's been news since the last news I read.
Speaker 1: well they spent a lot of money developing it.
Speaker 1: they better make some money on it.
Speaker 0: see now if I were them One I'd probably talk to my lawyers to see about if there's any way to bring a lawsuit against the ESRB or any Organizations behind them for perhaps holding take two to a higher standard than other game Companies due to previous events that might have angered the ESRB.
Speaker 1: yep because I've never played manhunt one or two.
Speaker 1: But I am pretty confident based on the information I've read in many many places that manhunt two isn't really any more violent than manhunt one.
Speaker 0: Well, I did watch the trailers for manhunt two, and it didn't.
Speaker 0: I've read books that were a lot worse than that.
Speaker 0: There's no adults only rating on my book.
Speaker 1: I think it's just a case of that.
Speaker 1: people are still holding video games to like some other standard than the other mediums when it comes to censorship and violence and ratings.
Speaker 1: you know if you make if you took like a movie that's rated R like you know the matrix right and You make a video game out of it.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be rated M. possibly you know if you if you have a Movie with like one boob right that like what's a movie with one boob in it?
Speaker 0: well I can think of a movie with three.
Speaker 1: yeah Try to think of a.
Speaker 0: catch our ass to Mars.
Speaker 1: yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: pick a movie with one boob in it.
Speaker 0: I don't know The Metroid movie that's coming out.
Speaker 1: that's not gonna have any boobs.
Speaker 0: it's gonna have one.
Speaker 1: That's an inside joke if I ever heard one.
Speaker 1: Anyway doesn't make your favorite r-rated movie that's got some titties in it and imagine making a video game out of that.
Speaker 1: it would be adults only with the same content and That's just the bullshit that we have right now.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is in America We have the you know G PG PG 13 are a a NC 17.
Speaker 0: I kept wanting to say X and adults only but no it's NC 17.
Speaker 1: and then X.
Speaker 0: no X is not a rating.
Speaker 1: One X is a rating?
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: no they got rid of that a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I thought the triple X was not a rate.
Speaker 0: no no The issue with that because I actually did a bunch of this in the argument class star IT.
Speaker 0: The X rating was originally intended to be you know beyond our and it wasn't necessarily intended to be for pornography.
Speaker 0: It was just the next rating like that the top rating, but they didn't trademark or whatever.
Speaker 0: so people just Self-applied the rating X mostly for pornography Mm-hmm and they didn't want to be associated with all that.
Speaker 0: there's a big problem.
Speaker 0: eventually they said screw it Let's make some other thing and just give up on X. That's the much much abridged version.
Speaker 0: But no X is not a valid rating for movies.
Speaker 1: Oh actually I just read really quickly.
Speaker 1: They had an X rating yes, yeah, and then because it wasn't trademark Oh like I said anyone could put an X rating on their movie like I said.
Speaker 1: and then Because they use the X rating so much They they invented NC 17 like I said yep all right spot on all right.
Speaker 0: see we research things.
Speaker 0: You get that from the Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe maybe no.
Speaker 0: No, actually I remember when I was a kid that there were two theaters in the area that didn't even bother with the rating system.
Speaker 0: They pretty much let anyone into any movie, and that was great.
Speaker 1: There is no law whatsoever that says I mean if you brought a kid to a rated X movie, right There's no law that says you cannot bring a kid to a rated X movie more other than possible.
Speaker 0: child endangerment laws.
Speaker 0: There are laws that say you know you can't endanger a minor whatever and basically I think it's contributing to the delinquents of a minor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: So if you had a kid and you brought him to a rated R movie right then it would pretty much be up to the court to decide Based on that movie and exactly what you did whether you were guilty of this other Crime.
Speaker 1: that doesn't have anything to do with movie ratings whatsoever.
Speaker 1: There's no law that says a theater has to keep out people from certain rated movies except for you know Port straight-up pornos.
Speaker 0: the sad thing was though It didn't really affect me because I became old enough pretty much right around that time.
Speaker 0: But a bunch of parents in town got into this uproar about oh Lord this movie theaters are letting the kids in to see these bad movies.
Speaker 0: We got to put a stop to that.
Speaker 0: so they came down hard on the movie theaters and basically Gave him the ultimatum of enforce these things or we will somehow destroy you and the theaters just all caved in.
Speaker 0: yeah But the theaters to their credit did something cool.
Speaker 0: They started checking Everyone's ID no matter what and it was very annoying to a lot of adults.
Speaker 1: That's a cool theater right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah The thing is what I hate so much is that these people they cave in so quickly to these loud Minorities and Like that.
Speaker 0: what's that thing?
Speaker 1: the parents television that sends in most of the pretty much?
Speaker 1: 99% of the complaints to the FCC are from one group of people.
Speaker 1: yeah, right most people in this country I'm very confident want to see lots of violence and lots of sex.
Speaker 1: That's why those things get big ratings.
Speaker 1: That's why those things get big ticket sales.
Speaker 1: That's what everyone wants to see except for this very small mine loud minority of people.
Speaker 1: and if theaters Just freaking had some balls think about how much money.
Speaker 0: There's not just theaters.
Speaker 0: It's the theaters It's the government is the contact.
Speaker 1: if they had some balls And they just told those people to shut up Then you would see you wouldn't see a lot of people go hooray because they're quiet Majority.
Speaker 1: what you would see is that them make a lot of money from a lot of teenagers going to see freaking violent movies.
Speaker 0: And maybe those teenagers we get used to seeing violence and then not I don't know engaging is there's really?
Speaker 0: no I can't make a logical argument for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that I don't think it would be such a big deal at all because while people like to see these things And I really want to see art be unconstrained and just let people do what they will so long as the creation of the art Itself does not actively harm people or things or up.
Speaker 0: well Maybe not things, but people are animals or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Like it shouldn't be illegal to have a movie where a guy gets shot all bloodily Unless you shoot a guy all bloodily in order to film it.
Speaker 1: well It could be a stunt guy who wants to get shot.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: There's there's problems with that.
Speaker 0: I know I know but Some hobo you shoot him in your film.
Speaker 1: No, you can't do that, but that's I don't think.
Speaker 0: that's the problem that the rating systems are supposed to know solving.
Speaker 1: I actually do think there should be rating systems because on paper what a rating system does is it provides Information and does nothing more than provide information, and there's always good to provide more information.
Speaker 1: in my eyes You know if you buy a book and it says on the back this book contains violence and boobies That's great that the book says that on the back It's more information about the contents of the book.
Speaker 0: the problem with that?
Speaker 0: Stores and governments and people use these rating systems to restrict what other people do.
Speaker 0: I mean look at this Because Nintendo and Sony have full control over their consoles.
Speaker 0: They can just say to these people all right We're not gonna carry any adults only games so dying of fire and these people have no recourse.
Speaker 0: That's why I wish PC gaming would just explode back with a fury because no one controls the PC gaming market.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one can stop your game from coming out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: See I don't really also don't have a problem with like Maybe not laws, but stores having a policy that says you know Kids can't buy if you're like a 12 year old you can't buy an M-rated game.
Speaker 1: I don't really have a problem with that either, but if a parent wants to buy the M-rated game and give it to their kid That's fine.
Speaker 1: You can't stop them from doing it.
Speaker 1: That's why this pisses me off that they made an AO game right.
Speaker 1: so you sell the AO game in the stores to Adults.
Speaker 1: only the fact that now people won't sell the game.
Speaker 1: This is the problem.
Speaker 1: I don't mind if the game is rated AO.
Speaker 1: I don't mind if the game exists.
Speaker 1: I don't mind if a parent buys it and gives it to a three-year-old.
Speaker 1: they can do that.
Speaker 1: But if a store won't sell the game even to an adult me I can't buy it.
Speaker 1: That's bullshit.
Speaker 0: But at the same time there's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: if I own a store you can't coerce me into selling things I don't want to sell.
Speaker 0: the only exception to that I think are pharmacies, but that's another thing altogether.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess that the store does have a right to not sell it if they don't want to but it's still sort of ass.
Speaker 0: and yeah I think the problem is that the way American and maybe Western in general consumerism is gone.
Speaker 0: is that very few?
Speaker 0: Retail stores control the majority of the markets.
Speaker 1: It's the same way that very few newspapers and TV stations control the media.
Speaker 1: You know yeah.
Speaker 0: So as a result if the big ones Decide not to sell something all the little ones usually follow suit for as far as I can see no reason because here's what they Could do and I wonder why people don't.
Speaker 0: in this case It's more difficult because it wouldn't be easy to just release this game on the PC.
Speaker 0: I don't think especially since it was we in PlayStation as opposed to Xbox.
Speaker 0: and then Anyway, what you do is if your game won't be sold in these places you market it as this is the game.
Speaker 0: That's too hardcore for Walmart.
Speaker 0: No one will sell this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except us.
Speaker 0: you can buy it directly from us online.
Speaker 0: We gave the ESRB the finger.
Speaker 0: Just give us your credit card.
Speaker 0: We'll send you your violent seat.
Speaker 1: That's what I would do.
Speaker 1: is I would say okay This game is illegal in Britain because Britain doesn't have freedom of speech apparently right?
Speaker 0: Oh, I would so set up some sort of gray market in Britain I know, but that's fine.
Speaker 1: the game is illegal in Britain cuz Britain is a backwards nation without freedom right now.
Speaker 0: But in the US, the only reason that this game isn't sold in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Is because the retail establishments the Walmart the GameStop etc.
Speaker 1: won't sell it.
Speaker 1: There's no law that says this game can't be sold here except for the fact that I guess also the system the consoles That the game is gonna be on don't want the game published on their consoles.
Speaker 1: This is why what I would do is if I was take two is I would just turn it into a PC game and sell It on Steam BAM
Speaker 0: and in the meantime because it might take a while to do that I would just keep marketing it as Nintendo and Sony are afraid of this game.
Speaker 1: Yep, all these people would sign up to steam.
Speaker 1: They would all download the game.
Speaker 1: Maybe I wouldn't use steam if I couldn't make a deal with valve.
Speaker 1: I do the direct to drive.
Speaker 0: I'm sure valve would be more than willing to game tap.
Speaker 1: There's like a bunch of different online game selling solutions out there.
Speaker 1: It's not too hard to convert a game from a ps3 game to a piece for a one-off like that.
Speaker 0: It'd be trivial to just sell the game straight up.
Speaker 0: It gets sent to you via a file transfer mechanism after the credit card number come.
Speaker 1: That's what the direct to drive thing is.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's it basically this website where you can yeah, just buy.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of ways to do that.
Speaker 0: There are.
Speaker 1: there are many ways to do it and I don't see why they don't.
Speaker 1: if the game is done They should just.
Speaker 1: it would take them maybe a few weeks to set something like this up.
Speaker 0: Maybe it might take longer than that.
Speaker 1: if they I mean depending on how they coded it Depends on how they coded it but they coded it properly.
Speaker 1: Especially there is the problem especially if it's a 360 game.
Speaker 0: There is the problem of PC gaming in general.
Speaker 0: I mean you don't have the right controllers.
Speaker 1: I almost every USB controller sucks And that's why they have to do Xbox 360 controllers for PC.
Speaker 0: Oh, but it's not an Xbox game.
Speaker 0: It's a PlayStation Wii game.
Speaker 1: I know it's.
Speaker 1: that's another mistake.
Speaker 1: They made Yeah, if you're anything you make one a Xbox Wii game not an X Wii ps3 game.
Speaker 0: I don't know that.
Speaker 0: I guess that what it boils down to is I don't see any Ideological problems with what happened.
Speaker 0: The problem is more that the implementation of our society in terms of things like this Has ended up fucking us out of a game a game that I probably didn't care about.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's because it was a Wii game now.
Speaker 1: I'm actually kind of interested.
Speaker 0: Yeah Maybe because the best game on the Wii right now is still Insert game here.
Speaker 0: I don't have anything funny because I haven't touched.
Speaker 0: the Wii is covered in dust.
Speaker 0: It hasn't been turned on in weeks.
Speaker 1: We hasn't been turned on in over a month.
Speaker 1: All right, so my news is quick.
Speaker 0: if you have a 360 and the date is June 27th, which it should be because I don't know how many of you listen Well, I know exactly how many of you listen to the show at night, but I won't go there.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: You should be Going into your little Xbox Live shopping marketplace, whatever they call it.
Speaker 1: I don't know I don't have one and you should be buying car Casa C. They are CA SS Oh and any.
Speaker 0: I insist that you do so.
Speaker 1: if you listen to this show and you have an Xbox 360 And you do not buy carcass own you are hereby no longer permitted to listen to this show.
Speaker 0: No, so you practice it.
Speaker 0: You're a bad person.
Speaker 1: I want to see carcass own in every game or tag I see in that forum.
Speaker 0: now I kind of wish I had an Xbox.
Speaker 0: The only reason I don't is honestly that I don't have enough time to play video games because I want an Xbox games I want on it.
Speaker 0: yep, I would probably play carcass own more than anything on that thing because you see in our front row crew and in the Extending no conventions and everything.
Speaker 0: in all of my life since I've started playing carcass own I have about an 80 to 85 percent win rate to this day and as Scott was pointing out This is probably the truest test I could
Speaker 1: have
Speaker 0: Because I would be forced to play against the masses the masses out there who are probably going to spend a lot of time playing It for whatever achievement points they might get.
Speaker 1: it would also display your worldwide rank over time And yeah, I just kept winning.
Speaker 0: you'd eventually be number one in carcass own and if I wasn't or if I'm rising in the ranks You could know who to fight.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You would know who is better than you.
Speaker 0: So if you guys want to see me either Attain my greatness get to the top of Maslow's pyramid or if you want to see me crash and burn in a glorious flame Of suckage bias at 360.
Speaker 0: Yeah bias next 360.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would actually buy one in a second if I had a single moment of the day in which I wanted to play video Games, but did not have a video game to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, funny how we're gonna get to that in a little bit funny how we're gonna get to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah carcass own It's an awesome German board game.
Speaker 1: But now instead of buying a board game and having to find friends to play it with you You can just play it on the 360.
Speaker 0: ever actually do a show on carcass own.
Speaker 1: I think we just rate up.
Speaker 1: I think we did we showed.
Speaker 0: if if we didn't let us know we will.
Speaker 1: I'll search for it right now.
Speaker 0: carcass own is a great game.
Speaker 0: I mean aside from being just a great game that stands the test of time well better than settlers or other entry-level game We did in May of 2006.
Speaker 0: All right, then I'll stop there.
Speaker 0: carcass own is badass.
Speaker 0: You must buy it.
Speaker 0: end of story things of the day.
Speaker 0: I Have to talk about this because it touches on a lot of issues that are dear to me.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna go into a lot of depth about Exactly how I feel mostly because if anything that would be a separate show.
Speaker 0: In fact, I imagine might be a good Thursday because the Thursday we got going now for this Thursday is kind of a crap cop-out.
Speaker 0: but there's a video that exploded all over dig today of a bunch of kids in some city and Apparently they were skateboarding and a cop didn't like it.
Speaker 0: He told him to stop.
Speaker 1: they did.
Speaker 1: there are no skateboarding sign.
Speaker 0: I'll get to that.
Speaker 0: Okay, and The one of the kids I don't know if he was planning on an encounter with the cops.
Speaker 0: If he's just a brilliant kid who realizes that in this modern society, that's really the only way to protect yourself from incidents Especially involving authority figures.
Speaker 1: and why watch some ACLU instructional videos?
Speaker 0: But he seemed he had what appeared to be a hidden camera on him not maybe as a cell phone cam.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't a cell phone cam.
Speaker 0: Definitely not.
Speaker 1: All right, and
Speaker 0: Basically the cop ends up head locking throwing to the ground threatening to pepper spray chases one of the kids around for a while there tries to run away and The situation just escalates and escalates and escalates and then all these kids end up being arrested for all sorts of crimes
Speaker 1: Like what besides
Speaker 0: obstruction of justice resisting arrest battery?
Speaker 0: The list goes on for a while.
Speaker 0: as the guys yelling at them all the crimes they've committed one of the kids starts crying.
Speaker 0: now, of course the internet is Outraged.
Speaker 0: as you might have guessed the internet is.
Speaker 1: it should be.
Speaker 0: well, then the internet seems very easy to outrage.
Speaker 0: I mean go to dig and every other story is usually people outraged about something whether or not it was justified.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the outrage usually goes well beyond a justifiable response.
Speaker 1: Well, I haven't actually gotten the details of this story other than what you just said.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know if I should be outraged or not.
Speaker 0: Well, I will boil it down very simply.
Speaker 0: There is a law against skateboarding in these public places that the kids were violating.
Speaker 0: The kids did ignore the cop and tried to just keep skateboarding and/or run away.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, however, the cop was a total dick.
Speaker 0: I will give the kids that this cop and his cop friend Basically acted like assholes and could have handled the situation I think better.
Speaker 0: there is the line at which you know teaching these kids a lesson would have been the good thing to do.
Speaker 0: I think they stepped a little bit beyond the line.
Speaker 0: However, the internet has reacted crazily to the point that the police station involved has been Succumbing to a flood of phone calls and emails from diggers and youtubers Expressing how horrible this cop is now.
Speaker 0: They should be fired and skateboarders writes and blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Now here are the issues.
Speaker 1: as I see them and I'm gonna break this down without just watch the video It's definitely different from the video where the kids are Skateboarding and some random dad with his daughters tried to wrestle around with them.
Speaker 0: No, this is one of those.
Speaker 1: obviously the kids were in the right this one.
Speaker 1: It's kind of gray.
Speaker 1: It's like the kids were in the wrong, but the cops are also a little brutality.
Speaker 0: But at the same time the cops were perfectly justified legally and all their responses.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah Here are my observations from this rule number one if you are going to run away from the police Do not do so unless you expect you will be able to get away.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because I have.
Speaker 0: I'm going to say this because the statute of limitations is out on all of my previous crimes.
Speaker 0: as far as I am aware, I have run from the police before on Dozens of occasions and I got away in all of those occasions.
Speaker 0: Had there been any doubt in my mind that I was going to get away I would not have run away from the police because if you run and you get caught you're fucked.
Speaker 0: if you run and they knew Who you were already?
Speaker 0: It's game over.
Speaker 0: You're done.
Speaker 0: Do not run away from the police.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like one of those like the way that a lot of criminal law works is like if you do something It's illegal but then every little tiny thing you do sort of adds on to it like robbing a convenience store.
Speaker 1: Okay, robbing a convenience store if you had a gun on you?
Speaker 1: Oh if you brandish the gun if you fired the gun every step every tiny thing you do adds like five years.
Speaker 1: So if a cop is coming after you for say stepping on the grass in the park and you run you just added like Running and like resisting arrest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you don't want those you'd rather just get in trouble for stepping on the girl You got to do is do with that kid in City of God did.
Speaker 1: yep Yeah, but if you do manage to get away for running then you can even avoid the stepping on the grass.
Speaker 1: So yes It's if you can get away get away.
Speaker 1: if you can't Just stop because you'll just get a ticket for stepping on now.
Speaker 0: Yes, perhaps if I ever need a special I could do rims guide on how to run away from the police.
Speaker 0: Yeah but that might land me in trouble.
Speaker 1: so don't run if you haven't done anything illegal yet because Running will be the first illegal thing you do.
Speaker 1: And yes, if you didn't do anything illegal, you can just wait to go to court.
Speaker 0: But anyway, that is probably the most.
Speaker 1: I'm not a lawyer neither am I.
Speaker 0: lesson number two skateboarding is illegal in a lot of places where it probably shouldn't be.
Speaker 0: yeah, and I Really disagree with these towns these cities that try to make skateboarding and rollerblading and anything kids would do for fun on the street illegal.
Speaker 0: But at the same time if there is a law and you're going to civil disobedience it You've got to go all the way in the civil disobedience.
Speaker 1: You've got to get basically every kid in town to skateboard down Main Street And then when the police come I'll stop and say officer we were all skateboarding.
Speaker 1: I suggest that you take it all of us Yeah, and do it every day cuz you know what kids your parents have to pay.
Speaker 0: those Truer words have never been said because I guarantee that the ticket is already more than your allowance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and what are they gonna do?
Speaker 0: dock your wages?
Speaker 0: You're not working.
Speaker 0: You're a punk kid.
Speaker 1: Yep, if every punk kid in town skateboards down Main Street every day and the police ticket all of you your parents will eventually say The law has to change.
Speaker 1: Yep, now they might make it worse.
Speaker 1: like you go to jail, but then every parents gonna have all their kids in jail every day You'll make friends with the cops.
Speaker 1: It'll be a good old time.
Speaker 0: plus it helps if you get your parents to go along with it Because your parents are probably sick you sitting inside playing video games all the time and they don't want you to go out and do Drugs, they don't want you to go out and vandalize things We
Speaker 1: should do next Thursday or this Thursday on this.
Speaker 0: yeah, there's the whole idea of kids need things to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah watch the video.
Speaker 0: I'm not on the kids side 100%.
Speaker 0: I'm not on the cops side 100%.
Speaker 0: It's a complicated situation that I think really encompasses a lot of issues that are facing modern kids in modern America And I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: So, um, but the cop was a dick.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of video games out there and you know a lot of people.
Speaker 1: we always yell at people for mispronouncing things Usually standard English words, of course many video games have names that are not English words and The games don't include audio especially old games and there's usually no way to know the connect the correct pronunciation of these games.
Speaker 0: See now that this funny because before we grew up in the era where there was Nintendo But there wasn't an internet so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah for all we knew it wasn't Nintendo.
Speaker 1: It could have been 19 dough until they had TV commercials.
Speaker 0: Now the same thing happened with words like anime and manga versus anime and manga.
Speaker 0: And I think there's one good example of this.
Speaker 0: where I grew up Everyone pronounced it Crystallis, but in other places of America like down in Philly.
Speaker 0: It was pronounced crystallis and These areas kind of emerged on their own.
Speaker 1: How many people do I know say Mario?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's Mario It's an Italian first name.
Speaker 1: We know how to say it.
Speaker 1: This is this.
Speaker 1: one was not a mystery.
Speaker 0: well, that was more of an accent than people just deciding how to pronounce my no, but it's Mario.
Speaker 1: that is the correct pronunciation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one said Sonica the Hedgehog except maybe the French.
Speaker 1: Oh The hedgehog.
Speaker 1: he is a blue and fast.
Speaker 1: He runs away like the French.
Speaker 1: we do.
Speaker 1: He is a hero.
Speaker 0: No offense to the French.
Speaker 0: You're a lot better than those albionic fools.
Speaker 0: You don't ban video games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have as many sexy video games as you can get as well.
Speaker 0: You should.
Speaker 1: So here are.
Speaker 1: there was a funny.
Speaker 1: it was on dig so everyone's probably seen it.
Speaker 1: But here are the video games.
Speaker 1: that are the seven the top seven mispronounced video game names.
Speaker 1: Number one as soon as I saw it.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh, yeah This is an old NES game.
Speaker 1: I'm very fond of and it is.
Speaker 1: the title of the game is spelled FAX ANA do you?
Speaker 0: I heard I always said Faxanadu when I hit anyone who said anything else.
Speaker 1: be correct pronunciation and this is actually something I learned here.
Speaker 1: is You know Xanadu like, you know The mansion and Citizen Kane and the DDR song only with a FA in front of it as an ado Fazanadu?
Speaker 1: Ah, yep, and actually the it says here incorrect pronunciation Fax Anna do and You know why it's Fazanadu.
Speaker 1: Why Oh Fazanadu?
Speaker 0: is it like Faux Xanadu?
Speaker 1: like you know Xana's a combination of Xanadu and Famicom.
Speaker 0: Ah Total ah.
Speaker 0: That kind of takes.
Speaker 0: that's kind of like when you think about you realize that Pokemon is just pocket monsters.
Speaker 1: The second one is actually one that I lost a pronunciation debate on so I know the critic pronunciation now.
Speaker 1: It is actually a manga slash anime slash RPG spelled Capital Y lowercase s ease not wise.
Speaker 1: Yeah ease ease.
Speaker 0: I said wise.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid I I said wise.
Speaker 0: but here's the thing when I got when I got to college and I hadn't said the name of this game because there was no reason for it to come up In fact, I never actually beat that game on the s.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of games and there's a picked up the screenshot here.
Speaker 1: I think it's a promotional picture for ease six.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's water of Napish, I think it was wanderers from.
Speaker 0: ease was the one on the SNES.
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my brother liked that game a lot.
Speaker 1: I just never see someone with a manga or an anime or video game and the title is spelled y s. it's ease.
Speaker 0: But when I got to college someone said I think it was katsu.
Speaker 0: He said he's.
Speaker 1: he said I think he said Isu.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is he said it right?
Speaker 0: Yep, and my brain immediately made this calculation.
Speaker 0: Wow I'll bet I was saying that wrong.
Speaker 0: He said it before I did.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna defer to him unless other information presents itself.
Speaker 1: Well, he's Japanese.
Speaker 0: You should us saving myself from the problem that Scott had and was made the fool of later.
Speaker 0: for yeah I kind of argued against the ease and I was also wrong, but I knew not to argue.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the next one is one that I've never pronounced wrong, which is su ik o den.
Speaker 1: So we could end its sweet good end.
Speaker 1: Alright, I gotta I don't know how anyone mess that one up.
Speaker 0: I gotta ask because this one always bothered me is no banagas ambition on there?
Speaker 0: because more people?
Speaker 1: that one isn't a matter of Mispronunciation it's a matter of not seeing all the letters.
Speaker 0: people in my life called it No bungas.
Speaker 0: ambition because I I had that problem too.
Speaker 1: because if you look at the word no banaga very quickly You don't see that oona in there and it just looks like no bunga.
Speaker 1: I like.
Speaker 1: I thought if you asked me how to spell it I would have said no B-u-n-g-a, but if you look at it carefully because of you know The Roman letters when you put them in that arrangement you have to look at it carefully to realize it says no banaga.
Speaker 0: See I will give people a little bit of a pass because it's obvious to us now that you know We're smart.
Speaker 0: We listen to Japanese a lot.
Speaker 0: So we're kind of used to Japanese and wrote all that stuff.
Speaker 0: So when we see that word it makes sense no banaga.
Speaker 0: But if you're not like when I first started watching anime when I wasn't used to Japanese I just kind of didn't really read words that weren't in English and just kind of pronounced them haphazardly.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, the next game is Called ahem.
Speaker 1: It actually this the article says we don't know how to pronounce it.
Speaker 1: pronounce this.
Speaker 0: Are you pronouncing words purposefully badly?
Speaker 1: Well, it actually says here in their article We say the name of this game is supposed to be mispronounced.
Speaker 1: do your worst, right?
Speaker 1: The way you spell the name of the game is P O P O L O C R O I S and that is pronounced Popola Croix, if you don't know how to say that you're there's nothing wrong with you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Popola Croix I remember a kid when I want to argue with me.
Speaker 1: bring it.
Speaker 0: That's how that said who was very excited about a new game.
Speaker 0: He got dr.
Speaker 0: Chows.
Speaker 1: Wow, yeah.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The next one is actually pretty sad that people mispronounce pronounce this it's Day sex.
Speaker 0: Yeah, day is X as in day of sex machina.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently some people say deuce X or D Or day of sex.
Speaker 0: ninth grade Greek literature called day Is X is the correct pronunciation?
Speaker 1: The next one is one rim likes the magic of Scheherazade.
Speaker 0: It's not that hard to say that word.
Speaker 0: people not sure Zade not sure Cherezade Cherezade most people seem to say Cesarade.
Speaker 1: the next one is one.
Speaker 0: that's that game sucked.
Speaker 0: by the way, I like I wanted to like that game.
Speaker 0: I forced myself to like that game Like.
Speaker 0: literally I would play the game and I'd say to myself this game is great.
Speaker 0: It's just like all those other RPGs.
Speaker 0: Check out all these spells.
Speaker 0: I can plant things and think.
Speaker 0: so many secrets so many secrets this kid.
Speaker 0: No, thank you suck ass.
Speaker 1: Yep, the next one is Pokemons Pokemon Pokemon Pokemon.
Speaker 0: the correct pronunciation is Pokemon partly because they added in America that Accent a girl above the E to make sure you say poke instead of Pokemon because poke man is kind of yeah perverted.
Speaker 1: So the other pronunciations while fun are admittedly incorrect.
Speaker 0: It's Pokemon my Pokemons.
Speaker 0: Let me show them to you one star.
Speaker 1: Yes, okay to monster Okay, and those are the seven Mispronounced game names.
Speaker 1: if you mispronounce them incorrectly from here on out.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with you.
Speaker 1: Well, actually one of my pet peeves is like if someone mispronounces something, right?
Speaker 1: I I correct them, you know, and then it's like they've heard the correct pronunciation.
Speaker 1: They are capable of pronouncing it correctly.
Speaker 1: They do so at least once, you know, they say it correctly But then they come around to it again and they say it incorrectly.
Speaker 1: the next time like someone will say Manga and I'll say no manga and they'll say all right manga.
Speaker 1: and then a minute later They'll say well, I was reading this manga and I'm like you just said manga.
Speaker 0: Now at least what the fuck.
Speaker 0: I'm fine with that.
Speaker 0: if it's an accent thing Like people who say Mario or the same people to say water and while I make fun of them for their accent I can't fault them for mispronouncing.
Speaker 1: This is an accent.
Speaker 1: We're talking here.
Speaker 1: They were just capable of saying it the correct way.
Speaker 1: They just did it.
Speaker 0: Well, there's no accent that forces you to say manga instead of manga.
Speaker 1: and I will say there's an accent that forces you say aluminium.
Speaker 0: I Prefer saying aluminium.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying it's an accent that forces that to happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, true true true, but I'm okay with that.
Speaker 0: In fact, I somewhat prefer aluminium and I like spelling is also an accent that forces you to say coke.
Speaker 0: Ah We're not getting into that.
Speaker 0: Are you sure we're not getting into that?
Speaker 0: because the numbers are still pretty much 50/50.
Speaker 0: The front the battle line is pretty much at Rochester, New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, so we'll get right to the chase Despite the fact that video game I mean if we look at all the geekeries know the different days of the week we do and we talked about this and kind of our origin shows.
Speaker 0: but Video gaming is the one that I have the most history with.
Speaker 0: it's my nearest and dearest and I think it's shaped my life As a whole more than any other of my geekeries.
Speaker 0: in the long run.
Speaker 1: just for the fact that it shaped my childhood So irrevocably, I mean when I was a little kid I was NES in in the single digits.
Speaker 1: the anime the manga the comics came around and I was like 10 or 11.
Speaker 1: My mother played the Atari 2600 Played the Atari 2600 with her med super breakout action.
Speaker 0: My grandpa played his Atari right up until his death.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and So did my grandma before any other geekery was inset, you know, I didn't have a computer until the double digits Even though I was using computers in kindergarten school, you know Apple twos.
Speaker 1: I didn't have that much time with them, you know.
Speaker 1: and everything else we did was mostly like, you know Outside in the backyard like normal kids and sports and those sorts of every young things I remember.
Speaker 0: I had big conflicts in my life.
Speaker 0: right sitting.
Speaker 0: I'd be sitting in front of the X like that extra TV Because my parents are watching a movie or something and it'd be sunny outside and I had pitfall and I wanted to play pitfall.
Speaker 0: But I also wanted to go outside and I wasn't sure what to do because they were both equal.
Speaker 1: Yep Often what I would do is ride a bike down the street and then play Nintendo at someone else's house or go get them Bring them back to my house.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'd go swimming in the pool.
Speaker 1: Then we dry off go inside and play video games.
Speaker 0: See we never rode to someone's house to get him when we were really young kids.
Speaker 0: We'd always just call up and it was the phone.
Speaker 1: We always just rode bikes down We always use the phone and there's.
Speaker 0: it was like we none of us wanted to like.
Speaker 0: we were awkward on the phone.
Speaker 0: Cuz no, we're little kids, but we had this ritual where we'd I'd get the phone.
Speaker 0: I'd call my friend So I dial 881-1892 which was my friend.
Speaker 0: Joe Ogilvy lived down this way to give away a phone number.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: They haven't yet one.
Speaker 0: I didn't give away the area code.
Speaker 0: All right, and two, um They haven't lived in that house for probably two decades.
Speaker 1: whoever lives there is in trouble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if they figure out the area code to which I am referring that's not hard to figure out what the Internet's.
Speaker 0: and actually no Because the area code changed.
Speaker 0: so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Oh pun but anyway And I'd be like is Joe there and the parents would say just a minute and then Joe would pick up and say hello And I'd say want to play.
Speaker 0: he'd say, okay, we'd both hang up and then we'd meet on the street.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would just have you would just knock on each other's doors and then they would you basically either You know, can you go or can you not go?
Speaker 1: It's pendant on your parents pretty much and it would.
Speaker 1: most of the time it was like yeah go I always notice as a kid like once in a while.
Speaker 1: It would be like no we're going out to dinner You can't go.
Speaker 0: it'd be like whoever knocked on the door Always brought the person whose door they knocked on away.
Speaker 0: You never knocked on someone's door and then went in.
Speaker 0: you always knocked on the door and then like let's go and then you dragged Him out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's what the kids do.
Speaker 1: Anyway Video games are the oldest geekery.
Speaker 1: I've been video gaming longer than any other geekery except you might say like baseball card collecting.
Speaker 1: But I stopped doing that.
Speaker 0: you collected baseball cards.
Speaker 1: Well, you know when I was a little kid, my dad would like buy one pack every weekend.
Speaker 1: News dad, you know is that kind of thing?
Speaker 0: I had a few but I always stuck them in my bike spokes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't do that.
Speaker 1: I kept him on the floor.
Speaker 0: My brother collected him so I can't really make fun of you.
Speaker 1: I got him sitting over there and then I stopped as soon as I stopped collecting things and wasting money on that.
Speaker 1: Right after you know, I gave up.
Speaker 1: basically I switched from baseball cards to superhero cards to magic cards.
Speaker 1: I was like good magic cards.
Speaker 1: These actually have a game associated with them.
Speaker 1: screw those other cards.
Speaker 1: and then I said wait this game And then I gave up all collecting.
Speaker 0: It's a good thing magic cards didn't come with bubble gum.
Speaker 1: Yeah without magic cards.
Speaker 1: I might still be collecting today.
Speaker 1: I would have ever realized collecting was a waste of time and money and space.
Speaker 1: But yeah video game is the oldest most revered geekery yet lately.
Speaker 1: I haven't been doing any video gaming at all.
Speaker 0: Well, I blame three factors and it's not a lack of time so much because there are times when I could choose to play a Video game and I choose to do something else instead.
Speaker 0: and I think number one.
Speaker 0: Is that the Wii at least for us is Absolutely useless because no games have come out for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think we've said talked about this a whole lot.
Speaker 0: This would be like the third or fourth time and I played Soul Calibur on the Wii more than I've played any Wii game.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that just to sum it up one more time.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go into this whole lot.
Speaker 1: Is that the Wii as a vast potential as a gaming platform?
Speaker 1: Incredible potential more potential than possibly any other gaming platform ever created?
Speaker 1: that potential is largely unfulfilled.
Speaker 1: In fact, if the Wii was just a GameCube with a better CPU The games currently available for it.
Speaker 1: Don't even feel that meager potential It's.
Speaker 1: that's how bad it is and I'm confident the potential will be fulfilled within a year or so partly because the DS was in the same boat and the DS is still Awesome.
Speaker 1: Yep, and Until that potential is fulfilled the Wii will remain sitting there off and barely used and that's a whole lot of gaming that I Would be doing.
Speaker 1: if there was a game right now that actually fulfilled more than 50% of the Wii's potential I would not be able to resist playing it.
Speaker 1: but as it stands there's pretty much nothing on the Wii Yeah that I can resist.
Speaker 0: I don't have so much trouble resisting playing Wario where we I don't even need to resist.
Speaker 1: I have no desire whatsoever Exactly.
Speaker 0: So in fact you would have to coerce me into playing it at this point.
Speaker 1: Yep, so the Wii is just sitting there dormant.
Speaker 0: All right, but friend you just said the DS is awesome.
Speaker 0: It is awesome.
Speaker 1: It's holy shit.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: I blame one Pokemons fatigue.
Speaker 1: Yep currently, you know the way the DS works is.
Speaker 1: it is very awesome And there are very many many very awesome DS games.
Speaker 1: but to really get the most out of a lot of them you need the multiplayer action and Well right now while you know the past few weeks we've been sitting in our houses we're going on trains to work.
Speaker 1: all the single-player action on the DS has been cleared out and Only multiplayer action is left.
Speaker 0: See we're in different.
Speaker 0: we're in different states because for me I still haven't even gotten past the first level of Kirby's canvas curse.
Speaker 0: Well, you know that's and I haven't beaten the second Phoenix right game and I stopped playing Pokemon and I never finished Princess Peach.
Speaker 0: Though fuck that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't finish it either.
Speaker 0: I will I beat it.
Speaker 0: I got to the end and then she's like no you gotta go save all the rest of the guys that you didn't save.
Speaker 1: I said what fuck that?
Speaker 0: wait, and I just never played it again.
Speaker 1: I'd be like four levels of Princess Peach.
Speaker 1: then I was done.
Speaker 0: It was fun.
Speaker 0: It was just you know easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah didn't provide much of a child.
Speaker 0: And actually I mean sadly one of the games that I love the most on the DS was still the new Mario Brothers.
Speaker 0: But I got to admit the new Mario Brothers was trivially trivially easy and I really didn't die in beating.
Speaker 1: It was also trivially easy and it had absolute almost no replay value other than going back to get all the big coins and actually Got four worlds worth of big coins.
Speaker 1: Yeah complete sets.
Speaker 0: and then I stopped because it was tedious and I don't know why because Mario world has a lot more replay value and so does Mario 3. and I'm not sure if that's just me and my bullshit nostalgia Or if there's a difference, but I think I'm gonna get it.
Speaker 1: But the reason for that I think is because in Mario world and Mario 3 Usually beat the game without beating all the levels and there was a lot of places to explore and levels to go to and things To do.
Speaker 1: yeah, we did talk about New Super Mario Brothers when I beat it the first time I beat it straight through.
Speaker 1: I beat almost every single level on the first Try in one shot and there wasn't any.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: There there was no content left for me to take in other than finding a few secrets, which I didn't really care about.
Speaker 0: also I mean all the the secrets and the things in Mario 3. in Mario world were kind of hard to get and You had to play through parts of the game, especially in Mario 3 to get to him but in this new one the big mushroom was pretty much a useless gimmick and the tiny mushroom was annoying and The shell just killed you like.
Speaker 0: there was no benefit to these things and there was no mystique about them.
Speaker 0: But the hammer suit.
Speaker 0: one was awesome Two was amazing.
Speaker 1: three was fantastic and for more mystique than any other item in any video game ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, definitely except possibly the hammer in Zelda 2 before I had gotten the hammer.
Speaker 0: Yes But the the thing about it once I got the hammer.
Speaker 1: the mistake about the hammer suit that gives it more mystique than say You know this most powerful gun in Metroid or the BFG or something like that.
Speaker 1: Is that it is not something that is required to beat the game.
Speaker 1: You could beat the game without even knowing it's there where I'll go hammer and Zelda - you're gonna get it.
Speaker 0: I'll go one step further.
Speaker 0: the hammer suit in Mario 3 transcended a hitherto Untranscendent boundary.
Speaker 0: you crossed this line.
Speaker 0: You were able to get a power and become like one of your enemies in a game Where traditionally there was no such possibility.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the possibility of getting the power of an enemy in Mario was amazing to me.
Speaker 1: is that's why Kirby's Adventure was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yes, I love those Kirby games.
Speaker 1: We should actually get the Kirby's Adventure.
Speaker 1: I think this.
Speaker 1: they remade it for the GBA.
Speaker 0: Yes, but I think there were.
Speaker 0: I mean my different.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have plenty of single-player content, but Phoenix, right?
Speaker 0: I got kind of fatigued trying to play it through it in one go just because it was mostly the same game.
Speaker 0: it was just you know, I like the game, but I got fatigued and Pokemon was the same thing.
Speaker 0: I just got fatigued and then at that point I'm really starting to crave Multiplayer action.
Speaker 0: I'm really starting to crave direct competition against my friends as opposed to single-player combat.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that would that niche would be filled by Pokemon except because of my Pokemon fatigue.
Speaker 1: I beat Pokemon the single-player But I'm really fatigued and I have no desire to level up my Pokemon and craft my team necessary for multiplayer.
Speaker 1: but without that team I have no desire to play the multiplayer.
Speaker 1: and it's also unless other people also have their team set They have no desire to play the multiplayer with me.
Speaker 1: So it's gonna take quite a bit of time of losing Pokemon fatigue for me to go back and train up a team And have that be enjoyable.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now, I think the other concern is that I like all this multiplayer stuff.
Speaker 0: I like to play against other people.
Speaker 0: I want to compete with other people.
Speaker 0: I want to interact in a shared space in some way and We just rock the board game something fierce.
Speaker 0: and I actually am trying to end this show as quickly as I can Because Alex is sitting in the other room waiting for us to come down and play a board game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we bought four board games and
Speaker 0: while
Speaker 1: you know We try to keep the Tuesday shows even between board games and video games with some RPGs here and there if we buy four board Games, we're gonna be playing those board games before we're gonna play a video game.
Speaker 1: That's just how it is lately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if there's a board game sitting there, we've only played once in our lives and it's a multiplayer board game That's really strategically deep and is say super paper Mario Which I've beaten a little bit over half of.
Speaker 1: I'm basically gonna completely ignore super paper Mario unless there's nothing else to do at all and when I'm also in addition to that personally when I'm sitting around the house with nothing to do and I need a Solitary activity.
Speaker 1: I'm either going to work on something like maybe housework or eating or you know something for the conventions or the show or something like that or I'm gonna read some comics and I got a lot of comics and books sitting there and lately I'm just in the mood to go for those before I go to beat super paper Mario, which is which is good But it's one of those games where I'm gonna play once and never play again.
Speaker 1: so waiting on beating the second half is actually kind of okay, okay, because it sort of prolongs the Usability of the Wii until this games actually come for come out for it this holiday season.
Speaker 0: I don't know to me I mean, I never.
Speaker 0: I didn't even play through Twilight Princess yet in fact I'm two hours into it and I'm not really sure why because I really like that game and I could.
Speaker 0: I do have time to Sit down and play an hour or two every other night and just start progressing through it.
Speaker 0: It seems like it might just be a personal problem I have where I have seasons of like and dislike of certain things and sometimes it's video game season Sometimes it's board game season.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's counter-strike.
Speaker 1: I'm generally getting the feeling that like I'm in me I really don't have a desire anymore to go out and play video games Like I don't seek them out so much.
Speaker 1: But well some games but a lot of those games I can't play or don't have time for.
Speaker 1: like I can't sit down and play Civ for you know civilization for hours and hours.
Speaker 1: right now, you know, I can't do that.
Speaker 1: But what happens is when new video games come out like let's say that Metroid corruption came out for the Wii, right?
Speaker 1: it has such a strong pull that I can't resist it and I go and I buy it and then I sit down and basically I Would come home every day and play it and play it and play it and play it do the show eat play it and play Play it play it play it until it's beaten and then I put it on the shelf and wouldn't play it anymore because I have Eliminated all its lure
Speaker 0: for me.
Speaker 0: It's more than I go through cycles.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like my man cycle my rim cycle and right now the cycle that I'm feeling cuz I I have my super fast computer And half-life 2 and I really kind of want to play.
Speaker 1: I couldn't resist half-life 2 at all.
Speaker 0: I I'm having trouble resisting it.
Speaker 0: I am but it's so.
Speaker 1: that is the strongest pull.
Speaker 1: the Half-life episode 1 2 comes out.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna be able to do anything else until it's beaten.
Speaker 0: The kinds of games that are available to me that I haven't beaten yet that are single-player on my consoles.
Speaker 0: You know I DS and the Wii.
Speaker 0: For some reason that's not the season.
Speaker 0: I'm in now.
Speaker 0: I was in that season before those games came out and by the time those games came out right now I desire really tactical really deep really immersive Really like maybe half-life but more.
Speaker 0: the things I get out of German board games are games like it has life.
Speaker 1: It's more cinematic experience.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's my real draw right now is games like advanced wars.
Speaker 0: But I've already beaten every advanced wars game entirely and I realize now that I forgot I bought Final Fantasy Tactics Advance, and I stopped playing it a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I think it's time to pick it back up.
Speaker 1: buy that I didn't know we had that.
Speaker 1: I have it I kind of want to play that.
Speaker 0: I bought it real cheap.
Speaker 0: I started it, and then I think I forget what distracted me.
Speaker 0: I think the Wii came out, and I just they're gonna be a Fire Emblem DS Probably.
Speaker 1: I kind of want that.
Speaker 0: now I'm really feeling that the problem is I keep forgetting that.
Speaker 0: I mean I just now remembered I have Final Fantasy Tactics Advance.
Speaker 0: I never played it.
Speaker 0: I'm probably gonna play that tomorrow on the way to work.
Speaker 1: I also think that the final problem is that all things we do in the summer have to compete with the outside of the house.
Speaker 0: Yes I'm like a winter they do not Especially since a bunch of us have decided to take up rock climbing and all these other things.
Speaker 1: well so a new board game that is Strategically deep can compete with outside, but hey super paper Mario really can't.
Speaker 1: it's good And I want to play it, but it can't compete with outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I guess it does just come down to things all.
Speaker 0: I mean.
Speaker 0: there's the competition for every minute of my waking life and right now all the other forms of entertainment are tickling my fancy So much more powerfully.
Speaker 0: Yeah Which is kind of sad because I really like video games and I can imagine the kinds of games That were they put in front of me.
Speaker 0: I would play them to the exclusion of all these other activities.
Speaker 0: But the games I imagine I are there already own and beat or I forgot about which means I'm gonna start playing Final Fantasy Tactics Advance a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: or they don't exist or I don't know about them And I'm not gonna waste.
Speaker 1: you know I have better things to do than spend time looking for them because I really just don't like spending time looking for things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh well.
Speaker 0: You know what screw this.
Speaker 0: I solved my problem.
Speaker 0: I'm felt playing tactics advance tonight, and at least maybe tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well no more video game drought for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, uh I'm gonna go play some board games and expect board game shows for the next week or two.
Speaker 1: God.
Speaker 0: But then we got conventions coming up - yeah, and then we're gonna go and have arcade shows once we get to the shore.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's true.
Speaker 0: I guess all right, but I'm really feeling the urge to go play power.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's another thing.
Speaker 1: the last reason.
Speaker 1: I'm not playing video games.
Speaker 1: There's one genre of game that I feel an urge to play more than any other board game outside or anything.
Speaker 0: What genre is that?
Speaker 1: the rhythm game?
Speaker 1: But of course we can't play DDR in our house because it shakes the house.
Speaker 1: well We don't own the guitar heroes.
Speaker 0: We could play DDR if we play it on the deck, and I'm not gonna do that.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna go to the shore and do the arcade machine.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna probably play DDR for hours and hours to bring my Nalgene over there.
Speaker 0: God.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be those guys.
Speaker 0: I haven't been that guy in a long time.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 1: I gotta be that guy.
Speaker 1: This is my legs right now are literally like there are muscles in my leg twitching like they want to step on arrows.
Speaker 0: you realize I am doing twitching right now in my feet all the steps to shooting star on maniac.
Speaker 0: because I play that song so many times I got to memorize.
Speaker 0: yeah If there's ever a question I love guitar hero, and I think it's awesome, but DDR is so much more staying power Plus the fact that you get exercise plus I'm holding out and buying the guitar hero.
Speaker 1: because while I could get a ps2 and a guitar hero pretty cheap I'm waiting to see which system in the long run has the most rhythm game Action.
Speaker 1: because if I buy a ps2 sure I have access to the existing ps2 rhythm game library and guitar hero 1 2 And I think the 80s version that's coming out.
Speaker 1: But the 360 has guitar hero 2 and I don't know what guitar hero games in the future are those also gonna come for the?
Speaker 1: Ps2.
Speaker 1: what DDR games in the future are gonna come for which systems I want to get if I'm buying a console That's not the Wii because I have a feeling the Wii is not gonna be the awesome rhythm game machine although it might be I won't.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna buy a console other than the Wii unless that is pretty much the home of the most rhythm game action Period.
Speaker 0: yeah rhythm games.
Speaker 1: I love when I first saw I gotta wait and see.
Speaker 0: the first time I played DDR I was converted from.
Speaker 0: while that's stupid - I have found my new calling in life.
Speaker 1: Yep, I saw it, and I people kept playing it, and I looked at it and said that's the stupidest thing.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna bother and I was stupidest thing.
Speaker 1: I'm not even a bother as the soup and I damn it.
Speaker 0: There's that one social night where you were off playing D&D and I played DDR by myself on a projector for like three hours And then you came back, and you were like what the fuck you do when you're playing that stupid game.
Speaker 0: And I was like do it once do it.
Speaker 1: once I said oh I must try everything once before knocking and then I tried it And I didn't want to admit to myself that it was yeah, and then we played until they kicked us out.
Speaker 0: Yep, my I remember how much my feet hurt the next day, so See I think that's all we got to say about.
Speaker 0: I would like to say you guys out There are really lucky because if our house allowed us to play DDR There wouldn't be as many geek nights out there.
Speaker 0: And if we own Guitar Hero wouldn't be as many geek nights out there.
Speaker 0: And if we had both that'd be the end of the show.
Speaker 1: yeah But it's not video game season.
Speaker 1: so if you notice a lack of video game related shows It's not video game.
Speaker 0: It's anime board game comic season at least until it snows again anime season It'll be anime season.
Speaker 1: when the more new shows, I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe in late September I'm probably gonna actually season for watching a lot of anime, but it's not the season for new anime.
Speaker 1: That was you know a few months ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, God.
Speaker 0: I'm just now watching gunkotsuo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm watching Zeta Gundam.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.