Speaker 0: It's Thursday August 2nd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nides.
Speaker 0: Tonight we review the concept of reviews.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Man, I was more productive today than I've been in like I don't know at least a year Yesterday at work.
Speaker 1: There was absolutely no work today at work.
Speaker 1: There was like five minutes of work, so I asked my other workers if I could have some work.
Speaker 1: They gave me two works that took 15 minutes each.
Speaker 0: You should have just gone home.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's what I did after I finished the second 15 minute work.
Speaker 0: See I'm not talking about work at work.
Speaker 0: I didn't do a lot at work today.
Speaker 0: what I did is I did more geek night stuff than I've done in a long time and I got all my ducks in a row and they're swimming In the water and everything's great.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: I sent out so many emails.
Speaker 0: that sounds like something lame, but I actually did.
Speaker 0: it was kind of important Alrighty send in the email.
Speaker 0: Yes, and I got like four more to send tonight.
Speaker 1: I actually started doing stuff because there was nothing to do.
Speaker 1: I tried to work on our new website, and I made a tiny bit of progress.
Speaker 1: mostly.
Speaker 1: I just sat around looking at actually well-designed websites and I realized something is that you see all these really fancy well-designed websites right and other than web 2.0 stuff like dig who hires fancy designers to make their sites and the sites of the fancy designers.
Speaker 1: There are hardly any sites that are fancy and well-designed like that.
Speaker 1: I mean you go to these sites that have galleries of you know screenshots of well-designed websites and links to those well-designed websites so that you can get Inspiration from looking at all these fancy sites.
Speaker 1: I said fancy sites like a thousand times.
Speaker 0: suffice to say
Speaker 1: Yes You look at all these fancy sites for inspiration for your own site in hopes to make it just as fancy and you realize that every single fancy site you're looking at is a site of a web designer or a Site one of the five sites made by one of those web designers.
Speaker 1: That's not actually a major website that anyone actually visits or uses.
Speaker 0: I think the real problem is that we came up with a couple of site designs that if we actually Implemented them somehow would be amazing like they'd actually be amazing and I think they'd be great for geek notch.
Speaker 0: The problem is the amount of time and effort it would take to actually set that up Without because WordPress wouldn't do it by itself mostly.
Speaker 1: See, that's the thing is that part I can handle easily.
Speaker 1: it's the Photoshop part that I can't handle and you know, I ask people to help out and The people who are willing they suck and the people who are don't suck are Unwilling or lazy or they'll charge me money or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, damn them trying to make a living off of what they do I know but the thing is they charge like I'm willing to pay someone.
Speaker 1: the problem is is that the market price is like Thousands of dollars which while I agree is a fair price if they're gonna make me a site that's that awesome.
Speaker 1: But I'm just not willing to pay that kind of money.
Speaker 1: I don't I. if I had that money I'd spend it on something else instead.
Speaker 1: So I don't know.
Speaker 1: I Guess we're just gonna have to.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll take the Craigslist route.
Speaker 1: poor poor design.
Speaker 0: We want to do now, are you sure?
Speaker 0: oh really?
Speaker 0: I just want to make our site some sort of two column instead of three column.
Speaker 1: I think I can succeed at doing that.
Speaker 0: basically We just want to make it less cluttered and kind of collapse a lot of the extraneous fluff like the archive million links into like One archives page and I think I can definitely succeed at doing that.
Speaker 0: the big thing because actually whenever we get a bunch of new Listeners, it seems like the biggest problem is that most people don't to this day Know what a podcast is or how to subscribe.
Speaker 0: and I'd still say that a good 40% of our listeners Go to the website and download mp3s manually.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I'm definitely gonna.
Speaker 1: I got that.
Speaker 1: I have that in mind in my design for the new site.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make it pretty obvious that this is a show of audio content that is made four days a week And if you want to subscribe you can do so.
Speaker 1: Anyway suffice to say god damn it stuff doing that.
Speaker 0: see now I'm doing it on purpose.
Speaker 1: No, don't do that.
Speaker 1: It's not funny on purpose or by accident.
Speaker 0: I think it's quite funny.
Speaker 1: No, it's not like it's annoying.
Speaker 0: No, I like it.
Speaker 1: No, well anyway suffice to say in some your mother in total your mother I'll come up with annoying thing to say.
Speaker 0: and what are you gonna say?
Speaker 0: What could you possibly say?
Speaker 0: That's annoying.
Speaker 1: suffice to say.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I forgot what I was gonna say, but We're expect a few changes to the website in the coming month or two.
Speaker 0: Expect t-shirts and swag and all that business in the coming month or two the con seasons over.
Speaker 0: until what December.
Speaker 1: Yep No more time.
Speaker 0: So we actually have time to work on stuff.
Speaker 0: Of course, a lot of those projects were working on actually have nothing to do with geek nights at least not directly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 1: That is just fine.
Speaker 0: so in the news this was all over dig and a lot of people were outraged about it.
Speaker 0: and while it is a Somewhat common thing in Mexico it bothers me and it bothers me at a bunch of levels.
Speaker 0: Some of these levels have almost nothing to do with this situation.
Speaker 0: The basic story is that Walmart is employing people in Mexico in their store about teenagers.
Speaker 0: Yeah people.
Speaker 0: Well, what are you implying there?
Speaker 1: Well, it's you know, they're only doing it to teenagers not doing it to anyone else.
Speaker 0: Well, are they doing it to teenagers directly?
Speaker 0: or is it simply that teenagers are the only people who do this sort of thing?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know that information is not given but it is reported as teenagers.
Speaker 1: That's what the report says.
Speaker 0: However, you definitely did give the the impression that somehow teenagers are not people.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: Well, this is really that wall.
Speaker 0: This is true.
Speaker 0: Anyway suffice to say Okay, I'm done with that I'm gonna get up and hit you.
Speaker 0: they're not paying these people any money.
Speaker 0: And in fact instead of paying them and they're all baggers and stuff They have a big sign that says quote our volunteer Packers collect No salary only the gratuity that you give them.
Speaker 0: super Rama.
Speaker 0: Thanks you for your understanding.
Speaker 0: now Here's how I read this sign translated into logic speak.
Speaker 0: We have effectively beggars that are under our employ that we do not pay.
Speaker 0: We are trying to guilt you into paying them for us so that we do not have to bother paying baggers.
Speaker 0: Thank you for your money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now I like how you said baggers where it could also be construed as beggars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see I could have made some sort of like.
Speaker 0: I could put a schwa there or basically all you dip thongs and made a little literary joke.
Speaker 1: basically you have these teenagers who are willing to do menial labor for money and Walmart is offering them not money, but they're offering them basically free marketing.
Speaker 1: They're basically marketing to the customers that they should somehow pay these people and they're paying these beggars Essentially these working beggars with marketing.
Speaker 0: this is only one step above that scuzzy guy with the bottle of water and the Nasty rag it tries to wash my window in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is This is like if that guy Had a gigolo or a pimp and that guy had like 20 of these guys.
Speaker 0: He directed them all and then I don't know took all the money.
Speaker 0: Not even took all the money just directed him off for no good reason and somehow made money off of it.
Speaker 1: The metaphor breaks down but you get the idea The thing the only problem the only thing I can say in Walmart's favor because this is horrendous and bad in every conceivable Fashion is that no one's forcing these people to work there.
Speaker 1: So there they are doing it on their own.
Speaker 1: It's not like there's slaves or anything But at the same time as far as I know they could.
Speaker 1: If they are that's even worse.
Speaker 0: Walmart is very obviously exploiting these people in a very direct manner Definitely.
Speaker 0: now the wider issue that bothers me a lot is the idea of tipping.
Speaker 0: the fact that in America I know we have a lot of foreign listeners, but in America you pretty much have to tip They don't pay waiters or busboys or anything practically any money in this country.
Speaker 1: Yes If you're someone who serves tables at a restaurant you do.
Speaker 1: you get paid usually like less than minimum wage Because you're not considered like, you know an hourly worker.
Speaker 1: And that's the way the crazy law is is a lot of those people get paid less than people at McDonald's and they're doing a More important job that requires more skills and and it's harder and it takes more hours.
Speaker 0: So in return the way they make money is that pretty much any time you eat anywhere in this country you have to leave a 15 to 20 percent tip or else you basically screw this person.
Speaker 0: and The fact that tipping is effectively mandatory in the US has bothered me for my entire life.
Speaker 0: It bothers me Means hey good lad.
Speaker 0: You did a fine job.
Speaker 0: Here's a shiny quarter.
Speaker 0: go about your day.
Speaker 0: Yep, and We had a plan that we haven't gone through with but we've talked about a lot and the plan was kind of self-centered Nassau.
Speaker 0: Basically, the idea was to not ever tip unless it was an establishment that we plan to return to in the future Where it is likely that they will remember us Mm-hmm, and basically just be bandits when it comes to tipping because I get nothing out of tipping.
Speaker 0: and the worst thing is the idea Is oh, well, if you have tipping like that Then you can punish a waitress who's bad and therefore waitresses will be good But I can't punish the cook if the food's crappy.
Speaker 0: I can't punish the restaurant if it's dirty.
Speaker 0: I can only punish the waitress.
Speaker 1: yep, and sometimes the waitress will be really nice or the waiter will be really cool and Something else sucked.
Speaker 1: and I have no way to express that suckage.
Speaker 1: Is there's nothing I can do about it?
Speaker 1: and Still I'm sort of still obligated in some way to pay extra money above and beyond what I am legally required to pay For no reason because bill basically because someone is getting paid less than minimum wage and I have to subsidize them or else I'm an asshole.
Speaker 0: Granted I have stiff people on tips a lot of times in the past, but they always deserved it.
Speaker 1: Yes, all I'm saying is that everyone should be paid minimum wage and you should only be Obligated or semi socially obligated.
Speaker 1: You should never be legally obligated to tip anyone ever.
Speaker 1: You should only be well, you're not in this country It's okay, but you should only be socially obligated to tip someone if they did something above and beyond the call of duty.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, they shouldn't expect a tip ever.
Speaker 1: a tip should be like a surprise like oh man's a surprise a tip Holy crap granted.
Speaker 0: by the same token back at RIT We actually were known at all the local restaurants for being extravagant tippers Which was kind of weird when I think about it because that was the poorest I ever was.
Speaker 0: and yet somehow we tipped a lot.
Speaker 0: But it worked out.
Speaker 0: we tip so much.
Speaker 1: I think the reason was is that a lot of people cuz you're so poor Right would eat something very cheap and you had a big table with a lot of people all eating things that were relatively cheap but everyone tipped at least one dollar.
Speaker 1: so you would get a situation where it would be like a $70 meal that for everyone total with like a $20 tip because there are 20 people there and that was crazy I think.
Speaker 0: the other thing was we used to hang out with our way the local gaming club and We just you know They kind of split up the bill and we always ended up throwing in X amount of dollars.
Speaker 0: At one time we went out to eat without all those assholes and we learned something.
Speaker 0: The bills were far lower than we thought.
Speaker 0: half those people were just asses who stiffed everyone on the check And we ended up leaving like a 200% tip that one time Just by throwing in what we normally threw in and then we stopped hanging out with those people.
Speaker 1: Yep, pretty much but yeah tipping sucks.
Speaker 1: the Walmart should fucking pay the employees in Mexico.
Speaker 0: luckily It looks like the Mexican government is all about fixing this loophole.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's good.
Speaker 1: And Yeah, that's all I got to say about that.
Speaker 1: Okay rim one of the things you hate the most you ready?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So is it some pyramid nut job?
Speaker 0: No, is it some Randy homeopathy?
Speaker 0: No, is it something about education?
Speaker 0: Yep, I knew it was one of the three who knew what it was cuz I semi told you before the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was trying to keep that secret.
Speaker 0: I could give the illusion that we'd.
Speaker 0: oh, well, yes There's.
Speaker 1: basically I'm gonna try to sum up this story the best I can because it's a two-pager in the New York Times ready.
Speaker 1: There's a teacher in a Manhattan school.
Speaker 1: He had a student who sucked right?
Speaker 1: he failed the student because the student failed and didn't show up for their final as he should have.
Speaker 1: the Administration Sort of forced him to pass the student because there's.
Speaker 1: it's sort of complicated.
Speaker 1: There was a note that excused them like a doctor's note but the administration misread the note and the note said that.
Speaker 1: the note actually said they were only excused for some days and not the days they actually missed.
Speaker 1: and Basically, the student missed dozens of classes failed to turn in numerous homework assignments.
Speaker 1: the teacher kept meticulous records.
Speaker 1: Other teachers corroborated what this teacher said and The student should have failed.
Speaker 1: they failed.
Speaker 1: They took the final and still failed the final when they got to retake it after getting extra tutoring from another math teacher which was not offered to any of the other students.
Speaker 1: and in the end they Administration still passed the student.
Speaker 0: Ah, I'm I'm seething here.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait and get it ready.
Speaker 1: Here's your ready.
Speaker 1: You want to go nuts?
Speaker 0: I don't want to go nuts cuz I I already had you want to be angrier than you've been angry all day.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna warn everyone right now that I now already have about an hour's worth of yelling from this story that I'm gonna hold in.
Speaker 1: Are you ready to hold in a thousand times the yelling?
Speaker 0: I hope the compressors strong enough.
Speaker 1: This is the final line or the final paragraph of this article ready.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Lamp rose who's the teacher?
Speaker 1: recalled one comment that mrs Fernandez the student's mother made during their meeting about why it was important for Indira The student to graduate she couldn't afford to pay for her to attend another senior prom in another senior year.
Speaker 0: Hate this country and everyone in it.
Speaker 0: that that symbolizes that exact Everything that happened there symbolizes everything that's wrong with America because it all comes down to education.
Speaker 0: in fact, I think almost every problem in the world comes down to poor education and
Speaker 1: I think this might sound extreme but I am going to say that in the If I were if I was in the position of the Congress of the United States And I was a judge interpreting the law that I just made and I was the police The mom would be arrested for neglect of her child.
Speaker 1: That's what I say.
Speaker 1: That's how it should be.
Speaker 1: That's neglect.
Speaker 1: right there You have a kid who's doing poorly in school and you say take my kid out of school.
Speaker 1: They don't need any more learning even though they're dumb as a brick.
Speaker 0: I think the problem though is far deeper.
Speaker 1: You should probably have your kid taken away from you if you're that bad Though I think the problem is far deeper than it is far deeper.
Speaker 0: But I'm not gonna get all John Taylor got to because I like him.
Speaker 0: He's a little nutty but I agree with about 60% of what he has to say, but I'm of the mind that the US educational system could be reformed Really simply to become extremely awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the span of like four years.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: basically
Speaker 0: doing a show on that remind me
Speaker 1: Yes but basically all I got to say is that while I think the best solution would be to redo the whole school system with some crazy new education
Speaker 0: not even that it
Speaker 1: could be a Very you're not letting me finish Is that I think that would be?
Speaker 1: the best solution would be if we did some crazy Revolution of the education system.
Speaker 0: We could just do a reverse pull pot.
Speaker 1: We could but reverse pull pot solves everything even if we just Regardless of that while slight modifications such as actually failing people, right?
Speaker 1: Wouldn't be the perfect?
Speaker 1: be all end all solution to having an awesome education system.
Speaker 1: They would improve things so much with such a with just a few small changes that you wouldn't be complaining.
Speaker 1: you wouldn't be thinking about having a big revolution because if we just started failing people and Actually having hard classes and being hard on students.
Speaker 1: I think the real is just pushing the honors people forward.
Speaker 1: That's all you have to do and if you do that Well the education quality will improve like a thousand percent and you won't even think about having a revolution because it'll be so great.
Speaker 1: It won't be perfect.
Speaker 1: Like it could be if you had a John Taylor Gatto style ish revolution of education, but it'll be great It'll be awesome.
Speaker 0: So think about that.
Speaker 0: All Scott basically said was reward students who do well.
Speaker 0: Have consequences for students who don't do well.
Speaker 1: Don't just pass.
Speaker 0: everybody have a press stupid reasons.
Speaker 0: have a path of improvement for students who don't do well.
Speaker 0: Those three things alone would revolutionize education in the US.
Speaker 1: Yep, and Here is here.
Speaker 1: This is New York Times people.
Speaker 1: It is a circumstantial evidence But this goes on all the time.
Speaker 1: In fact, this was there was the school policy is what makes this circumstance happen.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm gonna relate.
Speaker 1: policy of the school itself is not circumstantial evidence.
Speaker 1: This is just the kind of circumstances that arise from the shitty school policy.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna relate to you a short anecdote but in Michigan where I went to high school there were these tests these standardized tests that everyone in the state had to take when you were a junior and Basically you had to pass these tests with a minimal passing grade.
Speaker 0: You didn't have to do really well on these tests.
Speaker 0: You barely had to get anywhere the easy test.
Speaker 0: well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: if you didn't pass these tests you didn't get a certified diploma and Essentially they tested.
Speaker 0: can you read at like a middle school level at the end of high school?
Speaker 0: Can you do basic arithmetic?
Speaker 0: and that was it?
Speaker 0: That was all attested?
Speaker 1: Yeah in Connecticut actually there was a lot of standardized testing throughout my school years.
Speaker 1: But one test they added when I was in high school was the cap test the Connecticut aptitude something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had the right the Michigan something something so whatever.
Speaker 1: that was the new test They added.
Speaker 1: and the deal with that test was that it didn't determine whether you would graduate or not Basically it if you did well on it, they added a stamp to your diploma.
Speaker 0: That's what ours was.
Speaker 0: You got a certified diploma.
Speaker 1: It wasn't certified.
Speaker 1: It just had an extra stamp.
Speaker 0: That's all this early.
Speaker 0: That's all the certification.
Speaker 1: while they didn't say certified They said stamp that you got a stamp.
Speaker 1: Okay, and these tests actually Were quite difficult.
Speaker 1: like one of them you had to design and execute a science experiment and you know Take your lab results and draw conclusions from it.
Speaker 1: And another one actually had like a couple calculus questions on it and it was actually hard tests Except for the writing one, which is the same as every other writing test.
Speaker 1: It was read a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: then write an opinion.
Speaker 0: I don't remember the writing paragraph.
Speaker 0: Remember the writing test to get into RIT?
Speaker 0: No, every every freshman at RIT had to take this writing test to see if you got into.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah
Speaker 1: in the little
Speaker 0: blue book Yeah, I took the test was basically like right about your summer vacation in 20 words or less
Speaker 1: pretty much and
Speaker 0: the fact that
Speaker 1: I filled up like one and a half blue books
Speaker 0: a Significant number of the people who took that test failed it.
Speaker 1: Wow Staggered.
Speaker 1: yeah, those people I mean think about it those people they were already accepted to RIT.
Speaker 1: They failed the writing test After they were already in.
Speaker 0: now the writing test tested like writing at a fifth grade level and I'm not kidding.
Speaker 1: and they put them.
Speaker 1: They didn't kick them out of RIT.
Speaker 1: They put them in the remedial Like liberal arts class.
Speaker 1: what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Why does a college a post high school place have a remedial liberal arts class that you know?
Speaker 1: Class that like Ninth graders you can't read should go You know.
Speaker 0: it's even more fun the fact that even if you pass with flying colors and you got to skip the crap class and go into Like the most advanced required English class.
Speaker 0: It was basically eighth grade literature and that was it.
Speaker 0: Yes, I mean we read stories that I read in middle school and wrote essays that I wrote in middle school.
Speaker 1: That's mine was in middle school.
Speaker 1: The one I took at RIT.
Speaker 1: My first liberal arts class was basically ninth grade English.
Speaker 1: again It wasn't eighth grade English.
Speaker 0: I forget if I took part one or part two But I only took one of them and it was I think I don't remember because they were sort of combined.
Speaker 0: It was like oh, yeah, they were but I had a bunch of AP stuff.
Speaker 1: So I remember everyone else read that stupid tree red star.
Speaker 1: Yes tree red stars, and then I read it sort of after everyone else.
Speaker 0: I don't remember why actually I'm gonna when I had basically had to read this God-awful book called the tree red stars for the class and this is college.
Speaker 1: pretty much everyone read it.
Speaker 0: I didn't read the book I didn't even buy it.
Speaker 0: I got an A. so I Looked online.
Speaker 0: I read a Wikipedia about.
Speaker 1: I have pushed that out of my mind.
Speaker 0: All I remember is we all read a book red star something I remember when the author of the book came to give a talk at RIT After the teachers had basically given us all this bullshit about the metaphorical meanings and the hidden symbolism and all that crap.
Speaker 0: And she basically said I wrote this book because I liked it and there's no hidden meaning in it And I didn't really intend anything by it.
Speaker 0: and I'm surprised that you guys are making so much out of it And it's kind of frightening to me.
Speaker 0: Goodbye.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't actually go see that person.
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh, I had to to get extra credit to make up for the fact that I didn't do like 90% of the work for the guys.
Speaker 0: I never showed up ever and I always made up an excuse too.
Speaker 0: It's not like I just skipped.
Speaker 0: I actually made up an excuse every time she bought it.
Speaker 0: every time it was great.
Speaker 0: Yep I was like I hurt myself in fencing class.
Speaker 0: I had to go to the doctor because I thought time I hurt myself in fencing class 9/11 happened.
Speaker 0: I'm distraught over 9/11.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, that's that.
Speaker 1: read this article.
Speaker 1: if you want to be pissed off Remind me.
Speaker 0: we'll do a show about this at some point.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen the Simpsons movie yet.
Speaker 0: I heard it's kind of funny but not as good as the actual good Simpsons.
Speaker 0: But here's a compilation of all the prank calls that Bart made to Moe.
Speaker 0: Moses lag in like the first seven seasons of the Simpsons and I forgot how hilarious those were.
Speaker 1: I think the reason that the Moe phone calls are so funny right is because number one it's an actual funny bit like Hugh jazz or Amanda hug and kiss IP freely.
Speaker 1: Ivana tinkle something like no problem be a problem, right?
Speaker 1: And those are John's trap.
Speaker 1: So you've got that joke.
Speaker 1: then you've got most response like, you know I'm gonna take your eyes put them in your pants So you can watch when I kick the shit out of you or something like that.
Speaker 0: I somehow don't think most said the word shit.
Speaker 1: Whatever kick the crap out of you.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's fun.
Speaker 1: That's funny right, so you got two jokes, right and Lastly not.
Speaker 1: it's not just a prank call.
Speaker 1: like someone calls someone and you have one person is going ha ha ha ha ha And another person is going girl.
Speaker 1: I got praying called right?
Speaker 1: It's Someone calls someone.
Speaker 1: they get enjoyment.
Speaker 1: Usually Bart is standing with someone.
Speaker 1: he doesn't make the prank calls alone.
Speaker 1: very much.
Speaker 1: So the people around Bart also laugh and everyone in Moe's tavern also laughs.
Speaker 1: so it's not like one person torturing someone.
Speaker 1: It's like a whole bunch of people are all having a good time.
Speaker 1: Like hey
Speaker 0: I think that's one thing that South Park does really well, too And I think it might be why I like South Park so much is a lot of times when someone gets there come up in So something bad happens to someone who deserved it in South Park.
Speaker 0: It's not just oh they got their come up ins It's always like oh they got their come up ins.
Speaker 0: and you don't care You care about the fact that like everyone in town is watching them get their come up ins.
Speaker 1: Yep, and When I guess it's funnier when you see a whole bunch of Pete That's probably some psychological thing when you actually a bowl bunch of people enjoying something.
Speaker 0: Remember that article I talked about a while ago about how Laughter has almost no link to humor and the majority of the laugh response in mammals Humans particularly but monkeys.
Speaker 0: I have a similar thing Has to do with the power dynamics of all the people involved and people laugh as a social activity as opposed to as them themselves Being entertained by something in most cases.
Speaker 1: I must say that makes sense because if I watch Excel saga alone I don't laugh very much and I noticed that even though I think in my brain that what's happening is kind of funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least a little bit like I listen any lizard, but when I watch Excel saga at anime club, I can't stop laughing like when I listen Eddie Izzard in the car Like I'm highly amused but I just kind of sit there.
Speaker 0: same thing We're listening to Lewis black on the mp3 But then I'm riding with Scott or Emily somewhere and we're listening to the same thing and I laugh so hard I almost cry.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's it's not even like conscious like aha.
Speaker 1: I'm laughing to fit in.
Speaker 1: It's like I can't help it.
Speaker 1: It's actually like a contagion infectious thing.
Speaker 1: So yeah When you have a joke like the mo prank phone call and you see a group of people laughing at it It makes it funnier and easier to laugh at.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: Here's a flash game.
Speaker 1: It's basically the premise of this flash.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're using this.
Speaker 0: this look pretty piss-poor.
Speaker 1: It is pretty piss-poor.
Speaker 0: Okay, whatever.
Speaker 1: yeah at the premise of the flash game is that you're standing there plus it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: people listening like the zombies remember Oh, yeah, but they keep saying something about some podcast doing a show about that whatever.
Speaker 1: so the premise of this game is you're the last guy making the last stand against the zombies and You're on the right side of the screen.
Speaker 1: and the zombies come from the left to the right and they as soon as the Sun Comes up they stop coming.
Speaker 1: You have a gun and you can shoot the zombies.
Speaker 1: you die if the zombies break your wall.
Speaker 1: So you click on the zombies and you move up and down to shoot them and you try to kill them all before they destroy Your wall.
Speaker 1: then every night you have 12 hours to spend doing stuff.
Speaker 1: You can spend your hours repairing your wall And if you choose to spend an hour repairing your wall It repairs by 5%.
Speaker 1: and you could choose.
Speaker 1: you could actually spend all 12 hours repairing the wall to repair it by I guess 60%.
Speaker 1: You could spend hours looking for weapons and as soon as you spend enough hours looking for weapons you find one and You could spend your hours looking for other survivors And if you find them they will hide with you behind the wall and help you shoot at the zombies.
Speaker 1: The problem is that this game while the premise is pretty awesome The execution is kind of poor.
Speaker 1: clicking on the zombies to kill them is very annoying because they take many shots to kill and the aiming Is pretty piss poor and even if you get all headshots it takes like two.
Speaker 0: I think the real problem is that actually playing the active part of the game shooting the zombies There's no strategy or skill or anything.
Speaker 0: It's just stupid.
Speaker 1: There was almost a strategy in that you're allowed to have two weapons at once and you could switch them out.
Speaker 1: So I was gonna have a strategy of unload the shotgun to kill a bunch of zombies and the shotgun reloads So slowly.
Speaker 1: I would just switch to the machine gun and then use that for the rest of the level because it reloads quickly.
Speaker 1: But I would still get a bunch of shotgun stuff off to clear the level out at the moment I needed it, but it doesn't let you switch weapons while reloading.
Speaker 1: So I empty the shotgun and I'm stuck reloading it even though I'm holding like this You know full up assault gun.
Speaker 1: in the other hand it sucked well.
Speaker 0: The real issue is what the game should have done is not even made that an active part and instead of could actually Controlling and shooting the zombies in this really crappy way.
Speaker 0: You just have people and you allocate them to parts of the wall and arm them with weapons.
Speaker 0: That would have been a much better.
Speaker 1: something even worse if you spend out You don't know exactly how many hours you have to spend to do certain things So you can't plan it out exactly even though there is a meter that says, you know How many hours until you find another weapon?
Speaker 1: also getting the better weapons doesn't make it that much easier and Even if you find survivors to help you on the wall If you and when it becomes nighttime and you go out searching for things, you know searching for weapons again
Speaker 0: Those survivors
Speaker 1: are pretty much guaranteed to die while searching for other survivors and weapons So they don't stick around very long and you can't really build up a camp full of survivors.
Speaker 1: Basically, the game is just a really good premise with a really frustrating and tedious execution.
Speaker 0: We got to steal that premise and make a better game.
Speaker 1: Yes, but you should check it out because it killed five minutes of my day with entertainment.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't check it out.
Speaker 0: I saw what Scott was doing and realized it was crappy.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it's not worth your time.
Speaker 1: It's worth five minutes.
Speaker 0: No, it's not five minutes.
Speaker 0: It's not worth five minutes.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: I won't spend five minutes on it.
Speaker 0: You can if you want, but don't say I didn't warn you.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Now you could construe what Scott just did as a review.
Speaker 0: Perhaps that was a pretty good segue, wasn't it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was pretty good.
Speaker 0: So tonight we're gonna review the concept of reviewing because I've noticed that in Most of the world as far as I can see it reviews are utter garbage that don't help you in any way.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it comes down to this right.
Speaker 1: you look at all these blogs and these websites and these magazines and newspapers and people have been reviewing Entertainment making you know Commentaries on other works of art, you know, which are I guess are works of art themselves for as long as there's been art and People just seem to nowadays do it sort of reflexively.
Speaker 1: like a video game comes out people looking for the video game reviews you know, there's a movie people looking for the movie reviews and Video games suffer from this more than just about anything though.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I think people really have forgotten that.
Speaker 1: they've forgotten the purpose of a review.
Speaker 1: they've Sort of like not actually think about how they review things like.
Speaker 1: they sort of fallen into a formula of how things are reviewed and they follow it unthinkingly and We're creating a lot more reviews of products than actual products themselves And it's really just made this mess of useless stuff that people wade through.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: well I think the much more direct issue is simply that in the video game industry most reviews are pretty much blatantly paid off and crappy and Crappy in the sense that a video game doesn't get a bad review ever and people freak out of.
Speaker 0: a video game gets like an 8 out of 10 as unless it's like some kiddie game and even then The only reason they don't freak out is because the kids don't go on the inner tubes.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So first let's discuss What is the purpose of reviewing things in the first now?
Speaker 0: I see two separate purposes of reviews.
Speaker 0: I mean and I think that a review can do one.
Speaker 0: the other or both of these and Movies you should see is actually a good example of a podcast that does both very well I think.
Speaker 0: on one hand review is Describe in such a way a thing that someone who has not seen it or done it or played it or bought it yet Can figure out if it's the kind of thing that they would probably like and it would be worth the money to them Without ruining the thing for them to the point that it ruins the experience or they don't get as much out of it.
Speaker 1: Insert argument about how if something can be ruined that's Bad about the thing.
Speaker 0: but at the same time like Terminator 2 There was a thing that could have been ruined.
Speaker 0: that didn't matter.
Speaker 0: you can enjoy the movie with or without having that ruined.
Speaker 0: However, the original trailers to the movie ruined it already and totally fucked something that could have been amazing.
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about sports like about reviews But that's the thing.
Speaker 0: a review can not necessarily spoil something like oh so-and-so kill so-and-so in the end But they can spoil things about a movie or a game that had you discovered them on your own You probably would have enjoyed the movie more.
Speaker 1: Well, here's an example.
Speaker 1: There was a Ghostwriter is alright.
Speaker 1: You mean he's a dude with a flaming skull on a bike with flaming wheel.
Speaker 0: I'd find the idea of ghost rider silly at best regardless.
Speaker 1: There was a ghost rider movie recently.
Speaker 1: I did not see this movie.
Speaker 1: I don't think rim saw the movie either.
Speaker 1: I have no intention of seeing this movie.
Speaker 0: However, I like how you said.
Speaker 0: you don't think like I might have snuck out and watched.
Speaker 1: you might have you might have.
Speaker 1: There was a trailer for this movie for free on the internets.
Speaker 1: I watched that trailer.
Speaker 1: I think I watched it one and a half times.
Speaker 1: that trailer gave me all the entertainment that the movie would have provided.
Speaker 1: I got to see a dude on a flaming with a flaming skull ride a flaming bike up the side of a building.
Speaker 0: You know, I get this problem.
Speaker 0: That's it much done.
Speaker 0: every comedy movie like every normal mainstream comedy movie that comes out in the u.s.
Speaker 0: All the scenes that are funnier in the trailer and I just don't bother with the stupid movie.
Speaker 1: So when you do review something you have to prove you have to give You have to.
Speaker 1: what you're sort of trying to do when I review something at least is when I experience a work of art Whatever medium it happens to be in.
Speaker 1: it gives me a feeling.
Speaker 1: sometimes it gives a good feeling sometimes it gives a bad feeling, you know, and what I try to do when I review something is I'm Basically communicating to someone who has not yet experienced the work of art the feelings that I got when I experienced the work of art and I'm trying to do it also in such a way that they can predict based on what they know about themselves the type of feeling they will get if they were to experience the work of art in the same way that I experienced it.
Speaker 1: and I think that's really what you're trying to do without actually just giving them the work of art because The point of a review is that you have to go out of your way.
Speaker 1: You have to spend money you have to spend time You have to go through a significant effort to experience a lot of works of art.
Speaker 1: You have to spend an hour in a movie theater You have to spend 30 hours in front of a video game console.
Speaker 1: You got to ride the train for 20 hours with their DS.
Speaker 1: You got to spend $20 in a DVD and you want people to know what they're getting into before they put through the effort to experience the work of art.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, that's what a review is all about now.
Speaker 0: at the same time along those lines Reviews are not and cannot be objective.
Speaker 0: the fact people always try to like this is an objective review.
Speaker 0: We have metrics.
Speaker 0: That's bullshit.
Speaker 0: It's you gotta if someone's reviewing something you really have to.
Speaker 0: I mean you can try to take objective stances on certain.
Speaker 1: There are some things you can measure objectively.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah use those as criteria in your review, but in the end those criteria themselves are subjective.
Speaker 0: I guess my point is don't pretend that your objective.
Speaker 0: instead just go all out and say this review is from my perspective And as a result if you're trying to filter media for yourself you go and find reviewers who you know Tend to like the things that you like and hopefully they'll recommend things that you like.
Speaker 0: case in point penny arcade.
Speaker 0: I have very similar video game tastes to those two guys.
Speaker 0: as a result I tend to trust just about anything they say about video games and they have pretty much never steered me wrong.
Speaker 0: Dave and Joel are somewhat similar to and that I generally have similar taste in video games.
Speaker 0: if they tell me a game's good I'm probably going to like that game.
Speaker 1: Yep, especially when it comes to the shmups.
Speaker 1: They like the good shmups over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz they hate Ikaruga even more than Scott does.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is quite a feat.
Speaker 0: granted I hate Ikaruga more than anyone but that's just cuz I'm bad at shmups.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, alright.
Speaker 0: Anyway, now.
Speaker 0: the second possible purpose of a review is what I like to call the complete review or in gig nights as we call The final thoughts.
Speaker 0: that's the review where you're not really focusing on People who haven't seen it yet.
Speaker 0: You're reviewing something fully as kind of a companion to the media.
Speaker 0: So say we you watch I don't know the Watchmen movie that hasn't come out yet And then you go to see like the geek nights final thoughts or someone else's like full-on companion review.
Speaker 0: You basically go to hear someone else's opinion of the work as a whole in order to bring up points of discussion.
Speaker 0: Maybe realize things as symbolism you might have missed in the movie or in extra information about it.
Speaker 1: I think the purpose of a review like that is to sort of broaden your view.
Speaker 1: It's like you've seen a work of art from your perspective and now the reviews of other people have seen it.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like the same reason after you see a movie with all your friends you discuss it with each other so that you can sort of Conglomerate all your different perspectives into a unified perspective.
Speaker 1: So a review of something you've already experienced is sort of increasing your you know vision of the work and broadening the hurt.
Speaker 1: You know the work itself in a way from where you're sitting now.
Speaker 0: a hidden part of all that is not just the broadening your horizons and realizing, you know things you might not have noticed, but there's the secret pleasure of reliving the moments in the movie or the book or the game or whatever that Really really made it stand out to you.
Speaker 0: and I get this the most when I listen to movies You should see and I actually emailed them about this.
Speaker 0: I get much more enjoyment about when I listen to a review of a movie that I've already seen.
Speaker 0: now They're trying to sell me, you know, check out this movie, but I've already seen the movie But I kind of wait like when they reviewed seven.
Speaker 0: I wait.
Speaker 0: I just want to hear them talk about My favorite scene in the movie or the scene that I thought was awesome like the time when the guy did the thing to the Other guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's not so much what they say It's just the fact that they reference it and the synapses in the brain go off and I kind of relive this moment vicariously through them.
Speaker 1: well because experiencing the moment because you have this work of art that you experience and it gave you certain feelings and you want it.
Speaker 1: it's not Easy to replicate feelings again, you can remember them.
Speaker 1: It's it's weird how you can have feelings Remember what the feelings felt like but not consciously create those same feelings again, you know Sometimes they happen, but it's very difficult And I think you need to like achieve some sort of Zen Buddhism enlightenment to actually be able to just make them happen whenever you want.
Speaker 1: So listening to a review of say I don't know full metal alchemist after you watched It is a really good way to help you get the feelings back because you aren't you know The freaking Dalai Lama or anything like it'll remind you about like.
Speaker 0: actually last night I was flipping through music kind of randomly and Emily was reading and I Randomly just hit on the last song that they play in cowboy bebop And I was just kind of struck suddenly by like.
Speaker 0: all the memories and emotions of the end of cowboy bebop Just flooded back to me and I sat there going.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: That was a fucking awesome show.
Speaker 0: It's not like I forgot at the end of cowboy bebop or that cowboy bebop as a whole was amazing.
Speaker 0: I was just suddenly and viscerally reminded of it and reviews can serve that same purpose.
Speaker 0: I really think that reviews can serve either or both of these purposes and that they're both entirely legitimate and necessary.
Speaker 1: so why The reviews suck, I think the first reason reviews suck is because people forget these purposes.
Speaker 1: they just They don't know that thinking it's diary out the mouth.
Speaker 0: It's the would you read your own blog syndrome?
Speaker 1: Then they're not thinking about.
Speaker 1: let me make something so that people who haven't yet experienced this work of art Will you know what the work of art is like?
Speaker 1: they're not thinking hey People who've already seen this will read this and they'll relive it and get enjoyment.
Speaker 1: They're just thinking I Experience this thing bla bla bla bla bla say everything I can think to say about it bla bla bla bla bla.
Speaker 0: I really think that the reason a lot of reviews particularly on to internet suck is that the majority of people I believe This is my opinion on the internet who have a blog and they review stuff Review for only one of two reasons.
Speaker 0: Reason number one in a sad attempt to somehow get into the video game or whatever industry and hopes that people will send them Free shit.
Speaker 1: I think there are a lot of people who review things To hope that an industry will send them things to review.
Speaker 1: there are.
Speaker 0: there are those people number two to be the zero-day guy And get attention like the iPhone comes out.
Speaker 0: the iPhones popular.
Speaker 0: They want to review it as soon as they can in order to ride the wave of the items Popularity as much as they can for whatever stupid reason like ads.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are people who do that I also agree, but I think there is a some other reasons.
Speaker 1: people review things on the internet.
Speaker 1: one thing is that people want to make a blog or a site right and They don't really have interesting things in their lives.
Speaker 1: you know, I mean most people at least it seems like a lot of people I mean us included.
Speaker 1: a significant portion of their lives are defined by the Artwork and entertainment and culture that they consume especially in this consumer culture we have here.
Speaker 1: Yeah us when they want to blog, you know a log or a journal most of that is going to consist of talking about the Culture that they consume and that sort of amounts to what we call Reviewing things and people just do it because there's not much else.
Speaker 1: They have to say that you know It's like if someone makes a blog what do they have to say?
Speaker 1: They spent all day playing video games and watching TV.
Speaker 1: Guess what their blogs gonna be about the video games They played the TV they watched.
Speaker 0: I think another major problem that comes up very often is the fact that a lot of people for various reasons Just don't give negative reviews.
Speaker 0: I mean some people give like the funny negative reviews like the angry video game nerd who I crack up just thinking about him.
Speaker 1: They're very angry video game nerd.
Speaker 1: I love that guy is so awesome.
Speaker 0: I mean one.
Speaker 0: he gives really good reviews.
Speaker 0: these old games - I relive that the fucking jump in turtles.
Speaker 1: He he days got every base covered.
Speaker 1: if you haven't played it You see what it's all about without getting it ruined you.
Speaker 1: if you have played it You relive the suckiness and he's entertaining all at the same time.
Speaker 1: He's got like this trifecta.
Speaker 1: He conquers both purposes of a review while Simultaneously his review itself is an entertaining work on its own that could be reviewed.
Speaker 0: But like look at most podcasters when they talk about other podcasts Very rarely will a podcaster say anything negative about another podcast unless it's geek nights because we'll say podcasts suck all the time.
Speaker 0: I was gonna get to that cuz we're gonna launch a new famous for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we get a lot of ire from a lot of podcasters for kind of they say we're dicks.
Speaker 0: But all I have to say about that is the last time we were kind of down on a podcast We got more than 14. and when I say more than 14, I mean we got 15 emails or forum posts from 14 different people.
Speaker 0: Well 15 different people who all said man you were totally down on that podcast and they said you were assholes.
Speaker 0: But then I listened to you and I realized that you were right and I stopped listening to that crappy podcast.
Speaker 0: You've shown me the way or something like that.
Speaker 0: I'm dead serious.
Speaker 0: We got a lot of emails like that.
Speaker 0: yeah, it happens and uh We're gonna start doing that a lot more not just a podcast but to everything because I think you've known us long enough to Know that when we review something we don't pull the punches.
Speaker 0: No, I mean we gave kinetic on last year a Pretty bad review overall.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though we really like the people who run kinetic on and this year We gave a very awesome review and the reason was kinetic on Did awesome this year.
Speaker 0: if Otacon had a crappy year we'd say it.
Speaker 1: if Otacon had an awesome year I think part of what it is is that we're not fanboys of anything pretty much and We concentrate mostly on the negative because the negative is where there's things to say that are interesting.
Speaker 1: I mean if something's good, what do you have to say?
Speaker 1: It was great.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 1: It was fun.
Speaker 0: It made me feel I don't know I can say a lot about something.
Speaker 0: I mean I could talk for hours and hours about cowboy bebop or antenna and just like.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna talk about But you're not gonna be.
Speaker 1: you can't talk about how it was good.
Speaker 1: You got to talk about like some other things like, you know the interesting Symbolisms in the plot.
Speaker 0: honestly, I could do a whole show just talking about why it was good Like it was good because of these factors in the way they were executed.
Speaker 0: That's a good hour of talking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you can't talk about the actual goodness itself, but you can talk about the badness itself.
Speaker 1: Well, it's easy.
Speaker 0: I think more to the point It's easier to be funny when you're talking about something that sucks and that's what makes Dave and Joel amazing.
Speaker 1: Yes, but anyway, yeah We seem to basically everything.
Speaker 1: we seem to concentrate on the negative and we say everything that's negative And then we say if we didn't say something was negative assume it was positive.
Speaker 1: so even when we give an awesome review of something we end up just listing the few bad things it had.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, well the other thing is and this happens a lot with people who are friends with other people who create content Is that they're afraid to step outside of the friendship and objectively give criticism to each other.
Speaker 0: and I warn you podcast world We might be talking about a lot of podcasts in the future.
Speaker 1: yeah, well also I think that sort of branches that same idea into fanboys and where someone is a fanboy of say Megaman.
Speaker 1: so they won't give.
Speaker 1: they won't say anything negative about a Megaman game Even if it was a really sucky Megaman game that they barely played or they'll keep playing it and tell themselves They like it when they don't because they're such a fan of it as if you know Megaman is their friend.
Speaker 1: Just like if I was friends with an author I wouldn't negatively review their book, you know, or my my review of their book could be tainted.
Speaker 1: And while of course every review is biased period every review is tainted.
Speaker 1: There are certain conflicts of interest that can occur to make a review extremely tainted and incredibly biased to the point at which it's not really useful and it doesn't serve the purposes of the review and when that happens Not good.
Speaker 0: So originally our idea was and we came up with this pretty much today or yesterday was that we would Every Thursday or every other Thursday or whenever we got around to it We just take like one or two podcasts and just review them real quick.
Speaker 0: You know spend five minutes and just talk about.
Speaker 0: you know, this is a podcast worth listening to this one Isn't?
Speaker 0: here's why it's good years wide span just using quick reviews.
Speaker 0: and the feedback we got when we proposed this idea in the forums was Why just podcast review stuff all the time randomly make like a five-minute bit and you know what we're gonna do that.
Speaker 1: I think basically what's happened here on geek nights is because we cover one thing per day.
Speaker 1: pretty much I mean four things a week and there's a lot more things out there than four things a week and not just reviews.
Speaker 0: They're actually trying to shy away from Reviewing stuff all the time and do a lot more topical shows because I think they're a lot more interesting.
Speaker 1: yep, and not only that but There are a lot of things out there that say I played a video game rim hasn't played it or I read a comic rim Hasn't read it or rim watched a movie I haven't seen it.
Speaker 1: or there are things where we have something to say about it But not enough to fill a whole show, you know, and there's a lot of stuff We just don't get to.
Speaker 1: even though we have something to say it never gets said.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna add a new segment that could show up in any geek night's show randomly.
Speaker 1: You never know when you're gonna see it where we just do really short reviews of stuff like BAM.
Speaker 1: Here's a review of this video game or BAM is a review of this book.
Speaker 1: You know just really quick five minutes or less just to get more stuff out there, you know stuff.
Speaker 1: We have to say we could use it to pad out the episodes or you don't have a lot to say.
Speaker 0: Now the big part of all this is that they're not.
Speaker 0: they're gonna be so short You know a few three or four or five minutes that they're not gonna be straight up reviews.
Speaker 0: I'd almost call them recommendations or anti recommendations.
Speaker 0: It's basically gonna be.
Speaker 0: here's something that you'll pry like.
Speaker 0: Here's something that you probably won't like.
Speaker 0: here's a few reasons why.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean, I guess I just did basically an example.
Speaker 1: as my thing of the day I gave a recommend anti recommendation or slight recommendation for a flash game on a web page and That's the sort of thing you can expect if we you know in this segment that we're going to create that We don't have a name for yet.
Speaker 0: So all of that said suffice to say etc, etc.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's back.
Speaker 0: We're both.
Speaker 0: we're gonna start it tonight just by giving a quick recommendation review of a couple of random things.
Speaker 0: Cool I think we'll start with you.
Speaker 1: Well me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, go ahead.
Speaker 0: Are you not ready?
Speaker 1: No, I try cuz the name of my Thing I'm gonna talk about is different.
Speaker 0: All right, fine.
Speaker 1: So let me maybe I'll think of something different to talk about.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: anyway, the friend of ours Alex who works with us and collaborates a lot of the projects we do lives in Beacon And definitely one of the earliest and most senior members of the front row crew Recommended to me because he reads a lot more fantasy books than I do.
Speaker 0: even though I really like fantasy books A lot of them are really bad.
Speaker 0: So I kind of try to get recommendations from him.
Speaker 0: He suggested to me partly because he said that I kind of reminded him of one of the main characters Which as I read the books was a somewhat dubious honor, I guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah But these books are.
Speaker 0: it's a series of books that I'm just gonna call the Prince of Nothing by Canadian author R Scott Becker or Baker bak k?
Speaker 0: er.
Speaker 0: and If you like Tolkien the or any kind of like hard Dark hard-hitting Serious high fantasy not kidding around not for kids Really?
Speaker 0: Well-written Badass fantasy books.
Speaker 0: These are so up your alley.
Speaker 0: You could you can't believe it.
Speaker 0: I read the first two pretty much immediately and I'm ravenous for the rest of them.
Speaker 0: I Don't really want to spoil anything about what they're about.
Speaker 0: suffice to say the writing style.
Speaker 0: say yeah, I threw that in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah suffice to say The writing style is Somewhat fantastic and I'm not gonna even quote anything because I want you to find all of these Literary gems by yourself and you know them when they come.
Speaker 0: I believe one of my favorites was a sentence that ends in the words And then they attempted to enter the circle inscribed by his sword.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: This is some high fucking fantasy.
Speaker 0: It's absolutely amazing.
Speaker 0: And also if you've been listening to the podcast 12 Byzantine emperors or you know anything about the Crusades Or Byzantine history or anything like that You're gonna realize that these draw heavily from the Crusades in a very awesome way.
Speaker 0: Alright, I cannot recommend these books enough.
Speaker 0: So Scott, what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: Alright, it took time to find this on the internet because it was slightly problematic Alright, but anyway, there's a manga that just came out from CMX.
Speaker 1: who's the DC?
Speaker 1: CMX, you know, it's DC comic.
Speaker 0: They're the ones who just picked up toki wo kaka or shoujo.
Speaker 1: Yes, and it's a manga called samurai commando mission 1549.
Speaker 1: That's the name of it in English.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's the actual name of it in Japanese.
Speaker 1: I did see the actual name of it Japanese in the back of the book But I forgot it and I'll have the book on hand.
Speaker 1: It was based on a novel and I think there was also a movie whatever.
Speaker 1: basically, it's an.
Speaker 1: it's an awesome.
Speaker 1: awesome.
Speaker 1: if you are liking the militaries or if you were liking the samurais or if you were liking the Japanese histories or even just a sci-fi time-travel story This is a manga that will provide now.
Speaker 1: It's not some amazing knock your socks off manga But it's basically one of those manga where if you have a particular interest.
Speaker 1: it tweaks the fancy quite vigorously.
Speaker 1: It's a story of oh, man's some guy went back in time a real military guy from the present with tanks and guns Killed Nobunaga and Started making a castle.
Speaker 1: and what's he up to?
Speaker 1: and of course, this is destroying the present because you know time paradox and His sort of follower from when he was in the present, you know Goes back in time to stop him and crazy stuff happens.
Speaker 1: I read the first volume on the train.
Speaker 1: I think it's only two volumes.
Speaker 1: So hey pretty damn cheap The art it was actually.
Speaker 1: it's it's standard manga arts.
Speaker 1: But if you actually read about the artists in the back like the art studio They apparently made the art with almost no effort whatsoever compared to normal artists.
Speaker 1: So it's like whoa, they made this easily.
Speaker 1: what could they have made if they had spent a lot more time?
Speaker 1: and Yeah, I mean the thing is the character designs are not too exciting.
Speaker 1: The some of the action scenes are kind of like how what just happened?
Speaker 1: It's not like you.
Speaker 1: follow the action and there's an exciting action going on.
Speaker 1: It's just oh.
Speaker 1: they shot the guy up.
Speaker 1: They stabbed the guy.
Speaker 1: But the plotline itself is pretty complex and pretty intriguing.
Speaker 1: as to who?
Speaker 1: what's they gonna happen next?
Speaker 1: Oh, what's that guy thinking?
Speaker 0: What's they going to have?
Speaker 1: what's they gonna happen next?
Speaker 0: That was grammatically amazing.
Speaker 1: It was so happy.
Speaker 1: So, yeah If you are looking for a manga to read and you're bored of the usual Shonen jumps in the shoujo beats and you want some military Japanese history type stuff samurai commando mission 1549 is worth the price of paying for it.
Speaker 1: And also I actually recently read the Wikipedia of Nobunaga and a lot of the Japanese history stuff in there is actually pretty accurate.
Speaker 1: So if you're a fan of the alternate history type stuff, this will also tweak your fancy quite well score.
Speaker 0: So on that note expect more of this in the future.
Speaker 0: It'll probably become some sort of a. I mean, you know now the show is the formats pretty, you know We've got the news.
Speaker 0: the music plays to the thing of the day and then we do the main bit.
Speaker 0: I imagine that this bit and possibly other bits we had in the future the more of them will probably test in the experimental feed But I think this one's already fine.
Speaker 0: They'll probably just occur at the same place but semi randomly whenever we get around to them.
Speaker 1: I think actually the end of the show is not a bad place.
Speaker 0: I think so, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean other podcasts I know like that the comic geek speak they do towards the end of their show like hey They call it off the rack and they're just like hey Anyone want to talk about a comic they read recently and people do like the same thing but comics only
Speaker 0: also.
Speaker 0: I kind of got an idea because it wouldn't be that much more work to do.
Speaker 0: If you guys really like these segments and they're short It wouldn't be that far out of the way to.
Speaker 0: in addition to just having them in the normal show We could take that audio separately and make a feed.
Speaker 0: That's just all of our like geek nights flash reviews.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if you want to do that.
Speaker 1: we could.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm willing to do it.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't take much effort at all.
Speaker 0: And that's I mean a lot of people only listen to one or two nights of the show and a lot of people find Things like this like they like to have an archive of things like that in iTunes.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, I'm thinking of doing that for a lot of our bits someday in the future once I can automate the process better.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So that's what we have to say about reviews.
Speaker 1: Those are some reviews we have.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, and to all of you content producers that were out there whether or not you were friends of ours beware because we're coming.
Speaker 1: We're gonna start reviewing everything podcasts included.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night You.