Speaker 1: It's Wednesday November 7th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Why Naruto sucks?
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I came home the other day to box a really heavy big box, and it said to Scott Yeah, well there's a lot of boxes coming from the mail these days so sadly none of them contain brides.
Speaker 1: I wish there were some brides in there.
Speaker 1: That'd be nice, but no Not Yoko Kanno, I guess she would count as a bride.
Speaker 1: no Anyway, you know I had a.
Speaker 0: this is no joke.
Speaker 0: I had a teacher in high school whose father Did in fact get a Russian mail-order bride.
Speaker 1: I remember back in that when I was in Rochester There was on the local radio.
Speaker 1: a guy called in and talked about how he would go to Russia to be with brides.
Speaker 0: No this was that she came over and lived with him as his wife yeah, and she learned English.
Speaker 1: it is a real thing.
Speaker 1: It's kind of creepy, but it's real.
Speaker 0: It was an interesting situation And he would periodically give us updates about how his stepmother the Russian mail-order bride was doing.
Speaker 1: yeah Anyway, yeah, so in this box I don't know if everyone listening knows But I get a like the way I buy comics as I ordered them from this website DCB service calm direct comic book service.
Speaker 1: And the way it works is you order comic books two months in advance Which is kind of sucks because you don't get to look before you buy.
Speaker 1: and sometimes I buy crap But it's worth it because I get like 40% off.
Speaker 1: so even if I buy crap I still save a shit ton of money, and I get like.
Speaker 1: I spend like a hundred bucks in comics every month But I get like two hundred and fifty dollars worth of comics, and it's just like this big mountain.
Speaker 0: It's great because whenever I want a comic I if I find out when it's coming out I just tell Scott hey put it in your thing, and then it comes for almost no money almost no money.
Speaker 1: I mean manga.
Speaker 1: even an expensive manga will be like eight bucks Amy.
Speaker 1: and sometimes every month is like specials some like last volume of Death Note five dollars Five dollars brand new not used or anything anyway, so two of these comics of the I don't know 20 or so.
Speaker 1: Usually what happens is it sort of comes in waves so I could be light month with a little tiny box a little tiny Box little tiny box big box, and it was finally the big box this time, but I got the the trial of Colonel sweeto.
Speaker 0: Oh My god, which if you don't know what that is I suggest you search for the Perry Bible fellowship Which is nothing as nothing to do with Perry's Bibles or fellowships.
Speaker 1: I think it has something to do with Perry's does it now?
Speaker 1: it does indeed well.
Speaker 0: Regardless it is in my opinion one of the funniest things ever put to ink or any other medium.
Speaker 1: I would put it in the top 10 comic strips of all time in the history of the world.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: it's so wonderful and the book doesn't actually have a lot of specials in it.
Speaker 0: It has like 10 lost strips even though I've seen some of those so I'm not sure how lost they really were.
Speaker 0: but yeah Not.
Speaker 0: I expected commentary on all of them, and I was really sad to only get commentary on the lost strips.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't matter because it's still worth it to have those things a little book.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah website is sort of annoying to navigate.
Speaker 0: I just I love it, but the other thing I got that was really important.
Speaker 0: here We've talked a bit about.
Speaker 0: Jason are one of our favorite comic artists, and he did such things as why are you doing this?
Speaker 0: and?
Speaker 1: The Left Bank game?
Speaker 0: yeah, that was the good one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was all Hemingway, but it was also Anyway, they all have a very distinctive style, and we've talked about that, but I want to do a quick geek bite here.
Speaker 1: I remember back in the day when I first found out about what are you doing this from like some blog?
Speaker 1: I think was boiling boiling and I was like and I read the description of it I'm like oh, man.
Speaker 1: That's a comic for him.
Speaker 1: It was like years ago.
Speaker 0: Think about it.
Speaker 0: You're
Speaker 1: an RIT still Maybe it's
Speaker 0: a short simple psychological thriller
Speaker 1: and it had like animal people and I was like I soon as I read the description I knew it was the Comic for rim, and it took me how many years to actually get a copy of it, and then what I did.
Speaker 1: I was so right.
Speaker 0: so uh we just got finally.
Speaker 0: I think it's one of his newest works.
Speaker 1: It's the newest one.
Speaker 0: yeah is the title is I killed Adolf Hitler I killed Adolf Hitler and It's about Exactly, what do you think it's about?
Speaker 1: It's like you think.
Speaker 1: oh, you know it's one of you know.
Speaker 1: usually when people make something About Hitler like he appears once or you know it doesn't actually have to do with Hitler literally.
Speaker 1: no literally I killed it off Hitler literally, and I'm not gonna ruin it cuz Crime.
Speaker 0: but one you should read everything this man ever writes, but two I Just remembered what happened to Hitler.
Speaker 0: yeah This is excellent pick it up.
Speaker 0: There's no reason not to read.
Speaker 0: I killed Adolf Hitler.
Speaker 1: I think I think Fanta graphics publishes these things right.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: all I know is that they there.
Speaker 0: The trend in these works tends to be along the lines of concept.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Oh oh Oh And then it ends yep, and this one is true to farm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't exactly find the publisher that quickly because I'm not too quick with the computer.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to talk nothing else.
Speaker 0: just bear in mind read this and the last page I mean, it's good all the way through.
Speaker 0: it's excellent in fact.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It is published by Fanta graphics.
Speaker 0: I'm awesome, but the very last page is I guess You kind of could have seen it coming But at the same time you really couldn't.
Speaker 0: and it's just.
Speaker 0: it's so Perfectly executed and melancholy and just wonderful.
Speaker 1: yep, so every Book that you go to Fanta graphics calm and anything that is by Jason That's that's how what he goes by just goes by one name Jason sort of like sting Jason.
Speaker 1: get all of them because they're all great.
Speaker 1: actually Rem I just here's a title of one that we haven't read called.
Speaker 1: he gives what the title of this one.
Speaker 1: is you ready?
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: the title is you can't get there from here.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: You know what you got to get that one.
Speaker 0: You can't get there from here.
Speaker 1: No, but you got to get that.
Speaker 0: I think I'm going to eventually own the entire Jason collection.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think we've got like three or four of them already.
Speaker 1: so all right.
Speaker 1: Anyway check this out you ready.
Speaker 1: I'm ready all right, so there was a survey company called Oricon right which is a big Japanese survey company.
Speaker 1: I always see their name attached to all sorts of surveys about anime and stuff and they did a they survey for Japan's culture day on November 3rd and They had a questionnaire at and the questionnaire asked which cultural figure represents Japan?
Speaker 1: right like they asked Japanese people which cultural figure you know represents your country and They had two thousand two thousand people online and they evenly divided them between all the different age groups five different age groups You know of both genders and the results were Number two.
Speaker 1: the number two person who represents Japan was Miyazaki all right, but that's expected and acceptable.
Speaker 1: You know the number one Person was.
Speaker 1: I could say something funny, but it's a Japanese person you know, but I doubt you'll guess it, but just try Satoshi Ka.
Speaker 1: I know It was a Takeshi Kitano.
Speaker 1: Really, yes, really, huh?
Speaker 1: He's the number one person of representing Japan.
Speaker 1: if you don't know who that is He's the.
Speaker 1: he's the.
Speaker 1: he's the bad guy in battle royale.
Speaker 1: He's also Count Takeshi from Takeshi's castle and Takeshi's challenge the horrible Nintendo game.
Speaker 1: And he's also an amazing actor for many movies that you probably should see because they're all awesome.
Speaker 1: I think he was Zato Ichi in a recent in the recent Zato Ichi movie.
Speaker 0: He's almost as cool as Koyasu almost as cool as Takehito Koyasu, but not quite Aka pumpkin head.
Speaker 1: no, but you should Seek out Takeshi Kitano also known as beat Takeshi and see him in all his Artistic endeavors usually TV shows and movies right.
Speaker 0: so this is slightly old news But it's kind of interesting, and I'm very happy about this, but according to anime news network There's a new anime distributor translator, or whatever.
Speaker 0: just so we need another anime called Reanimedia and they're going to be releasing the melancholy of Haruhi Suzumiya.
Speaker 1: wait someone already has that here the place promised our early Days.
Speaker 0: we already have that to Wolf's reign.
Speaker 0: We have that also serial experiments lane.
Speaker 1: Those are all different companies that put that out here in Russia.
Speaker 0: Oh and the Baltic states.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's fine.
Speaker 1: Are Russians into anime?
Speaker 0: uh you know what I would imagine.
Speaker 0: so because it seems like Most of the world is into anime in some form.
Speaker 1: no Italy is super into anime like Italy loves going to gain To Italy and actually from what I hear Mexico Mexico.
Speaker 1: I can ball south them all.
Speaker 0: America loves loves frickin and Dragon Ball and G Gundam and anything like that.
Speaker 0: apparently Latin America.
Speaker 1: Just they love that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, Russia.
Speaker 1: Huh, I guess maybe the you know Russians.
Speaker 1: They know how to use computers pretty well.
Speaker 1: Maybe they torrents got over there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well apparently they also bought out a company called Excel.
Speaker 0: oh alright I was a little mistaken.
Speaker 0: half of those titles were being brought out by Excel media, which they just bought.
Speaker 0: But in addition they're bringing out pet shop of whores and Suzumiya, huh?
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a way to make some money.
Speaker 1: go to countries that don't have anime and bring it there.
Speaker 1: You know just like buy licenses and then go am I or like.
Speaker 1: what about companies like you know?
Speaker 1: At V is like.
Speaker 1: you know they pay all this money for rights.
Speaker 1: why they only buy the u.s.. Rights probably?
Speaker 1: Why don't you try to buy like some worldwide rights, and then you know go big.
Speaker 0: see it's hard to say.
Speaker 0: I wonder what the Japanese even say to someone offering to buy a worldwide right or not exclusive.
Speaker 1: That's really why the Japanese get the world right.
Speaker 1: they already own the world right rice.
Speaker 1: They made it.
Speaker 1: Why don't they go worldwide?
Speaker 1: I don't know I?
Speaker 0: Take issue with a lot of the way Japan tries to my.
Speaker 1: Take the world.
Speaker 1: I also take issue, but you would think that would be the way to get the most profits.
Speaker 1: no You know I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe a less Potential profit, but lower risk.
Speaker 0: or maybe they've realized that the American anime companies will just bend over and take it regardless.
Speaker 0: So why bother changing?
Speaker 1: yeah again?
Speaker 1: I wonder are they really making the most from the American ones and compared to any other country?
Speaker 0: see the problem is None of them ever say anything.
Speaker 1: we have no idea what anime.
Speaker 1: so we know like the UK anime companies could be you know Doing a lot better than the American ones.
Speaker 1: who knows I mean There's.
Speaker 0: so we've complained about this a lot and so is that in my world order the anime industry is so tight-lipped in the u.s.
Speaker 0: That it's it's ludicrous like it bothers me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't they see that like in every other industry the companies that are you know the more well?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I guess that's sort of incorrect to say that because you look at places like Apple and Google It's like the the tight lips and it seems to work out.
Speaker 1: But I guess well people tend to like companies that lose their lips.
Speaker 0: Well at the same time I feel like they could put a lot more pressure on the Japanese companies if even if they weren't more open if they I don't know colluded illegally Or in some way if any of them would just stand up and say no That much money is ludicrous for a show that you're not even gonna Let me release for a year and a half in the u.s.. And won't let me talk about until two weeks before whatever.
Speaker 1: yep Well people just you know they they don't make the day of the hardcore like business deal where businessmen duke it out and and drive A hard bargain.
Speaker 1: I think that day is sort of long gone.
Speaker 0: I don't think it is.
Speaker 0: I just think the anime companies in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Are run mostly by anime fans as opposed to by businessman with testicles.
Speaker 0: So things of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what I can say about this.
Speaker 1: Mickey fail.
Speaker 0: What it is a blog not in English Dedicated to pictures of Mickey Mouse that portray him in an unflattering way.
Speaker 1: Oh Mickey fail.
Speaker 0: Feo fe I.
Speaker 1: oh oh that's not Spanish, but that is a Latin language of some sort.
Speaker 1: because fail in Spanish.
Speaker 0: Oh, I never would have guessed yeah But I look ugly Mickey Mouse ugly Mickey Mouse bunch of ugly Mickey mice.
Speaker 1: you like ugly Mickey Mouse I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just I guess this speaks of the fact that one there's a blog for everything.
Speaker 0: That's true everything - I don't know that there's some amount of novelty to looking at a website that is so Specialized and to such a specific audience.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's more specialized than nadshots.com I don't know.
Speaker 0: it might be.
Speaker 1: no it's not.
Speaker 0: that is in all comics.
Speaker 0: This is just Mickey Mouse.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe but anyway Looks like a penis.
Speaker 1: I want to take this opportunity.
Speaker 1: So does this?
Speaker 0: I think that Mickey Mouse is constructed entirely of Stylized palaces.
Speaker 1: I want to take this opportunity to say that I actually really like Mickey Mouse and that.
Speaker 1: One thing that constantly pisses me off is that Disney doesn't let anyone make any Mickey Mouse cartoons with their endless copyright.
Speaker 0: BS Huh, but it wasn't that wasn't that copyright just about to expire?
Speaker 0: Bono copyright saved the day.
Speaker 1: But at the same time what have they done with Mickey Mouse besides merchandise since the prince of the pauper?
Speaker 1: well nothing.
Speaker 0: Let him fade as fast as they can into obscurity.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean more people around the world recognize Mario than recognize Mickey Mouse at this point.
Speaker 1: make Mickey Mouse cartoons make a whole Full.
Speaker 1: you know, you make a full-length Animation motion picture every summer.
Speaker 1: Why don't you put Mickey Mouse in one of those freaking movies?
Speaker 0: See is I'd be all for that except there's someone who needs a movie theater to see that shit much more desperately and that's Donald Duck, but you got a course.
Speaker 1: put all of them in there.
Speaker 1: But you know Mickey Mouse would be the main guy and you call it, you know I mean the other day I was randomly watching some of those old like goofy cartoons.
Speaker 0: Like goofy teaches you how to ski.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or ah, I know you are the biggest fan of the goofy and the Donald Duck.
Speaker 0: More so but well more than anything.
Speaker 0: It's anytime Donald Duck and Chip and Dale get into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah for me it's all about like the Mickey and the Beanstalk sock action.
Speaker 1: but of course Mickey and the Beanstalk is so great, but that part with goofy on the jello.
Speaker 1: You bring this up every time we talk about Jello, if you haven't seen Mickey and the Beanstalk, you're not human being.
Speaker 1: And also, I mean, come on Fantasia best part Mickey Mouse.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: say I guess that's second to the the finale Not a bomb out.
Speaker 1: All right, do I need to do a thing today?
Speaker 0: I think you do.
Speaker 1: Okay, Mickey Mouse is awesome.
Speaker 1: Anime News Network, you provide me all my news on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: You are so wonderful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, great I go to this one website.
Speaker 0: pick the least not interesting thing.
Speaker 1: read it kind of my news and my thing.
Speaker 1: They are both from anime news network.
Speaker 1: I would just like to extend my thanks to anime news network.
Speaker 0: So you're not doing the rocky thing?
Speaker 1: No, that was kind of funny, but it's not.
Speaker 0: it was good.
Speaker 0: It's funny cuz Scott always yells at me and Emily and everyone whenever it's like Like.
Speaker 0: I see something on the internet and he saw it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: five seconds ago man written.
Speaker 0: That's such old news What the fuck.
Speaker 0: but he says oh, man, I found this thing.
Speaker 0: This is like so awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, you have to come and watch it.
Speaker 0: We walk over and both of us simultaneously Say that's so old.
Speaker 0: I saw that like a year ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the difference is when I you know Different I don't care.
Speaker 1: You say it's so old.
Speaker 1: I'm like whatever.
Speaker 1: I just found it.
Speaker 0: However, if you've never seen it, you know yesterday I did Half-life in 60 seconds.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: This is rocky.
Speaker 0: One, two, three, four, five and six in five seconds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: so my actual thing today from anime news network is anime news network like many other blogs and cool websites that provide geek news had a pumpkin carving contest and these are all the pictures of the pumpkin carving contest and Many of them, you know, some are better than others But you know anime themed pumpkins some of them amazing in quality.
Speaker 0: Scott tried to show me a picture of his favorite pumpkin, but every time I tried to look at it He turned the laptop away.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: no, I didn't.
Speaker 0: ah You could have run with that.
Speaker 0: cuz if think about what your eyes Ruined the joke, maybe why do you do this to me?
Speaker 1: But anyway, yes, this is some really good pumpkins going on here.
Speaker 1: I mean, I see this really good gonkotsu.
Speaker 1: Oh one this housing one.
Speaker 1: That's just like amazing.
Speaker 1: Here is one where they actually made the pumpkin into a Haro.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff going on here, but Scott.
Speaker 0: What is the best one?
Speaker 1: Well, it's not actually the best one because the actual Quality of it is is pretty low, but the boo pumpkin is amazing.
Speaker 1: I like booze.
Speaker 1: I mean you could they could have just taken a picture of a boo printed out of their printer and taped it to the front of the pumpkin And then on the backside of the pumpkin taped a picture of the boo with his eyes closed And that would have been good enough for me.
Speaker 0: You hear that fangirls draw a boo and Scott will be all over that.
Speaker 0: maybe It's actually kind of sad because for the last two years we have said all right We're gonna carve pumpkins here in the game more like for flash ten years.
Speaker 0: Well here I mean known you pretend you count our IT where every year we wanted to carve pumpkins.
Speaker 0: But either I didn't have enough money to buy a pumpkin this year.
Speaker 1: We even failed at buying them.
Speaker 0: We didn't get one I don't know what's because last year we went and bought pumpkins.
Speaker 0: We're like, oh man, we got three pumpkins.
Speaker 0: We're all gonna carve pumpkins gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: And then we even got Emily to come out and like let's carve our pumpkins the three of us.
Speaker 1: and then we didn't even Bought the tools to carve them.
Speaker 0: So we've still got the tools.
Speaker 0: I've got like a hundred tea candles, but The pumpkin sat there until the others tea lights.
Speaker 0: It's a candle.
Speaker 1: It is a candle but it's a specific type of candle.
Speaker 0: Yes a tea one a tea light candle.
Speaker 1: No, it's a tea light is a subset of candle.
Speaker 0: So thus it is also a tea candle.
Speaker 0: no Anyway So this year we went apple picking earlier than we expected.
Speaker 0: So as a result, it was too early to buy pumpkins the pumpkins ahead.
Speaker 0: We're not so great dad.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it was mostly their lack of pumpkin selection.
Speaker 0: It was too soon.
Speaker 1: It was too soon also, but the selection was also.
Speaker 0: so we said don't worry.
Speaker 0: We'll come back and buy pumpkins when it's time.
Speaker 0: And Halloween came and went.
Speaker 0: yep, and we've still got the hundred tea candles.
Speaker 1: It's reminds me of an idea Open pumpkin carving tool.
Speaker 1: this reminds me of an idea I had today.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 1: I had this idea, you know Thanksgivings coming up right actually had this idea listening to Dave and Joel.
Speaker 1: Thank you, Dave and Joel, you know a cornucopia, right?
Speaker 1: You know what a cornucopia is?
Speaker 1: Yes, it's something that I People more often today use the word to say like oh a cornucopia of something as in a bounty, right?
Speaker 1: But the actual object a cornucopia.
Speaker 1: you've seen them.
Speaker 1: You probably might not know but it's it's a Thanksgiving kind of thing.
Speaker 1: It's like a it's like a horn basket thing with a whole bunch of crap coming out of it.
Speaker 0: I don't know, but I pictured something horrible.
Speaker 0: No, I Want people to make geek cornucopias and send them to us?
Speaker 1: Well, no, you can just take a picture and put it online but we're like geek cornucopias.
Speaker 1: right and try to make a theme like you can make like a an anime cornucopia or maybe a Halo cornucopia or full of grenades.
Speaker 1: Yeah a half-life cornucopia grenades Mario Cornucopia little bombs.
Speaker 1: Who knows, you know something like that.
Speaker 1: go for it and you know, it could even just be photoshops.
Speaker 1: It could be the real deal.
Speaker 1: I want to see people get creative here with the cornucopias.
Speaker 1: That is that is my request.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, one more thing.
Speaker 0: I'll just bring this up on the show because I'm proud I finally did it and I actually updated it.
Speaker 0: I have a blog.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: I've had a blog for Since 2003 or 4 well years.
Speaker 1: Technically I've had one since 1998 Here's in years ago.
Speaker 0: There was even Scott saw proto geek nights where he did an audio blog.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just I was bored one day at RIT and I said hey Why don't people like record themselves talking and then put it on their websites.
Speaker 1: There's no reason that can't be done.
Speaker 1: So I did.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I had a slash journal that I posted in twice and then never even looked at again.
Speaker 1: It's like I before.
Speaker 1: back in the day I just had to Geo cities which wasn't really a blog technically.
Speaker 0: then later my og my Geo cities was a semi illegal Bootleg ROM site.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then like I moved that I kept updating that and moving it over and it was just static HTML And then I kept moving it around and doing stuff with it and then I did a slash journal and then I set up some old pearl blogging software and then I set up WordPress and I'm still using that WordPress.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's not Dvorak org slash blog It's rim dot front row crew.
Speaker 0: calm because I know how to use domains.
Speaker 1: Actually, I should put me at that front row crew calm to forward with the C name.
Speaker 0: Yes, you should there's no reason not to.
Speaker 1: I know I'll probably do that tonight if I remember Yeah, I'll probably eventually.
Speaker 0: the problem is that rim net is taken by something stupid and rim calm is way for Way for it to expire.
Speaker 0: it expires in forever.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So tonight We learned from Dave and Joel again.
Speaker 1: They recently reviewed gal guy guy.
Speaker 1: now I'm not gonna comment on because I've never seen it.
Speaker 0: I've seen some.
Speaker 0: gal guy guy is an awesome show as long as you never watch it.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I like the song anyway.
Speaker 1: So what happened was is they they basically they didn't say they didn't They didn't hate on the show exactly.
Speaker 1: But again They weren't the biggest fans of the show and it seemed that the popular opinion was that the show was bad for a while And then got good really good and was an awesome show.
Speaker 1: So this the fact that their opinion was contrary to the popular opinion drew some attention.
Speaker 1: So he said hey, I got an idea.
Speaker 1: Let's start doing some shows where we give opinions Contrary to the popular opinion and maybe we can get some attention though.
Speaker 0: Don't worry because I think next Tuesday We're gonna do a show that is not contrary to the public opinion, but the two of us disagree.
Speaker 0: Oh Because it's been it's.
Speaker 0: I'm not even gonna say what it is, I'll see if you all can guess.
Speaker 1: It shouldn't be hard if you've been in the forums.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's only two things that we've been arguing about lately.
Speaker 1: So today we're gonna do something that's gonna piss a bunch of people off.
Speaker 1: We're gonna tell you that Naruto sucks So does bleach and so does one piece and so does dragon ball.
Speaker 0: There's a special place in my heart for the absolute disdain.
Speaker 0: I feel towards cried.
Speaker 1: I've only watched like two episodes of that.
Speaker 0: That's not a good show.
Speaker 1: brave master also sucks final fantasy unlimited.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to think of any others.
Speaker 1: I Can't that fist.
Speaker 1: the North Star is good, but only an ironic way and otherwise sucks.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah guy guy I think the real important thing I think it was Joel's comment that You can't get me to sit through 26 episodes of a good show and you expect me to wait through 20 episodes of a bad show.
Speaker 0: That might get good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Basically, it is the opinion of both of us that there there is a genre of anime and manga.
Speaker 1: That is the show not just shonen but shonen fighting a subset of shonen even right which is specifically a show where you have Incredibly long fights and it's the show is all about the fighting or some sort of combat.
Speaker 1: in some way You could even argue successfully that something like a car no go could be considered shown in fighting.
Speaker 1: Instead of fighting.
Speaker 1: they're playing go he car no go Initial D.
Speaker 0: Those are all shown in fighting shows as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're pretty much.
Speaker 1: you know, it's sometimes tough to draw the line between shonen fighting and sports You know because a lot of the sports show is shown in fighting where instead of fights.
Speaker 1: They have a sport.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say something.
Speaker 1: Not all sports shows though, cuz they're like touch not shown in fighting even though it is a sports show.
Speaker 0: I was gonna make some comment about how the difference is that Sports shows are worse.
Speaker 1: No some of them.
Speaker 0: I have not seen many sports shows.
Speaker 1: I like I really want to watch attack Number one as do I?
Speaker 0: Anyway, I think we're gonna be able to see that though I think the fact that I saw an episode of buzzer beater is what just tainted.
Speaker 1: Buzzer beater is not shown in fighting.
Speaker 0: It's just bad sports anime Also the fact that the only touch I've ever seen is the movie and if you've ever seen the movie You'll know why I said that right?
Speaker 1: Okay, so we don't like shonen fighting shows.
Speaker 1: We think that they're largely inept mindless a waste of time and not good.
Speaker 0: and At the same time there are shows that follow the same format that I. that in my opinion don't suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that is true.
Speaker 0: Like I think I'm gonna initial D. if you discount anything other than the original the first 26 episodes I think the rest of it is utter utter drivel.
Speaker 1: No, you said it is.
Speaker 0: It's awful.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 1: It's terrible.
Speaker 0: You can't make fun of anyone who likes Naruto.
Speaker 1: if you like initial D my past episode 27 I think what the rule is right is it's sort of like with with MMOs you're allowed one.
Speaker 1: It's like you can have everyone, you know If you've never seen a shonen fighting show or read a shonen fighting manga You can do one and then you learn your lesson from that one.
Speaker 1: But that one has a special place in your heart.
Speaker 0: And then yeah, I mean, I'm gonna do it again.
Speaker 1: Let's see thing with MMOs.
Speaker 1: Like I played a mud back in the day I played many muds back in the day, so I don't need to play World of Warcraft now.
Speaker 1: Yep, I've played World of Warcraft now, and it's your first MMO.
Speaker 0: You're excused You know what.
Speaker 0: once you learn your better off World of Warcraft is the best freaking memo ever made.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's still Or up like my.
Speaker 0: I've watched all of Sailor Moon my first magical girl show.
Speaker 0: I've got one.
Speaker 0: I like Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: You can all fuck off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should watch fancy.
Speaker 1: Lala instead fancy.
Speaker 0: Lala didn't exist.
Speaker 1: Oh, that sucks.
Speaker 1: I was in high school.
Speaker 0: I bought fan subs from V kill.
Speaker 1: I really want to know what.
Speaker 1: so if anyone knows is up with the dinosaurs.
Speaker 1: I'm still waiting to find out.
Speaker 0: I Can tell you what happens in the end of Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: it does involve dinosaurs.
Speaker 1: No, it's not as good as fancy Lala.
Speaker 1: So You're allowed one Shonen fighting show and only one.
Speaker 0: But also like Gatekeepers follows a very similar format.
Speaker 0: It's a monster.
Speaker 1: Gatekeepers is different, and it's a monster of the week.
Speaker 1: I think the difference is there's a clear difference between monster of the week.
Speaker 1: Which is something like Voltron or Gatekeepers and such.
Speaker 1: but and then Shonen fighting which is where You know the actual fighting in say a monster of the week is there's the monster you know and then it's mostly Attack.
Speaker 0: we saved the day with the power of friendship, right?
Speaker 1: It's it's sort of an action You know scene.
Speaker 1: it's like it's like a show where they have a big plot and then at the end of the episode There's one action scene where they beat the bad guy.
Speaker 1: That's a monster of the week.
Speaker 0: That big o one was.
Speaker 1: that big o one was totally monster of the week.
Speaker 0: It was just had other stuff going on and then big o two was Ava done properly, but that's beside the point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you look at you know something like Naruto.
Speaker 1: Naruto is not monster of the week.
Speaker 1: Naruto is monster of the decade of the 13 episodes.
Speaker 0: see here.
Speaker 0: Let's just tell this forget everything else and just focus on Naruto.
Speaker 0: because I think the reasons Why I was so excited about Naruto and because remember I liked Naruto.
Speaker 0: I wanted to see it.
Speaker 0: I heard about it.
Speaker 0: There was buzz.
Speaker 0: I saw the first four episodes.
Speaker 1: I heard about this thing called Naruto.
Speaker 1: It was getting pretty popular.
Speaker 1: everyone was talking about it.
Speaker 1: I hadn't seen it.
Speaker 1: I didn't go out of my way to see it, but you know I saw it at anime club.
Speaker 1: I saw four episodes.
Speaker 1: I was intrigued.
Speaker 1: I liked the four episodes, then I went home.
Speaker 1: I downloaded a bunch of fan subs.
Speaker 1: I watched 13 episodes of Naruto, and I read I think two volumes of the manga, and then I was done.
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: what we'll do here is just we'll take the story of our rise and fall of Naruto fandom as an example of why we dislike almost all shounen fighting shows
Speaker 1: and the same thing you know because Anything we say about Naruto pretty much applies to all the other big shounen fighting shows equally because it's the same story with all of Them at least as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: so we'd heard all the buzz For a while before we saw Naruto because you know running the anime club back at RIT.
Speaker 0: We were gonna show it once.
Speaker 1: we got four episodes hanging out with a hundred anime fans every week.
Speaker 0: when Naruto is new and popular kind of hard to avoid Naruto and Everyone was of the opinion that it was the best show ever.
Speaker 0: there were.
Speaker 0: people were talking about Naruto the way they talked about Fullmetal Alchemist after it started coming out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they actually did Naruto come first.
Speaker 1: It was around the same time, but people were there's the same level of.
Speaker 0: it's the best show ever.
Speaker 0: yeah People are just.
Speaker 1: oh they were talking it up.
Speaker 1: They were having conversations about characters.
Speaker 0: There were people at RIT who had made those Naruto headbands for themselves before two episodes had been fan-subbed.
Speaker 1: Yep, yeah, they didn't design those into the show for merchandising.
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 0: So we finally get four episodes And we show it to the club and of course we stick around and watch it.
Speaker 0: cuz that's kind of why I waited so I Could stick around and watch it with a big crowd of people.
Speaker 1: And it was great!
Speaker 0: It was funny.
Speaker 0: ninja school Awesome characters a good plot setup that obviously could come into play in a really interesting dramatic way.
Speaker 0: later Like everything was set up the character designs were great.
Speaker 1: But you know the only thing I could say bad about it after those four episodes was that the plot was a little bit Transparent like yeah, I know what's gonna go down in the long run.
Speaker 1: You know it's like yeah, obviously you know if they would have mixed They could have mixed it up which is the reason to keep watching.
Speaker 1: But that was the only bad thing after four episodes I could say about.
Speaker 1: it is obviously what's gonna go down.
Speaker 0: I don't think they needed to mix it up in the first four episodes.
Speaker 0: No, which is but that was definitely a long-term plot which didn't really matter.
Speaker 0: I don't think no I'm not sure and I really don't care, but yeah, I got it.
Speaker 0: I dug it.
Speaker 0: I thought Naruto was great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was I was laughing.
Speaker 1: I was you know when he turned into like you know.
Speaker 1: What's it called?
Speaker 1: Sexy nojutsu, that's what it's called and of course the guy with the eyepatch best character ever maybe.
Speaker 0: But I think when I got my first inkling that something was wrong Was when before I had seen this scene.
Speaker 0: So there was a big fight going on and someone who had already seen that episode Basically had a conversation with me along the lines of oh man when you see how he
Speaker 1: pulls
Speaker 0: off Like getting past this guy and winning like what he does like you'll see something happen And then they'll go back and reveal how he did it.
Speaker 0: Oh, man This is the best show ever and I was all psyched because I expected some sort of like crazy Choreography or some sort of like amazing spike Spiegel kind of thing or just something awesome and great and Instead it was nothing.
Speaker 0: it was like oh I used the shadow windmill whatever technique which allowed me to Blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah whatever the plot needed blah
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's one thing right like let's say you're watching two people play chess right and you have a commentator explaining Oh look at what he did there.
Speaker 1: Are you watching say a football game and someone says it's a draw play oh my god.
Speaker 0: Or even if you're watching a show that is obviously fake not a real sporting event or a real contest but yet is self-consistent or generally realistic like you're watching a show about a go tournament and Like someone says oh he did the blah move but in the show really did do like it really did it and they show it.
Speaker 0: or there's a Fencing fight and they actually choreographed his fight, and maybe there's commentary or it does something cool But it happens in the context of the show in a realistic self-consistent manner.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm Naruto has the sin that many anime and many other things fall for where instead of actually Showing something cool or coming up with something clever They make up something within like the fake Constraints of whatever's going on and then act as though the thing that they just made up was somehow Amazing.
Speaker 1: yeah, they just it's.
Speaker 1: basically I Watched 13 episodes and at the end of that 13th episode you know they were fighting this guy with a big sword and this person with like some mirrors.
Speaker 1: and it was like all the you know Naruto and his friends versus these two people.
Speaker 1: and That fight ended in like the 13th or 14th episode or whatever.
Speaker 1: and then I realized that fight started in like the 6th or 7th Episode or something like that and I was like wow and all I could remember from all that stretch of episodes Most of the scenes were Naruto's standing there pan across Naruto's face while you hear his inner monologue of.
Speaker 1: should I use this technique?
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe we'll use this technique.
Speaker 1: Oh wonder what their weaknesses?
Speaker 1: dah dah dah dah dah and Then pan across the picture of the bad guy with all the mirrors and the bad guys going.
Speaker 1: haha You cannot get through my mirrors, haha.
Speaker 0: Now consider the difference between these two kinds of writing.
Speaker 0: consider say I don't know.
Speaker 0: CS foresters ratio hornblower books.
Speaker 0: Now there's a scene where the captain is Like something's going on and he has to make a decision.
Speaker 0: Do I run against the Turkish gun batteries and try to escape through the channel or do I?
Speaker 0: Beat back and Lee again.
Speaker 0: So, you know, whatever his options are but the options are realistic either within the context of the fantasy or within the context of the fiction that is based in the real world.
Speaker 0: like the author obviously did a little bit of research and came up with Invitable options and an interesting conflict.
Speaker 0: in a show like Naruto you make up a conflict.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter what the conflict actually is.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much literally do I foo or do I bar?
Speaker 0: because whenever they need a conflict they just make something up like oh, well your blah blah blah technique didn't work because I Have the blah blah blah blah Yeah, and like the actual stuff that's happening doesn't matter because in the end it's entirely made up.
Speaker 1: They can do whatever they want.
Speaker 1: I mean, how many times do you see in these shows?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: You have used every technique, you know, and I'm still not defeated.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: What are you going to do?
Speaker 1: And then it's like I will use the super Superpower and they charge up times a hundred something never done before.
Speaker 1: then they win.
Speaker 1: his power level is over nine thousand.
Speaker 1: nine thousand the only thing You know.
Speaker 1: if the only thing that that is that you're not sure of is who is gonna win.
Speaker 1: everything else between Who is fighting and who is going to win?
Speaker 1: The fight is just meaningless and a waste of time.
Speaker 1: and it's not even like Interesting like how I bebop right.
Speaker 1: watch the first episode of cowboy bebop Even if you've seen it already.
Speaker 1: watch the end.
Speaker 1: There's a fight scene, right?
Speaker 0: It's got a sombrero.
Speaker 0: He kicks the table over that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that one it's a fight scene.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with a fight scene.
Speaker 1: I'm a fan of action.
Speaker 1: Rim is a fan.
Speaker 1: it watch something like Iron Monkey also a real kung fu move.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, Iron Monkey You see many fight scenes.
Speaker 1: many in fact over half the movie is fight scenes.
Speaker 1: Movie is just a vehicle for fight scenes but the fight scenes in and of themselves are a sort of work of art of Choreography or animation and is actually something interesting and stimulating to be seen there.
Speaker 1: It's not just a guy standing there another guy standing there and someone.
Speaker 1: now I mean Street playing.
Speaker 1: Street Fighter is more dynamic than watching Naruto.
Speaker 0: these shows Naruto fighting games though It's almost like I'm not watching a show.
Speaker 0: I'm watching a series of well animated storyboards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like someone is narrating.
Speaker 1: there are not even there.
Speaker 1: It's like these characters are self narrating some really slow boring made-up sporting event with no rules.
Speaker 1: It's completely.
Speaker 0: you know what it reminds me of I don't know maybe underwear perverts.
Speaker 0: I'll punch you you a little guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I have been punched and in the panel it says he is punching.
Speaker 0: No, I did back in the day nowadays a little different But yeah, or even just the idea of how many superhero comics would just whenever they needed a plot device They just made something up that kryptonite.
Speaker 0: It's just like oh, well that didn't work because of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like oh you punched me.
Speaker 1: I am dead uh-huh no I'm not actually dead because I was wearing the double armor.
Speaker 1: uh-huh now.
Speaker 1: I hit you with this weapon.
Speaker 1: Oh, I am trapped ah but I get out with my eye lasers It's just.
Speaker 1: it's basically like they just invent inventories of things And then they sort of use every item from each inventory And then make up new items in the inventories and just pull them out one at a time until they're done Just to drag things out.
Speaker 1: And it's really not Interesting or entertaining once you've seen it before like
Speaker 0: that scene that I talked about where I expected something awesome And then it was just oh I use the blah technique in the shadow of the ninja star or whatever he did I don't even remember now.
Speaker 0: It was just the fact that in a in a well-written show or a good show There would be some amount of foreshadowing or something you there'd be a Possibility drama that you could foresee ours going to happen.
Speaker 0: or at least take a guess.
Speaker 0: and when I saw it And then I found out I'm gonna find out how we did it.
Speaker 0: I thought huh well Maybe he did this or maybe he did this.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to figure out what he did.
Speaker 0: And then I find out that the writer basically said yeah, I don't fucking know what he did either.
Speaker 0: I just made up a word.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: I do use the something technique that I just made up.
Speaker 0: Okay, and then this is what really bothered me.
Speaker 0: Naruto of the show would often I don't know if it does this in later episodes, but I can guess Will not only make up some sort of technique or something, but then they'll go into excruciating and completely unnecessary Detail about exactly how the technique worked and why it worked and how it worked on this guy cuz he was weak against this But it wouldn't worked against this guy because his father was the fifth.
Speaker 1: I Really, just don't care.
Speaker 1: That's it the thing that's really disappointing about these shown in fighting shows.
Speaker 1: I mean it wouldn't be so bad if it was just a bad show right across.
Speaker 0: like you cried It's great at nothing because there I just started dumb kept being dumb.
Speaker 1: there are plenty of shows that are just dumb across the board and we ignore them.
Speaker 1: We don't complain about them so much, but you look at something Naruto or one piece right.
Speaker 1: and what's so upsetting here Is that they had these amazing characters this amazing plot this amazing humor?
Speaker 1: Actually pretty decent production quality mostly cuz it's so popular.
Speaker 0: how up my alley is a show about Smiling pirates seriously good.
Speaker 0: God right.
Speaker 1: I mean red shanks awesome.
Speaker 1: the Kakashi, I think the guy patch guy is awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, it's like bleach.
Speaker 1: even you have these shows.
Speaker 1: They could be the best shows And then they ruin them with all this pointless fighting crap in them.
Speaker 1: if you took the fighting out of Naruto And you said hey any Avius made every fight in Naruto Naruto a Choreographed fight like the first one in cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: We're actually animate people fighting and it's over really quickly.
Speaker 1: It'll be maybe the best show ever.
Speaker 1: It just might or it was funny ninja school just the whole way through 26 episodes of funny ninja school best show ever.
Speaker 1: But maybe it could be and that's why it's so upsetting is that it's actually one of the worst shows there is.
Speaker 1: But and it's stupidly popular.
Speaker 1: But it's 99% crap just pointless crap.
Speaker 1: Dragon Ball is the same way.
Speaker 1: at least the original Dragon Ball had more humor than DB.
Speaker 0: original Dragon Ball is actually pretty funny, and I've always looked at Dragon Ball Z as a kind of Self-reflective parody of those kinds of shows.
Speaker 1: that's what it is.
Speaker 1: But that's not the way most people view it and it's sort of set up You know with its ludicrous popularity.
Speaker 1: if you don't understand the level of popularity of Dragon Ball Look at Japanese weekly Shonen jump sales figures, and then look what happens to those sales figures when Dragon Ball ended.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I think that the fact that people took deep Dragon Ball Z more seriously than I think it was intended.
Speaker 1: But then again that is what sort of spawned that the current wave of.
Speaker 1: you know Shonen jump fight.
Speaker 0: That seems to be a common trend.
Speaker 0: I mean we talked about this I think last week or the week before where a lot of anime fans Especially when they're young they see shows that are intended to be humorous and for whatever reason just don't pick up on that like project Aiko.
Speaker 0: project Aiko is probably the biggest example because almost everyone I talked to when they were a kid Saw project Aiko and took it at face value, and they're like man.
Speaker 0: Why does she have superpowers?
Speaker 0: That's so cool.
Speaker 0: Oh, she saved the day.
Speaker 0: and now I look at it is like oh It's a joke Get it.
Speaker 0: I mean I was so into the drama of the.
Speaker 0: you know the movie battle gray battle blue and all that.
Speaker 0: I thought it was and then I saw it again, and it was just wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when I ever tell you when I first saw tank police I took it as seriously as someone that you're supposed to take something like Galaxy Express.
Speaker 1: and now well I still take Galaxy Express seriously.
Speaker 1: I don't take tank police nearly half as seriously as I used to.
Speaker 0: that is not to say that I do not enjoy Tank police or project About half serious and project Aiko is about 5% serious.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: Don't read the tank police manga because the seriousness drops away.
Speaker 1: I'm getting it eventually.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the point is is that Naruto and all these other shonen fighting shows you really don't like them.
Speaker 1: really think there's a waste of time.
Speaker 1: But anyone is excused from watching or reading one of this.
Speaker 0: well You know people are allowed to like whatever they want.
Speaker 1: they are allowed to like whatever they want, but if they want my respect No, you see they would need to enjoy one or fewer of these things.
Speaker 0: I just I. I think the real issue is much simpler.
Speaker 0: I don't like Naruto.
Speaker 0: I think it's a bad show.
Speaker 1: I think Naruto is bad.
Speaker 0: the worst is when people on pieces bad people try to argue with me on that point because remember I Didn't say you shouldn't watch it.
Speaker 0: I said I think it's a bad show and people will argue no It's not it's a great show you.
Speaker 0: and then there's always that pause And I always look hopeful and then they always say you just have to get past the filler episodes.
Speaker 1: That is the worst argument.
Speaker 0: You can make just if you're gonna make.
Speaker 1: You know what my argument to that is.
Speaker 1: okay, okay?
Speaker 1: All right, so it's a good show.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: I got it much simpler.
Speaker 0: We'll skip all that.
Speaker 0: I'll give you a dollar, but you have to get through me punching the crap out of you for five minutes first.
Speaker 1: That sounds like a loss.
Speaker 1: You know cuz I would pay a dollar to keep you from punching me for five minutes, huh?
Speaker 0: So I mean I think the line for me in terms of because people always argue But yeah shows can have bad parts gotta wait till they get good.
Speaker 0: I think gassaraki was the line that was the slowest show I actually finished.
Speaker 1: yeah, you look at this though right.
Speaker 1: someone says oh the show's really great If you just wait through the bad part.
Speaker 1: well cowboy bebop doesn't have a bad part.
Speaker 1: try gun doesn't have a bad part.
Speaker 1: So maybe the show that is part bad and part good is better than the show.
Speaker 1: That's all bad.
Speaker 1: I will give you that.
Speaker 1: But the show that is part bad and part good is not as good as the show that is all good.
Speaker 1: now There are plenty of shows that are all good, and I don't have time to watch all of them.
Speaker 1: So I'm not gonna have any time to watch.
Speaker 1: your half bad have good show.
Speaker 1: your half bad Have good.
Speaker 1: show is might as it to me is as good as the all bad show.
Speaker 1: breathe breathe fuck it Fuck it.
Speaker 0: It's all fuck the fuck up.
Speaker 1: It's all fuck the fuck up.
Speaker 1: But I'm economies off fuck fuck.
Speaker 0: I'll say this bodega bodega baby Moses, okay, let's not get on those tangents.
Speaker 0: I'll say when they're actually Woman tangents something I got nothing Naruto sucks.
Speaker 0: You know now I actually forgot what I was gonna say.
Speaker 0: I had something needed.
Speaker 0: oh all right all right.
Speaker 0: the next time you ever try to convince and me or Yourself that a show that has a bad like a long bad part is worth watching to get to the good part Just go watch.
Speaker 0: I don't know 12 kingdoms or Kazu.
Speaker 0: no yo Jimbo cuz I guarantee you haven't seen those shows hardly anyone especially Kazu.
Speaker 0: no yo Jimbo That show is awesome.
Speaker 1: Have you watched it?
Speaker 1: more than a few episodes that we've seen?
Speaker 0: I saw the first six episodes And they were all awesome.
Speaker 0: I also saw the first except even if the show gets crappy after that.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: if a show starts good and turns crappy I get to watch the good part And then I stop watching and I don't lose anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: It's actually not bad.
Speaker 1: It's like Naruto.
Speaker 1: Just watch four episodes.
Speaker 1: You'll get all this goodness, and you won't lose anything.
Speaker 1: It's actually.
Speaker 1: then it's an amazing show.
Speaker 0: if a show feels like I have to fight my it's kind of like Pokemon And why I gave up on it and stop playing it The moment anything that's supposed to be entertaining feels like work or like I just got to get through this part people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people say oh World of Warcraft is a good game once you get the level 70.
Speaker 1: What I need to?
Speaker 1: why would I work to get the fun part when I can just buy the fun part?
Speaker 0: there was a tiny.
Speaker 0: There was a time I would back in the day.
Speaker 0: what I would play through like Final Fantasy 4j I think that is.
Speaker 1: that's a topic for a separate show is the ongoing problem of the fact that when we were in college And I think most people who are in college or high school and younger than that have the same issue Is that they have plenty of free time and not a lot of money?
Speaker 1: So they've got all this time to enjoy works of entertainment, but not enough works of entertainment to enjoy whereas us We don't have a lot of free time.
Speaker 1: We need to go to work all day and commute and do all this other geek night stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah We have plenty of money.
Speaker 1: so we have all these Entertainment things to enjoy but not enough time to enjoy them all and it when you have you know when you're you're when you're the sort of a high school kid.
Speaker 1: I can very easily excuse something like Naruto because it fills up a Lot of time need the pleasure of Scott to be just excused from watching they do because it fills up.
Speaker 1: They have a lot of time on their hands and not a lot to be entertained by and whereas us We don't have time for Naruto.
Speaker 1: Seriously, it's what I get to spend.
Speaker 1: if I spend the time watching Naruto I'm not gonna be able to do anything else at all.
Speaker 0: period.
Speaker 0: I have not beaten Twilight Princess.
Speaker 0: I got maybe three hours into it.
Speaker 0: That's I just haven't had time, right?
Speaker 1: So I think that's what we got to say and I hope we pissed people off by telling you that all these shows that you like suck.
Speaker 0: I don't think many of the people who listen to geek nights are particularly fans of Naruto.
Speaker 1: No But that's fine because even if they aren't I'm hoping that fans of Naruto will pay attention to the show and link to it And be all like these guys are.
Speaker 1: do some art.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean like what he made fun anime pulse.
Speaker 0: and then we got like what actually we got at least six people who came Over and said man now I listen to you guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Naruto fans You know people post links to this show on all sorts of Naruto sites and other.
Speaker 0: you got nothing.
Speaker 0: others You got nothing.
Speaker 0: you are nothing.
Speaker 0: I think you are nothing to me.
Speaker 1: other shonen fighting shows also.
Speaker 1: the same thing applies.
Speaker 1: I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: Everything you've said about Naruto is true about one piece is true about dragon ball except initial D because that's awesome Until episode 27 and then it sucks and Scott is wrong.
Speaker 1: I'm allowed one.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.