Speaker 0: It's Wednesday August 8th.
Speaker 1: I'm Ren.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek night.
Speaker 0: Tonight we preview a brand new anime bakano.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So it uh rained overnight.
Speaker 1: It didn't even rain that much.
Speaker 1: I mean it just rained well up here.
Speaker 0: didn't rain that much?
Speaker 0: down further south of us it rained quite a bit Yeah But it wasn't like.
Speaker 1: you know OMG this water All the cars are like swimming around and you know you're up to your neck in water And this is the sewage is coming up out of the sewer or anything like that.
Speaker 0: so apparently according to you There's no sliding scale of it rained a lot.
Speaker 0: It's either torrential floods or nothing pretty much as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 1: Okay, well I can walk around and with my umbrella and be like doo doo doo doo That's rain, and then if I can walk around without an umbrella Then it.
Speaker 0: well I find out rain.
Speaker 0: when it rained you weren't up And you didn't have an umbrella But it must have rained pretty hard because uh all the subways in New York City got completely fucked.
Speaker 1: That's not because it rained too much That's because the subways really suck at handling rain.
Speaker 0: the thing is while the subways generally do suck at handling rain usually no matter How bad it rains.
Speaker 0: only the Lexington Avenue line goes out and everything else is usually okay?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean I got to the city today and I go down into the subway not knowing and there were portents of doom well before.
Speaker 0: Because I remember I get to the train station.
Speaker 0: I left early because it was wet outside from the rain and because my bike is broken.
Speaker 0: and by broken I just mean I have a hole in a tube and my patch kit is so old that the adhesive doesn't work anymore and No store anywhere near our house sells bicycle tubes.
Speaker 0: So I was gonna order it on Amazon.
Speaker 0: But for all that I'll just wait for the weekend and drive to the other bike shop.
Speaker 0: because last weekend We tried to go to the bike shop to learn that in the time between the last time I had gone and Going this time it had gone out of business and emptied.
Speaker 1: It's what happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess that is what happens businesses.
Speaker 0: Just suddenly go out of business and disappear without warning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what they do.
Speaker 1: I mean you don't go out of business with warning.
Speaker 0: You know yeah, you do a lot of places.
Speaker 0: when they go out of business They're like all right.
Speaker 0: We're going out of business time for that.
Speaker 1: Go out of business on purpose and not out of business because you sucked I don't know.
Speaker 0: maybe someone at leprosy or something and
Speaker 1: I don't know
Speaker 0: yeah But suffice to say I had to rollerblade to work which usually is kind of awesome because I really like rollerblading despite the fact that Unlike the Midwest where I grew up there as far as I'm concerned there are no sidewalks.
Speaker 0: in most of New York There are things that look like sidewalks.
Speaker 0: you can walk on them pretty well But they're not really sidewalks.
Speaker 0: if you try to rollerblade on them you just fall on your face.
Speaker 1: Well, that's cuz.
Speaker 1: they're digga digga digga digga digga.
Speaker 1: They're not like these big wide smooth concrete things.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: They're concrete.
Speaker 0: They're just narrow cracked and dirty.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're meant for walking.
Speaker 1: They're not meant for anything else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the other problem is that I don't know what the laws are here.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if rollerbladers are pedestrians or vehicles.
Speaker 1: Why don't you look it up on the Internet?
Speaker 0: I didn't get a chance to.
Speaker 0: I thought about it while I was rollerblading home And then we came home to find that the website was down.
Speaker 0: and now here We are.
Speaker 1: yeah apparently someone DDoS not our website But the machine that our website is on.
Speaker 0: my guess is that someone else on sharing our machine?
Speaker 0: Did something.
Speaker 1: it might not even been our machine.
Speaker 1: It could have been anyone.
Speaker 0: in the whole data center there I get the impression that someone did something untoward to draw the ire of someone else and that person was summarily removed from Linode.
Speaker 1: yeah pretty much Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I left really early because I had to rollerblade and if anyone of you out there is never Rollerbladed rollerblading on wet terrain is pretty much a death sentence.
Speaker 0: unless you have special wheels You're just gonna die especially if there's hills or grit or anything.
Speaker 1: really I wouldn't think that it would be so bad You lose.
Speaker 0: travel thing is the more traction you get with rollerblade wheels the more they wear out.
Speaker 0: And I have long run wheels that are really really hard, and they're great for speed skating, but When it's wet they just kind of slide left and right and if you're going too fast You'll just kind of fall over suddenly And you can't prevent it.
Speaker 0: because when you try to stick a foot out to kind of catch yourself and go in a different direction It just doesn't catch and you just slide.
Speaker 0: It's kind of awesome alright.
Speaker 1: Can you grab onto a tree or anything.
Speaker 0: not really you're going too fast.
Speaker 0: It's more a matter of you can't regain control because you can't grip the ground with your wheels in order to turn Because you have to turn to change your momentum.
Speaker 0: You're just gonna fall over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's complicated.
Speaker 0: rollerblading is not as easy as a lot of people make it out to be But it's not as difficult as people anyway.
Speaker 0: the point is I ended up at the train station earlier than I expected and There was all these warnings like warning trains will not be delayed here But may run into substantial delays in the Bronx due to flood conditions.
Speaker 1: I didn't hear any such message when I got to the train station Which was not much later after you, but later they announced it three times pretty spaced apart.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got there later than you, but not much later, and then they announced it on the train that I wrote.
Speaker 0: I don't know were you on the same train as me.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I was on.
Speaker 1: I said I was on a later train, but not much later train.
Speaker 1: I was on that like thinking in bag for eight.
Speaker 0: I was on the tree out like the Krazy Express that leaves before us.
Speaker 0: like before the train we usually take Was actually there until almost right before the other train left because there were delays further down the road Uh-huh, but luckily they must have fixed all that stuff well before Scott got into the city and Emily got into the city.
Speaker 1: like Maybe a half hour later.
Speaker 0: I think all the ass early trains that the Krazy Commuters take got held up who knows.
Speaker 0: But luckily my train gets off well before there's any chance of flooding so I never really have a problem.
Speaker 0: But yeah the subways were totally fucked and the buses were then fucked as everyone tried to take them and a bunch of streets in Midtown were closed.
Speaker 0: and Randomly unrelated to all that one subway station was closed due to a police investigation.
Speaker 1: And yeah, I mean I got to the city on the train which is perfectly normal.
Speaker 1: I didn't hear any about any trouble.
Speaker 1: It wasn't you know out.
Speaker 1: I'd been outside.
Speaker 1: It wasn't really that wet.
Speaker 1: it looked like it rained last night, and the Sun was out, and it was hot.
Speaker 1: But it didn't look like there was a flood or anything.
Speaker 1: there was some puddles And that's about it.
Speaker 1: and then down in the subway They're like there are no trains going in either direction.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: I saw on notices They were like the Lexington Avenue for line is not running between like Brooklyn Bridge and 86th Street Which is pretty much the entirety of its useful length for us.
Speaker 1: no the message I heard was like between the in the Bronx and in Brooklyn And I was like okay, there are no stops anywhere because the train goes from the Bronx.
Speaker 1: So and you know so it's not stopping.
Speaker 1: It's not even in Manhattan, so I Basically, I'm like okay I will take the s to Times Square, and then I will take the NQ RW to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because the four five six they like.
Speaker 0: you know the the green train as a lot of people who aren't from New York College It tends to flood in a few places pretty often when it rains.
Speaker 0: so if it's down people just kind of alright Whatever and take another subway.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I was gonna take the NQ RW, so I went over there, and I took the s Was not running.
Speaker 1: there was the three s trains were just sitting there.
Speaker 1: now the s train is a train that goes Maybe a couple miles.
Speaker 1: It's like the.
Speaker 0: not even it goes a distance that I routinely walk because it's not worth the hassle.
Speaker 1: It's like the shortest train ride ever.
Speaker 1: it goes from Grand Central to Times Square.
Speaker 1: It's like a five block train.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of them.
Speaker 0: They just go back and forth 24/7 just back and forth.
Speaker 1: not even it's like it's like a two or three Avenue block train.
Speaker 1: it's really short.
Speaker 1: But if you want to go from Times Central Times Square to Grand Central Yes, if you want to go to either of those two places from the other place in a hurry There's the s train and it's actually kind of crowded.
Speaker 1: They have three of them that just go back and forth all the time and they were just sitting there not moving And I was like whoa.
Speaker 1: that's amazing.
Speaker 1: They can't even like suck up the water or drain the water out of this little tiny train track.
Speaker 1: That's very short.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 1: So I took the seven train which makes the same trip and that wasn't too bad.
Speaker 1: taking the seven train I get the Times Square, so I'm looking for the NQ RW.
Speaker 1: I get over there.
Speaker 1: It's pretty crowded this NQ RW and an N train comes and people are like squeezing into the N train and I'm like I will wait for the next train
Speaker 0: and I wait
Speaker 1: and I wait and I wait anyway anyway and an N train comes And I try to get into it, but that's not happening.
Speaker 0: See, it's one thing when you see a train in this crowded and you think you know what?
Speaker 0: I'll wait for the next one or I'll wait and take the local or something.
Speaker 0: But every now and then you run into a situation where there's a train That even if you wanted to get onto it you could not physically push your way past the door.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I'm like, okay I know what I'll do.
Speaker 1: I'll be all clever.
Speaker 1: I'll take the queue because they're all these people trying to get NRWs.
Speaker 1: I was gonna get the queue right so I'm waiting over by the queue and it's it's nice You know on the other side of the platform, it's pretty quiet.
Speaker 1: Everyone's wants the NRWs and I wait and I wait anyway.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway a long time.
Speaker 1: I wait so long That there's people lining up the stairs like the platform is full and people are lined up up above the platform elsewhere.
Speaker 0: No, one of those people thinking obviously there's a problem.
Speaker 0: They might as well go take a cab.
Speaker 1: So No, Q comes no R's come no W's come.
Speaker 0: eventually another N comes, you know in a situation like that You kind of wait.
Speaker 0: you figure like maybe this is the apocalypse in the end.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, cuz you're sitting there and eventually a train just gonna go by full of skeletons or something But no kind of like those creepy-ass garbage trains that go by every now and then at night.
Speaker 1: Yes, anyway one of those no.
Speaker 1: So what happens is this end comes and of course people get off the end.
Speaker 1: so I go aha.
Speaker 1: Here's my chance.
Speaker 1: I got with the people who were getting off the end and use their momentum to get the hell out of there and I went up and I got a cab and I went to work for $15.
Speaker 1: Wow, yeah, cuz I wasn't gonna walk all that way in that deathly heat.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile because I was in I had my own adventure because I avoided all transit problems.
Speaker 0: now had I driven to work I would have been fucked because New York City regardless of the subway problems There are you know highways and freeways and then there are these things called parkways.
Speaker 0: Now in New York a parkway means that you can't have any commercial traffic on it So it means pretty much in all the Northeast.
Speaker 0: it was probably made a hundred fucking years ago.
Speaker 0: It's probably windy with dangerous old rusty guardrails.
Speaker 0: It's probably nothing like a real freeway and almost all of them followed a river of some kind.
Speaker 1: Yeah, parkways are generally like these highways that are just for cars and they're used a lot for Commuting and such even though they shouldn't be like the taconic.
Speaker 0: one of the biggest commuter roads around here was made back in the day So that people who have owned cars who happen to own a car in New York City Could have a nice place to drive like a fun windy Mountain road to drive on to go up and picnic in the upstate parts.
Speaker 0: and now it's a commuter road.
Speaker 0: So it's still windy and now it.
Speaker 0: that just makes it deadly.
Speaker 0: Yep, but they all follow these rivers that theoretically are supposed to take the water away.
Speaker 0: But those rivers over the years have clogged up to the point that they're basically just trickles.
Speaker 0: I mean I can spit more than these things have water in them and when it rains the parkways just turn into the rivers.
Speaker 0: And every time it rains at all my commute turns into like this four-hour nightmare.
Speaker 0: So now that I take the train, I just got to work.
Speaker 0: No problem.
Speaker 0: I get off the train.
Speaker 0: weather's fine.
Speaker 0: I start walking up the mile to the to run my work up this mountain and Suddenly starts pouring rain and I realized that I don't have an umbrella pun.
Speaker 0: So I hid in the woods for 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: the rain stopped and then I continued on my quest.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I got to work and no one was fucking there because they were all stuck in traffic.
Speaker 1: Apparently if I would have gotten to work on time Someone said that there was basically no one there and it was a ghost town.
Speaker 1: So I guess it's kind of okay that I got to work late and then I was gonna go home from work And I was.
Speaker 1: you know I went to the website and they said the subway still isn't working and I'm like, what the fuck.
Speaker 1: so I go and I'm like Okay, let's see what the bus is like and I could take this bus.
Speaker 0: Did you take the bus?
Speaker 0: No, I've never taken a bus in the city.
Speaker 1: subway started working again, and there was no one down there And I just took the subway back to the train station.
Speaker 1: it went home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the subway just suddenly started working and I got on it before it became stupidly crowded full of people who realized it was working Again, right?
Speaker 0: So technically that wasn't a tangent because it's Dave and Joe like to make fun of.
Speaker 0: I guess That was the opening kind of free flows.
Speaker 0: Talk about our day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is As bad as it is in New York City when shit goes wrong when everything works It's not so bad, which is honestly 99% of the time Yeah, but it's like the system just can't handle anything going wrong at all.
Speaker 0: Well, I think part of the problem Lee at capacity is just the fact that you know New York City is a big place.
Speaker 0: A lot of people live there and People keep moving there, but most of the subways were made, you know, 50 60 years ago.
Speaker 0: Well more than that Mm-hmm, and a lot of them haven't changed very much over the years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like there's there's this running gag in the city of the Second Avenue subway that is never gonna get built But they're actually working on building it now and it'll be done and I think 2013.
Speaker 1: the thing that.
Speaker 0: so if Quetzalcoatl doesn't come We'll get a new subway.
Speaker 1: The thing that just bothers me is it seems like there are some extreme measures that could be taken to fix a situation like this and then no one bothers to take them or that they're.
Speaker 1: you know, It's logistically impossible.
Speaker 0: There was a vote that we actually voted on in this area a while ago Whether or not to spend a whole bunch of money to make transit like a million times better and fix all the current problems.
Speaker 0: I voted yes, and most New Yorkers voted no because they're dumbasses.
Speaker 0: Good job thing is though that we can't complain because honestly New York City has some of the best public transit in the world like hands-down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty sad.
Speaker 1: Actually, I would if public transit was awesome.
Speaker 1: They'd be like whoosh whoosh whoosh and you'd have to be riding these nice comfortable.
Speaker 0: Hey for me public transit's awesome because I get to ride the nice new fancy mature North trains.
Speaker 0: I take the local.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's still you know, it's this nice air-conditioned car, it's all clean.
Speaker 0: the seats are big They got nice dividers by the heads.
Speaker 0: They don't have to smell or see the person next to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's you know, it's not every.
Speaker 0: I also learned recently It is against the rules of New York City to occupy more than one seat on a subway no matter the circumstances Uh-huh, and I've seen some people who merely by their girth took up two or three seats.
Speaker 0: So technically those people can be kicked off the subway.
Speaker 0: I find that hilarious.
Speaker 1: that isn't enforced.
Speaker 1: like you're not allowed to walk between the subway cars people do it.
Speaker 0: Thing is I've never seen someone who wasn't a shady person do that.
Speaker 1: I seen punk kids do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's always punk kids doing something shady or causing trouble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or it's those DVD sellers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know those those bootleg sellers that wander around the subway trying like DVD DVD.
Speaker 0: you want DVD?
Speaker 1: Yep, those guys those guys are all right, though.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, so if you couldn't tell we're stalling for time because there's just no goddamn anime news worth talking about Anime manga or comic news at all kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: Well, nothing we care about at all and nothing any of you would care about.
Speaker 0: I mean Otakon officially released their numbers But a lot of people went to Otakon.
Speaker 0: Otakon counts differently from other cons.
Speaker 0: We talked about this last year and the year before.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So here's my crap-ass news.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: So, okay My news isn't the news itself because the news itself is not what I care about.
Speaker 1: Right, and in fact the news is that I don't care about the news.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that's news because that's there would be old news, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's not news.
Speaker 0: It's geek nights.
Speaker 1: So apparently All over all the nerds are getting excited because someone named Gugino Gugino is gonna be in the Watchmen movie is some character and I just I want to say that you know, I don't know who this person is or whatever.
Speaker 1: But I keep seeing lately a lot of these film news's and it seems like anytime There's even the slightest thing to say about a movie especially a movie that has anything to do with nerdiness, right?
Speaker 1: Everyone's just like OMG.
Speaker 1: Here's a possible cast.
Speaker 1: OMG Someone so is directing.
Speaker 0: such as you know that is a common pastime among nerds and geeks.
Speaker 0: whenever you think about what if they made a movie about I don't know Forgotten realms.
Speaker 0: the first thing people think is well who would play Elminster?
Speaker 0: And then they talk about it and the answer is obviously Ian McClellan.
Speaker 1: But yeah, but I mean this this explosive news about even the tiniest changes to movies especially when 90% of these things are it verified or or Confirmed or in a press release or and oh
Speaker 0: I can
Speaker 1: add something some nerd either came up with or dug up or some Tabloid person.
Speaker 0: I can answer why this happens pretty easily.
Speaker 0: one.
Speaker 0: The blogosphere is more reactionary than the Royalist during the French Revolution.
Speaker 1: It's not the blogosphere at all.
Speaker 1: It's like these non blog sort of movie website.
Speaker 0: well, no, that was just the first point.
Speaker 0: just in general why things like this happen - is the fact that because Generally muggles are not on the internet in force.
Speaker 0: I mean normal people non geeks not nerds people who aren't terribly motivated about the things that all of us care about.
Speaker 0: They use Google and Yahoo and whatever to find the website about Britney Spears and look at it and check their email and then Check the news in the weather and they don't really care about anything else on the internet.
Speaker 0: So the primary force of voice on the internet is People like us who care about these things a lot, but I know that's the thing.
Speaker 1: I who the fuck cares about this?
Speaker 1: I mean, oh, this is God who cares about your stupid video game news, but I'm saying like, okay Maybe I don't even know.
Speaker 1: is there gonna be a watch from the movie.
Speaker 1: There's no guarantee.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be a watch probably Probably right there.
Speaker 1: They're deciding a cast.
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 1: this is gonna be the final cast.
Speaker 1: this could change at any moment.
Speaker 1: We made the movie.
Speaker 1: is it on the screen?
Speaker 1: if not everything is just bullshit.
Speaker 1: It's bullshit until there's a movie in the movie theater.
Speaker 1: Wow posters on the walls.
Speaker 1: It's just bullshit crap to sort of.
Speaker 1: I don't know it.
Speaker 1: God what the fuck do you care?
Speaker 1: And why are you wasting your time paying attention to it?
Speaker 0: I pretty much disagree with you.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's a problem at all.
Speaker 0: I don't doesn't bother me people.
Speaker 1: It's a bullshit waste of time to pay attention to all these.
Speaker 1: you don't have to pay Rumors and crap, you don't have to pay attention to a fan.
Speaker 1: attention to it.
Speaker 1: The problem is I keep seeing it filling up my RSS another crap and I'm like get this shit out of here.
Speaker 1: I don't want to see stuff if it's not true a hundred percent final thing and it's not something important that matters Get it the fuck out here.
Speaker 1: I got care Scott.
Speaker 1: I shouldn't care either.
Speaker 0: I Think you're full of shit.
Speaker 1: You're full of shit cuz Michael is shit.
Speaker 0: Well, frankly one if you don't like what's in an RSS feed don't subscribe to it.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I got some filters going on.
Speaker 0: Okay, and - I mean it's no different than what happens when a video game comes out, you know people bullshit - okay So what you're basically saying is people should never speculate on anything ever.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying is that you shouldn't be.
Speaker 1: you know, there's nothing wrong with speculating.
Speaker 1: All right, you can sit around in your forum and say ooh, wouldn't this be cool.
Speaker 1: or ooh, wouldn't that this be cool?
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: You can I am with your friends You can sit down and have a discussion and you know, imagine things and have fun, but don't go posting news articles like People can post whatever they want freedom of speech.
Speaker 1: You can't don't be passing it off as news.
Speaker 0: How are they passing it off as news?
Speaker 0: I mean is what was the news Scott?
Speaker 0: What article is it that's bothering you?
Speaker 1: this particular seems like it is actually news.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, oh But a lot of them aren't like what cuz.
Speaker 0: apparently this is news.
Speaker 0: They are in fact working on selecting a cast and if people are excited about that because they're interested in movies There's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: I mean think about all the speculation that went on about what characters they're gonna be in Smash Brothers brawl and that filled up millions of RSS feeds and websites and people arguing about and I was tired of that shit.
Speaker 1: The only ones I care about are the ones that say, you know, I don't.
Speaker 1: actually I don't even care at all.
Speaker 0: I don't want to know who the characters are.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter to me.
Speaker 1: I know the characters are gonna be good.
Speaker 1: What does it matter?
Speaker 0: which ones they are, you know what Scott?
Speaker 0: then those websites just aren't for you.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying And I don't understand the people that the websites are for.
Speaker 1: why are you so interested in scrounging up all these useless tidbits?
Speaker 1: Information about something that doesn't exist yet and you have no control over that information.
Speaker 1: It's like what do you?
Speaker 1: I don't understand the point of it because it's interesting.
Speaker 0: people like to find out about things.
Speaker 0: if I'm looking forward to a movie or video game or something and there's news about that video game like some details about when it's gonna come out or
Speaker 1: When it's gonna come out as important or
Speaker 0: who's working on it What art they might have or maybe oh it's gonna be a rehash of this or there's gonna be extra levels or it's gonna have Online player all those rumors and stuff.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: I find it interesting and I write it upside.
Speaker 1: Well, what's the point in knowing that?
Speaker 1: I mean you're not gonna be able to change it.
Speaker 1: You're gonna find out when it comes out.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's you're not gonna be able to make a decision about it until it actually comes out.
Speaker 1: So if I what's the point in knowing that information?
Speaker 1: So far in advance and collecting it bit by bit and I don't understand.
Speaker 0: What if you just got what if you just find it?
Speaker 0: Interesting.
Speaker 1: Why is it interesting?
Speaker 0: Why is anything interesting?
Speaker 0: if someone likes something and they want to seek out information about it Then that's their prerogative and I've had nothing wrong with that at all.
Speaker 1: I think it's guy.
Speaker 1: I just don't like all this stuff of like, you know.
Speaker 1: Hyping stuff up with these tidbits of information crap Rick in The only reason I would want to know about something like a video game or a movie is to make a decision as to whether To buy it or see it.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm sorry that the rest of the world is not as simple as you.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: rest of the world is frickin stupid following this shit?
Speaker 1: Like it's so important wasting their goddamn time Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm just absolutely surprised at these sheer amount of venom use that was.
Speaker 0: that was kind of a crazy rant You went on just now.
Speaker 1: is it really bothers me these people who?
Speaker 0: why would it bother you what other people like?
Speaker 1: It's not that it's what other people like.
Speaker 1: is that these people are like so crazed?
Speaker 1: How about things that aren't like substantial or real about this?
Speaker 1: It's like completely superficial useless pieces of information and they're like hanging on to it Like it's you know, actually like this humongous amazing news of some sort.
Speaker 0: How are they crazed?
Speaker 0: and is there any example of that?
Speaker 0: because you're just kind of saying stuff.
Speaker 1: right now I see these people.
Speaker 1: what people where nerds on forums and places.
Speaker 0: So it's no different than when we get excited about something.
Speaker 1: What do I get excited about?
Speaker 1: Well, maybe you just don't get excited about anything, but normal people I don't get excited about things until they're real until they exist until their final until it's something that actually matters Scott till it's.
Speaker 0: I'll say that I got excited about the Firefly movie when it was not even a rumor.
Speaker 0: It was just a. they should make a Firefly movie and no one had said anything yet.
Speaker 0: and I was already excited Yeah, and I thought what our politics?
Speaker 0: the Democratic and the Republican primaries.
Speaker 0: I can't make any decisions yet.
Speaker 0: The primaries are a long long way off and nothing I do right now matters, but I'm still paying attention to the field.
Speaker 0: I'm still interested in what's going on.
Speaker 1: Notice how I don't pay attention to that at all until it matters.
Speaker 0: Yeah and what I'm saying is People can be interested in different things and people have different tastes and things and I think it's a waste of time to pay attention To shit.
Speaker 1: that don't matter.
Speaker 0: You mean shit.
Speaker 0: that doesn't matter, right?
Speaker 0: Unless you were using the word shit without an S on the end.
Speaker 0: somehow in the plural also that see.
Speaker 0: Uh, the only thing that bothers me is bad grammar.
Speaker 0: Yeah Either way, I don't know why this bothers you so much and that was kind of a crazy rant.
Speaker 1: It's bothering me.
Speaker 0: Okay I pretty much disagree with me.
Speaker 1: what movie?
Speaker 1: tell me only if something is real and when it's coming out and how much it'll cost And what it's got.
Speaker 0: I'll even say that I'm excited about the fact that I learned a while ago that That series of novels the Temeraire books about the Napoleonic Wars with dragons that I found so wonderful and delicious and great Peter Jackson likes him and he's option the rights to make the movies and I'm already excited about that.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of following it to see what he's gonna actually make.
Speaker 1: the movie doesn't mean shit?
Speaker 0: No, I don't.
Speaker 0: but I know that he says that if things go the way he'd like him to he'd like to.
Speaker 1: so Why do you?
Speaker 1: even so you're getting excited.
Speaker 1: you could be getting your hopes up for nothing.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Nothing is certain in this world.
Speaker 0: So just about anything I could get my hopes up for there's a chance It might not come through but you know what I get excited.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this whole idea of keep expectations low and never hope or never dream for anything is really just kind of Banal and silly.
Speaker 1: Well, you know while I don't actually Like consciously say you shouldn't have hopes or expectations for anything Well, that's pretty much what you explicitly are saying.
Speaker 0: But I think what it is is that from being on the internet so much and from oh So you're the lord of the internet you get to say what goes on the internet?
Speaker 1: No From Swimming in this information for so long.
Speaker 1: I just don't.
Speaker 1: I don't expect anything.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: I don't hope for anything.
Speaker 1: I only care about what is now and all these, you know There's just so much rumors and bullshit on the net that anything that isn't Substantiated right now fact.
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit like these Apple people.
Speaker 1: They're like an iPhones coming until they until the iPhone was in the store.
Speaker 1: I just completely ignored every iPhone story.
Speaker 1: I didn't give a shit until you know, they were like who knew IMAX and new IMAX are coming.
Speaker 1: They're coming.
Speaker 1: They're coming until they said here's the picture of it.
Speaker 1: I didn't click on a single goddamn link, you know, and it's just I guess from experience.
Speaker 1: I sort of been trained to be that way and The stuff that goes against my training I filter it out.
Speaker 1: and because I filter it out it sort of has, you know It's like associated negatively in my mind as negative.
Speaker 1: get that out of here.
Speaker 0: Okay, all I really have to say and this is definitely a somewhat inside joke, but like I reviewed on our last geek bite I really like these prints of nothing books and a few people compared me to Kellis.
Speaker 0: in the books a character and Scott is reminding me more and more of K Nair or however you pronounce that guy's name And I think this argument just kind of illustrated that in a funny way to me But that's not gonna mean anything to the rest of you.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I think our friend Alex is probably laughing right now, but that's about it.
Speaker 1: Yes Anyway, are you guys?
Speaker 1: Don't give a shit if someone has been cast in a movie.
Speaker 1: That's not important Especially if you don't a hundred percent sure they've been cast in the movie or if you're not even a hundred percent sure the movie Is gonna even be in the theater.
Speaker 0: Okay, Scott.
Speaker 1: Tell me when there's a camera rolling.
Speaker 0: Well, if you're swimming in the pool then the pool of the Internet and what you perceive as the turd floats by just get out Of the pool.
Speaker 0: don't complain about the pool.
Speaker 0: You're like the people who get on dig.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's cuz I'm swimming in the pool and I'm having a good time And I got all these people shitting in the pool and I got to kick their asses out.
Speaker 0: But you don't own dig and the masses own dig and whatever they want goes up.
Speaker 0: So if you don't like what's on dig don't go there and I just filter it out.
Speaker 1: I'm alright, but the point Oh you filter it out.
Speaker 0: You're right.
Speaker 0: Then.
Speaker 0: Why does it bother you?
Speaker 1: Still it gets, you know, not all the turds can you know, you got a no So you're not filtering it fully you don't have.
Speaker 1: you can't filter proper can't make a perfect filter.
Speaker 0: Just doesn't happen Alright, well Scott's crazy ranting aside.
Speaker 0: I couldn't find any anime news.
Speaker 0: I cared about it all and I'm just gonna talk about this briefly, but there's a story here.
Speaker 0: It looks like it happened in New Zealand.
Speaker 0: There was a funeral procession.
Speaker 0: now the laws about funeral processions differ all around the world and even in different states in the US.
Speaker 0: But there are places in the United States where if someone dies They will put the body in a casket and put it in a hearse and then that hearse will drive from the church where the Ceremony or whatever happened or the funeral home or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah to the cemetery where they're gonna bury the person.
Speaker 1: Yep, because I mean old churches and stuff They have cemeteries right next to the church like on the church land.
Speaker 1: So then they just carry the casket out of the church and put it in the ground.
Speaker 0: But that's not the point.
Speaker 0: The point is that there will often be a funeral procession which dates back to a lot of old and I think Stupid customs, but
Speaker 1: except for the New Orleans ones watch James Bond movie
Speaker 0: only if there are international sexy Super-spies fighting it out secretly within the parade Otherwise not cool.
Speaker 1: now the per as long as it's a parade down the street with awesome jazz music.
Speaker 1: Well, it's cool.
Speaker 0: I have a somewhat controversial opinion that in general I mean I know that respect for the dead was one of the early signs among a lot of people who study civilization of The dawning of civilization and culture and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: I'm of the mind that society and culture should move beyond respect for the dead and I don't think that it serves any more purpose.
Speaker 0: But that is neither here nor there.
Speaker 1: I think you should respect the dead, but I don't associate that with respect the dead body because a body is just a lump of flesh.
Speaker 1: but the person and who they were and the Memory of who they were should be respect.
Speaker 0: That's respect for the former living.
Speaker 0: That's different from respect for the day.
Speaker 1: I see you're saying dead as in corpse.
Speaker 0: Well, and it's very complicated I don't want to get into it suffice to say specifically the corpses.
Speaker 0: I think cemeteries are perhaps the stupidest idea ever.
Speaker 1: I think cemeteries are pretty impractical.
Speaker 1: What they'll do.
Speaker 1: Well, I agree.
Speaker 1: They are impractical.
Speaker 1: I kind of want a mausoleum.
Speaker 1: Well, you're like mausoleums.
Speaker 1: What
Speaker 0: they'll often do is the first will go and then all the relatives and people who are going to the stupid funeral Will put little flags on their car and follow the thing and depending on the laws They now have full perfect right-of-way over stop signs traffic lights anything and they go straight to the funeral and cause all sorts of shit terrible traffic everywhere they go.
Speaker 0: and I hate funeral processions.
Speaker 0: I ran into them a lot as a kid driving around where I grew up and They just suddenly one would come around and it was illegal to get in their way or to cut him off.
Speaker 0: And even if you had a green light and they had a red light you had to let him go and they block traffic forever And you weren't allowed to pass him or cut through him or anything.
Speaker 0: And I just think the whole idea of it is stupid and I think that these customs should be utterly annihilated.
Speaker 1: I agree I mean if you have people who want to drive from place A to place B, even if there are a lot of them Why can't everyone just drive from place A to place B?
Speaker 1: Why do you have to go in sort of this line of unbreakableness?
Speaker 0: Well, apparently everyone go apparently a funeral procession here and I read more that this happens a lot.
Speaker 0: They were going and the guy at the front driving the hearse was speeding.
Speaker 0: So a cop pulled the funeral procession over.
Speaker 0: good during the course of being pulled over which was done in a very early manner There were a whole bunch of accidents because everyone in this procession was a moron who doesn't know how to hit up to hit the brakes.
Speaker 1: They got what they deserved and they're mad.
Speaker 0: there's their bloody furious quote with the police and they thought it was absolutely disgusting.
Speaker 0: and All I have to say is while I disagree with speeding you were speeding.
Speaker 0: cop pulled you over apparently to the funeral director Has been caught before doing this sort of thing.
Speaker 1: I guess he thinks because he's in the funeral procession thing he can speed and he probably likes speeding in his hearse.
Speaker 0: However, I'm on the mind that everyone who was involved in an accident in the funeral procession deserved exactly what they got.
Speaker 0: I hope they all get tickets for following too closely or something and I generally don't like funeral processions.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry, that wasn't anime related, but there's just nothing to talk about.
Speaker 1: I mean basically the problem is is that all the news that would be anime manga or comics with stuff that came out of the San Diego comic-con.
Speaker 1: but all of that news is along the lines of OMG, here's a pilot for a new TV show.
Speaker 1: We don't watch TV.
Speaker 1: OMG, these two people are gonna be writing and drawing this comic book.
Speaker 1: We don't read those comic books.
Speaker 0: Well, it doesn't help.
Speaker 0: that the few news is I cared about.
Speaker 0: I already talked about.
Speaker 1: yes And none of the news is that we're there are anything big or earth-shattering.
Speaker 1: They're all the sort of Superficial who gives a shit stuff that I was just complaining about.
Speaker 1: So there's nothing to say about them.
Speaker 1: It's just flat information and There's no comment to make unless you're really into that thing.
Speaker 1: in which case the only comment you can make is I approve or I Disapprove.
Speaker 1: and here's why and since we're so indifferent on any of that stuff It's not it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not that I'm indifferent so much as I don't have anything interesting to say about these.
Speaker 1: Well, you know you have anything interesting to say about say the fact that I don't know So and so and so and so have been moved from one superhero comic to a different superhero comic.
Speaker 0: I could talk about how the fact that they shuffle artists around is probably one of the problems with superhero comics.
Speaker 0: I could go on this whole sort of tangent about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's not you know, that's not related to the specific news.
Speaker 1: That's just in you know, and in general kind of thing about superhero.
Speaker 0: Yeah and the news is just a catalyst like now.
Speaker 0: my news was just a catalyst to get a tiny and Somewhat less insane than your rant.
Speaker 0: rant about funeral procession.
Speaker 0: I think the only difference between the sanity of our rants was that we agree on yours and you see well, I think the other difference is I You were spreading the obscenity around a little bit and I didn't so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's wrong with the obscenity?
Speaker 0: cuz while I just like funeral processions, I don't care I'm kind of indifferent if I see what I don't suddenly go into a blind fury I don't go into a blind for either but I do go grumble-grumble anyway.
Speaker 1: It's time for things of the day, you know, I'm thinking that you know, I mean yesterday We had that whole crazy argument that got cut out of the show, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and today we sort of just kind of went a little bit crazy there.
Speaker 1: you think maybe the weather is affecting the show.
Speaker 0: I don't think so at all because uh use well you started the first argument pretty much straight up and The second one that we had just now It was for at least 50/50.
Speaker 0: I think your crazy rant was crazy and I said so we didn't really argue so much Yeah, but I do feel like I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's the weather.
Speaker 0: I think it's just that there hasn't been a lot of interesting news to talk about and When I filled out the schedule for like the next two months of geek nights.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm more excited about some of the shows in the future than I am about the ones coming up right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh, well, we'll try to.
Speaker 1: next week.
Speaker 1: maybe We're giving you guys what you want because we get more requests for arguments than we do for I think we get those mostly from longtime listeners and our friends and I'm not so I'm not convinced that a lot of the The the more.
Speaker 1: I don't know the field, you know how they say in golf It's like Tiger Woods or the field.
Speaker 1: I think the field of listeners.
Speaker 0: I think it's just what's ever happening recently.
Speaker 0: because whenever we argue a lot We get a lot of people saying wow You guys need to lay off and not argue.
Speaker 0: and whenever we don't argue we get a bunch of people saying man Bring back the arguments.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like whenever we change anything It's like half the people say they want it the old way and after people want it the new way.
Speaker 1: What's your thing of the day?
Speaker 0: All right, I'll be real quick about this In Russia in Siberia, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think this was found recently.
Speaker 0: I think it's just there's pictures of it down.
Speaker 0: There's this old old they call it ancient fortress that's built in the middle of an island deep inside Siberia.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it's really cool.
Speaker 1: However, I saw that link, but I think the the picture was dead so I didn't get to see it.
Speaker 1: Show me.
Speaker 0: No, the pictures are really better.
Speaker 0: the way then I can't talk.
Speaker 1: I'm not I want to see the Fiberian fortress.
Speaker 0: But the thing I found really interesting about this is that you know, it's ancient ancient ancient.
Speaker 1: How ancient is it?
Speaker 0: and then they give the date which is dated more than?
Speaker 0: 1,500 years ago.
Speaker 0: now 1,500 years ago Rome was in.
Speaker 0: it was Rome had already fallen.
Speaker 1: It's not too old then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, oh, it's ancient.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's just because I'm really really studying Roman history now like more so than I have been ever before.
Speaker 0: I'm even kind of done with the Byzantine history because I've learned a lot of it.
Speaker 0: I'm moving further back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if it's not pre Rome, I can't really consider it to be ancient.
Speaker 0: Well, it seems like the more you study something like Roman It's set in a hyperbolic fashion the less ancient.
Speaker 0: It seems like the Middle Ages and like the Renaissance seems like it happened yesterday and the Middle Ages are like the day before yesterday And then there was Rome.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, so it's weird how this doesn't feel old to me But before I was really into Roman and Byzantine history this probably would have seemed really old and really cool.
Speaker 1: this reminds me of something I learned when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: something I didn't learn in school is You know, I like castles.
Speaker 1: I like I like castles, you know buildings made of rock.
Speaker 0: So this These pictures are on this like English Russia blog.
Speaker 0: It's like a blog about Russia in English.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I just scrolled down randomly while Scott was talking and you can comment on the site, but there's an anti-spam capture And it's in Cyrillic.
Speaker 0: no the picture is the word Soviet in red.
Speaker 1: All right, so anyway, so I like castles and you know I never got.
Speaker 1: I didn't get to see too many castles when I was a kid, you know I think we went to this one castle Called like Gillette castle in Connecticut and I have actually a snow globe from there Which is supposed supposedly really rare because they stopped making them.
Speaker 1: Well, there's Bannerman castle, which is our house is Bannerman castle and they're those cloisters in the city, right?
Speaker 1: And you know when I was a kid, you know I didn't I wasn't so much thinking and you know how mean that the history in the years, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, what was the that are that argument?
Speaker 0: We had way back in the day that the Romans learned about armor and swords from the Knights of the Middle Ages.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so whatever.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna bring that up for the rest of your life.
Speaker 0: Probably.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and so when I was a kid I would like drive by and you know, I saw like, you know The cloisters and I was like, ooh castles were there.
Speaker 1: can it gets in those castles, you know?
Speaker 1: Because I think castles can it gets right.
Speaker 1: and my parents were like You know, this castle is on this side is in the Western Hemisphere.
Speaker 1: This castle can't possibly be older than like 1600 something and I was like Oh snaps and it totally realized that every castle in the Western Hemisphere sucks unless it's like an Aztec pyramid Which isn't really a castle.
Speaker 0: it is pretty interesting when you think about the state of the natives of North America When the West eventually discovered them and started, you know, the raping pillage exploitation Colonization whatever and compare that to the civilizations that existed in Europe or in China, you know Thousand years before two thousand years before.
Speaker 0: I find that fascinating.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is pretty fast.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like in Civ - when you're playing the game and you get your infantry and you get your gunpowder And I got my boats and I'm going around and I got iron and then I stumble upon some guy with some cataphracts And he's trying to take over my city.
Speaker 0: Haha, or I find like this gigantic civilization that never found the wheel All right.
Speaker 0: The thing is I've never in the course of playing Civ - not immediately conquered those people without regret.
Speaker 1: Okay, are you ready?
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna give you the reveal of why I had the crazy red.
Speaker 1: Okay, you ready for this thing of the day?
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: There's a rumor going around that There's gonna be a new Toyota AE 86 and there's a picture of it.
Speaker 1: That's kind of old news I know but what else did I have?
Speaker 1: And also the point.
Speaker 1: the reason I chose this is I put it with the pre crazy, right?
Speaker 1: You see what I just did.
Speaker 0: they see what you did.
Speaker 0: I see what you did.
Speaker 1: They see what I did there.
Speaker 1: Check this shit out.
Speaker 1: It's basically it's not.
Speaker 1: it doesn't look anything.
Speaker 1: Well, I won't say it doesn't look anything like the original 86.
Speaker 0: the only thing that was special I mean the AE 86 was just a chassis pretty much but the only it.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's the same car in spirit But it's a new car and it's gonna be really light really small really low to the ground and it's gonna have like 120 horsepower.
Speaker 1: That's not so bad According to this here man.
Speaker 0: That's the same horsepower.
Speaker 0: My current car has.
Speaker 1: yeah, if I was buying cars now I'd actually consider this car greatly.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is I existed.
Speaker 0: I think that this is brilliant because The rice out culture is actually really kind of popular in the US.
Speaker 0: Yeah and a lot of those people even though they're not really anime fans at all a lot of them know about initial D a Lot of them not only that but in Japan, I mean this picture here is from Japan with Japanese riding on it.
Speaker 1: They're all into the initial D.
Speaker 0: still they'll buy it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Kind of I really think that if companies Released cars that were from initial D only Affordable and like if someone remade the celady somehow like made a this is a celady that we've made now Just like the old celady they make a lot of money.
Speaker 0: well I mean
Speaker 1: look at how cars like the Honda Civic just sell insanely because it's so riceable and The other company is like they don't have very many cars that are very riceable At least not as riceable as some of the others, you know Toyota releasing a new 86 would pretty much be making a car that's riceable on purpose to make a lot of money.
Speaker 1: I mean way the the Corolla not so riceable, you know I mean any car is riceable to a point.
Speaker 1: but this car will be like the rice Money-making machine if they put it out here and they should right.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about anime at least a little bit.
Speaker 0: Luckily, it's gonna be kind of short.
Speaker 0: You see we had a bun.
Speaker 0: I had the whole schedule filled out about what we were gonna talk about in the shows and the comics Whatever, but then we watched the first episode of one of the new anime coming out.
Speaker 1: Well, actually I knew this anime was coming cuz Emily said something about it.
Speaker 1: I mean basically all I heard was there's a show called this and it's a mafia show which Tells Scott good show coming mafia good by default no matter what pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean we didn't have any expectations about it.
Speaker 0: It was just alright.
Speaker 0: This is a show that has some potential and a lot of shows had potential.
Speaker 0: I mean ergo proxy, I think still has but I haven't watched it all.
Speaker 0: No, but when I saw that I was excited and all Bocorano, I'm really excited about still and all that.
Speaker 0: But this is just a show like that.
Speaker 0: The show looks like it might be better than the majority of the dross that we've been seeing lately.
Speaker 1: Yep, so the first episode finally comes out and the show is called baccano b a c c a n o Exclamation point and I think in Italian that means noise or something like that.
Speaker 0: And it's a show that is not translated as stupid commotion, uh-huh, and It's a show that is about Mafias, I guess and a whole cast of characters and other things see regardless of what it's about because I actually went into it Not knowing anything at all about.
Speaker 1: all I knew was mafias.
Speaker 1: That was all I knew.
Speaker 0: all I knew was the title and From that I think and then Scott Emily like yeah mafia something.
Speaker 0: so I think alright show about mafia this is gonna be great.
Speaker 0: and Scott accidentally pulled up the like preview trailer instead of the episode and It was all weird and music.
Speaker 0: people on a train killing each other like murders on a train in a kid with a weird scar tattoo something on his face and Kind of surreal almost supernatural.
Speaker 0: It didn't look anything like what I expected.
Speaker 1: No It looked like.
Speaker 1: it looked to me like a dark Sort of weird murder on the Orient Express kind of deal and the in the trailer.
Speaker 1: So then we watch the actual show.
Speaker 1: all right the show opens up right.
Speaker 1: first they give you that old sponsor.
Speaker 1: well No first they give you the opener.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: the opener has a pretty cool song.
Speaker 1: can we get the opener in the show?
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I don't want to bother.
Speaker 1: we could but The opener is a lot like the opener to snatch or one of those movies.
Speaker 0: That's that's the thing.
Speaker 0: as soon as we saw the actual opener all I could think was this is snatched the anime.
Speaker 1: yeah, they had all these really cool this really cool music.
Speaker 1: and What they would do in the opener is they would show you a character doing something then they would freeze-frame the character Put their name on the screen in English right English letters And then have a cool Transition to do the next character.
Speaker 1: and there were a whole lot of characters And they took the entire opener just going through all these characters.
Speaker 1: show a character show their name smooth transition.
Speaker 1: show a character show A name smooth transition.
Speaker 0: now the thing is every single character.
Speaker 0: They showed.
Speaker 0: you think wow that's obviously the main character.
Speaker 0: Oh wow that's obviously the main character and every one of them.
Speaker 0: just from what little you see You probably already like them as a character, and you think wow there could probably be a show just about this one person.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think that I didn't really feel that but I did feel that None of the characters really put above or below the others.
Speaker 1: usually you feel like some characters are more important and some are less important And some are main and some are supporting, but it really felt like every character.
Speaker 1: They showed was Equal like they are all Equally important and equally in the plot and none of them are minor or more major than others.
Speaker 1: most importantly for these two characters Because they had the most time in the opener and they're the last characters you see and also the first characters you see and the Opener.
Speaker 1: so I think they might be slightly more important than the others.
Speaker 0: They all just reeked of main character.
Speaker 0: like if anyone if you saw any one of them and some other anime you think oh They're a main character.
Speaker 0: They're some somewhat important to the plot.
Speaker 0: They're not just gonna get killed off randomly or anything.
Speaker 0: They'll have a name.
Speaker 1: They all have a name.
Speaker 1: They should have a name in the opener All right, so after that they give you the sponsor screen right, but the sponsor screen You know like where they usually say you know oh take your day Oh get it she must you know
Speaker 0: by
Speaker 1: look go you know it's brought to you by our sponsor Consume right.
Speaker 1: the guy said in English.
Speaker 0: now I don't know if they did that in English or if the fansubbers just being funny because that is possible I think they did in English.
Speaker 1: I mean the openers the characters names were in English.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wouldn't be surprised.
Speaker 0: I mean English is still pretty hip yes So I don't know it.
Speaker 1: does that mean that this show is meant for us in America more than it's meant for the Japan's?
Speaker 0: I don't know, but regardless of all that all right.
Speaker 0: so that opener happens now.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what this show is about because it still looks like it's about.
Speaker 0: it's about mafia something and Other than the weird trailer we saw a few snippets of I don't see anything weird about it right.
Speaker 1: So it opens up with this guy with a monocle and this is girl this little girl But she's not super little or stupid.
Speaker 1: She's just I don't know.
Speaker 1: is she a teenager.
Speaker 1: I can't really tell.
Speaker 0: no She's not a teenager.
Speaker 0: She's a really young little girl, but she she acts smart.
Speaker 1: She just doesn't look very old at all.
Speaker 1: She looks like she's maybe 12 at the most.
Speaker 0: well the thing is but she talks.
Speaker 0: the show opens with a conversation between these two characters, and you don't know anything about them at all.
Speaker 0: you don't really know anything about what the show's about and Nothing from the opener really told you what to expect.
Speaker 1: They just said here are the characters here are their names because
Speaker 0: it was all over the place and these characters Proceed they talk in a really cryptic way for a while But it actually all kind of makes sense and you kind of follow what's going on And it's kind of interesting and then you realize that they start arguing as to who are the main characters of the story?
Speaker 1: Huh gee I don't know.
Speaker 1: At the one hand it was really clever and awesome, but on the other hand it was Slightly sort of forced and obvious and not subtle,
Speaker 0: but it seats to me It wasn't really that force because then they also start arguing about When the story started and that
Speaker 1: part was actually pretty cool
Speaker 0: Yes, and they basically it keeps cutting back to them.
Speaker 0: But between them talking and arguing about when the story started who the main character is who's moving it What's going on?
Speaker 0: it cuts to these flashbacks from all throughout time from it seems like almost everything They showed is a scene from the show that we haven't gotten to yet either from the future or the past.
Speaker 1: Yep And you learn from the people talking that these two people that the old guy is like the vice Director of a newspaper of some sort and the girl it guesses his assistant I think and I think that's what they say.
Speaker 0: I think there's a funny bit where whenever she says something insightful the guy always says like you get 384 points and she's like out of how many and she says it's really funny.
Speaker 0: Look, I just keeps talking and he doesn't say anything.
Speaker 0: now The point I really want to make is that they they do this interesting thing that in any other anime would have been forced and Stupid, you know a bunch of care to characters arguing about who the main characters of the show are.
Speaker 0: it's really kind of meta breaking the fourth wall and all that sort of thing, but The show pulled it off to the point that I feel like it.
Speaker 0: it was done Well that this could be a really good mechanic or device in the show.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 1: it was done pretty well.
Speaker 1: I mean it didn't you?
Speaker 1: normally if like you had that kind of thing It might be the sort of thing you'd put it like the end of your show and it'd be like an end of Ava kind Of thing.
Speaker 1: that would be all we.
Speaker 0: it reminds me a little bit.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna compare the show to cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because there's no way you can know.
Speaker 0: but cowboy bebop was a show that basically came out and had the sheer testicular fortitude to Say we are making a new genre.
Speaker 0: We are going into uncharted waters We are doing something amazing and different and then it backed that up a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: Yeah this show is treading into those waters a little bit a little bit a little bit in the sense that they're going balls out and Saying we're doing something that if we don't do it right is gonna make our show really stupid in force.
Speaker 0: It'll make it so stupid if they don't do it, right and thus far they haven't fallen on their faces yet.
Speaker 0: That means a lot to me.
Speaker 1: The only negative thing I can say about the show so far is that it's a little bit hard to follow What's going on because of the crazy stuff that they're doing cutting all over the place in Chronology showing all these different characters without formally and introducing them slowly but sort of just throwing them in in your face.
Speaker 0: Yes, when we say cutting around it's not like you expect you'll have to watch it to see but literally there's no transition.
Speaker 0: It's like guy doing something cut to a different angle of guy doing something cut to what feels like a different angle But it's actually a different scene at a different time with different characters.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I gotta say as can be as confusing as it was.
Speaker 1: It wasn't stupidly confusing, but it was pretty confusing.
Speaker 1: I watched the first episode a second time and now I got a really good handle on.
Speaker 0: I gotta say it felt confusing.
Speaker 0: and there's It's a lot of books do this to not a lot but books that I think are good if you do it Right.
Speaker 0: It's a really nice thing if you introduce concepts or proper nouns or anything that is Specific to the world of the arts the world of that you're creating in the work and you don't explain it But you use it in the proper context and if you do it in the right way People will start to learn on their own how everything works without Realizing it and they'll learn a lot more about the world without having to have lengthy lengthy stupid boring exposition about the world.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the only problem with that if done poorly if you just get proper noun gobbledygook.
Speaker 1: Also, if the problem is is that you can't get someone into the world quickly.
Speaker 1: So if you've only got like one issue of a comic book or one episode of an anime It's sort of difficult for people to get all the way there and reach understanding in that You know one unit of the work also some people.
Speaker 0: I'll say this if you're one of those people who tries to figure out what's going On like really hard when you're watching a show I think that will hinder your understanding of what happens in the first episode because you'll spend too much time worried about Who's who and the names the side.
Speaker 0: already the scene will change and all this business and honestly if you just roll with it You'll learn you'll figure out a lot more real quick.
Speaker 0: Just don't don't try to remember the names of all the people.
Speaker 0: just pay attention to what's going on and just go with it.
Speaker 1: if you Really want to understand it just watch it twice.
Speaker 1: I watched the first episode two times and the second time I completely understood everything that was going down.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh I get it.
Speaker 1: Oh duh It's not that complicated now.
Speaker 0: the second moment that really stood out is the show went along and it's kind of interesting and you get All these glimpses of the future in the past and you see scenes that I'm sure we're gonna forget about.
Speaker 0: And then we'll get to like episode 12, I love that shit.
Speaker 1: Utena did that shit.
Speaker 0: Oh god Utena was like the king queen and they show you a really short like clip like.
Speaker 1: they'll show you like I don't know a rock flying across the sky or they'll show you like a bird standing.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'll give you a specific scene.
Speaker 0: There's a scene in Utena kind of early on when Auntie He met me other, you know The Rose bride girl the weird girl the Indian girl and she's just sitting in a classroom Doing something weird and it lingers on this scene for all and you think all right That scene just showed me that Auntie's a little weird something I knew.
Speaker 0: I'll bet they just needed to fill out this episode.
Speaker 0: That was kind of bland and short.
Speaker 0: and then you see the whole show and you go back and watch that again And it's like whoa.
Speaker 1: I know what she's doing now.
Speaker 1: Damn dams.
Speaker 0: This show can definitely pull that off.
Speaker 0: I love that when a movie shows you something and it's all right there You're just too stupid and uninformed to figure it out yet, but theoretically you could have within the first episode They do that.
Speaker 1: I'll actually give you a specific example from the first episode of Baccano.
Speaker 0: I think I know which one you're gonna get.
Speaker 1: Well, no They show you really quickly.
Speaker 1: at some point.
Speaker 1: one of the characters that you probably only remember from the opener getting like There's like some girl with like a spear that has like a cross of blades at the end of it Like she cuts his ear and then it's like a two-second clip.
Speaker 1: like cuts his ear and you're just like, huh?
Speaker 1: And then it goes away and deals with something else instead.
Speaker 1: and then like really close to the end of the episode You see the guy like.
Speaker 1: they go back to the guy suddenly like just cut to him and he's like, oh my ear something's.
Speaker 1: and then he says something else after that and I didn't notice that those two like.
Speaker 1: it's like they took a scene and they Just caught like the first five seconds of it and put it way early in the episode instead of putting them together.
Speaker 0: now I really don't want to ruin more about what's going on because I don't want to poison the.
Speaker 0: well I really want all of you to watch the show and figure out and just experience the revelations as you will.
Speaker 1: I also don't.
Speaker 0: but there's a moment.
Speaker 0: They were the moment other than when they start arguing about who the main characters are.
Speaker 0: There's a point at which a hobo tries to stab some dude
Speaker 1: and a good moment the
Speaker 0: scene does not play out the way you think it's going to play out and then when you think you know what's going on like You think oh, so it's going in that direction.
Speaker 0: No, it's not and it's great.
Speaker 1: It is pretty damn awesome.
Speaker 0: Of course related to that.
Speaker 0: This is one of those shows where there isn't a lot of violence.
Speaker 0: It's not like there's uncharacteristic or just violence without purpose or people getting blown up.
Speaker 0: It's none of those each of the killer things.
Speaker 0: but When there is violence, they do not dick around and it is brutal and it's not really graphic.
Speaker 1: It's like God except for that one since it's a lot like the violence and the Godfather.
Speaker 1: when this violence OMG It's it's sort of real they go out of their way to make obvious.
Speaker 1: That's what there is.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not super bloody and gory But it has that hint of realism to the point that you wince a little bit.
Speaker 0: and even me I mean I watch he the killer and laughed all the way through it.
Speaker 1: But I look at each of the killer is a lot of that sort of zipper on the back of the monster costume true Roast violence and not the sort of it's like you can have a lot less quantity of blood a lot less You know quantity of bullets and guts all over.
Speaker 0: this is the violence.
Speaker 1: but be more effective in making people wince or feel uncomfortable because your violence is more realistic and less sort of you know, Fake zipper on the back of the monster.
Speaker 0: I think the reason is this is the violence of permanence.
Speaker 0: I mean take a scene where a guy in an anime Punches another guy straight up in the face and then a scene change covers all the damage.
Speaker 0: Maybe he has a bandage on or a little scratch or something, but the character is otherwise fine.
Speaker 0: now Imagine the same scene only he punches the guy and you see very clearly blood and a tooth fly out of his mouth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then in the next scene his jaw is swollen.
Speaker 1: That's why slow-mo boxing.
Speaker 1: it is really painful to watch.
Speaker 0: All right, and I gotta say there is one kind of gross scene near the end where the guy is talking to the police Yeah, where that was pretty gross.
Speaker 0: It's a scene where I'm looking at it and Emily's looking at it and Scott Look, it's so quick.
Speaker 1: You might not even catch the grossness.
Speaker 0: So we're all thinking is that what I think it is?
Speaker 0: and it was.
Speaker 1: I watched it a second time on the train today And it was totally what you think it.
Speaker 0: by the time you realize what it is You've already missed the next scene because you forgot about the fact that the show is gonna cut away.
Speaker 1: Yep, and while it's grow basically shows you something really gross for like a half a second and then cuts away.
Speaker 0: I got to admit I found that scene hilarious just because of the delayed reaction of the police officers.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: think it was sort of like this weird scene because the top half of the frame was funny where all the police were but the Bottom half where the gross part was was gross and also the fact
Speaker 0: that
Speaker 1: the top was good and the bottom was not so good.
Speaker 0: Right before that happens There is a little bit of dialogue between him and another character on the screen and you suddenly Really hate him as a character.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz he says some pretty crazy and bad stuff and then it's gross and then now Lisa funny.
Speaker 0: I think the reason I'm excited.
Speaker 0: I'm more excited about this show than I've been about any anime in a long time.
Speaker 0: And even though the show might not I mean I was the same way about noir.
Speaker 0: The first episode of noir had all this potential and I thought it was gonna be great.
Speaker 0: and it's a noir Ended up being if you compare how much how good the first episode was to how stupid the last.
Speaker 1: I think the problem with noir is that they used awesome music to make their show seem better than it was.
Speaker 0: Yes, kind of like a die heck.
Speaker 1: Yes, same same compose same composer.
Speaker 0: Yes, or what was that other one?
Speaker 0: The one we reviewed the stupid one.
Speaker 0: I don't remember that was the same as noir or But this show is Whether or not it's good.
Speaker 0: They've decided to do something different.
Speaker 0: It's not like any anime I've seen in a long time.
Speaker 0: It's a breath of fresh air and if they pull it off It's gonna be one of those shows that stands out as you know, what all the anime right now is?
Speaker 0: the same moe crap.
Speaker 0: We're gonna fix that.
Speaker 1: All right, there's only two other things I got to say about the show before we end this business.
Speaker 1: The guy the guy who's the director of the newspaper something the assistant newspaper director, whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh, I totally forgot about that.
Speaker 1: the guy that guy he has the monocle.
Speaker 1: He's talking to the young girl for like, you know There's sort of the central characters at least of this episode.
Speaker 1: now think about once you talk about the main character I think you might know him.
Speaker 1: He the voice actor in Japanese for that guy is the same voice actor for Chiyo's dad and as a manga dial and also Mikazawa.
Speaker 1: and I gotta say I really like the way that guy says Dorshte.
Speaker 1: It just says it like so slow.
Speaker 0: I can't do it.
Speaker 1: I can't do it But the guy says Dorshte in a really awesome way and that's how I knew it was him as soon as he said that.
Speaker 0: now It was funny because I was thinking that voice sounds familiar But I couldn't quite pay.
Speaker 1: I said that's I think it's Chiyo's dad.
Speaker 1: and then when he said Dorshte I'm like it's Chiyo's dad.
Speaker 0: I was 50/50 but Scott was like, I'm sure I'm sure sure enough.
Speaker 0: Scott was right.
Speaker 1: I was right now.
Speaker 1: There's another character.
Speaker 0: Now my name is mr Luck is.
Speaker 1: his name is like luck and he's part of one of the mafia families I think the one that begins with a G. I'm not sure but his first name is luck.
Speaker 1: So he's like luck.
Speaker 1: and then his last name is Mafia family name that begins with G and I think he's like.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's the head of that mafia family But he's like maybe like one of the upper guys.
Speaker 1: He's pretty important.
Speaker 0: now both of us the guy said pretty much two words and Scott and I were like, it's him It's him.
Speaker 1: the guy the voice actor they got for this character who I think is pretty awesome is our man the Takehito Koyasu, I gotta say that guy still This is a lot.
Speaker 0: character is the same as every other character.
Speaker 0: He voice acts as he always plays the same character the cool suave guy They really like who's just too cool for school and really smooth and a badass.
Speaker 1: and he's gonna.
Speaker 1: He can't be touched cuz he's so awesome.
Speaker 0: The guy who's always underestimated by his opponents yet always wins in the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except against.
Speaker 0: well, I can't spoil.
Speaker 1: Yes, but yeah, the same voice actor is Toga and utenna and Takahashi ryoseki and initial D.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a hori and fushigi Yugi.
Speaker 0: Yes, bud mint and KO century beast He's my favorite voice actor ever probably.
Speaker 1: and so you got these two amazing voice actors in the show not to mention I think I recognize some other voice actors in there.
Speaker 1: I just wasn't.
Speaker 1: I'm not super fans of them nor did I a hundred percent recognize them because I don't know that much about voice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't look through super much, but I feel like this show might have an all-star cast.
Speaker 1: I think it does have Basically an all-star cast of anime voice actors and it's not an all-star cast of like, you know Japanese movie stars or anything, but you know, it's not like I do with the Mononoke game The Ghibli movies.
Speaker 1: when Disney does it they get like Hollywood real actors always like Billy Crystal.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, Billy Crystal was a really good job as the Billy Crystal is a fantastic voice actor And I like him as a person quite a bit.
Speaker 0: I find him hilarious.
Speaker 1: He's pretty funny guy especially in Princess Bride, but yeah, so This is a show that if you like anime and you watch the fan subs Probably a good idea to watch this show.
Speaker 1: if you don't I recommend you watch this first episode two times.
Speaker 0: I'll say this the less you like the average anime that's come out recently I think the more you're gonna like this show.
Speaker 1: and if you don't like weird stuff is the probably just weird you out.
Speaker 0: I do want to say give it a chance because there's something very Very important that we did not spoil and at least learn that before you decide.
Speaker 0: if you think you'll like this show Because it's kind of you won't guess what it is, but you should be able to figure it out during the course of the episode.
Speaker 0: There's there's another element to this show that is not expected in a mafia show And that'll that aspect I think is going to make a lot of people who would otherwise brush this show off.
Speaker 1: I think that I think how that aspect is handled is going to make or break the show.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek night's at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.