Speaker 1: It's Monday November 26th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight the post historic internets.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: ah Weekend in Rochester wow is it cold?
Speaker 0: It was sunny and 60 degrees when I left beacon in the morning and by the time I got to Syracuse suddenly the Sun disappears and the snow starts.
Speaker 0: sounds about right yep But there's like eight new buildings at RIT, and I hung out with I think the last people I know in Rochester.
Speaker 1: Any good new games at the Millennium or anything?
Speaker 0: actually I saw a bunch of games that I kind of want to own.
Speaker 0: I just didn't feel like buying them.
Speaker 0: remember that Mesopotamia game where you carry the sticks and the rocks.
Speaker 1: I don't want that game.
Speaker 0: It was kind of fun.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't pay for that.
Speaker 0: It's a good game to get people into gaming.
Speaker 0: It's just not.
Speaker 0: it's a game that if I played it one or two more times.
Speaker 0: I think I'd solve it.
Speaker 1: I'm not good with them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though.
Speaker 0: I did ask the guy about that dune game, and he pretty much said ha ha ha I'm going for it on eBay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how's that auction going?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: yeah, but one game that is in town.
Speaker 0: I was over at hammer girl and Luke has the new initial d arcade game Initial d4 with widescreen LCDs and 3d graphics like actual better 3d graphics And the game is a lot more realistic.
Speaker 0: as in my strategy of hit the breakdown shift turn the wheel all the way To the left and then all the way to the right causes me to fishtail and crash.
Speaker 1: Sounds about right.
Speaker 0: I have to actually I think counter-steer.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: I only played it twice I have no idea.
Speaker 0: I crashed into every wall, and I need to go to the dive Ella's.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: in fact I didn't either the pita pita Wegmans.
Speaker 0: I did go to Wegmans Uh-huh you know what one day in the in the true sensor in the innuendo sense in the true sense And I don't think the listeners know about the other Wegmans.
Speaker 0: Oh tough Suffice to say I used to go to used to.
Speaker 0: I still go to Wegmans on a regular basis.
Speaker 0: I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: All right, so that's a story for some day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so today at work You know I go to work and over the weekend.
Speaker 1: I upgraded the forum some and there were some problems I fixed in this morning, and then about a few hours like around 11 noon ish the internet at work stopped working and then it worked again and Then it stopped working and it stayed stopped working in till I left
Speaker 0: work.
Speaker 0: Huh, I wonder if it will be working tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be checking my work mail tomorrow, and if I don't have any mail that can only mean It's not working.
Speaker 0: Are you just gonna not go?
Speaker 0: I mean I couldn't do No, if there was no if there was no outside access at my company There's no reason for my company to exist.
Speaker 0: I might as well just stay home.
Speaker 1: I know me too, but it's the same.
Speaker 1: here's the problem though.
Speaker 1: They all have like IP phones So I can't even call or email.
Speaker 1: or Wow how can I?
Speaker 1: I can't communicate with the work.
Speaker 0: actually you know It's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: We're setting up one of those Open offices.
Speaker 0: not like the really slow and bloated office application But as in from all the offices we have all over the world open office isn't that slow bloated anymore?
Speaker 0: No, not as much as it used to be.
Speaker 0: it's no VI right Emags?
Speaker 0: Well, there's no VI in that.
Speaker 0: I like VI.
Speaker 0: I actually usually you know what I realized just now that it's not a joke I use VI more than I use any other word processing application.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think number two is the editor in the forum, and I think number three is WordPress editor Gmail Gmail.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz I don't use the pot it takes me like two seconds to make the post here.
Speaker 1: No, I know anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway, so uh Scott What do you have in the news?
Speaker 0: you know tech news?
Speaker 0: Tech news day.
Speaker 1: I don't have any tech news.
Speaker 1: what I have is sort of a tech geek bite kind of.
Speaker 1: I guess I don't know what else to call it now.
Speaker 0: I feel like this should be a show and we do also feel like it should be Probably going to more depth because we have some ideas and how to remedy this ideas that would probably turn into IPOs someday.
Speaker 1: IPOs are no good anymore because of Sarbanes-Oxley.
Speaker 1: It's all about getting bought.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that could be and getting VC and get bought.
Speaker 0: yeah, but anyway We're not gonna reveal those ways.
Speaker 1: some big company with mad money can take care of your Sarbanes-Oxley as opposed to you having to Take care of it on your poor ass self before you go IPO.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah anyway I think the sensationalist dig headline were we to have the full show about this would be is dig dead.
Speaker 1: Question mark exclamation point.
Speaker 0: maybe something like we did before about the dig democracy and the slash job Shitstorm Autocracy.
Speaker 1: yeah, anyway, I'm done with dig.
Speaker 1: I removed dig from my Google RSS reader and I'm just not gonna pay attention to dig anymore because I got an account there.
Speaker 1: I'll probably keep that.
Speaker 1: I might have to go and look you know to see if that maybe there's something I dug that I want to remember or something like that, but for the most part I'm ignoring dig now as opposed to using it more than any other website.
Speaker 1: because uh It you back in the early days a dig and hey was better than slash dot and just pretty much every story that showed Up on dig was something.
Speaker 1: I was interested in it.
Speaker 1: now pretty much everything on dig is useless shit, and I don't care anymore.
Speaker 0: and Scott said that and I thought but but dig it's it's not perfect and it's kind of shitty now But it's still the best we've got.
Speaker 0: and then I thought back to like the last month And I thought about where I'd gotten my news from and where I'd been reading things And I realized that I had not gotten anything other than a few Kind of lame things of the day from dig.
Speaker 0: in like four months every news I've talked about I got from somewhere else.
Speaker 1: everything on dig now is just Ron Paul.
Speaker 1: OMG Crazy conspiracy theory.
Speaker 0: OMG It's a video of gnome Chomsky who I really like But I don't need there to be a page of like eight gnome Chomsky videos.
Speaker 1: sensationalist BS OMG Something you knew about already.
Speaker 1: OMG OMG OMG
Speaker 0: yeah, and I used to back in the day I made the comments on dig useful to me and by doing the way I did this was that I pretty much blocked
Speaker 1: anyone
Speaker 0: who ever said anything stupid or ever misspelled more than one word or didn't capitalize.
Speaker 0: I ever and Now I can't keep up the last time I went to a conversation.
Speaker 0: I realized that I had to block Every single post that I had read and then I stopped reading the comments on dig.
Speaker 1: yep so now what I'm doing is I'm gonna use my Google Reader a lot more and I got Kick kick dig out, and I'm gonna go.
Speaker 1: I'm going I'm watching all these feeds, and I'm getting more feeds And I'm kicking other feeds out And I'm basically gonna start managing my feeds and I'm gonna go and get some you know feeds from sort of not not just blogs Which I you know I have like the engagement feed in there and the boiling boiling feed.
Speaker 1: But I'm also gonna go and like get feeds of people's deliciouses, or you know people's blogs.
Speaker 0: Well, I've noticed this trend in my head.
Speaker 0: I mean look at zero punctuation.
Speaker 0: He's a man if we talked about him a lot on Tuesday But he does these.
Speaker 0: he talks about video games, and I've found so far that I agree 100% with everything that he has ever said relating to video games that I'm aware of and As a result I tend to seek out his opinion on things And I feel like if I could just look at his delicious or whatever he used I could probably find things I was interested in without all the crap a lot more readily than I could on dig.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean even looking at zero punctuation itself.
Speaker 1: right I could have the dig feed which gives me 200 crap stories And the link to zero function every week when it becomes available.
Speaker 1: zero Punctuation zero punctuation, or I can just subscribe to zero punctuation speed and get whenever he puts something up.
Speaker 1: Oh, I do well.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: I'm on the front page of dig right now the dig technology.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go to the straight up just front page of dig and see if there's anything interesting.
Speaker 1: That isn't bullshit.
Speaker 1: if it's a lie or bullshit.
Speaker 0: you got to count it out right, so I'm now at the Absolute front page of all of dig.
Speaker 0: this is according to dig the current zeitgeist of the democracy of the Internet and the top one Washington Redskins safety Sean Taylor shot fighting for his life.
Speaker 0: Oh Thank you for telling me what the AP wire told me and Fark told me earlier today that I don't really all right.
Speaker 1: I mean it's sad or whatever, but I don't care.
Speaker 0: Oh a video of some bar trick grade Google announces.
Speaker 0: Google body search already knew about that.
Speaker 0: the benefits of garlic.
Speaker 0: Yeah Do blondes make us do okay?
Speaker 0: That's great.
Speaker 0: Should you trust your doctor?
Speaker 1: Great yes, yes, you should as long as they're a real doctor.
Speaker 1: Yes, you should trust them.
Speaker 0: Oh one good thing talking about that sniper who killed five hundred and five Soviet soldiers during the Winter War.
Speaker 0: I already knew about that, but I guess if I didn't know about that.
Speaker 0: That'd be cool.
Speaker 0: Extreme Alpine speed paragliding I saw that like a month ago.
Speaker 0: Female sex tourists great.
Speaker 0: That's just news that The seven habits of highly effective assholes.
Speaker 0: that sounds fun.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: there's nothing here that interests me at all.
Speaker 1: No not absolutely nothing.
Speaker 0: even King said something.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's a headline all in lowercase.
Speaker 0: great.
Speaker 1: Yet, I realized basically what happens.
Speaker 1: is you want when you go on the internet, right?
Speaker 1: There's a so much content You can't possibly get it all and I could do.
Speaker 1: I mean I could do talk about this for as long as I could.
Speaker 1: Only some of that content you care about and each person each individual human being cares about a different Subset of the total amount of content.
Speaker 1: if there's a million stories Maybe each person cares about ten of them right and for each person.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be a different ten stories They care about but if someone's similar for example me and rim Nine of our stories that we care about might be the same.
Speaker 1: So the thing with dig is that looking at the front page at least right you're.
Speaker 1: you're not seeing only the stories Other people like you care about at least not anymore.
Speaker 1: you're seeing the stories that everyone in the whole freaking dig cares about and You're basically getting the front page is sort of a one-size-fits-all.
Speaker 1: It's like everybody.
Speaker 1: all these different people Thousands and thousands of different people who all care about different things are all dished out the same top stories.
Speaker 1: Well, no It should be different top stories for each person person cares about something different.
Speaker 0: cool with that because otherwise you do have the problem if Everything is customized just to you with the balkanization where you'll never be exposed to anything.
Speaker 0: That might have been cool that you didn't think you were interested.
Speaker 1: Well, you need to work something out where you know, it shows something.
Speaker 0: You know what worked before.
Speaker 0: I mean, I hate to say something like this Before people really knew about dig and when dig was relatively small and The only people were on dig were while they had a lot of varied interests.
Speaker 0: They were mostly the early adopter kind of innovator.
Speaker 0: Hey, it's the new thing.
Speaker 0: It was the kind of people who used orca back in the day, you know before Facebook.
Speaker 1: The kind of people are using like the pounds in the Twitter and stuff now.
Speaker 0: and as a result while I saw a lot of Things that I didn't think I was interested in Almost everything on dig was interesting because interesting people were digging up interesting things and it was the kind of Everything interesting in the world would hit there because of that wide group of people would find the interesting things Now and dig was a slash a slashdot.
Speaker 0: dig was a snapshot of I guess The the global mind of all those interesting people.
Speaker 0: now dig is a slashdot of the I guess The main hump of the internet a lot more people use it's the lowest common denominator.
Speaker 0: not yet It's not the lowest common denominator.
Speaker 1: Maybe not.
Speaker 0: No, it's kind of like you've got the leading a low common denominator.
Speaker 1: You've
Speaker 0: got the leading edge and then you've got the like early hump and then you've got the big hump when like a lot of People use it and then the trailing line of you know Dads and uncles and people who watch Fox News are using it and then there's you know The end run which is like great-grandpa finds out about it because the grandson showed him something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and We're at the big hump now and as a result, it seems like the stories on dig are a snapshot of just a Lot of really stupid people to put it really bluntly and I feel bad saying that.
Speaker 0: but at the same time most of the stories on diggers sensationalist crap.
Speaker 0: or they're outright wrong or they're old or there's like eight stories that are identical and the same people dig everything up and It's like dig isn't selecting interesting content for me any better than say Random searches of Google News did a year ago monkeys with typewriters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically Google dig is not working for me anymore.
Speaker 1: You no longer solves the problem at once sort of solved and I am headed towards Hopefully greener pastures, even if they might take a little bit more effort on my part.
Speaker 0: I think our greener pastures is to make our own thing.
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe but for now, it's Basically RSS feeds of all sorts of things and hopefully I can find Interesting people would do delicious things often and get their feeds from their.
Speaker 1: delicious is Right.
Speaker 0: So there's the story on slashdot from Bruce Schneier's blog.
Speaker 1: Bruce Schneier is the expert on security They and that is the expert on security period.
Speaker 0: now I didn't get a chance to read the article, but I think the discussion it brings up is more interesting.
Speaker 0: it's called everyday copyright violations and It seems to according to the summary.
Speaker 0: I read kind of talk about the idea that Copyrights are so complicated and so just kind of out of touch with the reality of the world in general.
Speaker 0: Just the way the laws work that in the course of a day an average person especially on the internet Will violate and just just illegally violate countless copyrights all the time Even doing things that they wouldn't even think are illegal wouldn't?
Speaker 0: it's not even like oh I stole this music But just little basic things.
Speaker 0: I mean people forget the idea that if you ever write anything It's copyrighted immediately whether you show anyone in the world or not.
Speaker 0: If I write like a little tiny half of a story in an email to Scott Theoretically Scott can't just republish that without citing me.
Speaker 0: He can't just take that and finish the story and then publish it on his own because I have the copyright I can't even like forward it to someone else.
Speaker 0: technically there's all sorts of rules about this and I think the gist of it is that Copyright law needs to change to deal with the fact that information travels a lot faster now than it used to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not even talking about piracy here.
Speaker 1: we are talking about.
Speaker 1: you know, this is sort of like, you know that there's all sorts of those crazy laws that you read about like Can't do can't you know?
Speaker 1: have this certain kind of animal in the town square on a Thursday and you read and you go Oh, that's so funny that they have all these wacky laws.
Speaker 1: You know from way back when or for whatever crazy reason or maybe someone's just pulling a joke in the town council, right?
Speaker 1: But copyright law is sort of become a joke law.
Speaker 1: It is impossible to live and to operate within modern society without violating this law numerous times a day and it did.
Speaker 1: law is just that Silly and crazy and this is really the fundamental problem.
Speaker 1: Forget about your piracy's and your music industry business model.
Speaker 1: this and that We had.
Speaker 1: the laws that are behind this stuff.
Speaker 1: No matter what else you want to say about them are Fundamentally broken in a million different ways and I don't really see much of a solution besides Throwing them all out and starting again now.
Speaker 0: it doesn't mean we have to give up the idea of giving content creators some control over their creations or some ability to Make profit or anything like that.
Speaker 0: It just means that the laws as they stand even if you agree with what they're trying to do Can't really work because the way they are written is not good.
Speaker 0: We're in the same situation.
Speaker 0: we are with speeding in a car in the US.
Speaker 0: where go to any average freeway in the United States and 90% of the cars are speed.
Speaker 0: speed limit is 55 or 65. unless you live somewhere sane like Michigan or Arizona where it's 75 or 80 and You know speed limits 55 to go faster than that is to break the law.
Speaker 0: Yet when I get on that road, the slowest car is going like 80 Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: and it's actually unsafe for me to go less than the average speed and as a result Everyone's speeding and I'll pass a cop.
Speaker 0: I'm going 85 speed limits 55.
Speaker 0: Everyone's going 85. cop doesn't care.
Speaker 0: but theoretically if he wanted to he could just pull out into the road Drive at the speed of everyone else.
Speaker 0: Just pick a random guy for whatever reason decide.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna give him the gigantic ticket.
Speaker 1: I Want to make money for the state cuz that's my job or just I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm bored.
Speaker 0: Anytime there's a situation where People are breaking a law and they don't feel that they're breaking a law or a lot of people are breaking a law.
Speaker 0: You really have to examine the law.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying or a law is unenforceable.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying get rid of the law.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying give up on the idea of speed limits issue
Speaker 1: of whether copyright is is a good idea or a bad idea We're not even talking about that right now or that's not even an issue
Speaker 0: because I think Speed limits are a good idea Except when a speed limit is set so low compared to what people actually drive That you've effectively criminalized everyone on the road thus giving you the excuse to pull over anyone you want in any time.
Speaker 1: but Regardless the point is the way the law is written is just crazy and it's impossible Not to break the law.
Speaker 1: if you have a law that is impossible not to break like don't?
Speaker 1: we had a law don't breathe.
Speaker 1: That's sort of like the copyright law right now basically says Don't do anything.
Speaker 0: I mean it makes it illegal to do things that shouldn't be illegal.
Speaker 0: And like I said, we're not talking about stealing people's music.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about really really basic things.
Speaker 0: Oh, I just noticed here.
Speaker 0: All right, this is another thing.
Speaker 0: I don't like about the internet lately.
Speaker 0: I guess it's not lately, but all right slash shot everyday copyright violations.
Speaker 0: schnayers pointed out this stuff.
Speaker 0: go to schnayers blog.
Speaker 0: Oh He didn't actually write this.
Speaker 0: He just pointed at this article by John terrain Ian.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh Well, I trust anything schnayer points at anyway, so I do.
Speaker 1: that link sort of gives it an element of trust.
Speaker 0: It does but at the same time I feel like they could have just linked directly to the original article.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that that would have been nice too.
Speaker 0: But at the same I mean, it's not like.
Speaker 0: schnayer even adds much commentary.
Speaker 0: He says quotes.
Speaker 0: I think this is the extent of what he said.
Speaker 0: The point of the article is how simply by acting normally all of us are technically lawbreakers many times over every day.
Speaker 0: When laws are this far outside the social norms, it's time to change them.
Speaker 0: So if you listen to us talking about this you have listened to me and Scott talk about an article on slash shot.
Speaker 0: that talks about an article on Bruce schnayers blog.
Speaker 0: that Talks about an article written by a man named John terrain Ian things of the day.
Speaker 1: So I've been having problems lately is that I want to listen to more of my music.
Speaker 1: but I've got like 10,000 musics and and a lot of its unsorted.
Speaker 0: Scott Yeah, stay on top of it.
Speaker 0: Like the rim did?
Speaker 1: you didn't stay on top of it?
Speaker 1: You just had about you all your unsorted music deleted on a lot of hard drive that died.
Speaker 0: The thing is that the unsorted music that got deleted was less than a gigabyte.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the answer my unsorted music is about half.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and my sorted music is sorted in a way.
Speaker 1: I don't like.
Speaker 1: I want it sorted in a better way.
Speaker 1: So it's really just no good all around.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I was looking around for you know, pretty much every solution to this problem I know about.
Speaker 1: there isn't anything.
Speaker 1: I didn't know But I did discover something just now that's maybe has a use.
Speaker 1: It doesn't seem to fit my bill exactly, but it might have a use for someone else.
Speaker 1: It's called gin Zora Gin Zora and what this does is you get yourself MySQL or some sort of database?
Speaker 1: And you get yourself a web server Right a little Apache or a lighty or something and on that same computer or at least, you know accessible by that computer you have your music.
Speaker 1: so you set this up and What you've let's say I got all my music and the web server on the same computer all right, and it's on my local network and Someone comes into that into my house with a laptop and they open up their laptop and they connect to my wireless and they open up a web browser they type in the name of that computer that has all the music and the web server and they're presented with this web interface that allows them to search through the music and if I want to I can even let them play the music and if I want to I can even set it up where that computer is playing the music and they can change which music the computer is playing like some sort of jukebox and For many people I imagine this would be quite useful.
Speaker 1: for me not useful But for other people I could see this happening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm still just kind of holding out.
Speaker 0: I think if those rumors of 13-inch MacBook Pros are true, which you know, there's no way to tell.
Speaker 0: I ignore rumors But if they're true, I'll probably just buy that and then use iTunes.
Speaker 1: Yeah I tried over the weekend to import all my music from my computer through a Samba share to iTunes and it Mostly kinda sort of worked.
Speaker 1: But it still doesn't solve any of my problems except for now I can get music onto my iPod if I bother to sift through 10,000 tracks and pick out music.
Speaker 1: or I guess I might have to start making some sort of dynamic smart playlists something.
Speaker 1: but even those won't work perfectly because the Information up on them the ID threes and stuff is not complete.
Speaker 1: So see and if any failed to download the album artwork Like I said get album artwork and it got a few thousand album artworks and then it sort of hangs It doesn't get anymore.
Speaker 0: See I tell it not to do those things because it just kind of it always seems to slow things down and cause problems.
Speaker 1: So I wanted to get the album artworks.
Speaker 1: part of the coolness of of using an iPod or whatever.
Speaker 1: is you get the album?
Speaker 1: Artworks there so you can more easily get a you know A visual cue as to what the hell you're listening to and you can also go in the cover view and sort of you know Quickly scan through all the covers and they'll be like, ah, that's what I want.
Speaker 1: It's a lot faster than reading all that text looking for a name Even though you can search for the name with the search box in the top, right?
Speaker 1: Sometimes I might forget the name and remember the image especially since I got 10,000 music tracks And I only remember so many of them.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm lucky in one regard that just because of the way I organize my music I really just use the file system and to this like I while I may not have listened to all of it recently I might not remember a specific song.
Speaker 0: if I have any piece of music I have I could find pretty much immediately because I know where it would be.
Speaker 0: I have music I don't even know I have well see here's the thing I will not if I download music if I don't listen to it within a reasonable span of time.
Speaker 0: I just delete it because I obviously didn't want it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Music I do want it's just I don't know I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't know I want it because I don't even have time to listen to it.
Speaker 0: Well, see I only get things that I already know I want and I find out I want these things from games like guitar hero.
Speaker 1: Here's an example, right?
Speaker 1: I knew I wanted some buckethead.
Speaker 1: So I downloaded every buckethead album there.
Speaker 0: I did that with muck, right?
Speaker 1: So now I haven't listened to all that I don't even and some of it I don't even like.
Speaker 1: but what do I do?
Speaker 1: I got like these 30 albums.
Speaker 1: Some of them aren't even albums.
Speaker 1: Some of them are like some guy cobbled together some live tracks bootleg from a concert.
Speaker 1: Another thing is like some cobbling of a foreign single.
Speaker 0: Honestly, I tend to.
Speaker 0: I've decided at this point that it's so easy to get music that I'll go for quality over quantity and if I can't easily categorize or if I just don't think I like or anything I'll just delete it and forget about it.
Speaker 0: now worry about it.
Speaker 1: So I've already downloaded it and download it again is is more work.
Speaker 0: I probably won't download it again because there's so much music out there that if I miss one or two good songs or even good Albums here and there I've still got more to listen to than I have time to listen.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: the thing is I really I really because the the fact that my music is such in a state of disarray is Preventing me from listening to any of it because it's so difficult to get any to listen to right and
Speaker 0: I can't make fun of You because the only solution
Speaker 1: it's like if it was sorted I could listen to it very easily.
Speaker 1: well, the only solution really was either we need AI that'll just do it or It's like hey, I was trying to use music brains Which is the closest we have to AI.
Speaker 1: that will just do it and it works for the most part but it still requires a lot of manual labor on my part and Even then it screws up a lot of things and I end up with a lot of files that just have a crazy Batshit names because music brain screwed up.
Speaker 0: the solution Sadly is for the last decade to have constantly kept up with your music collection.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I basically I can go through and sort it all out You know back in time and tell yourself to organize your.
Speaker 0: goddamn you.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem is I sort of got a whole bunch of too much at once.
Speaker 1: You see that was the thing It's like.
Speaker 1: even I was keeping up.
Speaker 1: so, you know, I got like two gigs at once.
Speaker 0: You know what saved me right when I had the urge to download Infinite music before that urge went away and now I only download what I like again.
Speaker 0: I had the old computer and I couldn't put more hard drives in it and I was afraid to turn it off or open it Because it might break.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had bit torrent.
Speaker 1: I was at RIT and I had plenty hard drives.
Speaker 1: face.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I left our dangerous combination.
Speaker 0: I went for that like half a year with no internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that sabbatical from the internet is what.
Speaker 1: that was the time when I got all the music.
Speaker 0: That was the time when I organized everything I had left.
Speaker 1: that wasn't organized Yeah, and the other thing is I would sit down and just organize it all.
Speaker 1: but I feel like there are other things I want to do like podcast and You know make programs and learn things and then reads books and then play video games and Feel like sorting the music is way low on my list of priorities.
Speaker 1: So it's like not gonna get done and it's only gonna get worse.
Speaker 1: But what do I do?
Speaker 1: I guess I could pay someone to sort it all out.
Speaker 1: But then would they do it right?
Speaker 1: would they do it the way I want would they?
Speaker 1: It's so bad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, see a Jin Zora is my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So if anyone is wants to like let you can let everyone who comes into your house Listen to all your music on their laptops.
Speaker 1: Or you can have some sort of computer plugged into a stereo and let people in your house with computers Connect to that and then sort of change the music.
Speaker 1: or you can just you know, do it for yourself.
Speaker 1: You know if you have a computer plugged into a stereo you go upstairs You might want to change the song.
Speaker 1: you can do it from any computer in the house Just poop or even like from your phone if it has a wireless.
Speaker 1: or maybe you have one of those Nokia sort of tablet II things and it's got the wireless.
Speaker 1: If it's got a web browser and it can connect to your local network and connect to the computer running the Jin Zora You can control it.
Speaker 0: So so in the spirit of dig I decided that I would just go to the front page of dig and pick the best thing there in the videos.
Speaker 0: Wow and See cuz I remember back when I used dig in the early days I'd go to dig videos and easily two-thirds of the things there were cool.
Speaker 0: And now I'm looking through and Pretty much the choice was between a kangaroo playing with itself And a video that I've not only already seen but has already been a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Which video is that?
Speaker 0: the one about the guy paragliding?
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, anyway Kangaroo plays with himself while man is interviewed is the win.
Speaker 0: and it is Exactly that it is a kangaroo playing with himself while a man is interviewed.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a himself kangaroo not a herself kangaroo.
Speaker 0: He's using the motion that I think is universal among males that have digits.
Speaker 0: All right It's kind of funny.
Speaker 0: I'll give it that but I've already seen many videos of animals masturbating while once you've seen a monkey It's what else is there to say?
Speaker 0: or that one cat or that one?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that one.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right rocket.
Speaker 0: So tonight we're going to finish our two-part series on.
Speaker 1: It's not really on Google as much as it is on sort of like The history of search engines or like the web and searching and how it's changed and whatever.
Speaker 0: so where we left off Google had appeared and Pretty much anyone smart used it realized that it was better than every other search engine in the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah started using the web had been around for years.
Speaker 1: people were using the web But people had a hard time using the web seriously because all the search engines were shit.
Speaker 1: I mean, I actually remembered today that there were sites like, you know, I get what was it called before?
Speaker 1: It was called about calm.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember everything - or was that something else?
Speaker 1: No, everything - is something else.
Speaker 0: I'm looking it up right now actually because I honestly really never use those sites though I used to have a little cool plug anything Where I could like right-click on a word and it would tell me stuff about that word.
Speaker 0: But then that turned into spyware.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it was mining Co.
Speaker 1: Mining Co was the website.
Speaker 0: I never used that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the the logic behind mining Co which became which is now about calm sounds very cute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: It's sort of funny.
Speaker 1: It's like you think dig mining Co.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that site which is now about calm and I'm attempts I'm gonna say it.
Speaker 1: originally the idea behind that site was there would be different pages about different things.
Speaker 1: So you would go to say the video game site and there would be a guy who was the video game guy And you'd see his face at the top with some.
Speaker 1: you know his name and he Manually managed all the content at that site and it was back in the day.
Speaker 1: This is worthwhile because Searching sucked.
Speaker 1: So you'd go to mining Co and you would say I want to know about Fishing and there would be a page with a guy who was a fisherman who knew about fishing and he would make all these Pages and content about fishing and that's what would be.
Speaker 0: you know I almost wonder if in the long run before we have good AI or you know web 3.0 the semantic web if We'll go back to that sort of thing Where the only way to really really get good interesting content that you want is to find other people you trust or?
Speaker 0: Authorities and just go everywhere.
Speaker 0: They point you.
Speaker 1: Well, you can go to about calm if that's what you're looking for Or you can just come to me.
Speaker 0: I'll point you in the direction.
Speaker 1: All right, anyway, yeah But the internet the web at least was was pretty not so good at finding the information you wanted when you wanted it.
Speaker 1: it was sort of just like you would go and click on links and go from place to place in search of entertainment and Mostly misguided.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly entertainment - I mean back then they really were trying to sell to parents and people like Yeah The internet where you can do all your research and everything.
Speaker 0: all those other ways to do in research obsolete as basically impossible.
Speaker 0: You couldn't do research for dick on the internet back then.
Speaker 0: you couldn't find anything worthwhile or Citable or is it?
Speaker 1: you could but it's just extremely difficult.
Speaker 1: You were better off going to the library and I still went to the library in those days.
Speaker 1: I did too.
Speaker 0: In fact, I still used a card catalog.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then Google came around and everything changed because Google unlike previous search engines was actually useful and If you wanted to know something or you wanted to find a page about something you could type in what you wanted into Google without having to type a bunch of complicated shit and What you wanted would very likely be on the front page and as time went on it only got better.
Speaker 0: So where did Google come from?
Speaker 0: How did it?
Speaker 0: where did you just appear from?
Speaker 0: because it kind of at least to people who didn't already know about it just appeared Out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: I mean like I said on the last show I mean I was using Yahoo, which is the best at the time
Speaker 0: I use Yahoo and if Yahoo didn't find it I used Lycos Yeah,
Speaker 1: and at the bottom of the page it said, you know after a time I mean originally Yahoo was powered by Yahoo and then it was powered by something else And then it said Yahoo powered by Google and after a while I eventually just clicked on the Google and it took me to Google and I started using that and I realized it gave me the Same search results only better.
Speaker 0: So Google as it were was founded by two men Sergei Brin and Larry Page.
Speaker 1: You probably know that already.
Speaker 0: Yeah a long long time ago less than ten years ago I think they were incorporated in 1998 Yeah.
Speaker 0: And there were students at Stanford University and if you want to know more just read the Wikipedia because I don't think you really want Boring history lesson, but it is interesting to note the name of Google.
Speaker 0: I mean now it's kind of synonymous with searching.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot, you know how people say Oh, well the name will be diluted like Kleenex Kleenex kind of D branded and became a generic term for a lot of band-aid and scotch tape.
Speaker 0: and yeah, but Google I mean the way when people say like oh I Google something.
Speaker 0: Google used to really worry about that because you know People are using the word Google to mean search on the internet.
Speaker 0: that will Invalidate our trademark over time.
Speaker 0: No when people say to Google something They mean very literally to use Google to search for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah pretty much.
Speaker 1: But also it's generally can say at least as far as I see it It's considered a good thing when your brand name becomes, you know an actual regularly used word I mean like, you know, it could.
Speaker 1: I think the the calling, you know, I mean nowadays We don't people don't say Xerox so much anymore.
Speaker 1: But you know when people call when people were photocopying and say you sang Xerox as into photocopy I think that sold Xerox a lot of copiers.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling it also sells band-aid a lot of band-aids.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure band-aid sells.
Speaker 1: a brand-aid brand sells more than the other brands.
Speaker 0: All right, you know what?
Speaker 0: because all the information is right here.
Speaker 0: I am gonna just gonna read a paragraph or two from Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: So if anything here is wrong and it looks like it's all right as far as I can tell This doesn't get it all out of the way.
Speaker 0: to paraphrase and quote Wikipedia Google began in January 1996 as a research project by Larry Page and Sergey Brin to PhD students at Stanford University.
Speaker 0: They hypothesized that a search engine that analyzed the relationship between websites could produce better results than existing techniques Which ranked results according to the number of times a search engine appeared on the page?
Speaker 0: Their search engine was originally nicknamed back rub because the system Back links to estimate a site's importance.
Speaker 0: a small search engine called rank decks was already exploring a similar strategy convinced that the pages with the most links to them were Paraphrase paraphrase more relevant.
Speaker 0: They tested their thesis as part of their studies laid out the foundation for the search engine.
Speaker 0: Originally, it was used that they used the Stanford University website with the domain Google.stanford.edu.
Speaker 0: the domain google.com was registered in September of 1997.
Speaker 0: They incorporated in September of 1998 at a friend's garage in Menlo Park, California where everything awesome happens And then they IPO'd sometime later.
Speaker 0: They originally wanted to call it Google, you know, Google with an O as per the number But someone else already had that name and wouldn't give it up.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh and everything else really doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, the point is is that the way Google worked is you know back in the day?
Speaker 1: You would search your video games and the page that would show up at the top of say AltaVista would be the web page that said video games video games video games video games video games video games video games.
Speaker 1: When you searched on Google for video games It would find it a website that happened to have the word video games on it And it would find the website that had the most links to it.
Speaker 1: So if let's say a hundred people were linking to my website about video games and a thousand people linked to rim sites about video games Rim site would show up first and my site would show up next.
Speaker 1: So the idea was that if a site had more people linking to it, it would be a more popular website, and people don't link to websites that are, you know, video games, video games, video games, video games, video games.
Speaker 1: They link to real websites, and the more people link to something, the more people think that site is useful.
Speaker 1: Therefore, Google, in its early days, before anyone was trying to game the system, worked wonderfully.
Speaker 1: You would type in "video games," and the most popular video game site in the world would be right at the top, and that would be what you were looking for, and there weren't so many websites, so that was probably exactly what you wanted, every time.
Speaker 0: Another thing that really made Google stand out back then was that they have, and to this day, they claim to still have it.
Speaker 0: It's probably a little different internally now that they're a publicly held company, but their motto has always been, "Don't be
Speaker 0: evil.".
Speaker 1: Do no evil?
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: So a lot of other search engines, think about it.
Speaker 0: I control the search engine.
Speaker 0: I can do whatever I want, put whatever sites I want in it by whatever means I want, and other people, especially people who want to make money, really care if they show up as number one or number a thousand.
Speaker 0: What if I just offered, kind of semi-secretly, where people could buy the number one or the number five spot in my search engine?
Speaker 0: I remember,
Speaker 1: in fact, a search engine that was around back in the day, way back in the late 90s, that specifically advertised the fact that, "Hey, we are a search engine where you pay to get in the
Speaker 1: search."
Speaker 1: And it was, "Whoever pays the most gets to the top for a specific term, and this way, we'll have the best results, because the only people who will pay will be in there, and as we know, they're real sites.
Speaker 1: They're not around
Speaker 1: anymore.".
Speaker 0: But Google never did that, and if they somehow did, which is highly unlikely, it never affected the content of the site, because consistently, the number one thing or the number two thing was exactly what I wanted.
Speaker 0: And it wasn't video games, video games, video games.
Speaker 1: Google does a lot of things, and some people argue, they say they are doing evil, you know, such as with their China business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Google, the least evil.
Speaker 0: Look at what Yahoo's been doing in China.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Google, you know, the privacy stuff is not perfect, but you could argue whether Google has done no evil or some evil, but it's kind of hard to argue that Google's done a lot evil.
Speaker 1: They have done less evil than every other company of that size ever.
Speaker 0: Considering that both myself and Scott, who are relatively paranoid in the world of protecting our data and just technology in general, I trust Google with a lot of my personal information, and Google can read all of my email.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at the same time, though, personally, I kind of do worry about it more than, I guess, not at all.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand, it's sort of like eggs are already in the basket situation, where it's like, "Well, they already can fuck me, so why not?
Speaker 1: If I give them more information, it's not going to make a
Speaker 1: difference.".
Speaker 0: I trust Google enough to give them all this data.
Speaker 0: I don't trust them totally.
Speaker 0: I trust very few things in the world completely.
Speaker 0: But I trust Google enough to handle almost all of my personal communication.
Speaker 0: And I trust them enough with the ability to read every email I ever send and every document I ever write, for the most part.
Speaker 0: And I guess one reason is, I'm not arguing this at all, but personally, the worst thing Google could ever do to me is tell the truth about me.
Speaker 0: And I'm not really ashamed of anything I've written, so I'm not going to make the, "Well, if you haven't done anything wrong, then you've got nothing to worry about" argument.
Speaker 0: But I will make the argument that there's nothing Google could do to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, me either.
Speaker 1: I'm not worried.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess they could take all my money.
Speaker 0: They could.
Speaker 0: They could publish my credit card numbers.
Speaker 1: They could just go to my bank website and take my money out.
Speaker 0: They could put all my email up, and then they could publish my address and probably my work schedule.
Speaker 0: And it wouldn't be that out of the realm for them to publish How to Get a Key to My House.
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 1: Regardless, in general, Google search itself, you know, not the ad words or anything like that, but they have always and consistently throughout their almost 10-year history done everything in their power to keep that search being the best search for people who are searching for information, and better than every other search engine I've ever used, and it still is that way.
Speaker 1: If you want to find something on the internet, you type it into Google.
Speaker 1: Odds are you're going to find it.
Speaker 1: You're not going to find dead links so much, you know, very often.
Speaker 1: You're not going to find bad stories very often.
Speaker 1: The vast majority of the time, you're going to find the best link.
Speaker 1: In fact, someone did a study where what they did is they, you know, they gave people sets of search results, right, without telling them which search engine the search results were from.
Speaker 0: I would bet a lot of money that I could tell what search engine, as in Google or not Google.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And they told them what the search term was, and the people decided which set of search results were the best.
Speaker 1: And Google won about half the time.
Speaker 1: So for every search engine, all the major search engines, Google was the best half the time.
Speaker 1: That's a lot.
Speaker 1: One beating all the others half the time.
Speaker 1: That's damn good.
Speaker 0: Now we could talk about how Google makes money and ad words and AdSense and all that, but I think like that sort of thing could be a separate show altogether.
Speaker 0: I don't want to go too long.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about how Google made the Web useful and how it changes the way we use the Web.
Speaker 0: And I mean, if we just go along that tack, Google made effectively the best searching that exists right now.
Speaker 0: And it's not perfect, but nothing's perfect.
Speaker 0: It's far and away clearly the best search engine out there, at least in the English speaking world.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But think about this, right?
Speaker 1: The Web right before Google was just a mess of stuff.
Speaker 1: It wasn't really that useful or anything like that.
Speaker 1: And regardless of what Google's trying to do for itself, for the Web as a whole, they've made it useful.
Speaker 1: I mean, you couldn't have no dig without Google because who would find a thing to post a dig?
Speaker 1: You couldn't have Wikipedia without Google because who could search to do the research to write the Wikipedia article to find the sources to link to in the Wikipedia article?
Speaker 1: None of these things that we have on the Web today that we sort of take for granted that are separate from Google entirely.
Speaker 1: You don't realize they depend on Google.
Speaker 1: If we didn't have Google, you wouldn't have any of this shit.
Speaker 1: You had nothing.
Speaker 1: The Web would just be this useless mess without a search engine backing it up.
Speaker 1: It'd be like going to the library without a card catalog or with a card catalog that was messed up and half of it was wrong.
Speaker 1: How would you deal with that?
Speaker 1: The library would be useless.
Speaker 1: You couldn't find the book you wanted unless you were crazy and looked through every shelf.
Speaker 0: This isn't just a let's filet Google session because it could have been anyone.
Speaker 0: It's not so much that Google, Google, Google.
Speaker 0: It's that someone, anyone made a search engine that was good enough to allow everything we wanted to happen happen.
Speaker 1: Google just happened to be that search engine.
Speaker 1: It could have been any search.
Speaker 1: It could have been more than one search engine at once.
Speaker 1: It could have those what he said, those wrecks people, whatever they could have.
Speaker 1: They could have come out with their thing just as well because they were thinking along the same lines.
Speaker 1: There could have been two competing search engines that were just as good.
Speaker 1: And then who knows what happened?
Speaker 0: Actually, it might have been even better if that had happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the point is, is that someone made a search engine that actually worked, thus changing everything.
Speaker 1: And we would be way back in the gutter if no one had done it.
Speaker 1: And Google just happened to be the ones who did it.
Speaker 0: So beyond searching, where is Google going?
Speaker 0: I don't want to do a lot about this because, again, that could be like the third part if we wanted to do it.
Speaker 0: You know what we use Google for.
Speaker 0: But Google has been going in a lot of directions.
Speaker 0: They have Google Maps, which gives awful directions.
Speaker 0: But in terms of looking at a map is probably the best thing out there, hands down.
Speaker 1: And also is really good at telling you what businesses are nearby.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: And Google Docs, I always kind of mistrusted any sort of web based application for a long time.
Speaker 0: But Google made one good enough to where I use Google Docs for almost everything I write.
Speaker 0: Except for, you know, VI stuff.
Speaker 1: But mostly because after leaving, you know, college, I use a lot less, you know, word office app.
Speaker 1: I don't really use.
Speaker 1: I could live without any open office or M.S.
Speaker 1: office.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not writing papers like I used to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not writing papers.
Speaker 1: I deal with one spreadsheet a month.
Speaker 1: And the only reason I don't deal with that spreadsheet in Google spreadsheet is because it's too big for Google spreadsheet to handle.
Speaker 1: So I use numeric.
Speaker 1: But other than that, I don't word process anything.
Speaker 1: If I do, it's like a blog entry.
Speaker 1: I do it in a text editor in the blog editor.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, so I don't really need an office application that's big and slow.
Speaker 1: Google Docs does more than what I need.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And there it is.
Speaker 1: And it allows me to share things I make with other people easily, especially if they're all.
Speaker 1: And most of the people I want to share with are also using Google Docs and Gmail, making it really easy.
Speaker 0: I think that's the big thing right now that Google is offering to us is just this online collaboration is so easy now because, I mean, one, we have our Google for domain.
Speaker 0: So, you know, all our front row crew is actually Google behind the scenes.
Speaker 1: If you email us geeknight@frontrowecrew.com, I actually go to mail.frontrowecrew.com, which is Gmail, and I log in there and it's Gmail.
Speaker 0: But I can collaborate and share my calendars and my documents and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: And I can schedule things.
Speaker 0: And I use Google calendars a lot.
Speaker 0: And I used to never bother with calendars.
Speaker 1: I didn't use a calendar anything.
Speaker 1: Like I kept trying to use different calendars and I never stuck with one.
Speaker 1: But Google calendar I actually use.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 1: I use Google Reader for my RSS.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, Google, if you really look at their business, they're sort of unsuccessful at everything except for their search engine and Gmail.
Speaker 1: They try a lot of other stuff, and most of it is just sort of they're trying stuff and it's not working out so well.
Speaker 1: The maps is kind of working out.
Speaker 0: But if you look at it from a business perspective, the only thing that works is the fact that they sell text ads and they make a lot of money off of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's really it.
Speaker 1: Google tries to do a lot of things.
Speaker 1: They're doing more and more things every day, like they're doing this Android cell phone thing and they're doing all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: And none of it really works from the business perspective.
Speaker 1: But what ends up happening is they do make a lot of stuff that is useful for people and it makes lives better on the net and no one else really.
Speaker 1: Maybe because Google just has the resources and has the manpower and the brains and all that stuff to pull it off and no one else can really compete.
Speaker 1: But they just happen to be the company that makes all these things that make the web more and more useful.
Speaker 1: They took the web from shit and they turned it into gold and they're slowly polishing that gold and perhaps making some platinum, too.
Speaker 1: And other people are helping, like Wikipedia did a lot to help out and some other people and YouTube.
Speaker 1: But Google owns YouTube now.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, you know, there are a lot of people who are Google detractors, a lot of people who really, really hate Google or complain about Google all the time.
Speaker 0: And all I really have to say is that a lot of these people seem to not really understand it.
Speaker 0: Or more importantly, Google does not serve their purposes and their purposes nine times out of ten are contrary to the desires of the majority of people on the Internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: And I mean, most of the people who complain about Google say, ah, Google fucked me in my SEO scheme or Google knocked my page rank down and now I can't sell my ads.
Speaker 0: But think about it.
Speaker 0: That hurts you.
Speaker 0: But for most of the people who are using Google, you know that the people like us, from a pure consumer perspective, that does nothing but make Google better.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you're trying to get your stuff up on Google, that's you know, if I search for something related to what your page is about on Google and I get results and I'm happy with those results and your page is not a part of those results, Google's doing a good job.
Speaker 1: And it's very likely that your page is at least no better than it's probably worse than the result I got.
Speaker 1: So just because you're upset because you're not, you know, less people are visiting your site from Google.
Speaker 1: Well, the people who are searching for stuff are happier because they're not finding your shit and it's better for us.
Speaker 1: And if you want to if you are want to change Google to benefit yourself, you're basically saying is you have no problem making the Web worse for everyone else, making it more like it was in the late 90s and making it shittier and less useful.
Speaker 1: You're basically saying that's like saying that you should go into the card catalog in the library and replace, you know, get rid of all the cards that talk about, you know, podcasts and only put in one card for podcasts as geek nights.
Speaker 1: And you'd be happy with that, even though it makes the library shittier for all the actually looking for books about podcasts.
Speaker 0: Now, if it weren't Google, like let's say suddenly Microsoft search started giving me better results than Google.
Speaker 0: But let's say it happened.
Speaker 1: Let's say it did happen.
Speaker 0: The technological people like myself and Scott and people we would we even know as much as I love Google, it's only because they do me good.
Speaker 0: And if Microsoft were better tomorrow, I would be using MSN search tomorrow immediately without any looking back.
Speaker 1: It's not just the quality of the results, though.
Speaker 1: It's also the interface, the speed of the results.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's other factors.
Speaker 0: MSN or Yahoo or anything became better.
Speaker 0: I would not hesitate to use them immediately and without any sort of qualms.
Speaker 1: No, but see, actually, the thing is, is like even if they became better, it's like I'd have to find out that they were better.
Speaker 1: And the only way I would find out that they were better is if Google started sucking to where it was no longer serving my purposes.
Speaker 1: Like as long as Google kept doing the job, I'm already using it and sort of the momentum of using it.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't move away.
Speaker 1: You know, I'd only move away and like go check.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't even check Yahoo or MSN to see if they were good unless Google didn't live up to the task.
Speaker 0: Well, see, that that is the inherent interesting issue of kind of the low ceiling and that all right, I'm searching for sandwiches on how to make a peanut butter and jelly sandwich.
Speaker 0: Let's say Yahoo gives you five good sites that PB&Js and two of them are SEO crap.
Speaker 0: And MSN gives me four good pages.
Speaker 0: And the fifth one is SEO crap.
Speaker 0: And Google gives me four good ones.
Speaker 0: And the last one is just.
Speaker 0: it's about like people having sex with peanut butter and jelly sandwiches, which isn't exactly what I wanted, maybe.
Speaker 0: But in that case, it doesn't matter what search engine I use, because if any one of those things I clicked on told me how to make a peanut butter and jelly sandwich and it was good enough, I succeeded.
Speaker 0: And I don't care what I used.
Speaker 0: I only care about the results.
Speaker 0: And Google just has the best odds of giving me good results right now.
Speaker 0: And it would take a lot for Google if Google would have to not give us enough to do what we want for us to switch by us.
Speaker 0: I mean, pretty much anyone.
Speaker 1: Back in those late 90s days, I would search for something on one search engine, not find it, go search on another search engine, maybe find something a little better search on different search engine.
Speaker 1: They'd all completely different results nowadays and search on search different search engines.
Speaker 1: It's not even something I would think of.
Speaker 1: I mean, I search on one search engine and either find it or I don't.
Speaker 1: And if I don't find it, it's probably ludicrously difficult to find and switching search engines.
Speaker 1: I mean, I might try something else, but that's really not going to help.
Speaker 1: I, you know, I generally refine my terms and then I get what I want.
Speaker 0: And I've never in recent memory searched for something on Google, not found it and then found it from another source at any point in the future.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just and I really if I can't find it on Google, I feel like it's not worth finding.
Speaker 1: The only time I can't find it is if I'm looking for like I remember a specific page and I'm trying to find a specific page again and I forgot to bookmark it or delicious it or whatever.
Speaker 1: That's the time when Google can fail me and it becomes pretty hard.
Speaker 1: It's like go and find, you know, the blog or whatever that I found the thing on and then search on that blog, usually with Google.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share-a-like 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.