Speaker 1: It's Wednesday March 21st.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek night.
Speaker 1: tonight We review one of our favorite anime ever.
Speaker 1: here is Greenwood.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Damn you Netflix.
Speaker 1: damn you See we have this love-hate relationship with Netflix Which started as pure love and the hates really kind of new because this is a recent development that only seems to occur with ghosts in the fucking shell.
Speaker 0: oh I think it occurs with some other things.
Speaker 0: it's happened to us before But it's happened with ghost in the shell a whole bunch of times.
Speaker 1: well in general I've noticed that we use Netflix a lot, and we've alternated between spending most of our Netflix's on South Park We missed or Simpsons or Futurama and for a while.
Speaker 1: We watched a bunch of movies.
Speaker 0: It seems like a higher percentage of anime DVDs are scratched up cracked or broken than any other kind of DVD we get Pretty much, I mean usually what happens is we'll put an anime DVD in and it'll work and then eventually it'll get to a scratch Part.
Speaker 0: we'll take it out and look at it and go shit.
Speaker 0: today when I put well yesterday when I took the ghost in the Shell DVD out of the little you know Netflix slip case the edge of it Like for about I'd say a quarter to a half inch of the disc.
Speaker 0: in one spot It looked like I don't know someone stabbed that part with a knife or something.
Speaker 0: It's ripped in two, but since it was near the edge of the disc That's the last part of the DVD.
Speaker 0: so maybe that's just the extras.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's just the last episode.
Speaker 1: see the thing is while we reported it to Netflix.
Speaker 1: We're gonna get our new DVD.
Speaker 1: They always send it right away even though.
Speaker 1: I forgot to report it yesterday, so I'm gonna report it after this.
Speaker 1: But we couldn't risk.
Speaker 1: we had to watch at least an episode because the last DVD ended on this crazy cliffhanger.
Speaker 1: We're about to stand in there with one of the bad guys TM.
Speaker 1: He's got a gun named at his face.
Speaker 0: Yeah, is it the DVDs?
Speaker 0: they seem to be doing a pretty good job of making the last episode on the DVD a crazy cliffhanger.
Speaker 1: It's always Episode that has nothing to do with the plot episode.
Speaker 1: that has nothing to do with the plot episode.
Speaker 1: That's pretty interesting Episode that ends on a crazy cliffhanger.
Speaker 1: So then you ah and you wait for the next DVD.
Speaker 1: you get the next DVD and you gotta watch a bunch of episodes to Get any sort of resolution.
Speaker 0: It's good though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's real good real good.
Speaker 1: I gotta say I really want to talk about standalone complex second gig.
Speaker 1: so much we finish it finish it.
Speaker 1: We're probably gonna review it pretty quick Pretty much that week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah, but yeah, I'm wondering if maybe though anime fans are less careful with DVDs.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a higher percentage of punk kids with Netflix is getting anime.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what it is.
Speaker 0: I remember that when the anime club got DVDs they made everyone before.
Speaker 0: they cuz you know VHS is they can rent them out.
Speaker 0: Crazily they don't care.
Speaker 0: Well, what are you gonna do to a VHS?
Speaker 1: Hey, this was also back when it was a big step to decide to put DVDs in the anime club library.
Speaker 0: Yep But they realized the one problem would be that if you're renting out DVDs that you spent a lot of money on and you're not Blockbusters you can't just buy a bajillion DVDs if someone scratches one.
Speaker 0: That's a big freaking deal.
Speaker 0: That's like 20 bucks Lost plus.
Speaker 1: it's real hard to break a VHS tape unless you're a consummate jackass.
Speaker 0: It's real easy to break a DVD if you just put it on a surface face down or if your CD-ROM is full of sand?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah we actually made anyone who wanted to check out DVDs sign this agreement saying that they would pay for the DVD if there was so Much as the slightest blemish.
Speaker 0: Yep, and every time people brought return discs The library would inspect all of them by hand to make sure that they weren't scratched That there was no way that you could say it was the person before me who scratched it.
Speaker 0: We knew it was.
Speaker 0: it was you.
Speaker 0: you just took it.
Speaker 0: you're responsible for it.
Speaker 1: Yep Now I'm surprised that Netflix doesn't actually be very proactive about this.
Speaker 1: I mean I went ahead.
Speaker 1: I wonder if maybe they are and they just send the discs out anyway to see it.
Speaker 1: But maybe they don't check it.
Speaker 1: Maybe they just get a complaint and they send it out again and again and maybe if they get ten complaints Then they pull it off the line.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of people just might not complain About.
Speaker 0: you know a disc that's scratched?
Speaker 0: or people aren't?
Speaker 0: don't realize you know disc scratching and what the whole issue is because they don't understand DVDs or at all and they just get a disc.
Speaker 0: it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: So they mail it back without saying anything and then they add it to their queue again because they don't know any better?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I had a fun idea for a patent that I've mostly written up.
Speaker 1: I just don't feel like paying the money to actually get it put forward of a system that would allow Netflix to Trivially figure out on average who was damaging discs in order to kick them off the service.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's very likely.
Speaker 1: It's a small number of users relative to the total user base of Netflix.
Speaker 0: yeah, pretty much you're either the kind of person who scratches DVDs or you're the kind of person who doesn't and The kind of people who do can be punished and the kind of people who don't can get better discs.
Speaker 1: I never understood how you could be the kind of guy who scratches DVDs.
Speaker 1: What do you just not put it back in its case after you watch it?
Speaker 1: Do you just carry DVD players around with discs in them?
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: people just don't understand DVD.
Speaker 1: I had a DVD at work way back at IBM and I lent.
Speaker 1: I lent anime DVDs to people there fairly often.
Speaker 1: I was always trying to promote anime and usually when I gave someone a DVD they'd open it up.
Speaker 1: They look at it.
Speaker 1: Maybe they'd watch it on their work computer.
Speaker 1: I don't know, but one time I lent it to this guy who wasn't in my department and he opens the case and He was looking at the DVD.
Speaker 1: he's like I'm gonna put this in my laptop right now and he Hamfist this DVD out of the case by like cracking the case to the side to pop it out.
Speaker 1: He puts his finger right on the data part.
Speaker 0: Did you yell at him?
Speaker 1: I was like, dude, never mind I didn't give it to him.
Speaker 1: Good job I don't think he liked me after that, but there's no.
Speaker 0: you explained to him why you said dude.
Speaker 1: Never mind Oh, I did.
Speaker 1: He's like chill.
Speaker 1: It's just a DVD.
Speaker 0: That fine.
Speaker 0: Give me the 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'll sell it to you.
Speaker 0: if DVDs are free Chill because I just get another one.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, well, luckily the next ghost in the shell will come and luckily the cliffhanger that we were most recently ended on was not that Bad.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't as bad as the previous one.
Speaker 1: granted It was kind of bags of the disc hadn't been scratched.
Speaker 1: We probably would have watched the whole disc.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We could have watched the remaining two episodes.
Speaker 0: That's that damage could have been on the extras now.
Speaker 1: See I wasn't gonna risk it because I also wasn't.
Speaker 1: you know how it goes?
Speaker 1: We would have been halfway through the last episode like the major would have been shot in the face and right.
Speaker 1: then it would Have just blacked out.
Speaker 1: Yep We were to spend an hour trying to get past the spot just to.
Speaker 0: well No We could tell from looking at the bottom of the disc that there was no way past the point of no return.
Speaker 1: We've been Trying to push the data part back together instead of take a tape on it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work.
Speaker 1: I've gotten that to work before.
Speaker 0: it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: So anyway, you got any news?
Speaker 0: Yeah, remember that cup noodle freedom action.
Speaker 1: I remember that.
Speaker 1: I remember being funny because Emily found it way back.
Speaker 1: It was like, oh my god Here's something that rim and Scott won't know about.
Speaker 1: this is really cool and she comes back and she's hey guys Guess what?
Speaker 1: I'm like wait before you tell me and we showed her this cup noodle thing.
Speaker 1: We'd seen.
Speaker 0: yeah I think she listened to the show actually and heard it is the thing of the day and she was like no anyway So that cup noodle freedom thing It's also.
Speaker 0: it was originally a commercial for cup noodle and then it was an OVA.
Speaker 0: we've seen one episode of it.
Speaker 0: Well bandai who is the licenser of cup noodle freedom or just freedom OAV or OVA?
Speaker 0: Whatever you want to call it has decided a good thing.
Speaker 0: They are going to release it on DVD simultaneously in North America and Japan With Japanese audio only and English subtitles.
Speaker 0: hot damn, but wait, there's bad news.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna guess I haven't read this news.
Speaker 1: if I were them I probably would packages You know how a bowl noodle is about the size of a DVD.
Speaker 0: That would be a good news if they did that.
Speaker 1: What's the bad news?
Speaker 0: All right, first of all, well actually there's one other good news about it.
Speaker 0: It will be the first high-definition release of an anime in North America ever.
Speaker 1: wait high-definition.
Speaker 0: Well, but it's on a disc.
Speaker 0: That's HD DVDs slash DVD twins.
Speaker 0: So one side of the disc is an HD DVD and the other side is a DVD.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So it's alright.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: They seem to think Because they're not licensed.
Speaker 0: It doesn't look like they're licensing it to America.
Speaker 0: It looked because it's like a simultaneous release with no dub that it looks like it's being released by the Japanese company.
Speaker 0: So this thing's gonna be $40, huh?
Speaker 1: I'm going to make a guess as to how many Americans are going to buy this DVD I will wager that three will be sold.
Speaker 0: wait.
Speaker 0: Wait.
Speaker 0: Wait now.
Speaker 0: Here's the worst part.
Speaker 0: You're ready.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many episodes are in this OAV.
Speaker 1: for 40 bucks that would have to get at least 10 episodes per disc.
Speaker 0: But I don't know how many episodes are in the OV OAV total.
Speaker 0: But it's going to be released across a total of six volumes.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: So $40 times six.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I didn't pay that much for box sets of popular anime ten years ago.
Speaker 0: I mean their anime that I could get the entire like 26 episode series of.
Speaker 0: I could get all of asa manga dial for 60 bucks or less if I wanted to.
Speaker 0: I could Probably get it for 40 at the cheap anime ATV set.
Speaker 1: I got all of eska flown a for $23.
Speaker 0: I got all of Ava for $19 and they're gonna sell Probably one or two episodes of freedom.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many episodes per disc for 40 bucks.
Speaker 0: So I guess my kids in HD.
Speaker 0: it's in HD.
Speaker 0: So it's an.
Speaker 1: But I got a couple 40 bucks one.
Speaker 1: it in terms of making the media HD doesn't cost that much more than D.
Speaker 0: Well, it is an HD on one side and DVD on the other.
Speaker 0: So still the Can't be that much.
Speaker 1: You can't claim the production costs are that much.
Speaker 1: now to HD is well and good for live action, but in terms of anime, what are you gaining?
Speaker 0: Well, I think the anime was made in HD.
Speaker 0: we saw it.
Speaker 0: it was definitely an HD anime originally.
Speaker 1: even then I wonder if many people could even tell the difference.
Speaker 0: I imagine a double-blind test.
Speaker 0: a lot of people could not tell the difference but Regardless, you know, there is a difference.
Speaker 0: if you looked at him side by side You can always pick it out which one is better and go.
Speaker 0: it does look nicer, but it doesn't look $40 nicer.
Speaker 1: Maybe some good will come out of this.
Speaker 1: Maybe now a Japanese company will take a bath trying to sell DVDs for 40 bucks in America and maybe then they'll realize that Americans won't pay 40 bucks for a DVD no matter what it is.
Speaker 0: or maybe they'll say hey look at this Americans won't buy things that aren't dubbed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I'm hoping they'll be smart because maybe the Japanese companies.
Speaker 1: The reason the licensing costs are so high is that they just assume maybe they don't know that American Companies sell DVDs for like 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: Maybe they think that they're selling over here for 40 and they wonder why the American companies are always bitching about licensing costs.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: But the point is every time someone is gonna do something good with anime distribution in America They always seem to accompany it with something bad and then they they the good thing never happens again.
Speaker 0: You know Viz is like we're gonna put Death Note on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yay.
Speaker 0: We're gonna put DRM on it.
Speaker 0: No, we're gonna put freedom out right away on DVDs.
Speaker 0: Yay We're gonna give you like barely any episodes per disc in HD for 40 bucks.
Speaker 0: No, it's like ah Just do what we say.
Speaker 1: For some reason I have a feeling that the anime industry is not listening to geek nights and anime world order to figure out Their business plans even though they should be and that's why they're losing making less money than they were making four or five years ago.
Speaker 0: Well, not that we actually know how much money anyone makes but that's a whole pretty sure if you look at the number of shows That are being licensed the show's coming out, etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 1: Oh If I look at my own personal when was the last time we bought anime that wasn't five bucks at a con.
Speaker 0: Yep It's in there.
Speaker 0: They're definitely not making as much money as they were four or five years ago.
Speaker 0: I mean all that.
Speaker 0: remember what Otakon like every major every anime company set up a huge booth at Otakon and now they don't Do that anymore?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So speaking of licensing issues, I find this rather hilarious, but according to the anime news network Libre which publishes b-boy and b-boy gold in other words a yaoi.
Speaker 0: Well Central Park media Who's almost out of business that gave rim stuff for free that provided the prize for our contest?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, all them.
Speaker 1: Well, they have been publishing these things in America, which everyone assumed was just legitimate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know, there's a lot of different companies now licensing yaois for.
Speaker 0: you know Distribution in America and they always put a different name on.
Speaker 0: you know Cuz it's all imprinting.
Speaker 0: if you're a publisher of books you have a different imprint for your different books.
Speaker 0: You know like Marvel also publishes like.
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 0: but DC also publishes vertigo And it doesn't say DC on it, but it's the same company.
Speaker 0: They just put a different publishing label on there.
Speaker 0: It's called an imprint.
Speaker 0: So when CPM makes yaoi, they don't say CPM they say be beautiful on it.
Speaker 1: Yep, well according to Libre and a statement on their website Be beautiful has been releasing many of their works in America without any permission or license or anything whatsoever And they've issued a cease-and-desist and there's.
Speaker 1: there's probably going to be a lawsuit.
Speaker 0: That's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: I wonder is this true.
Speaker 1: Maybe this is some sort of Marketing BS thing.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's just gross and confident somewhere.
Speaker 1: How could this happen?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: CPM didn't seem that doesn't seem that confident overall.
Speaker 0: Maybe they thought they licensed something and didn't.
Speaker 0: Maybe that company licensed something and didn't realize what it did get lost in translation.
Speaker 0: Maybe CPM just took a manga translated it and printed it said haha.
Speaker 0: No one will notice.
Speaker 1: I just really wonder if this was a an act of actual maliciousness for hey maybe we'll get away with this or if they just there was some sort of technicality in the contract and Libre is just going nuts about it.
Speaker 0: It does give me an idea though.
Speaker 0: We could totally get cancellations of manga print them and Covertly sell them.
Speaker 0: as you know bootleggers totally illegally totally on the black market of manga.
Speaker 1: Well, I find something interesting that they're asking fans to not purchase these items Which I would.
Speaker 1: I would think that if they were gonna sue CPM that they would just sue them and that would be the end of it.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't have to worry about telling fans to stop buying it because they could definitely recoup losses for everything sold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it could be some sort of Backdoor, you know hidden information that we don't know about such as They saw the releases in English and they don't like them or you know CPM.
Speaker 0: They had a deal and maybe they didn't realize that the deal was in CPM scam them.
Speaker 0: So they're trying to get back at CPM or something.
Speaker 0: It's kind of stupid to say fans don't buy these because if you say that someone's doing something illegally You just make it it more likely that fans are gonna run out and buy them real quick before they're gone.
Speaker 1: I really wonder if there's gonna actually be a lawsuit or if they're just telling them to stop.
Speaker 0: if they just tell them to stop And they don't sue them I say we go and find out all the Yahweh this company publishes Translate it and print it cuz they're not gonna do a goddamn thing about it.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm gonna watch it too because this will test a lot of ideas I have about how copyright law works internationally and I want to see if this company can actually follow through and Bring charges against or not.
Speaker 0: if they can't I'm taking fan subs putting them on DVDs and selling them.
Speaker 0: It's not a goddamn thing.
Speaker 0: Anyone could do about it.
Speaker 0: But of course, I'll only do it with anime that Aren't licensed in America and no one will ever license in America because they're too awesome.
Speaker 1: and I got one more little bit.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna mention this briefly work.
Speaker 1: We'll probably talk about it in more depth later.
Speaker 1: what's more details come out, but it looks like in 2008 there's going to be a dragon ball online a massively multiplayer online dragon ball.
Speaker 0: So wait.
Speaker 0: So all you do is you you really only have like four or five characters designs to choose from like green guy bald guy Girl and yellow hair electric guy.
Speaker 1: Have you ever actually seen your dragon ball?
Speaker 1: There's more to it than that.
Speaker 0: and then you're in a big Sky flying around and when you see someone you yell into your microphone at them.
Speaker 0: come And then you hit your spacebar as fat.
Speaker 0: you can tend to finger your spacebar as much as you can to see who grows Brighter and has a bigger number on the screen 9,000 and his power level is over 9,000.
Speaker 1: Apparently this is set several hundred years after the events of Dragon Ball, huh?
Speaker 1: And don't forget players can freely customize their hair Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Oh god, I didn't even notice that there's screenshots.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll talk about this in more depth later just so you are aware things of the day Now.
Speaker 1: we've known about the Mario manga for a long time and we really want to read it But there don't seem to be many fans Translations of it meaning there aren't any as far as I can see.
Speaker 0: yeah, and we've known about the Mario show and some other Mario shows from other countries and We've known that there's at least one Mario anime that we saw one episode of.
Speaker 0: that was pretty bad.
Speaker 1: Well, it looks like there's another one.
Speaker 1: That's wild pretty bad.
Speaker 0: Not quite as bad It's kind of bad.
Speaker 0: I think it's more faithful to the video game than a lot of the other ones Which is why it doesn't seem so bad in the first place Yeah, but at the same time it's far less faithful to what King Koopa should actually be.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean a Koopa that just goes.
Speaker 0: he's like Godzilla.
Speaker 0: He doesn't talk.
Speaker 0: He doesn't seem too intelligent.
Speaker 0: He just goes And picks up the princess and walks away.
Speaker 1: well, someone seems to have uploaded the first three or four minutes of this thing, which is moderately entertaining mostly because you know You don't have to actually watch the whole thing.
Speaker 1: And all I really want to point out is that you'll probably enjoy this if you've watched anime long enough Even if you don't speak Japanese, this isn't subtitled obviously, but you might be surprised how much you Understand despite not speaking Japanese.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Understood Me like enough of what they were saying.
Speaker 0: I felt like, you know, like what a one-year-old in Japan would understand.
Speaker 0: Yep Yep, that's where I feel as opposed to a zero-year-old.
Speaker 1: I guess we've watched way too much anime.
Speaker 0: Perhaps we have but that's good because now I don't really you know I mean for something complex like ghost in the shell pretty much fucked without subtitles.
Speaker 1: God even with subtitles I have trouble with ghost to me too.
Speaker 1: But it was that one episode in standalone complex where we're just sitting there and they talked for like 10 minutes Just about deep hard to understand political bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yep I still don't understand half of the shit that's going on in that show.
Speaker 1: I've started to figure out what's going on.
Speaker 0: I think I have I got the general idea enough to enjoy the show But I don't think it's worth the time and effort to go back and figure out all the details.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure I understand what all the different parts of the government have at stake and why they're all involved.
Speaker 1: and we're section 9.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I got that but like all the little tiny You know things that they just keep going like oh this and that and this and that like what?
Speaker 0: just give me the main Gist and go shoot somebody.
Speaker 1: most of that isn't really as complex as you might think if I know.
Speaker 0: it's just the way.
Speaker 0: the subtitles Is there like a big two big sentences and they'll only be there for a real quick and then they'll be two more.
Speaker 0: and it's like Ah, I'm still processing the last one.
Speaker 1: I just can't imagine reading a manga adaptation or anything of that because it'd have to be crazy.
Speaker 1: kanji No one's ever seen before.
Speaker 0: well in English.
Speaker 0: It'd be okay.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this Mario anime worth your four minutes of time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly Alright, so there are a lot of martial arts out there.
Speaker 0: There's a kung fu Karate Krav maga kra, that's krav maga, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah Taekwondo judo all kinds but one kind that is extremely entertaining perhaps the second most Entertaining martial art to watch.
Speaker 1: what's the most entertaining?
Speaker 0: I kiddo nah, huh?
Speaker 1: What about capoeira?
Speaker 0: Capoeira is pretty cool, but it's much.
Speaker 0: It's more like dancing even though I guess it is a martial art.
Speaker 0: Plus kung fu is my favorite martial art to watch especially fake Hollywood kung fu or a Hollywood kung fu is a separate martial art though It's not the same as Shaolin kung fu.
Speaker 0: But yeah Jujitsu is really entertaining.
Speaker 0: I had a friend in high school who was super into jiu-jitsu and the way he explained it to me back in those days.
Speaker 0: You know, I didn't look this up or anything.
Speaker 0: This is just going by what some guy told me that.
Speaker 0: what I remember is that the majority of real fights in the street Like if you're at a bar and some guy starts to mess with you or you know If you're in a town and a crazy hick starts to come around and push you around Most fights like that end up with two guys rolling around on the ground, you know There isn't a whole lot of stand-up punching in the face fighting going on.
Speaker 0: when it comes to real You know street violence in the United States.
Speaker 1: Well, I remember when I was a little kid at elementary school.
Speaker 1: I was attacked by this other thug kid.
Speaker 1: I went to downtown Detroit schools and this kid just attacked me.
Speaker 1: We never really found out why but the fight ended up on the ground after about two seconds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean people, you know, it's like there might be a punch or two but then you're grabbing the other guy and you're rolling around on the ground and Jiu-jitsu is all about step one get the guy on the ground.
Speaker 0: step two when you're on the ground Jiu-jitsu will tell you how to do the most physical damage possible in the least amount of time.
Speaker 0: Now this isn't the most impressive video because the guy is obviously fighting.
Speaker 1: You know his students who are what you expected him to go around in the street picking fights.
Speaker 0: Hell's yeah.
Speaker 0: But no, it's not at least the competition where the other people are trying to fight back.
Speaker 0: This is his students basically letting him do what he wants to them.
Speaker 0: But he shows you the crazy ways in which he puts someone on the ground and then pins them there And I particularly.
Speaker 1: they're like the one where the guy tries to punch him and he just kind of takes the punch like grabs the Guy's arm and lets the punch come in.
Speaker 1: then he jumps off with his legs Which his whole body on top of the guy and just pulls him to the ground.
Speaker 0: You know back in the olden days, you know Just fighting around as kids where kids would just fight.
Speaker 0: I've done stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Just is natural kind of like someone grabs my arm and then I'll like just swing my legs up onto their body And then they'll be weighted down by me and then eventually they'll fall.
Speaker 0: It wasn't quite as elegant, you know and practiced is what this guy's doing But that's sort of a natural fighting move of mine I don't know.
Speaker 1: my generic idea if I ever get into a fight again is simply punch them in the nose quickly and then run Away, that's a good move.
Speaker 1: or the classic kick him lightly in the shin as soon as they look down punch him in the nose And then run away.
Speaker 0: I just kind of like jiu-jitsu because it seems slightly more practical than a lot of other martial arts at least on paper and As far as I know it doesn't have a lot of that hokey-chee malarkey But it probably does.
Speaker 1: it probably doesn't have as much punch yourself in the gut for ten minutes.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of punching or kicking knuckle push-ups and keep doing until everyone in the room is done ten And if someone can't do ten you're stuck there doing a hundred.
Speaker 0: Yeah, jiu-jitsu just doesn't have a lot of punching and kicking and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of striking at all.
Speaker 0: It's mostly grabbing and pinning and twisting and holding and that sort of thing only more practical than say judo Which is similar.
Speaker 1: so not too long ago.
Speaker 1: We there's an anime.
Speaker 1: We're really excited about.
Speaker 1: we're gonna talk about it Once we've seen more of it, but it's called Moonlight Mile and it looked like it was everything We wanted out of an anime and we released according to the preview.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the trailer and the preview were like This is not Brim and Scott's alley.
Speaker 1: it's got nothing but politics robots technology drama serious geeky guy kind of action outer space and Without ruining anything.
Speaker 1: it basically was space orgy and then nothing.
Speaker 1: It wasn't what we expected completely and I was so pissed off that I'm not even ready to talk about it yet.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have to see it probably the second episode and then we'll be pissed off enough to talk about it.
Speaker 1: So as a result this week we had to talk about something good to get that out of our mind.
Speaker 0: It helped that.
Speaker 0: I think it was was it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was the most recent episode of animal order the one where they played all those voicemails.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, that one and someone sent him a voicemail and said hey if you heard of this anime here is Greenwood And I was like, oh shit's we needs to do an episode on that before anybody else.
Speaker 1: Yeah Here is Greenwood.
Speaker 0: is is very near and dear to rim and sky and it's a great Awesome anime and manga that not too many people know about hence perfect for a geek nights episode.
Speaker 0: So, how did we find out about here is Greenwood?
Speaker 0: Well, you see basically, I mean this anime was obscure when we were in college.
Speaker 1: It was also hard to get because the VHS was out of print and there was no DVD for a while.
Speaker 1: I remember the club had three tapes.
Speaker 1: It had the basically these tapes that had the whole away the on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a six episode OAV and each tape had two episodes on it and people kept stealing the second tape.
Speaker 1: Yes, like literally people constantly would steal this.
Speaker 1: what you wanted to check out here is Greenwood.
Speaker 1: We had to get.
Speaker 1: we had to get special permission and make sure that you were in a scuzzy, dude Because they kept getting stolen.
Speaker 0: It was that good.
Speaker 0: people would rent it from the anime club library and keep it.
Speaker 1: see the thing was Here's Greenwood is one the official anime of the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: That was the largest anime club in the country.
Speaker 1: Yes when we were in it now, this was true before we got there God, this was true for like a decade before.
Speaker 0: we didn't know anything about here's Greenwood when we got there until they showed it To us.
Speaker 0: now the official motto of the RIT anime club is we are the no-brand heroes Which is the closing song of here's Greenwood.
Speaker 1: It's also a fairly well-known and popular phrase among older anime fans.
Speaker 0: it is indeed of course the official mascot of the RIT.
Speaker 0: anime Is the great messenger which has nothing to do with here's Greenwood?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the tradition was that not every year because that would get old but every few years Maybe every two or three years depending on what kind of people were coming.
Speaker 1: through RIT The club would show here is Greenwood all in one go as one showing and without fail.
Speaker 1: People would wonder what the hell this show is that they'd never heard of and by the end of the episode People were crying and jumping around and yelling and screaming and then there'd be a mad rush for people to check the tapes out to Show it to other people.
Speaker 0: Well, luckily now if you're smart and cool, you can get all of.
Speaker 0: here is Greenwood on a single DVD Six episodes one disc beat that Yeah
Speaker 1: And I usually don't bother trying to tell people to buy anime because you can Netflix it or you can watch the fan subs before It comes out or you can buy the super box set years later borrowed from a friend.
Speaker 1: but here's Greenwood is one of those shows where it's good to own it because it's the kind of thing that every few years you're Gonna want to whip out and show to someone who's never seen it or lend it out to people.
Speaker 0: I would go so far as to say that no anime DVD shelf is complete without.
Speaker 0: here is Greenwood.
Speaker 1: now as for the manga I really like the manga, but you don't have to buy the manga.
Speaker 1: The manga is in no way Integral to actually watching the anime.
Speaker 1: You don't need to know anything about it.
Speaker 1: The anime is completely self-contained.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the manga is only nine volumes though.
Speaker 0: So if you really like the anime, then if you want the manga go and get it.
Speaker 1: All I'll say about the manga is that is pretty much exactly like the anime.
Speaker 1: It's just not only more.
Speaker 1: It's just not animated and it doesn't get old.
Speaker 1: You might think that something like this could get old but it doesn't.
Speaker 1: I've read a good half the manga and I've got the rest Of it and I really really like it probably more than I should Alright.
Speaker 0: so now I'm gonna tell you what here's Greenwood is about and you will quickly see why is the official anime of the RIT Anime Club.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now originally the manga is by Yukinasu and she's really cute and that's all I'll say.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, here's Greenwood.
Speaker 0: It's about this guy.
Speaker 0: What's his name?
Speaker 1: Hasekawa Kazuya.
Speaker 0: Yes, Hasekawa Kazuya, whatever he lives at home with his brother and His brother's girlfriend.
Speaker 1: Yes, they're there to be married their fiance.
Speaker 0: Yes But it turns out that before they were engaged This kid had a super crush on that girl.
Speaker 0: That is now his brother's fiance.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like his older brother stole his woman from him.
Speaker 1: Yes, Sumire is in this manga and in the anime utterly adorable.
Speaker 1: They go out of their way to make her as adorable as possible and not adorable in this modern You know moe almost kind of sense like adorable anime characters now.
Speaker 1: She's adorable in this very old-school Ranma mazani koku kind of way.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like imagine if you were a kid and The girl you had a super crush on all of a sudden was your older brother's fiance And with the parents are dead or something, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't that doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: You hardly know about them and they don't come into it, but the parents aren't there.
Speaker 0: He's pretty upset.
Speaker 0: So when it comes time to go to school But he can't stand being in that house seeing his brother and this girl be an all lovey-lovey Mostly because he knows what they do in the bedroom at night and he just can't deal with that.
Speaker 1: Yep Also, he's been driven by stress of trying to get into high school and stress of living with the woman He loves and the man she loves gave him an ulcer and all sorts of complications.
Speaker 0: So when it finally comes time to go to high school, he goes to the local high school But he decides to stay in the dorm even though he lives in the same exact town, but he shows up late.
Speaker 0: He doesn't go to school on the first day because of the ulcer that rim just talked about.
Speaker 0: So when he finally shows up to the not first day of school, but his first day of school late He is put in the dorm known as Greenwood.
Speaker 1: now Greenwood I recall if you look at the kanji basically means something along the lines of den of thieves or forest of thieves or something like that.
Speaker 0: Greenwood is a dorm full of craziness.
Speaker 0: Oh snaps.
Speaker 1: It's It's hard to really explain.
Speaker 1: It's not zany like Excel saga or any of these modern anime.
Speaker 0: Well, I think for the time it was zany.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not a raised the zany bar, but it's not as zany as stuff we have now.
Speaker 0: by today's standards It is pretty tame.
Speaker 1: It's a very low-key zany and a lot of very strange things will happen, but it's not like a modern Everyone.
Speaker 1: oh something crazy.
Speaker 0: Oh my random animals flying around.
Speaker 0: It's not chromarty crazy, but it's just a gorilla.
Speaker 1: Randomly when a crazy thing happens or something weird happens It's taken at face value by all the people and it's not anything weird.
Speaker 1: They don't even bat an eye at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so as you can see It's perfect choice for a college anime club to pick as their official anime when it's about a crazy wacky dorm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically Hasekawa or tsukachan as they end up calling him ends up falling under the wing of these three upperclassmen and as a result he basically ends up kind of at the center of all of the goings-on at this high school because it turns out that these Three people are themselves the center of just about everything that goes on at this high school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much each episode has some sort of crazy plot that involves some mostly these four characters And you know stuff goes on and they solve it along the way, but what really makes this show great I think are all these secondary characters.
Speaker 0: Just the random people who live about the dorm making it wacky.
Speaker 1: I mean, let's see There's one dorm one room where the two people living in it have turned their entire room into a not just an arcade But a profitable arcade.
Speaker 0: Yes, they are specifically known as the guys who have turned their dorm room into a profitable video arcade.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they ever get names at least in the anime They don't.
Speaker 0: there are also this one guy who's the best character in the whole show?
Speaker 0: Who you know.
Speaker 0: in Japan if you have a motorcycle?
Speaker 0: You can't really like leave it outside anywhere.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of room in Japan for that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: So if you have a motorcycle you can carry it up to your room And there's a guy who carries his giant motorcycle up to his room and whenever people go down the stairs He always seems to be on the stairs carrying this motorcycle.
Speaker 1: I guess he just carries it up and down all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty funny when you see this huge American looking guy.
Speaker 0: He's like five taller than all the Japanese people carrying this giant motorcycle or one thing that happens when this kid comes.
Speaker 1: He joins the dorm.
Speaker 1: He comes in the first day.
Speaker 1: all the clubs are desperate to get people to join But the dorm is cool.
Speaker 1: The people who run the dorm are great.
Speaker 1: They set up this whole policy where the clubs can't try to recruit him on the dorm ground.
Speaker 1: So he has a little bit of sanctuary.
Speaker 1: one of the clubs is the crazy Christian group the equivalent of the American campus crusade for Christ and The way they're drawn in the manga and the way they're depicted in the anime are absolutely hilarious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've got you know, your stereotypical swirly eyeballs.
Speaker 0: They're like They look sort of like zombies and they're holding like, you know a book with a cross on it and they're standing straight up and like oh Now the actual main characters are also would really make this manga anime manga shine.
Speaker 1: I mean hasakawa is a typical kid.
Speaker 1: He overreacts to everything.
Speaker 1: He's stressed all the time.
Speaker 1: He always has an ulcer any time Sumire comes to see him.
Speaker 1: He freaks out and can't deal with it.
Speaker 1: He furthermore has to deal with the fact that his older brother who is Dating married to his first loving to be married to is also the male nurse of this dorm of the school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is an all-male school.
Speaker 0: So his brother a male is the school nurse.
Speaker 0: It's like if you're trying to get away, why did you go to the school where he's the nurse?
Speaker 0: You should have gone to a faraway school.
Speaker 0: What was wrong with you?
Speaker 1: This kid has issues.
Speaker 0: He's got definitely the serious issues.
Speaker 1: However, despite that when push comes to some shove he's fairly confident and he grows into a real man by the end of the OAV.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean despite having all sorts of stress and Being sort of you know freaked out by all the crazy things that go on around him and the Greenwood dorm of wackiness He's actually sort of the straight man, you know He's not really that wacky himself so much as the other characters and he's not stupid You know, even though he doesn't do as well in class as maybe he should.
Speaker 0: but that's just you know To help you identify with the character if you're not a genius, but yeah, he gets along.
Speaker 0: Okay So then what you would think there is his first roommate.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to ruin Well anything about his first roommate.
Speaker 1: suffice to say the anime is going to start with a plot.
Speaker 1: That is so stereotypical.
Speaker 1: You're probably gonna want to turn it off because when they introduce what this plot is, you'll think wow What the hell is wrong with rim and sky?
Speaker 1: This is stupid.
Speaker 0: But that plot that the first plot of the first episode that everyone pretty much goes what?
Speaker 0: Oh, come on, boo What's this BS Stereotypical crap is resolved pretty quickly by the end of the before well before the end of the first episode.
Speaker 1: Not only is it resolved really quickly.
Speaker 1: It is resolved hilariously and when it happens, I want you to not spoil this for yourself and One remember when you figured it out and there's a moment at which you probably should have figured it out But you didn't.
Speaker 1: and then they've main character is gonna figure it out like 20 seconds later.
Speaker 0: It's good times.
Speaker 1: Yes, but suffice to say that is not the what this show is about.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess what it appears to be is not what the show is about.
Speaker 1: how it is resolved is what the show is all about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as soon as you get to the end of that first bit there where there's a reveal of some sort and you go Oh my god, that's how the rest of the show goes from there on out.
Speaker 1: So then the two upperclassmen who have kind of taken this kid under his wing are Mitsuru who is a pretty boy all the girls that local junior high and all the girls at this school Not at this school, but at their sister school, whatever really like him.
Speaker 1: He's really pretty really popular.
Speaker 1: he's the head of the dorm kind of the equivalent of the RA or the RD and He has.
Speaker 1: they make mention that he has a special power Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: His power is that his face is 100% immune to damage that would in any way disfigure him Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Now they mentioned this kind of tongue-in-cheek and is kind of a joke.
Speaker 1: But way later in the show There's a point in which a woman slashes his face with a knife and it heals right away and everyone's like, whoa
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone whether you realize they're not seems to have some sort of special power of some sort in this show Even if it's a very small special power or an insignificant special power or something It doesn't even seem like a power at all, you know, and when you figure out what each character does It's kind of like ooh
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's done in this casual really kind of way.
Speaker 1: but the whole show and even the manga is even worse about this is Really kind of it'll break the fourth wall The manga actually does that fairly often and there'll be little elements like the superpower that come out of nowhere And yet they really really fit and then they're thrown away and you don't worry about him again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't have really much to do with what's going on.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of like.
Speaker 0: it's more of a character thing than a plot thing these power things that people have.
Speaker 1: Well, the characters are all there is to the show.
Speaker 1: the plot exists and there are various subplots.
Speaker 0: Well the plots also.
Speaker 0: it's like there aren't any big plots that all Encompass the entire show or the entire manga or anything.
Speaker 0: every plot is sort of a you know, this character.
Speaker 0: We're gonna resolve his bit about this or we're gonna reveal a whole bunch of stuff about this Character and then tie up a couple of the loose ends on it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The anime generally follows the format of little subplot.
Speaker 1: That's funny little subplot.
Speaker 1: That's funny a bunch of those and then the last two episodes are actually a pretty serious Good story arc and then that's where it ends and it ends on a very poignant note.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 0: It doesn't keep up the funny level.
Speaker 0: it towards the end of the anime, but it's still funny enough.
Speaker 1: Well, it works Well because it has this really good level of funny and then it tapers off into the serious thing.
Speaker 1: that's not super serious But it's serious enough to where the show leaves you feeling good at the end.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, plus out all the people we showed it to.
Speaker 1: they really like the last two episodes more than the rest of the show.
Speaker 0: Usually wasn't there a Halloween episode.
Speaker 1: Well, there was a thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the show does have a little bit of supernatural kind of action.
Speaker 1: But here's the thing like many times when something appears supernatural.
Speaker 1: It's actually not.
Speaker 1: now in the anime There's one thing that actually is supernatural.
Speaker 1: But even then it's done in this really kind of low-key funny way.
Speaker 0: There are also a lot of things that are just like WTF.
Speaker 0: what the hell?
Speaker 0: WTF mate like the guy's sister.
Speaker 0: It's just oh, yeah, it's just so Crazy that it's just unbelievable.
Speaker 0: The thing is it's crazy more along the lines that this woman is just crazy And as a result a lot of the stuff just makes no sense and all the characters that aren't stupid are just like what?
Speaker 1: Yeah That's the thing.
Speaker 1: that characters react to these weird things very nonchalantly because I guess they're used to it But at the same time they react to them the way a normal person who just saw this would deal with it.
Speaker 1: I mean if one of these characters older sister happens to go crazy and kidnap him in this crazy Absolutely insane thing all the other characters deal with that in the way that a normal human being would probably deal with it Insofar as a normal human being who had been living in this dorm would deal with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the show also in addition to being generally wacky and you know Generally character driven has a lot of like repeating jokes that they're just.
Speaker 0: they're just sort of like these one-line Jokes or innuendos here and there like the two pretty boys would be like, oh We're gay.
Speaker 0: And if like ha ha ha ha and then they're not gay, you know just be like, haha We made a gay joke and then someone else makes a joke about you know Something else and these jokes recur every once in a while and they're like, oh they made that joke again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yet the jokes never really get tired.
Speaker 1: I guess part of it's that the OAV is very short and sweet.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's only six episodes.
Speaker 1: You can watch it in one go.
Speaker 1: So it really doesn't have enough time to get cliched.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the manga really starts expanding on all that to where it never gets to the point where you think ah They're doing that again.
Speaker 0: Yeah the anime can repeat itself because it's so short and the manga doesn't repeat itself because it has room to grow.
Speaker 0: whereas if the Anime tried to grow.
Speaker 0: I think it would not fit in its shoe anymore.
Speaker 1: But meets her was kind of the laid-back bad-boy kind of character and his friend the student council president Shinobu is the cool calculated not necessarily evil But definitely always has ulterior motives and it's always manipulating everyone around him kind of guy.
Speaker 1: He also is Totally corrupt when it comes to running the student government Super corrupt when it comes to running the student.
Speaker 1: good God.
Speaker 1: So in a word if I had to describe here is Greenwood the anime or the manga I would have to use the word charming Maybe.
Speaker 1: I guess it's definitely this low-key laid-back Kind of the humor will often build on you.
Speaker 1: the humor is usually it won't be the zany thing itself but it'll be the reaction shot or the look on a character's face when something happens or the little side quip that a side character makes as they're walking by or That sort of thing.
Speaker 1: lots of little jokes that kind of build up and make you laugh out loud by the end.
Speaker 1: Of course I do think that part of the reason I like this show so much and Scott likes the show and all of our friends like The show is that not in terms of events or the way things worked out But in terms of the spirit of the of the work What happens and here is Greenwood is a lot like our lives were when we were at our IT.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were actually talking about that the other day how we missed the fact that I remember coming home from class or from whatever I was doing and without fail Something weird would happen.
Speaker 1: I'd always see like a naked guy running around or there'd be a couch on fire Or there'd be a guy with an ethernet cable running out his window to his car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it as much as even though it's about high school in Japan if you're a college student in the u.s Especially at a geeky college.
Speaker 0: There is just so much that is like this is they must have gone to a geeky college and pretended It was a Japanese high school dorm when they made this because it is so dead-on Hence the matching with our IT.
Speaker 0: and it really did match with our IT.
Speaker 1: so well I mean reading here is Greenwood fills me with horrible nostalgia for living in the dorms in college.
Speaker 0: When I was living in the dorms in college and I saw here is Greenwood for the first time It gave me nostalgia for the previous day.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like oh, yeah yesterday.
Speaker 0: I saw something crazy like that.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a good days yesterday and all.
Speaker 1: So I can't recommend this show enough the manga I really like.
Speaker 1: if you like I'd say buy the anime.
Speaker 1: you have nothing to lose by buying this anime.
Speaker 1: It's one DVD one.
Speaker 0: You could probably get it real cheap.
Speaker 0: In fact, I'm gonna look up and see how much it is right now.
Speaker 1: at least put it in your Netflix.
Speaker 1: If nothing else there is no reason not to risk watching this anime.
Speaker 1: I almost guarantee that you will come out of it liking it And if you like it, then you might want to pick up the manga.
Speaker 0: All right I see this thing on eBay for $11 from one person.
Speaker 0: So for $15, you could probably get this new six episodes man That's like two dollars and change an episode at the most for an awesome six episodes of anime.
Speaker 0: I've said more than $11 on lunch on one disc won't take up too much room on the shelf and You really just can't not watch this show and be an anime fan at the same time.
Speaker 1: Yes, this show should be near and dear to anyone who went to college.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially it's like if you're not if you didn't go to college or if college isn't fresh in your mind Then this show will be a great show for you.
Speaker 0: If you have been to college you were recently out of college or you're in college right now This show will be an amazing show for you.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess there's a chance it won't be but if that's the case you go to a really lame college.
Speaker 0: Yeah You should think about if your school is if you're in school or you got thinking about going to school.
Speaker 0: Watch here is Greenwood And if that's not the experience you're having then or you that you think you're gonna have go somewhere else.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear You can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives Visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution Non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.