Speaker 0: It's Monday January 29th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and I'm rim and this is geek night Tonight.
Speaker 0: we teach you how removable media formats work.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Man work just keeps getting more and more surreal.
Speaker 1: I had two managers fighting over who got to use my services today Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I go into work because I was supposed to have jury duty, but they delayed it.
Speaker 1: I have jury duty tomorrow now, which is great because now I can sleep in And I don't tell you not get paid.
Speaker 1: I have to waste a vacation day, but I get 40 bucks from my company on top of that.
Speaker 0: Whoa $40.
Speaker 1: Yeah, 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah rolling in the dough.
Speaker 0: That'll pay for the parking And maybe the gas might pay for a lunch.
Speaker 0: maybe a lunch though.
Speaker 1: I'll get to eat something up in Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 0: Oh, you could eat at that place.
Speaker 0: that we ate it.
Speaker 1: That was a good place.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that's near the courthouse.
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I got to look where the courthouse is and everything.
Speaker 0: So what if you take a little long going to get on lunch during the jury duty?
Speaker 0: What could happen?
Speaker 0: I just hope what would happen if you went to jury duty and like you went to lunch and they told you you could and You just came back a little late.
Speaker 0: What would they do to you?
Speaker 0: not much?
Speaker 1: Well, actually there's a whole bunch of rules about if Something comes up numbers you can call to not get arrested or whatever and protocol you have to follow if there's an emergency.
Speaker 0: I'm sure if you're there and something happens that you someone you go up and you say something and then you can go.
Speaker 1: Also today I was working in one of the hospitals that we work at and I'm up in the computer room and I'm doing stuff And I go out to find a bathroom and there's no one in the halls anywhere, but people were in the computer room.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of surreal like maybe a zombie horror is about to begin.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I'm walking around I don't see anyone anywhere.
Speaker 1: So I go to the elevator and the elevators not working.
Speaker 1: Oh Now powers on and there were people in the computer room, which apparently is basically sealed off from the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: So eventually I give up and I go down a flight of stairs and the elevator still won't work and I go down another flight Of stairs and then I see a bunch of firemen coming up the stairway.
Speaker 1: Oh carrying hoses.
Speaker 0: you want to go up?
Speaker 1: So I just back away and they all go past me.
Speaker 1: They don't even say a word.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so I'm like, huh, so I go down to the lobby and there's a. Basically the security guards have set up a court like they've cordoned off the entrance and they're like no one comes in No one goes out.
Speaker 1: Why me no one goes out no one comes in no one goes out.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I'm like What if there's a fire I'm leaving.
Speaker 1: so I'm like what's going on and they're like there was a fire.
Speaker 1: Like okay, they're like we followed our procedure.
Speaker 1: We just can't let anyone go anywhere until they solve it.
Speaker 0: But if there's a fire don't they want everyone to leave?
Speaker 0: No, no,
Speaker 1: no It's actually interestingly most hospitals the procedure for if there's a fire is not to evacuate everyone because that's crazy
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: what they do is usually there are safe rooms on every floor of a hospital Mm-hmm, and these rooms are especially ventilated to at least keep people breathing and okay.
Speaker 1: And if you have to evacuate people away from a fire you evacuate them there.
Speaker 1: I mean, how are you gonna get thousands of people in hospital beds out of a building?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's all sorts of.
Speaker 0: that's why I remember like Katrina.
Speaker 0: A lot of people just got left there.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it kind of sucks, but it was kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: There was this fire but the command everyone, you know was standing downstairs whatever but the computer room didn't have any sort of fire Alarm in it.
Speaker 0: Well, no because if you have a big multi-story building Generally, if there's a fire the alarms only go off on the floors that need it, you know.
Speaker 0: And if you're on the right, I forget you split under the fires better like there's a fire on top here.
Speaker 0: Okay, or is on bottom of you?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I forget.
Speaker 1: I submit to you the towering inferno.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're under the fire, it's cool.
Speaker 0: You know, you just go down the stairs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nothing really came of it.
Speaker 1: It was just interesting.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: More importantly we ordered new microphones.
Speaker 0: Oh shit They haven't arrived yet.
Speaker 0: How long have you been thinking about doing that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and suddenly on a whim I ordered the same microphone that has been used by the President of the United States since I think Johnson.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: The Shure SM57 Or 58.
Speaker 1: Not the 58.
Speaker 1: Not the 58, the 57.
Speaker 0: There is a 58.
Speaker 0: There is.
Speaker 1: It's slightly different and Crook slightly slow.
Speaker 0: Crook slightly slow.
Speaker 0: Megaton, Megatone, Megatone, Megatone It's not one better than the 57 though.
Speaker 0: It's just a different number.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much exactly Identical in terms of the relative usefulness.
Speaker 1: They're just slightly.
Speaker 0: The physical appearance is different.
Speaker 1: Well, they're useful in slightly different ways Which none of you probably would know or care about.
Speaker 1: All I have to say is for the vast majority of Podcasters out there because I know a lot of podcasters listen to us There's really no reason to ever buy a microphone better than the Shure SM57.
Speaker 0: No, you could you could buy a better one, but it's not gonna do much for you.
Speaker 0: I mean unless you start distributing your podcast as flak or wave then Then it might do something.
Speaker 1: Or if you also have a good compressor or good SSR and all that other stuff that you probably don't have Yeah, but you start to get diminishing returns on your money like you could get something better and it would be better.
Speaker 0: It just wouldn't be significantly better like it's a hundred bucks for the 57.
Speaker 0: All right, you could do better with a $200 microphone, but it wouldn't be twice as good as the $100 microphone.
Speaker 0: It would be like 10% better.
Speaker 1: plus how many people have we seen you have you know Like the same kind of mixer we have and they have fancy condenser microphones plugged into it.
Speaker 1: There were a lot of money But they don't have a compressor or any sort of signal thing in the way.
Speaker 0: It's all we see people who have more fancy equipment than we do fancier microphones fancier pot filters Lots of compressors in a big-ass mixer and it sounds shittier because they don't know what the fuck they're doing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's one podcast in particular.
Speaker 0: Yeah Knowing what you're doing is far more important than spending money and There is a point at which spending money is diminishing returns.
Speaker 0: unless you distribute your podcast on fully mastered super audio CDs.
Speaker 1: Uh, maybe that should be our next extra.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: Sounds good to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, uh on Thursday I'm finally going a interview for some job.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: I don't think I'm gonna tell my work.
Speaker 0: I think they're just gonna think I'm working that day.
Speaker 0: Wow I'm more I. it's like I'm working a job and I'm going to interview for other jobs while working the current job.
Speaker 1: So your job is basically paying you.
Speaker 0: that's the kind of stuff that like you see on TV and you think is crazy.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of thing George Costanza would do exactly the guy.
Speaker 1: See now what you got to do and I think this is brilliant.
Speaker 0: Let's say see I would go to my work in the city that day and just tell them I haven't like something to do in The city and then in the afternoon go to the interviews, but I'd walk in there wearing all fancy clothes and they'd be like Hey, what are you all dressed up for?
Speaker 0: You know, you should say looking for a better job than this one.
Speaker 1: You should say a date.
Speaker 1: I have a date During the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, a friend is in town from Hong Kong.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen her in six years.
Speaker 0: You're really not good at this whole making up an excuse thing Because it's much better to just not say anything than to lie.
Speaker 0: If you don't say anything then you don't have anything to cover up.
Speaker 1: now, here's my brilliant plan.
Speaker 1: Let's say you get a new job.
Speaker 0: Just I figure on the odd chance that I bump into someone from my work in the city Even though the interview is so far away from my works office on the odd chance that I do bump into someone like way downtown Where this office is?
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna be like, yeah, I mean if you're in front of the job, what you can do about it.
Speaker 0: That's my plan.
Speaker 1: But don't say you get the job, right?
Speaker 0: You should know if I want this job.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to interview any job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Why even tell your company that you just collect a paycheck as long as you can?
Speaker 0: Because then there might be legal issues that you get me sued.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason I don't do that.
Speaker 0: well, otherwise I would because technically what would happen is Everything I do is a work for hire for the company I'm at now.
Speaker 0: So if I started working at another company that my current company would own the work I did for the second one.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: You know how you do that?
Speaker 1: You ask for a two-week vacation.
Speaker 1: Okay, just be like.
Speaker 1: can I burn my vacation is whatever.
Speaker 1: I need a two-week vacation and Start your new job as soon as your vacation starts and then just don't just tell your work at the end of vacation.
Speaker 1: Oh, by the way, I quit.
Speaker 0: It's alright, but I don't know.
Speaker 1: it depends if your company will pay you all your own use.
Speaker 0: Let's remember when I go to these jobs I'm gonna be you know Because I already have a job that I'm safe in.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna heap demands on whoever wants me to work for them.
Speaker 0: Like I'm going to take off these this week and two days for Otacon and the week afterwards and I'm Taking off this and I'm gonna go see my grandma in Florida and you're gonna pay me more money than they paid me And I'm gonna show up at this time and leave at this time and I'm never gonna work later on a weekend and you can Shove it if you don't like that.
Speaker 1: See you I interviewed like that even when I didn't have a stable job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm real picky when it comes to job.
Speaker 0: The only reason I'd interview like that before was you know, my previous two times ago I was like I need a co-op or I can't graduate.
Speaker 0: So I was like give me whatever and the lat the preview the time after that which is my current job.
Speaker 0: I interviewed.
Speaker 0: I have to get at my mom's house.
Speaker 0: I'll take it now.
Speaker 1: I can interview like that for oh, here's another way You could swing it.
Speaker 1: So say your new job starts in a month.
Speaker 1: That's like a standard.
Speaker 1: No a month from now I'm gonna start at this new job.
Speaker 0: I don't know the job that I currently have.
Speaker 0: I started like the Monday after her.
Speaker 0: I they Gave me an offer.
Speaker 1: Well, I gave IBM a month's notice.
Speaker 1: I was real nice to them Oh, but anyway, so let's say the job starts in a month.
Speaker 1: even swing it Like.
Speaker 1: I'd like to start the first of next month.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Just stop showing up to your normal job and don't have a job and just collect money until they fire you and then start the New job.
Speaker 1: and if you make and then have a bet I have a pool.
Speaker 1: if you make it the whole month Without getting caught just quit.
Speaker 0: Yeah Thing is do I do anything during the month to keep from getting caught?
Speaker 0: cuz they those.
Speaker 0: the odds are in a month that Someone will email me and ask me to do something and it might be something that takes five minutes.
Speaker 0: Should I do it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It depends on what kind of pool you want to set up.
Speaker 1: I mean how.
Speaker 1: how about what do you want the odds to be?
Speaker 1: What's the over-under?
Speaker 0: I don't know Who's gonna bet.
Speaker 1: I'd bet.
Speaker 1: All right, I'd bet like I'm ready legal.
Speaker 1: Oh, we'd be breaking all sorts of laws.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: All right, right.
Speaker 0: You should do some news.
Speaker 1: So in the news It looks like Apple is starting to run into the same kind of trouble Microsoft used to run into in Europe.
Speaker 0: Oh, we we.
Speaker 1: well it turns out that Norway now It's not the Norwegian government straight up But it's the Norwegian Consumer Council Which has a lot of clout has analyzed fair play and iTunes and Apple and Apple's DRM.
Speaker 1: you know fair play and the iPod and everything and They have determined that iTunes and fair play and the iTunes store Violate all sorts of laws and rules and regulations and contract law in Norway.
Speaker 0: all sorts of laws Not just one or two good God.
Speaker 1: And in fact, they have given Apple a fairly strong ultimatum that if they do not correct these problems They will be suing Apple.
Speaker 1: and the end result if they win and I don't see many ways for them to lose Would simply be that Apple would not be able to do business in Norway.
Speaker 0: I think Apple would just choose not to do business in Norway rather than comply because no lying would be bad for Apple.
Speaker 1: Now here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Sweden and Finland Have basically said yes These people are exactly right.
Speaker 0: Apple would pull out of them too.
Speaker 0: It would take like literally many many countries.
Speaker 1: just France and Germany Apparently are also coming right on board with this.
Speaker 0: possibly I don't know.
Speaker 0: I still don't know if that's enough.
Speaker 0: That's almost enough.
Speaker 1: Oh, it might not be enough.
Speaker 1: But even if you know, Apple just says alright gives him the finger and pulls out That's a pretty big PR blow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's a pretty big money hit - it's also a stat.
Speaker 0: It's not as big as the money hit they would take by opening up the fair play.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is it's like basically because Apple chose to be assholes and use these DRM.
Speaker 0: now They're stuck in a situation where okay, we can either give up, you know a bajillion dollars now or Give up two bajillion dollars.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends.
Speaker 1: I mean how many people buy an iPod just because they want to use the iTunes store as opposed to because as far as they're concerned iPod means mp3.
Speaker 0: Well, it's more an issue.
Speaker 0: It's more the opposite issue.
Speaker 0: It's that people who use the iTunes store can only use iPods.
Speaker 0: It's it's not iPods can only use the iTunes true But how many?
Speaker 1: I really wonder how many people who use the iTunes store as opposed to people like us who just use iPods Would seriously think about if they were able buying a non iPod?
Speaker 1: I think those people at least 90% of them are never going to abandon Apple unless Apple start sacrificing babies to their God.
Speaker 0: But I think people would you know buy iPods and they would just load them from some other music store with regular Mp3s like a music or that other one, but that's not.
Speaker 1: the issue is just more specifically that one fair play only works on iPods pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you buy a song from the iTunes store, you can only play it in iTunes or on an iPod.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: They're saying that's unfair restraint of trade restrictive.
Speaker 1: Whatever it is now beyond all that There's a lot more to this.
Speaker 0: That's the reason that Apple has always Continuously said even if the music companies didn't want it We would still have the DRM because they don't want you buying songs from the Apple iTunes music store Playing them on your Zune or your cheap-ass $5 Hong Kong mp3 player.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess everyone has to remember that as much as you like Apple or any company like that like Nintendo Nintendo is not your friend.
Speaker 1: No, they're no wants your money.
Speaker 1: They might do nice things to you to get your money from you but in the end their sole purpose is to get money out of your pocket
Speaker 0: and Sometimes they do things that you like and therefore you can say, okay you did something I like you could have my money and sometimes they do things you don't like.
Speaker 0: so you say no You cannot have my money this time.
Speaker 1: Well, apparently the problem stem not just from fairplay but from the iTunes and user license agreement in total.
Speaker 1: now the very interesting thing is that almost every argument they made against this EULA is equally valid against almost every software EULA And user license agreement.
Speaker 1: that thing you click OK on without reading.
Speaker 0: You know the thing that says I agree I do not agree when you install software that thing.
Speaker 0: well one.
Speaker 1: according to Scandinavian law Any written agreement it between two parties must favor both parties.
Speaker 0: You can't I can't write a contract that says rim agrees to give me $100 and Scott will kick rim in the shin Pretty much.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know the actual law but it seems that there's.
Speaker 1: there are protections that agreements cannot be exploitative and There are things where in an agreement between a strong party and a weak party The weak party has special protections outside of the contract signed and rights that cannot be waived.
Speaker 0: Hmm Alright, um
Speaker 1: also this is a big one apparently the iTunes and user license agreement contract Which almost every software license and many hardware licenses in the world has a clause near the end That says something like we can change this terms at any time without notice any reason whatever.
Speaker 0: every contract says that shit.
Speaker 1: Well according to Scandinavian law, all right This is not kosher and you can't just change that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: And in fact changing the terms of a contract like that would either invalidate the contract or they'd be forced to Honor the contract as it was signed and written until it expired.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, there was something that there's something similar to that US law I'm not a hundred percent sure but recently like singular change their text messaging rates and that you know If you called singular you could get out of your contract without paying the fee because they changed the text messaging rates.
Speaker 0: Verizon also changed the text messaging rates But apparently they got out of it and you can't cancel your Verizon contract by some loophole because Verizon is smarter than you.
Speaker 1: Ah Well, another big one here is that apparently the iTunes contract basically says that it'll follow I guess American law, but it the contract tries to specify what jurisdiction the contract should be understood in and enforced by.
Speaker 1: According to this consumer group any product that is marketed to Norwegian customers in Norway is subject to Norwegian law and Norwegian jurisdiction Period and that cannot be waived in a boilerplate contract.
Speaker 0: So if I'm a French guy and you're a French guy, which we're not and we're in France I can't write a contract that says yeah Only the American law counts on this contract.
Speaker 1: Well, you might be able to I mean in the US there are a lot of contracts to say Well, the terms of this contract shall be interpreted as per the rules and blah blah blah of Illinois.
Speaker 0: Well, yes states are different thing different countries Yeah, but I don't know what other countries laws are.
Speaker 1: but Norway very specifically seems to say that this is not the case.
Speaker 1: Specifically because not only is this a contract whatever.
Speaker 1: the product is marketed in Norway to Norwegians.
Speaker 1: It's not like this.
Speaker 1: is them going to America and buying something that is marketed there is provided there There's.
Speaker 0: yeah, they have the Norwegian iTunes store, they've got it.
Speaker 0: Norwegian language.
Speaker 0: what language they speak?
Speaker 0: Norwegians anyway Swedish.
Speaker 1: it goes on and on and it's pretty interesting article.
Speaker 1: I really can't wait to see Apple has responded to this at all.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell I guess that if Norway keeps Pushing it.
Speaker 0: They'll eventually just leave Norway and stop selling their shit there.
Speaker 1: Yeah I just don't know what ramifications will come of that if anything Apple not making money for Norwegian people anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, I know one thing will happen.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, um, what language do people in Norway speak?
Speaker 1: I'd wager the Norwegian speak Norwegian.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize there was a language Norwegian.
Speaker 1: Well according to Wikipedia Bokumol and nin yorsk.
Speaker 1: I don't know if those are dialects as Norwegian or if there are three.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they're in parentheses.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to look in.
Speaker 0: Norwegian is a Germanic language spoken primarily in Norway.
Speaker 0: I just if you click on the word Norwegian it gives you a.
Speaker 1: but I don't know what's up with Bokumol and nin yorsk.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's closely related to and generally mutually intelligible with Swedish and Danish.
Speaker 1: The more you know.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So one problem I've always had I don't know about you it when getting people to try out Linux is that they They can't fucking install it.
Speaker 0: and it's you know, it.
Speaker 0: it's not that they can't install it It's that they can't you know get a CD.
Speaker 0: They don't know how to download an ISO burn a CD and boot the CD.
Speaker 0: if you can get them to do those three things Then installing it and playing around in the live CD is no problem.
Speaker 1: Well, it doesn't help that in Windows You can't just burn an ISO.
Speaker 1: You need special software, even though it's built into Windows.
Speaker 1: There's an ISO burner built into Windows.
Speaker 1: You can use an MSI to unlock it and then you can just right-click on an ISO and say burn.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, anyway, that's what a rims pet peeves.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you know, I have a few pet peeves.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So anyway This isn't.
Speaker 0: that is one thing that someone finally thought up and that is to make a Windows program that installs Linux.
Speaker 1: What do you say?
Speaker 0: So you go to this website and you download an exe file and you run it which is something every Windows user knows how to.
Speaker 1: Of course they do.
Speaker 1: That's how they get all that spyware.
Speaker 0: Of course and you do this and What will happen is this exe will allow you to format your hard drive make a little partition for wait for Linux to go on It'll install Linux to the partition and when you reboot the computer grub will be there and the whole thing is a go.
Speaker 1: So does it leave your windows intact?
Speaker 1: is just dual boot it it.
Speaker 0: not only does it leave your windows intact, but it can handle the.
Speaker 0: You know the NTFS with all the NTFS 3g support and all sorts of other good stuff.
Speaker 0: Wow, it basically is Extracts a live CD to a partition on your hard drive.
Speaker 0: That's how it works right now and of course will work better in the future.
Speaker 0: The only disadvantage of this is whereas with the live CD you can try out Linux risk-free This isn't really risk-free.
Speaker 0: You're installing Linux and partitioning your hard drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, more importantly your live Resizing a partition.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know if it resizes.
Speaker 0: Maybe it only works if you have some free space.
Speaker 0: I haven't I haven't looked into it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try it on this computer tomorrow at work and I will get more information.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess the news here isn't that you know the specifics of this implementation.
Speaker 1: It's just that.
Speaker 1: what a good idea.
Speaker 1: Look into this.
Speaker 0: If you're someone who's wanted to try out, you know, Debian, the only one that works now is Debian Linux Which is well think about it.
Speaker 0: Debian's hard to install but now it's not.
Speaker 0: And once you see the difference really between Debian and Ubuntu Ubuntu is you know, some of the packages in Ubuntu have different patches, you know, like Ubuntu comes with the real Firefox yeah, and Debian doesn't and such like that.
Speaker 0: Well Debian also doesn't come with really software.
Speaker 0: by default You have to install a bunch of stuff or as Ubuntu comes by Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: Yeah, stop it.
Speaker 0: by default It comes with Firefox and openoffice and all that stuff and in Debian none of that stuff comes in.
Speaker 0: you have to go and get It yourself.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't go get it.
Speaker 0: You just install it.
Speaker 0: It's when you if you just install Debian, there's like nothing there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like empty.
Speaker 0: It's a barren wasteland.
Speaker 0: You have to go install all the software you get a command line You take LS.
Speaker 1: it doesn't answer because it's not bash.
Speaker 1: It's nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just raw.
Speaker 0: This Debian installer will leave you like that.
Speaker 1: Maybe it will raw binary to the processor.
Speaker 0: Yeah the point is is that now you can go to this website, which is goodbye - microsoft.com and You click on the Debian logo and it says Debian dot exe and you save it to your desktop or wherever and you run it And it'll install Debian and it's that's crazy.
Speaker 1: Wow, imagine going back in time to when you were trying to install like Red Hat 6 on something and showing yourself that yeah No, wait, check this out.
Speaker 0: Ubuntu is planning on copying this feature and I imagine we're gonna get Ubuntu dot exe some time in the future and The things that they're planning to have working in their Ubuntu dot exe are crazy Like they're planning to have it configure your network.
Speaker 0: when the first time it boots Configure X the first time it boots Automatically generate FS tab.
Speaker 0: the first time it boots all sorts of crazy stuff the first time you boot it up.
Speaker 0: and that's pretty awesome things of the day.
Speaker 0: And I'm sure you all out there know that we are fans of f1 here at geek nights.
Speaker 1: I'm about as much of a fan as f1 of f1 as I can be of any motorsport.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway There's this thing on dig about f1 recently.
Speaker 0: It was a picture of a terrible f1 accident.
Speaker 0: There's no video which is kind of sad.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess it's very thankful.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't want to see a video of that.
Speaker 0: You may have already seen it, you know, because he got 5592 digs because it was so terrible.
Speaker 0: But anyway, let me read you the The dig description of this picture because what else can I say about it?
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean you really just got to look at the picture.
Speaker 0: Yeah Excessive downforce during a shunt led to damage of key suspension resulting in going off leaving horrific wreck.
Speaker 1: now That doesn't sound like much does it?
Speaker 0: but according to the prof getting help was no longer possible.
Speaker 1: When you see the picture you realize what that was all about.
Speaker 1: That's a very clinical discussion of something Breathtaking to put it lightly.
Speaker 0: Yes, so if you You know like to look at accidents you really need to see this picture.
Speaker 1: However, the reason it got over 5,000 digs I would consider it possibly not safe for work Especially if you're a little squeamish.
Speaker 1: you might not want to look at this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, check this thing out.
Speaker 0: it's it's it's.
Speaker 1: I get the chance I get the chills just looking at it and I mean my Reaction.
Speaker 1: it took me a few minutes to realize exactly what I was looking at.
Speaker 1: yeah, if Scott hadn't told me it was an f1 accident, I might have guessed eventually from what remained.
Speaker 1: but Yeah, there's no way that guy could have gotten any help.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: There's just no words.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure I guess there's probably a thousand words.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you're all familiar with Frank Zappa.
Speaker 1: If you're not I suggest you read Wikipedia Now listen to some fucking music.
Speaker 0: what the hell.
Speaker 1: now aside from being you know a great musician and a great man Frank Zappa Did a lot for America and more specifically for the First Amendment than most people and a lot of people don't really know these days Exactly how important he was You see for all you youngins out there and even for us because we I was like three or four when this was going on.
Speaker 0: I was four.
Speaker 0: I was I was in nursery school and my brother was being born.
Speaker 1: there used to be a big issue in America where you know.
Speaker 1: today it's like hip-hop music is ruining youth and Terrorists are out there killing people in the 50s.
Speaker 0: It was OMG Elvis is moving his hips back and forth.
Speaker 1: Yep, it seems like at any given point There is a bunch of prudes who think that whatever people like at any given juncture in time is Somehow going to bring about Satanism and anarchy and doom the end of the world.
Speaker 1: Well, there is this huge movement.
Speaker 0: It's okay to have nukes.
Speaker 0: You just can't say fuck.
Speaker 1: There was a huge movement among scary conservative not jobs in America to Basically overturn the First Amendment which guarantees among other things freedom of speech and this led to among other things Congress basically sitting down and having hearings to try to figure out how to censor things in rock and roll music and radio and television and literature that were somehow Damaging to America or dangerous.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and of all the people Frank Zappa Really came through here.
Speaker 1: Not only did he testify before Congress multiple times at length and not only if you can ever get Transcripts or he read anything about Frank Zappa testifying before the Senate.
Speaker 1: he to put it in modern terms couldn't them Frank Zappa.
Speaker 1: But I mean, I don't know what you think you musicians.
Speaker 1: Frank Zappa is a very intelligent man.
Speaker 1: He's a very upstanding man.
Speaker 1: He's a wonderful man.
Speaker 1: He's one of my heroes.
Speaker 1: He's not quite on the part of that Canadian guy No, but he's a really great guy.
Speaker 1: Yep, and he put the Senate in its place and While that was awesome.
Speaker 1: There is a video of another incident where he put some people in their places, which is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Yes, he was on CNN crossfire, which is a show that I believe still exists, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah now it was four people three other people.
Speaker 1: I forget their names.
Speaker 1: I don't care Robert Novak.
Speaker 0: It was one of them.
Speaker 0: He's yeah, he's a famous guy.
Speaker 1: There was that Washington, whatever guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah God anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's even if he you don't care about the free speech issue.
Speaker 0: Just watch this to see what CNN crossfire looked like in 1986.
Speaker 1: Yeah Wow, I'll start by saying that I agree with every single thing that Frank Zappa said.
Speaker 0: I also agree with every single thing Frank Zappa said.
Speaker 1: now the interesting thing is video.
Speaker 1: you think that today You know you watch say Jon Stewart or someone cool on a show where someone's stupid or crazy Or some nutjob conservative who's like we got a band gaze and we got a band blah blah.
Speaker 1: And what?
Speaker 1: are you?
Speaker 1: a terrorist?
Speaker 1: the same thing was going on in the 80s, but back then it was what are you an anarchist?
Speaker 1: And this bit like this starts out like, you know crossfire and it's supposed to be about you know, rock music.
Speaker 1: Are these lyrics controversial?
Speaker 1: What should we do about them is should we do anything about them?
Speaker 1: but right away the tone of the video is more along the lines of how are we going to censor these horrible words?
Speaker 1: and Frank Zappa is I?
Speaker 1: I can't imagine the amount of patience it took to not punch all of them in the face.
Speaker 0: Yeah Imagine like trying to argue with Hitler that Jews are all right, and then he's just.
Speaker 0: you know, he's not getting violent He's just yelling at you all his crazy Hitlerism.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and how long did?
Speaker 0: how long could you go without just kicking him in the nuts?
Speaker 1: I mean, he'll ask you a question and then as soon as you start to answer He'll interrupt you saying that your answer was wrong.
Speaker 0: All right Go find a KKK guy and try to argue with him that black people are okay and See how long it takes before you kick him in the nuts, but this was three on one.
Speaker 1: So we got a little.
Speaker 0: it was three on one and somehow Frank Zappa didn't kick anyone the nuts.
Speaker 1: I mean he made these three people look like fools straight up and I have so much respect for the band and the moment about seven minutes in where he basically just says, you know What fuck you guys?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and with a perfectly straight face and they just lose it.
Speaker 1: and If you don't know how great a man Frank Zappa is or if you don't just watch this video The it stands alone.
Speaker 1: it stands for itself and for everything.
Speaker 1: That's wonderful.
Speaker 0: He's not as great as Lieutenant General Romeo Alain Diado, no, he's not.
Speaker 1: However, dire Frank Zappa is definitely in my top 100 people ever.
Speaker 1: Yep Romeo Dalek also the fact that he said that the Reagan administration and effectively Neoconservativism is going to push America to a the a theocratic fascist state.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait a minute, huh?
Speaker 0: Where have I seen that before?
Speaker 1: I love how the three people when he says that laugh and they're like, yeah, you're joking But seriously, you can't actually have that opinion.
Speaker 1: That's crazy.
Speaker 1: He's like, I'm dead serious and it's funny.
Speaker 0: looking back in retrospect I'm feeling like we're more Theistic fascist state now than we were in 86.
Speaker 0: What do you think?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's a little from column a little column B. Yeah, I mean there's gay marriage in some states now.
Speaker 0: We're getting a little better Yeah, but are we also have Utah?
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, right.
Speaker 1: so being Monday and realizing that many people don't actually know a lot about this We're gonna have a little bit of fun and talk on a very non technical level about all the different kinds.
Speaker 0: Well slightly technical level.
Speaker 1: I'd say that we'll talk on your parents.
Speaker 1: technical level.
Speaker 1: No, we're not gonna go grandparents.
Speaker 1: Okay, but we're not gonna go six-year-old kids.
Speaker 0: Hopefully your parents are educated But basically of media storing data the various ways and hopefully you're not old because if you're old And your parents are grandparents then we're talking to you.
Speaker 1: But I mean, you know you floppy drives and CD-ROMs and flash memory and SD cards and modems and all these, you know, HD DVD.
Speaker 1: I wonder how many of you actually know how they work on at least a basic level because some of it's kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know for all these years, you know, you just put a floppy disk in your computer You put a CD in there and burn it.
Speaker 0: But do you know actually know how that works?
Speaker 0: You know why it works the way it works, you know why.
Speaker 0: you know It's pretty interesting and it's not too complicated if you don't worry about the details and it all really comes down into two basic categories analog and digital.
Speaker 1: We don't need to go into great detail.
Speaker 1: In fact, we talked about that at length in one of our older.
Speaker 1: how computers work shows Yep, but basically you can break down all kinds of storing data into these two categories.
Speaker 1: Digital means you turn it into ones and zeros.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: ones and zeros.
Speaker 1: you quantify or quantize things into a form where ones and zeros and some sort of data Structure can describe it as well as you would ever want to describe it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and analog data is a more fuzzy set of Like say.
Speaker 1: digital is zero and one analog is any value between zero and one.
Speaker 1: yep, however analog is that doesn't mean that analog has perfect resolution or that digital skip steps because you can make digital that Skip steps so small that there's no way a human could tell and you can make analog that skips so many steps It's not?
Speaker 1: you couldn't even recognize a song in that format Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: There's all.
Speaker 1: there's a fallacy out there among a lot of very audiophile golden ear types that old analog media for audio was somehow superior when in fact, it's vastly Inferior is incredibly inferior.
Speaker 0: I mean you mean it's true that you know Vinyl record does sound different from a CD and you might.
Speaker 0: you might prefer the sound of vinyl record to the sound of a CD.
Speaker 0: that's preference.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: But there is no arguing that the quality, you know, the numerical quality the quantifiable quality of the audio that is on a compact disc is Beyond compare when it comes to at least a vinyl record.
Speaker 0: You need a super audio CD or a wave file to beat a CD.
Speaker 0: It's pretty tough.
Speaker 1: So analog media, I mean what?
Speaker 1: what analog media do people even use nowadays?
Speaker 1: I mean, no one uses cassette tapes anymore.
Speaker 0: Really someone might use a vinyl record if they're a DJ.
Speaker 0: Vinyl record works.
Speaker 0: It's a big record with bumps on it and this needle goes in the groove and it bounces on the bumps and The bumps are all different sizes and shapes and different distances apart and when the needle bumps up and down Music comes out the other end.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, it also kind of bumps left and right.
Speaker 1: Yep We're not gonna go into detail but suffice to say actually the way Records work and the way they make them sound the way they do is very interesting.
Speaker 1: I mean you actually have to apply a crazy Crazy equalization filter to anything you put on a record.
Speaker 1: Otherwise anytime there was a bass beat it would throw the needle out of the grooves.
Speaker 1: Yep, and You high frequency stuff wouldn't even register because you couldn't make grooves that small.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean if you take the needle the needle doesn't move around that much You know.
Speaker 0: if you just take it and like poke it with your finger all sorts of crazy noises come out.
Speaker 0: The record has to very subtly and accurately move the needle in the correct way with the correct amount of force to get the right Sounds to come out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now cassette tapes are very simple.
Speaker 1: You just take a magnetic field and you impart that magnet.
Speaker 1: I mean you you make the magnetic field manipulate the tape.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically if you take a plastic tape and you put like iron Ferro whatnot, you know magnetic cruft in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you put it on both sides.
Speaker 0: Just like it's magnetic paint.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's just iron paint and you put it on both sides.
Speaker 0: Well, that would it's not really iron paint.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's not really both side.
Speaker 0: I mean when you talk about the two sides Oh, yeah, if it's a cassette tape, it's it's one side.
Speaker 1: Basically, I mean cassette tapes have two sides, but it's really the left side and the right side.
Speaker 0: Yeah at the top of the bottom.
Speaker 0: That's a cassette tape.
Speaker 0: But anyway other things that use the same mechanism do use both sides.
Speaker 0: but now you have this tape and You have basically this magnetic head that can magnetize and demagnetize the tape in different positions.
Speaker 0: So, you know, let's say you have a spot on the tape you magnetize it.
Speaker 0: It stays magnetized unless of course another magnet comes along and screws it up.
Speaker 0: So it's basically when you want to read the tape.
Speaker 0: it goes down the tape and it's magnetized not magnetized.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like the magnetic equivalent of the grooves on a record.
Speaker 1: You're making a magnetic field that changes in relation to the audio out there.
Speaker 1: That magnetic field is being created in space and there's a tape moving through that space.
Speaker 1: So the magnetic field that's moving in space changes the magnetic properties of the tape as it goes by.
Speaker 1: Then you can use a device that will read those magnetic fluctuations back from the tape.
Speaker 0: So instead of physical bumps moving a needle up and down this magnetic field That's on the tape moves a magnet around and when that magnet moves music comes out.
Speaker 1: Essentially now, of course, it's a lot more complicated than that.
Speaker 1: You actually if you just tried to do that I mean way back people realize this would work a long time ago But they couldn't make anything intelligible come out because it turned out that if you just did that with a magnet Due to various things that we're not going to get into what you would get when you played it back was garbage and you had To do special things to the tape before you recorded audio to it And you had to make the audio look a certain way to make the stuff come back.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's why tapes weren't the best quality.
Speaker 0: Yeah And you would go to the store and you get like these hi-fi tapes and they had DAT tapes and all sorts of crazy.
Speaker 1: Well, DAT is digital.
Speaker 0: DAT is digital, but you know, totally different.
Speaker 0: It's still magnetic.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Just real quick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of people seem to think that cassette tapes and VCR, you know VHS tapes basically work the same way and all I'm going to tell you is that not really I mean on a fundamental level Yes, but if you have time go to like how stuff works and look at how a VCR a VHS VCR actually reads a tape.
Speaker 1: It's not the way you think.
Speaker 0: no I mean, it's the same kind of principle of you have a tape that's magnetized in different amounts on different spots on the tape.
Speaker 0: Yep, but because there's it's a video with audio.
Speaker 1: That's a lot of data.
Speaker 0: That's a lot of data.
Speaker 0: How do you get so much data into such a small amount of tape?
Speaker 0: I mean back in the day they'll use big reels of magnetic tape to put stuff on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're using this little tiny VCR video cassette.
Speaker 0: It's not an inch wide and it's holding a whole movie.
Speaker 0: I mean you and you download a movie from the internet.
Speaker 0: It's it might be might even be a gigabyte.
Speaker 0: Who knows it's hundreds of megabytes at the least.
Speaker 1: Yeah for like a half hour and think it's not even an inch wide And it doesn't move that fast.
Speaker 1: So, how do you get that much data out of a piece of poorly magnetic tape?
Speaker 1: That's moving relatively slowly because you have to get all the data for a given frame at the same time or it's useless.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's so.
Speaker 0: I guess you could buffer it up But they didn't have the memory that buffer it up.
Speaker 0: if they had that they wouldn't need visa VGS tapes.
Speaker 1: The answer is essentially that they actually stored the data at a really wide like at an angle and it's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: It's pretty tricky the way they did that.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean while old technology seems old and archaic the Limitations people had to work with even as recently as the 90s with a lot of this stuff forced a lot of really innovative solutions and I'd say that a lot of old technology at least from The non this perspective here is a lot more interesting than modern technology.
Speaker 0: It is more interesting because nowadays it's like, okay We have a hard drive.
Speaker 0: Well, what can we do?
Speaker 0: I know let's make the hard drive bigger.
Speaker 0: Oh, look, we found a way to make it bigger instead of huh?
Speaker 0: We haven't found a way to make it bigger.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have to pull some tricks in order to make it big.
Speaker 0: Get more out of what we've already got, you know.
Speaker 0: And that's why hacks are always interesting because hacking is all about getting more From what you've already got as opposed to just getting more.
Speaker 1: Yep, because now especially the digital media You can almost always make up for any other deficiency with more processing power or more data manipulation or buffering or something like that.
Speaker 1: Those weren't options back in the day.
Speaker 0: It's a lot more impressive when a guy takes, you know, like a piece of shit Chevy like Cavalier that was $5,000 and makes it 500 horsepower.
Speaker 0: then one a guy just gets a lot of money and buys a Ferrari.
Speaker 1: That's a good way to put it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but enough analog because I don't want to get into things like FM radio, but Well, actually this is one more thing I want to say about tapes.
Speaker 0: is that tapes are not just used for audio.
Speaker 0: tapes are used for computers.
Speaker 1: Ah, yes.
Speaker 1: In fact, there was a thing for the Atari where you could record games to a audio cassette.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean the Apple computers pretty much any computer.
Speaker 0: you had any personal computer, you know after the Altair when they actually made personal Computers they would have in your house.
Speaker 0: They didn't have cartridges.
Speaker 0: They didn't have floppy disks.
Speaker 0: They had cassettes.
Speaker 0: you would take a cassette tape put it in a cassette deck it would basically play it and it would play into your computer and that would load software from the cassette tape into the computer and It basically worked, you know, if you ever used a modem a dial-up modem you hear it making all these noises like That's the sound of digital data being sent out Audio wise.
Speaker 1: well, it's digital data being sent in effectively an analog medium Yes.
Speaker 0: So if you just record let's say you put because I meet modems It is a little secret.
Speaker 0: if you ever noticed back in the day a lot of Packard Bell computers and other shitty computers the modem and the sound card would be the same thing.
Speaker 0: maybe because a modem is Basically a sound card with a phone hole on it.
Speaker 1: Yep, even more there used to be some contest among, you know Super cool hacker types back when modems were really slow To try and whistle and warble and make noises to get a modem to respond to you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: a telephone line.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 0: You talk on it?
Speaker 0: You send audio data over it.
Speaker 0: So what does the modem do?
Speaker 0: it converts digital computer data?
Speaker 0: Into audio sends it over the phone line as if it was you talking and the computer on the other end listens to the talking And talks back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we're not talking 56k.
Speaker 1: That was a wholly different thing.
Speaker 1: back in the day Modems were just audio data.
Speaker 1: There was no digital component along the line.
Speaker 1: You were sending it over the exact same path that your voice went over Yep.
Speaker 0: So back in the way back in the day all you had was a cassette tape and you would play the cassette tape into the Computer.
Speaker 0: and it worked the same way as a modem.
Speaker 0: does the computer listen to the cassette tape talk to it?
Speaker 0: And that was the data, you know, the cassette tape would basically go one zero one zero Yeah, all kinds of nasty noises.
Speaker 0: That was before we invented the floppy disk, you know to this day not gonna talk about punch cards.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: or or punch tape.
Speaker 1: No or any of that.
Speaker 0: No, cuz it's not really that interesting It works like a scantron sheet.
Speaker 1: the end floppy disks are kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: floppy disks are very interesting.
Speaker 0: they work with the same basic principle as You know tapes and big reel-to-reel tapes and cassette tapes.
Speaker 0: and you know, it's it's magnetic.
Speaker 0: There's a magnet that makes parts of the tape Magnetic and not magnetic.
Speaker 0: However, a floppy disk doesn't go from reel to reel.
Speaker 0: You don't have to read it from beginning to end you can.
Speaker 0: it's a disk.
Speaker 0: It's if you take the plastic off you.
Speaker 0: most people probably took the plastic of a floppy disk.
Speaker 0: It's a big magnetic disk and You can read either the part that's close to the middle or close to the edge and it spins around so you can go to any part of this disk that you want and Read any part of it you want and write any part of it you want.
Speaker 0: you don't have to move it very far I mean it takes this little tiny motor.
Speaker 0: it takes it less than a second to spin the whole thing around and You can move the reader and the writer back and forth, you know from one end to the other pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: so Instead of having to read something from beginning to end or write it from beginning to end and waiting for a whole tape to play You could just read and write any part of this disk you want with the same, you know magnet No magnet and that's what a floppy disk does.
Speaker 1: Yep Now the interesting thing is that floppy disks just especially all floppy disks really were actually kind of messy in terms of how they were Just because the technology wasn't quite there yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah As a result you could do clever things if you messed with your floppy drive Like you could change the angle of the head or whatever And write data to a floppy disk that couldn't be read by another standard floppy drive But could be read by any drive that you would equally modified.
Speaker 1: in fact A lot of people with older computers back then would have a problem where they could use their floppy disk.
Speaker 1: just fine.
Speaker 1: But if they went to their friend's house No one could read their floppy disk because their floppy drive was messed up.
Speaker 1: the head would drift over time due to I don't know Being a cheap floppy drive or whatever.
Speaker 1: And a lot of people just because they didn't know how how floppy drives worked had no idea What was going on.
Speaker 1: and imagine that you burn cds.
Speaker 1: they work fine in your computer.
Speaker 1: They don't work in anyone else's computer except maybe crazy joe's computer down the street in his basement.
Speaker 0: Yeah So you could always take your floppy drive to someone's house if you had a small kind if you're lucky.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, I just want to shock people a little bit.
Speaker 0: The first floppy disk was the ibm 23 fd.
Speaker 0: It was eight inches.
Speaker 0: It was introduced in 1969.
Speaker 0: Can you guess how much data you could put on it?
Speaker 1: 4k?
Speaker 1: 81.66 kilobytes, it's not bad.
Speaker 0: But compare that to today that doesn't even store a single microsoft word file.
Speaker 0: Now that's how small this is.
Speaker 1: I have text files bigger than that.
Speaker 0: I also have text files bigger than that.
Speaker 0: It's basically useless.
Speaker 0: and think about this even for most of the floppy disk days.
Speaker 0: We used 1.44 megabyte floppy disks.
Speaker 0: that doesn't even hold An mp3 of any reasonable length.
Speaker 0: It's so small.
Speaker 0: It barely holds two pictures.
Speaker 0: It's so ridiculous.
Speaker 1: Now aside from I mean moving on from that you've all used cds.
Speaker 0: cds have been the gold standard for a long time And cds are the first thing that we're going to talk about now.
Speaker 1: We're not going to talk about red book, whatever or all the actual standards.
Speaker 1: Who developed it?
Speaker 1: That's all stuff you don't care about.
Speaker 1: cds while they're really shiny And while they were absolutely amazing to most people when they came out are not quite as uh, I don't know Really cool or revolutionary or crazy as you might think if you really look at how they work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a cd is what's known as an optical disc now optical.
Speaker 0: What does that mean?
Speaker 0: that the eyeballs eyeballs optics opticians?
Speaker 0: It's about seeing.
Speaker 0: it uses light not magnets.
Speaker 0: light.
Speaker 0: There's a laser in the cd drive and it points the laser at the cd and just like a floppy drive You know It moves the laser closer to the middle of the cd and close to the edge of the cd and it spins the cd around And the laser literally looks at the cd and it bounces off the cd.
Speaker 0: And in the cd if you get real close you can see There are these pits in the cd.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: There's basically a groove a spiral that goes all the way from the middle of this The outer the disc.
Speaker 0: it's one long spiral Just like on a record only where the record had all kinds of different bumps.
Speaker 0: the cd pretty much either has a bump Or not a bump.
Speaker 0: That's all it has is bump and not bump.
Speaker 0: if the laser sees a bump I don't know if that's zero or one I forget but it's it.
Speaker 0: that's basically how it is.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: You just look at the bumps.
Speaker 1: theoretically if you had a high enough resolution scanner You could scan a cd.
Speaker 0: There was a guy who did that.
Speaker 0: He had a fancy scanner and put the cd on the scanner.
Speaker 0: He scanned the cd and then it made a file that was 640 megabytes on his hard drive.
Speaker 0: that was the same as what was on the cd.
Speaker 0: It was pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: Now the methods of making cds changed over the years and the cds used to be thicker And there's all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: but an interesting thing that a lot of people don't seem to realize Take a cd and look at it, right?
Speaker 1: It's got the shiny side where all the data is And on the other side, there's usually a label or some kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Now, where do you think the data is stored on your cd?
Speaker 1: Where do you think it actually sits?
Speaker 0: Well, see at first I always thought that you know, obviously the very bottom is plastic and the top is paint.
Speaker 0: So the you know, the actual grooves and things must be some layer in the middle.
Speaker 1: Well in old old cds that was the case.
Speaker 1: there used to be plastic sheathing on both sides.
Speaker 0: Oh, they used to put the cd in like a plastic kind of.
Speaker 0: uh, what was it called?
Speaker 1: My uncle had one of those drives.
Speaker 1: we had to put the cd in basically a special cd cartridge and then put that in The cd drive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because they you know They didn't want the cds wobbling all over the place and they didn't yet develop the technology where it was okay If the cd wasn't perfect, yeah, you know cds are like 40x 80x whatever.
Speaker 1: that is the Because originally cd run for all 1x meaning they read a cd at the rate of playing audio from a cd.
Speaker 1: That means if you wanted to read an entire cd, it took an hour.
Speaker 0: It was really slow.
Speaker 0: I mean you used to distribute these uh Encyclopedias on cd and it to open up any page on the encyclopedia was slower than opening up a page on wikipedia.
Speaker 1: I'm, so glad the internet obviated the need for uh, yeah But the data Effectively, I mean you're looking at your cd, right?
Speaker 1: The data is just on the other side of that label and if you scratch some of the label off You're gonna ruin that cd.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, if you scratch the shiny side All you have to do is buff the whole thing down evenly And the data is still there and it's fine and you can read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course buffing cds has always proved to be uh painful and usually doesn't work unless you do it really professionally.
Speaker 0: All those like doctor cd fixer things are a bunch of crap.
Speaker 1: I mean they can work in some situations.
Speaker 0: But well in general and the only time I tried to use one of those is my friend gave me a copy of final fantasy 7 for the pc and at one of the fmvs it see it was a scratch in the bottom of the cd.
Speaker 0: So there's no way to continue with the game.
Speaker 0: Because think about it.
Speaker 0: if there's a scratch in the cd the laser is looking at the cd.
Speaker 0: if there's a scratch It doesn't see the right thing and that's why it screws up.
Speaker 1: now You might be thinking I have a lot of cds and a lot of them are scratched to hell but yet they still play well one.
Speaker 1: Holding cds is not a difficult skill.
Speaker 1: to this day.
Speaker 1: I cringe when I see people that handle dvds and cds and any kind of medium like this wrong.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna lay it on a table lay it with the label down So you're not scratching the good bit.
Speaker 1: the dust isn't gonna hurt it.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna pick it up put a finger in the hole put a finger on the edge and don't touch the shiny part Or drop it like I just did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should not touch the bottom of a cd because If there's smudges on it, it's really hard for the laser to see the dots.
Speaker 1: And if you have a dvd and you're watching it and you're done with it Don't just leave it laying on the floor.
Speaker 1: good god put it back in this dvd case.
Speaker 1: I do that.
Speaker 1: I can't even as a kid.
Speaker 1: I remember that all my friends cds would be scratched to utter fucking hell.
Speaker 1: And my cds were I. I one cd ever got scratched and that's because the cd case broke and it bounced around in there for a day And I was mortified and I rebought the cd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway How come it still reads that data?
Speaker 0: Well, but yeah, because I mean sometimes it gets scratched and it's game over.
Speaker 0: but sometimes it gets scratched and it's like, oh It's still good.
Speaker 0: It's still good.
Speaker 1: Well cd was such a robust standard that they thought so far ahead they knew That you're probably going to scratch your cds.
Speaker 1: And normally any scratch anywhere on a me on something like this any single bit being wrong basically makes the whole thing useless.
Speaker 1: Well, all the bits on the cd aren't used to hold your data.
Speaker 1: In fact a lot of the bits Are used purely as redundancy.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of redundancy built into cds so that if you scratch it The laser can get the data elsewhere or based on the data around it.
Speaker 1: You can recreate the data that's missing.
Speaker 1: Yep Wasn't as much of an issue for audio cds.
Speaker 1: because you don't you're basically recreating an analog sound.
Speaker 1: so if you play an audio cd and there's a scratch a good cd player will just skip it or Interpolate what it thinks the noise would have been in that microsecond and just kind of make a staticky noise.
Speaker 1: And with digital data, there's just all this redundancy.
Speaker 1: Now people trying to put drm on cds tried to put stuff in there instead and all that did was make cds that break The moment you look at them.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, okay now dvds aren't basically the same as cds.
Speaker 0: It works with the same principle as a laser and it looks at the dvd.
Speaker 0: Only it can.
Speaker 0: there's a lot more dots there because they're closer together.
Speaker 0: They're smaller the laser's better and there's multiple layers.
Speaker 0: They use refraction and reflection so that you know, even though it's just the same amount of surface area on the bottom They can actually bounce the laser to look at things and go one layer up into the disc.
Speaker 0: and it's all sort of crazy.
Speaker 1: Early dvds were not multi-layer.
Speaker 0: No, they weren't.
Speaker 1: in fact early dvds couldn't hold some movies in their entirety.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean think about this, you know those little like holograms you'll get where you look at it one way And you see a guy with like a thumbs up and you look at it the right You angle it differently and you see a guy with the thumbs down.
Speaker 0: That's kind of how dvd layers work.
Speaker 0: The laser looks at it one way and it sees one thing.
Speaker 0: then it looks at it the other way and it sees another thing.
Speaker 0: So you're holding, you know twice as much stuff without making the dvd any bigger, you know laser discs.
Speaker 0: That was before they invented multiple layers.
Speaker 0: They just had a big giant disc that was basically the same as a cd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just bigger.
Speaker 0: It was just huge so that you could actually fit a whole movie on it, but it kind of sucked.
Speaker 1: Now, you know hd dvd blu-ray all these new things They're basically The same as a cd.
Speaker 1: just technology to do that exact thing has gotten better and better and better.
Speaker 1: They use different lasers and different reflections The blu-ray uses.
Speaker 0: the blu-ray gets its name from a blue laser, which is much higher frequency more powerful more dangerous But more precise and it can.
Speaker 0: you can have the dots be a lot smaller and you can hold a lot more data And a lot less space just by looking at it.
Speaker 1: But at the same time think of this.
Speaker 1: there's a lot.
Speaker 1: the data density is a lot more because it's still the same size as A cd but you've got so much more data on there.
Speaker 1: So an average scratch covers a lot more bits than it covers on a cd.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 1: Now I not enough people have had enough experience with blu-ray and hd dvd to know if this is going to be a serious issue Or I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean if you scratch a cd, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say a cd has a bunch of uh, Mp3s on it, right?
Speaker 0: It's not a music cd.
Speaker 0: It's an mp3 cd.
Speaker 0: one scratch might kill One mp3, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe two.
Speaker 0: if it's a normal scratch, you know.
Speaker 0: Say a fingernail scratch.
Speaker 0: if you have a blu-ray disc, let's say you fill the whole thing with mp3s.
Speaker 0: now There's a lot more mp3s there and one scratch, you know, that's the same size might lose the same percentage but you're gonna.
Speaker 0: that percentage is you know, one percent of ten mp3s is Not so many.
Speaker 0: one percent of a billion mp3s is a lot more.
Speaker 0: One of the last things I want to tell you is how a cd burns.
Speaker 0: I mean a cd from a factory.
Speaker 0: they do it with a special machine and they do it really well.
Speaker 1: god I have a audio textbook from the 90s and it shows how they used to make cds talk about clean room scary.
Speaker 0: Good god Yeah, nowadays you burn cds the cdr now, how does that work?
Speaker 0: I mean it's hard to put bumps in something when there's plastic in the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah contrary to popular belief You're not burning little pits into the cd.
Speaker 0: No, that would be too professional.
Speaker 1: But think of this, uh when you read a cd It basically the light comes back or the light doesn't come back.
Speaker 0: if there's a it comes back differently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if there's a pit or not a pit.
Speaker 0: So the reason the bottom of a cdr is blue Or red or black or green or whatever or whatever color they put at the bottom of the cdr.
Speaker 0: But usually it's sort of this bluish purple.
Speaker 0: It's because there's ink in there and there's a different.
Speaker 0: There's a better a different kind of laser.
Speaker 0: It's not really different.
Speaker 0: but they use the laser in a different way and they you know They hold it there for longer and it points at the bottom of the cd.
Speaker 0: And when the laser hits this special ink in a special way It burns the ink and the ink changes color.
Speaker 0: so you can put dots in the bottom of a cdr By burning this ink thus writing data to a cd that can later be read by any other cd drive.
Speaker 1: So instead of reading pits and non-pits is reading dark spots and non-dark spots.
Speaker 1: Yep Now we could go on and we would accept that we've already gone for pretty long as the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't talk about flash.
Speaker 1: You'll have to find that out on your own or all sorts of things or wait for another show like magneto optical Which is really kind of cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or we didn't even talk about hard drives, but hard drives are basically just better magnets.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I guess one is if some of our analogies weren't exactly perfect We really really tried to not be technical and to explain things in easy to understand terms.
Speaker 0: Yes, so don't tell us.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, you got it wrong.
Speaker 1: Technically a cd would be a better metaphor of blah because we know we're perfectly aware We're trying to make this a little bit accessible.
Speaker 1: Yes, and two if you thought that was cool Uh, let us know.
Speaker 1: we could either go into much more depth on any or all of those topics the ones we just talked about or we could do another show and talk about all the other things like flash and magneto optical and Cdrw, which is kind of cool actually.
Speaker 0: and uh that rosetta thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, but uh, yeah, if you want to find more information on your own you can go to howstuffworks.com Or wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Yes, actually howstuffworks.com is pretty fantastic.
Speaker 0: I must say At howstuffworks.com you can find out basically how any part of your computer works or your car.
Speaker 1: I remember way back I look I didn't actually know how an automatic transmission worked.
Speaker 1: So I I watched an animation on how stuff works and I was like, oh that's kind of cool planetary gears for the win.
Speaker 0: All right I think the show's over.
Speaker 1: I think it is.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map And links to all the rss feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and rpgs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via odeo.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an odeo on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in itunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.