Speaker 1: It's Wednesday June 27th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we discuss our second annual trip to the museum and of comic and cartoon art arts festival.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Warm today warm yesterday even warmer today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fucking it's hot.
Speaker 0: It's hot outside.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: is it actually?
Speaker 1: I don't think it actually is warmer today than yesterday.
Speaker 1: It's just because I'm used to it from yesterday.
Speaker 0: It is more humid today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yesterday was definitely fucking warm and today is also fucking warm warmer.
Speaker 1: These are the two warmest days of the year so far without a doubt.
Speaker 0: yep Which we can definitely see because today the power went out all over the Upper East Side.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and all over the Bronx.
Speaker 1: I think that was due to a thunderstorm action.
Speaker 0: No it looks like it was a distribution problem.
Speaker 1: I was I could I didn't actually hear the news But I someone was like thunderstorm something something and someone else is like power out something something.
Speaker 0: What I saw on the news talked about an explosion somewhere in the Bronx as a transformer just had a problem.
Speaker 1: Well as a result the the six train stopped working.
Speaker 1: I basically went down into the subway.
Speaker 1: the sixth train was not working, and they wouldn't let me through the turnstile.
Speaker 1: So I walked two blocks to the other six train entrance and when I walked down the stairs the train was working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't know what.
Speaker 1: I guess I just got off of work at the exact moment the train was fixed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well Metro North luckily.
Speaker 0: There's a light little bit of a delay for me, but by the time Scott got on the train I think everything was working normally.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my train uses a you know a fossil fuel engine half of the way, so it made it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what.
Speaker 0: so does the train I was taking?
Speaker 0: it was just delayed because of some other train in the way.
Speaker 1: See that's the thing about Grand Central is?
Speaker 1: you know there's a whole bunch of tracks and in Grand Central But they all pretty much go out to four tracks At 125th Street.
Speaker 1: So if there's four trains Every other train on both sides has to wait for those trains to get out into the wherever they're going.
Speaker 0: yep of course It's weird how I really hated sitting in the heat outside of Croton Harmon waiting for my late connecting train.
Speaker 0: I thought I was gonna miss it, but then ah my trains late my connecting trains late.
Speaker 0: Everything's cool, but That was the most oppressive part just sitting there in the Sun.
Speaker 0: My only choice was either sit in the Sun and be hot and there's no wind at all because there's trains in the way And the Sun's just bearing down on me Or I could go inside the unairconditioned greenhouse Which was otherwise known as the shelter and basically be cooked yeah?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta tell you walking from the train to my car was the suck, but yeah luckily It was only a couple minutes.
Speaker 0: riding my bike two miles home in the heat up The hill was nothing compared to sitting in that Sun.
Speaker 1: well I mean because you're moving you got some wind blowing on you, and if you ride your bike even when it's not warm out You're gonna get warm, so it doesn't feel any different or weird Whatever today.
Speaker 1: We're keeping the air conditioner on during the show.
Speaker 1: It's on right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's gonna stay on.
Speaker 1: I Listened to the episode yesterday, and I did not hear the air conditioner.
Speaker 1: I will listen to the episode we're recording right now later to see if I hear the air conditioner and Hopefully we'll be able to keep the air conditioner on during the show.
Speaker 1: if I don't hear anything.
Speaker 0: But enough meta because both of us have some pretty important news I think I'll let Scott go first because this is something that is very dear to us, and we've talked about it before.
Speaker 1: Well there haven't been that many awesome new animes in recent years.
Speaker 1: I mean there are a couple movies like the paprika and whatever and There this season there's a couple shows like Volcarano and such claymore claymore that are pretty hot But they're not like awesome animes of all time that will watch again and again.
Speaker 1: It's yes It's something I would Netflix and that's something I would buy.
Speaker 0: they're not cowboy bebop They're not the show where I'll forgo all other forms of entertainment Like I'll come home from work and say I gotta watch the next episode.
Speaker 0: I gotta see it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Oh Nana.
Speaker 1: I guess but that's also a Netflixing show.
Speaker 0: That's just because we lost track and we stopped watching at like one critical juncture And then the fan subs just went way beyond us.
Speaker 1: yeah, anyway, the one show in recent years that I've cared a whole lot about and wanted to see desperately is project blue cheek.
Speaker 1: you SOS project blue earth SOS cheek you means earth and We talked about it in an episode and basically.
Speaker 1: It's it's an OVA of six episodes not an OAV.
Speaker 1: Yes, each episode is 45 minutes long about and it's fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: We did an episode on it.
Speaker 1: if you want to know more about the show you can go listen to that episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really really simply imagine a future sci-fi show But the future sci-fi as envisioned in the 50s.
Speaker 1: if you like the read or die OAV you'll like this.
Speaker 0: you'll like this a lot.
Speaker 0: if you like encyclopedia brown you like this.
Speaker 0: if you like the idea of Spaceships coexisting with flash powder cameras and reel to reels.
Speaker 0: This is for you.
Speaker 1: Yes, so This show.
Speaker 1: today a TV just announced that they have licensed this show.
Speaker 0: hot shit.
Speaker 0: It's about time.
Speaker 0: Why didn't they license it earlier?
Speaker 0: What was the story?
Speaker 0: Why did this get delayed?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: it just says we are proud to announce we have licensed this show for distribution in the u.s Blabbity blabbity blah.
Speaker 1: I I'm so happy that this was licensed that I'm pretty much gonna buy this as soon as it comes out.
Speaker 1: But there's a chance I won't because remember it's six 45 minute episodes.
Speaker 1: Right if they release this on One set like you buy it for like $30 you get the whole show.
Speaker 1: even $40 you get the whole show.
Speaker 0: I might pay 50.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't pay 50 for the whole show.
Speaker 1: I might but if they do this like three separate DVD business where each DVD has two Episodes and each DVD is full retail price.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna give them the big double deuce until they lower that price down and sell it in one set.
Speaker 0: Well, you're probably gonna have to wait.
Speaker 1: remember what happened with blue sub six, yeah Yeah, that was bullshit, but that was in the olden days.
Speaker 1: and well I'm pretty confident that they are going to release it in two discs of three episodes each.
Speaker 0: That is my prediction.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty confident that they're gonna drag it out and I I would imagine that they're going to market this heavily Cuz.
Speaker 0: it does kind of stand out.
Speaker 0: I mean the fact that they picked it up Relatively quickly despite the fact that I was complaining about how long it took Says something and it's a show that's really different from a lot of other shows that are out right now And it has high production values and I could see if they marketed it right making a lot of money off of it.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think they can make a lot of money off the show.
Speaker 1: I think that what this is is it shows you that CPM is gone, right and ADV unlike Funimation and Genian who mostly you know are very big licensed shows because they want to sell them and they try to sell every show they get.
Speaker 1: ADV still occasionally is gonna license a show just because they think it's awesome whether they think it's gonna sell or not.
Speaker 1: and while ADV You know is not perfect in terms of anime releasing like I don't know who is perfect in terms of anime releasing Ah, no one.
Speaker 1: anime egos kind of perfect.
Speaker 1: It's just they don't do quantity They just do quality.
Speaker 0: and I've had some good ones regular bandai not bandai vision.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're their problems.
Speaker 1: But you know ADV I think is is showing that they're still there for the fans as well as there for the monies Depending on the price and all that.
Speaker 0: I would I'd highly recommend you pay just about anything for this at least for the first episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty much I'm gonna when it comes out.
Speaker 1: I'll see what the you know, there's no release date yet.
Speaker 1: So I'll see what the episode per discount and the prices and then I'll either buy it on Amazon right away Or I'll wait till I see it at a convention and get it then.
Speaker 1: or who knows it depends on a lot of things But by this show if you buy any anime in the next year or two, this is it.
Speaker 0: Yes Right.
Speaker 0: So in the other related unrelated semi related anime news Otakon has finally started to get its act together at least in the sense that we know the musical acts are.
Speaker 0: They've for the most part dealt with the panel situation and a couple other things.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna start right off that.
Speaker 0: the two musical acts this year one is triple-a Attack all around.
Speaker 0: I don't know much about him.
Speaker 1: That sounds the opposite of me.
Speaker 1: I'm attack only one.
Speaker 1: So how are they attack all around that their philosophies do not match?
Speaker 0: Well, it looks like they did.
Speaker 0: the theme song to the live-action initial D Terrible live-action initial D. The music was okay Music.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the music wasn't so bad.
Speaker 1: I don't remember it being bad or good.
Speaker 1: So yeah, whatever I'm sure they're a band that will play live and I imagine some sort of music.
Speaker 0: So I'm ambivalent partly because last year I hadn't heard a mock and I figured I stopped the same thing about muck and muck was Awesome.
Speaker 1: Yep, so, you know, we'll just have to wait and see on the triple-a.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I wish their name was attack only one A OO yep, but much more important and much more interesting and this is the concert that I am going to kill people to see Eminence.
Speaker 0: to sum it up.
Speaker 0: They take violins and various classical instruments and they perform anime video game music.
Speaker 0: Titles will include this is quoting from the Otakon website dot hack Gundam seed Princess Mononoke Lapita Ava noir Totoro crud across Dino saga Romeo ex Juliet and Other memorable themes to name a few.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is pretty good actually because you know Even though many people probably haven't heard of Eminence I don't know who these specific people are.
Speaker 1: the the idea of playing geeky music with.
Speaker 1: you know A classical orchestra or a string quartet or any sort of other?
Speaker 1: Classical arrangement is very popular these days.
Speaker 1: the video games live is popular.
Speaker 0: Oh the video game pianist pianist is popular was a pretty cool dude.
Speaker 1: whenever they release, you know They release like orchestral soundtracks of like, you know Final Fantasy Phoenix Wright music even the Final Fantasy that's in phonics sweets, which was recorded live in Japan.
Speaker 0: a long time brothers I Imported that when I was in high school and I paid $40 for it.
Speaker 1: This kind of stuff is becoming very popular in the geek culture and it's still you know Maintaining its popularity and in fact a lot of you know orchestras and things weren't making so much money doing their typical classical musics.
Speaker 1: you know their Beethoven's and their Mozart's and a lot of them have decided to start playing geeky music and holding those sorts of concerts and they found They're making a lot more money that way.
Speaker 0: I see this being very similar to what I imagine was the motivation behind not all but definitely some of the nerdcore artists out there.
Speaker 0: It seems like not to name names but a lot of the mediocre to average nerdcore rappers.
Speaker 0: We're just crappy normal rappers and realize that there's this weird niche market that will give them an automatic plus three to sales Just because they sing about D&D instead of hoes.
Speaker 1: I think that while there are a few people like that I think that a greater percentage of the nerdcore rappers are either people who happen to be like rap and Were geeks or geeks who saw nerdcore rap and decided to start rapping.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah but I definitely I think that it was a factor in the decision of some of these people.
Speaker 1: not there is indeed
Speaker 0: and I think I mean, I'm definitely not the case with these people But yeah I could see a lot of the people doing this if you've got a skill and you find an audience that is willing to pay You to exhibit your skill in a way that's very easy to exhibit.
Speaker 0: I mean most of this video game music except I assume they'll have some special arrange things for this.
Speaker 0: It's pretty easy to play.
Speaker 0: I mean I can play the Zelda theme.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's not a hard one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why the video game pianist.
Speaker 1: He adds a whole lot to the music.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, he also noticed how he'd play video game video game real song.
Speaker 0: video game video game real song.
Speaker 1: Yep, I think part of that is he's trying to show you.
Speaker 1: Hey, the real songs are awesome, too Yeah, but the quote real song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't want to imply the song is it's not.
Speaker 1: you can't make a fake song.
Speaker 1: It's either a song or not.
Speaker 0: I don't want to imply that video game music is somehow less here.
Speaker 1: This is a song doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Speaker 1: That was a song right there.
Speaker 0: I mean music by no boo.
Speaker 0: Yep, but also Otakon.
Speaker 0: There's a good and a bad about what's been going on with panels.
Speaker 0: as you all know There were some issues with panels at Otakon.
Speaker 0: we complained about it a while ago.
Speaker 0: several Otakon staffers got back with us within an hour of our episode going up haha and The situation is somewhat resolved.
Speaker 0: Otakon has released the list of the panels that are going to be at Otakon.
Speaker 0: Four of them are our band panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah the fan panel.
Speaker 0: They list the industry panels - oh, that's good.
Speaker 0: And of course those.
Speaker 0: well, they were on the same list at the same time.
Speaker 1: No, I think I looked at it right away and there they were there.
Speaker 1: They were not there immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were later.
Speaker 0: I think I'm pretty sure they were there Scott.
Speaker 1: Uh, I'm a hundred percent sure that at as deep when they post the at the moment.
Speaker 0: They what do you say?
Speaker 1: They originally posted the fan panels the under the industry panels heading.
Speaker 1: It said coming soon.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Oh, well, I'm doubtful.
Speaker 0: I don't believe you.
Speaker 1: I will just have to find someone else who looked at that immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one because no one seemed to know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah I'm not gonna really go over the whole list other than that.
Speaker 0: four of them are ours and one in particular.
Speaker 0: I'd like to put a plug out for a self plug because I think this is gonna be a pretty badass panel.
Speaker 0: Myself Scott and Gerald from anime world order not Daryl because he's a wuss who is afraid of Otakon.
Speaker 0: I won't come back and I Yeah, I'm calling you out Daryl not coming back to Otakon.
Speaker 0: I didn't you have a good time.
Speaker 0: Gerald had a good time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I just didn't want to have a good time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think cuz I remember when I was walking around and I kept him running into Gerald and Daryl at Otakon.
Speaker 0: Gerald was you know Hey blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: check this out Check this out and Daryl was like going out of his way to find the things that would piss him off the most and then Sticking around to make sure those things pissed him off.
Speaker 0: But Anyway, the three of us are doing a panel entitled Gekiga putting the man back in manga.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be Friday or Saturday night in the 18 plus block and I can guarantee there's gonna be a lot of mr.
Speaker 0: Tokai.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 0: Tokai, I'm all about this panel.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be a hot panel.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you if you are someone who likes the the manly mangas or If you are someone who you know would like to read some mangas but you know all you go to the borders and all you see is girly stuff and Shown in fighting stuff and you know, there's nothing that really appeals to the manly man who likes, you know rape.
Speaker 1: Then this is a panel for you, we're also doing the panel at kinetic on well practicing the panel at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: well, we're doing the same basic panel, but we're not gonna have Gerald and his.
Speaker 0: uh, Let's just say that Gerald has been thinking about what he is going to talk about as the like the conclusion to this panel For a long time and we're not gonna have that with us at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna have to put some sort of substandard filler in to take up its place Probably just question-and-answer type stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that I was.
Speaker 1: you know, that's the greatest thing about running a panel is I love question answer.
Speaker 1: That's like my favorite part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz it's so easy.
Speaker 1: you just stand up there and I know and more than anyone could possibly ask in that room.
Speaker 0: and Well, it depends on what panel we're doing.
Speaker 1: I mean the only person who could probably yeah But I'm not gonna do a any panel I would do if someone asks a relevant question I can answer ninety nine point nine to nine percent of the time.
Speaker 1: the only way someone could defeat me is if like Gerald was there in the audience instead of yeah, and he tried to ask me About something I didn't know and he knew I didn't know it.
Speaker 1: So I just stand up there and people ask questions and I'm like BAM BAM BAM BAM.
Speaker 0: See at the same time I kind of dislike it.
Speaker 0: just be cool.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's because the panel I've done more than any panel at any con ever is the hotter on an anime Questions.
Speaker 0: every time it people ask like.
Speaker 0: it's amazing that people ask the exact same Questions and almost the exact same order every year for five years running.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think that's why it's good to mix up the panel though
Speaker 0: I must say and I want to remind everyone that at Kinetic on last year when we took over the anime club panel That we're running a kinetic on this year Someone asked a question that we'd never run into before.
Speaker 1: That was the greatest question probably ever at any panel.
Speaker 0: it was that guy was pretty cool too.
Speaker 0: I wish I remembered his name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, give him a shout out and he was dressed up as the guy from Ranma who runs around the world.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: What's his name?
Speaker 1: Some anime fans we are God.
Speaker 0: I Last time I watched Ranma was when I was in high school.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Ranma guy who runs around the world with the leopard skin stuff Pichan.
Speaker 0: No, no, he turns into Pichan.
Speaker 0: Does he?
Speaker 1: Oh the pig, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd have to look it up on the Wikipedia or something to see.
Speaker 0: not normally a normal Yoga, yes, yoga.
Speaker 0: Aha.
Speaker 0: I am the geekier see normally and in you know, one of those erudite anime.
Speaker 0: I didn't look that up by the way.
Speaker 0: They would have cut that out looked it up and then just said well he was dressed up as yoga But we play it loose by the wire.
Speaker 0: We don't edit anything out.
Speaker 1: and rim was here.
Speaker 1: He can he can testify.
Speaker 1: I did not touch my keyboard.
Speaker 0: Yeah coming up with that answer, of course I don't actually look at Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm usually staring at various meters still here.
Speaker 0: if I go ticky ticky ticky ticky I can because the microphones right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, there's the more interesting thing Otakon did.
Speaker 0: on June 22nd There was an announcement on the Otakon website.
Speaker 1: They didn't tell them what question that real good guy is.
Speaker 0: Of course not.
Speaker 0: That was part of my plan.
Speaker 0: Haha, I was expecting that to just slide and someone in the forum is gonna be like.
Speaker 0: so what question did that guy ask?
Speaker 0: and My answer was gonna be well you best come to Kinetic on and see us in case he comes and asks it again.
Speaker 0: You stole my thunder right like so June 22nd, you see what happens when it's hot out.
Speaker 0: We just we lose all sense of logic.
Speaker 1: I could barely stay awake here.
Speaker 0: Are you know, I felt I almost missed my stop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't almost miss my stop, but I was worried.
Speaker 1: I'd miss my stop.
Speaker 0: You know, it's cold spring.
Speaker 1: I was so sleepy.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, alright beacons.
Speaker 0: next I'm gonna close my eyes and I'm thinking but people around me might think that I'm gonna fall asleep But now I'll show them I'm gonna wake up and then get off and then suddenly I wake up and the doors are open and I think uh And I get up very quickly and I walk out and I'm in beacon.
Speaker 0: Yeah I was this close to missing my train and ending up in New Hamburg and that would have sucked.
Speaker 1: No, it is sucked ass cuz.
Speaker 0: I drove to New Hamburg once it's in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not a good place.
Speaker 0: Anyway on June 22nd 2007 Otacon on their website announced attention panelists I'm quoting all approval or denial notices have now been sent.
Speaker 0: I want to point out that that was a lie.
Speaker 0: I had not received any.
Speaker 0: If you have not received an email regarding the status of your flannel Please email the panel's department using the contact at whatever.
Speaker 0: I did that if your panel was approved Please pre register at this time select instructions for what you have to do and then in bold This information must be received by June 22nd.
Speaker 0: in order for you to be on the list of members to receive a comped badge Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right information must be received by June 22nd.
Speaker 0: This announcement was put out on June 22nd on the website.
Speaker 0: as far as I can see they didn't send out an email.
Speaker 0: Uh, I can say based on other panelists.
Speaker 0: I talked to that not many people saw this announcement.
Speaker 0: Yeah nope, nope, nope, and I'm expecting I mean not many people have been posting much about it in the forums But there are a lot of panels listed here and I'm expecting there to be some sort of trouble at Otacon proper when panelists who?
Speaker 1: Registered by check didn't pay and then can't get in even though they have panels and their names are on the panels and whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus it was funny I mean we.
Speaker 0: well I got approval for a panel that I submitted for someone else But yet I did not actually get approval for the gecky guy putting the man back in manga panel.
Speaker 0: That is most definitely mine.
Speaker 0: I know what else submitted.
Speaker 0: that panel with that name is 19 plus Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know I'm not really busting Otacon's balls because I think everything's coming together.
Speaker 0: I just I think the panels at Otacon could be run better in the future.
Speaker 0: And I'm not saying oh because this year there was a problem.
Speaker 0: I understand that We we were told basically exactly what the problem was and I sympathize It was a problem where Otacon did the best they could to cover it up and fix it and make everything work.
Speaker 0: But I'm gonna say that last year I don't think the panels were run too well either.
Speaker 0: and the year before that I don't think they were run too well either.
Speaker 0: I mean they work they haven't.
Speaker 0: but I was not impressed with my dealings with the people running the panels in the past.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think generally the number one problem seems to be a failure at communication with the members of Otacon.
Speaker 0: now see if we were one of those other podcasts we'd probably play some sort of soundbite there like What we have here is a failure to communicate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm not gonna do that.
Speaker 1: It's just that Otacon seems to assume that you know The people who go to Otacon must go to the Otacon website every day of the year I mean you have to.
Speaker 1: when you make an announcement about panels You should have an email list that has everyone who's doing a panel.
Speaker 0: Well an email all of them to their credit and you know as well as I do Why that was not the case and there's really nothing they could do about that at least nothing they could Once they fixed it.
Speaker 0: there is nothing they could do about that fact at After it had happened there.
Speaker 0: They could have done something about that had they run panels differently, but that's entirely beside the point No, but I mean like now that they actually created the list of panels.
Speaker 1: They know who's doing all those panels that they listed.
Speaker 1: They know the email addresses of those people.
Speaker 1: Why did they notify them?
Speaker 0: Well more importantly I wonder why they set such a short deadline suddenly like that.
Speaker 0: if anything I would have been.
Speaker 0: The issue is that since the people doing the panels had to work on short notice anyway And they basically pulled a hey if you didn't see this just now.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get a free badge.
Speaker 0: I think they could have handled it better.
Speaker 0: if anything I would have set up a system to just count people at the door or fix it after the fact with refunds or something.
Speaker 1: Is it really that hard?
Speaker 1: I mean You know if someone's doing a panel or not.
Speaker 1: is it really that big a mystery?
Speaker 1: if someone comes in to the con and they Doing a panel you send them to the con ops.
Speaker 1: the con ops can easily verify if that person's doing a panel.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know panel cons do things differently.
Speaker 0: I mean some cons.
Speaker 0: I've gone to and just said hey Let me in free and they just do and some pound cons They gotta fill stuff out.
Speaker 0: some cons can trick keep track of how many panels we run and then they give us money back.
Speaker 0: But in old Otakons when I did a panel I usually just walk in and say hey I'm a panelist and they had me an associates badge Usually without questions asked.
Speaker 0: I know they don't have associates badges anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they eliminated the associates badge now.
Speaker 1: They just pay for your regular bed.
Speaker 0: granted It's probably good that they've regulated it a little bit more because it was startling how easy it was to convince someone to give me a badge in old Otakons and If I were an unscrupulous person, I probably could have just gone in and gotten a badge if I'd known the right words to say
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I guess it's good that they have some sort of system, but regardless they still Seem to not be perfect on everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone else should run panels at Otakon next year.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: Can you think it?
Speaker 0: you know one or two people who maybe really care about anime?
Speaker 0: Kind of a little bit related to the industry.
Speaker 0: Maybe they know a lot about how to run panels at cons.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're staffers at a whole bunch of other cons have a lot of experience.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: many people like that have a lot of ideas as to how to run Panels at a con.
Speaker 0: maybe people who have their own personal staff all ready to go already have a system in place Already figured out how they were to run the panels for Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we should run the panels at Otakon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think also and if Otakon doesn't let us do it and they pick someone else then That person better be awesome or else Otakon is a fool because we're dead.
Speaker 1: Otakon doesn't believe us.
Speaker 1: We're gonna walk the walk here if we do it and then screw up you can Make fun of us and shit talk us all you want because you'll be right now.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is I mean do a better job than anyone's ever done.
Speaker 1: Then you got nothing to say.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I just got to say because Kineticon again to their credit when we said your panels all suck.
Speaker 0: They said fine Why don't you run some panels?
Speaker 0: and here we go We will.
Speaker 0: and they said fine you're running nine and we said nine.
Speaker 1: fine We can do that and we're gonna do that and that's gonna show them.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: Yep It's basically they might as well just call it Rimm and Skatakon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except there's actually a lot more than nine panels at the con.
Speaker 1: We could just take over Kineticon.
Speaker 1: instead of like starting our own geek nights like special front row crew con I'd rather take over Katsucon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's too big.
Speaker 1: We can't eat it.
Speaker 0: See, the thing is Katsucon is too awesome more edible and closer.
Speaker 0: Let's take over Torakon.
Speaker 0: Let's go back to RIT.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Wow think about that.
Speaker 0: we could just re-enroll at RIT Run take over the anime club take over the Torakon and just have a convention.
Speaker 0: We could yeah enough people still know our names.
Speaker 0: Back there we could get the votes easily.
Speaker 0: That's kind of like sanctuary if the people in sanctuary had really really low expectations and we're really striving for much Like yeah, we're gonna take over the McDonald's on 4th Avenue things of the day.
Speaker 0: So, uh, our friend Ido who is often giving us wonderful things of the day and the one who told us about Washington, you know six foot twelve fucking killing for fun.
Speaker 0: Washington Washington, I mean he saves children, but not the albionic children.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, apparently guy who did that did something else.
Speaker 0: basically, it is a history of Sodom and Gomorrah as told by.
Speaker 1: it's not history that say the story.
Speaker 0: Well the story the the fictitious history the juneo-christian mythology of Sodom and Gomorrah.
Speaker 0: Yep And I don't know what I find funnier when the professor winks at the kid When the guy's having sex with the fire or when Jesus and God high-five at the end.
Speaker 1: I don't know It's all good all around.
Speaker 1: basically Whoever's making these things?
Speaker 0: Brad Neely.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's my new favorite.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: He needs to make more things Make it easier to find all of his things.
Speaker 0: I haven't watched much else yet on the site, but so far It's all been rather delectable.
Speaker 0: But seriously, this thing is hilarious.
Speaker 0: It's a little bit.
Speaker 0: uh, it might offend you but if you're offended by this then how the hell are you listening to geek nights?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: some people They got problems.
Speaker 1: It's like they're offended by things but they keep listening to them.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah Well, uh, I don't know.
Speaker 0: maybe when the people have sex with the rocks that are shaped like painted like God's head Or the oats the oats.
Speaker 0: Oh the oats.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well way back I don't know if it was ever a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I think it might have been.
Speaker 1: somebody took a box Right and in the box They cut a hole in the side and they mounted a Kodak or I guess I don't know if it was Kodak brand But a disposable camera in the side of the box and they be revealed.
Speaker 1: they had a button wired up so that you just push this button on the box to make the box take a picture.
Speaker 1: and They sent this box through the mail with instructions on the outside of the box telling the postal workers to take pictures of things with the box and then When he got the box at the destination He would see pictures of whatever the postal workers decided to show him and that was pretty cool.
Speaker 1: That was a cool thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Someone saw this?
Speaker 1: or I believe they saw it.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I don't know how they thought of this.
Speaker 1: They did basically not just twice as good as they get that guy but ten thousand times as good as that guy.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess mathematically, let's see seven thousand divided by about thirty is how much better?
Speaker 0: Well, it is a little bit different in that.
Speaker 0: It's more voyeuristic and less.
Speaker 0: Hey, see how cool people are along the way
Speaker 1: That's true but he took a box and he put in a camera and he put in some hard drives and some batteries and some electronic circuitry that he wired up and He basically made a video camera that would take a picture every 10 seconds and he sent it through the mail In this box and when he got it on the other end there were six thousand nine hundred ninety four pictures and he edited them together to make a Animated slideshow of the boxes travels through the postal system and it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Right, you can see like the mail truck and the sorting facility in his house and the mailbox and all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 0: I just love clever things like that.
Speaker 0: And this is pretty cool to check out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is you can't actually see the whole video.
Speaker 1: I mean if you can I'm having a hard time finding it, but there is a tiny Small section of the stills from the animated film and there's pictures of the inside of the box Which is very cool also and pretty much you're gonna see all the important bits if not the whole film
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So over the weekend we decided to trek out as is our annual tradition after our second annual last year.
Speaker 0: Yep to the mocha for the mocha art festival the mocha arts festival.
Speaker 1: The mocha is the Museum of comic and cartoon art.
Speaker 1: I think it used to be in Florida if I remember because I think I went to it when it was in, Florida.
Speaker 1: I might be wrong about that, but I'm pretty sure I'm not.
Speaker 1: and it's in New York now and every year They have the biggest fundraiser of the year for them, which is the Arts Festival, which is in the puck building which is a nice building down in right two blocks away from where I work and basically all sorts of comic artists of varying shapes and sizes Come set up a table and hawk their wares and display their arts and you pay I think eight bucks to walk around for a day and look at everything.
Speaker 1: and it is it's basically a bargain for eight.
Speaker 0: but imagine gigantic artist alley full of Nothing, but awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the reason the mocha is so cool Is that unlike other comic conventions which are say primarily a dealer's room and such like that?
Speaker 1: It's pretty much just an artist alley perhaps bigger than any other artists alley even like the Otacon artist alley in terms of quantity and quality and you go up to a table and you'll see a comic and There's a 90% chance of.
Speaker 1: the person behind the table is the person who made that comic.
Speaker 1: and that is way way cool.
Speaker 1: because I mean our friends are buying comics and they didn't even realize they were buying it from the creator and then the creator were Like draw doodle in it and sign it and they'd be like, whoa.
Speaker 1: I didn't realize.
Speaker 1: and sometimes, you know It's like a big semi famous creator and sometimes it's just some nobody.
Speaker 1: you just discovered them and just like hey, what's up?
Speaker 1: But no matter who it is or how famous they are you walk up to them and you're like hi How you doing and they talk to you like they're your friend and I've never met anyone who is mean there ever.
Speaker 1: And it's way cool.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about who we meet met before we talk about what we bought or what we saw.
Speaker 1: Oh, let's see.
Speaker 1: The first person people we saw were all our friends.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We ran into the ninja consultants.
Speaker 0: Yep, Aaron one of them.
Speaker 0: I didn't see.
Speaker 0: I saw both of them.
Speaker 0: Oh, I only saw one.
Speaker 1: Yeah I talked to them all about Otacon and such.
Speaker 1: so we're straight with them.
Speaker 1: They're cool.
Speaker 1: ninja consultants rock.
Speaker 1: Who else do we see?
Speaker 1: I finally got to meet stupid not stupid but Steve cloud the guy who makes boases who I have tried to see at many conventions and he's just never been there.
Speaker 0: We've always just not been able to find him.
Speaker 0: He's the most awesome guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah boy on a stick and slither is Easily in my top three of webcomic.
Speaker 1: It's tied for my number one webcomic miss along with a few like penny arcade.
Speaker 0: that penny arcade order the stick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and dr.
Speaker 1: McNinchy guy was there as usual.
Speaker 1: I've seen him a whole bunch of time.
Speaker 0: He's really cool.
Speaker 1: Yep Brian Lee O'Malley the guy who makes Scott pilgrim was there.
Speaker 1: He was there last year.
Speaker 1: Also you hesitated.
Speaker 0: you hesitated to say Scott pilgrim.
Speaker 1: Yep I had to remember what it was that makes you weak Scott pilgrim for is coming out.
Speaker 0: You must be ready.
Speaker 1: I already pre-ordered it.
Speaker 0: good so I can read it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he drew a sketch of my pirate book.
Speaker 0: Yep However, his sketch was definitely filled with the rye irony of someone who did not particularly want to draw the particular thing That Scott had asked him to draw which is the idea.
Speaker 1: Yes Let's see who else was there.
Speaker 0: There was an unfortunate moment where see and this is Scott doesn't have this problem as much but I do Because I know names but I have no idea what any of these kind of only
Speaker 1: reason I'll keep going
Speaker 0: Alright, but I don't know any of these people look like at all and some of them just don't wear their name tags Or they wear them kind of obscured.
Speaker 0: So I generally have to kind of wait and I won't talk to anyone behind a table until I see a name tag.
Speaker 0: So I don't make a faux pas or do anything wrong.
Speaker 0: But Scott said he was gonna go over and talk to mr.
Speaker 0: Scott pilgrim.
Speaker 0: So he goes over and we lose sight of him and then another friend of ours walks over and sees him talking to a kind Of geeky looking guy with glasses just after he had said I'm gonna go talk to the Scott pilgrim guy.
Speaker 0: So this person assumed that it was in fact the Scott pilgrim guy and hilarity ensued.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all was taken in good fun.
Speaker 1: in fact the only reason I knew who that was is that it was Steven cloud was because he was wearing a shirt where the cloud On it.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: However, that is I would not have known.
Speaker 0: that's a little bit of out-of-the-box thinking.
Speaker 1: Actually, I think I had seen that shirt elsewhere before and like I'd known that he had it or something It must have been on the website or see.
Speaker 0: so lucky.
Speaker 0: He can just wear a picture of a cloud I got.
Speaker 0: there's no picture of a decoster unless they were I don't know a shirt with a picture of my dad on it.
Speaker 0: I can get a picture of a sandwich Speaking of which I saw you bought some bread.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 1: I bought a rye bread because I could.
Speaker 0: all right Yep, but yeah, and of course we met the people from indie spinner rack.
Speaker 1: Yep, the indie spinner at guys We also went to their dinner party.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll talk about all those people later.
Speaker 1: Yep We saw.
Speaker 1: I saw Sal Avenatti who makes this very pockner comic which I bought just as it's very pockner.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: I'll gonna see if it's good or not after.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is, but we really like these all the aesthetics and the mute everything about pockner.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe old pockner not so much new pockner older red pockner Being the Soviet Union.
Speaker 1: by the way, I really don't like communism.
Speaker 1: I just like hammers and sickles and red and yellow and that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: remember that Mario communism That's that's so up our alley.
Speaker 0: It's kind of scary.
Speaker 1: I also don't know why I said like I didn't like this stuff before.
Speaker 1: I've only liked it in the past few years.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: I have a large collection of Soviet era choral music Let's see.
Speaker 1: I met.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to go around the room like the different ballrooms in my mind.
Speaker 1: I met Brian wood who writes DMZ.
Speaker 1: I met Cameron Stewart who draws the other side, which is this really great if you haven't read it.
Speaker 1: It's a vertigo book.
Speaker 1: It's just one book.
Speaker 1: You can read the whole story.
Speaker 1: It was like five or six issues.
Speaker 1: It's like this awesome new Vietnam War comic.
Speaker 1: That is the highest quality.
Speaker 1: I recommend it to all.
Speaker 1: and this is the guy to the art.
Speaker 1: I met him.
Speaker 0: There's one artist now.
Speaker 0: I've never heard of her before and I don't think any of us had but in our group Pretty much almost every single person in the crew who was there independently of one another and without any sort of or coordination Found this artist talked to her and bought something from her and furthermore each one of us bought something different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well some people just have an artistic style that really appeals to our group of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Shelley Perline I'll put a link to her site in the the sites a little broken in Firefox, but I don't know I like her art.
Speaker 0: So I guess I'll forgive that.
Speaker 1: Yep Let's see who else.
Speaker 1: oh There was a book that I bought called fun home by Alison Bechdel.
Speaker 1: I think that's how you say it.
Speaker 1: Oh, and it's like.
Speaker 1: it's not just like an award-winning comic.
Speaker 1: It's Time magazine's number one book of the year period.
Speaker 1: right and I ordered it.
Speaker 1: I pre-ordered it and I got it at the beginning of the month and I still haven't read it.
Speaker 1: I don't know why but the person who writes and draws it was there that I saw her and I was like, hey Like I didn't have much to say because I didn't read her book yet Left the book at home.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna go through the list of all the stuff I bought but suffice to say I spent every single dollar I had and then I borrowed money from Scott.
Speaker 1: I actually regret not buying a few things like.
Speaker 1: there was a. there was one thing I wanted to buy this book called Sundays But it was really big and I didn't want to carry it.
Speaker 1: That's the only reason I didn't buy it Yeah, and there were a few other things like I didn't buy just because you know We sorta didn't stay there that long and we got there like an hour later than I wanted to get there.
Speaker 1: So yeah, well, what can you do?
Speaker 0: I got one thing that I'd really been wanting for a long time But that pyeongyang comic about the guy who goes and lives in North Korea for a while while he's working at an animation studio.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Emily had recommended it a bunch of times and there was there.
Speaker 0: so I bought it without hesitation and art boy Also bought it without hesitation.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I read it just yesterday and it was quite the awesome.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about it somewhat soon.
Speaker 1: Yep, maybe even next week.
Speaker 1: What else did I see there?
Speaker 1: It was just so much awesome stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh, right Um, I don't know if we've talked about it on the show, but last time we went we got these wooden ghosts, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, they were free these tiny little wooden pac-man they were.
Speaker 1: they were not.
Speaker 1: pac-man goes specifically But they're in the style of their.
Speaker 1: pac-man goes mine sitting right there Yeah, and we got these little ghosts for free But we had no idea who gave them to us.
Speaker 1: But sitting in the exact same position as last year was the guy who made them and he had more wooden things and I gave.
Speaker 1: I got his business card from him.
Speaker 1: He is Chris Yates chrisyates.net and If you want cool wooden sculpture things, he is the man.
Speaker 1: I went around his website and he had many many cool things Some of which I wanted but I did not buy because I have no use for a wooden thing like that.
Speaker 1: But maybe we could get him to make some sort of wooden geek knights figures or something.
Speaker 0: That'd be pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Think about it.
Speaker 1: sitting next to him was the wonder mark guy who we discovered at mocha last year.
Speaker 0: and ah Wonder mark is the rising star of webcomics as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that guy's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I Forget his name.
Speaker 0: I Don't remember either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, in fact for the longest time.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know it was called wonder mark.
Speaker 0: I just remembered poop jokes and top hat.
Speaker 1: That was the slogan that was on the bumper sticker.
Speaker 0: He gave you yeah Yeah, that pretty much describes everything about that comic.
Speaker 0: It is very literally poop jokes wearing top hats.
Speaker 1: one last thing is the.
Speaker 1: I think it was the Dutch Consulate was actually there and they had this big table with all sorts of Norwegian Fiti Swedish Finnish Swedish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're gonna say swindling next finish in Swedish Comics there.
Speaker 0: I had to resist buying just piles of stuff from them and I just I ended up picking up this little brochure That was kind of cool.
Speaker 0: it basically lists all the Finnish artists that were represented there and a little kind of sample of their art and a little explanation of what kind of things they Write.
Speaker 1: I actually paid $12 for this book called angst the best of Norwegian comics and it had a pic had some of Jason's art on the cover, you know, Jason is the awesome guy who did.
Speaker 1: why are you doing this and all that?
Speaker 0: And the left bank gang.
Speaker 1: Yeah, did you read left bank yet?
Speaker 1: You bought it and I read it yesterday.
Speaker 1: That's I think that's gonna be like your favorite kind of action.
Speaker 0: I gotta ask one thing.
Speaker 0: Is it better or equal?
Speaker 0: better than or equal to why are you doing this?
Speaker 1: I would say that why are you doing this is probably it's tough call.
Speaker 1: Why are you doing this?
Speaker 1: I think is better for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that might better for you because it has some.
Speaker 1: you know, Sun Also Rises action.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, I'll probably get some hate for this but Scott knows me too.
Speaker 0: Well, the Sun Also Rises For whatever reason is one of my favorite books ever.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much that.
Speaker 0: and the Count of Monte Cristo You're gonna.
Speaker 1: I think you're gonna like the left bank gang a little bit more Oh, but yeah, this angst comic basically just has.
Speaker 1: it's like an anthology of a whole bunch of tiny comics by various northern European artists and Some of them are pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Some of them are just kind of weird, but it was definitely worth my $12.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: What else did we see there?
Speaker 1: a whole lot of stuff?
Speaker 1: It's like hard to recall all of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have this pile of business cards in front of me in this pile of brochures and everything But I don't remember specifically which one goes with which cool thing I saw.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not always easy.
Speaker 1: I mean you had this giant room.
Speaker 1: you're walking around this ballroom.
Speaker 1: You see arts there arts over here arts over there.
Speaker 1: Some is cool some you don't care about so much.
Speaker 1: You know, it seemed like it was kind of weird.
Speaker 1: The thing about this show is that I basically brought how many ten people there right last year?
Speaker 1: It was just you me and did anyone else go with us?
Speaker 0: Oh, we went with I do.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 1: So it was you and me and eight other people this year had never been before.
Speaker 0: we brought a frickin posse.
Speaker 1: The people we brought weren't the biggest comic fans.
Speaker 1: I mean only me and Scott Johnson buy comics regularly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other people did.
Speaker 0: I mostly dislike the majority of comics, right?
Speaker 1: So you bring these people and I didn't tell you know, I didn't walk around with them saying oh, that's good.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's not good That's good.
Speaker 1: That's not good Right, and then you know when we left and when I met up with them later seeing what they had purchased.
Speaker 1: First of all, they bought more than I'd bought right.
Speaker 1: second of all They bought things that I knew and knew were good and probably would have told them to buy and things that were right up Their alley.
Speaker 1: a lot of them bought the same things and it was so it was pretty cool seeing like all these You know my friends buying all this stuff without me recommending that I would have recommended.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: If you live anywhere near New York City and you have any excuse to go the mocha is well worth four hours of your time.
Speaker 1: Yep, yeah, I would like to go, you know for maybe five or six hours just so I can walk around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the mocha itself is cool independent of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you want to go to the mocha itself, you know, just check their website and it's mo CCA.
Speaker 1: Just search that on Google.
Speaker 1: You'll find it and Wait for them to have an exhibit you like.
Speaker 1: I think the current exhibit is a Stan Lee exhibits.
Speaker 1: a rim doesn't want to go But they just I think they recently had a Todd McFarlane exhibit.
Speaker 1: That was higher quality.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if Stan Lee were a book he's definitely not on my he's not.
Speaker 0: my son also arises.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could I was.
Speaker 0: I mean I'd make a bolding joke, but it's hard to do that with audio.
Speaker 1: But for anywhere in New York City and in I guess the month of June you kind of have to go to the mocha Arts Festival, I mean, it's nothing like, you know, the Comic Con you think about.
Speaker 1: there's barely any superhero action Even though there is some there and there are people who usually don't like any comics at all.
Speaker 1: But you walk around this place and no matter who you are even if you're a comic hater There'll be some sort of art on a table somewhere that'll appeal to you and you'll walk out spending a lot more money than you ever thought.
Speaker 1: Also an awesome thunder.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I also want to point out briefly that they had concession stands like inside and They were so perfectly catered to the demographic that would be at this.
Speaker 0: They were basically selling nothing but energy drinks energy bars and like It was like soy and granola and energy bars and Red Bulls awesome and chocolate chip cookies.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't see the concession stand.
Speaker 1: So I did not buy.
Speaker 0: I was very thirsty.
Speaker 0: So I bought two Red Bulls.
Speaker 1: one thing that was different this year.
Speaker 1: That was a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one thing that was different this year from last year Is that they they used to have the panels and I think the seventh floor right.
Speaker 1: or is it the 17th floor?
Speaker 1: I think it's the seventh floor and This year they moved the panels over to the actual mocha museum because remember this festival is in the puck building.
Speaker 0: We should probably cut this short.
Speaker 0: the Thunder's getting closer.
Speaker 1: I know we're gonna cut it short pretty soon and They instead added more table space on the seventh floor, which is awesome because it wasn't crowded up there as it was crowded downstairs.
Speaker 1: You could actually move around more freely.
Speaker 1: The Sun was shining into the room instead of it being dark like the other rooms And it was.
Speaker 1: I spent a lot of time up there just because it was so pleasant also And they kept.
Speaker 0: you know The elevators were kind that have really.
Speaker 0: they set up the elevator system to make sure people didn't get in other people's way and took the elevator efficiently Beautifully like props to them for keeping that under control.
Speaker 1: Yeah I didn't have any problem at the elevator.
Speaker 0: every time I went by they said if you're brave you can go around the corner and Take the antique elevator.
Speaker 0: Ah, so I was up there with Emily and finally, you know, we hear that.
Speaker 0: So I'm like is there really an antique elevator?
Speaker 0: and she's like, yeah.
Speaker 0: So I go over there and there was the most awesome antique elevator.
Speaker 1: was there really?
Speaker 0: yes It was I didn't know super awesome and super old-school.
Speaker 0: it it's manually operated.
Speaker 0: So there was a guy dressed up in the finery Standing there who would let us in ask what floor we wanted to go to drive us there.
Speaker 0: He had a little stool.
Speaker 0: He had his little water bottle under.
Speaker 1: that's how the Empire State Building works.
Speaker 1: If you go to the Empire State Building, there's a guy there's an elevator guy who operates the elevator.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but mostly to keep you from going to random floors and keep it going efficiently, but this was quite awesome.
Speaker 1: Yep Anything else we got to say about the other.
Speaker 0: the only thing we could really say is there was an after-party.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking since we've already gone a little bit long and there's a gigantic thunderstorm a-sailing our house that just this second It's about to come.
Speaker 0: Yep Maybe we'll talk about.
Speaker 0: the after-party is a special or something since we need a bunch of filler for when we're out of town For Otakon.
Speaker 1: There wasn't that much to say about.
Speaker 1: the after-party went to a Chinese restaurant.
Speaker 0: I got a bunch.
Speaker 0: we got some stories.
Speaker 0: I could definitely do a 15-minute thing about the after-party.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we saw it was run by the Indy spinner at guys.
Speaker 0: So if they do a podcast about independent comics Indy spinner rack calm I can figure out how to spell.
Speaker 1: I think it might be blog spot.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure you can search for it's Indy spinner rack calm.
Speaker 1: All right, the comic geek speak.
Speaker 1: guys were there.
Speaker 1: a bunch of their listeners were there.
Speaker 1: a bunch of other cool people were there.
Speaker 1: It was generally cool.
Speaker 1: You should check out all those people's.
Speaker 0: the after-party was really fun.
Speaker 0: The food was really good.
Speaker 1: There were some issues with the Knowledge of where the after-party took place and there were some issues with some other people besides us at the after-party getting adequate Food service.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we had a good time and it was actually it was funny that We brought our whole crew and we got there before everyone else.
Speaker 0: So we basically had this kind of dominating presence as all the real people who were running the party showed up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, imagine, you know, it's like the people running the party sort of like, you know, you have a mixed table.
Speaker 1: I got a table and whatever.
Speaker 1: we'll talk about it some other time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was awesome.
Speaker 0: Everyone there was awesome.
Speaker 0: We expect to see a lot of you people at cons coming up and we're gonna stop this before the lightning comes out.
Speaker 0: the power Go.
Speaker 0: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.