Speaker 0: Hey, it's Thursday October 4th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek knives.
Speaker 0: tonight I explain what I was doing in Arizona, and why there weren't any shows at the end of last week.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I got into work yesterday.
Speaker 0: well this morning like I do cuz I skipped work yesterday And I'm sitting in my office going over email getting ready to maybe do some actual work And an email pops up from the person at the front desk and normally I don't need to read an email from the person at the front desk because no one's gonna come and see me in my office.
Speaker 0: But the topic of this email intrigued me, and I decided to read it.
Speaker 0: the topic read warning skunk.
Speaker 0: So I open this email and it says not to alarm anyone.
Speaker 0: But a skunk was spotted on the first floor somewhere in the atrium In the building.
Speaker 1: yes, how do you get in?
Speaker 0: I'll get to that okay, so I'm thinking huh?
Speaker 0: I wonder how that happened.
Speaker 0: and the email goes on to explain do not attempt to catch or bother the skunk Just stay in your office.
Speaker 0: if you really feel like leaving you're free to leave.
Speaker 0: But there's a skunk in the building just so you all know just the animal.
Speaker 1: people come and take it away.
Speaker 0: Well, I stayed in my cubicle.
Speaker 1: Did you see the skunk?
Speaker 0: No?
Speaker 0: I didn't see the skunk.
Speaker 1: What kind of you might as well not even told the story what the hell well the thing is.
Speaker 0: I That was not what I expected to happen this morning But yeah about three hours later another email came back saying the skunk has been found.
Speaker 0: animal control has taken it away.
Speaker 0: It was rather happy with the cat food.
Speaker 0: We fed it and it is going to be released about 12 miles north of here and hopefully Apparently I didn't know that they had a live trap.
Speaker 0: They fill it with cat food.
Speaker 1: do skunk seat?
Speaker 0: You should probably go to what skunk seat.
Speaker 1: calm What do skunks eat?
Speaker 0: but apparently cat food.
Speaker 0: And yeah, the skunk was found apparently because the building I work in used to be a warehouse you know like turn of the century whatever in this industrial complex and they turned it into offices and This skunk just found a way in.
Speaker 0: they found the hole they filled it in and hopefully no more skunks will wander into my office Looking for food.
Speaker 1: skunks eat mostly into insects many of which are pests to humans.
Speaker 1: They're therefore beneficial to have around.
Speaker 1: they also eat some plant material including wild fruits apples and corn.
Speaker 1: in winter and spring They eat mice and the eggs of ground nesting birds.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So apparently cat food should be added to that list.
Speaker 1: I think but this isn't Wikipedia so I can't.
Speaker 1: This is please be kind.
Speaker 0: calm skunk daddy as opposed to what badgers eat calm, which I believe is still up.
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: You don't know if I got all about that website.
Speaker 1: You did forget.
Speaker 0: It's still there.
Speaker 0: There it is Kind of like zombo.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: I think that's gonna be around forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's got a little Simpsons logo at the bottom.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So anyway skunk related news aside We've been talking all week except Tuesday where we keep forgetting.
Speaker 1: but oh you remembered us.
Speaker 0: I totally forgot a week from a week from now.
Speaker 0: So probably the week after next we're gonna do it Unless you know your questions all suck, but so far so good.
Speaker 0: Instead of just doing a you know question show ask rim and Scott we're doing a questions week.
Speaker 0: So this being Thursday night if you have anything you want to ask us from I don't know.
Speaker 0: How do you feel about Barack Obama's ring - why did you get into podcasting?
Speaker 0: go right ahead and ask it and we might just answer.
Speaker 1: Yep, you can answer ask any question.
Speaker 1: It's not a Monday Tuesday or Wednesday question.
Speaker 0: Nothing is out of bounds.
Speaker 1: Nope, and we will decide whether we will answer it or not on the show.
Speaker 1: and If you want your question to be answered, I recommend you make it a question that could be answered quickly a Question that is not stupid.
Speaker 1: Do not put an essay before after or around your question making it difficult for us to figure out what your question is.
Speaker 0: if your question Can be answered by Google on the first page We might not answer it or we might answer it just to make you look stupid.
Speaker 1: if your question was answered in a previous episode Of geek nights.
Speaker 1: the same is also true unless of course the answer has changed which it could very well be possible.
Speaker 0: Yes, very much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah ask the questions.
Speaker 1: You can send them by email to eat nights if I were crew to come or in the forum.
Speaker 1: We have four different threads one for each question show.
Speaker 1: I think it should sell question to me the appropriate.
Speaker 0: I think it should be self-evident which thread is for which kinds of questions unless you can't read.
Speaker 1: in which case don't ask a question Please.
Speaker 0: I can't read or write.
Speaker 1: Yeah, please don't ask questions if you can.
Speaker 1: The only question you should be asking is how do I learn to read and write?
Speaker 0: All right, so there is kindergarten But anyway, it is a Thursday mean we can talk about whatever we want.
Speaker 1: So it's good because there's not much to talk about.
Speaker 0: if anything specific I got a lot of tech news, but I got a hold off on that.
Speaker 1: I don't really have that much tech news.
Speaker 1: Okay, so, you know those guys, you know most dumb people out there.
Speaker 1: now dumb people is a relative term.
Speaker 1: You know, they can't fix their own computer if it breaks, you know If there's an error message and it won't go away and they can't make their computer do what they want it to do They have no clue what to do.
Speaker 0: It's just like if the check engine light comes in my car.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: All I know is crap.
Speaker 1: got to go to a mechanic or if it doesn't turn your car doesn't start.
Speaker 1: What do you do?
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 0: I go to the mechanic and I say ah, my car doesn't start exactly exactly.
Speaker 1: So, you know normal people who were not lucky enough to offspring computer professionals or be offspring of computer professionals Or be related to someone who has offsprung computer professionals, etc.
Speaker 1: They really don't have anywhere to turn most of the time and they have to call up.
Speaker 1: You know the geek squad or one of those other ones firedog?
Speaker 0: What were you saying?
Speaker 0: You don't have any tech news nerd something.
Speaker 1: This isn't a news really It's sort of a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I turned into a news.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh So the CBC the Canadian Broadcasting Company is sort of like the BBC of Canada.
Speaker 1: They did on their news a little expose of all these Computer repair nerdy geeky companies that will come to your house to fix quote fix your computer, huh?
Speaker 0: I Wonder how that turned out.
Speaker 1: so they went to a local college which seemed like an okay college, you know.
Speaker 1: and they said okay break this computer in one way and They broke the computer by putting in one bad stick of RAM.
Speaker 1: Right now you you and me know that if you have a bad stick of RAM the computer when you try to turn it on Might go beep beep beep.
Speaker 1: It also depends.
Speaker 1: I might go beep beep beep beep Will give you all some sort of screwed up errors, right?
Speaker 1: So those would be that cuz I'm a computer rational.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: those would be the symptoms of the only stick of RAM in your computer being bad Yep.
Speaker 0: Now if you have multiple sticks in one's bad, it'll just boot and you won't have enough RAM most likely.
Speaker 1: Yep It'll just be like if you have two 128 meg sticks totaling 256 and one of them is bad.
Speaker 1: your computer will either say 128 when it starts up or it'll work and then it'll crash randomly Which really sucks.
Speaker 1: So they call up ten different places to come and check out this computer in this one apartment All right now before I just want to point out before Scott six, I don't know what the results are.
Speaker 0: But this is Such a trip.
Speaker 0: This isn't a trick question.
Speaker 0: This is such a trivial problem.
Speaker 0: any computer professional even a non-professional Take.
Speaker 1: you see I would have had to investigate.
Speaker 1: it would have taken me like 15 minutes of trying different things to figure out.
Speaker 1: Is it the motherboard?
Speaker 1: is that the RAM stick?
Speaker 1: Is it the video card?
Speaker 0: Maybe but this is not a difficult question.
Speaker 0: It is not a difficult thing to solve given enough time to poke at the computer.
Speaker 1: I would have gotten the correct answer a hundred percent of the time and any Standard PC equipment plus the fact that they make it so that there's no Complimentary problems is huge.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: There's no other problem, but the RAM stick.
Speaker 1: All right, so They call ten people.
Speaker 1: All right, guess how many of the ten people got it, right all ten?
Speaker 0: No, none of them.
Speaker 0: I figured you'd only ask if the number was really high or really low.
Speaker 1: no, it's it's neither It's three.
Speaker 1: Three of them knew it was a bad RAM stick.
Speaker 1: seven of them got it wrong You know, that's kind of better than I expected.
Speaker 0: What did the seven say?
Speaker 1: Because well some of them were just like motherboards dead, you know.
Speaker 1: And obviously that's an easy thing to mistake if you're not well trained and you're not good at the troubleshooting is you know you then?
Speaker 0: Why are you in the computer repair business?
Speaker 0: You're just ripping people up Oh Ripping people off.
Speaker 1: No, you think that is bad.
Speaker 1: One of the guys was like Yeah hard drives bad you're gonna need to pay like a hundred.
Speaker 1: so, you know, he's like.
Speaker 1: you got to pay me $100 for my time right now and replacement a hard drive.
Speaker 1: hundred forty dollars.
Speaker 0: Wow At my inflated consulting rate the the the ten or fifteen minutes It would take me to solve this.
Speaker 0: Plus the cost of a stick around would be less than that.
Speaker 1: plus It was like an average Dell the stick around would have been like 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if that he probably has one laying around probably.
Speaker 1: but yeah, some of the guys say some pretty crazy stuff and Basically what they do is they in the in this video?
Speaker 1: They expose the fact that most of the people doing this job are not computer professionals.
Speaker 0: They have almost no training Whatsoever except that one guy who was obviously just a con man.
Speaker 1: Well, some of them were con men and some of them were poorly trained and some you know.
Speaker 1: And I think the problem here is that this job does not pay enough unless you're scamming people to Basically get someone who actually knows that they're doing to do that job.
Speaker 0: This is a broader problem that I've run into in my life a lot And I think it's just because IT and computers and all this are kind of new and cars have been around a while The average person if their car breaks they immediately they think crap I'm gonna have to spend a lot of money to get this fixed.
Speaker 0: and Then they go to a mechanic and they say all right mechanic, I don't know what's wrong with my car.
Speaker 0: I'm going to trust you to fix it for me because I know I can't do it myself And you're the only one qualified.
Speaker 0: and while there were a lot of scummy mechanics who ripped people off there's also a lot of mechanics who did the right thing.
Speaker 1: and but the other thing is that it's not like a Mechanic can go and make like more money elsewhere without getting more skills.
Speaker 1: true I mean skills required to do this computer repair job are the same skills required to like not do my job But do a similarly paying job.
Speaker 0: You need the equivalent of an associate's degree education to do Basic computer repair.
Speaker 0: It's not that.
Speaker 1: but with an associate's degree You could work as like, you know a job that pays a lot more money than computer repair guy.
Speaker 0: and for the geeks, dude I'll be honest with an associate's degree.
Speaker 1: You could do my job Yeah, and rims job pays more than geeks.
Speaker 0: My job pays twice as much as geeks.
Speaker 1: The thing is the only people who do this job are say high school and college kids who you know know what they're doing but they can't get a real job yet or People who aren't qualified or people ripping you off Enough money.
Speaker 0: in a lot of places there's regulation as to who can be a mechanic and what they are allowed to offer and also there's just a lot of.
Speaker 0: It seems like people customer side to know a mechanic is going to be expensive and most of the time just find a good mechanic and pay whatever they Ask and expect it to be a lot.
Speaker 0: but a lot of times people who want a computer repaired They they look at what we do and say oh you just looked at it for a second and you know Flip the switch that I could have done that.
Speaker 0: Why should I pay you a hundred bucks?
Speaker 1: Another problem here.
Speaker 1: Is that a car cost say $20,000?
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: and Parts of a car, you know, they're big and mechanical and you gotta your hands dirty and it looks like hard work.
Speaker 0: And and it is hard work.
Speaker 0: We're not pretending it is.
Speaker 1: But you know paying $800 to fix a $20,000 car makes sense Right, and you know whether that $800 is the the rare skilled knowledge of the laborer or the parts doesn't really matter to you Because the price compared to the price of the whole thing that you're fixing makes sense for a computer, right?
Speaker 1: $1,000 computer, you know, you might need a $50 repair like a ramstick But the price of the labor of the person makes it seem stupid.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have to if you want me to come to your house spend the time to figure it out.
Speaker 1: deal with you Get the ramstick you install it give it back.
Speaker 0: you notice Scott pies at that.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of tech jobs out there that both of us could do.
Speaker 0: that would pay quite a bit of money that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: but Honestly dealing with a lot of people is just not worth any amount of money.
Speaker 1: and when you add it up It doesn't make sense for the people getting their computer repaired to have me do it because the cost to have me do it versus untrained guy Makes it no law.
Speaker 1: you're better off buying a new computer than getting me to fix it But then untrained guy might not be trained.
Speaker 1: that's why the only way to get your computer fixed if you don't know what you're doing is either a learn something or Be find me in high school or college while it's still worth it to pay me to do it.
Speaker 0: Well, I think one big difference and I think this will be good in the long run Is that to be a mechanic to fix problems with cars?
Speaker 0: You need a lot of very expensive tools a lot of equipment a lot of like physical knowledge in addition to technical knowledge.
Speaker 0: So it's out of the realm for the average person to fix their car.
Speaker 1: not just physical knowledge But like tools like you need a lift.
Speaker 1: It's like sure I might read all these books on mechanics and everything about it and buy a tool set at Home Depot But I don't have a lift.
Speaker 1: that guy has a lift, you know No one can.
Speaker 1: it's not like everyone can afford to buy a lift.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know one guy buys a lift and everyone uses his.
Speaker 1: but he made money It doesn't you really everyone can own a Phillips screwdriver.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't need much.
Speaker 0: at most if you really want to repair computers You need one working computer from which you can take known working parts and stick them in possibly not working computers.
Speaker 1: You also need a Phillips screwdriver Possibly a flathead a little one to pop off heatsink and an internet connection with that working computer.
Speaker 1: So you can go to new egg calm or possibly Google.
Speaker 1: mostly new egg calm.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's a complicated thing is like I was kind of hitting that.
Speaker 0: I think the root issue is that people I By and large don't understand how Complicated computers are and as a result, they don't like like.
Speaker 0: they look at what we do and they think wow, that was easy.
Speaker 0: Why do I pay you when in fact it's not quite so easy.
Speaker 1: It's so easy.
Speaker 1: Why'd you call me?
Speaker 0: Yeah But they're more willing to pay for other things like cars or you know house repair because the car means a lot more to them Than their computer and the car cost a lot more.
Speaker 0: But the computer does mean a lot to them because they really need those pictures and they really care about it.
Speaker 0: It's it's kind of like people want something and they really want it and it's important to them But they're not willing to pay what it costs.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't mean that much to them.
Speaker 1: It means less than that.
Speaker 0: Well that that's the problem.
Speaker 0: It means just as much.
Speaker 0: but they decide they're not willing to pay and as a result That's a market where there's no money to be made by skilled people And it's not even worth it.
Speaker 1: You know, even if people were willing to pay the amount they're willing to pay could buy them a new computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the amount that they were required me to get to do the job.
Speaker 0: I think there could be a happy medium where the prices could be reasonable and yet people get a good help.
Speaker 1: what it will take Is an increased number of people with these skills to repair the computers.
Speaker 1: thus the the price that we can get.
Speaker 1: like You know, that would be like the job you could get and you couldn't really make any more money without getting more skills.
Speaker 0: I think another problem is just that computers Despite people don't realize that they take as much if not more maintenance than a car.
Speaker 0: I mean people.
Speaker 0: when they have a car they know.
Speaker 0: All right, I got to get an oil change every X.
Speaker 1: I gotta rotate my tires.
Speaker 0: I gotta buy new tires period.
Speaker 1: sometimes They maintain them more than they have to because someone scams them into doing it.
Speaker 1: Like you got a valve lean like hey, you want to replace that filter?
Speaker 1: You only had to replace 40,000 miles even though you've only had it for a thousand miles.
Speaker 1: But yeah You want to replace that filter 40 bucks?
Speaker 0: People expect that they have to do maintenance on a come on a car and if they don't know how to do it themselves They expect to pay someone else.
Speaker 0: not a lot of money, but they got to pay something.
Speaker 0: with computers Most people don't realize there's maintenance involved.
Speaker 0: they buy a computer and they just assume it'll last forever.
Speaker 1: It's like they don't do maintenance on their DVD players or their stereos.
Speaker 0: or you know They're televisions DVD players and stereos and televisions last a lot longer if you do do periodic maintenance.
Speaker 1: They do but they don't.
Speaker 1: they're not expected to have to do maintenance on those things.
Speaker 1: And in fact many of those things will say don't maintain me.
Speaker 1: Don't open me up You know, whereas with a computer and like a personal computer, it's not a Mac I guess you have to do maintenance and no one knows how or is told to do so or anything.
Speaker 0: See if people knew that maintenance had to be done if that was part of the these computer repair guys be out of a job.
Speaker 1: well
Speaker 0: No if it just if there were a global consciousness among people who had computers that there was some sort of maintenance that had to be done periodically That periodic maintenance can be done by much less skilled people for much less money than Actually fixing the problem that comes from a lack of maintenance.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: And if we could just convince people that computers are not these you just boxes like DVD players and that they're not Simple and you can use one and you cannot know a lot about it.
Speaker 0: But you have to be willing to pay someone if you're not willing to learn it's one of the two.
Speaker 0: learn something pay someone.
Speaker 0: If you're not willing to do either your computer is always going to crap out on you and there's nothing you can do about.
Speaker 1: but Don't get ripped off by one of these guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but who you how you gonna know?
Speaker 0: if you're gonna get ripped off because you don't know anything?
Speaker 1: Ask us right.
Speaker 0: So I'm not gonna talk about this much but our friend James Randi the most crotchety man in the world Has the James Randi challenge.
Speaker 0: we talked about this a while ago but he's kind of switched it up and he's ignoring the batshit crazy people because there's Nothing to be gained by slamming those.
Speaker 1: but he's paying attention to the batshit crazy people for how many years?
Speaker 1: And he's just fed up with it and they're a waste of his time.
Speaker 1: You know people come up.
Speaker 1: they're like I can douse.
Speaker 1: watch me douse and he's like, okay I'll watch you douse like I said, I would Okay, you didn't douse.
Speaker 1: now that I actually looked at it go away you nut job.
Speaker 1: But but the the spirits were not an alignment.
Speaker 0: like your pocket watch is interfering with fine I'll put my pocket watch at home.
Speaker 0: when will the spirits be in alignment and then the test still fails.
Speaker 0: and but nothing good was coming out of that.
Speaker 0: because basically, he was finding people and One by one at significant cost was either getting them to realize wow Maybe I can't douse or just making up excuses, but it wasn't changing the world in any meaningful way.
Speaker 0: so he decided now to only go after people where they have something to lose where the public and the press would care.
Speaker 0: and one of these groups of people are the golden ear audiophiles the people who spend $10,000 on a wooden knob to stick on top of their volume knob to make the Resonance of the crystal a quantum matrix sound better and thus make the music more playful to the ear.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, or you know the $40,000 speaker cables that are actually just whatever gauge wire.
Speaker 1: Yep, but it's hand-wound in Indonesia So why wouldn't it be better if it's hand-wound in like Malaysia?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: all I know is that these people are idiots and they're all over the internet And there's a famous quote that's like you know people who are into music You know they listen to songs and audiophiles listen to stereos.
Speaker 0: Oh so true Yeah, but the funny thing is anytime someone does a test of this audiophile crap it turns out that No, human being has ever been able to hear the difference.
Speaker 0: ever.
Speaker 0: I remember ever.
Speaker 1: I learned this lesson early on cuz when I was a kid I was watching PBS and there was some show.
Speaker 1: I forget what the hell it was called.
Speaker 0: was it Nova?
Speaker 1: No, it was started with a Z I think but he was they.
Speaker 1: basically it was when CDs were really new right and he was actually like a choice like CDs or cassettes, I don't know right.
Speaker 0: see I know right away.
Speaker 0: the answer was cassettes because I knew a lot about her CDs.
Speaker 0: Why did I say cassettes?
Speaker 0: Yep, cuz I'd learn I knew a lot about how cassettes worked and I knew that it was really shitty and making cassettes sucked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, once I knew what bias was and why I had to use it.
Speaker 1: Ah, but anyway, but anyway, of course CDs are better.
Speaker 1: However, what they did is they did a test of all these kids and they had the kids come in blindfold And they had four boom boxes and two of them had cassettes and two of them had CDs, right?
Speaker 1: They actually did like CDs.
Speaker 1: I think they're all CD slash cassette boom boxes right and they had four of them and the kids would come in and they try to you know say which was better and which Was worse and in the end They what cassette or a CD didn't matter.
Speaker 1: all that mattered was which boom box it was.
Speaker 1: and the boom box that looked the shittiest Actually was the best and it was because it had better speakers that were wooden and it didn't look as fancy as the other ones.
Speaker 1: But apparently it got more that sounds betters than the other ones did and it didn't matter if it was CD or cassette.
Speaker 1: it sounded the cassettes and that one sounded better than CDs and the other one.
Speaker 1: and Then I learned huh?
Speaker 1: A lot of people are gonna trick you into thinking things sound better when they don't yep.
Speaker 0: and taken to the extreme Now people will buy $40,000 speakers that don't sound better than $50 speakers and other people will make $40,000 without having to work, you know how many times Scott and I have been tempted to just be con men.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't start the audiophile business.
Speaker 1: It would be I could go to Radio Shack Then write a story put the story on a piece of paper in a box with the shit I bought at Radio Shack resell mark up the price times a thousand.
Speaker 0: it would be so easy.
Speaker 0: But yeah James Randi is going after these people and pretty much saying he's going after a bunch of specific ones.
Speaker 0: if in any double-blind test you can find any Statistically significant correlation between any of your products and a preference from listeners will give you a million dollars.
Speaker 0: Yep, and funny how they're not taking him up on it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it's real fun.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, is there any?
Speaker 1: he's basically saying if you can prove this difference easy?
Speaker 0: He's targeting a specific cable maker saying if your cables are actually better We'll give you a million dollars because you're so awesome.
Speaker 1: He's even like he's comparing them against monster cables, which are still a ripoff, you know I say go all the way compare them against like lamp cord.
Speaker 0: Lamp cord is some of the best speaker cable you're gonna find.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 1: that's why I'm saying, you know, really insult them.
Speaker 1: He's basically saying yeah try to beat monster cable.
Speaker 1: He should say try to beat lamp cord Cuz.
Speaker 1: I had lamp cord is really good.
Speaker 1: I should get some from Home Depot.
Speaker 1: It's cheaper than anything at Radio Shack Things of the day.
Speaker 0: So this might be a little old.
Speaker 0: I've seen videos like this before.
Speaker 0: People at RIT did something similar but nearly not as awesome.
Speaker 0: I have seen many similar pranks in my day But this one is just so well done and also it uses one of my favorite disco songs.
Speaker 1: It is the perfect execution of the idea.
Speaker 0: In fact, I think it's the best execution I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 0: So imagine if you're just you know, you're bored in college.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: Obviously pull a prank So you get two of your friends.
Speaker 0: you got three people get to an elevator Boombox playing born to be alive not the Hitler remix or the original born to be alive And disco ball and some lights And you dress up in polyester and you have a disco party in that elevator all day.
Speaker 1: I love doing shit in elevators like that, but only first got to RIT.
Speaker 0: I remember I went to visit in another building and the elevator opens and there's just a guy sitting in a lawn chair in the And he says hey and I say hey and I get in and he says so how you like an RIT so far And I'm like, it's okay.
Speaker 0: I met some weird guy sitting in an elevator.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah, they'll do that.
Speaker 0: Then I got off on the third floor and it was just Good time.
Speaker 0: I love that kind of prank.
Speaker 0: This video is so worth watching.
Speaker 1: I missed the days when I would see Unexpected things like that in my life on a daily basis.
Speaker 1: remember
Speaker 0: when we came home that one day and there's just a burning couch outside of our apartment And I remember all I thought was I hope that's the only one and we just walked past it and went in and then an Hour later we came out and it finished burning.
Speaker 0: There was the campus safety guy looking at it obviously thinking wonder who set this on fire?
Speaker 1: good times.
Speaker 0: Or that crazy guy who wore a Viking hat for what like a year and a half.
Speaker 1: I know that guy.
Speaker 0: I know that guy too.
Speaker 1: I think you might know him.
Speaker 1: You may know him very well.
Speaker 0: So, what do you got for me speaking of the college times?
Speaker 1: Oh boy You know people in college.
Speaker 1: They're pretty bored.
Speaker 1: No think of things to do, you know, they'll play some hacky sack They'll play some kickball some quarters 140 bucks playing quarters.
Speaker 1: All right, they'll play some frisbee.
Speaker 0: All right ultimate frisbee.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: What if they Get really bored and they're inside with the frisbee.
Speaker 1: What do you do then?
Speaker 1: Well, this is what you do.
Speaker 1: You play a game that these people call GlaxoSmithKline.
Speaker 1: No relation to the pharmaceutical company.
Speaker 1: The way the game works is step one you get a table.
Speaker 1: step two you get a frisbee Hopefully good frisbee.
Speaker 1: step three you get some grease.
Speaker 0: Grease me up woman.
Speaker 1: step four Grease the table.
Speaker 1: Oh Step five spin frisbee sideways on table.
Speaker 1: Get four people around the table and much like hacky sack Keep that frisbee spinning.
Speaker 1: And you watch this video these people doing this.
Speaker 1: and I'm like, hey, that's good times right there You know, there's something about.
Speaker 1: they even document all the different techniques.
Speaker 1: They come on.
Speaker 0: That's that's exactly what I was gonna About that college thing where you're so bored that you'll come up you and your friends with a new sport Whatever it may be and then you'll proceed to play that sport obsessively until you are Probably the best four people in the world at that sport.
Speaker 0: I think they're the only four people in the world Exactly, and at that point you have all the strategies all that you have names for the different possible moves.
Speaker 1: Like yeah, where do you think like, you know skateboarders?
Speaker 1: They call things like yeah, you're doing the reverse.
Speaker 1: I'll leave Ali something in the 720 handstand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or like, you know what figure skating the back the Lutz something and the something else.
Speaker 1: Where do you think those names came from the first guy to do it was like, oh look at this I'm gonna do the.
Speaker 1: he does something you're like, I call it the something chess is the same way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got the Polish opening my favorite opening even though I've never fucking won with it ever, but I think it's I like it Yep.
Speaker 1: so this one they've got like the wall and like the slide and the hop and the whatever.
Speaker 1: and These guys they got the right idea.
Speaker 0: There's just something to be said for making up a sport and then being really good at it.
Speaker 0: Yep, almost like air hockey.
Speaker 1: I've got a table.
Speaker 1: You don't mind getting greasy and a frisbee.
Speaker 0: They get the grease off.
Speaker 0: Towel grease doesn't come off so easy.
Speaker 1: towel grease remover.
Speaker 0: I imagine that table never recovered and they probably are gonna throw it away.
Speaker 1: pretty shitty table looking at it.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what they should have done is they should have had a square table.
Speaker 1: the square the table sort of rectangular with a square table.
Speaker 1: then all the players would be sort of equal and also they could sort of change the sport into instead of.
Speaker 1: How long could the four of us keep this up to?
Speaker 1: Knock it off the other guy's side.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: Sort of like warlords.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: That's a good reference.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: We got to review that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a damn good game.
Speaker 1: warlords is a good.
Speaker 1: game needs to be brought back 3d warlords Right.
Speaker 0: So the show might be a little different from usual shows because it's mostly gonna be me talking and Scott going.
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: Wow, huh?
Speaker 1: Or why you're stupid?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well because you might have noticed that there was no show last Thursday and last Wednesday was a cop-out.
Speaker 0: That's because for various reasons.
Speaker 0: I was in Arizona from Wednesday night until you know Not too long ago in the desert in the desert.
Speaker 0: Oh, I have never been west of Chicago in my life Until I flew to Arizona.
Speaker 1: I haven't been west of Novi, Michigan unless you count Israel is West But I went east to get there so I don't count that.
Speaker 0: wow Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: when we drove out to Novi that crazy land were at 4 in the morning.
Speaker 0: You were staring out at the freeway from the window and bitching about how many cars and where the fuck are those people going at?
Speaker 0: 4 in the morning.
Speaker 0: Why are there so many of them?
Speaker 0: But that's it was a good time.
Speaker 0: I think we've talked about that trip enough But I was in Arizona and I think I'm just gonna kind of chronologically talk about my trip because I noticed a lot of interesting things.
Speaker 0: So first off I'd like to say this is the first time in my life Since high school when I flew to Florida to March in the Citrus Bowl that I flew in a plane without incident.
Speaker 0: Nothing bad happened.
Speaker 0: My flight wasn't delayed.
Speaker 0: Nothing weird happened.
Speaker 0: I got four bags of animal crackers.
Speaker 0: I coconut tonic water.
Speaker 1: You know why that was?
Speaker 0: Cuz I flew jet blue.
Speaker 1: cuz you listen to me and you flew the jet blue instead of flying whatever crap you're flying before.
Speaker 0: Well, the reason I flew whatever crap I was flying before is cuz jet blue didn't fly at all the places I was trying to fly.
Speaker 1: They're a domestic airline.
Speaker 1: They only fly where it's profitable, which is what you wanted, right?
Speaker 1: You know, you didn't want the airlines to fly where it's not profitable.
Speaker 0: It's both cheaper and easier to fly to Tucson, Arizona or Phoenix, Arizona.
Speaker 0: Then it is to fly to Detroit, which is much closer.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know jet blue started out as we're gonna have all the same planes.
Speaker 1: We're gonna have flights to get out on time where they've actually got two kinds of planes now with less weight.
Speaker 1: That was originally.
Speaker 0: though they less waiting thing is they only have two kinds of planes and the planes are very similar.
Speaker 1: Yep, and they're gonna you know Not give you the crap food on the plane because you don't want it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, and it would cost too much to give you food.
Speaker 1: You actually want instead.
Speaker 1: I got animal crackers and water or cashews.
Speaker 1: Yep, and You know, we're gonna give you a TV in every seat and there's no first class.
Speaker 1: It's just coach all the way through this one class and it's pretty nice class.
Speaker 1: It's not quite coach.
Speaker 1: It's not quite first class.
Speaker 1: it's normal class and They started expanding and it totally worked.
Speaker 1: and while nowadays They're still not as cheap as they used to be because of rising fuel costs and whatnot as a whole Jet blue in my experience is still a more a less stressful flying experience than any other domestic airline.
Speaker 0: And pretty much I just got to say if you ever drive to JFK Unless except in very specific surface.
Speaker 0: So parking's a lot of money You're probably stupid because it not only is it cheaper faster easier and nicer to take air train to wherever you're going But it's just better.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to drive to JFK.
Speaker 0: Well, you know luggage.
Speaker 1: Well, like my dad would drive me there.
Speaker 1: Let me off and then go away.
Speaker 0: That's okay Yeah, but if you don't want to park there, so I just took Metro North to Grand Central.
Speaker 0: Then I took the sixth train up to 51st Street.
Speaker 0: I took the E train all the way across to Jamaica.
Speaker 0: Then I got off there got right on air train took me right to my terminal got off check my bags Right there and then I had a really crappy burrito in the terminal.
Speaker 1: Ah, you don't eat that food in the terminal.
Speaker 1: I was hungry this one place in the jet blue terminal there where you can get like mad french toast for breakfast.
Speaker 1: But that's it.
Speaker 1: You don't want to eat in the terminal.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, yeah Well, there was a sushi place and I really wanted it, but it was way too expensive and I imagined it wasn't that good.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah They do have that really big convenience store there that sells like half touristy crap But also half useful stuff.
Speaker 0: I bought a naked juice there and I bought some cookies for the plane Usually buy gum there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm glad I didn't eat at the sushi place cuz when I got off in Tucson Three hours later.
Speaker 0: I can't believe how fast we flew to Arizona.
Speaker 0: even the pilot got on.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah, there was a tailwind.
Speaker 0: We're here stupidly early.
Speaker 0: Just so you know.
Speaker 0: But the exact same sushi place was in the terminal and Tucson.
Speaker 1: That's how those things go like when you go to the rest stops on the highway.
Speaker 1: They all have the same places.
Speaker 1: Yep places you don't see in normal places cuz although I Would eat at them.
Speaker 0: so I got picked up at the airport and one thing I'd like to notice is it was a lot Fucking hotter in Yonkers than it was in Arizona.
Speaker 0: God damn.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe did it.
Speaker 1: was it actually temperature wise hotter or would just feel hotter?
Speaker 0: Well, it was both cuz.
Speaker 0: one it was like a 10 or 11 when I got to Arizona.
Speaker 0: So it was cooled off to like 75 80 degrees.
Speaker 0: that makes sense, but it was like 90 and Yonkers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people always tell you, you know, like oh the desert is really cold at night.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe but I was in the desert in Israel, which is a real desert and at night it was still warm.
Speaker 0: It depends on what part of the desert and when.
Speaker 0: but I got to say even during the day when it was, you know 90-95 degrees whatever It was really nice.
Speaker 0: I was never uncomfortably hot the entire time there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean in Israel again because my only desert experience I walked through the desert for the whole day.
Speaker 0: You can't walk through ten deserts.
Speaker 1: I walked through the desert the whole for like an entire day and then part of another entire day.
Speaker 1: I think maybe even two and a half days.
Speaker 0: I don't remember, you know people always say it's not the heat It's you that's the humidity.
Speaker 0: That's a hundred percent true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never got like tired like I was gonna fall over.
Speaker 1: Well, that's cuz.
Speaker 1: I was drinking water.
Speaker 1: But regardless of that, you know that feeling of like, you know water.
Speaker 1: Well, you know the the stereotypical cartoon guy in the desert that's all parched.
Speaker 1: You never felt bad walk in the desert.
Speaker 1: I was just walking and Drinking water and walking and the water was warm and it didn't feel good to drink it.
Speaker 1: But I just kept walking.
Speaker 1: I didn't feel tired at any time.
Speaker 0: I always say I like really hot weather.
Speaker 0: people always a lot of people balk at that.
Speaker 0: But I gotta say if it was always 95 degrees and 2% relative humidity I would be a happy rim.
Speaker 0: I can tell you what it was so nice out there.
Speaker 1: as long as the showers are cold and there's a fridge rater somewhere I was just perfectly comfortable the whole time.
Speaker 0: I didn't even work up a sweat except when I was you know Cleaning out the horses water and giving the goats some hay.
Speaker 1: Now it's are talking about animals camels, right you get to like when you're in the desert in Israel You get to ride the.
Speaker 0: they're really cool, but they smell bad and they'll spit on you.
Speaker 1: No, not really Riding them is not comfortable.
Speaker 1: You're better off walking.
Speaker 1: notice that whenever you see a picture of a guy with a camel all his Cargo is on the camel and he's walking with the camel like held on a leash.
Speaker 1: That's cuz.
Speaker 1: riding the camel sucks it bounces up and down and hurts your ass, you know, my grandpa told me the same thing.
Speaker 0: It's like you.
Speaker 0: you lean so far back you feel like you're gonna fall off.
Speaker 0: then you lean so far forward You feel like you're gonna fall off.
Speaker 0: then the camel stops and scratches itself.
Speaker 0: Then you lean so far back you feel like you're gonna fall off.
Speaker 1: riding on a camel is not.
Speaker 1: is you're better off walking?
Speaker 1: We didn't do it.
Speaker 1: It's not a camel goes fast either.
Speaker 1: I mean if it went fast, you'd be alright, but it doesn't.
Speaker 1: That's why you want a desert horse.
Speaker 1: is that that's comfortable and goes also desert horse.
Speaker 0: You could you late and then sweep down upon the caravan slaughter them all with scimitars and take their trade good.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: As long as it's an oasis to have the horse drink water Yeah, and if the oasis dries up, well, you better invade another one.
Speaker 1: That's right right with beautiful women.
Speaker 0: So I see my mom and I get picked up and I get back to the house and I got to say I haven't Seen my parents yet out in the desert.
Speaker 0: But they have a beautiful freaking house in the middle of nowhere like an hour out of Tucson near this town called Benson But Benson's even not that close.
Speaker 0: They have this beautiful like southern Mexican American Spanish American villa.
Speaker 1: Well, you know desert.
Speaker 1: I mean buying a house.
Speaker 1: most of the cost is the land and desert land is cost nothing But it looks like it fits in with the land.
Speaker 0: So well, it's got.
Speaker 0: this beautiful terrace outside is gigantic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've got like a covered shed and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: houses like that are real easy to make tons of land And there's a desert.
Speaker 0: so it's not like the natural disaster is gonna destroy it and my parents are really cool So they don't have a green lot or anything.
Speaker 0: They have whatever grew there.
Speaker 0: granted, you know, they're doing a lot of work.
Speaker 0: They pull up all the prickly vines and all the bad things and they burn the brush.
Speaker 0: every few got a cactus.
Speaker 0: There's cactuses all over but mostly it's just you know desert trees and I gotta have a big cactus in the front lawn.
Speaker 1: Just you know, I live in Florida I gotta have a palm tree.
Speaker 0: you realize that when those cactuses get to the point Where they grow like they're too little happy arms coming out the side.
Speaker 0: They're already hundreds of years old.
Speaker 0: It's such a fucking crime to harm a cactus there.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't believe I know but that's why I build my house Where the cat where the front lawn would be where the cactus already is.
Speaker 0: But uh, the land is big and the dogs the dogs freaking love it out there and I haven't seen those dogs.
Speaker 0: and you know Years, I love those dogs.
Speaker 0: I grew up with some of those dogs and I'm very proud that the dogs remembered me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't know they remembered you.
Speaker 1: they could.
Speaker 1: isn't like it's a man it's man.
Speaker 0: no they remembered me.
Speaker 0: They acted quite differently from the way they acted around my uncle Mike uh-huh, but they came out and they have all this land and the Keeley.
Speaker 0: the little Irish Setters showed me around the property like.
Speaker 0: she took Me out and showed me like the whole perimeter and every time I'd stop she like came back and said come on Come on and grab me and made me follow her and Riley just like.
Speaker 0: apparently there's this spot where this tortoise comes through every few Days and the tortoise either isn't smart enough to realize that there's a dog there or the tortoise just wants a ride.
Speaker 0: because Apparently Riley goat this big Irish setter goes to the spot and always checks if he finds this tortoise He picks it up and runs around with it with like a football for like an hour and then tosses it somewhere.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But driving in I got to say, you know, we're coming down this desert road.
Speaker 0: There's no light.
Speaker 0: We're kicking up dust.
Speaker 0: I saw like 40 jackrabbits running out of the way and kicking and jumping and stomping and then later on I get to you know Right near the house and a quail rock walks by and I I've never seen a quail in person other than in the zoo.
Speaker 0: But quails are really cute when they run because they just kind of run like bit a bit a bit a bit a bit of straight across and they make these really great noises.
Speaker 0: and There were like two or three hundred quail and they just kept coming and then every time I tried to drive by they ran one Way or the other across the road.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've ever seen a quail.
Speaker 0: You know what a quail looks like with a little like Bob Lee coming out of the top of his head like quail man.
Speaker 1: I've seen cartoons of quails.
Speaker 0: Have you seen quail man?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Well, they look a lot like that.
Speaker 0: I figured they're really really cute.
Speaker 0: All right, and of course my mom I didn't like.
Speaker 0: I heard talk but I hadn't met it.
Speaker 0: They have a horse and it's one of the cutest horses I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: She's a half Arabian half quarter horse and she's this really dark not a long horse No quarter cross not like a long cat.
Speaker 0: and she's really smart and really sweet and really pretty.
Speaker 0: and she's just beautiful horse.
Speaker 0: And I spent a lot of time just brushing her and feeding her and cleaning out her stall because I just I wanted to do that and I gotta say like by the second morning getting up and you know carrying hay out to the horse and brushing the horse and cleaning out the water Trough and then giving hay to all the goats.
Speaker 0: and the goats are really friendly.
Speaker 0: They're just like dogs They want to play with you and taking the dogs out.
Speaker 0: and you know, I could see myself living that life Just getting up every morning gathering the brush burning it feeding the animals.
Speaker 0: I could live that life.
Speaker 0: I could be one of those pioneer in the desert type guys Drive into town once a week with a pickup truck buy a bunch of hay don't even have to pay because everyone knows me.
Speaker 0: They know I'll pay at some point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think I can live that life.
Speaker 0: The only thing is I realized not too long after I got there that in the entire state of Arizona You cannot get pizza.
Speaker 0: There is no pizza worth eating in that entire state the whole state as far as I can tell from everyone I talked to.
Speaker 0: no one in Arizona knows how to make pizza.
Speaker 0: They don't know bread sauce cheese One the water is kind of bad out there.
Speaker 0: to one place We went to.
Speaker 1: I mean there's such rapid communication in the world now didn't one place we went to?
Speaker 0: it's like they.
Speaker 0: just they opened A pizza place.
Speaker 0: so you order pizza and they give it to you in your styrofoam box.
Speaker 1: Won't the styrofoam melt and then get on the pizza?
Speaker 0: and even if it doesn't that's gonna be one Soggy ass pizza by the time it gets to you.
Speaker 0: It sure is and a lot of them They just don't put yeast in the pizza.
Speaker 0: So it ends up being like this flatbread, but it's not good flatbread It's just crappy flatbread.
Speaker 1: how they could go on the internet and look up pizza recipe.
Speaker 0: They just don't think to.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: How does I don't understand this?
Speaker 1: we?
Speaker 1: it's a known solved problem.
Speaker 1: What do people like?
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: But at the same token I can get good Mexican food anywhere for no money, and I learned something.
Speaker 0: I did a bunch of different Mexican places, you know authentic Mexican food real Mexican food with Mexicans.
Speaker 0: You know what it tastes the same as the cafe Maya.
Speaker 0: Yeah 100 percent.
Speaker 0: that made me so happy because my mom was like you can't get good Mexican food up there.
Speaker 0: and everything I tried I was like, you know what?
Speaker 0: This is exactly like the cafe Maya up near us.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: We have one place that has you know Mexican food right like like they have everywhere.
Speaker 1: They have zero places that have pizza like we have here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So what does that tell you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time we make pizza down there.
Speaker 1: the way we make it here We can charge a lot of money for it because I'm sure the cafe Maya charges a lot more money for that food than the places down there.
Speaker 0: I think the reason for that is just simply that it's not so much because we live outside of Arizona or that Arizona's weird.
Speaker 0: It's just that we live in downstate New York City where we can get Authentic food from pretty much anywhere in the world if we want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we want Somalian food.
Speaker 1: We want Brazilian food, but they don't even have pizza Hut in Arizona.
Speaker 0: Pizza Hut's not pizza.
Speaker 0: That's like saying Taco Bell is tacos.
Speaker 1: I know but I mean it'd be better than the stuff that you're talking about.
Speaker 0: The other thing I noticed driving in there was a surprising number of Japanese or borrows is almost pizza Japanese or quote unquote Japanese or sushi restaurants like a disturbing number between The like the edge of town and the airport.
Speaker 0: I saw no less than 35 sushi restaurants 35 I counted Mm-hmm and one.
Speaker 0: I wonder where they get their sushi from.
Speaker 1: that is a good question.
Speaker 1: They imagine the freshest fish.
Speaker 1: I imagine they desert and she's dead.
Speaker 0: I yeah fishes desert.
Speaker 0: There's no fishes in the desert fishes in the sea chickens on the land.
Speaker 1: There's no chickens in the desert either.
Speaker 0: Actually, there are a lot of them.
Speaker 1: Well, what are they eating?
Speaker 0: They're eating seed that you put out for him.
Speaker 0: Okay, actually a lot of my parents neighbors have a bunch of chickens and I'm trying to convince cuz my mom wants to start milking the goats and make goat cheese, which I'm all about.
Speaker 0: and I'm trying to convince him to get some chickens too because chickens.
Speaker 0: there's certain breeds of chickens that do really well in the desert and I know my mom would take great care of those chickens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't like goat cheese.
Speaker 0: I really what's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: go cheese is awesome.
Speaker 1: plus, you know As you know as much as you would study to me like even if I made goat cheese and studied on the internet how To make it.
Speaker 1: I don't trust it not to be diseased.
Speaker 0: Apparently it's not that hard to make.
Speaker 0: I talked to some locals and a lot of them do it and my mom actually works with This Russian woman who has been pestering her constantly.
Speaker 0: you have a goat and you're not milking it.
Speaker 0: What the hell is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: I'll come and milk it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just give me that milk.
Speaker 1: I'm crazy rushy woman watch out.
Speaker 0: But actually I ate some Russian food because the woman made us some Russian lunch and it was these.
Speaker 0: they were meatballs But they were Russian meatballs.
Speaker 0: I gotta ask what spices she used because it didn't taste like anything I've ever eaten before but it was awesome like super awesome Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: We didn't have any Vodak to go with it.
Speaker 1: But oh well, they don't have Vodak in Arizona.
Speaker 0: I'll admit I don't know much about Russian food.
Speaker 0: I kind of imagine it's similar to Polish food.
Speaker 0: And the only other thing I can think of is the stereotype of caviar and vodka.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of Eastern European foods while not, you know, exactly identical from country to country are very similar.
Speaker 1: You know, it's sort of like a gradient like the.
Speaker 1: you know It's like you go east and then as you go, you know the Far East like, you know Siberia and as you go west the food changes a little bit more
Speaker 0: Like in France, I mean
Speaker 1: and then like you get to Poland that it's you know, it's food
Speaker 0: in northern France and food in southern France.
Speaker 0: it's all French, but it's very different.
Speaker 0: But yet if you go from south to north like it changes a little bit every time you go to along the way.
Speaker 1: Yep, so that's you know, that's what it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: But the scary thing is aside from there being a lot of Japanese food There was a lot of fake Japanese food.
Speaker 0: Like I looked at some of these places and they had sushi and they had you know Japanese food I like.
Speaker 0: but some of these places they're like yes Asian Japanese bowl house and I looked inside and it was just a Chinese restaurant or even worse They had dishes like Asian bowl that had rice and stuff in it Mm-hmm, and even my mom because my mom doesn't like that finding kind of food very much for she was like Yeah, those places are no good, but people around here love them
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll get to people eating around there cuz I noticed something disturbing.
Speaker 0: But aside from all that one other thing I know is leading the pizza.
Speaker 1: That's not real you'd be.
Speaker 0: there aren't a lot of national change.
Speaker 0: Like there weren't a lot of McDonald's and there weren't a lot of.
Speaker 1: well, did you go to like, you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I heavily populated area.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: I also asked a lot of.
Speaker 0: I went through like Tucson, which is a big city.
Speaker 0: I also just talked to a lot of people and people who Phoenix my parents.
Speaker 0: not, you know I asked her out.
Speaker 0: I it was weird and my mom was asking me cuz no Walmart.
Speaker 0: There's Walmart Okay, but I'm talking about food wise.
Speaker 1: not that I like that but just you know, yeah
Speaker 0: but she even asked me, you know, I'm asking a lot and it's weird how I paid attention to things that I wouldn't have paid attention to if I'd gone there previously just because
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: do geek nights and I Kind of looked at a lot of things from a sort of journalistic side Like I thought about what am I gonna say about this experience when I came back.
Speaker 0: and it's weird out.
Speaker 0: Just doing this show has kind of changed the way I look at the world.
Speaker 0: I pay attention to a lot of things I otherwise wouldn't have cared about.
Speaker 0: But while there aren't a lot of McDonald's and Burger Kings all over the place There's a lot of Really really really specific niche only from a certain part of the world.
Speaker 0: a certain part of America change.
Speaker 0: They're like there was a Little Caesars Pizza.
Speaker 0: Well, I've never didn't have actual pizza.
Speaker 0: Yes, it tasted exactly like Little Caesars Pizza.
Speaker 1: I'm like, so is the best pizza in Arizona is what you're saying?
Speaker 0: Yeah, while Little Caesars Pizza is not good from a pizza perspective.
Speaker 0: I love Little Caesars Pizza.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure if you went to like a baseball stadium or something or the football stadium You might have been able to get real pizza Possibly.
Speaker 0: but at every place like Phoenix I got my mom has been looking around I gotta imagine this pizza in Phoenix somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's hard to find.
Speaker 0: you have to go to like a fancy Italian restaurant and they'll make you a good pizza.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, but
Speaker 0: there was a Little Caesars and there's Jack in the Box, which wasn't really common elsewhere but in the cities there was a couple of them and So many of these little chains that I found out why from all the locals that most of the people living in Arizona especially in the cities are not Arizona natives their transplants from all over the country who just decided screw it.
Speaker 0: I'm done with this snow bullshit.
Speaker 0: I'm moving to Arizona.
Speaker 1: Yep, a lot of old people move out there just as many as move to Florida and those people are kind of adventurous.
Speaker 0: A lot of them don't like, you know, normal fast food, whatever but at the same time they miss whatever their local thing was.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of money in finding out where people came from in Arizona and making whatever local chain.
Speaker 0: My mom wrote to White Castle and was like you should open a White Castle here.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, and you know what they said?
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: You know how many letters we get.
Speaker 0: we're trying.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: Are they trying to come up with to the health standard or what?
Speaker 0: Actually, that's a problem because remember our friend Kate's trying to get Wegmans out, you know in New York around here The problem is just you know White Castle or Wegmans or whatever have distributors in a certain area.
Speaker 0: You got to get similar distributors in other places and sometimes that's hard.
Speaker 1: You got to have a truck show up every day with new White Castles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what a truck has to come from somewhere.
Speaker 0: but White Castle is a warehouse.
Speaker 1: You can't have a whole warehouse just for one White Castle.
Speaker 1: You need to open a whole bunch of White Castles to support that warehouse and it takes a lot of time to set up that Warehouse.
Speaker 1: and then how does this stuff get to that warehouse from some other warehouse?
Speaker 1: But bigger?
Speaker 0: just the fact that White Castle responded right away.
Speaker 0: I was like, seriously, we know.
Speaker 1: Oh my god It's probably their form letter.
Speaker 0: No, they told her like we've gotten four other specific letters about this in the past month.
Speaker 0: Believe me.
Speaker 0: We will tell you when one comes.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I was just thinking about that.
Speaker 0: cuz actually I'm really hungry right now and I'm also the hungry.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to like it the hunger.
Speaker 0: No But now my mom brought this up long before I made any Observation and you know even Emily's been making fun of me.
Speaker 0: because lately whenever someone's in my way I'm always like yeah fat people and a lot of times I almost say it not even in the Fat people but it's like a generic term for people in my way like not fat of the body but fat of the mind And I just I use the word more than I show
Speaker 1: fat of the character.
Speaker 0: Yeah like.
Speaker 0: there are fat people who are jolly and awesome and there are skinny people who are Indignant and crappy and I I got to pick a better word I guess but I'm never gonna complain about fat people as in obese at New York State again Because good.
Speaker 1: Well, even if you're at IBM and there's a lady taking up the entire hallway is that was only one lady?
Speaker 0: Good fucking God are the majority of people other than like the workers like the?
Speaker 0: you know The Mexican workers and the laborers.
Speaker 0: they're so fat and there's so many of it.
Speaker 0: And my mom was like she like when I came.
Speaker 0: she's like.
Speaker 0: then you won't believe how many people are fat around here.
Speaker 0: And I was like whatever, you know my oh my god.
Speaker 0: the majority of human beings I saw were scared not like, you know a little overweight.
Speaker 0: cuz you know, there's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: I'm talking medically Dangerously scarily obese Mm-hmm and all of them are also transplants.
Speaker 0: and the thing I don't get is why they move to the desert.
Speaker 0: How can they bear it?
Speaker 0: It's so hot and they're so big.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to look up like what's the fattest state in Mississippi?
Speaker 1: I know but try to look up like a list.
Speaker 1: I know Mississippi's the fattest but I want to see like the second.
Speaker 1: third.
Speaker 0: fourth I don't remember.
Speaker 0: all I know is that Colorado's the leanest Yeah, and New York City is actually like the leanest urban center.
Speaker 0: But the thing is there's nothing wrong with being a little fat or a little, you know Chubby or whatever.
Speaker 0: cuz you know what.
Speaker 0: not everyone has to be rail thing But if you weigh more than 200 pounds more than you should.
Speaker 0: something's wrong.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I can't got on the numbers for Arizona, right?
Speaker 1: But apparently Arizona has less than 25% adult obesity, Mississippi has 29 and a half percent.
Speaker 0: You know, that's the thing the the illegals because there's a lot of them.
Speaker 0: I even talked to a few but I'm not gonna cuz.
Speaker 0: the opinions in Arizona are very mixed about that.
Speaker 0: It's kind of interesting cuz.
Speaker 0: on one hand.
Speaker 0: They're like a lot of people I talked to were yeah I don't want them coming in illegal But at the other hand they're like.
Speaker 0: I really want them to come in legally because they work really hard and they're really really nice People.
Speaker 1: so I'm looking at the map of the states that have more than 25% adult obesity all in the southwest.
Speaker 1: No, it's pretty much Michigan.
Speaker 1: It's a straight.
Speaker 1: People are super fat in Michigan, Michigan, Indiana, Kentucky, Tennessee, Alabama, Mississippi, Louisiana, Texas.
Speaker 1: You know what it is down to Texas straight what it is.
Speaker 1: and then South Carolina and West Virginia.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's where all the corn is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even that's where the corn is.
Speaker 1: the same amount of corn gets eaten everywhere Maybe but maybe there's more corn there.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's corn in the air.
Speaker 1: I think it's just the lifestyle of the Midwest.
Speaker 1: Yeah is is the most.
Speaker 1: sit around do nothing ist.
Speaker 1: Ah Yeah, the most driving ist the least walking ist.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's the other thing I gotta say.
Speaker 0: when I was going you know 85 miles an hour 90 miles an hour.
Speaker 0: and I saw a cop and I go ah shit and I slow down to 75 And my mom says why'd you slow down?
Speaker 0: you weren't speeding?
Speaker 0: And even better the cop I passed wasn't even a cop.
Speaker 0: It was Border Patrol.
Speaker 0: They don't care if someone's going 150 They're just watching for unless 150 full of Mexicans.
Speaker 0: Yeah But really that the the whole you know immigration debate down there Being down there really puts a different perspective on it because on one hand They really are putting a big strain on the educational system and on a health care system.
Speaker 0: But at the same time and no one I talked to disagreed They're really nice people and they work really hard and everyone I talked to really wanted a system where they could come here Illegally as long as they weren't let in illegally.
Speaker 0: they should be citizens and they should get help and they should you know get classes to learn English.
Speaker 0: and The sentiment among a lot of those people was that they and this is the sentiment of those people.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna say my opinion either way But I'm just gonna paraphrase.
Speaker 0: those people work a lot harder and try a lot harder than that people know don't then?
Speaker 0: a lot of people who were born in this country and A lot of those people probably deserve to be here more than a lot of people who live here now That's for sure, and I don't know how I feel.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a complicated issue, but it's interesting to hear the perspectives of people are actually down there.
Speaker 0: You know dealing with this problem Yeah, but at the same time while a lot there's a lot of problems with people not speaking English Most people down there speak English.
Speaker 0: In fact more of the people I talked to even some illegal immigrants spoke more English than people running the white castles up in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I could probably talk for another hour.
Speaker 0: I don't want to borrow everyone but Arizona at least you know Tucson out in the middle of the desert is a really nice place and I'll save this for another time because I got a whole show I can do about my childhood because My mom gave me I found all the things that I've left with my parents from when I was a kid all the essays I wrote.
Speaker 0: I read a Christmas list that I wrote when I was in fourth grade.
Speaker 1: Yeah All that kind of stuff is mostly at my parents house and a lot of it's thrown out Whatever.
Speaker 0: my mom gave me my high school class ring Which on one side has a picture of a trumpet and on the other side has a picture of a dragon.
Speaker 1: I just always had mine.
Speaker 1: It's over there.
Speaker 1: I think it has like a computer on one side and then something else on the other side.
Speaker 1: the best
Speaker 0: thing was my mom gave Me a bunch of pictures I had and one of them was a photograph of my bedroom in high school And I'm going to scan that in and kind of put a bunch of call-out boxes to point out cuz I Was such a dork.
Speaker 0: in this picture offhand from memory visible are like 40 forgotten realms books For container ends so many pewter dragons and wizards and crystals.
Speaker 1: I don't waste the money on those.
Speaker 0: a wizard staff a bet a bastard sword a bunch of Atari games all The manga I owned which constituted a good majority of the manga in the state of Michigan Like displayed prominently as prized possessions.
Speaker 0: I had comic books in those days all of Sailor Moon along with End of Evangelion in fan sub form a Big like Les Miserables poster.
Speaker 0: two Star Wars posters one of which is tasteful one of which is 14 year old tasteful.
Speaker 0: It was so nostalgic the fridge that was full of dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper and nothing more.
Speaker 1: yeah, I guess it's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: It's like you.
Speaker 1: you know like what was the last time you were in that house.
Speaker 1: You know like a zillion years ago.
Speaker 0: It's like I.
Speaker 1: I was in that it was in my bedroom.
Speaker 1: I had the same bedroom since I was like three and it's still there, and I still go to it.
Speaker 1: It's largely intact and my brother lived in it alone for a few years.
Speaker 1: So he messed it up and made it sort of his.
Speaker 1: but most of my stuff is still there.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of like seeing a picture of.
Speaker 1: it is like what I was just there.
Speaker 1: Yeah big deal, right?
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna go any longer.
Speaker 0: We've gone kind of long.
Speaker 0: and yeah, Arizona was awesome.
Speaker 0: once I get the pictures developed I say developed because I couldn't find the charger to my camera in time.
Speaker 0: So I just bought a disposable camera out there, and now I got a shit about a disposable digital.
Speaker 1: You could hack it to reuse it what I couldn't find any Yeah, so even at CVS.
Speaker 0: So I've got this archaic thing where I have to go to a store And they're gonna use a chemical process to get pictures off of it.
Speaker 0: such poison those chemicals I'm gonna have to scan him in.
Speaker 1: it's weird the smelliness the chemicals.
Speaker 0: But I'll post them when I get a chance and don't forget to send us in your questions and the show will resume on Monday.
Speaker 1: That was an easy show for me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: if you like what you hear you Can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.