Speaker 1: It's Monday June 25th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights Tonight we talk about firewalls.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: The second mocha that we went to I'm sure it's not the second mocha ever.
Speaker 1: Well as far as we're concerned it is I'm sure okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's nice and done.
Speaker 0: It was the high quality as expected.
Speaker 1: yep We got to hang out with a lot of awesome podcasters at the awesome after party.
Speaker 1: But we'll talk about all that on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I got to buy a lot of stuff But I kind of regret not buying some things that were there.
Speaker 1: I spent Every single dollar that I had on me, and then I borrowed 10 bucks from Scott to buy one more thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would have liked to walk around it one more time, but oh well Seeing is how many people had the exact same stuff and the exact same tables and the exact same spot as last year.
Speaker 0: I'll just go again next year get whatever I missed.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: But also on Sunday the the Visigoths came over to play D&D yep, and they didn't make as many Hidden damages they have in the past.
Speaker 1: I didn't find any broken glasses for the first time ever Wow, but they they were not perfect by any means.
Speaker 1: no I particularly like how they left Boxes full of unrinsed soda cans on the floor by the door just waiting for the ants to come.
Speaker 0: oh that was just awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah I was glad to come home to that.
Speaker 0: and how about all those people who weigh over a hundred and fifty pounds sitting in the 150 pound weight limit?
Speaker 0: video?
Speaker 1: right yes, we I mean we like the video rocker But there isn't really an adult video rocker that isn't either overpriced or crap.
Speaker 1: so as a result Scott and I bought the children's video rockers, which are fine because Combined we weigh less than 300.
Speaker 1: We worry about 300 pounds combined.
Speaker 1: We don't weigh so much yeah, but a lot of people weigh a lot more than us and those video rockers can't hold so much weight and They're basically they've been all but destroyed by our friends over the last couple of years.
Speaker 0: We should just go buy some high-quality ones and say no one's allowed to sit in them But us.
Speaker 1: I've already told people not to sit in them.
Speaker 1: They do anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even better someone in sitting in the video rocker improperly happened to also fall backwards and break my piano.
Speaker 0: They can pay.
Speaker 1: yeah, well I can fix it.
Speaker 1: It's just the pedestal is cracked a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the PI I can't get it fixed just because that thing's ancient.
Speaker 0: They don't make it anymore and the people yell at us like we're somehow mean when we yell at them for messing up.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna have to go back to the strategy of not letting people bring stuff into our house when they visit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, keep everything that belongs to you in your car.
Speaker 1: Well, at least when they all visit if we bring one person over there's no trouble when they all come that's right.
Speaker 0: And we got to take pictures of the house.
Speaker 0: We got a duct tape shut all ever all the cabinets and everything so they can't use our stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah and then we take pictures of the house before they come and then we just Detain them illegally and don't let them leave until the house looks the same way It does in the pictures and if they break anything they got to pay for it.
Speaker 1: Luckily this time I pretty much kept everyone out of my room.
Speaker 1: I mean one person slept on the blue chair as a result.
Speaker 1: My room was untouched.
Speaker 1: I don't think guests are ever sleeping in this room again, except maybe in the blue chair.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my room also is untouched except I had to like move a whole bunch of stuff out of the way and then well Yeah, well the stuff you moved out of the way was the gigantic mess of yours.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's just a pile of dirty clothes.
Speaker 0: It's all that's ever on my floor.
Speaker 1: I don't know how you get this pile of dirty clothes on the floor.
Speaker 1: Don't you have a hamper?
Speaker 0: Basically, what happens right is I do some laundry and then I don't put the laundry away.
Speaker 0: So the baskets with the clean laundry are on the floor and I don't have time to put the laundry away.
Speaker 0: So the clean laundry sits in the basket.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: So what you're saying?
Speaker 1: that you don't have time to put one baskets worth of laundry.
Speaker 1: Oh Two baskets.
Speaker 0: No, not until a weekend comes around.
Speaker 0: I don't have time to do laundry.
Speaker 0: I got to do what I only did half my laundry the last time.
Speaker 1: Does it take you to put laundry away?
Speaker 0: It takes less than five minutes takes me a lot of time.
Speaker 0: How you don't even fold things the way I do cuz I got a lot of compartments and I got to sort it all out.
Speaker 1: It doesn't take that long.
Speaker 1: You might I'm gonna have to.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be like that Seinfeld where they taught Kramer out of shower.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna teach you out of a clothes away.
Speaker 0: You wanna put my clothes away be my guest.
Speaker 1: No, I'll just stand there and watch you do it and point out ways you could do it faster.
Speaker 1: I'm not like in a rush Whatever, you know a Kramer how he washed each individual part of his body and then rinsed it instead of doing the whole wash And then the whole rinse.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I might be.
Speaker 1: are you going like sock?
Speaker 0: sock no Underwear Sock, no, I'm not doing that.
Speaker 1: Do you sort your socks by length size color and dirtiness?
Speaker 0: All my socks are the same.
Speaker 1: How can it take so long?
Speaker 0: It's not Whatever.
Speaker 0: my other problem is I do lots of laundry less often as opposed to if we had a dryer.
Speaker 0: It would be much better off.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: The best part of all of this is that There's one person in our group will do people who always kind of say hey We should run D&D at our house sometime and even though while their house is really nice.
Speaker 1: They have a basement It's not really.
Speaker 1: it doesn't have one big room for D&D like we do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you need a big room.
Speaker 1: Our house isn't even big enough for D&D.
Speaker 1: No, it's not, you know big room with a big table But at the same time I'd love to have D&D there because then it's I don't have to deal with the Visigoths anymore Yeah, but maybe they won't mess up their house.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, well, we'll see how many of them listen and then try to complain to us when we make fun of them on the air.
Speaker 1: I think the real plan is next time we have a bunch of people over We'll just quietly keep track of who breaks what and when and who makes what mess and we'll just call you out on the air With your real names, that sounds good to me.
Speaker 1: I like that plan.
Speaker 1: It's okay.
Speaker 1: I'd sort of gotten the news.
Speaker 0: So this is really really good essay written by Dana Boyd.
Speaker 0: I saw it on this blog many too many that I read and it's a. it's a group web blog on social Software and it basically posts, you know, there's all these big thinkers.
Speaker 0: They're always thinking about blog is fears and Folksonomies and all those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I'm always dubious of those people I know but they write all their essays on the web 2.0s and all that business and you know while they're not a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: Right, you know, they're.
Speaker 0: they're always very intellectually interesting.
Speaker 1: Not everyone can be geek nights.
Speaker 0: It's generally very.
Speaker 0: it's just an interesting blog to read.
Speaker 0: if you if you're interested in what's you know Where the web and social networking and things are taking us?
Speaker 0: No, and they posted one today by Dana Boyd called viewing American class divisions through Facebook and myspace.
Speaker 0: now I'm not gonna go over all the details in it because well you can just read the essay and if I try to Summarize it for you.
Speaker 0: You'll be like, well, what about this little bit?
Speaker 0: And what about that little bit?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, well the person wrote it.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna.
Speaker 1: well, I didn't read it But I'm gonna hazard a guess that the general line is low-class myspace high-class Facebook.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much what it is.
Speaker 0: What I like about this article and why I want people to read it is because first of all, they separate class not by money, but by Class.
Speaker 0: the way we talk about class, you know, like rim always says our class system Yep, I'm classes, but that has nothing to do with money, right?
Speaker 0: And there's this.
Speaker 0: this essay actually contains a really great explanation about how his friends making $14,000 a year in cafes are not the same class as the immigrant janitor in Oakland Even though they make the same amount of money.
Speaker 0: and it's like, you know class doesn't have to do with money.
Speaker 0: It has to do with your culture and your attitude and your lifestyle These other things that are up to you in a modern Western capitalism.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're talking about America here.
Speaker 0: This is the reason I don't want to go ever everything in the article because it's like every time you're gonna be like Oh, I'm gonna say another word to shut you up now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I got a bunch of but what about?
Speaker 1: but what about?
Speaker 0: yep But it goes on to point out how he's got.
Speaker 0: he separates like the hegemonic teens Right who are like they're like us, you know the college going, you know.
Speaker 0: Well off, you know, I'm gonna go to college and get a job and be awesome teens from the you know, I'm You know Like most of my friends in high school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much any.
Speaker 0: I forget what he calls those teens.
Speaker 1: God You know.
Speaker 1: I realize that it's not gonna be too long until my 10 year high school reunion comes up and they talk about how You know the the way that Facebook went along.
Speaker 0: where it started out is college only and then college guys could invite High-school people and then they opened it up and how that created a you know A dichotomy between who used Facebook and who use myspace
Speaker 1: definitely different from the or cut path
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also how the visual aesthetic of you know Facebook with its clean, you know shiny Usable interface and myspace with its.
Speaker 0: I don't think we're doing talk about myspace.
Speaker 1: My space is.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many of you are old enough to remember Back when you could have a geocities website with your one megabyte of space and if you didn't know HTML You could edit your web page with this horrible Java something based editor That basically made the early aesthetic of myspace all over your geocities.
Speaker 0: Yep, but anyway, it talks about how that sort of bling he actually uses the word bling a gaudy immature.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah bling.
Speaker 0: these teens are very aware of myspace and they often have a negative opinion about it.
Speaker 0: They see it as gaudy immature and so middle school They prefer the clean look of Facebook noting that is more mature and that myspace is just so lame.
Speaker 0: and that's basically what this our essay gets into and I agree with it over 90% and I think everyone should read it to.
Speaker 0: you know I guess better understand what we talk about when we say class as opposed to money class.
Speaker 1: So Google didn't really stand up to China so much but they've stood up to China more than say Yahoo quite a bit more.
Speaker 1: In fact, I generally dislike Yahoo because they tend to kowtow to every whim and demand of the Chinese government.
Speaker 1: But Google pretty much holds the line as hard as they can hold it while still being able to offer Google in China.
Speaker 1: However, there are other countries in the world countries that also have beasts with Google and I note that Google is generally Willing to just give them the finger or in fact to go one step further and actively threaten them.
Speaker 0: Well what it comes down to is, you know, it's simply a Machiavellian kind of thing.
Speaker 0: It's like Google needs China more than China needs Google.
Speaker 0: So Google bows down to China in exchange of mountains of money.
Speaker 1: But in this case Germany needs Google more than Google needs Germany.
Speaker 0: So when Germany tries to boss Google around it ain't happening.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like when a bunch of South American countries got mad at Google over the or cut Fiasco where they claim that there was pedophilia and child porn and drug selling.
Speaker 0: I wonder who put that there.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but they wanted Google to make do all these things that Google decided They weren't comfortable with.
Speaker 1: they said, you know what now come back with court orders and whatever and nothing came of it.
Speaker 1: But basically the German government is.
Speaker 1: they have a law.
Speaker 1: they haven't passed it apparently, but it's some sort of German internet Surveillance law that basically says that any data that goes over the internet or phone calls or anything like that Has to be saved for six months and anonymizing things like Tor are illegal.
Speaker 1: and it's basically this really 1984 watch what people do on the internet and keep records of it thing that I don't want to get into.
Speaker 1: that.
Speaker 1: That's not the news.
Speaker 1: I don't really want to talk about the ramifications of it or why.
Speaker 1: I don't care because I encrypt everything.
Speaker 1: but no the issue here is that Google offers Gmail and When they basically said if this law gets passed They're probably just going to give Germany the finger and shut down Gmail in Germany rather than comply with these outrageous demand.
Speaker 0: that really sucks.
Speaker 1: If you're a German Gmail user who doesn't want to change your email address Well, maybe if you're a German Gmail user You should be writing to whatever your body of government is which I'll admit.
Speaker 1: I don't actually know actually going on.
Speaker 1: But robot Hitler's are always popular.
Speaker 1: You gotta go with the robot Hitler.
Speaker 1: superd robot hit spur tomato is so last year, yeah No one's gonna get that.
Speaker 1: No, anyway, so, uh, I just find it interesting and I say I'm generally very proud of Google.
Speaker 1: I generally respect what they do.
Speaker 1: I generally still trust them despite the fact that they have a lot of power over me.
Speaker 1: now I mean look we use Google for our front row crew email.
Speaker 1: I use it for all of my searching and I mean all of it.
Speaker 1: in fact If I want to search a site like the only searches I do that are not Google are hired Bay.
Speaker 1: Well, no searches on individual sites No Even then if I want to search an individual site a lot of times particularly with the Gentoo forums I use the Google site search instead of using.
Speaker 1: well, it depends.
Speaker 0: it depends on the site, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if I'm on a site already I'll just try their little search box and then if I have problems I'll do the Google thing and I use the Google thing to search.
Speaker 0: fucking dig cuz goddamn the dig search is useless.
Speaker 0: God, there's actually a dig story today.
Speaker 0: That was like dig search.
Speaker 0: useless dig this so he can complain about it.
Speaker 1: I Don't think I've ever successfully found anything.
Speaker 0: I was looking for with the dig search I have but I generally have to go like many many pages in.
Speaker 1: it sucks Yeah, but I also realized that Google has the power They have is not terribly dangerous to people like me and I think I've said this before but I you know I realized what.
Speaker 1: does Google have a lot of information about me?
Speaker 1: what's the worst thing Google could do to me as a person?
Speaker 1: if they decided to be a hundred percent evil is Tell the truth.
Speaker 1: the worst they could do is post to the world a list of the things rim is searched for and the text of all rims emails.
Speaker 1: And while I like to protect those things as best I can I don't think that would particularly cause me any harm personally.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying that I don't people shouldn't fight for privacy.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying the privacy isn't important, but Google doesn't really have so much hanging over my head.
Speaker 0: No me either.
Speaker 0: I mean even if they fucked me all the way they can't take my money cuz.
Speaker 1: well Well see what Google could do because they can probably figure out your credit card numbers.
Speaker 0: I'll just get my money back.
Speaker 0: is this fraud?
Speaker 1: and if anyone used the same passwords or usernames or whatever for the Gmail that they also used for say all their credit cards and bank accounts and online banking and Google could easily figure out what your bank was and all that.
Speaker 1: if they were really evil they could just empty the bank accounts of Most of the people who use Google and then disappear.
Speaker 0: Yeah even if they did that though Uh, it wouldn't hurt me because I would just go to my bank and say hey Google fucked me and then they'd fix it.
Speaker 0: Maybe they do
Speaker 1: but even then I just a lot of people complain like oh Google has is gonna be the 1984 evil But I'm still seeing no signs of that and this just proves once again that Google While they're not really gonna take much of a loss by denying their business to the great and powerful economy of Germany Especially considering that the services they're denying are free anyway
Speaker 0: They make money off the ads
Speaker 1: yeah, but how much do they make off of Germany as opposed to I don't know anywhere else
Speaker 0: Probably less,
Speaker 1: but they're standing up for privacy here now granted They might have an ulterior motive of it would cost us money time and effort to save this data And we're gonna do this thing against Germany under the aura of fighting for privacy, but you know what?
Speaker 1: While the end doesn't justify the means if someone does something good for a bad reason.
Speaker 1: I think the good was still done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 0: Oh and one last thing Yeah, the the iPhone comes out on Fridays.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 0: Just don't buy one, but beware don't go near any Apple stores or anything.
Speaker 1: It's coming.
Speaker 1: It's come.
Speaker 0: You should buy one if you just have like money on your pocket on fire, and you you you just you're rich yourself.
Speaker 1: It's coming.
Speaker 1: things of the day.
Speaker 1: So there's a lot of interviews with Richard Dawkins all over YouTube and dig and they pop up.
Speaker 1: It seems like every couple weeks.
Speaker 1: There's a super dug-up story.
Speaker 1: check it out.
Speaker 0: Richard Dawkins was interviewed by so-and-so But the man wrote a book recently and he's got the PR machine and he keeps cranking the PR machine.
Speaker 0: thus he's interviewed pretty much by like thousands of radio stations and Thousands of TV stations all around the world and in all sorts of newspapers and magazines, and that's what he does now.
Speaker 1: I find the phenomenon interesting that people are Digging these stories up despite the fact that by and large if you watch any interview with Richard Dawkins.
Speaker 1: He says the exact same thing because he wrote his book.
Speaker 1: That's what he had to say and he just says that over and over again.
Speaker 1: I mean imagine if you no one has brought up a Credible argument against him and he generally just knocks people down when they try to get him.
Speaker 0: I mean imagine if you wrote a book and you have to interview with radio stations about it.
Speaker 0: She's basically what the happens is on some day, you know in the morning They put you in a room with a phone and it rings.
Speaker 0: you pick it up and there's some radio guy.
Speaker 0: You don't know and he asked you a few questions.
Speaker 1: Yes, the same questions that everyone has been asking you for the last year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you pick it up again.
Speaker 0: You is another radio guy you hang up you pick it up again.
Speaker 0: There's another radio guy They all ask you the same question.
Speaker 0: You give them all the same answers.
Speaker 0: So you just get into a groove of interviewing and every interview is the same thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though if anything the way I see it The reason people dig these things up is that dig is more and more becoming a hotbed of activist atheism.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's how it goes and I find it funny that a lot of people on dig complain about it like oh Why are these things getting dug up?
Speaker 1: This isn't blah blah blah, but that dig is the Regardless of how wise it is.
Speaker 1: the wisdom of the masses and the wisdom of the masses on the internet is generally very pro Atheism these days.
Speaker 1: but it seems like when people dig these stories up.
Speaker 1: I don't think they even watch the interviews I think they just see there was a new one and decide that all right I'm gonna dig this up because I like Richard Dawkins and it's not just with Dawkins with a lot of things.
Speaker 1: I see a lot of Stories that they're not a story.
Speaker 1: There's nothing new.
Speaker 1: There's nothing interesting.
Speaker 1: It's just some garbage blog article somewhere with a headline that says something that a bunch of people on dig agree with.
Speaker 1: So they all dig it because they agree with the headline and then they argue about it in the comments.
Speaker 1: But other than that, it's not useful.
Speaker 1: It's just a vote of confidence in this idea.
Speaker 0: And I noticed that's happening with Michael Moore's new movie.
Speaker 0: It's like there was one news the movie is on the Internet's before it's in the theater.
Speaker 0: That was the news.
Speaker 0: I've seen that like two more dig stories about it that didn't have any news to offer.
Speaker 0: It was basically just people Dugging it up like yeah, I like it.
Speaker 0: No burying it.
Speaker 0: No, I don't like it.
Speaker 0: What the hell.
Speaker 0: if it's not news, it should just be eliminated by.
Speaker 0: you know Fiat.
Speaker 0: It's not news gone.
Speaker 1: See the reason.
Speaker 1: that's it unless dig decides to change the way it works.
Speaker 1: Currently a lot of people view dig as nothing more than all right.
Speaker 1: I believe in X. I am going to dig up anything that also agrees with the things I believe in in order to spread these ideas and it's A bunch of competing ideas and it's less and less news.
Speaker 0: People always complain about dig and it's you know, how it's not perfectly democratic And I think it dig is too democratic and it shows you why such a super democratic system doesn't work.
Speaker 0: That's where I think.
Speaker 0: slash dot, you know is the counterexample where it's super editorial, but I think it's that's too editorial.
Speaker 1: You know, I gotta say Whenever I actually want tech news, I still go to slash dot because generally it hits slash dot I don't know.
Speaker 1: ten minutes after dig so I don't get the OMG, check out what's happening right now.
Speaker 1: I'm a little bit delayed here, but Usually they at least wait until there's some slight amount of verification and while there are occasional dupes on slash dot They're not dupes of nothing.
Speaker 1: They're at least a dupe of something.
Speaker 0: Yep But yeah, what's the thing of it?
Speaker 1: well my thing of the day is this interview with Richard Dawkins.
Speaker 0: It's the same as all the other ones.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I want one.
Speaker 1: I wanted to get all that off my chest.
Speaker 1: So I decide alright, this will be the last one kind of like Jack Thompson I don't talk about him anymore.
Speaker 1: I don't need to talk about Richard Dawkins anymore other than that.
Speaker 1: I Can't find any fault with any argument he made But I like this interview and I think I'll make it the thing of the day as the last time I'll bother talking about him Because it comes out with a new book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you probably be about biology.
Speaker 1: the interviewer goes after him.
Speaker 1: Well one you could see where he's going.
Speaker 1: the interviewer is trying to trap him into Saying something that'll be a soundbite or that look bad in the media or in some way make his interview stand out.
Speaker 1: So he goes on this really different tack and he faints to try to draw Richard Dawkins into this kind of trap he set.
Speaker 1: but the trap was really poorly set and Richard Dawkins is pretty smart and You can tell the guy loses when he does that really quick nodding near the end Little hint rims hint in arguing number 487. any time anyone does that they have already lost the argument and they're angry at you.
Speaker 0: Yep Guy wasn't probably going.
Speaker 0: girl is because he was interviewing someone on TV and you can't go girl.
Speaker 0: He has to keep the face unless you're Bill O'Reilly.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah They just cut people off when you're losing and say shut up pinhead.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, so we often tell stories about this.
Speaker 0: one convention we went to Called penguin con.
Speaker 0: thank you.
Speaker 1: con 2.0 penguin con 2.0 the best technology or Linux convention I've ever been to the only one you've ever been to.
Speaker 0: it's also awesome.
Speaker 1: from what I gather based on all the other events like That that was probably the best Linux convention period because I think the other ones tend to be more tech Conference like and not so not so much convention II yeah, not so much.
Speaker 0: hang out with Neil Gaiman I and the gaming and the Linux all wrapped up into one for the triple hurt, right?
Speaker 0: But one interesting thing that happened there is Steve Jackson brought.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you ever played with marble works It was this toy I had when I was a kid and I actually had two sets of it where you would take these plastic pieces and each piece had an entrance and an exit or multiple entrances multiple exits and There was a starting piece and an ending piece and there are also support pieces and you would basically attach all these pieces.
Speaker 0: you know beginning to end beginning to end in such a way that you put marbles in the top and they would go down and Do various things like you get there's even a jump you get the marbles to like jump across the room or spin a spinny Thing or go back and forth or go in a spiral
Speaker 1: Like there was the little trampolines you could put mounted somewhere at an angle and just launch marbles at it and up into something else.
Speaker 0: yep, there was all sorts of stuff like that and Basically he brought the more newer more advanced version of marble works.
Speaker 1: furthermore.
Speaker 1: He brought a lot of it.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is not.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's business related to marble works.
Speaker 0: I think it's a different company and a different product all together But it's generally the same idea that you put marbles in it They go and they do all this crazy stuff then they get to the bottom and there's actually an electronic Elevator that brings them back up I forget the name of the toy but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: and then the marbles go to the top and they do it again and it was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: and One night I think we caught we were bored and we decided we got a crazy idea and that hey would it be possible to make a Binary adder out of this machine?
Speaker 1: So we went over and the thing is he said he's basically just dumped all this stuff in the room and said Do what thou wilt and he was gonna come back at the end of the con and see what had been made of his thing pretty much 24/7.
Speaker 1: so we sat around myself and Scott our friend James and I think Alex and We took all these bits and we saw all the ones that weren't being used currently and we started trying to figure out how to make an adder with what we had.
Speaker 0: and I think the You know, we had some really good ideas.
Speaker 0: We were working on it But I think the conclusion we came to is that in order to make an adder We would need a new piece that wasn't in the set that would allow us to hold a marble Temporarily and then release it, you know based on something else
Speaker 1: and there was no piece in the entire thing short of heavily modifying them.
Speaker 1: That would do that.
Speaker 0: Yep So he pretty much you know gave up even after much thinking and we pretty much Pushed it to the limit and then we were done.
Speaker 0: Well this guy here in this website it's actually make magazine out of wood and marbles.
Speaker 0: he has made a Binary adding machine and this is pretty good to watch because number one it reminds me of PangoCon Yeah, and it shows you what you're trying to accomplish.
Speaker 0: Yeah Do if you don't know about binary math This will help you understand how computers do math.
Speaker 0: This is how the computer you were using adds numbers together.
Speaker 0: It does the same thing only instead of pieces of wood bouncing back and forth.
Speaker 0: It has transistors that Electricity back and forth.
Speaker 0: This is exactly how it works.
Speaker 0: This is how your computer does it.
Speaker 0: You can see it now on a big scale how your computer does maths.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you wanted you could do calculations with this thing straight up.
Speaker 1: You could make a bigger one You could make a nested one all sorts of fun things.
Speaker 0: Yes, if you have a little pocket calculator it is doing this Exactly doing this.
Speaker 0: the same thing that's going on here with transistors instead of wood and marbles.
Speaker 0: So if you don't understand binary math, this is a good video to watch.
Speaker 1: Actually when I was in middle school in science Olympiad in seventh grade I made a machine almost exactly like that with the help of an engineer to much other people that were working on this project with Us.
Speaker 1: but we basically made one just exactly the same with the same mechanism of the rocker and the marbles.
Speaker 1: We use pachinko balls that we happen to have.
Speaker 1: But what we did is we set it up with a pendulum clock and every time the pendulum swung every second It would release a marble from the pachinko machine at the top and send it into the adder and as a result We could keep track of time By saving the states in the adder and make events happen at specific times based on the order of the bits.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: This guy just has sort of like the input then the processing and then he pushes something in.
Speaker 0: the output falls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just it's really cool and check it out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So we haven't done this in a while.
Speaker 1: It's time to do it again.
Speaker 1: I think the Explain how computers work and somewhat layman semi non-technical terrorists is round.
Speaker 0: I think we're beyond how computers work.
Speaker 0: now We're into like general how technology internet type things work.
Speaker 1: No, it's still part of the how computers work series.
Speaker 0: I guess yeah, of course, but you know, we're we're beyond the physical PC now.
Speaker 1: Yep though I would say that if you don't know a lot about computers and you haven't already listened to our shows on IP You know layer 2 layer 3 how networks work on basic level and if you didn't listen to our shows about ports and how ports Work, you might have a little trouble with what we're about to talk about.
Speaker 1: I think we did.
Speaker 1: Hey, it doesn't matter I'm pretty sure we did.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But basically we're gonna talk about some firewalls.
Speaker 0: You've probably heard of a firewall.
Speaker 0: You might even use a firewall or think you're using a firewall and you hear a lot of you will talk about breaking through firewalls or firewalls getting in the way or All sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: and well a lot of people don't really know What a firewall does and how it works and how to use it and what it does and what it doesn't do.
Speaker 1: Yes, a firewall is not the magical barrier.
Speaker 1: You have to break through in order to hack the Gibson.
Speaker 1: That is true Basically in a very simple term a firewall.
Speaker 1: well first of all think about why it's named a firewall.
Speaker 1: in the real world a firewall is a structure in a building that Separates multiple compartments of the building from each other in such a way that if a fire starts in one area It is difficult if not impossible for the fire to spread beyond the firewall to the other area.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know some buildings like they have the fire doors and you have to leave them closed Because if you leave them closed and there's a fire the fire can't get past that door.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like in a lot of modern buildings when you have like the big double doors just in the middle of a hallway And you say why are there double doors in the middle of the hallway?
Speaker 0: But you don't notice really because they're held open by these magnets on the wall.
Speaker 0: But if you pull the fire alarm or the fire alarm goes off all the magnets holding the doors open turn off and all the doors Close.
Speaker 0: and now if there's a fire in that hallway It's not gonna get beyond those double doors because they're magic doors that block fire.
Speaker 1: Now firewalls in terms of computers are a little bit more elegant than that in that they're not a break they're not a solid barrier.
Speaker 1: instead very simply all they do is Filter the IP traffic or whatever traffic on the internet or network that's coming into your computer.
Speaker 1: they filter it based on a set of rules and they don't let things in that you didn't explicitly tell them to let in and They don't let things out that you didn't explicitly tell them to let out.
Speaker 0: Yep And by default if you just take a computer and you connect it to the internet and you get an IP you have an IP Address you you own one.
Speaker 0: Let's say right.
Speaker 0: Yep, and you're on the internet.
Speaker 0: any Traffic on the internet that's going around if it's meant for you your computer will take it in.
Speaker 0: You know, your actual computer will take that traffic in and consider it and do whatever it needs to do with it.
Speaker 0: It might not do anything with it But it'll.
Speaker 0: it'll take it in and do something.
Speaker 0: and if the traffic is not meant for your computer Well, you can.
Speaker 0: your network card ignores it.
Speaker 0: So you're never gonna see that and Anything your computer wants to send out of itself to elsewhere on the internet will go.
Speaker 0: it'll go out to the router and go Wherever it needs to go and then whatever they do on wherever that destination is They'll do.
Speaker 1: now in a perfect world This is fine because your computer has ports and ports are basically where the applications sit and listen for someone to connect to them.
Speaker 1: So if I'm running a VNC so I can get into my computer from somewhere else The VNC port on my computer is open and listening and whenever someone connects to it It says basically I'll connect and say hey port VNC.
Speaker 1: Are you there?
Speaker 1: And my computer says why yes I am and I say I am so-and-so and I would like to VNC.
Speaker 1: and the computer says I object you are okay.
Speaker 1: I'm letting you in.
Speaker 1: that's great.
Speaker 1: But uh, what if Scott?
Speaker 1: Decides that he wants to VNC into my computer and I don't want him to?
Speaker 1: well He knows that my computers online.
Speaker 1: so he connects to my computer and the computer says hi I'm port VNC.
Speaker 1: and Scott says I know.
Speaker 0: and Now while theoretically in a perfect world the VNC won't let him in because he can't authenticate properly I don't know the VNC password, you know, so I get this login screen to log into VNC But I don't know what the password is.
Speaker 1: But in a perfect world.
Speaker 1: the software on the computer itself is secure and just doesn't let Scott in anyway.
Speaker 1: So now Scott has learned that my computer is running VNC because it responded and said hi.
Speaker 1: I'm running VNC But beyond that there's nothing he can do.
Speaker 0: However, the world is not perfect.
Speaker 0: In fact VNC many versions of VNC like older versions especially have many flaws and I'm sure new flaws will be discovered is far from a perfect service and pretty much anything you run on Your computer even SSH, which is probably the most secure thing in the world is not a hundred percent perfect.
Speaker 1: Furthermore a lot of times your computer has ports open and you don't even know it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and Someone who knows what the business is Even if you have VNC and even if you have a password Someone can still connect to that and do something.
Speaker 0: they can get the VNC going on.
Speaker 0: Maybe they had.
Speaker 0: they can type something in as a username and password.
Speaker 0: That's all garbled that your will confuse VNC that because it has a bug in it and will override it and let them log in.
Speaker 0: Maybe they can you know Manually craft some network packets and send those packets to the VNC port thus confusing the DNA Yeah, the VNC service and giving them access.
Speaker 0: There's all sorts of things they can do Be able to try those things even in a perfect world by having your computer exposed like that.
Speaker 1: People can learn more about your computer than you might expect Because you can do something called port scanning.
Speaker 1: where my computer isn't behind a firewall It's just connected to the internet.
Speaker 1: Anyone can see it.
Speaker 1: someone could just start on port one and go all the way up to the top knocking on every single port saying hello anybody there and Recording whatever response they get.
Speaker 1: and certain operating systems respond to certain things in different ways.
Speaker 1: certain applications respond to things in different ways and You can learn a lot of information about a computer just by looking at what ports are open.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like oh look this computer has these ports open.
Speaker 0: Oh, and this is right.
Speaker 0: This is the response I get from that port.
Speaker 0: So I know what service that is.
Speaker 0: Hey Did you know that like a default?
Speaker 0: Installation of Red Hat 6 has the exact same ports open and the exact same services running on those ports.
Speaker 0: is this computer?
Speaker 0: Obviously, it's a Red Hat 6 machine.
Speaker 0: Well, let's go look up a Red Hat 6 exploit.
Speaker 0: Oh, look I owned you Yep.
Speaker 1: Now you might think because this is a common fallacy.
Speaker 1: if we ever do more shows on computer security We'll talk about this a lot But a lot of people think alright But what hacker out there is gonna go after me?
Speaker 1: and the real answer is no no hacker is going to target you unless you're A bank or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you're just a home user, it's not like rim.
Speaker 1: the hacker when he was in middle school or high school Thought I'm gonna go get Scott Rubin.
Speaker 1: this guy I've never met because I just happen to know his IP address and he's a fun.
Speaker 0: I mean theoretically if you're at Def Con or something then yes, so Or if you have a friend or you know an enemy who's someone you know in real life Maybe like a kid at school is like actually elite hacker like a really elite hacker and he wants to get you Then maybe you could get got.
Speaker 1: yeah But the odds were you know, you might think all right.
Speaker 1: Or if you go on IRC in some dangerous chat room and say something stupid But in general no one's gonna go after you and that's true.
Speaker 1: The problem is Computers are fast.
Speaker 1: It is not very difficult to scan one computer all the way through on the ports.
Speaker 1: It's not that difficult to scan every computer on the internet for all its ports.
Speaker 0: It's also not very difficult to say if you get one computer Then you turn it into a zombie that you can get that computer to scan a bunch of computers or just send out attacks.
Speaker 0: you know, you can just start attacking without even checking to see if that attack will work on all the computers nearby.
Speaker 0: and You know if you just shoot a machine gun left and right just gonna make a gun analogy You're gonna hit somebody the way.
Speaker 1: think of it this way.
Speaker 0: You got a lot of machine guns and a lot of zombies.
Speaker 0: You're gonna end up hitting a lot more people turning them into zombies too in the modern modern America or Finland Or whatever.
Speaker 1: you're walking down the street.
Speaker 1: You might think well everyone says I should wear a Kevlar vest because those stop bullets, but no one's gonna shoot me.
Speaker 1: I'm just some guy and that's true.
Speaker 1: No one wants to shoot you, but the internet is not modern Finland.
Speaker 0: It is the Wild West.
Speaker 1: internet is the Wild West and there are bullets and Indians and cowboys and hatchets Everywhere flying randomly in every direction.
Speaker 1: It's not even the Wild West.
Speaker 1: It's the Wild West if every street had a Maxim machine gun pointed in every direction firing 24/7.
Speaker 0: So you kind of want to put some armor on so you don't get chewed up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: It's not just security.
Speaker 1: firewalls also serve the purpose of keeping traffic out of your network to prevent it from slowing it down.
Speaker 1: I mean our network here gets hit in terms like someone will try to connect to the IP address We have on the outside via SSH Probably once a second 24/7.
Speaker 1: Mmm And if we let that into our router our router is gonna have to deny or deal with all those connections.
Speaker 1: If I let it into our network It's gonna go to our computers and mess with all of our.
Speaker 1: even if it doesn't break in even if no one hacks us It's still using our network capacity and causing trouble for us.
Speaker 0: Yeah we have to.
Speaker 0: all these packets get through into the network and they eventually get to a computer and then that computer has to deal with It.
Speaker 0: if we can somehow keep these packets outside of the network, you know Cuz there's only one hole one pipe that goes out onto the real interview.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one tube that goes from our network to the internet.
Speaker 0: if we can somehow keep all the packets We don't care about on the other end of that tube.
Speaker 0: Then our computers don't have to worry about them and our computers can only worry about the things I have to worry about and some other machine on the other end of the tube Can sort of keep all the bad bits out.
Speaker 1: now there are hardware and software firewalls and we're really talking about hardware firewalls But we'll talk about the difference at the end of all this.
Speaker 1: The way the firewall works on a fundamental level is extremely simple.
Speaker 1: The complexity is all in knowing what commands and numbers to put in and what rules to set.
Speaker 1: But basically a firewall is a very simple computer and it looks at the traffic coming in.
Speaker 1: It applies rules that you wrote to that traffic and then forwards it as you have specified.
Speaker 0: for example I have a firewall right the one end.
Speaker 0: one side is the internet on the other side is the network of computers.
Speaker 0: in this house I make one rule and one rule only.
Speaker 0: that rule could be don't allow any traffic on port 8,000.
Speaker 0: Okay, all this traffic is coming in from the internet, right?
Speaker 0: If it's for port 7999 it comes right through.
Speaker 0: if it's on port 8001 it comes right through.
Speaker 0: everything would be just the same as if I connected my computer directly to the internet.
Speaker 0: But now anything that wants to go on port 8,000 it doesn't get through the firewall Just doesn't do anything about those packets.
Speaker 0: It drops them off and ignores them and they don't go through to the other side and my computers don't even know they exist.
Speaker 1: Yep, so on a fundamental straight-up dumb firewall all you do is tell it either what ports do I want to allow in which directions or What ports do I not want to allow?
Speaker 1: you see there are two defaults and it's pretty logically obvious Why this is the case.
Speaker 1: you can either have a firewall that by default blocks everything and then open up the things you want to Open up or you can have a firewall that by default lets anything through and then you specifically block The things you don't want in and both I have their uses and are equally valid.
Speaker 1: But in general the former is what people use for security because the vast majority of the ports out there You're not serving anything worthwhile on them and you don't want anyone sniffing around
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm generally the setting that most people use because the default setting the most people use just to make you know the quick secure thing for a non-specific situation is Okay, don't let anything in.
Speaker 0: if someone just tries to come in unsolicited, you know.
Speaker 0: Just someone just comes up and knocks on the door.
Speaker 0: Just ignore them all the time No matter what port they're on.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter if someone on the inside of the network wants to ask for something on the internet Let it go out all the time.
Speaker 0: These are people on our network.
Speaker 0: We trust them.
Speaker 0: They can send anything out that we that they want to.
Speaker 1: now you might Go ahead because I think you're gonna jump ahead.
Speaker 0: Oh my good jump ahead.
Speaker 1: I think so I think you're gonna stay the concept that we hadn't brought up yet.
Speaker 0: Oh, it is a concept.
Speaker 0: We have brought up.
Speaker 0: Yes, I was moving on.
Speaker 0: Ah, so now let's say someone on the inside Connects to google.com on port 80.
Speaker 0: We're letting that through that's going out.
Speaker 1: Yep It's going out but like Scott said we're not letting anything come in.
Speaker 1: but we can go out but nothing can come in.
Speaker 0: and what?
Speaker 0: We do and we go out is all we're sending out is a message that says hey google Send me google.com the web page.
Speaker 1: so google sends it back, but we're not letting anyone in.
Speaker 0: so it doesn't get in.
Speaker 0: And now I can't visit google.com.
Speaker 0: What the hell's the use of that?
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is dumb firewalls or Stateless firewalls are like that and you have to specifically set up exactly what you want going in and what you want going out.
Speaker 1: Those are generally used in enterprise situations and corporate situations and very tightly controlled situations where in this case you could use a rule where you can.
Speaker 1: you can figure out what port Google would be coming back on and Let all those ports in Automatically by default but not let in the low numbered ports.
Speaker 1: because remember when we did the port show We talked about how there's certain services that run on low ports.
Speaker 1: But the really high numbered ports are random or ephemeral and they're only used for these temporary connections to things like Google Yep.
Speaker 1: but even then that's still a kind of complicated firewall rule and you got to deal with it and you
Speaker 0: never know a Service could be running on a high-numbered port Screwed
Speaker 1: a lot of virus bought whatever things will run their evil services on the high up ports because they know that a lot of Dumb firewalls.
Speaker 1: Well, let's stuff in on those ports.
Speaker 1: Thus the concept Scott was gonna get to is that Intelligent firewalls new firewalls modern firewalls not piece-of-shit firewalls.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah granted though I have oftentimes set up firewalls that were not stateful on purpose.
Speaker 0: Yes, but they are not useful for normal people.
Speaker 0: They're useful for mostly computers that not desktop computers that people are sitting at.
Speaker 0: they're useful for other sorts of computers and you know Strange environments and data centers and all that.
Speaker 1: The big use is in networks like between two large networks where you know exactly what's going to be going around.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the other thing is that Any you know firewall that is the new kind can do everything.
Speaker 0: the old kind can yeah Yeah, so, you know Even if you're using it in the old style the busted style You can still use a new firewall that is capable of doing awesome new things.
Speaker 1: now a stateful firewall as opposed to a stateless firewall Very simply remembers what's going on so you can tell it.
Speaker 1: All right, let anything go out no matter what and Let anything that is associated with a pre-existing outgoing connection come back in.
Speaker 0: So if I connect to google.com That's a pre-existing outgoing connection and when the stuff comes back from google.com for me The firewall knows that that goes along with the stuff that I sent out already and it lets that in but it doesn't let anything Else in.
Speaker 0: yep So it's only lets things in that are solicited.
Speaker 0: if I ask for something to be brought in from the inside It lets it in.
Speaker 0: if it's not asked for it doesn't get it.
Speaker 1: now you might wonder well How does the firewall know what was solicited and not?
Speaker 0: it's really smart.
Speaker 1: Well, actually the answer is there's a couple different ways to do that.
Speaker 1: I think that's a little too technical for the level we want to go for today, but suffice to say it's really smart.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll do a show in the future on smarter than you.
Speaker 1: It's actually still kind of dumb.
Speaker 1: But and there a lot of the ways to do it can be fooled and the ways that are more difficult to fool Are also more difficult to implement and expensive but not really have to buy a thing from Cisco for a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean basically we could go into more technical detail But that's all you need to know.
Speaker 1: That's how a firewall works.
Speaker 1: That's all it does.
Speaker 1: It's very simple.
Speaker 1: now That was a hardware firewall a box like a Cisco picks or something.
Speaker 0: We're talking about a box with lights on it in two holes and a wire goes in one hole and another wire goes in the Other hole.
Speaker 1: now a lot of costs like hundreds of dollars like to run software firewalls Which basically do the same thing that a hardware firewall does but they run on your computer as?
Speaker 1: A program as a service and they co-opt all your ports.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they block things on their own.
Speaker 0: We're talking about here is zone alarm.
Speaker 1: Cygate Windows Has it built in?
Speaker 0: Yep Vista has it built in?
Speaker 0: I think actually Mac OS has something built in sort of like that.
Speaker 1: These are generally fairly effective and they're better than nothing Because you can at least know what ports are open or set it to by default block ports You're probably not going to use.
Speaker 0: yeah, and a lot of them will tell you like hey Someone's trying to connect on this port.
Speaker 0: or hey, you're trying to use this port.
Speaker 0: Are you sure you want to use this port and that way?
Speaker 0: Let's say a virus gets on your computer from an email attachment and it tries to send things and zombie bites out on the internet.
Speaker 0: It'll the firewall will tell you Hey, this thing is sending zombie bites out and then it sort of keeps you aware of what your computer's do.
Speaker 0: That's
Speaker 1: a really overlooked important part of firewalls And in fact that was one of the primary reasons we said of the firewalls We set up back at IBM not so much to keep things out But to keep things in because we had a lab where we did a lot of our development work and we wanted a firewall To monitor and block things coming out of our network into the real IBM network To make sure that we didn't do anything bad or break anything out there or to see what was going on on our end.
Speaker 1: So if you've got a computer that might be compromised you can usually see that if the firewall suddenly is blocking all these strange Request from your computer to web servers or IRC things that you've never heard of.
Speaker 1: The problem with software firewalls is that they run on your computer and thus they can be compromised Just as easily as anything else on your computer.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean if someone has a worm that can take over Windows XP, you know Your fire what your software firewall might block that worm, but it doesn't mean your software firewall doesn't have its own Vulnerability and someone could take over your software firewall and then use the Windows XP worm.
Speaker 0: and that's that It's not network level security.
Speaker 0: It's still on the same level of security as Your actual computer.
Speaker 0: your network card still has to deal with all this stuff.
Speaker 0: your processors still has to deal with all this stuff.
Speaker 0: It takes up system resources and you're not getting all the advantages of having a real hardware firewall.
Speaker 1: However, we're not saying that you shouldn't use these things because these are still important valuable tools and keeping your computer secure Especially especially and especially if you go around to using open wireless access point Yes, or LAN parties or college campuses.
Speaker 0: Yep, but if you're in your house Right, and we told you before if you're in your house You should have a router even if you only have one computer a NAT router.
Speaker 0: if you have a net router You probably don't need a software firewall.
Speaker 1: You see the net kind of by default.
Speaker 1: We talked about how networks.
Speaker 1: I suggest if you don't know what that is that you listen to a whole episode on this.
Speaker 1: We did that you listen to our show on net network address translation.
Speaker 1: But basically if you have one of those links is whatever routers Running the net you get almost all the benefits of a firewall because by default stuff just can't connect to you from the outside Unsolicited
Speaker 0: and if you connect out and you ask for something, it'll get back in.
Speaker 0: It's like having a you know, the default stateful firewall But it's net.
Speaker 1: so the simple answer for you home users is have a net router and run a software firewall.
Speaker 1: and While you might think like oh, but shouldn't have a hardware firewall?
Speaker 1: Hardware firewalls are mostly only used by businesses corporations or people who are really really really care about security.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a hardware firewall right that if you bought a hardware firewall Let's say you've got one for free from Cisco, you know, like a pick.
Speaker 1: Cisco picks.
Speaker 1: They're pretty hot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like the default firewall that's like the standard one, you know If you got one of those you'd probably just configure it to do the same thing.
Speaker 0: You're not router does?
Speaker 1: yeah?
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah The only time you don't want to use the net is if you're serving a lot of things.
Speaker 1: You've got a really extensive network or you've got like permanent connections and VPN setup and all these things that you're not going to be Doing.
Speaker 0: yeah, plus also for the price of one of those things you could just get a computer.
Speaker 0: Yes You know how many links is this?
Speaker 0: Could you get?
Speaker 0: you get tons of links?
Speaker 1: This is here's where we'll end it.
Speaker 1: If you really want to have a hardware firewall remember in the beginning Are we said that a firewall is basically just a specialized computer?
Speaker 1: You could get an old computer and there's actually a bunch of them I think in the forum or the comments or whatever will probably list a few good ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are Linux live CDs and Linux distributions and also just Linux software.
Speaker 1: Yep, where Windows software you can take an old computer that you're not using anymore run the software on it and effectively use that as A hardware firewall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you basically and a router and a VPN and all those other things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: a firewall is just a computer.
Speaker 0: a router is just a computer, right?
Speaker 0: If you just take a computer and you put two network cards in it or more network cards one of them is the out network card and one's the in network card and one side of this computer is the internet and the other side of the computer is your network, right and you install some software on the computer to make it firewall and Tada you now have a hardware firewall.
Speaker 0: It's it's a computer instead of just.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 1: this gives me an idea.
Speaker 1: We should do a show not now not anytime real soon.
Speaker 1: But what do you guys think?
Speaker 1: what if we did a show where we picked what like one of the good Linux like?
Speaker 1: Network service firewall security, whatever solutions and just did a show of all the cool things you can do with it Just in your home.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like all the things you could set up with it how to set it up securely how to make the VPN thing is a lot.
Speaker 0: Actually set up a lot of those things is kind of complicated to edit a lot of config files And it's it's not really an easy thing to do.
Speaker 1: It depends on which one to use.
Speaker 1: I haven't actually used any of the Modern ones.
Speaker 0: it seems like even the ones that have the nice web GUI interfaces on them to just you know with the easy setup Basically still require you to understand, you know networking and mess networks and subnet masks and gateways and all that You know.
Speaker 1: if you listen to geek nights, you should be learning these things from us bit by bit.
Speaker 0: You should be but you know people got it.
Speaker 0: You actually have to understand a lot of stuff to actually configure one of these things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even if it has the simple GUI But at the same time we always get interesting feedback.
Speaker 1: how it seems like a lot of you like these episodes where we just kind Of explain how things work, but a lot of you also want the much more technical episodes.
Speaker 1: But that alienates the first half of you, but the latter it.
Speaker 1: so yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: How's the level of tech?
Speaker 1: What do you guys want?
Speaker 1: That's what I'm asking.
Speaker 1: Yep And on that note, it's warm today warm yesterday Even warmer today, so I'm gonna turn the air conditioner back on.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.