Speaker 1: It's Wednesday April 25th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm Rin and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we give you our first impressions of four new anime.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So for the past week, I've been taking the train to work as I've been saying a lot And I saw you take the car at least once.
Speaker 0: I took the car home once on Monday because I ended up working late in the Bronx where I couldn't take a train home from aha.
Speaker 0: But for every other trip, I've been taking the train and it's really great except today I go and I'm on my way home and I get to the train station sure enough.
Speaker 0: It's raining.
Speaker 1: Yeah this morning I was pretty much torn between because when it's warm out I have this problem where I don't want to take a coat if I Don't have to.
Speaker 1: because if I take a coat and I don't have to know I got to carry it and it sucks.
Speaker 1: So I'll always check the weather I'll reach my hand out the window or something and decide if I'll take a coat or not.
Speaker 1: and the only coat I really have That's appropriate is my leather jacket.
Speaker 1: The problem with the leather jacket is you take it and if it rains now You're in trouble because you gotta like not get it too wet or that's no good.
Speaker 1: So I decided not to take it today and it rained.
Speaker 1: the worst possible Combination.
Speaker 1: it just sucked all around.
Speaker 0: see the thing is taking the truck taking my bike home in the rain.
Speaker 0: It's no big deal because it's not like.
Speaker 0: I wear my business clothes.
Speaker 0: I change on the train So everyone else is wearing.
Speaker 0: they're really stuffy expensive Uncomfortable dress clothes for whatever business they had in the city and I'm there in shorts and a t-shirt.
Speaker 1: just chillin I wear shorts and t-shirt to work.
Speaker 1: So it's all good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't get away with that.
Speaker 0: In fact, I often have to wear a tie.
Speaker 1: Haha, I've never.
Speaker 1: I will never take a job where I ever have to wear a tie Unless I'm working for myself and I decide to wear a tie to impress some other business guy I want to make a deal with.
Speaker 0: so I don't mind riding home in the rain.
Speaker 0: Like I said, I ride my bike in the rain all the time.
Speaker 0: This is no different But the looks I got from people as I got on my bike and started riding away People just couldn't seem to grasp the fact that I wasn't breaking out or taking a cab or something.
Speaker 1: Well at the same time I gotta say it was a little bit cold When I got off the train and it was raining, but that was probably because I'm wearing shorts and a t-shirt.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I was also in shorts and a t-shirt and I was biking.
Speaker 0: wasn't that cold?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it wasn't that cold, but it was a little cold and I had to run to my car.
Speaker 0: I only had a bike a couple miles.
Speaker 0: if I'd had to bike like five or six miles, then it would have been too cold.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well this weird thing is now that I take my bike every day.
Speaker 0: I've noticed that there are three other bikes and they're in good condition and they've been locked to the train station fence in The exact same positions unmoved for the entire week.
Speaker 0: so far They have not been touched in any way by a human.
Speaker 1: Maybe people went to the city for a week.
Speaker 1: Maybe people like leave those there.
Speaker 1: It's like when they come back.
Speaker 1: They you know get him.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's a terrible idea.
Speaker 0: bikes rust immediately if you leave them out like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But I do see quite a few people who bike to the train station at least maybe like ten people or so.
Speaker 1: So, you know, you're not alone.
Speaker 0: No, I was alone today though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I did see people taking the cab.
Speaker 1: Yep, people take the cab every day.
Speaker 1: I'm wondering what like People cab.
Speaker 0: every day a lot of people take the cab to my job.
Speaker 0: Every morning a bunch of cabs pull up and drop people off.
Speaker 0: really I really don't get it because a cab costs so much more money than any other means of transportation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean per mile.
Speaker 1: a cab is more expensive than an airplane.
Speaker 1: It's more expensive than a train.
Speaker 0: even worse It's in Yonkers.
Speaker 0: So it's not like it's a yellow cab.
Speaker 0: It's some car service.
Speaker 1: Oh god Yeah, car service is the most expensive way to get anywhere.
Speaker 1: running a car service is awesome because you get lots of money.
Speaker 1: Because it does think about how much it cost me to drive.
Speaker 1: to say Otakon right it cost me what two tanks of gas at the most of 40 bucks Even add in my car payment.
Speaker 0: and whatever two tanks of gas for 40 bucks.
Speaker 0: Where are you shopping?
Speaker 1: 20 bucks for a tank of gas?
Speaker 0: It's not 20 bucks for a tank of gas.
Speaker 0: How many gallons does your car hold Scott?
Speaker 1: It says 15, but usually it takes like 11.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, so you're not using all of it for one.
Speaker 0: All right, multiply 11 by the current price of gas, which is currently 304 I still 60 bucks doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I haven't bought gas in weeks because I've been riding the train.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what we used to go a guy take a gas still wasn't 20 bucks and not even close.
Speaker 0: anyway You make.
Speaker 1: it is A cab right for the same trip would be hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of dollars Maybe even a thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: see it's just like with Kramer and the Michigan bottle scam.
Speaker 0: Your margins are all messed up now because you're using the wrong numbers.
Speaker 1: My numbers don't have to be that exact because the difference is so enormous.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Did you read about those crazy people who took a cab like all the way out to like?
Speaker 1: Arizona or something?
Speaker 1: because the airline wouldn't let him take their pets or something.
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 0: what all it was was that they're too old people and they're moving and they didn't want to drive themselves and They didn't want to go on the airline because they don't trust the airline to not kill their cats Which isn't that much of an unfounded fear?
Speaker 0: airlines tend to kill pets more often than they should.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you could just like pay you could UPS the pets.
Speaker 0: No, you can't.
Speaker 0: no no There are very few services that transport pets specifically and they cost a lot more than higher in that cab.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's an entrepreneurial idea.
Speaker 0: It is indeed.
Speaker 1: Let's open up a little pet transportation.
Speaker 0: So now if we were clever Instead of actually transporting the pet we do what people did with that mail back in the day at the a similar pet get a Similar bed.
Speaker 0: So you just have a stock at all the major cities of every genet generic kind of puppy and you only take puppies.
Speaker 1: And Yeah, and you just mail the tags to the other side.
Speaker 0: you put the tags on a similar But forget that why you mail in the tags you have a tag fad.
Speaker 1: Ooh You just make the test copy the tags on the other end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what if they have some sort of like unique handmade collar or something like that?
Speaker 0: Uh, we don't accept collars.
Speaker 0: It's dangerous because we take such good care of the puppies.
Speaker 0: We don't want them to have a collar on.
Speaker 0: It's too perfect.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay anyway, so in the news the Naruto movie.
Speaker 1: well I don't know much about Naruto so I can't tell you anything about this movie.
Speaker 0: Well, I know I know enough about Naruto.
Speaker 0: It is about ninjas and they fight and fights last between one and one thousand episodes.
Speaker 1: I knew that yes But this movie is.
Speaker 0: the movie is about these ninjas engaged in some sort of fight.
Speaker 0: It lasts one movie.
Speaker 1: I can guarantee that the movie will contain the character Naruto.
Speaker 1: at least There will be at least one other character.
Speaker 1: there will be fighting and Ninjas throwing those pointy things with spirally thing headbands and all the stuff that Naruto is known for as long as Kakashi's in the movie.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, there's no reason to watch.
Speaker 1: I know anyway this movie Naruto the movie ninja clash in the land of snow.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guarantee there'll be snow in this movie.
Speaker 1: It's actually going to be in theaters in the US.
Speaker 0: not only that that's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: I mean, we're gonna go see paprika in the theater.
Speaker 0: It's not like anime is not in the theater often.
Speaker 1: Yep Pretty much all the big anime movies anything bigger than a drop in the bucket ends up at at least one theater in the US.
Speaker 1: But this Naruto movie which I know nothing about other than what we've already said is going to be on 160 screens in North America.
Speaker 0: That's not every theater by far.
Speaker 0: no, it's not a small release but not too bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually something like paprika is like, all right It's four screens in New York ten in Texas five in California one in Seattle There's that one in Philly one in Philly one in Connecticut and then if you're lucky one Nowhere near Florida.
Speaker 1: animal doesn't get dick.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you'll usually get like 20 screens.
Speaker 1: 30 screens I mean 50 screens would be a big deal, but this one's gonna have a hundred and sixty screen.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much every major city and then some.
Speaker 1: so no matter where you live in the country.
Speaker 1: I mean on average if there's 50 states including Hawaii and Alaska 160 screens it's gonna be in at least three places in your state or at least somewhere within driving distance.
Speaker 0: I would however wager that some states due to Socio-economic factors may have more of an audience for foreign Japanese cartoons than certain other states.
Speaker 1: Yes, I can imagine that the five screens that I'm allocating to Kansas are actually in California But I don't think Utah is gonna be so rocking it there.
Speaker 1: No, Nevada might have some though, and that's pretty close.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Hawaii definitely will.
Speaker 1: oh, I will have some Alaska.
Speaker 0: I don't even know if they get movies up there.
Speaker 0: That's like the.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about a projector at the snow.
Speaker 1: They don't have screens Yeah, but yeah It's pretty big news that an anime movies actually gonna get a better than an incredibly small release in American theaters.
Speaker 0: well the thing is Naruto as a film.
Speaker 0: I'll bet they would treat it more like a typical kids cartoon film movie than they would any other kind of anime because it's definitely not geared at the Relatively small demographic of people our age who like shiro tasm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is definitely marketed at 12 to 12 and a half year old kids.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling it's gonna get treated like the later Pokemon movies got treated.
Speaker 1: You know cuz like I remember the original Pokemon movies like theaters everywhere And I think the later ones were still in theaters, but not theaters everywhere.
Speaker 1: You know I've never seen a Pokemon movie me either, but I heard that like the early ones are kind of okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I they were watching when they said you can't hold ten Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to watch the first movie.
Speaker 0: the plots kind of cool, but then again This is the time for Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I mean I'd never played a Pokemon season rabbit season Pokemon see I'd never played a Pokemon game.
Speaker 0: I'd never.
Speaker 0: the only Pokemon I knew was the good manga the bad manga and the anime.
Speaker 1: as far as I'm concerned I've watched the anime, and I've played bad video games And I looked at the bad manga once and the only Pokemon I care about is the main line of video games and the good manga you mean the one with red and yellow.
Speaker 1: Yes, the games that are Pokemon color or Pokemon gemstone Those are the ones that are worth playing.
Speaker 1: everything else.
Speaker 1: I couldn't give a shit except Pokemon snap which is okay, but It's only worth playing once and Pokemon puzzle league which is actually paneled upon.
Speaker 1: So there's no reason to play Pokemon puzzle league when you can just play paneled upon.
Speaker 1: So yeah Naruto in the theaters.
Speaker 1: if you like Naruto the winner is you if you subscribe to Shonen joke winner being a relative Term.
Speaker 1: yes, if you subscribe to Shonen jump you can get your tickets on April 27th.
Speaker 1: general ticket sales would begin April 30th and The first showings will be in New York, LA Boston, San Francisco, Philadelphia, Atlanta and other major cities on the 30th.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's gotta be harsh.
Speaker 1: if you live in another major city, and you don't it's not billing And other Unnamed cities, so let me click on the little link here, and I'll see what cities there.
Speaker 1: I don't think you need to read them all all right go to like vis calm And you'll find out what you know.
Speaker 1: theaters is it and real?
Speaker 0: just to warn you only one news tonight Because we've got a lot of anime to talk about and we figure it's new anime season.
Speaker 0: give or take.
Speaker 0: We've got a lot of shows to cover in relatively short time before they become irrelevant.
Speaker 1: Yep, we basically watched a whole bunch of new shows at least the first episode
Speaker 0: and a couple of old shows and
Speaker 1: a couple shows that we watched the number one episodes of a bunch of shows that are brand new and we're gonna let you know whether we Think they're worth watching based on the first episode alone.
Speaker 0: things of the day.
Speaker 0: Scott had something old so I had something old - I brought this up mostly because I remember seeing this exact Advertisement on Television when I was young.
Speaker 1: I don't remember it at all.
Speaker 0: not only that but back then I don't know if this still happens, but a lot of children's shows would have Messages like that at the end of them.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I think there was some sort of like law.
Speaker 1: actually Like you know this laws like you can't advertise certain like the toy for the show during About the but you know by the way, you know the more you know or anything like that.
Speaker 0: I was talking very specifically about sexual harassment.
Speaker 0: Okay, I there were several shows that had hey kids if somebody touches you in a bad place tell someone.
Speaker 1: I Don't remember ever seeing any of them.
Speaker 1: But then again, I don't remember any of those at all whether they were about sexual harassment or something else.
Speaker 0: see I used to watch He-man and I did used to watch he-man, and I barely remember it.
Speaker 0: yeah I remembered very well, and I remember now that I'm older wiser smarter stronger better.
Speaker 0: I Recognize that he-man is perhaps one of the worst shows ever made.
Speaker 1: he-man is so bad.
Speaker 1: I was so disappointed that when I finally had the Internet's and I thought hey he-man That's a show.
Speaker 1: I know I liked when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I had a bunch of the toys.
Speaker 1: I know I watched it, and I know I liked it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go and get it and watch it and see you know cuz I don't remember it so well I'm gonna see what it's like and it was terrible good.
Speaker 1: God was it bad.
Speaker 1: It's so bad and I cats and transformers very watchable Thundercats the most so actually Voltron the most so but he-man unwatchable on Watchable.
Speaker 1: so I couldn't think of a thing of the day really.
Speaker 0: so how we never have that problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah I'm just as guilty.
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 1: So I started thinking of things that had to do with anime or comics from the way back.
Speaker 1: I try set my mind into the past and I actually dug something up.
Speaker 1: I remembered a long time ago like perhaps 2099 times there was a fun anime plot generator on the Internet's.
Speaker 1: and well I searched for anime plot generator, and I found it.
Speaker 1: so you ready to hear some anime plots.
Speaker 0: I'm ready all right.
Speaker 1: here We go.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make a random anime plot.
Speaker 1: in Modern-day Japan a team of young psychic cyborg gun loving cops battle gang of evil Psychics androids criminals and destroy the city in the heat of combat sounds a lot like tank police.
Speaker 1: Yep, in Chicago a young brooding hero travels on an eternal quest acquiring one or two loyal companions While seeking wealth and fortune and does battle with evil demon psychic overlord and his lieutenants and Triumphing moves on to the next installment.
Speaker 0: that sounds a lot better than some of the anime we watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you're looking to have some laughs, maybe make a new anime.
Speaker 1: May make a webcomic.
Speaker 1: who knows fanfiction?
Speaker 1: Go to the random anime plot generator, and it'll save you a lot of time and effort.
Speaker 1: so today like we said We are going to not review, but sort of give first impressions of Four new anime out the season.
Speaker 1: actually one of them I think is from last season, but it's pretty damn recent.
Speaker 1: so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: yep And we're gonna do a bunch more shows like this in the next several weeks because we've watched a lot of new anime.
Speaker 1: Without further ado let's get on with this business.
Speaker 1: We why?
Speaker 1: oh well first of all we watched one episode of each of these and we're going to spoil Probably those first episodes, so if you want to be surprised by something in the first episode Yeah, you probably don't want to listen.
Speaker 0: see the thing is the only spoiler a first episode can ever have really is oh The show is not about what you thought it was about and that's really the only thing that could be spoiled in a one episode.
Speaker 0: Shot of a real full-on show.
Speaker 1: yeah well technically you know there are those shows where on a pond the second viewing there are things In the first episode that spoil the whole show.
Speaker 1: But no one who hasn't seen the end could possibly see those things in the first episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like you could watch the opener to Evangelion in slow motion to watch every frame and a lot would be spoiled for you.
Speaker 1: Or you could watch the first episode of antenna and the whole show could be spoiled for you But only if the show's already been spoiled for you if we've already seen the whole show
Speaker 0: otherwise or you're some kind of psychotic Genius
Speaker 1: thing if you're so psychic powers or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's no way you're gonna figure out the end of a tenor from the first episode.
Speaker 1: But if you've seen the last episode then you will realize that it is possible, but not possible anyway.
Speaker 0: So let's jump right in.
Speaker 0: yeah the first show we watched El Cazador de la Bruja What does that translate to?
Speaker 0: it looks like it translates to the witch hunter?
Speaker 0: Oh, okay, which now that I've seen the first episode makes a little bit of sense.
Speaker 1: It does because the first episode does contain a witch and some bounty hunting action.
Speaker 0: now Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: the show starts out Awesome music that reminds me of other shows and the animation is really really pretty.
Speaker 0: the opener is really pretty.
Speaker 0: the show is really pretty.
Speaker 0: Everything about this show is incredibly cool except the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the whole time pretty much five minutes into it.
Speaker 0: You're gonna sit there and you're gonna think this is noir.
Speaker 0: Someone just made noir with a different skin.
Speaker 0: It's the exact same goddamn show except the colors are bright.
Speaker 0: Except unlike noir Nobody gets hung by a necktie in a stairwell.
Speaker 1: Yeah The violence is a lot more cartoon violence.
Speaker 1: the colors are brighter the characters are more stereotypical anime characters.
Speaker 1: It's got a sort of.
Speaker 1: it's weird the setting because the setting is obviously the present day with present-day technology Like there's even scenes of people sitting in cubicles in an office doing work, but it's also Western.
Speaker 1: So I think it's like modern-day Mexico and some reason Japanese people think that all of Mexico is like Western town like you know from the 1800s.
Speaker 0: It's kind of weird, but the music was really good.
Speaker 0: However, the music doesn't fit the show at all.
Speaker 0: I mean at least noir Nominally until you see enough of noir to realize that there's actually nothing underneath that veneer.
Speaker 0: The music's really good But it sounded exactly like the music from noir and I'm thinking to myself while I'm watching all right did they just rip off or They're the same people involved?
Speaker 0: So now I finally look it up and sure enough the music for this show is done by Yuki Kajiura Who you might remember from noir dot hack all that Yep The person who makes the really good music exact same music and it's she's not.
Speaker 0: it's not just the person who makes the good music It's the person who makes the good music for the really crap anime.
Speaker 1: See the thing I don't understand right?
Speaker 1: is I really like this music?
Speaker 1: right that this person makes Yuki Kajiura?
Speaker 1: But she always makes the music for these kind of good not really so good anime And you can always tell her music right away Whereas Yoko Kano she also makes the really good music for the anime, but the anime she makes them for tend to be better.
Speaker 1: and Also, you can't always tell Yoko Kano music right away because she does all different kinds of music and this person seems to do the same Kind of music all the time.
Speaker 1: You can just tell it like oh, that's that person.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: So the worst thing though is just that.
Speaker 0: I mean there was similar music that I don't think was done by her in Gundam seed and it was used sparingly in certain scenes where important things were going on and it added a lot.
Speaker 0: It made those scenes amazing in this show.
Speaker 0: They have the same level like oh, this is an amazing scene.
Speaker 0: The music is saying watch me.
Speaker 0: I'm amazing.
Speaker 0: But what's going on on the screen is Even worse than that noir kind of a girl running around shooting a bunch of people who for some reason never scream or bleed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just it'll be like this.
Speaker 1: serious music like this is like an epic happening right here And this cartoon violence going on or like, you know, just kind of like a silly, you know slightly interesting But not too serious action scene of like haha.
Speaker 1: I kick you and I shoot the gun out of your hand and I smile.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of either shooting the guns out of people's hands or if someone shot somewhere where they would die There's no blood.
Speaker 0: They just fall over and disappear from the show forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the worst part is the plot of the show is as far as I can see Exactly the same as noir.
Speaker 0: There's two female lead characters one of whom is older competent and cool and All-hit has a gun.
Speaker 0: The other one is young doesn't understand The world has something weird about her yet is magically super competent when she needs to be.
Speaker 1: It sounds like the noir guy.
Speaker 1: Well sure again.
Speaker 1: Sure enough.
Speaker 0: This is directed by none other than Koichi Mashimo You may remember from such wonderful wonderful shows as dot hack and noir.
Speaker 1: So if you're a fan of the dot hack noir legacy the kill yourself.
Speaker 1: This is the next show for you by the same team.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you watched all 26 episodes of noir right up to the end where there's nuns with guns running around and you still liked it And you thought damn if only someone made another show that was exactly like this only in a Western modern Setting with brighter colors.
Speaker 0: See that's the other thing that the way a lot of the shots were put together in this Mexico which again as far as they're concerned Mexico is just the Wild West.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was so much like the first episode of cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was painful and Like a scene of guys in a bar.
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 1: you know, we're there old men talking.
Speaker 1: There's a scene of people sitting in a bar Then they shooting and the main of someone's sitting down with like a Native American fortune teller of some sort.
Speaker 0: and the worst part is You walk in and we're all watching it together and I'm like you got any Bloody Mary's and everyone nobody I yeah They always order Bloody Mary can't get any.
Speaker 0: there's no tomato juice.
Speaker 0: All right, you don't just say bloody eye.
Speaker 0: If you want a drug, you don't just walk around the street going.
Speaker 0: Hey got weed.
Speaker 0: Hey, what about some weed?
Speaker 1: But don't drive with a mad woman.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go out on a limb and say that this is not going to be a good show.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be noir part two.
Speaker 1: I think this will be a perfectly average anime in all respects and I will not spend my time watching it Anymore than I already have.
Speaker 0: there's even the semi mystical plot that you they don't tell you much about But no or had the same thing.
Speaker 0: where there was that some sort of prophecy some sort of magic.
Speaker 0: Maybe we're not sure what's going on, but there's nuns at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like there are things that happened before the first episode that involved the younger girl Like, you know, why is she beat?
Speaker 1: Why does she have a bounty on her head?
Speaker 1: You know, did she actually kill someone or did she not kill someone?
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 1: What's this mysterious thing?
Speaker 1: how come she can jump over that very tall fence and the main character girl can't you know, and That's it.
Speaker 1: then for some reason the main character girl decides to stop bounty hunting this little girl and to protect her from the bounty hunters instead as Is painfully obvious is going to happen.
Speaker 0: Oh, don't forget the mild lesbian overtones.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, and the scantily clad main character?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the main character basically wears a poncho and not much else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she's got like the short shorts And those aren't shorts.
Speaker 0: That's basically a tight jean loincloth And she wears a gun.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: in fact her belt covers more of her skin than her pants do and it's like even the poncho barely covers the legs.
Speaker 1: See she's always showing off the leg and then when the poncho usually opens up during the fight scenes.
Speaker 1: So in the fight scenes, you're getting the sex and the violence together.
Speaker 0: Dave and Joel will be all about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if only it was good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's worth watching the first episode because there's also this really cute set of characters that they introduced But didn't do anything with.
Speaker 0: but it's not worth watching the show.
Speaker 0: I don't think to see what's up with them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the cute little girl.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess if you've never watched we're like one beer and one milk.
Speaker 1: Yep, if you never watched any of the shows by these people so you don't know what they're like watch noir.
Speaker 0: Don't watch this.
Speaker 0: I don't know this one Noir while it has probably one of the worst Second halves to any anime ever made in terms of how far downhill it went.
Speaker 0: that first episode was so badass.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah The first episode was so badass.
Speaker 0: I mean that scene everyone knows.
Speaker 0: everyone who's seen noir remembers that one scene where she hangs the dude in the stairwell.
Speaker 1: Yeah well if you like Darker shows watch noir and if you like brighter shows watch this.
Speaker 1: and if you know what kind of show this is Without watching it.
Speaker 1: Don't watch it.
Speaker 0: If you like really dumb shows you can watch that hack.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, 20 episodes of bla bla bla bla bla key off of the Twilight.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So the next show we watched was the brand new and amazing Two-terra.
Speaker 1: remember we talked about the two-terra manga which is coming out now and is super awesome and sci-fi awesomeness.
Speaker 1: Well that we mentioned when we talked about that That there's gonna be a new show about that manga.
Speaker 1: and lo and behold the show is out and we have watched one episode of it.
Speaker 0: now the show.
Speaker 0: when it first starts the very very beginning before the opener or anything.
Speaker 0: it Gave me the same feeling that the Phoenix at the new Phoenix anime did and that they it seems as though they're treating it with the proper level of respect and And faithfulness.
Speaker 1: Yep, the people who have made this anime version of two-terra Definitely have read the manga and they're sticking pretty close to it as close as can be expected and they definitely Capture the right mood and the right setting.
Speaker 1: and they're they're not like, you know Just taking the idea and running away with it like nut cases.
Speaker 1: They're basically taking the manga and animating it for easy enjoyment.
Speaker 0: Yep Now they do take a bunch of liberties and change a few things.
Speaker 0: We'll get into that but they're really not doing any more than what the Phoenix people did with Phoenix because Phoenix has a lot of goofy characters and goofy things in it that they pretty much Completely removed from the anime.
Speaker 1: and yeah, the random Tezuka humors and things like that.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, and there are similar things occasionally into terror which are also for the most part removed.
Speaker 0: But more importantly they change that stupid rocket sled Roller scooter through the inside of the planet whatever scene and they made it cool That.
Speaker 0: not to disparage the manga because the manga is amazing as least as far as I've read and I think it's going to continue.
Speaker 0: The second one's gonna be here in like next week but one of the major plot points when he goes into the amusement park and he gets on that ride.
Speaker 0: if They had actually stuck and made the anime version exactly like what they show you in the manga.
Speaker 0: That would have been so lame.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, it's sort of like how you read like American comics from the 70s and they're all super cornball.
Speaker 1: But the deep plot if you view it from far far away is actually good.
Speaker 1: It's just the writing and these specific happenings and the way it's presented is like, you know cornier than all of Nebraska This.
Speaker 1: they.
Speaker 1: they take the corn out and they make it presentable in the modern times and that's good for me And it's good for people who might not like the manga so much because it's kind of old and corny.
Speaker 1: This is much more accessible to them and you can get pretty much the same plot without being turned off.
Speaker 0: One thing I thought that was interesting a few liberties They did take is in the early early part before you find out what's actually going on And before everything really hits the fan and everything explodes and soldier blah blah blah, whatever, you know the stuff from the manga.
Speaker 0: they flesh out a lot of the minor or previously non-existent characters around Jomi in his life and Particularly, they flush out his mom and they add a lot more to him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz it's the manga definitely concentrated more at least the first volume on The plot surrounding the characters and like the huge big goings-on and you know Why everything was the way it is and the sci-fi plot and all that stuff and this seems to actually Concentrate on that less.
Speaker 1: it zooms in more on just what Jomi's doing.
Speaker 1: It doesn't show you a lot of what soldier blue and whoever else is doing.
Speaker 0: like the manga You get a lot of him interacting with his friends from before everything crazy happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah you get scenes of like you know Jomi eating breakfast with his parents and when he it's funny cuz there's one part where he eats a hot like a sausage on a fork and then like the way they animate it is he moves the sausage towards his mouth and I get one frame the Sausage is there right in front of his mouth and the next frame the sausage just disappears.
Speaker 0: you Scott in this goddamn sausage Not when we were watching it We're all you know, just a very hot dog and suddenly Scott goes Oh my god That hot dog just disappeared and he backs it up and watches it again to point out that the hot dog disappeared.
Speaker 1: I watched it again today and the hot dog disappeared.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they made they took I mean the parents.
Speaker 0: in the manga pretty much just exists for purposes of plot and that's all this As far as we've seen.
Speaker 0: obviously in the anime the dead The character is still one-dimensional.
Speaker 0: In fact, his character could be described as nothing more than stern But the mom.
Speaker 1: they made a character out of her not not a full character But they gave her enough that there would be some sympathy for the mom where in the manga It's just like she's the mom.
Speaker 1: so I think that's actually sort of necessary because modern anime and manga tend to deal a lot more with You know characters and people like, you know, it's more about the characters and less about plot.
Speaker 1: these days.
Speaker 1: So if they would have stuck with the plot heavy No one gives a shit about the characters kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Not too many people would have enjoyed it if they you know weren't already in on what's going on.
Speaker 1: There's also a funny scene where Jomie's playing soccer.
Speaker 1: Oh then and they have these robot referees.
Speaker 1: They're basically floating eyeballs.
Speaker 1: the referee the game and I think that's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: But then Jomie argues with the robot referee and he says it wasn't offsides or was offsides.
Speaker 1: He says it wasn't offsides and the robot called him offsides.
Speaker 1: So his goal didn't count.
Speaker 1: and then Jomie just smashes the robot referee.
Speaker 0: It's it just spikes it right into the crown and it's pretty hilarious.
Speaker 0: Not only is it hilarious, but that comes up again more than once in the rest of the episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they make an offsides joke.
Speaker 1: I laughed.
Speaker 1: I lolled.
Speaker 1: The only other thing is that there's a. there's a battle scene in the in this episode in the battle scene.
Speaker 1: It's pretty bad It.
Speaker 0: it could be really cool.
Speaker 0: the the the computer that he is facing off with when it's trying to erase his memories is very Interesting aesthetically and it could have been a well-done scene.
Speaker 0: However, they show it to you on screen far longer than it should have been on screen.
Speaker 0: You start to notice that it looks kind of weird and cockeyed and then the best way I can describe it is when Jomie is Fighting with the thing.
Speaker 0: It's basically Bonk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bonk Bonk.
Speaker 1: Well, there's gonna be 24 episodes of this thing.
Speaker 1: We've seen one and If I don't watch them all fansubbed I'll watch them all someday Netflix cuz I can guarantee that someday this will be available in the United States for your buying pleasure.
Speaker 0: Yep, definitely gonna finish the manga first.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: There's only three volumes of the manga and we're getting the second one in a week.
Speaker 1: So I think we're gonna be finished with that way before we watch 24 episodes of this.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, the next show is a show I just discovered.
Speaker 1: I thought actually I thought that this was a show from last season because I felt like I had it in my folder for a Long time, but actually it says on anime news network encyclopedia that it came out on April 8th this year.
Speaker 1: So I guess it's a new show.
Speaker 1: It's actually I think a new gonzo show.
Speaker 1: It's called ha boku.
Speaker 1: Rano B. Okay, you are a no Well, if you haven't listened to us or anime world order or David Joel before you'll know that gonzo shows are typical For having really awesome first episodes really awesome premises really great animation and then as the show continues Everything just goes downhill from there and it's a big disappointment.
Speaker 0: It's like what if we made an anime about blah?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that'd be really cool.
Speaker 0: They get to episode 22.
Speaker 0: They're like, how do we end this?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Fuck it.
Speaker 1: So I'm hesitant to give a positive view to this show because it follows the gonzo trend.
Speaker 1: The first episode of course is great and later on it won't be so great.
Speaker 1: However, I'm gonna review just this episode.
Speaker 1: it was pretty damn great both in its execution and in the premise.
Speaker 1: basically what this show is about is you have these 15 kids and They're bored in the summer and they're all sort of friends with each other.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're at a summer camp Maybe they're at school something like that I don't know.
Speaker 1: and They're hanging out on the beach one day.
Speaker 1: and what they do in this first beach scene is they introduce you to all the different Characters and they've got characters like covering every possible base, you know, the shy kid, you know the strong leader kid You know the the girl who doesn't talk so much the Gabby girl the bad kid The really cute young fourth grader girl where everyone else is in seventh grade
Speaker 0: I gotta say.
Speaker 0: for the most part the short bit of interaction between all these characters is generally pretty realistic and well-executed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually it's like the first part of the show like five minutes.
Speaker 1: all you see is these characters interacting with each other on the beach as kids would and It's totally believable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it introduces you to all the characters by the end of the first episode.
Speaker 0: You already might not remember all their names But you already know what all the characters are like to a degree and you already feel like you have Something.
Speaker 0: you have some sort of investment in all of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz it doesn't seem like this show has a main character.
Speaker 1: I mean some of the kids are more important than others or more central But none of them gets enough, you know lead time to say aha That's the character who's really the number one and all the other kids are just kind of behind them.
Speaker 1: It seems like a really even deal.
Speaker 1: so you need to you know get some you know something about all of them in order to enjoy the show.
Speaker 1: and Then what happens after?
Speaker 1: that is the kids are bored They go exploring and they go into a cave and to explore the cave because it's plunking is fun I guess.
Speaker 1: and in the cave they see something better than rocks and bats.
Speaker 1: They see computers What the fuck computers doing in a cave.
Speaker 1: and then a weird guy shows up who reminds me of characters from other anime But I can't quite put my finger on it.
Speaker 1: Like he seems like all those scientist guys, you know, who are all Sort of like but he's also sort of mysterious and that he doesn't talk so much and he doesn't say any more than he has To yeah, he's got those circular glasses that light up.
Speaker 0: Well the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah the professor Tomoe glasses.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the way he Says things and I mean obviously I'm relying heavily on the fansubbers and I don't know how good the fansubs were But he always like they say oh, is this a game?
Speaker 0: and he'll say something like yeah game that works.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, anyway He tells these kids that they're gonna play that he's making a game and I don't know why these kids don't question Why a guy's making a game in a cave?
Speaker 0: Well, some of them do they're like But a few of them are oh cool, and I don't know I probably been ooh cool Yeah, cuz I wouldn't expect what happens to happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so he says you can all be the beta testers and they're like, oh, okay So, you know, he says all right, just walk up to this thing say your name and touch it with your hand.
Speaker 1: so they do so except for the little girl who doesn't want to.
Speaker 1: and He says all right this in the game There's you know, 15 attacking aliens and you have a robot you have to defend the earth from the aliens Alright, and then there's static and the kids wake up on the beach.
Speaker 1: Oh snaps What the hell's going on here?
Speaker 1: It's craziness.
Speaker 1: All right, you know the same.
Speaker 0: Now one really interesting thing and I really don't think this had anything to do with commercial breaks Is that periodically whenever there's a break in the action?
Speaker 0: there'll be this sudden cut of static and then you'll be in a new scene and I really really really really get the impression that this is a new tennis style.
Speaker 0: Hey, you're just gonna think get used to the static and not worry about it But then the static is actually something important later in the show.
Speaker 1: The static is definitely something important But what it is, I cannot bet on.
Speaker 1: right now I have a few hunches, but there are definitely a bunch of hunches But I can't.
Speaker 1: I don't have any evidence to support anyone over the other.
Speaker 1: All I know is that one of them is probably true and the others are all false.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what ends up happening?
Speaker 1: Of course is that it's not a game.
Speaker 1: they have a robot and they need to defend the earth from other robots and it's a really great scene when they fight the robot with their robot because they The actual fighting is not so interesting.
Speaker 1: What's interesting is that no one else can see either of these battling robots except the kids and the scary scientist guy.
Speaker 1: But the effects of the robot battle are felt throughout the city.
Speaker 1: so there'll be crazy weather and storms and waves and earthquakes and lightning and all sorts of stuff but None of the people will see these robots so they'll just be like OMG this is crazy weather and earthquake.
Speaker 1: I hope the kids are alright.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, the kids are fighting these robots that are making all this terrible weather and such and they're the only ones who realize that The earth is under attack from horrible robots and they're the only ones who can defend the earth with their own robot.
Speaker 0: Plus the the way they actually fight and especially the first fight that you see where the guy who set all this up is very much just sitting there explaining to them how it all works in a very matter-of-fact way and half of them are freaking out and Some of them are paying attention and the way they set up the fighting and the way they set up the control of the robot.
Speaker 0: It's really interesting and I don't want to say exactly what it is.
Speaker 0: I just want you to watch the show and I want to see where they run with this.
Speaker 1: Yeah Even if this turns out to be another gonzo bust this first Episode was so great that I say you should watch it until it turns crap.
Speaker 1: I mean if the first one's enjoyable, right?
Speaker 1: Even if the end is crap You can keep watching it as long as it's enjoyable get enjoyment out of it And as soon as it's no longer enjoyable just stop.
Speaker 1: It'll be worth it.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah sure It would be nicer if the ending was actually awesome and this whole thing was great, but I can't guarantee that's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: However, this thing isn't very likely to have that many episodes for reasons.
Speaker 1: I will not go into.
Speaker 1: I mean Anime news network only knows eight episode names.
Speaker 1: So it might just be an eight episode show.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Oh plus Emily did watch more of it and she said a few things that we're not going to repeat because they might be a Little spoiler.
Speaker 1: ish or they might not be true.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah We're not exactly sure where the show goes at all yeah,
Speaker 1: but I do think that this is a good chance of being a great show because Gonzo tends to screw up shows way past, you know towards the later episodes and if they keep this show short and the premise is Strong and it seems like this premise has like a built-in good ending So they can't just fuck it up by trailing off at the ending.
Speaker 1: They have to go with the ending that the premise implies or something related to that.
Speaker 0: now This might sound a little strange and I don't know how many people out there have actually read this book.
Speaker 0: It was part of an assignment for school when I was in elementary school so I ended up reading it, but the plot on a very Hard to explain level really reminds me of this sci-fi novel called interstellar pig that I read God how many years ago?
Speaker 1: I've never heard of this and I know nothing about it.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not gonna say what the plot of interstellar pig is because I don't know if there's any relation at all Or if it would be any sort of spoiler or anything.
Speaker 0: And also I want to see more of the show because it's very likely that there's just no connection at all But at least the plots feel similar in terms of what might actually be going on.
Speaker 1: Yep, so bokurano a show worth keeping an eye out for a in the long run.
Speaker 1: This will probably also be available in the US and it'll probably only be on a few DVDs.
Speaker 1: cuz I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't see this Being more than like 15 16 episodes.
Speaker 1: There's no way it's gonna be 26.
Speaker 1: That'd be crazy.
Speaker 1: So Cool.
Speaker 1: So last and least last and most You might remember we reviewed a show a while back called Gog manga Biori Gog you Bongo Biori.
Speaker 1: It's one of those totally wacky comedy shows from Japan with the Japanese Humor that's very Japanese that Americans can't really understand without lots of help.
Speaker 0: Yeah, granted if you've watched enough anime and you have watched if you get used to it This is the kind of humor that you're probably going to start understanding whether you realize it or not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you can understand as a manga daioh and Cromartie high school and the first season of Gog manga Biori You can understand the second season of Gog manga Biori.
Speaker 0: I gotta say the show is picking up right where it left off and I love it.
Speaker 0: is what my favorite shows.
Speaker 1: They changed the opener but with they have a similar style song about Waikiki beach or something.
Speaker 1: And then at the open at the end of the opener, they still go Gog manga Biori And then the closer they still go.
Speaker 1: Yep and basically, there was an episode in the first season that had a joke about a bunny detective girl in school and It was a pretty funny episode.
Speaker 1: in this The first episode of the second season is just more of the high school bunny girl detective.
Speaker 0: I don't know why it's the same joke every time but I laugh at it every single time.
Speaker 1: The high school bunny girl detective is a great joke as the joke basically goes like this.
Speaker 1: There's a school There's a bunny girl who's a detective in the class sort of like encyclopedia brown or whatever.
Speaker 1: She's talking to this bear guy this bear kid.
Speaker 1: The bear kid is like can't be a bear right?
Speaker 1: the bear kid is like, oh there haven't been any incidents lately.
Speaker 1: She's like, yeah, I wish I could do some detecting.
Speaker 1: then he's like, uh, then she'll say something like why don't you go?
Speaker 1: Die in a fire.
Speaker 1: So there'll be an incident.
Speaker 1: He's like no I'm not gonna go die in a fire.
Speaker 1: Then there'll be an incident like, you know, oh something happened.
Speaker 1: Hmm and The bear guy will just talk to the bunny girl.
Speaker 1: Like they'll be talking about the incident.
Speaker 1: I wonder who did it.
Speaker 1: then the bunny girl gets the eyes of doom.
Speaker 1: I know who did it.
Speaker 1: That's a lot better than the gums yep, and It's always the bear guy who did it.
Speaker 1: and it's hilarious because you that it pans.
Speaker 1: it moves the camera out and you see him Doing the crime like right in front of the bunny girl, but he's talking like you didn't know it.
Speaker 0: It pretty much always ends with him being taken away by the police.
Speaker 1: It's just great It's hilarious and it doesn't matter if you know what the joke is because when you actually zoom out and see what he's doing It's always funny no matter what.
Speaker 1: even if you've seen it before I watch this episode for the second time is still funny.
Speaker 1: so yeah, if you like Humor, you should be watching Gogmog of B or E.
Speaker 0: and if you haven't seen the first season don't even bother watching this yet Go find the first season.
Speaker 0: watch episode one.
Speaker 0: If that doesn't hook you on this show.
Speaker 0: There's no hope.
Speaker 1: there's no hope for you.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's still my favorite one and I've seen it like ten times because I just remember I was laughing Painfully hard at the end with the stick.
Speaker 0: Yeah well even like the I was laughing already and I was laughing and laughing and laughing and I'm about to stop laughing.
Speaker 0: my body says All right, you've left enough and then the sticker and I kept laughing but there's no more air.
Speaker 0: It was just too much.
Speaker 1: Take care of Coon is the only one in my.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was really surprised though because you know I just I check anime ski every day to see if there's any new shows.
Speaker 1: I look for the number one because that means a new show.
Speaker 1: right and might I mean a new show?
Speaker 1: but it might mean a. you know the first episode of a show that hasn't I've never seen before and I didn't expect to ever see in my entire life more Gogmog of B or E. I thought I was done.
Speaker 1: You know, I saw the whole first season.
Speaker 1: that's over but no Gogmog of B or E 2 episode 1.
Speaker 1: I was like, yes Yes, oh, yeah can't get better than that.
Speaker 1: there's no question whether this is gonna be good or not.
Speaker 1: I don't have to watch it to know if it's good or not.
Speaker 1: and good and there it is.
Speaker 0: If you have any qualms about fan subs, the show's not getting licensed anytime soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah If this gets licensed that'll be crazy and I'll buy like two copies just to show my support for that shit.
Speaker 0: if This show or a show of this level of I don't know localness to Japan.
Speaker 0: I mean how.
Speaker 0: what market is there for a show like this?
Speaker 1: how many people in America would I mean they license Cromartie?
Speaker 1: But this is even more Crazy than that.
Speaker 0: This is beyond Excel saga because Excel saga at least is accessible in that.
Speaker 0: It's just weird a lot of the time and super wacky.
Speaker 0: This is not wacky like that.
Speaker 0: It's zany in this kind of off-center way.
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: it'd be almost sinister if it went any further with its concepts.
Speaker 1: Harris Impact all Yeah.
Speaker 1: So if you missed the first season of Gog manga B or E and maybe you can't find it online Or if you enjoyed the first season of Gog manga B or E go download the second season Gog manga B or E Because if you don't you have no sense of humor and I don't care about you.
Speaker 0: So, of course before we wrap it up once again remember Kinetic on.
Speaker 0: it's a ways out yet But we're gonna be rocking that con where we're gonna be super rocking that con.
Speaker 0: this weekend two days from now is torque on torque On in Rochester, New York at the Rochester Institute of Technology.
Speaker 0: Gig nights is appearing there in a panel though.
Speaker 0: Scott will not be joining me.
Speaker 0: So it'll basically just be me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was thinking about going I was thinking about not going but now I'm thinking about not going.
Speaker 1: so It's just not worth a five-hour drive to Rochester to do one panel and go to a game store And then come home and maybe eat a really good sandwich, but I can get a really good sandwich in the city.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'm just.
Speaker 1: I really don't want to drive either.
Speaker 1: I got stuff to do here I don't know.
Speaker 1: I need to go buy new shorts.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'll go to any more Torah cons after this just because it's far away.
Speaker 1: and yeah I'm like other cons like if you weren't going yeah, like if you weren't going to this convention.
Speaker 1: I would have gone because we promised to go and do the panel so I would have oh, oh, I'm not going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you are no, I won't go we'll see.
Speaker 0: no I just won't go.
Speaker 0: now you have to go we'll see.
Speaker 0: what do you mean?
Speaker 1: We'll see because I wouldn't back down on a place you promised to appear but at the same time it's you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you're anywhere near Rochester, New York, you definitely should go to tour con.
Speaker 1: It'll be worth your time if you live close by.
Speaker 0: yes, it has been very fun the two times I've got.
Speaker 0: it is also very cheap and it is only one day so you don't need a hotel room or anything.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's sort of also why it's not worth driving five hours because it's only one day.
Speaker 1: so and you know I've been to tour con before and I went to RIT school for five years.
Speaker 0: So well, you see it's like ever here.
Speaker 1: I'm not in a rush to go back there.
Speaker 0: So for me Torah con is like my annual pilgrimage back to my spawning point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right, you spawned before RIT I just.
Speaker 0: RIT is like the land where all of my geekery became Crystallized and I became the man that I am today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is sort of like the front row crew Mecca in a way.
Speaker 0: Yes, we have to make periodic pilgrimages or will become lame and have desk jobs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll probably go back there when there's something going down But actually I plan to go to at least several at least several RIT hockey games next year.
Speaker 1: Well, let's go to the one they play at Sacred Heart Which is near my right like five minutes from my parents house.
Speaker 0: Didn't we say we were gonna do that last year and we didn't?
Speaker 1: well We'll do it this year because my friend works at Sacred Heart as a sports guy.
Speaker 1: So he'll totally get us the hookup.
Speaker 0: He'd better get us the hookup and then get us in his press.
Speaker 1: He is the well, he's not the press.
Speaker 1: He's like the announce II talky guy.
Speaker 0: So, can you get us in his press?
Speaker 1: I don't know what he can get us in.
Speaker 0: I'll cover the game.
Speaker 0: I'll take pictures.
Speaker 1: No, they have people who cover the game.
Speaker 0: I'll cover the game better.
Speaker 1: Anyway, they Also, we could probably go to the West Point game because they play army and that's not too far God army is one of the worst hockey teams ever till I heard they were kind of good.
Speaker 0: Maybe they are now but I I mean, I didn't know anything about the division one We were getting into.
Speaker 0: and I remember very clearly when I was at IBM I was like, hey my old school RIT is joining division one blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: and I said all the stuff.
Speaker 0: and he says hey Is that where army plays?
Speaker 0: and I said yes the Atlantic League.
Speaker 0: and he said I used to play for army.
Speaker 0: They're the worst hockey team to ever exist.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe it's different from when he played for them might be I don't know.
Speaker 0: I haven't followed RIT hockey at all.
Speaker 1: All I know is that RIT hockey did really well this year, but because they're brand new in the division one They're not allowed to be in any tournaments or win anything because they're brand new.
Speaker 0: So how much would that suck if you're the guy who won and you have to remember that the only reason you won is because?
Speaker 0: The team that was better than you was Statutorily prevented.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm winning the turn like.
Speaker 1: imagine this.
Speaker 1: imagine like pick a sport right now.
Speaker 1: Let's say let's pick baseball.
Speaker 1: Let's say I start a brand new baseball team an expansion team a team that never existed before.
Speaker 1: the the beacon Front row crew nerds right brand new Major League Baseball team, but because we're a brand new team We're not allowed to win the World Series.
Speaker 1: Let's say we go the entire regular season undefeated.
Speaker 1: I know that's pretty much impossible.
Speaker 1: But let's say it happens just for the sake of argument.
Speaker 1: We're the best team.
Speaker 1: hands down No one can even hope to beat us.
Speaker 1: But because we're a brand new team We're not allowed to go into the playoffs or win the World Series or anything.
Speaker 1: That's what this is like.
Speaker 1: So hopefully in a year or two when RIT is actually allowed to win the tournaments and things.
Speaker 1: they will Still be good and win because that would be awesome.
Speaker 1: All right, it shows over.
Speaker 0: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.