Speaker 0: It's Thursday November 8th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: Scott ran out to get Chinese food, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We talk a bit about the most recent US elections.
Speaker 1: Let's do this woman.
Speaker 0: It's uh, it's cold today.
Speaker 1: You can always tell what season it is in the northern hemisphere.
Speaker 1: well in the geek house Yes by the by how we open the show.
Speaker 0: well People have pointed this out, and we kind of realized it long after.
Speaker 0: but ever since we saw NASA Cuffled with that one family guy there for whatever reason just stuck in our heads.
Speaker 0: mom today home yesterday Today woman space is one cold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though, it's cold.
Speaker 1: I get it's pretty much.
Speaker 1: I mean like you know Eskimo not Eskimos.
Speaker 1: But anyway, they have like a hundred zillion words for snow because there are many different You know varieties of snow.
Speaker 1: the snow is sticking more.
Speaker 1: They have a different word if it's taking less.
Speaker 1: they have a different word if it's clumpy different word, right?
Speaker 1: But for us you pretty much boiled out weather entirely down to two things woman and Warm today warm yesterday.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much the only two kinds of weather we can have.
Speaker 0: It was annoying though I get up you don't go to my car, and I see frost all over it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was quite frosty.
Speaker 1: I had to warm the car up a bit.
Speaker 1: I really I maybe I'll get a remote starter.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: those aren't the greatest.
Speaker 1: I know that's why I'm thinking about not getting one, but it's it's I don't know.
Speaker 0: I remembered our IT.
Speaker 0: I used to go out start my car Just leave it there unlocked and running next to the eight other cars that were doing the same thing.
Speaker 0: go back into my apartment Take a shower get dressed and then go to my car.
Speaker 1: It was a good plan because it totally melted off the whole car.
Speaker 1: I mean the car is like a fire in an engine.
Speaker 1: the thing is it's so cold it takes a while for that fire to Actually warm up this giant car made of metal.
Speaker 0: No That's way to impress little kids.
Speaker 0: when you drive it in a car just explain to them that the engine is a thousands upon thousands of controlled explosions every minute.
Speaker 0: yep That kind of fascinated me as a little kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was like how come the fire is not killing me over here.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, let's just get to the chase.
Speaker 0: It's short week.
Speaker 0: We're trying to catch up on the fact that we've been going along for the past.
Speaker 1: I don't know seven months and also the Libsyn fill it up.
Speaker 0: We got a we're gonna upgrade it But until we do we gonna.
Speaker 1: probably we can't.
Speaker 1: we can't afford a graphic designer But we'll upgrade lives because Libsyn cost nothing.
Speaker 0: That's why there's no excuse not to use it.
Speaker 1: All right, so You know, we always talk about you know, the potential of you know.
Speaker 1: Oh you bought some DRM and then they fucked you over and now you paid for something and it's gone.
Speaker 0: And how a lot of our friends and people on the internet always say but they don't actually screw you.
Speaker 0: look no one ever Actually takes something away except for tribes too, but no one cares about that.
Speaker 1: Take away traps to with DRM but well they took it away.
Speaker 0: Well, it almost because you had to authenticate with their server to run their product.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then they just took their server away and never gave any way of unlocking said product.
Speaker 1: Well, they gave away keys until there weren't any keys left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can still download the game for free But there's no keys left.
Speaker 0: Yes, because yeah, hence the game is effectively unplayable.
Speaker 1: Anyway, they you know, people always talk about this with steam.
Speaker 1: like I don't want to buy a game on steam What if steam can screw me over and it's I guess it's technically possibly and they can maybe but you know the way steam works.
Speaker 1: I mean you can play stuff offline and shit kinda.
Speaker 0: there are problems with it.
Speaker 1: There are but like for example the quake games, right?
Speaker 1: It all it does is I can go into those folders and double click on quake daddy XE and it will work.
Speaker 0: That's just because those are old ass legacy game.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that's you know, that's how it works.
Speaker 1: It doesn't, you know check online too often.
Speaker 0: I mean it's like how the old counter-strike was beholden to one.
Speaker 1: Yep, yep.
Speaker 1: Yep But anyway, you know, there's some DRM there and there's a potential.
Speaker 1: but valve is generally trustworthy.
Speaker 1: I think that if something happened that they would you know Just turn the steam off in such a way that everyone could play all the games they had that were single-player and they would just Turn off whatever they had to pay for.
Speaker 1: Regardless there is a potential for this in many situations.
Speaker 1: For example, the Apple iTunes action.
Speaker 1: they could just you know DRM everyone away But you don't actually see too many real-world examples of it actually happening.
Speaker 1: Someone actually turning off the DRM and everyone getting hosed Hence.
Speaker 0: a lot of people call us technologists who rent and rail against DRM as alarmists.
Speaker 1: Yes paranoid that won't happen.
Speaker 1: The company's on screw you over blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Well major league baseball just did it.
Speaker 1: now if you don't know It's pretty hard.
Speaker 1: I mean one thing that TV still has going for is that if you like sports watching professional sports at least TV and radio are really the only places to get at that action You can like.
Speaker 1: if you just want to listen to baseball games on the computer it costs money a lot of money a Ludicrous amount of money for this is because major league sports particularly Major League Baseball, but also the football.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hockey is one of the more liberal and even that he is very liberal.
Speaker 1: and even then actually f1 is probably the worst of All in the whole world.
Speaker 0: funny how despite the fact that oh, we need more people to watch f1 Let's make it as hard as possible for young hit people to watch our sport.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's make it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's you know It's obviously something people are stuck wood.
Speaker 1: It would get popular if you've noticed how many videos that I get dug up on dig compared to say baseballs or hockey's or anything.
Speaker 1: But they make it so hard to watch so we can't actually take off.
Speaker 1: It's like all these people see it on dig and they might be interested but up can't actually.
Speaker 0: well all these industries are deathly afraid of the internet for various reasons and don't want anything to do with it unless they can charge a lot of money because They make us all their money from sponsorships.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much so.
Speaker 1: people just start distributing their videos on YouTube.
Speaker 1: They'll have no money.
Speaker 0: I mean it's to the point where they they make it impossible and they actually.
Speaker 0: I've seen a lot of people talking more and more about how the Basically, they say that you don't have fair use rights to sports games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've been saying that for a long time and now there's rumblings.
Speaker 0: the legal world where people are saying You know that might not be true.
Speaker 1: It's almost definitely not true.
Speaker 1: You have fair use buried fair use.
Speaker 1: It's in a law.
Speaker 0: It's kind of an implied right though, it's not very oh it's pretty much says fair use.
Speaker 0: what does it say Scott?
Speaker 1: There's a list of things.
Speaker 0: the problem is those that list come from.
Speaker 0: is that list in the law or is that the opinion of?
Speaker 1: Someone know those things are in the law, huh?
Speaker 1: The thing is is that those things are not like straight and narrow.
Speaker 1: They're.
Speaker 1: they're pretty loosely Interpreted by courts, which is their weakness.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is these people don't want anything to do with the internet.
Speaker 0: They stay away from as best they can and they go after anyone who so much as talks about a baseball game on the internet.
Speaker 1: Yep so if you want to watch baseball at least on the internet you can pay money and they will let you watch baseball on the internet.
Speaker 1: and What they just did is they turned off the DRM server.
Speaker 1: So people who paid a lot of money to watch baseball on the internet They just turned all their baseball off so that these people paid.
Speaker 1: they got videos.
Speaker 1: now the videos are gone.
Speaker 0: Now the argument that they made was that well you only paid for one viewing.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we were just graciously letting you watch more than one So you didn't lose anything.
Speaker 0: when we turned off all the access to every video you'd ever purchased Google did this actually before.
Speaker 1: when they had they were selling videos on Google video Before you know, they stopped doing that and they turned it all off and then they said alright everyone.
Speaker 0: Here's your money back You know, yeah, but Major League Baseball not quite so honorable.
Speaker 1: Nope what they have.
Speaker 1: it is though You know, here's a real example of someone turning off the DRM and fucking everyone over and going.
Speaker 1: aha.
Speaker 1: However, I think the the bad press on the issue They have been forced to do something about it and they they now said that you know I guess when stuff comes back up that if you bought something you'll get it back but not post season stuff.
Speaker 1: So if you like bought some playoff games, you won't get those back right away.
Speaker 1: Wow Maybe later you'll get them back when they figure out what to do with playoff stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but anyway, you know they did, you know bring something back.
Speaker 1: but the point is DRM you you.
Speaker 1: basically it's it's like if I go to Best Buy and buy a bunch of DVDs and I watch him or Maybe I don't watch some of them I watch a few of them and then the next day the Best Buy comes over and takes all the DVDs and My house and then there's nothing like.
Speaker 0: DRM is a tool like any other where you give up control Over things that you have paid for our own to someone else and you always have to think how much do I trust this person?
Speaker 0: it's kind of like this remote controlled gun of Damocles that's always pointed at whatever you just bought.
Speaker 0: and Who do you trust with remote control to the gun of Damocles pointed at whatever you just bought?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: do I trust valve kind of mostly trust Google pretty much Major League Baseball.
Speaker 0: No now now Yeah right, so speaking of Nothing to do with DRM at all.
Speaker 0: This is kind of related to our actual show more so than anything else, but Unslash out there's article here.
Speaker 0: It looks like the FTC is starting to actually crack down on all those people who are just blatantly ignoring the do not call list in the United States, ah Good times.
Speaker 0: the problem with this is that of course they can't crack down on the worst offenders.
Speaker 0: I the people who are not covered by the do not call list.
Speaker 0: I'm speaking specifically about politicians and Quote-unquote Surveys.
Speaker 1: now remember charities.
Speaker 0: right charities are just as bad God.
Speaker 1: There are certain people who are allowed to call the people on the do not call list and it really it just shouldn't be anybody.
Speaker 1: No one should be allowed to go see.
Speaker 0: on one hand I understand the argument for the politicians because the argument is if you're a politician You should always have the right to contact in any way that you can your constituents and political speech and freedom of speech And all that and I I'm kind of I at least understand that argument.
Speaker 0: but then they allow polling in surveys and a lot of these polls and surveys basically come down to How great is our product?
Speaker 0: How much money would you pay to buy this awesome product?
Speaker 0: Let me tell you more about the product so you can make a better answer to the question of would you buy our product?
Speaker 0: You like to buy our product.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: I Just feel like this problem shouldn't exist.
Speaker 0: and it only exists because the way phones work even with all the fancy technology and cell phones is Still pretty archaic.
Speaker 0: and while we have similar spam problems on the internet with things like email and I am It's pretty trivial to filter that out, but I can't filter out phone calls easily.
Speaker 1: Well, you have caller ID but caller ID is trivially spoofed.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean think about it.
Speaker 1: I went to that Transformers website right and I typed in rims phone number and I typed in my phone number and then I typed I chose a funny Message.
Speaker 1: so some computer somewhere called the rim on the phone rim looked at his caller ID thought it was me Even though I didn't call him right and then had a conversation with Optimus Prime.
Speaker 1: that covers it lots of crime.
Speaker 1: So Faking caller ID is basically perfect and easy and it's it's not useful as a real filter of calls.
Speaker 0: Also, there aren't many systems that will automate.
Speaker 0: I can't set up an access list for my phone with the caller ID.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that would be pretty cool as if like you could have your phone set up So only people on your contacts list could call you.
Speaker 0: you can pay for services.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do things to that effect.
Speaker 1: The thing is, you know, how it would only it could only work on the caller ID.
Speaker 1: Well, how would it work?
Speaker 0: If someone did actually a lot of these services you can pay and all all incoming calls except on a white list get routed to Basically a secretary who answers figures out if they're a telemarketer or not and then only forwards you real calls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I was like what if someone caught my mom calls me collect for the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: I'd be like, uh-oh You know calling someone collect is not gonna help.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna find a computer somewhere and email him.
Speaker 0: It's it's the modern world people.
Speaker 1: I know but you get.
Speaker 0: the point is it I'll use my cell phone And you might say what if you don't have your cell phone?
Speaker 1: Your cell phone ran out of battery and it's an emergency.
Speaker 0: I'll borrow any of the thousand cell phones nearby.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then the caller ID won't be right and you'll be filtered.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I'm saying?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just really don't care.
Speaker 0: what matters to me more than anything is people not being able to call me and bother me and charge me money because I pay for my cell phone minutes and There's no argument anyone can make that will convince me that a comprehensive do not call list should be anything other than outright Immediate law.
Speaker 1: I think we should have some sort of thing where if someone calls you and they're a company of some sort you can ask for like certain information and then if you You know You just report that information to some place and then you get money and then they if they ever call you again You get more money.
Speaker 0: The other trouble is the old problem with pre-existing business relationships where if a company can make up some sort of fanciful Notion that you have somehow ever Contacted them in any way then they can use that as a loophole to call.
Speaker 1: The worst offender is the cable company Like I had.
Speaker 1: I pay for the.
Speaker 1: you know The optimum online cable internet service is in my name and they call me like every month like hey Do you want to get phone and TV too?
Speaker 1: Do you want to get phone and TV when you get phone and TV?
Speaker 1: We're gonna get phone and TV.
Speaker 1: You have a special deal special deal special deal.
Speaker 1: I'm like, you know have a special deal.
Speaker 1: the triple play is this deal that you have all the time?
Speaker 1: It's non-stop.
Speaker 1: I could get it any time.
Speaker 1: I wanted.
Speaker 1: it's not a new deal.
Speaker 1: Stop calling me.
Speaker 1: Stop calling me I don't.
Speaker 1: I only want internet.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna make my internet cheaper without making me get anything else?
Speaker 1: I don't want.
Speaker 1: no then.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: go away.
Speaker 0: I remember when they used to send people out every now and then to just look at us and see if we were stealing cable Because they didn't believe that we don't actually watch TV.
Speaker 1: Well, they've stopped doing that.
Speaker 1: So maybe we should start stealing cable.
Speaker 0: Yeah To what end?
Speaker 0: what would that?
Speaker 0: I I guess we could watch South Park, but even then we'd have to get a Smith TV set up because I'm not gonna watch an ad.
Speaker 0: Yep Things of the day.
Speaker 0: so we take CG, you know computer graphics and computer animation kind of for granted now, but There was a time a time in 1983 When computer graphics were shall we say in a primitive state?
Speaker 1: I remember that episode of the Muppet Babies that had some CG in it like.
Speaker 1: I'll check this out.
Speaker 0: Oh, man You know I just remember the Muppet Babies and I would give a lot to be able to buy a DVD box out of that entire thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people forget that the Muppet Babies was like.
Speaker 1: basically I could probably I could probably make a good case that YouTube would not be What it was that Muppet Babies?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, we'll get we'll do a show or something about that about the Muppet Babies.
Speaker 0: I think we could.
Speaker 0: okay I think we could easily anyway, so this I found this on YouTube kind of randomly, but it is a Disney's I guess one of their first forays into digital animation and 3d animation ever and Specifically they had the rights to where the wild things are.
Speaker 1: I don't think they have those rights anymore, but I'm feeling back then they did and they couldn't like.
Speaker 0: they never did anything with it Except they use the characters just because that was what they wanted to use and they made a little animation And then they tried to integrate it with this 3d computer animated world mm-hmm, and this is that original primitive clip and It's very interesting to watch because the hand-drawn animation is great And the rest of it looks like a video game from the multimedia era.
Speaker 0: It's it's pretty It's kind of interesting and they there's a bit of stuff before they show it where they talk about Why Disney animation was so great and why it was better than anyone else's animation.
Speaker 1: They had more money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, no, no specifically squash and stretch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he brings it out He's like, yes, our characters squash and stretch, right?
Speaker 0: That's they were great.
Speaker 0: Well Emily taught me what that was.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling that this is sort of like.
Speaker 1: also like this is like the seed that grew into the Pixar I have a feeling well.
Speaker 0: the real thing I got to say though.
Speaker 0: Is that I I really want to see Where the wild things are by Disney.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that'd be cool.
Speaker 1: That'd be really cool I like especially if you watch the animation from this I'd like and where the wild things are.
Speaker 1: It's high quality.
Speaker 0: So watch this before Disney finds out it's on the internet and probably removes it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, cuz that'll happen.
Speaker 1: So, okay.
Speaker 1: All right Speaking of wild things this has nothing to do with wild things has to do with Lord of the Rings.
Speaker 0: you I can't steal my joke.
Speaker 0: It's my stick to say speaking of blah and then say something unrelated.
Speaker 0: Well, I've rhymed Barely Wings things rings that that was weak.
Speaker 1: anyway You know origami, you know, you make a little paper crane make a little spider.
Speaker 1: You've seen some good origami something internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen a few.
Speaker 1: This is the best origami I've ever seen on the internet.
Speaker 0: This is so good.
Speaker 0: I would feel that it was fake except I just have this impression that no that guy's just that dedicated to paper folding.
Speaker 1: This is for real.
Speaker 1: Hey check this out.
Speaker 1: You got a Gandalf.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's what looks like.
Speaker 1: it looks like a Gandalf a Gimli and a Legolas Made out of each.
Speaker 1: each one made out of a single square piece of paper.
Speaker 0: Keep that in your mind.
Speaker 1: a single Folded sheet of square paper Probably a really big piece of paper, but it just one piece of paper.
Speaker 0: and look at these things.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're almost as impressive as Lord of the Rings on the go.
Speaker 0: I Just had to bring that up.
Speaker 1: Yeah Check this stuff out and maybe I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe seeing this will encourage you to become an origami master.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm awful at origami.
Speaker 1: I am also awful at origami.
Speaker 1: I can't even make the stupid crane.
Speaker 0: I tried a lot.
Speaker 0: In fact in fourth grade we had we were all making paper cranes for there was something.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember what the deal was, but we were sending them to Japan.
Speaker 0: I think it was actually on the anniversary of Hiroshima or something.
Speaker 0: Like there's some big tall.
Speaker 0: the Catholic schools were doing it But I failed at making even a single one.
Speaker 1: I can barely make a paper airplane.
Speaker 0: They the T the nuns actually rejected the few attempts I'd made and didn't send them.
Speaker 0: No because they were that bad Wow.
Speaker 0: I Felt bad as a kid about that.
Speaker 1: actually, uh, yeah, I just kind of accepted it.
Speaker 0: Hey, at least they were better than my handwriting.
Speaker 1: My handwriting is yeah, right?
Speaker 0: So we're not gonna talk about this at too much length, but this previous Tuesday was in America election day but a lot of people in America seem to think that elections only happen once every four years and Pretty much we have an election every year for various things.
Speaker 0: But this is what we call like the super off-term election and nothing Important or big was really up in most places except for you know, mayor of the town.
Speaker 1: Oh, but remember as far as most Americans are concerned voting for president is the only election they even know about Either one that matters least whereas, you know, I'd say Congress people Person is probably the most important person you vote for.
Speaker 0: most people only vote for Congressmen because they happen to be in the polls on a presidential election.
Speaker 1: Yep, in fact state congressperson is probably the most important person you vote for.
Speaker 1: that matters in your life the most more than anyone else.
Speaker 1: Yep, at least in the US.
Speaker 0: But uh, we had one of those elections and of course hardly anyone voted.
Speaker 0: But the election in Beacon where we live was actually a little bit contested.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the the existing mayor was going out So it was no incumbents running for mayor and there were a lot of other You know important positions like County executive that were up for grabs.
Speaker 1: So, you know some guy who from what I can tell from his ads was not the greatest guy was going up against the long-term incumbent, you know.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, there were a lot of seats pretty much on the county and local level all up for grabs.
Speaker 0: now Scott and I because you Know, well, I'm more politically minded than Scott I'd say but even he agreed that we can't really shit talk about all the government block if we don't get active locally and we Don't you know pay attention to what's going on locally make informed decisions, you know Actually be at least vote and care why we're voting and not just only vote for presidents and Congress people.
Speaker 0: Yeah so we endeavored to find out as much as we could about all the candidates and all the positions locally and in the county and the city and everything.
Speaker 1: and Actually, there was one thing I could have done that I didn't do and that was the actual.
Speaker 1: the local newspaper had videos and interviews with all the candidates and I was gonna watch him and then I didn't.
Speaker 0: I Tried to watch them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm There's a word for it.
Speaker 0: I believe the word is boring.
Speaker 0: I believe the words the sentence would be.
Speaker 0: they didn't say anything.
Speaker 0: that wasn't in their ads.
Speaker 0: I watched one and I didn't bother.
Speaker 0: Yeah but we endeavored to find out everything we could and vote as informed citizens and That's where the trouble began.
Speaker 0: It seems that the only way we could find out about their positions was from the edge They sent us.
Speaker 0: So alright once we accepted that fact fine We'll vote solely based on what these people have said they're going to do.
Speaker 0: We will trust what they are saying.
Speaker 0: They're going to do.
Speaker 1: well What they said they're gonna do is nothing nothing.
Speaker 1: They didn't say anything.
Speaker 1: you pick up the ads and it's like, okay I pick up one ad.
Speaker 0: they'd always say things like I am an advocate of an open government an active government a Government that's transparent and that'll do what the people want.
Speaker 0: We need change.
Speaker 0: We need things to be better than they were before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: I pick up it one ad for County Executive and the other ad for County Executive.
Speaker 1: the two different guys right.
Speaker 1: one guy says I'm gonna keep taxes low.
Speaker 1: The other guy says I'm gonna lower taxes.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: What's my choice?
Speaker 0: What choice do I have?
Speaker 1: What if I want to raise taxes?
Speaker 1: I have no one to vote for and that's the problem.
Speaker 0: I do want to raise taxes.
Speaker 1: I've decided mostly because I don't pay them directly.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not just that.
Speaker 0: I mean this area actually Alright little bit of history in New York State.
Speaker 0: there is often the kind of conflict between New York City Which is the majority of the population of the entire state and the entire rest of the state.
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: in terms of the fact that generally New York City kind of funds development everywhere else in New York State and like At
Speaker 1: the same time everywhere else in the state provides food and water for the city
Speaker 0: Even though New York could probably just buy it off from China if they wanted
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 1: but then we'd get much shittier food and shittier water.
Speaker 1: But the thing is New York City has the best tap water.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm not saying oh, New York City shouldn't subsidize these things.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying that New York City kind of does.
Speaker 0: and the economy of New York City and the taxes New York Tend to be distributed is why New York works is because you have one city one big city.
Speaker 1: You have some other cities, but not so many and they're not really that big.
Speaker 1: Well considering like I think Yonkers is the second biggest city and you've got a whole lot of just open land.
Speaker 1: That's not really city.
Speaker 1: that's more rural.
Speaker 1: that basically powers all the city.
Speaker 0: I mean, we've got big cities at the other end of the state, but they're so far away that I'm not gonna Yeah, and Buffalo really not much of a city compared to I don't know Manhattan Compared to the Bronx.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's just cuz.
Speaker 0: New York City is a gigantic monster.
Speaker 0: That's beside the point.
Speaker 0: the politics of New York State Tend to oscillate between two states two Conditions either They're taking money from the city and throwing it furiously into improvement projects in the state Or they're trying to cut those programs as fast as they can because they think they need to send that money back to New York City.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: But lately a lot that there's been this idea that a lot of the money has been going into very specific Targeted I guess local improve improvement programs mostly along the Hudson River, which is where we live.
Speaker 1: Well, it's those ones we notice cuz that's where we live.
Speaker 1: well
Speaker 0: actually the Hudson Valley improvement projects have been taking a great deal of money and part of that is because there's a lot of state money put aside anyway for you know rivers and estuaries and drinking water and tourism and also there's a lot of federal money for that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: and Beacon and all these cities along the river.
Speaker 0: well at least the ones that are doing it right have actually been using this money and Improving like markedly and the economy in upstate New York and by upstate I mean the Mid Hudson Valley.
Speaker 0: in the Hudson Valley has been going gangbusters Lately not relative to what it was relative to what it was ten years ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it's not like oh man's everything here is awesome.
Speaker 1: But then again, it was a shithole a while ago and now it's not.
Speaker 0: So the thing is it seems that in this area the the increase of civil services and basic You know city services has been very pointedly improving the economy.
Speaker 0: It has indeed and I am of the mind that we should spend more money to improve Local infrastructure while we currently have the money and the liberty to do so and while I live here and it like commuter infrastructure Everything I want Metro north to get more money.
Speaker 0: I want there to be more buses and local transit.
Speaker 1: I want everything that makes my life better to happen.
Speaker 1: Yes, I agree.
Speaker 0: There's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's not just I want these things.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to pay for them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I already pay for them.
Speaker 1: I'm
Speaker 0: willing to pay more to get more because they have proven that in this in this one instance in this one little area in This one little state in America More taxes is turned into better services that were worth the money We spent
Speaker 1: kind of for the most part.
Speaker 0: But the problem is every single candidate for every position except the judges who didn't campaign for jack all.
Speaker 0: I felt bad about that Because I actually wanted to vote for them, but it's like voting for the judge might matter.
Speaker 1: But the judges didn't campaign so I didn't know which judges stood for what at all.
Speaker 0: But there was no candidate that advocated anything like that.
Speaker 0: They either advocated lowering taxes or not raising taxes.
Speaker 1: Wow, there's a big difference.
Speaker 0: and on every other issue They were silent like literally there was nothing to differentiate candidates other than one was a really old man And one was a slightly less old man with slightly worse policies.
Speaker 0: and by worse policies I mean he wanted to lower taxes instead of not raising them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was really no way.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's like that, you know in a much smaller town I could maybe know these people You know and be able or if I was you know Not a commuter and I was actually able to participate in the town.
Speaker 1: cuz this thing the biggest problem with town politics The only people who can participate are people stay home all day or people who work in town.
Speaker 1: You know like most of the guys running like one of the guys Owned an insurance company on Main Street Another guy owned a real estate company on the other side of town is the people who work in town live in town stay in Town all day can do town things, you know people who commute but happen to live here.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much impossible.
Speaker 1: Sure, they keep the polls open and I can vote which is good I guess you know sort of necessary But I don't really.
Speaker 1: I can't really do much in the town because I'm not here most of the day even though I live here So I can't really get involved.
Speaker 1: I can't run for anything I can't really know these people or get to know them and it generally sucks.
Speaker 1: I mean these people came to our houses like one time.
Speaker 1: I came and I went to the front door and there was a piece Of paper that said, you know, I was here basically and one of the people running for mayor had stopped at the door.
Speaker 1: But but I didn't.
Speaker 0: I was like one o'clock on a weekday clearly doesn't want to talk to the commuters clearly wanted to talk to Homemakers nothing more because no one is gonna be home at one o'clock in a commuter town except homemakers.
Speaker 1: In fact, it was crazy that it actually happened on one day.
Speaker 1: I happened to be home from work, but I was in the shower.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he came by while I was home from work when I took that week off before my new job and I was a different guy.
Speaker 0: I think I didn't even hear anyone knock.
Speaker 1: I think that guy was running for like, you know County like counsel?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think the problem was I wanted later.
Speaker 0: I wanted to vote I wanted to be active in local politics and then upon investigating no candidate stood for anything.
Speaker 1: No, they were all.
Speaker 1: just I want to make the town better.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make vote for me.
Speaker 1: vote for me.
Speaker 0: on one hand I have taken very little issue like the only Complaint I saw like Quimby on The Simpsons.
Speaker 0: the only complaint I had about our local government and what goes on Had nothing to do with the elected people.
Speaker 0: It was a referendum and I just think the people in the city voted stupidly.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean there was a referendum some sort of you know question to vote on this time.
Speaker 1: But I went in the booth and it was like something something Lake something reservoir something something I'm like.
Speaker 1: I read it and I understood what it was saying But I had no idea the places it was talking about.
Speaker 1: it was like Do you want to start getting water from this lake and stop getting water from that lake and remove state funding for this?
Speaker 1: But get state funding for that and give this to the state.
Speaker 1: But then the state will give this to us.
Speaker 1: and I was like, I don't know enough about it I'm just not gonna vote on that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one publicized it So we didn't even know it was gonna be on the ballot.
Speaker 0: So I didn't have time to do research.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I guess I could find out about this stuff from the local newspaper.
Speaker 0: the last two referendums We had one was should we raise taxes and then make Metro north and you know New York City transit super big in the state.
Speaker 1: and everyone said no no god No, even though I said, yes, I'm probably the only we're about the only two people who said yes Maybe I mean I could find about this local paper But I had to pay money to find out what's going on in my town.
Speaker 0: And the other one was let's spend millions of taxpayer money To buy land that people are trying to put houses on and not let them put houses on it because we don't want too many People to move to our city.
Speaker 1: I want more things here.
Speaker 1: more things is better things.
Speaker 1: I like things.
Speaker 1: I like people.
Speaker 1: I want more people here.
Speaker 0: You don't like people.
Speaker 0: you hate people.
Speaker 0: you come.
Speaker 0: you do nothing would complain about people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I want more of them.
Speaker 0: That must be your DNA.
Speaker 0: Apollo's song Maybe.
Speaker 1: but you know a town with more people means more demand for services Which means more services.
Speaker 0: and also more people means a greater variety of services and then competition over that market Which means better services.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean the biggest problem in beak.
Speaker 0: I mean Here's the real problem.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not a problem.
Speaker 1: No grocery store.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say that but beacons doing great.
Speaker 0: The thing is regardless of the fact that these people like there was no reason for me to vote for one person over the other Beacons been generally getting better.
Speaker 0: So I'm not angry to the point if I should run for an office or actually Do something risky to try to change things or be super loud about anything.
Speaker 0: But at the same time there are things that could be better that just don't get better Because no one cares with me and if
Speaker 1: I want to do something about it I'm screwed because I'm a commuter who spends four hours a week podcasting though
Speaker 0: Actually, Scott and I are really thinking about as soon as we get time maybe over the holidays We'll set this up of forming a local political action committee.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll see designed specifically for commuters and will advertise at the train station.
Speaker 0: And then basically all we want to do is get a list of I guess Grievances and desires from all the commuters in the city and then present that to the city government.
Speaker 0: You know like like here are the top three priorities for commuters.
Speaker 0: There are this many of us will vote in a block.
Speaker 1: All right I think I kind of want to end this now because I can get a good food neat and we got to keep it Sure, but in general I think the thing is ideally.
Speaker 1: we local politics are cool and having you know A federated government is awesome and we want to be involved and we want to be active in in controlling the destiny of our town and The the quality of our lives and the place that we live, but it's incredibly just kind of crappy And it's not really.
Speaker 0: I'll end on this because this is the important thing other than a little tidbit.
Speaker 0: A lot of people have told me this over the years, but now I've seen it firsthand.
Speaker 0: generally locally in the US Republicans and Democrats are Reversed.
Speaker 1: are they really?
Speaker 0: it's like if you want the stuff that Democrats want nationally That's the same thing that Republicans want locally and vice-versa.
Speaker 1: Well, it kind of makes sense because Republicans are all about you know - theoretically on paper It's they're more states rights, you know more local power less federal power and Democrats are more federal power less local power.
Speaker 1: So if you really want just a more powerful government across the board if you vote for Republicans in your state and your town And you vote for Democrats in the federal place Then you're just gonna get a more powerful government in every possible location.
Speaker 0: on paper think of that what you will.
Speaker 1: Yeah on paper though.
Speaker 1: That's not the way it really turns out Yeah, but that's the way it is in the social studies textbook, which it does not match.
Speaker 1: reality
Speaker 0: But - I decided after getting a phone call from a fucking Autodialer that how I was gonna vote because it didn't matter anymore at any rate was just I was gonna keep track of any candidate that called me with an Autodialer on my cell phone and just not vote for them.
Speaker 0: and by the time the election came Every single candidate for every single office except the judges had called me with an autodialer and left some stupid message Yep, mostly telling me about how bad the other candidate was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I went into the voting booth.
Speaker 1: I clicked like one box for one guy that I remembered and then I pulled the lever.
Speaker 1: I voted one vote for one guy and that was it.
Speaker 0: I went and I was gonna do a protest vote.
Speaker 0: either I was gonna write in myself or I was gonna vote for no one.
Speaker 1: just pulled the lever and pulled lever again.
Speaker 0: But the reason I didn't was by the time I got there There was like a half-hour line to vote and I wasn't gonna stand there for a half-hour to do nothing.
Speaker 1: No, I wasn't gonna do that.
Speaker 0: So I went home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I there wasn't a line when I went.
Speaker 1: I just went pulled lever click pulled lever.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: I actually spent a minute in there reading the stupid referendum that I didn't vote on.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.