Speaker 1: It's Thursday, June 28th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We discuss sports steroids and spectators.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So pretty much everything interesting that happened to me today happened in the last 10 minutes of my day And then my commute home.
Speaker 0: so before that not exciting before that not exciting normal work stuff going around.
Speaker 0: Just before I'm about to leave I'm talking to one guy who I'm working with more and more because generally I don't have many Social relations or interactions on any level with the vast majority of my co-workers.
Speaker 0: it's just the nature of my work.
Speaker 0: and I end up talking to this guy who I've been talking to bit by bit and I mean it's turned out that he went to RIT way back and all sorts of little things.
Speaker 0: He's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And I discover pretty much right before I got to go catch my train That he's an anime fan and not just you know, oh I've heard of anime.
Speaker 0: or oh I saw a cowboy bebop but yeah Second gig his old hat.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So as much as I wanted to talk to him after talking to him for a few minutes I realized that I'd been lingering too long and I know I had five minutes to make it to the train station a mile away.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Well, uh, I made it there in six minutes and Luckily the train was slightly late.
Speaker 0: I got.
Speaker 0: you know I get to the platform and I run up and I'm like and I see the train coming in the distance and I think wow Holy shit, I can't believe I made it cuz.
Speaker 0: I was still wearing my business clothes.
Speaker 0: It totally sucked.
Speaker 0: So I'm standing there and I'm watching the train come and I think wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Something doesn't look right.
Speaker 0: It looks like the trains going to the other platform.
Speaker 0: then I look to the right away from where the trains coming and I see that on the little electronic display it says track change.
Speaker 0: So now I have to run a flight of stairs up across that thing a flight of stairs down.
Speaker 0: I barely made it Totally sucked.
Speaker 0: So now I stagger out of this train completely covered in sweat just dripping.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: The people on the train look at you funny.
Speaker 0: Uh, not really I know.
Speaker 0: one seems to react to anything that happens on a train these days.
Speaker 0: I mean someone could get up and just start screaming I'm gonna kill all the whiteies and the blackies and I'm crazy.
Speaker 0: I think someone would say shut up the most you get is an angry glare.
Speaker 0: It's so rare for someone to even tell someone loud to shut up.
Speaker 0: Usually they just clarify them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've had people shut him up before.
Speaker 1: It takes quite a loudmouth to get that like.
Speaker 1: so.
Speaker 1: one time there was a cell phone lady who just wouldn't shut up and then people were just like the whole train like woke up and started looking at each other and then Finally, you know, wow It was.
Speaker 0: it was guys kind of like an ad hoc subtle election where everyone kind of eventually elects one person.
Speaker 0: Who's gonna be the spokesperson for the mob?
Speaker 0: Yep, so get on the train sit down.
Speaker 0: Realize at that moment that I had left my 10-trip ticket.
Speaker 0: in my book is a bookmark that I just finished the book.
Speaker 0: So I left the book in my office.
Speaker 0: Haha.
Speaker 1: The winner is you.
Speaker 0: so the guy comes by and I'm like I forgot my ticket and he says it's cool.
Speaker 0: I'll hit you next time.
Speaker 0: Yep, I was like, whoa.
Speaker 1: Wow, really and he came back and hit you the next and hit you.
Speaker 0: Well, no, no No, I mean tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna show him my 10 trip.
Speaker 0: He's gonna take an extra one off.
Speaker 1: Oh Usually when they say hit you next time.
Speaker 1: It means they're gonna go down the rest of the train then come back and get the people who didn't get ticketed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now there's almost no one on that train for some reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I must have just been lucky.
Speaker 1: Maybe me cuz the track change everyone got fooled.
Speaker 0: Then I'm coming home around the train and I get up.
Speaker 0: cuz I got.
Speaker 0: but the station we're at where we live beacons getting bigger and bigger and bigger and more and more people are getting on and off at beacon and There's two ways from the train platform to the parking lot.
Speaker 0: one is a tunnel that goes under the tracks and one is this big elevated thing that goes above the tracks and pretty much you have to get up and stand there for five minutes in the train just to be close enough to a door to Have a chance of getting to those things and getting halfway up them before the fat people get there.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the fuck is wrong with these fat people.
Speaker 1: I really need to get some sort of system.
Speaker 1: We're like, okay Anyone who's going to run can go first and then the people who are gonna walk slow is ass.
Speaker 0: very simply You know stay to the right or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: It's funny like the train gets off and you'll see like the 20 spry young cool people Who push their way past the fat people and then run up and down this thing and get in their cars their bikes and get Away before all the fat people get there.
Speaker 0: when I say fat people.
Speaker 0: I mean a good 70% of the people on this train Oh, yeah, they're.
Speaker 1: if they're not fat.
Speaker 1: They might be old.
Speaker 1: They're at least overweight They're all over.
Speaker 1: where the people with the wheelie luggage or I don't get the people with the wheelie luggage because they're carrying less than I am are people some people they kept the wheelie luggage.
Speaker 1: That's just full of lots of unnecessary shit that they don't need that shit.
Speaker 1: And then he got people with like a baby in a stroller.
Speaker 1: And what all these people carrying too much shit need to get out of the way.
Speaker 0: me with my little bag.
Speaker 0: damn, baby It's right.
Speaker 0: but It's funny because you see all this Smart quick people run and get to this thing and get up and get out of the way and get out before the traffic and the fat people in the man.
Speaker 0: But if you don't get there before this crush of fat people gets there You basically have to stand there forever while fat people very slowly trudge up these steps Huffing and puffing the whole way and then just kind of block the whole thing huffing puffing their way back down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm standing on the train.
Speaker 1: it shouldn't be illegal for me to push those fat people down the stairs.
Speaker 0: How are you going to push them?
Speaker 0: their momentum alone will keep them stationary for a good five minutes.
Speaker 1: Well, you see I just go and I if I can get past him.
Speaker 1: I just lean backwards.
Speaker 1: They won't that.
Speaker 1: I'll add just enough force that they won't be able to make one step up.
Speaker 1: So their only choice will be to take a step down Or stand still and I'm sure they'll just be as soon as if they're.
Speaker 1: if they don't lower their center of gravity They'll topple pretty easily.
Speaker 0: I don't know Scott.
Speaker 0: Nothing moves the blob Except Cyclops who moves him very easily.
Speaker 1: He just pushed one button.
Speaker 1: They falls down.
Speaker 0: Nothing moves up.
Speaker 0: No, no, nothing moves that and then you win.
Speaker 0: Yep So, uh, I'm standing there in front of all the fat people though They're pressing in.
Speaker 0: I can see him like crush crushed up against the door to the area between the cars Like trying to get in and get in front of me so they can be all slow and then the train Slows down and we're not at the station yet and then it gets real
Speaker 1: slows down some.
Speaker 1: no No, it's up.
Speaker 0: It really slows down and they're just been a big thunderstorm.
Speaker 0: So I'm thinking crap now I'm gonna be stuck here on the train with fat people in every direction.
Speaker 0: there's no way to get out of where I'm standing now because the fat people can't move and People start grumbling because it's all you know the cool young live people standing in this area trying to get ahead.
Speaker 0: so they're all like Train delayed something fall on the tracks.
Speaker 0: This totally sucks from grumble grumble rabble rabble rabble.
Speaker 0: and then someone says oh man Look out the window.
Speaker 0: So I look to the right and there's the road I normally drive home on there and there's a gigantic accident Consisting of one car that is completely blocked the road in both directions.
Speaker 0: The winner is that guy something SUV Just must have been going too fast and flipped his car over like ten times and Hit the the rocks and hit it hit a lot of things and I don't think anyone survived.
Speaker 1: How similar is this though?
Speaker 1: You have the fat guy Blocking the stairs so you can't pass and you have the SUV Blocking the road, you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's almost poetic I it puts me one step closer to believing that maybe there's some meaning in it all.
Speaker 1: maybe there's some karmic justice out there Or maybe just people create that with their minds.
Speaker 0: or maybe Large things are generally bothersome unless they're giant robots.
Speaker 1: Yeah giant robots wouldn't block any pads.
Speaker 1: They would just open up Like through the middle of the earth or around Mars something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah get to the train station.
Speaker 0: I get past all the fat people.
Speaker 0: Pretty much the moment the train door opens it starts pouring rain.
Speaker 1: I had my umbrella cuz I checked the weather.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my umbrella is really gonna help me when I'm riding my bike.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's your problem.
Speaker 1: That's why I drove.
Speaker 0: see I don't really mind getting wet.
Speaker 0: It was just slightly annoying that the weather decided to bust out at that exact moment.
Speaker 0: It could have waited five minutes.
Speaker 0: It could have done it five minutes earlier.
Speaker 0: The fact that it started right when I got there was the kicker.
Speaker 0: Hey, that's it you get and now I'm home and I'm wearing silk and I'm dry and I'm happy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got to take a shower didn't take one this morning.
Speaker 1: I woke up late.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I noticed you woke up late.
Speaker 0: How are you blood?
Speaker 0: you went to bed early.
Speaker 1: no, I didn't.
Speaker 0: well you went to your room early, that's right.
Speaker 1: What did you do in there?
Speaker 1: I was I was installed Linux's on my desktop.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: That could have waited.
Speaker 1: I don't use my desktop so much anymore.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait a minute, so not only could it have waited, but you don't even use that computer.
Speaker 1: That's why it's okay.
Speaker 1: Linux's on it.
Speaker 1: Wait.
Speaker 0: Wait, I don't use it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so that's why I for went to the sleep I needed in order to upgrade it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was just you know, trying out some distributions.
Speaker 1: cuz if I don't use the computer, what does it matter?
Speaker 0: We're gonna be home this weekend.
Speaker 0: We got nothing to do except prepare for Connecticut.
Speaker 0: I got to do that this weekend instead and play tigers and Euphrates Hey a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: Yeah and teach Pete how to play power grid and all the other games.
Speaker 1: We just bought.
Speaker 0: So, yes, that was the saga.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to get to work tomorrow to talk more to this guy about anime because he recognized the names of anime.
Speaker 1: Amazing someone who is connected to the world.
Speaker 0: I mean previous to this point the most connected person I had met in my working life meaning at any job I had ever had outside of when I worked at that sub shop with Alex back when we lived at our IT.
Speaker 1: I bet you there are more connected people at the sub shop RIT students.
Speaker 0: Oh, definitely definitely definitely.
Speaker 0: but The previously most connected person liked anime a little bit because of his son and he'd seen cowboy bebop and really liked it Not the Korean guy.
Speaker 1: Ah, he knew about the metal girl.
Speaker 0: Well the metal girl.
Speaker 0: I don't work with her I just know her through work.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: She's not really a co-worker.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and it's not the metal girl It's a whole metal department.
Speaker 0: It's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: It's like this one enclave of cool transfer to the metal department.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to work in that department.
Speaker 0: That's not a technical department.
Speaker 0: I'd be doing paperwork metal paperwork No metal work.
Speaker 0: They can only listen to the metal when one of the bosses isn't there which is kind of often.
Speaker 0: But whenever that boss is there, it's a totally different office and everyone's just a busy busy worker be.
Speaker 0: Thank God, it's Friday.
Speaker 1: Someone's got a case of the Mondays?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Can't complain too much.
Speaker 0: My job's not so bad compared to what my job could be.
Speaker 1: Ah my job Yeah, fuck you Don't get.
Speaker 1: don't work at shitty places.
Speaker 1: That's that was how I got.
Speaker 1: I just know how to work anywhere.
Speaker 1: That wasn't at least moderately cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, part of the issue is IT is a different field from CS.
Speaker 1: We got IT guys one one IT guy one IT guy.
Speaker 0: There's no more IT openings like that.
Speaker 0: that are good.
Speaker 1: I think you're smarter than he is, but he knows more about windows than both of us combined.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, well, I could get his job.
Speaker 0: I applied for a fairly senior position at my company internally.
Speaker 0: cuz I want.
Speaker 0: I don't want to stop doing what I'm doing now But I'm doing now.
Speaker 0: I could teach any one of you out there how to do my job in about a week.
Speaker 0: It's not that tough, but they pay really well, which is kind of weird.
Speaker 0: But I applied for some big tech position and I get it.
Speaker 0: I'm the job would be trivial to do But I don't have any Cisco certs.
Speaker 0: So we'll see where that goes, yep, I might just get the stupid Cisco cert.
Speaker 0: It would probably take a week of studying and then pay the whatever hundred bucks to take the stupid test.
Speaker 1: That's the thing that really bothers me.
Speaker 1: is you got to pay to take the tests.
Speaker 1: They what they should.
Speaker 1: it would be fine If it was just pay to take classes.
Speaker 1: taking the test is you know, like a minimal fee just like 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: But let's pay to take the test.
Speaker 1: it should be.
Speaker 1: you're testing to see if I'm smart enough.
Speaker 1: Why should I have to pay to take the test?
Speaker 0: because they're not to do.
Speaker 0: they're not testing the classes.
Speaker 0: They're not testing to see if you're smart enough.
Speaker 0: if you're getting a Cisco certification You're paying to give them money.
Speaker 0: Cisco makes a lot of money off of that.
Speaker 1: Yep That's why it's all.
Speaker 0: a lot of people make a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Certification right test that only costs like 10 bucks to take and then just charge money for the class.
Speaker 0: You know that kind of gives me an idea.
Speaker 1: and then we'll say we'll market it to all the businesses like hey This is a real certification.
Speaker 1: It's basically it's not about paying money to a company.
Speaker 1: It's about determining if your employees actually knows what the fuck they're talking.
Speaker 0: You know that gives me a much more interesting and fun idea that doesn't require much investment.
Speaker 0: Yeah Why don't we you and me?
Speaker 0: write the geek nights test to certify if you are or are not a Useless person or a crappy person or something like that.
Speaker 0: the awesome test the are you awesome test and we'll administer it online And we'll set something up and if you pass it, I guess you only get to take it once maybe once every year.
Speaker 0: We could set it up.
Speaker 0: then you're so officially certified people.
Speaker 1: They might use the Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: if we you know We got a maybe we could like administer it at cons at our table or something.
Speaker 0: That'd be a pretty good idea.
Speaker 1: People couldn't use the Internet's.
Speaker 1: it would just be are you awesome in that case?
Speaker 0: We could have an interview portion.
Speaker 0: Ooh Yeah, people could walk around you even sell the shirt.
Speaker 1: Rimmins got like if you pass the test then you get like a certified Button that says like certified the button.
Speaker 0: if someone I say we make the test difficult enough to where?
Speaker 0: if people pass it one Automatically our friend.
Speaker 0: No questions asked.
Speaker 0: Member of the crew to diploma three t-shirt.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I guess t-shirt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I took this test and all I got You can't pass 10 tests.
Speaker 0: All right, that's enough of that.
Speaker 0: So in the news, I'll start first because this this has been festering for a long time.
Speaker 0: I know we have a lot of international listeners and I know a lot of our international listeners understand the The difficulties faced by the American politician and the American people abroad in the last I don't know several years.
Speaker 0: Well internally things are actually heating up and there is what might be a looming constitutional crisis in the United States.
Speaker 0: Aha Basically what it comes down to is that the US government is set up into three separate branches that Nominally are equal in power and each one has some control over the other two.
Speaker 0: Thus it is very difficult to actually fully take over the US government Because no matter what the odds are one of the three branches is gonna hold out long enough For whoever's in power to lose power or die or whatever and it generally keeps the system going.
Speaker 0: well, uh Congress has power over the executive branch a number of ways and due to some improprieties that have happened in the last several years Congress has been subpoenaing many people and documents and demanding sworn testimony from members of the executive branch the president's office and Those people basically gave Congress the finger and said no executive privilege.
Speaker 0: We're not testifying for shit We're not giving you our documents.
Speaker 0: dine of fire.
Speaker 1: They have to.
Speaker 0: yeah, they do have to or else that's contempt.
Speaker 0: So now the deadline has passed and it's too late.
Speaker 0: It happened and Congress is going to jail.
Speaker 0: well, we don't know.
Speaker 0: yet Congress is saying well, uh, we're probably gonna slap you all with contempt and It looks like the White House might say under what authority?
Speaker 1: The authority of the Congress of the United States of America.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but to quote one of my What the moat?
Speaker 0: I have very ambivalent feelings about this.
Speaker 0: and Jackson John Marshall has made his decision.
Speaker 0: now, let's see him enforce it.
Speaker 1: and with his federal marshals He does.
Speaker 1: that doesn't happen so much that the feds nobody has testicles the law Totally supports.
Speaker 0: the federal marshals didn't really go.
Speaker 0: well, they didn't exist back then I don't think.
Speaker 0: but they didn't go over and stop Andrew Jackson's Indian genocide.
Speaker 1: No, they didn't.
Speaker 1: but they could have stopped him if they really wanted to.
Speaker 0: they just didn't know how what John Marshall is gonna Go stand in front of him on the battlefield.
Speaker 0: He just showed him.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think he would have.
Speaker 1: I think he would have Jackson would have but no one else would.
Speaker 0: yeah, but it was Andrew Jackson.
Speaker 0: That's why it happened.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they could have had someone arrest them, you know, if the president Someone arrests him.
Speaker 0: He had an army with him.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah ready if the president right now Let's say George Bush right now went and robbed a bank, right?
Speaker 1: All right, someone arrests him.
Speaker 1: who would do that?
Speaker 0: Uh, Probably no one.
Speaker 1: someone arrests him.
Speaker 0: He goes to jail not so much not above the law.
Speaker 1: He follows the same laws as everyone else.
Speaker 0: You have to be impeached first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could get arrested and go to jail.
Speaker 0: then you would have to be convicted in in the impeachment proceedings And then no impeachment would just be to make him no longer the president.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but you'd be the president.
Speaker 1: It's not jail.
Speaker 0: impeachment just means you're bringing the charges.
Speaker 0: you then have to go through the whole process.
Speaker 1: Like if he robbed a bank and didn't get impeached he could theoretically be in jail.
Speaker 1: Guilty of robbing bank.
Speaker 1: I'll still be president.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna argue because I don't want to extend the news long, but that's not what would happen.
Speaker 1: I think that could happen.
Speaker 1: Uh, you continue to think I don't think it would happen But I think that's that's the way I read it read.
Speaker 0: lawyer What what what clauses would you cite in this assessment?
Speaker 1: Scott law number one rob bank.
Speaker 1: go to jail.
Speaker 1: Law number two Constitution.
Speaker 1: if the Congress wants to remove someone from office because they did X Y or Z. they do X Y and Z. Well a B and C.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: What I was saying was they can't do anything to him until they remove him from office.
Speaker 1: I think you can now Someone's in office doesn't make them immune to going to jail for crimes.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'll just let that stand.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is gonna be a big issue because it looks like no one's really sure how to proceed.
Speaker 0: Congress is gonna do what they're gonna do and the White House is probably just gonna continue to ignore him and The courts are gonna have to decide and no one can really say where the court will swing.
Speaker 0: This could end in a big uproar followed by nothing or it could end in the possible arrest of several high members of the United States government Generally.
Speaker 1: and because how many times this happened already in the past eight years where?
Speaker 1: and it was oh my god Oh my god, oh my god, and then nothing's changed.
Speaker 0: things did change.
Speaker 0: Scooter Libby is going to jail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's Scooter Libby who cares and those investigations are still ongoing and a bunch of other people have gone to jail for things With the Abramov scandal.
Speaker 0: It's all still happening just behind the scenes.
Speaker 0: The press doesn't cover it a lot because it's very boring and it's not really changing anything that much.
Speaker 1: We're still in the same shit.
Speaker 1: We've always been in.
Speaker 0: oh, so you you don't even pay attention to politics.
Speaker 0: No reason for that.
Speaker 0: cuz shit don't change but things do change.
Speaker 1: what just slowly over time too slowly to make a difference?
Speaker 0: Uh, it's making a difference.
Speaker 0: now The presidency is having less and less actual power to do what they're doing because we voted for Democrats in Congress.
Speaker 0: It's not just that because the Democrats don't alone don't have the power to just change things.
Speaker 1: No, but they the Republicans no longer have the power to keep doing more bad things.
Speaker 1: Yeah And that's why.
Speaker 0: well the issue at stake here is that they were doing the things they were doing anyway Because the presidency was just doing it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and Congress doesn't didn't really have the power to stop him the way things were going.
Speaker 0: now Congress is saying All right, we're stopping you and he said you can't.
Speaker 1: oh It's not gonna work.
Speaker 0: Well, we don't know if it.
Speaker 0: if that's not gonna work Scott Then this is going to be a big crisis because a bunch of key people are gonna go to jail.
Speaker 0: Otherwise it is gonna work and then like you said nothing changes in which case what you just said was wrong.
Speaker 0: So which is it?
Speaker 1: I think it's not gonna be.
Speaker 0: What do you think it's gonna?
Speaker 0: well, that's such a cop-out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz really either way it goes.
Speaker 1: It's not really gonna Bother me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're saying that you you were excited about fits miss.
Speaker 0: I don't think you're saying that you would.
Speaker 0: yes You were you acted like.
Speaker 0: you're gonna say that you wouldn't care if half of the president's cabinet or his advisors all went to jail.
Speaker 0: All right, so then he's gonna get away with it.
Speaker 1: and you know what.
Speaker 1: until it does happen I don't care.
Speaker 1: Okay, everything before the news that says everyone goes to jail is just BS news.
Speaker 1: It's just something might happen.
Speaker 1: I don't care about something might happen.
Speaker 1: news Remember I was talking before about the countdowns and the video game websites.
Speaker 1: I don't care until it's there's a news like people are in jail or something's changed.
Speaker 1: There's a huge deal.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: I don't care about what might be.
Speaker 1: I don't care about what could be.
Speaker 1: I don't care about something may be happening.
Speaker 1: I care about happenings.
Speaker 1: That's all I care about.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: what I would say is that because of that you often ignore a lot of news or a lot of things out there and as a result you end up having a very Narrow world view and that you don't know a lot about a lot of things that
Speaker 1: don't affect me
Speaker 0: that it might be useful to Know about them in order to have a greater understanding of the way Politics and the economy and everything interact as a whole.
Speaker 1: but I don't need to know about those things nor do I care.
Speaker 1: I need to know about geeky things.
Speaker 1: Okay, I've decided that it's just not worth it to pay attention to all that bullshit and because it all it does detract from my Everyday life all I really want is that how does it detract from your everyday life?
Speaker 0: to be more?
Speaker 0: Knowledgeable about the processes in the government.
Speaker 1: every minute I spend thinking about that bullshit is one less minute of geeky awesomeness.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to maximum.
Speaker 1: all I want see if they let's say the government was just running perfectly and smoothly with no problems Right, which is what I would want Then I would pretty much spend all my days doing geeky awesomeness and not thinking about you
Speaker 0: realize That's one more step toward being a nerd because you're narrowing your knowledge of the world willingly.
Speaker 0: Hey, I know enough about what's going on, you know, correct?
Speaker 0: I remember and I hate to bring this up on the show But I do want to point out that there was a fairly heated debate a long time ago in the forums that predated this Where Scott asserted?
Speaker 0: Seriously that the Romans got the ideas for their battle tactics and their swords and their armor from the Knights of the Middle Ages.
Speaker 0: Hey, so and it took quite a bit of convincing to show him that that was not the case.
Speaker 1: That's one problem I always had in history class is that they would always teach you about these different points in history Like we're gonna teach you about this.
Speaker 1: No one ever in any history class ever took told me what order all these different parts of history happened.
Speaker 0: You know, you know those numbers that they occasionally threw out.
Speaker 1: No That's the thing is that in all my years of school like our entire school system had a thing where there was absolutely no Memorization ever.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm not saying memorization, but they'd still say no They never.
Speaker 1: they would just complete say years don't you know, don't worry about what year things happened in.
Speaker 1: That was the way my school taught things.
Speaker 1: Well one that my entire Trumbull public school system because they wanted to get away from that, you know Stereotypical history class like what year did X happen?
Speaker 1: in what year?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: that seems silly and - I highly doubt that even if they didn't say years that you I mean, how could you have not?
Speaker 0: Understood some basic level of what came before what they never told us ever?
Speaker 1: So then you're saying you didn't learn anything about the middle and also even if I let's say I didn't even know the Middle Ages Happened right now Wouldn't really affect my life.
Speaker 1: I'd still be alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's why I'm saying that you have a very narrow and somewhat sad worldview.
Speaker 1: as a result now my worldview is pretty Better than the vast majority of people on this earth.
Speaker 1: You're stepping toward becoming another to know these complicated details of things.
Speaker 1: It is no basically what's going on and that's good enough for me.
Speaker 0: however I would say that your lack of general knowledge of the world often leaves you in a situation where you can't effectively argue your points Because you can't draw analogies or parallels with other people regarding the events.
Speaker 0: You're trying to argue about currently like what?
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get into that.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh That's all I thought.
Speaker 0: well I'll say it like this in general when we argue in the front row crew and I among our friends.
Speaker 0: It is exceedingly rare that anyone agrees with you on any points.
Speaker 1: people agree with me all the time.
Speaker 1: It's just when they agree with me.
Speaker 1: They usually isn't an argument.
Speaker 1: So if there's an argument, but it's probably something to disagree on when has there been a time in the past?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Seven years where there wasn't an argument at least two or three in a given day.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we've gone on about that for a while.
Speaker 0: So what's your news?
Speaker 1: My news is that some people are yet again Bringing up the bullshit rumor that there's gonna be some sort of Led Zeppelin reunion something something but John Bonham's dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, the the rumor always is is that his son will play the drums instead of him because he's dead, but it's not him I know But I you know are there?
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: I assumed at least some of them are still alive.
Speaker 0: I'd stop paying attention to Led Zeppelin a lifetime ago.
Speaker 1: consists of Jimmy Page John Paul Jones The the deceased John Bonham and Robert Plant.
Speaker 1: Okay bottom is the drummer.
Speaker 1: So only the drummer is dead and his son knows how to play the.
Speaker 1: Joe wasn't sure.
Speaker 0: it is a lot.
Speaker 0: I wasn't sure who was still alive.
Speaker 1: only John Bonham is dead.
Speaker 1: He died.
Speaker 1: I think when I was born yeah, and they haven't been together since he died.
Speaker 1: and they're the greatest rock band ever and People always rumor that they're gonna have a reunion because Goddamn with the tickets to that sell out stupidly fast and ha cost like a billion dollars on eBay.
Speaker 1: funny how you say sell out yes, yeah, yeah, and well the rumor yet again is false, of course, but But Tom was.
Speaker 1: one very funny thing is that someone went up and asked Robert Plant about it?
Speaker 1: And he said this is funny.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 1: He said a Plant insisted he hadn't heard anything about the rumored Zeppelin reunion and jokingly added quote If there was one then there wouldn't be enough doctors to support it.
Speaker 1: I thought that was pretty funny.
Speaker 0: It seems like there's been a lot of speculative rumor-mongering lately on.
Speaker 1: well dig Yeah, generally, I think that's you know dig is too democratic and slash.
Speaker 1: that is not democratic enough And I'm not gonna talk about that again.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it is time for none other than the things of the day.
Speaker 0: so apparently in January of 1992 a storm caused a cargo container full of well I'll just leave them as unnamed objects into the ocean where they promptly scattered and disappeared into the ocean currents.
Speaker 0: Alright, these items has four have for the past 15 years been floating about the oceans of the world.
Speaker 0: periodically chunks of them have been making landfall and It's kind of a cool funny story.
Speaker 0: So it's 30,000 floating rubber duckies.
Speaker 0: Apparently they're over the flash 15 years.
Speaker 0: They have eventually become bleached white Some of them sunk.
Speaker 0: many of them were frozen in ice in the Arctic for a very long time as they slowly made their way.
Speaker 1: Kind of weird like if they all started in the same place wouldn't the ocean currents take them to generally the same place?
Speaker 1: And they know it's the majority of they did.
Speaker 0: there's a flotilla of them that has been journeying nearly 17,000 miles.
Speaker 0: it crossed the Arctic Ocean.
Speaker 0: It's been all over the world and Apparently it's heading toward Britain shortly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so is it gonna hit any beaches or something eventually?
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 0: yes, it looks like it is.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna go into the details of where it's gonna hit because we already talked forever but this is a pretty interesting story that you'd fry like to check out and Apparently there's a bounty.
Speaker 0: the company that lost them says that if you find one They'll give you a hundred bucks if you give it back to them.
Speaker 1: Well, if you find the whole flotilla just freaking get a scoop send them back most of them and keep one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well apparently there's a few on eBay right now that sell sold for like 500 pounds and they're kind of collector's items.
Speaker 1: Well, I just take a rubber ducky and bleach it and free and unfreeze it and then sell it on eBay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually I thought about that quite a bit.
Speaker 0: I didn't say anything on the show because I was thinking about doing that.
Speaker 1: Well, let's do it.
Speaker 1: What are people gonna do it say about it?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: They won't be able to put.
Speaker 1: there's no certificate of authenticity.
Speaker 1: Just be like hey, I found this on the beach.
Speaker 1: I think it's one of those ones and put some sand on it and you're good to go.
Speaker 0: actually one cool thing that came out of this is there are groups of scientists that study the ocean currents of the world and They've been keeping track of every time these things made landfall to kind of chart the ocean currents that pushed them around over the last 15 years.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Why did they do this on purpose as a scientific experiment then?
Speaker 0: I think they do things like that on their own.
Speaker 0: this just happened to be a thing So they might as well be it to pay attention to it.
Speaker 1: Sounds good All right My news is equally trivial to that.
Speaker 1: if you've ever watched initial D or if you know anything about cars You might know that there is a car that exists that called the Nissan Skyline GTR.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty badass car.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't want to own one just because it's kind of useless to me, but pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yes, basically this car in short was made in Japan only is not street-legal in the United States.
Speaker 1: However, many people get them brought to Canada then they make they fix them up So they are street-legal in the United States.
Speaker 1: Then they bring them into the United States.
Speaker 1: that cost a lot of money haven't made these cars in a very long time.
Speaker 1: So you're you're buying like a car that's many years old.
Speaker 1: You're not buying a new car here.
Speaker 1: you know all of the most of them are modified and Basically the thing about this car is that it is heavily computerized like literally driving.
Speaker 1: this car is As the same as driving like Gran Turismo.
Speaker 1: the computer keeps you from skidding off and all sorts of stuff and it even shows you like g-forces and It's really really high-tech and it turns a mediocre driver into an amazing driver.
Speaker 1: I mean, you're not gonna go win the rally with this thing because those guys just Colin McRae is still gonna kick your ass or whatever.
Speaker 1: But you're gonna beat all your friends if you buy this car pretty much guaranteed if they don't have one That's unless one of your friends is secretly an awesome drive
Speaker 0: or if you much like Nakazato
Speaker 1: our choke artist Yes, but this car is a freaking awesome amazing car that is greatly coveted by ricers and non ricers everywhere.
Speaker 0: So what's your thing today?
Speaker 0: Is that this car exists?
Speaker 1: Well, no because I knew that There's been people talking for a long time.
Speaker 1: that are they're gonna remake the car They're gonna bring it to the US something something and it's never really happened.
Speaker 0: You know what probably gonna happen right around when Led Zeppelin comes back together?
Speaker 1: Yeah Well at the Goodwood festival of speed.
Speaker 1: the Goodwood festival of speed is basically the world's biggest most baddest car show.
Speaker 1: You know you go to local car shows.
Speaker 1: some guys bring out their classic cars.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Goodwood is like that for the whole world of amazingness and They saw GTR there one of the new awesome ones.
Speaker 1: that isn't available yet.
Speaker 1: So and there's a picture of it right here for you to ogle.
Speaker 1: It's got a bra on the front I think covering up some secrets, but that's definitely a GTR.
Speaker 1: There's no mistake in it.
Speaker 1: You just compare it to what the old GTR looks like and you're like, yep.
Speaker 1: That's what that car is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that definitely has something in common with my first car.
Speaker 0: It has a bra on it Covering something up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, however in my case.
Speaker 0: It wasn't so much secrets, but dense now faded paint and a rust spot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this car doesn't have to worry about that.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if I ever I don't know get more monies or if this car comes out and my car happens to be dead Maybe like by the time my car dies this car will be out and like a little bit old I can get a used one Or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's definitely a very desirable vehicle.
Speaker 1: It's mostly because it's so nerdy with its advanced computer systems.
Speaker 1: Alright, uh For Thursdays, we've been doing kind of air topics.
Speaker 1: I think oh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe not.
Speaker 0: I think they've been okay They've been alright.
Speaker 0: I think the ad topic the ad problem was that the shows we planned to do were always kind of lame and we just filled It in and we'd always like Wednesday night come up with the show.
Speaker 1: We were actually doing every week Yep So I tried to think of something because people have been talking that me and rim do better shows me Disagree.
Speaker 1: most of the shows you've been doing for the past many months have been all agree shows where we're like, yeah this yeah Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I wanted to pick something that we slightly disagree on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's part of the reason we I think the news I picked is we decided to make the show as adversarial as possible.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I think so Scott came up with this dumbass idea for a topic.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not a dumb idea It's crap.
Speaker 1: You saw you're just trying to be adversarial your mom.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right There was that recent news story about that pro wrestler who like killed his family and then killed himself or whatever.
Speaker 1: And I don't know I didn't read the story and nor do I like pro wrestling.
Speaker 1: I could do a show.
Speaker 1: No, why I hate pro wrestling.
Speaker 0: It's weird because that story came up Unrelatedly in a discussion about autism that I was reading on farm autism.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't don't ask I don't know if it's a story where they cured the autism in the rats.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't read the articles about this murder.
Speaker 0: I just knew about it because someone referenced it and they claimed that the Daughter or whoever was killed in addition to all this had mental problems and that might have been part of the reason.
Speaker 1: Well, anyway, like I saw headlines over people's shoulders on newspapers on the train and he was like trying to link You know the steroid use of the pro wrestling guy to the murder somehow and I was like what the fuck How does steroids link to a murder?
Speaker 0: Well Actually, it is possible that it could have been a contributing factor if it is true that he was taking steroids Which we don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure you they found steroids in the house.
Speaker 1: I know that much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there are no pro wrestler does not take steroids.
Speaker 0: There aren't too many people who keep anabolic steroids around, you know, just as a decoration.
Speaker 1: Yep And the that caught the steroids being recently in the news in combination with us recently discussing many times the relationship between good sport and Spectators sport.
Speaker 1: I think we should discuss Steroids and sports because yeah, I know rims opinion differs slightly from mine.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is my opinion is fairly complicated and yes, I don't have an answer opinion.
Speaker 0: I have a. I feel this way in this way in this way in this way.
Speaker 1: Yep well let me summarize the situation here.
Speaker 1: you have a sport and a sport is a competition of athletic ability.
Speaker 1: in some fashion, you know and Basically in a perfect sport, you know as if like if a sport was like a German board game a perfect sport Whoever had the best physical prowess and skill in that particular area Would win and whoever had less physical prowess and skill would win less,
Speaker 0: you know I'd step back a bit and I don't think it necessarily has to be a physical competition.
Speaker 1: It's a sport.
Speaker 1: It's a physical competition.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it's a game.
Speaker 0: I don't make that differentiation.
Speaker 1: Well, we're not gonna argue about semantics.
Speaker 1: No You're not gonna let me pull up the definition in the on the dictionary want to talk about Sport then like sport could be like all sorts of you know, the other definitions of sport Yes, like just having fun.
Speaker 1: You can make sport of something exactly and that's not the kind of sport I'm talking but it's perfectly valid.
Speaker 1: Yes, but that's obviously when you say this is goddamn it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna talk about this now.
Speaker 1: now when someone's some words in the English language have multiple definitions, right?
Speaker 1: Like for example Wake.
Speaker 1: the word wake could mean what.
Speaker 1: you know that thing after before our funeral where you look at the body Also mean wake up in the morning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I say oh it's time to wake up Obviously, I'm using one definition and not the other.
Speaker 1: you can't make a semantic argument claiming that I was using the other definition of.
Speaker 0: however In the case of sport It's very much relevant because you use the word and the definition you arbitrarily chose in order to just eliminate All these other things that other people maybe using the word sport.
Speaker 1: I should say athletic competition every time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 0: No Anyway So I think the only the issue I take is I agree with define a term and then use sport from then on and that's Fine because you can use that definition of sport.
Speaker 0: You can pick a definition and go with it.
Speaker 0: That's how civilized people argue.
Speaker 0: The issue I take is that a lot of people call things that aren't athletic non sport as a way of trivial izing them.
Speaker 1: No, no, just because I don't say that something's trivial because it's not a sport.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: I do recognize most people do make the argument Like that's not a sport like crickets.
Speaker 1: not.
Speaker 1: as for trying to say it's lesser than football.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't say many people I'd say most people.
Speaker 0: Yes There is definitely a negative connotation of game as opposed to sport in the wider American community.
Speaker 0: as a result I will not use the definition you were using of sport because I don't want to play into that.
Speaker 1: I think we see.
Speaker 1: that's exactly why I use my definition of sport to separate things that are Physical from the non-physical because a game like chess, you know is not a sport.
Speaker 1: It's it's a game you play on a table As opposed to a physical thing.
Speaker 1: but the reason is two different words game and sport.
Speaker 0: but yet I would put forth that in the Context of the argument we are about to have and the situation at hand The differentiation doesn't matter because the exact same arguments can be applied to non-physical activities.
Speaker 1: Ah, that is case in point.
Speaker 0: Drugs to increase performance mentally during a chess competition.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I guess all right.
Speaker 0: I have often been known to drink copious amounts of Red Bull before an important board game or some counter-strike.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: All right, we'll do with that now, but basically the thing is I've discovered For him.
Speaker 1: Yes I've discovered recently that if you have a sport and you try you want the sport to be as fair and as true a Competition as possible.
Speaker 1: That's like the spirit within me says let's have the real sport.
Speaker 1: You know Like if you have a like some sort of like if someone makes a bad call Even if it's for the team that I'm not rooting for, you know in their favor or if it's in my team's favor I don't like a bad call because I want the sport to be fair and perfect in some way.
Speaker 1: unless it's hockey unless it's hot You know I want it to be a fair game and I want the best man to win or the best team or the best woman or Best the best side needs to win.
Speaker 0: Yep Now here I think is the biggest issue at stake.
Speaker 0: We're saying the best and you're saying a pure sport.
Speaker 0: But at that point that means that you have to analyze whatever you're trying to test figure out What is the thing you were trying to test in this competition?
Speaker 0: Yeah, are you trying to test purely athletic ability purely skill a mixture of the two?
Speaker 1: Well, you know if you're using hockey you're testing ability to skate skate quickly skate dexterously to handle the puck, you know the puck dexterously to Bump into people and you know have strategic maneuvering of your guys but skill of your goalie at blocking.
Speaker 0: You're also testing teamwork.
Speaker 0: You're testing tactics.
Speaker 0: You're testing the system that allowed the team to buy the players.
Speaker 1: They wanted Yep You're testing all sorts of things and whoever passes the combination of those tests and in you know The greatest fashion should be the winner.
Speaker 1: the problem is when you have a sport that is so perfectly tuned It becomes very quickly Boring to spectate case in point formula one.
Speaker 1: for many years Michael Schumacher the greatest driver of vehicles go motor vehicles to ever live was an f1 racer and he won Just about every time he had the best car.
Speaker 1: He was the best driver.
Speaker 1: He would start most of the races in the front.
Speaker 1: He would take off.
Speaker 1: Nobody could catch him and it was a. it was a very well tuned sport.
Speaker 1: the best person won and the second best guy came In second place just about every time for many many years and it was boring as all hell to watch.
Speaker 0: Yep, well to take hockey or actually I think baseball is a better example because I think great exam.
Speaker 0: I think baseball suffers from it the most and I think this is the sole reason Why I dislike baseball because I realized that I would like baseball a lot more if this weren't the case Yep.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: baseball like hockey the actual competition what it was testing on a base level was a bunch of things Teamwork the ability of batters the ability of pitchers the ability of base coaches the tactics of the team the put the makeup of the team the crowd's effect on the team all these sorts of things, you know dealing with conditions and Over time as baseball was played and played and played and played one by one These issues became moot.
Speaker 0: the tactics of baseball are at this point 99% perfected.
Speaker 0: it's obvious what to do in any given situation.
Speaker 1: The only variable is if you have some sort of incredible player in a certain spot in a certain situation Then you might want to try something risky.
Speaker 1: But even then you could just write a book and that says if this is the situation in your baseball game this inning this These players on base, you know This kind of person at bat then do this and it would.
Speaker 1: you would be just as good as most major league managers with that Book.
Speaker 0: so it came down now to mostly the ability of the players Physically, yep, but then as time went on human bodies start to peak.
Speaker 0: There's a point at which a human body is at as far as we know its maximum potential to do a given time.
Speaker 1: You have the best possible baseball playing body.
Speaker 1: Someone could possibly have maybe you could be a little bit better But you're better enough that you're just incredible.
Speaker 0: and so yeah.
Speaker 0: So it gets to the point where the best pitchers are all Mostly identical in that there's there's not much competition left.
Speaker 0: the margins between a one player and another player are So slight physically that the actual outcome of the game Ends up coming down to the margins and the chance and the randomness as opposed to the skill of any given player Because the skills are all so similar.
Speaker 1: granted, you know, that's why we had star players.
Speaker 1: they're just the difference between a star player and a not star player is Actually pretty small.
Speaker 1: the thing is they're just that much better.
Speaker 1: You know there that then all the other people on average that those people do make the difference in Beating chance and helping the team win, but if you take even like the shittiest major league baseball pitcher There are so many light years beyond all the non major league pitchers.
Speaker 1: They're just amazing.
Speaker 1: and then the peep they're just not stars because someone else is a tiny bit more amazing.
Speaker 1: and that tiny bit more Amazingness is what makes them win and the other guy not win.
Speaker 0: now as a result.
Speaker 0: There's no surprises in baseball other than the occasional.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, he dropped the ball and something bad happened Which is relatively rare.
Speaker 0: Nothing exciting happens in baseball anymore.
Speaker 0: I mean even home runs.
Speaker 1: look back in the day home runs were relatively Fences are way back and it was really hard to hit it all that way.
Speaker 0: and also I mean the science of training human to swing a bat was not where it is today.
Speaker 0: There was a lot of just.
Speaker 0: I mean Babe Ruth was a big old fat guy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: He sure was nowadays an amazing fat guy But the fat guy nonetheless.
Speaker 0: the science of training someone to swing a bat is so advanced that home runs Because home runs are just trivial.
Speaker 0: They have been often and once a game at least yeah, and they're not exciting anymore.
Speaker 1: Also the science of pitching and throwing a ball fast and with accuracy has progressed so much.
Speaker 1: if Babe Ruth had to face today's Pitchers, he wouldn't do so.
Speaker 1: Well, he'd be in big trouble.
Speaker 1: And the only reason to play the batters we have today don't.
Speaker 1: if they were back in Babe Ruth's time They would have hit a home run every time they were up.
Speaker 0: It's because pitching has changed so much and it's so perfect now So because the physicality has gotten so good we're left to rely on the tactics.
Speaker 1: But the tactics are already known because the game itself is fundamentally very simple and as a result in the end Baseball is not exciting to watch because you don't see things happen like someone dropping the ball Someone throwing to the wrong base a suicide squeeze.
Speaker 1: It's basically by the book.
Speaker 1: You know exactly what everyone's gonna do and it all just comes down to these very very slight things that are not Exciting to watch or so interesting.
Speaker 1: It's just you know, they're playing the exact game exactly the way it should be played every time.
Speaker 0: Case in point.
Speaker 0: I enjoy watching two twelve-year-olds play pickle much more than I enjoy watching an actual Major League Baseball game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think this is also why a lot of people like watching college football.
Speaker 1: they like watching college basketball and college hockey and college baseball more and more and more and Some major league sports is starting to stagnate in their popularity because if you go watch college football People are doing all sorts of funky plays.
Speaker 1: not every player on the field is the master.
Speaker 1: all sorts of crazy stuff happens all the time Whereas in major league football?
Speaker 1: it's you know, except if yeah, unless you ever no one tries funky plays because you're not allowed to and You pretty much have to do everything by the book.
Speaker 1: and you know Sometimes is exciting things mostly because some teams out there suck and just because football is a game in which crazy things can happen Despite amazingness, but it's it's not isn't entertaining as college football as the game goes.
Speaker 1: so because of this some people decided that To make the game more exciting to stand out from the crowd in which everyone is awesome It takes some steroids to gain that slight advantage to go from the better than most of the world to slightly better than everyone else playing.
Speaker 1: and People didn't like that because now it's sort of unfair again, you know We tried to make it so fair that we made it unexciting.
Speaker 1: So people tried to make it more exciting and thus made it less fair.
Speaker 0: But at this point and here's the interesting thing taking the steroids All right It's you're doing an artificial thing to your body to make it perform better Even though I don't think it's that much of a step beyond a lot of the other semi artificial things or training Regimes that people go through.
Speaker 0: Yep but what if someone is born who has a genetic defect that causes their body to create excess testosterone that gives a similar effect to take an artificial testosterone.
Speaker 0: if You say that people aren't allowed to modify themselves
Speaker 1: with
Speaker 0: steroids then what you're basically saying is that now the only true determiner of skill in baseball is going to be genetics and genetic freaks who have an Advantage purely based on their genes are the ones who will excel because they're going to be stronger than other people.
Speaker 0: Yep Well at the same time Testosterone and that sort of thing can be dangerous.
Speaker 0: Are you going to encourage people to do something dangerous?
Speaker 0: But yet what if someone is willing to take that risk?
Speaker 0: and it's a complicated issue?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well first I want to say I do think people should be allowed to do to themselves Whatever they want as long as it doesn't hurt anyone else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they want to take steroids and you go go nuts.
Speaker 0: You did argue that people shouldn't be allowed to commit suicide.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: That's one thing you can't do.
Speaker 0: I disagree with that fundamentally, whatever.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that another time, but while you can do anything you want it goes back to the question of what are we testing and it seems that
Speaker 0: people
Speaker 1: At least in sports have generally agreed that you know in the Olympics We're testing the limits and abilities of the natural human body.
Speaker 1: What can you do with your natural unmodified human body simply by training and practicing?
Speaker 1: How far can you how far can you take it without you know using drugs or a robot suit or?
Speaker 1: Special equipment or anything like that?
Speaker 0: now at this point.
Speaker 0: What's the definition of human?
Speaker 0: I mean, all right normal like you and me born We train our body as much as it can be trained without chemicals or anything Whatever and then we you know compete in the competition.
Speaker 0: What if someone is born genetically superior?
Speaker 0: because at that point you're not testing the ability so much as of the person the individual Athlete?
Speaker 0: you're testing their genetics plus the science of training them.
Speaker 0: Yep So, all right not allowed to take steroids.
Speaker 0: Am I allowed to engage in genetic modifications to get the same effect?
Speaker 1: It's a good question that nobody is bothered with yet because it hasn't happened.
Speaker 0: All right, say they ban that you can't modify your genes artificially.
Speaker 0: What if I set up a generation upon generation of people and breed them well with their consent to create?
Speaker 0: People that would have the same effect as if I had done it artificially?
Speaker 1: I think people already have no problem with that.
Speaker 1: as you can see from history.
Speaker 1: There have been many you know sons and daughters of existing athletes who've become athletes yet again And then their sons and daughters also become athletes and they get better or worse over the generations.
Speaker 0: But I mean many sports families that have bred for sporting Oh, but I mean very specifically and scientifically breeding for athleticism over many generations.
Speaker 0: How is that different from doing it artificially?
Speaker 1: It's I think it just comes down to the fact that you know over the years That we've played the sport.
Speaker 1: Everyone who's played it has been not you know until recently I guess the past decade or so not artificially modifying their bodies.
Speaker 1: so if you want to be able to compare you know fairly the Achievements of the people in the sport today to the people in the sport of yesteryear Then they have to do the same exact thing.
Speaker 0: But the rules are different.
Speaker 0: anyway A lot of things have changed in all the sports over the years in addition to that and also steroids have been around for a long Time.
Speaker 1: yep steroids have been around for a long time.
Speaker 0: There just weren't tests before that were easily available.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but people weren't using sports steroids as a performance enhancer.
Speaker 0: actually more than a couple decades I've seen the argument that it's not that people are using the steroids that is making the issue.
Speaker 0: It's that they're using the steroids in conjunction with very scientific training regimens and that the training Regimens alone account for a lot of the ability we see today.
Speaker 0: Aha that I mean the science of training an Olympic athlete is immense.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like f1 where it's almost more about the the scientists training this person or the engineers building and designing this car.
Speaker 0: Then it is about the driver.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well the driver matters a whole lot.
Speaker 1: F1 though, but yeah, there's.
Speaker 1: basically it comes down to what are you testing?
Speaker 1: and we've decided that you know in sports like baseball That earliest the commissioners and then those sorts of people have decided they are testing a non-chemically modified human beings ability to hit a ball and throw a ball and run around bases.
Speaker 0: fine Then I'll use genetics like a coordinator and Gundam seed to create the uber baseball, baby His arms are gonna be an extra six inches long super muscles.
Speaker 0: He's gonna have short squat legs cuz he doesn't need to run.
Speaker 0: He'll always hit home runs.
Speaker 1: Hey, I guess that would be fair.
Speaker 1: I get I mean it's you know That's come up.
Speaker 0: All right, so that's it.
Speaker 0: Then why ban steroids for not banning that and also notice how we banned specific performance enhancers, but not other ones.
Speaker 0: What's the line of performance enhancer?
Speaker 0: is Red Bull a performance enhancer?
Speaker 0: There's clear clinical evidence that taurine is a performance enhancer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the the part of the actual reason I said performance enhancer a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: Yes It would be difficult to actually convince me that you know Sporting commissioners are actually thinking about this game theory type perspective that I'm thinking of.
Speaker 0: That's the only thing that bothers me.
Speaker 1: I don't obviously against steroids because they don't want to promote this sort of bad behavior.
Speaker 1: They like their sports to appear clean and they want to promote their athletes as good role models.
Speaker 1: eat now No, and all that sort of notice God said appear.
Speaker 0: I don't think they care at all.
Speaker 0: They would go steroids a hundred percent if that's where the money was.
Speaker 0: but I think they see the negative public perception and also the negative pressure from the government and They don't want to go in those waters because they'd make less money or they get regulated.
Speaker 0: Yep I think that if the people had no problem with steroids and the government didn't care they jump on the steroids like that.
Speaker 1: yeah, cuz I mean if they they would jump on the steroids and then basically they would be able to increase the entertainment value of their Sport for a time because some of the players would be on steroids and some would refuse but they would still be better than all the other players in the world and you would then again have a you know a Ability and the steroid players would be.
Speaker 1: there would be amazing plays happening again because of the gap of skill between the steroid users and The non steroid users, but at the same time everyone became a steroid user.
Speaker 1: then the sport would be boring again at the same time.
Speaker 0: That's definitely a stopgap and a poor one at that because it seems like the fundamental issue Is that we have maxed out every aspect of baseball or a lot of games?
Speaker 0: I mean like most German or most American board games.
Speaker 1: Yep I'd say most board games in general games athletic or not have been maxed out.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So once a game is maxed out Other than stopgaps to force like to make players have more options like extending the game or something to try to make it more interesting Why not just change the game to add more complexity or add more points of contention in other places like take baseball Normal game but instead of the four bases have a branch network of braces going out the field Or something like that.
Speaker 0: multiple actually multiple paths home and a lot more decision-making on the fly on the field.
Speaker 1: Well, I think two reasons for that.
Speaker 0: first of all traditionalists traditionalist, uh, you know, what?
Speaker 0: All ancient board games sucked all old card games almost without fail are Terrible.
Speaker 0: the game theory and science is advanced to the point that we can construct better games that are clearly better on all levels Tactically strategically.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also if you're making millions of dollars because people are coming to see your sport if you change that sport Drastically, I mean changing a little bit.
Speaker 1: So it resembles the current sport enough that people still understand what's going on.
Speaker 1: hockey does that right, but if you change the sport Dramatically like you basically completely change the rules like blurns ball or something.
Speaker 1: if you suddenly change it to blurns ball People wouldn't come to see it because it's not something they're familiar with It's not something they know.
Speaker 1: the rules of like every time someone tries to come out with like Slamball or speedball or arena football or those things don't get a lot of attention.
Speaker 1: I mean You can't even get attention for soccer in the US because a lot of people just don't know how it's played or what the rules Are.
Speaker 1: they don't care.
Speaker 0: see now?
Speaker 0: I think this is gonna change over time because the sports are less and less popular.
Speaker 0: a lot for football American football is still stupidly popular and getting more but all the other I'm saying in the long run I think kids growing up are going to be less and less interested in sports Particularly because there's so much more entertainment on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's possible and I could see new sports becoming popular in the next 20 to 30 years.
Speaker 1: Yep, the problem is is again a lot of our new sports, right?
Speaker 1: if if we assume geeks are going to inherit the earth would be things like counter-strike and Puerto Rico and whatever.
Speaker 1: and those things remember are Perfect games basically of tests of skill and where we basically maxed out a lot of those things.
Speaker 1: I mean fatality is just about maxed out FPSing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's just not too many of him right now.
Speaker 1: there's one of him and there's some other people just as good as him who aren't as famous, but they're out there and South Korea has maxed out Starcraft completely and me rim and Alex might have maxed out Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: We have to test it.
Speaker 0: We have a theory.
Speaker 0: we think we've solved Puerto Rico Maybe.
Speaker 0: well, we we've been close to it for a long time Yeah, but now we finally hit a situation where every time we play even trying different permutations We can see a clear path to who is going to win based on the first round of play.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But anyway None of these are going to be very good Spectator sports.
Speaker 1: I mean if you want to make a good spectator sport You can you pretty much.
Speaker 1: the other end of the spectrum is the pro wrestling.
Speaker 1: It's not a sport anymore It's just a show.
Speaker 1: It's no sport.
Speaker 1: left is just designed to be appealing to spectators with nothing else.
Speaker 0: I think you can make interesting sports.
Speaker 0: I mean things like Take paintball as an example.
Speaker 0: I think paintball could have been an amazing spectator sport.
Speaker 1: Mmm, it could be.
Speaker 0: the problem is paintball as it is played by paintball people is Incredibly boring and lame and it's just like this stupidly rules obsessed capture-the-flag crap game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's not fun.
Speaker 0: I've played it a bunch of times But say we took airsoft or whatever or counter-strike which is a fun game, but not the greatest spectator game And we made a sport that was counter-strike in the real world.
Speaker 0: You play paintball where it's interesting.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: go get that terrorists and they just film these athletes who train like Navy SEALs or SAS agents with guns And they go around and they do these things as a sport.
Speaker 1: Yep I think the the problems with that, you know You got to think about all these crazy factors Like, you know, how easy is it to film that for television like like football and hockey and baseball, you know They were designed or even if they weren't designed originally like football works so well with television.
Speaker 1: It's it's a big wide rectangle.
Speaker 1: The TV camera takes a big wide rectangle.
Speaker 1: You can see everything that's going on.
Speaker 0: hockey.
Speaker 1: Not so much though hockey not so much really.
Speaker 0: that's probably I'd say that's that might be a big factor to why hockey is less Popular.
Speaker 0: it's just that people can't watch it on TV.
Speaker 1: That's a big factor in why football is so popular in the US because it is designed for television.
Speaker 1: like perfectly Watching on television is better than being there.
Speaker 1: I've been there many times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless you're really close in just the right seats You're not gonna see a lot of stuff that God.
Speaker 1: the last you look up to the video screen for the replays.
Speaker 0: the last NFL Game we went to we walked out Halfway through.
Speaker 1: that was a really that was the worst football game ever.
Speaker 0: Well, not only was it a it was a particularly boring game of football.
Speaker 0: It's a really bad game.
Speaker 0: It was like one degree.
Speaker 1: It's a good football game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is worth it to go to a good football game, but not that one good God.
Speaker 0: even then I'd rather watch him on TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah I think what we have to do is you have to come up with some sort of new sports that are both.
Speaker 1: that are Basically things that it'll take humans many many years to get really good at.
Speaker 1: even if we use performance enhancing Equipments of all sorts that way It'll still be a good game in which the best team wins or the best side wins depending whoever has the most skill and ability.
Speaker 1: But since we haven't figured it out yet and we won't figure it out for a very long time all sorts of interesting and exciting plays will still happen because People haven't figured it out yet and people mess up and people will try crazy things now and then and yeah It'll be way cool.
Speaker 1: And then when that gets boring we have to come up with something new again.
Speaker 0: now see if kids keep having Shorter attention spans which I can definitely feel my attention fan shortening the way I use me So short now compared to what it used to be.
Speaker 0: but if this keeps up I could see a time where we come up with a new sport a new game.
Speaker 0: It immediately becomes popular and successful and it's the sport that everyone's watching.
Speaker 0: and then it gets maxed out and they have the final Tournament of who is the best and then everyone just forgets it drops it and there's a new sport That could possibly happen.
Speaker 0: That's not that I see.
Speaker 0: that's the only way forward.
Speaker 0: is you have to drop a sport or a game pretty much at the falling edge of the curve of its perfection like once it is solved?
Speaker 0: and once it is solved to the point to where People can like most of the players playing have it solved to know exactly what to do and the game becomes predictable You drop it and move on.
Speaker 0: that's why we don't play most of the board games.
Speaker 0: We own we.
Speaker 0: we solved them We figured out what they were at their core and there were no longer interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't continue to just keep playing them year after year to see.
Speaker 1: you know Who is the best because we were all equally the best.
Speaker 1: we all solve the puzzle.
Speaker 1: It all just comes down to the slight bit of randomness, you know, like in baseball the weather.
Speaker 1: Well, you know if two equal baseball teams play at the same field and there's no the factors that determine who's gonna win are gonna be the weather and The random bird flying in front of a pitch.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know, maybe some dust getting kicked up here and there, you know the umpire making a bad call all these sorts of things you can't control.
Speaker 1: or what's gonna be the determining factor and That doesn't make for a very fun thing to watch.
Speaker 0: Well, at least not for people like us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you might as well roll a six-sided dice and see what size up.
Speaker 0: Die is the singular of dice.
Speaker 1: I know it bothers me Profoundly, that's why I do it.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I think you just forget because I don't like the word die.
Speaker 0: Well, then always use it in the plural.
Speaker 1: you'll be okay, I just all right.
Speaker 0: we went on forever.
Speaker 0: I think we're done.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.