Speaker 1: It's Tuesday July 3rd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights Tonight we talk about power grid.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: so yesterday I was debating whether to upgrade my computer or buy a new one and I decided to upgrade.
Speaker 0: so I ordered some RAM and a hard drive and from new egg and I paid for the normal four dollar UPS shipping four dollars.
Speaker 0: Hard drive showed up today ordered it yesterday today today.
Speaker 0: It was there when I got home.
Speaker 0: the RAM will be here.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it'll be here tomorrow cuz I don't know if UPS works on Independence Day.
Speaker 0: They may or may not but if not, it'll be here Thursday.
Speaker 1: damn That's all I got to say, you know I've never in my life paid for expedited shipping because everything always comes real quick.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's just because we live in the Northeast.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, it also depends on who's shipping it and where they're shipping it from.
Speaker 0: I mean because the hard drive was from New Jersey.
Speaker 0: I found that that's why I got here so fast.
Speaker 0: The RAM is from California.
Speaker 0: So it's gonna take a day or two more.
Speaker 1: actually, you know what?
Speaker 1: I had the same deal.
Speaker 1: my case and power supply Came from New Jersey and we're here the next day when I were in my computer.
Speaker 1: The rest of it took four days because it came from California.
Speaker 0: Yep, and also like DHL sends my comic books They take like four days from I think Indiana.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile You know FedEx from California or UPS from California is faster than DHL from Indiana.
Speaker 1: At any rate expect us to be playing some PC games now that we both have generally functioning computers.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe.
Speaker 1: well, I will be.
Speaker 1: I'm playing half-life 2 and I gotta tell you it's awesome.
Speaker 1: It is meeting and or exceeding all expectations thus far and I've played it for an hour and five minutes.
Speaker 0: Haha I got to play it again me.
Speaker 0: I maybe what I'll do is I'll play episode.
Speaker 0: I'll play episode zero, you know one and two all in a big row might be a good idea.
Speaker 0: Maybe I could time it so that I finish episode one like the day episode two comes out or something like that.
Speaker 1: now I'm holding out because real soon I'm getting either the 20 inch to the 22 inch widescreen and I really want to play the game in the widescreen.
Speaker 0: Awesome Yeah, that's probably good idea.
Speaker 0: So I ran from work to the train today because you know tomorrow's Independence Day in the United States The day of the Declaration of Independence signing.
Speaker 0: supposedly, I guess we don't know 100% but it probably is.
Speaker 0: that's the date They wrote on it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway Continue calendar could be off, you know, it's an old 1700s calendar.
Speaker 0: You can't trust those things.
Speaker 0: Like we don't know.
Speaker 0: the year zero was the actual day.
Speaker 0: Jesus was born.
Speaker 0: if there was such a person Well, we've got an idea.
Speaker 0: We got an idea but not a perfect idea.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so that means I don't to work tomorrow.
Speaker 0: So getting home sooner makes a big difference because it adds to my one-day middle-of-the-week vacation All right.
Speaker 0: So I tried to get on the 509 instead of the 528 which usually gets me home about 20 minutes earlier.
Speaker 1: I do notice you came home about the same time.
Speaker 1: You always do.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, I'm sitting on the train and it's going.
Speaker 0: I made the 509.
Speaker 0: I had to run.
Speaker 0: I got on it like 507 and Somewhere like right before the Riverdale station some lady in the car is like screaming and I'm like what the hell, uh-huh and everyone's like what the hell.
Speaker 1: cuz I just want to point out that I ride a different train on the same line and There were a bunch of cops on my train and add a bunch of the stations as I was going up.
Speaker 1: No, not related.
Speaker 0: No, okay.
Speaker 0: I just wondered so, you know, she was screaming something and I guess it must have been her daughter.
Speaker 0: She looked like a grandma and her daughter was like, oh, what's the problem?
Speaker 0: And then I guess they had.
Speaker 0: the daughter also had small children.
Speaker 0: Apparently this lady was having I don't know a heart attack a stroke a diabetic shock or something.
Speaker 0: All right, and You know the late the the daughter tried to go for the emergency break.
Speaker 0: wine No, and I had to.
Speaker 0: I was like no I see because I was sitting at the end and I was like, no, I didn't let her do it.
Speaker 1: Good for you You saved.
Speaker 1: you probably saved a life.
Speaker 1: Hitting that break is probably the worst thing you could ever do an emergency for anyone on a train ever.
Speaker 0: There's a thing I in the train it says emergency break.
Speaker 1: they're all over there between the cars.
Speaker 1: They're usually a glass thing.
Speaker 1: They're hidden under seats.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of them.
Speaker 0: There's like red handles that you can pull to activate the emergency break.
Speaker 0: Never under almost any circumstance.
Speaker 0: Should you ever pull that thing ever?
Speaker 0: Even if it's the worst emergency ever like nuclear bomb don't pull it Don't not pull it.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: part of the reason is that these break.
Speaker 1: that is the last chance break.
Speaker 1: That is the Emergency break.
Speaker 1: it's not like in your car where it's also the parking brake.
Speaker 1: if you pull that all Shit breaks loose and all bets are off.
Speaker 1: also that train stopping and not going anywhere for a long time.
Speaker 0: Yes The way the emergency brake first of all The.
Speaker 0: there's one that basically the reason they have those brakes at all is let's say your train car gets loose and is just rolling Down the track.
Speaker 0: you have a way to stop.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much the only reasonable circumstance in which you would ever pull that thing.
Speaker 1: I mean granted that there are different mechanisms and all sorts of yes Yes, it's actually kind of interesting how those brakes work, but we're not gonna get into that.
Speaker 0: But if you pull that thing the brake activates and cannot be deactivated.
Speaker 0: without powerful machinery You will be sitting in that train car for a long time.
Speaker 0: Also, even if it was a normal break now, you're stuck in the middle of nowhere as opposed to at a train station.
Speaker 1: Yeah See I it always bothers me how so many people just lose their head whenever something bad happens and instead of Doing the logical thing, which is all right alert the conductor.
Speaker 1: There'll be paramedics waiting at the next train station Guaranteed.
Speaker 0: actually we got to Yonkers before the paramedics got there.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah after I actually, you know Riverdale's like right there so I know.
Speaker 0: but basically I called 911 after I stopped the lady from pulling the thing and Everyone else was going.
Speaker 0: is there a doctor on the train?
Speaker 0: I'm just talking to the 911 operator and he's like, all right.
Speaker 0: So what station are you at?
Speaker 0: I'm like, uh, and then I see Riverdale go by and like Riverdale And then he's like, what's the next stop?
Speaker 0: I'm like, I have no idea not a clue.
Speaker 0: Yeah And he's like could I talk to the conductor?
Speaker 0: and the conductor wasn't even there yet at that point.
Speaker 0: and then the conductor was like Yeah, I'll talk to my dispatcher first.
Speaker 0: I'm like, all right, whatever.
Speaker 0: Wow, and then the 911 guy eventually didn't want to talk to me anymore and we waited at Yonkers for like 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: thus I could have gotten on the 528 train had been fine.
Speaker 1: But no, you know, you probably could have caught any number of trains from Yonkers.
Speaker 1: Did they make you stay on the train or could you know we're all staying on the train and could you have gotten off?
Speaker 0: There was no train past us while we were sitting there.
Speaker 1: Oh must have just been bad timing.
Speaker 0: Yeah So that was that.
Speaker 1: oh, well you saved a life.
Speaker 1: No, think about it.
Speaker 1: if she had pulled that brake, you know You know hard it would have been for any sort of EMT to get to that train.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah If she pulled the brake, you know the lady next the lady sitting across to me also didn't let her pull the brake.
Speaker 1: So I just I mean one.
Speaker 1: there are signs everywhere saying don't ever pull this brake ever not for you Not for you ever.
Speaker 1: but on the other end.
Speaker 1: It seems like whenever people panic they look around if there's anything red or looks like it's an emergency thing.
Speaker 1: They'll hit any emergency button they see.
Speaker 1: but they never think to do the logical thing of stop assess the situation Call 911 if appropriate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess we're pretty cool-headed when they took the lady off the train.
Speaker 0: She was not dead.
Speaker 0: She was kind of unconscious ish, but not dead.
Speaker 0: So wow.
Speaker 1: Well that beats the hell out of my leader bit.
Speaker 1: So I'll just keep quiet.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So speaking of racism racism Those black trains?
Speaker 0: No, it's those red handles those red, Connecticut trains.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Those are always the nastiest trains, too Because they use the overhead electricity.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I mean not to mention the fact yeah If you stop that train in Riverdale, not only can the EMTs not get their little EMT ambulance out there You can't turn off the third rail Plus, I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: I'll die trying to get to the train.
Speaker 1: It's not like it was gonna be stopped at a station.
Speaker 1: It was gonna be stopped.
Speaker 1: I mean the.
Speaker 1: the train tracks down in New York.
Speaker 1: there on the heart the Hudson line.
Speaker 1: on one side is the Hudson River Usually like five feet away from the train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and on the other side is usually a cliff.
Speaker 1: there's no access.
Speaker 0: Yeah, do not.
Speaker 0: well, this is before Yonkers But even so yes, if you pull it and the train is stuck between a cliff and the river They're gonna need helicopters and boats and you're gonna be waiting All right.
Speaker 1: So anyway speaking of racism I'm sure you're all familiar with John Gabriel's greater internet fuckwad theory.
Speaker 1: if you're not I've linked to it.
Speaker 1: I think
Speaker 0: it's become at this point John Gabriel's greater internet fuckwad law
Speaker 1: Possibly because I have yeah, I mean Suffice to say this theory states that if you take a normal person and you add to this normal person anonymity and an audience of any size They will inevitably over time become a total fuckwad.
Speaker 1: yeah, now the the term for both this process and For the resulting Items that happen of interest is shit cock shit cocking shit cockery.
Speaker 1: Yep We actually ran a counter-strike server a long time ago that we named shit cockless Stan because we kicked anyone who shit cocked But that resulted in quite an empty server.
Speaker 1: Yes, it did because you know what?
Speaker 1: I gotta say shit cocking and counter-strike is much like cheating at Euchre.
Speaker 1: The games not the same with you.
Speaker 1: Don't do it.
Speaker 0: That's right, right.
Speaker 1: So we're used to this.
Speaker 1: we've been playing counter-strike and not a day goes by in my life where I'm not called a gay Homosexual lizard by some sort of 12 to 12 and a half year old kid.
Speaker 0: at least they're honest.
Speaker 1: Now it seems like people use.
Speaker 1: I'm just getting right over that.
Speaker 1: I'm just not even gonna dignify that with a response.
Speaker 1: So this is endemic on the internet.
Speaker 1: this happens.
Speaker 1: you have to deal with it.
Speaker 1: The Internet is the wild wild west and there are very few places where you can escape from this Anywhere.
Speaker 1: you can in any way manipulate anything that any other person will ever see.
Speaker 1: Hoards of people Scott and I included will do everything within their power to make it resemble a penis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that that is also true.
Speaker 1: going to my I mean going to Mario Kart and play Mario Kart Everyone can make the little custom icon.
Speaker 1: Mine is crazy.
Speaker 1: Bunta I can't mind you.
Speaker 1: the sheer number of Phalluses that I encountered playing that game some black ones some white ones.
Speaker 1: One of them was oozing.
Speaker 1: one of them was pointed right at me.
Speaker 0: I mean if there's any game that actually lets you make an avatar penises abound Of any kind.
Speaker 0: not just people can put decals on the pokeballs that they can draw.
Speaker 0: Can you actually draw them or do you need to collect them?
Speaker 1: I think you have to collect them.
Speaker 0: But if they let you draw the decals for your pokeballs people would have these pokey penis balls.
Speaker 1: Ah, I mean, that's just the way the internet is.
Speaker 1: if you want an example of this go to YouTube and look at any Comments any Oh Akaki board you will see penises.
Speaker 1: Oh god Any shared space on the internet?
Speaker 1: Second life is as a lot of you know that thing where it's like.
Speaker 0: it simulates a refrigerator with the alphabet magnets on it.
Speaker 1: I spent a lot.
Speaker 0: everyone kind of shares the same refrigerator.
Speaker 1: I remember one time I was there when these things first started getting popular at RIT And I was trying to construct a penis by taking all the letters and drawing them in the shape of a penis.
Speaker 1: Someone else was trying to write the word fuck as many times as he could and he kept stealing my letters.
Speaker 0: Yeah I like the people who just grab as many letters they couldn't put them in the corner and a giant stack making it really hard to do anything,
Speaker 1: but that's the way the internet works and You gotta have a little bit of a thick skin if you want to be on the internet And you want to be in any sort of shared space
Speaker 0: You
Speaker 1: have to deal with the fact that you're going to be playing games with people who were named things like Snape kills Dumbledore or Penis or my favorite was on Mario Kart.
Speaker 1: There's a man whose name.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess a man was fuck fuck Nice, and his graphic was the word fuck written in white with a black background.
Speaker 1: No, and that was it.
Speaker 0: Yeah counter-strike sprays all porn.
Speaker 1: Oh Sometimes furry porn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually just straight-up porn.
Speaker 1: Yep, sometimes gun porn.
Speaker 1: Well, uh Apparently many of the people using Xbox Live are not quite familiar with this law of the Internet.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: See someone on Forza 2 you can customize your car.
Speaker 1: So they made the 1954 300 SL white power mobile.
Speaker 0: I Gotta say it's pretty terrific while the guys if the guys that you know white power are not cool, but white power mobile Awesome.
Speaker 1: I highly doubt the person who did this is actually racist.
Speaker 1: I mean it can it.
Speaker 1: first of all it has the SS lightning bolts on the back.
Speaker 1: It says real Hitler white power.
Speaker 1: It's got the Iron Cross.
Speaker 1: It's black like all those Nazi cars back in the day Yep, but the hood as a red Nazi flag on it complete with swastika And the guy's name is dreamer 61.
Speaker 0: So that's a pretty cool thing there.
Speaker 0: cuz as much as Nazis are the worst.
Speaker 0: I Mean Indiana Jones wouldn't be cool if it didn't have Nazis in it.
Speaker 0: I mean you got to look at it that way.
Speaker 1: I hate Illinois Nazis as much as the rest of you But I do not condone Jake and Elwood's actions in regards to those Illinois Nazis.
Speaker 1: I do but I Enjoy their actions exactly.
Speaker 1: I do not feel sympathy for the people those actions were directed toward.
Speaker 1: However, I don't condone them because freedom of speech.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is they're blocking the road Yeah, but they had a permit.
Speaker 0: you'd have a permit to block the road They did in the movie.
Speaker 1: Remember the cop was like they got a permit.
Speaker 0: I thought that was a permit to protest not to block the road They were allowed to brought.
Speaker 1: but the point was the cop wasn't getting rid of them.
Speaker 1: So they obviously had some sort of the cops acting.
Speaker 0: cop was probably one of them.
Speaker 1: No, cuz he didn't like the Nazis now he didn't.
Speaker 1: oh, all right If you guys don't know what we're talking about right now get off my podcast.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I find this hilarious and I got to say what.
Speaker 1: the reason I find it interesting Is that there's a shitstorm on the internet?
Speaker 0: How dare?
Speaker 1: Microsoft let this stand.
Speaker 1: how dare they let this be here.
Speaker 1: They should do something about it.
Speaker 0: Oh, you don't want your free speech.
Speaker 0: fine.
Speaker 1: Shut up Now.
Speaker 1: the best part is all the people who are so mad about this cite the terms of service Which state that you can't have hate literature on Xbox Live.
Speaker 0: It's not hate literature or anything like that.
Speaker 1: if you read the terms of service this kind of thing is pretty Specifically, but I don't think it's hateful.
Speaker 1: I think it's humorous now regardless that the actual things They've got here are pretty much disallowed by the terms of service.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: However, I want to point out to a lot of people out there why your argument is faulty.
Speaker 1: sure It might be in violation of the terms of service.
Speaker 1: just because Microsoft says you're not allowed to do X on their service does not mean they're Obligated to prevent you from doing X if they don't want to because they did not tell you or have an agreement with you saying that they would get rid of these things or that they have to or that you Will not see these things.
Speaker 1: All they said is that they don't want you to do these things and if you do they have the right to kick you off Or deny you service, but they do not have the responsibility to kick you off.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So Apparently to Microsoft is trying to do something about this.
Speaker 1: I think the problem is now that this sort of thing is Recognizable on the internet.
Speaker 1: the Hitler penis white power fuckwad shit.
Speaker 1: cockers are growing in number.
Speaker 1: Hooray That's all I have to say about that.
Speaker 0: All right, I probably would have used this news tomorrow But I have more important news for tomorrow.
Speaker 0: So Apparently there's a comic book store in I think Utah Salt Lake City maybe called night flight comics.
Speaker 0: Utah is not a place near the Salt Lake City main library something.
Speaker 0: All right, and someone went to this comic book store over the weekend and They were looking at some Simpsons bust-ups.
Speaker 0: And basically what it is is a little miss.
Speaker 0: It's a little cardboard box and Inside is a you know, a plastic bust of a Simpsons character.
Speaker 0: I know there's sort of those collectibles where you you know, you don't know which ones in there.
Speaker 0: So you buy one you might get Bart you buy another one You might get home or you might get another Bart, you know, how many boxes of anime ones?
Speaker 0: I've got all over the place and then you might you know, if you're lucky you'll get like the the golden moe or something I don't know with two knives.
Speaker 0: Yeah the chase figures anyway, so someone was looking at these and They saw the lid was taped shut.
Speaker 0: and the fact that it was taped shut leads me to believe that it had been previously opened.
Speaker 1: But that's beside the point.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the person saw the box was taped shut.
Speaker 0: They actually the person said because this is all just you know What the people said.
Speaker 0: he said she said yes that it appeared that the box had already previously been opened.
Speaker 0: So they figured there was no problem opening it and looking inside.
Speaker 1: I will point out I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying that I disagree with this person.
Speaker 1: All I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Oh, I haven't even got to the new.
Speaker 1: No, I know.
Speaker 1: All I'm saying is that that specific statement reeks of Someone trying to justify their actions and/or get out of having possibly done something wrong.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's a seven dollar toy, right.
Speaker 0: and someone opened the lid and the store proprietor Said, you know, basically hey, you got to pay for that.
Speaker 0: and they were.
Speaker 0: and the people said, uh, no we don't cuz they don't.
Speaker 0: and The star proprietor then told someone else to stand in front of the door and not let them leave.
Speaker 1: Whoa That's the point I call 9-1-1 and Sam being illegally detained.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: So the store owner called 9-1-1 to tell what was going on.
Speaker 1: This is a genius here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like hey, these people are shoplifting opening up merchandise and refusing to pay for it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna translate Here's what the 9-1-1 operator heard from.
Speaker 1: this guy translated.
Speaker 1: It was a girl.
Speaker 1: I think this is a store owner.
Speaker 1: Yep, here's what was the what actually was said?
Speaker 1: Hi, I'd like to report that I am currently in the process of kidnapping and detaining two people.
Speaker 1: Yes in my store Yeah, please come and force me to let them go possibly press charges against me.
Speaker 0: So 50 minutes later the cop showed up and said, uh-huh, well You have to let these people go and we're gonna look into it and possibly charge you with illegally detaining them.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah See I like it when a cop knows the law in most places in the United States first off.
Speaker 1: Anyone who says they ever break it you bought it policy or anything like that is foolish.
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 1: There's nothing they can do about it unless they can prove that you did it willfully.
Speaker 0: and if you did it willfully, that's vandalism.
Speaker 0: So it's completely different.
Speaker 0: if you go into a store Let's say I go into the Ferrari dealer right the Ferrari dealer and I accidentally Like fall over and I don't know scratch chain reaction of events happens and it blows up the car Like boat.
Speaker 0: the car is ruined.
Speaker 0: That's like a $300,000 car.
Speaker 0: You know how much I'm liable to pay Zero if I didn't do it on purpose.
Speaker 0: and if they want money I gotta have to sue me and win which is not gonna be easy.
Speaker 1: Yep So yeah, I remember this almost happened to us at Connecticut last year.
Speaker 1: this not that it was any fault of Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Remember when we're getting ready to leave right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and when we'd come in in the morning There was a lady with the uniform on and she was selling the parking tickets to everyone and she said all day five dollars.
Speaker 1: so we bought one.
Speaker 1: everyone bought one going in and we're trying to leave.
Speaker 1: the con at the end of the night and Every person in front of us takes forever.
Speaker 1: It looks like they're arguing with the attendant.
Speaker 0: We don't know I remember now.
Speaker 1: so we finally get up.
Speaker 1: we hand the ticket and he's like twelve dollars.
Speaker 1: So we're like It said all day for five dollars.
Speaker 1: and he said yeah until 8 p.m And we said, um She said all day.
Speaker 1: She didn't say 8 p.m.
Speaker 1: We're not paying and We sat there waiting for his response.
Speaker 1: now had he chose to not just sigh and let us go We probably would have been calling the police right away.
Speaker 0: Yep, cuz you can't keep me there.
Speaker 0: That's illegally detaining me.
Speaker 0: I will pay the five dollars.
Speaker 0: I agreed to pay.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that's it.
Speaker 1: So if a store owner ever gives you grief like that or ever decides to bar your way out unless they are a peace officer You can just leave and if they lay a hand on you you can sue.
Speaker 0: not only that But if you're say leaving Best Buy right and they say hey, can we see your receipt?
Speaker 0: You don't have to say anything.
Speaker 0: You can just leave.
Speaker 0: they can't keep you there.
Speaker 1: granted They could ban you from the store if they want.
Speaker 0: they could ban you from the store if they wanted to.
Speaker 0: they could You know call the police I guess but they might get in trouble for you know Calling the police for no reason.
Speaker 1: if they have if they have a peace officer or a police officer And they have reasonable suspicion that you did steal something they could arrest you or stop you.
Speaker 0: But yes, I mean they could always try to citizens arrest you or something like that.
Speaker 0: But if they got it wrong man, are they in trouble?
Speaker 1: I guess the moral is don't ever detain another human being Unless you are an officer of the law.
Speaker 0: or unless you are like if you see someone beating someone up you can detain them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or do you see like if you see someone like hit someone with their car and try to run away?
Speaker 0: You can detain them too.
Speaker 0: Probably you'll be fine.
Speaker 0: I imagine.
Speaker 1: but if someone opened your Simpsons bust You can't lock them in your store and demand payment.
Speaker 0: That's just the tough shit rule.
Speaker 0: So also if you own a store don't put anything expensive in a precarious position.
Speaker 1: Yes, because then it's your fault if it breaks.
Speaker 0: Yes, oh.
Speaker 0: and one last thing if you go out of a store just like the receipt if the security system goes off You can just keep walking.
Speaker 0: Also, however, I give you two pieces of advice.
Speaker 0: Number one if you're shopping for clothing You probably want to turn around because you're not gonna be able to get those tags off at home without getting ink all over your clothes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and number two You might want to look in your bag before you just keep walking because what if someone like slips something in there and you are Shoplifting and you don't know it?
Speaker 1: or what?
Speaker 1: If you just forgot and you have something in your pocket or an extra bag or something under the card or whatever?
Speaker 0: but if you're sure that you're not shoplifting and you're sure that you know all the security devices have been removed from your products so that you can take them home and not worry about It and the security thing goes off when you walk through don't even hesitate.
Speaker 0: Just keep walking.
Speaker 0: See, I'm usually no one.
Speaker 0: don't just keep walking.
Speaker 1: See if they ask for my receipt and it's not a good inconvenience I'll just stop and show it to him cuz I don't care.
Speaker 1: But Generally, it's been the case where I'll be trying to leave a Best Buy or something and there'll be a line at the receipt checker Guy, because there's only one guy and a bunch of people trying to leave and there's no way I'm waiting.
Speaker 1: I'm only gonna stop if it's convenient.
Speaker 0: It's basically never convenient for me.
Speaker 1: I'm never in that much of a hurry.
Speaker 1: the two seconds as I wave the receipt at him and then he nods me by.
Speaker 0: Maybe I could have a policy of throw the receipt at the guy and keep walking.
Speaker 1: Yeah fashion into a paper airplane be like, here you go.
Speaker 1: Yep What would be really funny is if you'd written on the receipt I stole a TV, haha.
Speaker 0: And then if I didn't what would happen if they called the police, ah I'm not a lawyer.
Speaker 0: Yeah That'd be kind of a weird situation like you sort of lying that you committed a crime but not to a police officer not under Oath.
Speaker 1: I know part of an investigation and it's not illegal in and of itself to lie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know I mean like what if I tell you hey rim, I killed somebody?
Speaker 1: I think you're within your rights to do that.
Speaker 0: However, I think by the same token, but then if you call the police and I didn't kill someone can I get in trouble?
Speaker 1: See I think by the same token the worst that would happen is the police would have the right to investigate you.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, that would because yeah It does create a probable cause.
Speaker 1: see I think the punishment for that while it is not a punishment of law like alright You broke the law by lying.
Speaker 1: whatever the punishment is you've now got the attention of the police.
Speaker 1: They're probably slightly displeased with you.
Speaker 1: Okay, all right the hunger oh good guy is never-ending with the wolf.
Speaker 1: All right, this is unequivocally the worst Music video ever made.
Speaker 0: I remember that willow whatever that's got nothing on this.
Speaker 0: This is worse than that.
Speaker 1: So all I'm gonna say and I really think you need to watch this and I'll warn you The song might get stuck in your head.
Speaker 1: I'm having some so bad though I don't know how it happens, but it is it's stuck in my head.
Speaker 1: I keep thinking about it.
Speaker 1: I have to force it out with other things.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's so bad.
Speaker 1: Basically, this is the kind of thing that would have been awesome to me when I was 12.
Speaker 0: I would never be awesome to me I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe not this specifically but the kind of aesthetic of the dark and brooding whatever blah blah blah But maybe for a goth kid more importantly emo kid.
Speaker 1: This is very much Reminiscent of pretty much everything that I saw like every Personality traits that I saw in many of the larpers that we knew back at our IT.
Speaker 0: That's what it is Like.
Speaker 1: I think the moment that really crystallized that for me Was when he falls into the middle of a white wolf larp Basically and all the vampires sitting at their tables in their cloaks walk toward him menacingly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was sort of out there basically the poorly rendered Anubis.
Speaker 1: When Anubis slaps him and then they go on a vacation to our bad CG Egypt Yeah on the bad CG boat on the bad CG Nile.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: This is I. You know, some things are so bad that they're good because you know, they're so bad that you laugh at how bad it is.
Speaker 0: This is just so bad.
Speaker 0: But yet at the same time this is worse than like great digital target.
Speaker 1: It's almost Mesmerizing.
Speaker 1: you have trouble looking away.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: No, I don't have any trouble looking away now.
Speaker 1: What's really funny is that if you look at this, I'm reasonably certain that one the guy who did it the main guy somehow Feels that this is indicative of the feelings.
Speaker 1: He feels inside - I'd wager there's a girl He likes who's with some other guy who isn't crazy and he feels like they should be together.
Speaker 1: And this is kind of a cry for help to her to show her how he really feels.
Speaker 1: I also think that he basically wrote a fanfiction about himself and then Mary sued himself into it.
Speaker 0: All those things are true.
Speaker 0: Also, I'm pretty sure the guy who made this thinks that this is actually really good when it's the worst thing ever.
Speaker 0: So I wonder what sort of movies and TV shows and books does he like now?
Speaker 0: I know who's buying all those really crappy books at the pin the sci-fi.
Speaker 1: He probably plays white wolf but with his own variant.
Speaker 1: because he dislikes the cam and their political bullshit.
Speaker 1: He probably larbs to the exclusion of all else.
Speaker 1: I'll bet he wears a lot of black.
Speaker 1: I'll bet he's a neo-pagan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll bet he didn't graduate from college.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that's that's it.
Speaker 0: I would not bet against you.
Speaker 1: I recommend watching this once and never ever watching it again.
Speaker 0: If you need to show it to someone else just send them the link don't watch it with them or at least turn it on And then walk out of the room because watching it more than once is probably going to damage you somehow.
Speaker 1: god That's kind of like the goat see Bob.
Speaker 1: go to a website That'll show a goat see after a couple minutes and then just leave the room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a good one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what do you got for me?
Speaker 0: So it's video game action here.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's a video on YouTube and I'd say this video is an ingenious work of art.
Speaker 1: I'll agree in that if it was exactly what I expected which was somewhat unexpected I know that sounds strange, but that's how I feel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this this video is called Goombas lifetime.
Speaker 0: it shows you the life of a Goomba and there's not much else to say about it.
Speaker 0: It's art.
Speaker 1: What can we say?
Speaker 0: That's it, right?
Speaker 1: So we bought a bunch of board games a while ago that we keep talking about how we're going to talk about and this past Weekend, we did something we haven't done in a long time.
Speaker 1: Instead of having no one over or the entire front row crew over.
Speaker 1: we had one person over and we played board games pretty much All weekend.
Speaker 0: Ah, we haven't had one of those in a long time.
Speaker 1: It was pretty awesome particularly the fact that we played tigers and Euphrates which is still far away two times My favorite game ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah However, I do want to get this gripe out into the world since now I have an audience for it.
Speaker 1: I won the first game pretty handily but no biggie the second game.
Speaker 1: while I might not have won it I definitely would have not have lost so much had Scott not given the game to Alex.
Speaker 0: Yeah I really that was sort of accidental there.
Speaker 1: Scott built a gigantic point generating machine and then basically said Alex I entrust this to you and then he proceeded to bumble around the board for the next 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: I had a plan in which I would gay I would remain retain control of that point generating machine.
Speaker 0: I also had a backup plan Scott and both of those plans failed miserably.
Speaker 1: I uh, I don't think you thought your clever plan quite all the way through.
Speaker 0: No, not all the way through only as much of the way through as I usually think it which yes It's sufficient most of the time but it's not as sometimes it just goes downhill.
Speaker 1: What can you do about it course Pete who has a good history of winning the game?
Speaker 1: Ended up losing and I note that this was one of the few times he deviated from his classic strategy of fill one corner of The board with squares.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is all.
Speaker 0: that's pretty much the default strategy.
Speaker 0: You know in order to win you have to beat that and in order to lose you got to do worse than that.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like the guaranteed average.
Speaker 0: You know Strategy and then if you can pull off a couple great moves on top of that like some big external conflicts Maybe a monument.
Speaker 0: You're got a good chance of winning the game with that one man.
Speaker 1: That's a good game.
Speaker 1: Oh, I want to talk about it again sometime.
Speaker 1: But if you guys buy Tiger's and Euphrates, right?
Speaker 1: It's Great.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we're not talking about that tonight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you go to board game geek calm, the number one game is Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: All right, the number two game is Tiger's and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: The number four game is Kayla's.
Speaker 1: now These are.
Speaker 0: I would say that these are my number one two and four games the number three game a game that We haven't played ever until I bought it just a week or two ago.
Speaker 0: Think about that.
Speaker 0: the number one two and four games.
Speaker 0: we bought him and we played him a whole lot.
Speaker 0: Number three game didn't play.
Speaker 0: I played it two or three.
Speaker 0: We played it three times now, right?
Speaker 1: Yep I've won two of those three.
Speaker 0: just gonna get number three game I've played three times in my life and I just bought it recently is called power grade.
Speaker 1: We had heard about power grid often for many people.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We'd always seen it wanted it thought about it Just never ended up getting it.
Speaker 0: and I to this day I've seen it at all kinds of conventions and it's just one of those.
Speaker 0: You know, we can only get so many games at once and it was just we never chose to get it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Why not course?
Speaker 0: now we've basically wasn't.
Speaker 0: there wasn't a reason.
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 0: It was just there never was a reason to get it.
Speaker 1: But now I mean we're looking at the top 10 on board game geek and we realized that we love and own or have at least Played pretty much all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we need to get.
Speaker 1: we own Florence almost all of them.
Speaker 0: Yep So power grid the first thing about power grid.
Speaker 0: is that the art on the box and the pieces and the cards?
Speaker 0: I like it a lot.
Speaker 0: It's really cool.
Speaker 1: There's a I don't know what it is Like.
Speaker 1: the theme is very unified kind of like targets and your freighters where the theme is not important.
Speaker 1: The theme has nothing to do with the game proper other than you know, adding flavor and making it make sense more.
Speaker 1: But it really feels good.
Speaker 0: I Like the way the cards look.
Speaker 0: I like the way the power plants are drawn.
Speaker 0: I like the like all the wooden cubes.
Speaker 0: I like the box.
Speaker 0: It's just awesome.
Speaker 1: I like the fact that two of the power plants.
Speaker 1: There's two wind power plants, right?
Speaker 1: They both produce the same amount of power.
Speaker 1: one of them just costs somewhat significantly more money.
Speaker 1: it's just and the only difference in the art between the two is that the more expensive one has one more tiny little wind turbine in The background.
Speaker 1: that doesn't do anything.
Speaker 0: So the next thing you notice about this game is the rule book.
Speaker 0: now I read the rule book before playing the game cuz usually when I get a new board game I just read the rules and I look at all the pieces.
Speaker 0: and you know I may read the rules two or three times before we actually play.
Speaker 0: and The rules at least the English rules in the Rio Grande version of power grid Which I assume is the version you're gonna get if you buy it like we tell you to.
Speaker 0: they're written Really poorly.
Speaker 1: They're not the worst rules I've ever read, but they're really really bad and it acts technically.
Speaker 1: A lot of the game is actually kind of ambiguous.
Speaker 1: The only reason we know what to do is because we just you make assumptions.
Speaker 0: Yes, and there's a lot of things the game doesn't explicitly say but you're safe and reasonable assumption.
Speaker 0: It is correct 99% of the time, but I can't have a rule book that leaves me assuming the rules.
Speaker 0: That's just.
Speaker 0: that doesn't work for me.
Speaker 0: We need to have every rule written down now.
Speaker 0: granted, you know You can take this argument to the extreme and say well Do you need the rules to say take your thumb and forefinger and clasp the wooden cube with enough force so that the Friction will prevent it from falling out of your hands when you elevate your?
Speaker 0: you don't need that.
Speaker 0: But you do need to have enough rules so that someone who knows the English language and knows you know What has a big enough vocabulary?
Speaker 0: Will not have any questions at least read the rules at least.
Speaker 1: it's not like to call which was okay but they had fluff.
Speaker 1: they had extra information in the rules that had no bearing on the game and Wasn't even historical or interesting.
Speaker 1: like you can move guys around.
Speaker 1: So in the rules, it says the guys move via secret tunnels.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: I needed to know that.
Speaker 0: a teleport secret tunnel Secret tunnel, there are no actual secret tunnels in Tikal.
Speaker 1: They just teleport Yeah, but they tell you the secret tunnels for no good.
Speaker 0: Never mind Yes, so once you get past that the next problem in power grid see good art bad rules.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that once you do understand all the rules, even if you understand them perfectly Some of the rules are kind of arbitrary Like there's just a table on the back of the instruction book that says you have this number of players.
Speaker 0: Is this the circumstance in the current game?
Speaker 0: Well, this is how many new resources come into play and there's a table.
Speaker 0: I don't like tables.
Speaker 0: tables are no good.
Speaker 0: It's basic.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's other arbitrary rules too like you know.
Speaker 0: if this happens and this happens then remove a card from the game and put it here and put a card there and It's sort of annoying a little bit.
Speaker 1: Your best bet is to play this game at a con or somewhere where someone else at least one person knows the rules inside and out and has already played so they can teach you how to play and then play the first game with You and then you'll be you'll be set.
Speaker 0: you'll be set because people who know how to play the game know how to play.
Speaker 0: Now once you get beyond those two things though power grid is awesome.
Speaker 0: I don't know how they pulled it off where all these arbitrary rules actually work really well But all these arbitrary confusing rules work really well.
Speaker 1: I think what I really like about the game is that it has the wooden cube game feel because there's different kinds of board games.
Speaker 1: So there's the tile lane games the exploration games, whatever but the cube games the wooden cube games.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of wooden cubes and you manipulate them around the board Always have this kind of really hardcore feel to them and I always liked him a lot like el grande is a good example of That.
Speaker 1: yep, and while this isn't really a wooden cube game I feel the same feeling playing it that I feel playing a wooden cube game like it gives me that feeling of Beating my brain against a difficult and somewhat unsolvable math problem where I know that I can't figure out the perfect optimal move And I have to make a decision and a compromise.
Speaker 0: What power grid does I think is?
Speaker 0: there are many different tight, you know general genres of German board game.
Speaker 0: You know is the bidding game.
Speaker 0: There's the territory at you know game.
Speaker 0: There's the tile laying game and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: power grid is a bidding game a Economics management game and a Territory graph sort of manipulation game all in one.
Speaker 0: It's like three separate games all at once that all intertwine.
Speaker 1: yep, I mean basically really cool.
Speaker 1: you want to generate power for houses that you put on the board and you build houses on the Board and you can make connections through the nodes and different connections cost different amounts of money.
Speaker 1: so you have to deal with all that and You power these with power plants that you bid on and each power plant Requires a different kind of fuel and a different amount of a different kind of fuel and powers different amounts of houses.
Speaker 0: More expensive power plants can are either more efficient meaning they make more electricity for less resources or They make more electricity for more resources.
Speaker 0: It kind of goes in a cycle like first there'll be a power plant that makes like two Electricity for three coal.
Speaker 0: then there'll be one that makes two electricity for two coal.
Speaker 0: then there'll be one that makes three electricity for three coal and you know, Then there'll be three electricity for two coal and four electricity for three coal and so on and so on and so on.
Speaker 1: and so now the market dynamics are really interesting.
Speaker 1: I mean say I buy coal gets more and more out there.
Speaker 1: there's more coal coming out throughout the game until the end when it starts to dry up.
Speaker 1: so by the mid game there's a ton of coal coming out.
Speaker 1: but if three different players all have a bunch of coal power plants suddenly coal starts becoming really expensive and really rare.
Speaker 0: yeah cuz the same number of three people buying them.
Speaker 0: if you don't get to buy them first and other people buy them first then you're gonna have to buy really expensive coal or not buy coal and it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: so a lot of the game is trying to stay ahead of the curve figuring out what other people have and what other people want and trying to always put yourself in the market where you can buy what you need to run your power plants for the least money.
Speaker 0: yeah basically the way the game goes.
Speaker 0: in summary cuz I'm not gonna go through all the crazy rules God is that on your turn someone we auction off power plants and at most you can buy one power plant per turn.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: so everyone buys a power plant and you there's a really good one out there.
Speaker 0: everyone's gonna fight over it and if there's a crappy one no one will buy it.
Speaker 1: and God I love the bidding just because the way we play like they'll be a power plant that comes out in the minimum bids 40 and Scott and I go back and forth and it'll be like 40 41 42 100 101 300 300 and -.
Speaker 1: yeah for some reason I really enjoy that.
Speaker 0: yeah it's a pretty fun bidding and you're trying to get better power plants you know and that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: having better power plants is super important but at the same time you don't want to spend too much because right after you buy power plants you have to buy resources to power those power plants and basically everyone takes one turn and the worst whoever's in last place goes first and they get to buy as many resources they can as they can.
Speaker 0: hold they they don't have to buy that many but they can.
Speaker 0: they could buy as many or as little as they want up to the amount they can hold in their storage areas which are your power plants.
Speaker 0: and then the next person buys and the next person buys.
Speaker 0: next person buys until everyone had a turn buying resources and basically each turn.
Speaker 0: at the end of the turn more resources come out and then after we buy power plants everyone buys all the resources.
Speaker 0: and that's it now.
Speaker 0: when more resources come out they get cheaper because there's more out there and when people buy them they get more expensive because there's less out there.
Speaker 0: yep supply and demand going.
Speaker 1: there's four kinds of resources coal oil trash and uranium.
Speaker 1: yep and like uranium starts out really expensive and gets cheaper as time goes on and trash gets cheaper as time goes on and oil gets slightly cheaper and coal gets more expensive.
Speaker 1: and there's all these sorts of dynamics.
Speaker 0: yep it depends a whole lot but they're also power plants like mostly wind solar and fusion at the end that give you electricity without using any resources and they're pretty good.
Speaker 0: they're really good but at the same time they also cost a lot more than power plants that use resources and they're also not capable of producing as much electricity total like the fusion.
Speaker 0: I think what makes five or six right?
Speaker 0: yeah and there's a trash one that makes seven which is a big deal.
Speaker 0: after everyone buys resources you put houses on the map and I'm gonna go through all the details of putting houses on the map.
Speaker 0: but basically it costs money to put houses on the map.
Speaker 0: you cannot.
Speaker 0: you're trying to get as many houses on the map as you can because let's say I have three power plants that make a total of ten electricity.
Speaker 0: if I only have nine houses that means I can only power nine houses even though it would normally be able to power ten.
Speaker 1: yes a power plant that powers three powers three no matter what if you power even if you only have one house.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 0: so if you want to get you know the maximum you know bang for your buck you want to have the same number of houses as you can power.
Speaker 0: that way.
Speaker 0: you didn't buy extra houses.
Speaker 0: you can't power.
Speaker 1: granted I'll note that I've won two of the three times we played.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I didn't do that at all.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying getting.
Speaker 0: that's the way to get the most bang for your buck not the way to win.
Speaker 0: yeah and you don't want to have more power plants than you have houses because then you're making all this electricity you're not using anyway.
Speaker 1: suffice to say the game is a race to the finish of who builds you like once someone builds a certain number of houses then the game is going to end and then at that point whoever powers the most houses wins not whoever has the most house.
Speaker 1: yeah for example the gate.
Speaker 1: I don't think we need to go into the details of that.
Speaker 1: no no no at all.
Speaker 0: but I'm saying there was an awesome game.
Speaker 0: we played the second game.
Speaker 0: we played where we thought the game was gonna end in two turns and I realized wait a minute Alex didn't.
Speaker 1: Alex did one thing so he wasn't gonna power all his stuff this turn to save up money to bust out next turn.
Speaker 0: he purposefully thought the game was gonna end in two turns.
Speaker 0: he purposefully did not buy resources.
Speaker 0: that way he could buy a whole bunch on the last turn and win.
Speaker 0: rim ended the game.
Speaker 0: that turn instead of the next turn.
Speaker 0: Alex is unable to power because he didn't buy resources and he's super lost even though he was I guess technically ahead of me.
Speaker 1: I had fewer houses than anyone but I could power more of them at that one instant where I ended the game.
Speaker 1: it was awesome.
Speaker 0: yeah that's a good move.
Speaker 1: I want interest.
Speaker 1: one thing I really like about the game is that like Scott said the last player goes first.
Speaker 1: this game is the opposite of age of steam.
Speaker 1: the catch-up mechanics are very well crafted and you can't lose the game based on a bad decision early on.
Speaker 1: you can't have a bad time of it but you're always going to be progressing and if you screw up and no one else screws up you're still gonna lose.
Speaker 1: but in general every round you reset the turn order and whoever's doing the worst gets a little bit of a boost every round.
Speaker 0: yep and this is pretty.
Speaker 0: it's actually really well balanced even though it's kind of arbitrary and you know the rules are kind of a. but I guess the fact that it's arbitrary it was coldly calculated to be exactly perfect where if you just decide to suck on purpose and stay last you're not gonna get enough of a boost to help you beat everyone.
Speaker 0: that's not gonna have I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think you will because I often would keep myself in last place for a long time.
Speaker 0: but it's you can win.
Speaker 0: you're not precluded from winning.
Speaker 0: it's not like oh I'm in last I can't catch up but you're not guaranteed to win by staying in last.
Speaker 1: it's not this.
Speaker 0: aha by sucking I can win.
Speaker 1: I think my point was more that kind of like a choir where you want to shoot for second place to actually win the game.
Speaker 1: yep in this game it's already.
Speaker 1: it's even like when you play initial D with the rubber band effect on you can advance players use the rubber band.
Speaker 1: they use the catch-up mechanism on purpose in order to get an advantage over other players.
Speaker 0: yes for example if I have the best power plants on the board right they're super efficient and I have a lot of money it might be and often is opportunistic to not build any houses in a turn.
Speaker 0: everyone else will build houses maybe and thus I will go last even though I'm probably in the most powerful position in the game.
Speaker 0: thus next turn I combine that boost of going first and buying resources first along with my super efficient power plants and my current fistful of dollars and I take a double jump ahead and now way ahead.
Speaker 0: beat that you can use it pretty smartly.
Speaker 1: I mean it's just.
Speaker 1: it's a fantastic game.
Speaker 1: I think we're eventually gonna get sick of it but not anytime soon.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean this game definitely does feel like a game that could be figured out to a point where you just be like yeah yeah yeah yeah but it's so.
Speaker 0: there's so much to it.
Speaker 0: I mean I'd probably first have to figure out you know the houses optimization which I think I'm getting close to that and then you got to figure out the resource buying optimization.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: it's not any harder to solve than any other game but I have to solve three or four games.
Speaker 1: well also because a lot of people make alternate maps for it and they all work fine.
Speaker 1: the game just deals with it because it's a market.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: so whatever you modify the game to do by changing power plants or adding power plants or changing maps the game's still gonna work because the market evens everything out.
Speaker 1: so the moment we solve the game all we have to do is add a bunch of power plants and change the rules a little bit.
Speaker 0: I do really think I do think that's very cool.
Speaker 0: is that the the designer of this game Friedman fries who's a cool German guy with green hair.
Speaker 0: he's like all punk awesomeness.
Speaker 0: he he said that he designed the original map based on realistic Germany or at least what he thought.
Speaker 1: you know general German geography and so didn't he say that he didn't take game balance into account at all.
Speaker 0: pretty much and the map works just fine and the map pretty much will.
Speaker 0: you could just make any random map for this game and it'll most likely just work because everyone is playing on the exact same map.
Speaker 0: it's a perfectly even playing field.
Speaker 0: so if the map could just be like you know completely random and the game would probably work just fine.
Speaker 1: now this game is no Tigers and Euphrates it's not the best.
Speaker 0: no it's late.
Speaker 1: however if you like a hard-hitting hardcore German board gaming experience this game is right up your alley.
Speaker 0: if you like power plants electricity and cool graphics and playing with little wooden coals and oil barrels and uraniums is also a good game.
Speaker 1: and on that note I kind of want to fry some rice.
Speaker 1: so I think we're done you're done.
Speaker 0: those are.
Speaker 1: that was pretty quick not really we've gone on long enough I think all right.
Speaker 1: plus we've been kind of filling up the lips in with a lot of long episodes lately.
Speaker 1: okay good this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays we have video games board games and RPGs Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: you can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.