Speaker 0: It's Tuesday December 25th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight the Mario tennis.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: well, it's a Christmas.
Speaker 0: well, no one's gonna be listening.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess we are gonna put this show up tonight, aren't we?
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could save this show for next week.
Speaker 0: I forgot you started.
Speaker 0: I was confused for a second.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh the show's going not going up tonight.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes it is.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is yeah, I think what confused you is that we're trying to record ahead.
Speaker 0: maybe maybe.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, we're gonna dispense with all that and get right to what's important in life, which is video games.
Speaker 0: video games Which I still not playing enough of correctly.
Speaker 1: You're playing plenty of video games.
Speaker 1: you sit down in the living room playing stupid guitar hero constantly.
Speaker 0: I know I need to go and beat that new trauma center and that Mario Galaxy and stuff, which I'm not doing.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe if you stop playing guitar hero, maybe.
Speaker 1: but maybe if you practice your real harmonica.
Speaker 0: But the plastic guitar is so much easier.
Speaker 1: You know the real harmonica.
Speaker 1: I can play songs on harmonica much easier than you can beat through the fire through the flames on expert.
Speaker 0: No, I can kind of almost beat it on hard, but I can beat a whole bunch of songs on hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Alright anyway, so what do you have for me?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's our opening bit.
Speaker 0: That was wonderful.
Speaker 1: Well, we do have the dune game.
Speaker 1: Oh Finally got a hold of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah kind of did a little eBay auction got it for 40-something bucks.
Speaker 0: We didn't talk about this last week.
Speaker 1: I don't think we did not in any detail.
Speaker 1: We've played the dune game.
Speaker 1: Finally.
Speaker 0: Yeah it.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it might be a good game, but I think it's not a very good two-player game.
Speaker 1: It's definitely not a good two-player game.
Speaker 0: I mean it says you can play a two-player but it's lying.
Speaker 1: Well, you see what happened was Scott and I were gonna play the dune game.
Speaker 0: So, uh, ah Scott picks the old ladies and I and I chose them at random by the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then you are deliberately chose the old ladies the second time.
Speaker 0: Well, I said I wanted.
Speaker 0: I thought that you know since I was already familiar with the rules of the old ladies that I could You know play better on the second go after learning how to play from the first go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the Harkonnen can't lose in two-player.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We should test it out and see.
Speaker 0: but they're pretty strong right away because they get fistful of cards for almost nothing and they have a fistful is spice right away and I have to like if I'm the old ladies I have to fight to get spice and fight to get cards and I realize
Speaker 1: for your right to spice
Speaker 0: It's really difficult.
Speaker 1: I think what seals this game for me is that what so Encapsulates the dune universe is that you have this board and it shows this planet whatever and there are only two piles of cards.
Speaker 1: You have spice and you have treachery.
Speaker 0: Yep Right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got in the news?
Speaker 1: Okay, not a better opening bit you have here with that.
Speaker 0: no, okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you know impossible mission not mission impossible, but impossible mission, you know that game.
Speaker 1: I recall that game vaguely.
Speaker 1: I never really liked it.
Speaker 0: Ah, it's.
Speaker 1: it's one of those Classic amazing games that no one actually likes but everyone talks about.
Speaker 0: no, no one actually likes this game.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: it's incredibly impossible and difficult platforming game where there's like endless similar looking hallways and doors and Elevators and all sorts of shit like that and the game is called impossible mission for a reason because the game is basically impossible and I didn't realize this but it was originally on the Commodore 64, but the version I know was on the NES and Some people remember this game fondly.
Speaker 0: but it's one of those sort of like he-man things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if he actually went back to play he'd realize that your dad was just childhood memories and not reality.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway Somebody's remaking this game I think for DS and we and I think the DS version might already be out.
Speaker 0: But I think well, actually I'm sure that whether when it is out if it even if it's out now It's a GameStop exclusive.
Speaker 0: so you can only get this game a GameStop and nowhere else.
Speaker 0: I think that sort of ass like someone's making a game and only selling it at one store.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go to GameStop.
Speaker 1: I like GameStop less and less as time goes on.
Speaker 0: I know where were the Amazon exclusive video games.
Speaker 0: help me out here.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I think that's pretty interesting.
Speaker 0: Someone's doing retailer exclusive video games.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like, huh?
Speaker 0: Why do you even make it in the first place?
Speaker 0: Like how you get a profit off?
Speaker 0: I mean they selling it for 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: Maybe it was just a really cheap game to make I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe they figured they'd get some hype from the fact that it's only being sold at GameStop.
Speaker 1: I'm sure GameStop is trying to bundle it with all sorts of things.
Speaker 1: Maybe but hey check this out only 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: Hey only 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: check this out 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: But like who seriously is gonna go to GameStop just for this game, you know I mean that's the reason you have an exclusive thing Right, like you have an exclusive game on the Xbox 360 because you want people to buy a 360 just for the game.
Speaker 0: You have an exclusive game in your store because you want people to come to your store just for that game.
Speaker 0: Who's coming to GameStop just for Impossible Mission DS?
Speaker 1: Admittedly the only time I ever the only thing I ever look at in GameStops nowadays is use games because I'm just gonna buy new games On eBay or on Amazon.
Speaker 0: Yeah selling game.
Speaker 0: You know GameStop is pretty much only useful for buying used stuff.
Speaker 0: It's not useful for selling you stuff because you get a better deal on eBay, but buying you stuff It's you know more convenient than eBay, I guess.
Speaker 0: but yeah GameStop, I mean what else that's gonna get me to come to your store?
Speaker 0: You need like an exclusive like Mario Galaxy GameStop only then maybe I'd come to GameStop.
Speaker 1: I mean I'd say oh But you should go to a GameStop or something when a console comes out to get it early But you can buy a console at Best Buy.
Speaker 0: You can buy a console on Amazon and just wait.
Speaker 1: I still remember when I was in Times Square and I tried to go buy some DS lights and I saw the pile of Wiis and the people physically fighting over them.
Speaker 1: and Just is there a Wii?
Speaker 1: No, and they're totally sold out of DS's and everything.
Speaker 1: And then I go to a Radio Shack not that far away from there and there's Wiis and DS lights.
Speaker 1: Yep So in other news I stumbled upon this when I was looking for news to talk about because I haven't really gone to Kotaku in a while.
Speaker 1: I just haven't had time to poke around the internet.
Speaker 0: that he's the Google Reader like everybody.
Speaker 1: Even then I don't subscribe because I don't care enough.
Speaker 1: Very little of what token Kotaku tells me is anything I would care about unless that's true.
Speaker 0: I just don't read.
Speaker 0: Let's see how much let's see.
Speaker 0: Let's let me check my Google Reader and it will tell me how much of Kotaku I actually read.
Speaker 1: The only time I read Kotaku or any site like that is one if I'm looking for something to talk about on geek nights or Two if I'm bored and seeking entertainment on the internet, and I am right.
Speaker 1: I have not been bored enough to seek entertainment on the internet in a while.
Speaker 0: So in forever, right?
Speaker 0: I've read a hundred and forty stories on Kotaku through my Google Reader.
Speaker 0: That's 11%.
Speaker 0: So only 11% of Kotaku stories are actually read by me.
Speaker 0: The other 89% are ignored.
Speaker 0: Way to go go talking Right.
Speaker 1: Well, they've kind of have a semi.
Speaker 1: They're really the best source for that kind of news.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, but there's this game coming out on the PSP called pat upon.
Speaker 1: That's upon and pat upon looks kind of I feel like more and more.
Speaker 1: I'm eventually going to be forced to buy a PSP.
Speaker 1: What I Mean if I'll when I can pay 80 bucks for a PSP I'm probably gonna buy a PS by the time.
Speaker 0: then PSPs will be done for That's fine.
Speaker 0: You can emulate PSP games.
Speaker 1: I think the point is that I want to play him on the go.
Speaker 1: I could podcast with it still I guess I guess.
Speaker 0: But you could podcast better with other things.
Speaker 1: what my iPod?
Speaker 1: that doesn't have Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know right my cell phone They can't do.
Speaker 0: problem is it's too big.
Speaker 0: So it's like carry on this giant thing in your pocket.
Speaker 0: try to listen mp3s.
Speaker 1: I get the PSP slim.
Speaker 0: It's still.
Speaker 0: it's still giant.
Speaker 0: It's not anything less wide.
Speaker 1: It's just game.
Speaker 1: It's almost the same for what I can tell to that old SNES King Arthur game.
Speaker 1: or yet it's kind of like lemmings.
Speaker 1: but instead of Helpless stupid lemmings you have Knights and wizards and you tell them to march right and they fight with things and do stuff.
Speaker 1: but To control the game instead of telling things what to do.
Speaker 1: it looks like you just have to play the right rhythm and it's a rhythm game.
Speaker 1: and Dang in how rhythmic you are your soldiers will do different things.
Speaker 0: That sounds pretty good to me.
Speaker 0: I mean, I looked at the screenshots of this game and I watched a little video and it seems like You know Sony in general is really ever since Katamari is really going after these games with the sort of cute Graphic design and interesting gameplay like they got
Speaker 1: just then.
Speaker 0: remember they got that flow game.
Speaker 1: remember way before Viv Riven.
Speaker 0: Yep, they got the Viv Riven.
Speaker 0: They got the loco roko.
Speaker 0: They got all those kind of games.
Speaker 0: Sony is really sort of fighting and doing everything They can to keep those games on their system and really those are the only games they have that I'm interested in.
Speaker 0: But I'm kind of interested in them but not interested enough to actually buy any a Sony console.
Speaker 1: What this does show at least is that the PSP is a viable second place Which we've talked about how crazy that is before.
Speaker 1: but if you don't buy a PSP to play this game But if you already have a PSP, you would better be playing this game once you can get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much I mean, you know other rhythm games out there like the DDR And the guitar heroes.
Speaker 0: they're just sort of rhythm for the sake of rhythm.
Speaker 0: Well games like this I separate.
Speaker 1: I mean.
Speaker 1: the thing is this game is still all it is and we've talked about this before.
Speaker 1: What if you made a fighting game where you just do DDR and depending on how well you dance It just animates the whole fight and this game could be something like that?
Speaker 0: I think this is more like not how well you dance but you do different Dances to get the guy to do different moves.
Speaker 1: The only thing that worries me is that the dances are basically limited to hitting buttons on your PSP.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much this game would have been better if it came with some sort of bongo Maybe some sort of plastic.
Speaker 0: Well, you could get you could play.
Speaker 0: something like DK's was a jungle beat I think was the one.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah We use the bongos to control Donkey Kong.
Speaker 1: And it came with a spear that you put the Wii mode in and you had to shake the spear around and bang it on.
Speaker 1: Things no be all right, maybe bang the spear and shield together.
Speaker 1: It's very I don't know.
Speaker 1: the game is very stylish in that kind of way that these sorts of games always are and I got To admit the kind of
Speaker 0: I could just see it now a bunch of people playing multiplayer for people with shields and Spears banging them on each other like that shark
Speaker 1: Azula
Speaker 0: like it's some sort of Cave people like ook ook ook and it makes the people on the screen do things.
Speaker 1: I Think the much more important issue with having a bunch of Spears and shields is that kids gonna lose an eye pretty much immediately pretty much After that expensive vase gets knocked over.
Speaker 1: look smash vase doo doo be caveman be.
Speaker 0: How do we get from Pat upon PSP to caveman?
Speaker 1: one thing I can say though that for a rhythm game.
Speaker 1: It's got some very uh catchy rhythms going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was definitely rocking to those rhythms for sure.
Speaker 0: I would love to get like a little soundtrack or something.
Speaker 0: That'd be fun time I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like it's kind of music I could play in the background while I'm playing some other game to keep me concentrating.
Speaker 1: Yeah so things of the day be Mmm, dude My thing of day be I'd fuck that fuck it.
Speaker 1: So, uh Griefing is a time-honored tradition in first-person.
Speaker 0: She we talked about griefing before.
Speaker 1: if we haven't I think we're gonna do a show on it because griefing is really really horrible and stupid and it's this immature thing that a lot of people do.
Speaker 1: but at the same time if You can I guess transcend it and not be annoyed by it Like if it happens and you don't freak out about it and you can take it on this intellectual level.
Speaker 1: It is also hilarious.
Speaker 0: It can be hilarious in the right situations, you know, like a guy Killing someone then killing them when they respond then killing them immediately when they respond.
Speaker 0: That's not really funny.
Speaker 0: It can be funny.
Speaker 0: It can be funny if you've never seen it before or if you the idea of spawn camping itself was new to you Then it would be funny.
Speaker 0: Well like oh that's possible lol, but once you understand the idea of spawn camping is no longer funny.
Speaker 1: See I understood the idea of spawn camping But there was that one time when the cyberdemon was spawn camping me and Ken while we were trying to be tomb - okay I guess in a particular crazy situation like that.
Speaker 0: It could be funny like oh You know foreseen spawn camp situation lol, but you need to be a clever griefer.
Speaker 1: For example, I was playing a game of counter-strike once back when speed hacking was easy to do and rampant Especially if you had Windows 2000.
Speaker 1: Yep, so We're on the server and someone keeps accusing this one guy of cheating.
Speaker 1: He's like fucking cheater Yeah, and he's just yelling and this guy's cheating.
Speaker 1: So finally the guy's like I'm not cheating god damn it.
Speaker 1: Yes, you are.
Speaker 1: so the next round the guy appears in our spawn immediately as the round begins and Stabs us all to death before we can move and he says now I'm cheating fucker.
Speaker 1: But I know I always found speed hacks funny even even if they were really just annoying and griefing.
Speaker 0: I think they're.
Speaker 0: I think they're funny just because the way it looked when someone was speed hacking I'd be walking real slow.
Speaker 1: I stop at a corner.
Speaker 1: I yell.
Speaker 1: All right guys come in I come around the corner.
Speaker 0: Yeah It was that it was definitely the animation of the speed hack and the way it looked on the screen was funny Not the actual act of griefing with the speed hack itself.
Speaker 1: Now this video my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: there's a chance it was completely staged, but I give it a 60% chance maybe even a 70% chance of being fully legitimate.
Speaker 1: Yep, it looks like they got a couple of people on two different teams on the same server to collaborate for epic cross team griefing.
Speaker 0: Okay so basically the first thing they do is they set up some teleporters right and they set up the teleporter exit and then they Says they have buddies on the other team.
Speaker 0: They set up turrets.
Speaker 0: aiming is a steam fortress - by the way at the teleporter exits.
Speaker 0: so, of course if you're on a team you spot you spawn you go outside the teleporter there you go in it a turret immediately kills you and
Speaker 1: Eventually, I think my favorite moment in that is when this one guy's like guys Don't use the teleporter with the guy with all the stupid name with all the squares in it And then that guy's like up why it goes right to the enemy base.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they got sentries on it and then the guy the engineer the cheating collaborating engineer while stifling laughter says no Those turrets are gone man.
Speaker 1: Just go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's like if the turrets are there they would destroy the teleporter.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't be there.
Speaker 0: Just go go.
Speaker 0: the teleporter guy tells him the teleport dies.
Speaker 1: And that's only the beginning.
Speaker 1: and the the epic Lols that follow are quite worth while.
Speaker 0: the funniest part is they use this house with the scouts to lock everyone in the spawn Room, right and then they sort of refuse to let they could.
Speaker 0: just you know If that happens, you can just sort of change classes and then everyone can get out.
Speaker 0: They refuse to do that and they basically say alright everyone.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do a little game show.
Speaker 0: You have to answer our quiz questions and we'll let you out.
Speaker 1: What organ of the body produces bile?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you guys like gallbladder.
Speaker 0: guys like no not the gallbladders liver, which is wrong, but it's pretty fun.
Speaker 1: Actually the I think the best part of that is the one scout who's doing it instead of immediately saying alright I'm fucking with you guys time for a quiz show.
Speaker 1: He acts serious man.
Speaker 1: I'm stuck I don't know what to do and this one guy who doesn't get it is like just kill yourself.
Speaker 1: But but I don't want to mess up my stance and the guy loses it.
Speaker 1: Yeah guy just loses it.
Speaker 0: It's funny how these people like took it so seriously like you moron just just freaking you know on spawn But at the same time this one thing you just leave.
Speaker 0: if so if I'm gonna server and someone's pulling shit like that I just leave the server.
Speaker 0: It's funny how no one leaves the server.
Speaker 0: They just keep fighting the griefers.
Speaker 1: well at the same time if you're in the middle of a good game and it's It's almost fun when a clever griefer is there it's whenever anything weird happens in a moment.
Speaker 0: This guy is clearly not having fun with the griefer.
Speaker 0: He's clearly upset.
Speaker 0: I mean I would say if I was having fun with the griefer, but if I wasn't I would leave this guy.
Speaker 0: It's clearly not having fun yet.
Speaker 1: He's saying We just It's just it's funny and it's worth watching.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's been around the net for like a day or so.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, we're not news.
Speaker 1: We're commentary.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright, so check this video out.
Speaker 0: It's called Mario Troyd.
Speaker 0: Basically, it looks to me like it's hard to tell exactly what the story is with this thing, but it's pretty obvious.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought you were gonna do the blades of steel thing.
Speaker 1: You'll have to save that or save that.
Speaker 0: Yeah The guy took Mario and he took Metroid and you sort of combined him.
Speaker 0: It's it's definitely a Mario game or you're controlling Mario, but he can double jump like Samus but he jumps.
Speaker 0: the way Mario jumps, but he sort of has a double jump and then He can also has like permanent firepower and he might be invincible.
Speaker 0: I can't really tell.
Speaker 0: it's hard to tell from the video if he's invincible or not or how much life he is.
Speaker 1: I don't think it matters at all.
Speaker 1: This doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: you would actually play.
Speaker 1: he basically made this hack Just to create a cool video to look at on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it basically it's Mario but like in a Metroid world and all sorts of crazy stuff happens.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a really good mashup of Mario and Metroid ROM hack kind of deal.
Speaker 0: It is impressive looking It's very impressive and then at the end, there's an awesome boss thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a little long like you'll get bored of it after you watch it for a minute or two.
Speaker 0: So then just skip to where the boss is and you see the Metroids and stuff and it is the boss is Baby Metroids yellow baby Metroids and then you skip and the awesomeness at the end and then that's it.
Speaker 0: but this is worth five minutes of your time if you like Mario's or Metroids or combinations thereof right, so I don't think we've actually ever talked about this.
Speaker 1: I guess franchise this series of games, but Mario tennis has a long and illustrious history in the front row crew.
Speaker 0: Well, most people don't realize this.
Speaker 0: the very first Mario tennis game.
Speaker 0: Do you know what it was for?
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 1: Believe it was for the virtual boy.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was indeed for the virtual boy.
Speaker 0: It was a quote 3d game with only two colors of red and black.
Speaker 1: And if any of you have ever played a virtual boy, I got to say well if you haven't I guess It's.
Speaker 0: I imagine most listeners have not played.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 1: I have also.
Speaker 0: I in fact I played Mario tennis in a Toys R Us on a virtual boy.
Speaker 1: I played every game for the virtual boy.
Speaker 1: Wow every single one.
Speaker 1: How'd you do that?
Speaker 1: because they had him all for play admire Okay, and a friend of mine to this day owns his virtual boy.
Speaker 0: Yep I have a friend who also.
Speaker 1: he got it for Christmas right after it came out played it for like a week Got a headache every time he played it never played it again.
Speaker 1: Well one thing I can say the 3d effect was actually pretty damn impressive.
Speaker 0: It was it actually looked.
Speaker 0: when you're playing Mario tennis on the virtual boy it actually looked like you were very.
Speaker 0: Mario is very close to you and the other guy was very far away from you and it Was sort of a ball level view of the game.
Speaker 0: and it was.
Speaker 1: it was good stuff Yeah, and not the bad ball level the good ball level right.
Speaker 0: then again that Mario tennis was not exactly a great game.
Speaker 1: Well, it could have been.
Speaker 1: it was a pretty good game.
Speaker 0: The problem was a game.
Speaker 1: the virtual boy was an abortion to put it lightly.
Speaker 1: Lightly, well, I will talk about the virtual boy someday.
Speaker 1: and what exactly what the deal was there, but yeah Virtual boy, it's an important part of Nintendo history.
Speaker 0: Regardless there was also the original tennis for the NES which is a terrible game terrible.
Speaker 0: Absolutely unplayable.
Speaker 0: Don't even bother with it For the Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: not really so much tennis going on.
Speaker 0: Are you kidding?
Speaker 1: I forget what it was called, but there was one really awesome tennis game.
Speaker 1: Well, I I didn't know.
Speaker 1: I think it had a like.
Speaker 1: it was an Andre Agassi or something.
Speaker 1: I'll have to look it up.
Speaker 1: But all I remember is when I was a kid Children's Palace went out of business.
Speaker 1: They were like it used to be.
Speaker 1: there were two toy stores in America Yep, Toys R Us and Children's Palace.
Speaker 1: Yep, and Children's Palace went under.
Speaker 0: so they showed houses a crap hole.
Speaker 1: Children's Palace was nice.
Speaker 0: Actually ours was a shithole.
Speaker 1: Ours was really nice.
Speaker 0: I remember when they were going out of business and we went there.
Speaker 0: there was just toys just all over the floor everywhere.
Speaker 0: Who is the man?
Speaker 1: Well, that's because it was going out of business.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying before then though.
Speaker 0: It was still kind.
Speaker 0: it wasn't much messier when it was going out of business.
Speaker 1: When it was going out of business I my family and I it hit the point where finally there was an ad on TV one day that said next week Children's Palace for the last week of its existence 70% off Everything in the store video
Speaker 0: games video games video games.
Speaker 1: So, of course, I was there with my family in that that that that that chaos It was.
Speaker 1: it was amazing that no one died.
Speaker 1: yeah, it was just yelling and screaming and people knocking over shelves and rooting through things that had fallen off.
Speaker 1: and but We bought like a thousand dollars worth of toys.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well a thousand dollars before the discount.
Speaker 1: So but at one point I remember we went to the Nintendo section first as did every kid who was smart and there was nothing there.
Speaker 1: Now everyone else went oh And I said, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I was here when the store opened and I didn't see anyone checking out.
Speaker 1: There is no way that someone got here before me.
Speaker 1: They are somewhere in this store and sure enough There was a hidden part of the store where all the Nintendo and Super Nintendo games they had left were.
Speaker 1: We bought one of every unique game.
Speaker 1: That's where I got populace.
Speaker 1: I got this tennis game.
Speaker 1: I got some city and I got God I got a pile of games shitty games something good.
Speaker 1: This was a pretty damn good game.
Speaker 0: They're big come populist.
Speaker 0: DS is coming.
Speaker 1: I Think I knew that but I'd forgotten.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, man anyway anyway So Super Nintendo there was.
Speaker 0: I guess there were tennis games.
Speaker 0: I never played any of them and none of them were I guess epically famous or anything.
Speaker 0: and it wasn't until the n64.
Speaker 0: They came out with Mario tennis for the n64, there's also some Gameboy color and advanced versions.
Speaker 0: we don't care about those.
Speaker 0: But yet Mario tennis at the n64 was quite the game.
Speaker 1: I Mean that game along with Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: I think I started a whole new.
Speaker 1: I'd almost call it a genre of sports games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: it was like a party game yet It was also a sports game yet.
Speaker 0: It was a Mario game.
Speaker 1: Yep, cuz Smash Brothers has the same thing.
Speaker 1: It was a party game, but it was a fighting game, but it was a Mario game Yep, and it basically the game had a full loadout of characters of all different kinds.
Speaker 0: You know some were fast some were slow some hit hard.
Speaker 0: some hit not so hard.
Speaker 0: some were big.
Speaker 0: some were small.
Speaker 0: Some could do tricky stuff.
Speaker 0: some couldn't do tricky stuff.
Speaker 0: some controlled really nicely some controlled really slippery.
Speaker 0: It was you know, very well balanced across all the characters.
Speaker 0: you could play in your own style.
Speaker 0: It was actually a lot more complex than just hit the ball back and forth.
Speaker 0: you can hit the ball different ways with different shots and it was actually a strategy to it and doubles play worked really well and Just everything about.
Speaker 0: it was terrific.
Speaker 0: I mean it was basically it mean it's a tennis game, but really it's the evolution of Pong.
Speaker 0: I mean Pong was supposed to be table tennis.
Speaker 0: this is basically Pong except you also had to.
Speaker 0: you can move closer and farther away from the center line, which is the net and You have to actually push a button to hit the ball.
Speaker 0: Otherwise it goes past you.
Speaker 1: this game was like one of the best party games ever.
Speaker 1: when it came out It was.
Speaker 1: I never even owned an N64, but I knew about this game and we were at RIT actually Long into the GameCube era pretty much right up until the GameCube Mario Tennis came out.
Speaker 1: Every time we ran an event anytime we had a social night any sort of video game anything.
Speaker 1: Pretty much the most popular game was Mario Tennis for the N64.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'd have a doubles trash talk Mario Tennis tournament all the time, and it was great fun.
Speaker 0: It never failed.
Speaker 1: now granted the trash talk was probably the most important element of the Mario Tennis tournament.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the thing is once you're good enough and Mario Tennis it sort of becomes in a very even game of you know deuce advantage deuce Advantage deuce.
Speaker 0: I mean one game there one game here one game there one game.
Speaker 1: Scott And I have not played in a long time and before we did the show just now we pulled out Mario Tennis for the GameCube the current best tennis game in the world as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 1: Yeah, other than I don't know tennis.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: There's that virtue of tennis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is supposedly I guess that's the best realistic tennis game.
Speaker 1: if you want one yeah But the thing is realism and fun can coincide, but don't always coincide.
Speaker 0: no But I know I've played those virtue of tennis games, and they're pretty good.
Speaker 1: But Mario Tennis just has the perfect level of simplicity coupled with the perfect level of complexity to make it just great, but we played it and It was pretty much neck-and-neck the whole time and Scott barely won the first set and then I barely won the second set.
Speaker 1: So great, it's like we didn't even play.
Speaker 0: I got started because during one of the tie breaks I was up.
Speaker 0: I was up on top the whole time and I couldn't get down to the bottom and it sucked.
Speaker 1: See I can actually do better at the top than you do for some reason.
Speaker 0: Good at the top.
Speaker 0: see that is something about Mario Tennis right because you're only playing with one screen, right?
Speaker 0: It's one television.
Speaker 0: everyone is sharing it.
Speaker 0: right if you play multiplayer Someone's gonna be on the top half of the screen trying to hit the ball down.
Speaker 0: It's almost me.
Speaker 0: the bottom half is you're hitting the ball up.
Speaker 0: It's much easier to play when you're on the bottom of the screen hitting the ball up.
Speaker 0: now of course if you play enough games And sets it rotates you so you take turns being on top and bottom.
Speaker 0: But still being on top is kind of suck.
Speaker 0: It's not sucky.
Speaker 0: It's just not as good as being on bottom and ideally.
Speaker 0: Ideally there would be some way to play this game perhaps to the DS Where you know everyone could always be on bottom from their perspective?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if we could also have a some sort of Wi-Fi game where we could play it with two wheeze.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe yeah some Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: we Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: Normally, this is the part of the show where I'd talk about.
Speaker 1: you know how a Wi-Fi tennis could be great But I know Nintendo is gonna totally fuck that up and not make it worth a damn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course Nintendo's online play is a joke.
Speaker 1: It's laughable.
Speaker 0: It's worthless pretty much.
Speaker 1: I mean like what DS Wi-Fi tried it when it came out and since then Yeah, pretty much ignoring all Nintendo I remember I played a Mario Kart on the Wi-Fi and Everyone I played against quit as soon as I beat them, and it just wasn't fun Nope.
Speaker 1: Well also then after about a month.
Speaker 1: You couldn't even start a game because no one played anymore.
Speaker 0: Yep Maybe you can play right now, but I don't even.
Speaker 1: I don't even know where my Mario Kart is.
Speaker 0: I have done with that mine, but yeah, I'm done with that game also anyway, so Mario Tennis, what's this game like?
Speaker 0: Well first you basically his is how it's complex, but it's not too complex to be you know, stupid, right?
Speaker 0: So what are the controls?
Speaker 0: you have a and B that's it.
Speaker 0: Alright, you push a to hit the ball one way you push B to hit the ball the other way.
Speaker 0: But if you you know If you're depending on where your person is your character is in relation to the ball They'll do like a backhand or a forehand.
Speaker 0: so it's like if you want the ball to hook to the left you have to sort of you learn.
Speaker 0: it pretty quickly becomes Intuitive like where if you should push a or B to get the ball to go the way you want it to go.
Speaker 0: Well, that
Speaker 1: is one thing that I think this is what makes Mario Tennis really shine Is that most tennis games were either really simple to the point of not even being fun Yeah,
Speaker 0: it was just pong but you had to push a button
Speaker 1: or they were so complex that well to do a backhand You want to hold right and hit B but to do a forehand you want to hold left and hit a after you've stopped moving and to do a blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: But and those games were just impossible to play and not fun.
Speaker 1: Mario Tennis boiled it down to this somewhat intuitive system.
Speaker 1: and even better if you don't know the system exists if you just pick up a controller and play Mario Tennis having no idea or keep hitting a and always do the Asia or B or A and B And you'll no matter what you hit the game's gonna work.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's like there's multiple levels I can play the game at but someone who knows all the buttons is gonna own you because they're always gonna hit the ball far Away.
Speaker 0: who you can't reach it every time and you're gonna be screwed.
Speaker 1: Yep, and there's basically the game boils down to the front-back game and the left-right game much like real tennis.
Speaker 0: Yep you're either trying to hit the ball over the guy's head when he's very close to the net or Right or just over the net onto the ground when he's far away from the net or when he's to the right head to the left when he's the left hit it to the right and That's pretty much all there is.
Speaker 1: I used to play tennis with Luke actual tennis back at RIT and I remember that my strategy Was to win was pretty much Hit it to the left and right and left and right to make him run back and forth until he was too tired to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's it works really well.
Speaker 0: That's the only way to.
Speaker 0: that's how tennis works.
Speaker 1: Nah, really?
Speaker 0: Now as I'm our dentist works except for the tired part.
Speaker 1: now Scott seems to always play boo duh, which sometimes bites him in the arse because boo in see the doubles play will get to but in single play Boo has some substantial Drawbacks.
Speaker 0: Well, he's kind of slow, right?
Speaker 0: So the problem here is that if you play in a court with a fast ball speed Boo will sort of get owned because there's not much he can do to go after the ball cuz he's so slow.
Speaker 1: So so Scott whenever he wants to play against us always wants to use the slow ass courts.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Slow court is best for boo because boo has the trickiest shots.
Speaker 0: if boo gets the ball He can't hit it particularly hard, but you can always hit it in some tricky place and totally screw you up.
Speaker 0: He'll get you to come right up in front of the net and then I'll hit it way over the back your head and then What can you do?
Speaker 0: nothing of course.
Speaker 1: Some people prefer to use the kid Koopa who just as I recall in the most recent game Beat boo pretty handily wasn't even a tie break in the third set.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter He was hit.
Speaker 0: first of all, we won the same number of games.
Speaker 1: I won 17 gasps But all that matters in tennis is who wins the number of sets to get the match.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: and uh, I won two sets and there was no tiebreaker in that last set.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was still bullshit.
Speaker 0: Anyway, oh, yes Considering the fact that it was boo in singles who has a significant disadvantage in singles and I and I won the same number of Games as you playing on that slow car.
Speaker 0: No, that was the normal court.
Speaker 0: Yeah, your information not the slow court play on the fast court.
Speaker 1: See how you do.
Speaker 0: No, I won't be boo.
Speaker 1: I play a very Specified specific use character.
Speaker 0: I'd be probably paratroopa or Yoshi or something.
Speaker 1: See, I always like in kid Koopa no matter what it's cuz kid Koopa is sort of all-around ish.
Speaker 1: Well, no because I like kid Koopa when it comes to games like that.
Speaker 1: I pretty much Always choose the character.
Speaker 1: I like the most and then whatever style that character plays in.
Speaker 1: I'll just play in that style.
Speaker 0: That's what I do too.
Speaker 0: Except for You know, sometimes I pick the character.
Speaker 0: I like the most boo But occasionally there'll be a situation where the character can't win and in those cases, I won't pick those cases I'll keep playing my man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just lose on purpose.
Speaker 1: No, because that I have dedication and it increases my skill.
Speaker 1: and if I do win epic Yeah If what?
Speaker 0: if there's a what if you know that there's absolutely no chance of winning in the current set of Circumstances with the character you like?
Speaker 1: there's no Nintendo game That's like that except Mario Kart and it just so happened that in Mario Kart for the DS the character I liked was dry bones.
Speaker 1: who happens to be the unbeatable character?
Speaker 0: Good for you.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes, very good for me.
Speaker 0: I think the thing is, you know, what if you?
Speaker 0: what if there was a situation in which there was a course in which dry bones Could not possibly win.
Speaker 0: Would you pick dry bones on that course?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: All right anyway.
Speaker 0: So you hit A and B. One is like forehand ones backhand ish or like top spin and backspin or whatever they want to call it.
Speaker 0: But you can also go AB like you push A and then B really quickly not at the same time But one after the other like AB.
Speaker 0: if you do that You do this sort of lob move that hits it way up in the air and over the other guy's head or BA is You know, it'll come in.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can also go AA and BB and do like power shots.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh, that's right.
Speaker 0: If you do that, it's sort of a charge up shot.
Speaker 0: And yeah, yeah, that's right You charge it up and lady.
Speaker 0: That's why I won maybe but in uh What's it called in the original Mario tennis?
Speaker 0: Not the original but the n64 mario 10 the real original.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna bother pretend the virtual boy one doesn't exist as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: this to n64 GameCube And that's it and we in the future In that one.
Speaker 0: if there was always a problem where people would charge up their shots by accident And then when you're charging up, you can't really move So people would miss and be like fuck.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to charge up.
Speaker 1: There's a secret way around that that I didn't push.
Speaker 0: see you cancel the charge.
Speaker 1: No one knows that.
Speaker 1: if you're ever in a mario 64 tennis tournament Hit Z or as my strategy was I just held Z down all the time So you never charged up.
Speaker 1: no never I did.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not bad But yeah You'll never charge up accident that way.
Speaker 0: in the GameCube one charging up by accident is much less of a problem.
Speaker 1: It can't happen but happen to me like four times, but it can indeed happen.
Speaker 0: But then again charging up on purpose can provide you with quite the powerful shot.
Speaker 0: They can't be returned.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these games are just fantastic.
Speaker 1: now the GameCube one had these power shots.
Speaker 1: these like power-up charge yeah, like super moves like the tennis equivalent of hadouken or hurricane kick and they also have the Beginner normal and advanced mode in terms of how to control those things.
Speaker 1: I don't want to talk about how the game works too much But basically with the out these offensive and defensive power moves and the offensive move makes it very likely you're gonna score.
Speaker 1: The defensive move saves your ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if someone hits the ball way over your head.
Speaker 0: There's no way you can get it, but you have a special move ready.
Speaker 0: use it and you you know.
Speaker 0: Even if you know they return it for the score You you did the best you possibly could have you returned the ball one more time and there was.
Speaker 0: you were gonna lose it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it might as well go for it.
Speaker 1: Yep Now a lot of people claim that the moves are BS.
Speaker 1: a lot of people complain that by using those moves or by having those Moves in there they'll say oh you only got the point because you had your stupid power charged up.
Speaker 0: Get the power charge at the same time.
Speaker 0: Well, actually you can also use taunts.
Speaker 0: You don't get it at the same time relatively the same because I always a number of return thingies.
Speaker 1: It's not the only factors guy.
Speaker 0: I know but it's it's the most important.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 1: Okay, I'll look I'll show I'll show you on game facts exactly what it is.
Speaker 1: but anyway anyway the The deal there is that you'll get in pretty much the same amount and you can use taunts to remove the power from people.
Speaker 1: So anybody complains about that is just full of crap.
Speaker 1: If you got a point because of a power shot that means that you were managing your power shots more effectively.
Speaker 0: Yep It's sort of like you have a power meter, but it's not a visible power meter.
Speaker 0: But you can sort of figure out how it works and you'll know when you're gonna get a power shot.
Speaker 0: and it's very rare that You know someone else will have power shots and you won't get them, you know soon enough to save yourself.
Speaker 1: Now the true beauty of this game is the doubles play.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I mean when we did these trash talk tournaments, we never did single play.
Speaker 1: We wanted to.
Speaker 1: Partly we wanted to force people to pair up into groups of two to make these anime fans talk to each other a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we did a lot of things like Blindfolded monkey ball where one person is blindfolded the other person just tells them what to do.
Speaker 0: That's good stuff left left right.
Speaker 1: But when it came to Mario Tennis this forms some interesting because we ran this in pretty much every event we ever had and Certain teams started emerging and there you'd see like the broken alliances.
Speaker 1: You'd see, you know, the one framed me like hey, we're signed up for the Mario Tennis Tournament, right?
Speaker 1: I already signed up and I'm playing with Pete because you suck.
Speaker 1: And of course the whenever the game actually starts playing in doubles I've noticed something Whenever anyone misses a point or loses, it's never their fault.
Speaker 1: It's always the partners fault.
Speaker 0: Exactly exactly like if someone misses the ball when it's coming at them They'll say you weren't behind me covering me and if the other person he just misses it straight out the be like, you know Oh, you got in my way.
Speaker 0: You were all up on the ball.
Speaker 1: And that's what made the trash talk so great.
Speaker 1: because we you know, we'd play it and we'd make a point of saying All right, you have to trash talk.
Speaker 1: That's the point of this and we'd even do it.
Speaker 1: We're like the semi finals and the finals.
Speaker 1: instead of being off in whatever room We're in the main room on a big projector.
Speaker 1: We have a big crowd of people watching and Pretty much by the time you got to the final rounds.
Speaker 1: There would be almost no trash talk directed at all between the teams.
Speaker 1: The trash talk was directed almost entirely within the teams.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's it's the beauty of the doubles play is that you sort of even if both people are really good You have to coordinate.
Speaker 0: you either have to play front and back or left and right.
Speaker 0: You know one person gets all the stuff on the left side of the court.
Speaker 0: The other person else is up on the right side of the court.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a very Basic pedestrian strategy.
Speaker 0: Well, you have to at least you know cover different parts of the court If you both like get right up on the front, you're you're in trouble playing against someone.
Speaker 0: good, you know.
Speaker 0: but you generally you have to cover the whole court with two people.
Speaker 0: and Coordinating which parts of the court you're gonna cover, you know as the game progresses is not you don't have.
Speaker 0: you don't unless you're Siamese twins Sharing the same brain in some way.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be very easy.
Speaker 1: and Then there was team Scott.
Speaker 0: Oh team Scott undefeated I think.
Speaker 1: still I have a feeling that one of the Scots will drag it down if you ever play again.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that Especially since boo is far superior in doubles play because he doesn't have to run around so quickly.
Speaker 0: So you you have one person with a really fast character going around, you know Making all the returns that are really hard to make.
Speaker 0: they you know We're hitting way to the left or way to the right But when the other when the other team hits a nice easy shot right to boo tricky shot, haha You can't return.
Speaker 1: it is a team Scott gonna have to demonstrate this at the New Year's party.
Speaker 0: Maybe they'll have to be some.
Speaker 0: Martin is at the news bar.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should deal.
Speaker 1: just have a Mario Tennis tournament at our party.
Speaker 0: I think maybe we should.
Speaker 1: I think we will.
Speaker 1: we're gonna.
Speaker 1: we're going to have.
Speaker 0: maybe I won't play team Scott because I don't know About the other Scott.
Speaker 0: that see notice how I didn't pick a better partner than who.
Speaker 1: are you gonna pick?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'll pick I'll see I'll watch everyone play and then pick is the best.
Speaker 0: cuz I know I'm the first best.
Speaker 1: I have to find out who's the first best but I won the most recent game.
Speaker 0: How about you and me first?
Speaker 1: That that wouldn't be fair.
Speaker 1: Yeah So, uh, he's the most fun.
Speaker 1: I was very diplomatic in my stating of you know maybe half of teams Scott is not as good as it might should be but You're pretty open in your trash talk of the other Scott.
Speaker 0: That's how it has to be with Mario.
Speaker 0: Tennis is wide open trash talk.
Speaker 0: If you keep it in you're ruining the game.
Speaker 1: See at the same time when we're in Scott and I were playing because we hadn't played in a long time I definitely engaged in my post-hoc trash talk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't you always do the yeah I pretty much sat there through the whole game real quiet just playing and when I was losing I just be like when I was winning.
Speaker 1: I'd be like and right about through the last two games of the final set, you know match point is when suddenly the Scott How you doing there?
Speaker 1: Huh boo keeping up we're getting tired.
Speaker 0: Yeah Boo's a little tired.
Speaker 0: Maybe we shouldn't have played six game sets.
Speaker 1: That's what you're supposed to do.
Speaker 0: I know but it was so long.
Speaker 1: now there there's all this other Shit in the new Mario Tennis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the GameCube one is all those extra bonus modes and courts that do weird stuff.
Speaker 0: And oh, there's always the ability to enable star.
Speaker 0: if you unlock if you beat the game with a character You can play that character with star power which basically means they'll hit harder move faster, etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 0: And if you both have star power like you.
Speaker 0: if every player playing has star power It does change the game and it's still even.
Speaker 0: it's not unfair But it's not quite the same as just playing normally and it's not as good and in some ways it is.
Speaker 1: It's very high powered advanced play.
Speaker 1: as in if you're playing that way Someone who isn't skilled at the game pretty much will never get a point.
Speaker 0: Yeah ever.
Speaker 0: but then again if some person has star power and the other person does not the star power person has this Ludicrous advantage they can move so fast and hit so hard.
Speaker 0: the normal non star player basically can't compete.
Speaker 1: but see at the same time the great thing about Mario Tennis is that If you get a great player and a bad player together the bad player will every now and then still like they'll still do.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's like the worst you can be at.
Speaker 1: Mario Tennis is a lot higher than you expect So pretty much anyone who ever plays a Mario Tennis game will always have a good time.
Speaker 1: Yep unless you're not a human being.
Speaker 0: the other thing about Mario Tennis is I think the AI is Really good at controlling the the players is bad when you're playing doubles and you have a friend Who's the other person on your team is AI controlled because you can't coordinate with them and that sucks.
Speaker 0: But as an opponent the AI isn't half bad and actually when you you can beat the hardest hardest settings of AI the ace setting It's beatable.
Speaker 0: If you're really good.
Speaker 0: It's just also really hard and I think that's exactly how it's got to be.
Speaker 0: There's like five different levels of AI difficulty and the easiest is impossible to lose to.
Speaker 0: But you can lose to it if you're a moron and the hardest is possible to beat.
Speaker 0: But you can only beat it if you're awesome and that's it.
Speaker 0: Everything else is perfectly in between where it belongs.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Team Scott's gonna have to compete because I already picked my partner who AI a I ace?
Speaker 1: no No, I just thought back to a time a simpler time before we podcasted where our friend Pete moved to Albany And I went up there to visit and we played some Mario Tennis and I discovered he's not bad at the Martin.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm not talking about Pete.
Speaker 1: He's not gonna be on my team God.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a diss.
Speaker 0: Open with your trash talk there.
Speaker 1: I I discovered that there are other people in that former household who were very good at Mario Tennis.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna go that way, huh?
Speaker 1: And I think I remember we were playing with one of the gimmicks So they're the alligators.
Speaker 0: I think this is I think this is the other great thing about my.
Speaker 0: oh I think the other great thing about Mario Tennis is that unlike so many other games we have like say Soul Calibur.
Speaker 0: Right, maybe I guess I guess a lot of us are good at Soul Calibur But like a few people are so much better right with Mario Tennis a lot it's not.
Speaker 0: it's complex enough to be a fun awesome game, but it's simple enough that people get good at it and enough people have mastered it because it's not so incredibly difficult and thus it actually makes a really good tournament game because a lot of people if you have played it at all are great at it and tournaments are the most fun when you have a ton of people who are all awesome or equally awesome or you're unsure how equally awesome they are and Even if someone's better than someone else is by such a small margin that you're still on the edge of your seat throughout the whole Tournament.
Speaker 1: see that Mario Tennis is a great spectator sport.
Speaker 1: actually It is if you're an anime club or some sort of college club out there or whatever and you need some sort of tennis.
Speaker 1: run a Mario Tennis doubles trash talk tournament and have to make a big deal about the championship.
Speaker 1: You gotta pump everyone up.
Speaker 1: you make a beat like this.
Speaker 1: is the championship?
Speaker 1: have a big projector.
Speaker 1: Bring the two teams out one member at a time.
Speaker 1: talk to him a bit.
Speaker 1: you can do something pretty epic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is I'm worried about Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: we right because if they use the waggles it's gonna ruin that game.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends.
Speaker 0: I mean I could see good waggles and I can see bad.
Speaker 1: I cannot see a good waggle.
Speaker 0: I could see a good wag maybe waggle to activate powers Hmm.
Speaker 0: I see good waggle is like swing to the right for the a and swing to the left for the B Maybe something like something like that I think could work.
Speaker 0: but It's gonna be rough because if they try to make it full-on like Mario for it like Wii Sports Tennis That's not gonna be good.
Speaker 1: Wii Sports Tennis wasn't full-on.
Speaker 1: Wii Sports Tennis was barely a game.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: But if they try to make if they try to make it just controllers with no waggle Then it'll basically why.
Speaker 0: why just play the GameCube one?
Speaker 0: Why should I?
Speaker 1: well because they'll probably make it.
Speaker 1: I mean you could say that why not play the n64 one?
Speaker 1: because the GameCube one was just incrementally better.
Speaker 0: It was incrementally better.
Speaker 1: I mean It's not like other games where say Mario 2 is worth playing in and of itself because it's a different game from Mario 3. there's really no reason to play Smash Brothers 64 or Mario 10 is 64 if you have the GameCube ones.
Speaker 1: just no reason.
Speaker 0: There's different Arenas and stuff.
Speaker 1: There's no real reason.
Speaker 1: It's just an incremental improvement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's some reason.
Speaker 1: the game is better in every way.
Speaker 0: It is quite better in almost every way.
Speaker 1: there's really no reason to go back except for a kind of historical.
Speaker 1: This is what these games used to be is there isn't there right?
Speaker 0: There is not a reason to play Mario Tennis in the 64 if you have a GameCube there or a Wii there.
Speaker 0: just really isn't.
Speaker 0: I mean except to see what it was like because then it was still a good game.
Speaker 0: But the Mario Tennis of the GameCube is just better.
Speaker 0: It's the same game but better in every way.
Speaker 1: So So yeah, there's going to be a tournament at the New Year's party.
Speaker 0: Oh no this weekend.
Speaker 1: Oh, no I've chosen my partner.
Speaker 1: if Wyatt will step up Wyatt will be my partner.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you don't want to play with me.
Speaker 0: we just win cuz.
Speaker 1: uh, I think that you have to defend the honor of Team Scott.
Speaker 0: and Are you gonna force it?
Speaker 0: Are you gonna force it?
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm gonna force it.
Speaker 1: But you get to decide if the honor of Team Scott I mean, I think I think you're.
Speaker 1: would Rocky walk away from a challenge?
Speaker 1: would Rocky say no I'm not gonna box you you're too good or is he gonna step up and say alright, I'm gonna box?
Speaker 0: I think what you've decided is that you know that you and me are pretty equal and you're pretty sure that we're the best And we played the game most reason.
Speaker 1: so I chose the second best person.
Speaker 0: I think I don't know.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Maybe I can get my.
Speaker 0: the other Scott to practice is Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: He's got like three days.
Speaker 0: That could be enough.
Speaker 0: It only takes like a couple plays to get back in top form.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens right.
Speaker 1: if anything we might have some content to put up from the New Year's involving this at the end.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it's.
Speaker 1: I think we might force everyone to do some pre-hoc press trash talk.
Speaker 0: You have forced everyone to pre-hoc trash talk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, great.
Speaker 0: So now no matter what whether you win or lose you're gonna have to say you're gonna win except me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, I'll say it right now.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna win whatever team I'm on.
Speaker 1: We're gonna win this tournament.
Speaker 1: Oh Snaps Oh snap, cuz no one else is good enough.
Speaker 0: Oh snaps what it's gonna happen when you lose?
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna lose.
Speaker 0: no, no, I just said what's gonna happen when you lose not if when.
Speaker 1: ah Oh, yeah, so our New Year's party.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I get the rest of the stuff together for that probably All right, that's the end of the show tonight.
Speaker 1: Mary Xmas ding-dong.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.