Speaker 1: It's Wednesday April 18.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we review the first volume of the awesome comic DMZ.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure you all noticed that there was no show yesterday.
Speaker 0: Emily was kind enough to take me out to see Avenue Q Which I'd wanted to see for a long time and I finally got to see it.
Speaker 1: I stayed home and went to sleep because I hadn't slept enough, and I was falling asleep at work And today I didn't fall asleep.
Speaker 0: It was so you had enough time to get plenty of sleep.
Speaker 0: in fact We went to bed fairly early the night before.
Speaker 1: no he didn't.
Speaker 0: yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: we were done with the show by 11.
Speaker 1: Yeah, meanwhile before we were getting done with the show at 10 now.
Speaker 1: We're starting the show at 930.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 1: I don't like this business.
Speaker 1: We gotta start the show earlier, but yeah Part of the sleeping late does have to do with Pokemons.
Speaker 0: see Despite the fact that you seem to be staying up late playing this Pokemon And I'm not my pokemons are all higher level than your pokemons cuz you're a Bulbasaur which gets more levels easily.
Speaker 0: I don't even use the Bulbasaur.
Speaker 0: It's all Pidgeotto or now Pidgeot.
Speaker 1: So you got two pokemons I'm leveling up like seven Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what all my main Pokemon are at least level 30.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: why don't we have a Pokemon battle?
Speaker 1: Maybe we will one day when I have the Pokemon I want and not the Pokemon I'm forced to have out of necessity of not being done with the game yet.
Speaker 0: But yeah, Avenue Q was absolutely hilarious, and I highly recommend that all of you go see it while it's still playing.
Speaker 0: I imagine it'll play for a while yet since Apparently Emily got the last two tickets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know plays are sort of like as long as they keep playing.
Speaker 1: They're probably worth seeing.
Speaker 0: Unlike movies which you know that doesn't really work because that they always play at least a couple nights.
Speaker 0: So it kept playing those nights.
Speaker 0: It doesn't mean it was worthwhile.
Speaker 1: Well, it seems to be that like a play is so expensive to put on that like as soon as you stop selling out You can't afford to keep putting on the show.
Speaker 1: So as long as a show's been going for a long time or it's still going or if all the tickets keep selling out And you manage to get some it's probably worth seeing.
Speaker 0: well The thing is Avenue Q is weird because it's kind of that Muppet thing.
Speaker 0: so it's all actors on stage But they're holding puppets and the puppets are the actual characters.
Speaker 0: the actors are just people in gray pants and gray shirts.
Speaker 0: You're supposed to ignore it.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: after about 30 seconds you totally forget.
Speaker 0: They're there.
Speaker 0: It's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: wow It really is.
Speaker 0: you'll watch like all right, so there's that guy and then by the end You just you suddenly realize that wait a minute.
Speaker 0: There's a guy there.
Speaker 0: whoa What's that guy doing there?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen videos of it online And I've always paid attention to the guy, but I didn't never went to see the things.
Speaker 0: seen it live.
Speaker 0: You don't pay attention to the guy.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: maybe I will pay attention to the guy.
Speaker 1: I tend to have a problem going to see plays that I always Tried this.
Speaker 1: I do the same thing.
Speaker 1: I do like a magic show where I try to look on purpose where I'm not supposed to look and it ends up actually Giving me the wrong experience.
Speaker 0: But so what?
Speaker 0: yet ed lame is yet see the guy at the edge of the stage after he gets off the spinny bit like take his wig off and yeah pretty much and I got.
Speaker 1: look at the spinny turntable like just to see how it works and like Look for a guy controlling it.
Speaker 1: We're not like a guy enters and leaves stage or is like these guys in the corners.
Speaker 1: I'll always look always to the sides and every door is supposed to be looking or like when people are dancing.
Speaker 1: I got look at their feet to see what's going on.
Speaker 1: one thing
Speaker 0: I always do because I always tend to sit kind of high up or in balconies or whatever as I always look and try to See if I can point out all the little stage marks like where so-and-so is supposed to stand or where the smokes gonna Explode or whatever's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's sort of a bad thing like looking at the end of a book or something.
Speaker 1: Maybe I shouldn't do it anymore, but I can't really help myself.
Speaker 0: when I was young I used to have a thing with books where whenever I got a new book I would always flip to the second to last page read a random sentence one sentence and stop right there.
Speaker 0: I just keep that in my mind throughout the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Why what's the point?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It just it gave me a perspective.
Speaker 0: I guess sometimes sometimes the sentence wasn't really relevant and that was the end and so it stood and so low.
Speaker 0: All right, of course that's a lot better than Ava where I saw interview van galleon before I knew there even was a TV show.
Speaker 0: Well, that made it a little bit different to watch a little bit not much So in the news and this ties very much into my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: But there's a show out there called Hokuto no.
Speaker 0: Ken Aka fist of the North Star.
Speaker 1: anime world order likes to show a lot.
Speaker 1: It's a really old show from the 80s.
Speaker 0: I have my opinions about it.
Speaker 0: I'll leave that as it may but it's a generally Surprisingly popular show at least outside the US.
Speaker 0: It is very popular in the US not so much and you can't deny that it is in many ways an important show.
Speaker 0: However today some 3,000 people Attended a real-life acted-out funeral for a character from the new fist of the North Star movie Entitled true savior legend fist of the North Star the legend of Rao fierce fighting arc.
Speaker 1: Wow Yeah, quite the name.
Speaker 0: Now they're doing this straight up.
Speaker 0: It looks like it's going to be a traditional Buddhist send-off or a traditional beauty Buddhist funeral and they've got To represent the family of this character who I guess dies in this movie is none other than baron-san
Speaker 1: way to way to spoil the movie for people who haven't gone to see it by Having a funeral for a character who dies in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well apparently 3,000 people showed up in the bitter cold to stand there and pay their respects to this guy.
Speaker 0: Wow the legend of Rao fierce fighting arc to quote anime news network is the Third in a five-part series is the conclusion of the Rao saga and features, huh?
Speaker 0: It features the epic battle between Kenshiro the main character and Rao.
Speaker 1: Yes, I never would have suspected It's a total shocker right there, you know a Jurassic Park has dinosaurs.
Speaker 0: You know someone's ruined Titanic for me.
Speaker 0: Apparently that boat sinks.
Speaker 1: Oh god.
Speaker 1: So in Pearl Harbor the Japanese?
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, but fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: a lot of people have mixed feelings about it and as far as I can gather all the Show is is a bunch of muscly men who there's ostensibly a plot, but that doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: They yell at each other and Kenshiro stands there clowering and then he'll go.
Speaker 0: The guy will say that didn't hurt.
Speaker 0: then Kenshiro will say you're already dead.
Speaker 0: then the guy will go, huh?
Speaker 0: And his head will explode to dramatic music.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much the show right?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: That's the whole show Yeah, and apparently people love that so much that they'll go to a funeral for a fictional person.
Speaker 0: I will admit that I have had a lot of fun.
Speaker 0: Just randomly watching fight scenes from it on YouTube lately.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's.
Speaker 1: It's something about it where you watch it and it's so dumb, but then the guy goes And Some head explodes and that in and of itself is hilarious and you can watch it a thousand times Plus.
Speaker 0: this guy has bigger eyebrows than Bell dandy used to.
Speaker 0: oh Ha ha I went bigger than rim used to oh, oh, I don't think his eyebrows are really a match for mine.
Speaker 0: You see much like the characters and various shows like Dragon Ball who will somehow limit their power I pluck the middle of my eyebrow solely to prevent it from being so powerful that would in fact rule the world and Overpower lesser men's minds.
Speaker 1: I'll just say Burton Ernie.
Speaker 0: then Yeah, yeah, so there's.
Speaker 0: there's a gay Burt in Avenue Q if you haven't seen it great.
Speaker 1: So I got a news here and this news is so insignificant that no one cares.
Speaker 1: the odds of anyone listening to the show having already known this news are pretty small unless you go to Temple University in Philly, which I don't think anyone does but I'm gonna give you this news Anyway, because it will prompt much discussion.
Speaker 1: Are you ready for this?
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 0: Scott refused to tell me what this was earlier.
Speaker 0: We were doing pre-production.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna be surprised by this.
Speaker 0: I assume.
Speaker 1: Yes the temple university Is having student government elections at some point in the near future.
Speaker 1: All right, I Have stories about our it's student government elections, but that'll be a Thursday Yep, and then we're gonna have an event at some point Where some of the student government people are gonna give speeches or whatever?
Speaker 1: Something.
Speaker 1: and generally people as people are to student government things are apathetic and don't care whatever.
Speaker 0: So we're any cockboats involved.
Speaker 1: No, so they show up to.
Speaker 1: you know, the student government people are having this event.
Speaker 1: They show up and they find that the stage that they have scheduled is already occupied by the anime club Which is having a martial arts demonstration.
Speaker 1: but obviously when you read the description these people are just Cosplaying as Dragon Ball characters and Pretending to fight with each other.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Now had this anime club reserved the stage duly?
Speaker 1: they did.
Speaker 1: They actually reserved it before the student government people did and the student government people had to leave that Harkins back to our IT on at least a hundred different.
Speaker 1: Okay me Apparently the you know event office of student activities fucked That's the same room to two people at the same time.
Speaker 0: Ah See that happened a lot at our IT where we'd plan an event for the anime club and some other group.
Speaker 0: most often It was the women's group on campus the Women's Center who I have but also the players RIT players.
Speaker 0: the players almost never really gotten.
Speaker 1: our way was well, they could be in the hall at the other side of the hall.
Speaker 0: Yeah But that didn't cause any trouble.
Speaker 0: one.
Speaker 0: The only problem we ever had was at the Women's Center because they'd always get mad That there was noise going on outside of whatever event they were having That they somehow didn't seem to look at the calendar and see that.
Speaker 0: oh the anime club is planning some sort of horrible gigantic Festering massive fanboys watching anime and dancing for four or five hours and they would just schedule their vagina monologues or whatever.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 1: I'm checking that schedule there.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: It's a good idea to have our convention the same weekend as Otacon.
Speaker 1: I don't need to look at schedules of other things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure I can reserve the BCC.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, Jimmy easy Okay, I'll just reserve the Javits for tomorrow and I'm gonna mention the funny thing about that one instant.
Speaker 0: Was that this Women's Center the guy who runs the Women's Center came over and he's yelling at me in this tire Like you've got to turn that loud crazy music down and you're ruining my event.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna call campus safety and I was like go ahead and call campus safety.
Speaker 0: You knew we had this room.
Speaker 0: I got the piece of paper saying I have this room.
Speaker 0: What do you think campus safety is gonna say?
Speaker 1: And it gets a person pretty pissed off when you pretty much say haha you're wrong nothing you can do With one exception.
Speaker 0: that guy is the most indignant person I've ever met.
Speaker 0: Well, you're one person more than one person and I met that person while waiting at the law Lewiston bridge into Canada once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just want to point out one more time that the anime club at Temple University probably cool people but they were Randomly for no reason at all other than to have fun.
Speaker 1: I guess if they like that sort of thing was cosplaying Dragon Ball and pretending to fight each other.
Speaker 0: They called it a martial arts Demonstration.
Speaker 1: I assume so are these guys like?
Speaker 1: are you sure this wasn't the temple elementary school my anime club?
Speaker 1: Or perhaps the temple middle school anime club.
Speaker 0: What kind of event is that?
Speaker 0: I don't know but granted that makes the humiliation of the actual legitimate student government that much more hilarious.
Speaker 1: That is the point.
Speaker 0: Things Of the day.
Speaker 0: right along with my news about that funeral for that fake character from that Japanese cartoon I've got a link to said Japanese cartoon.
Speaker 0: now more specifically we've been watching a bunch of and then head exploding all over YouTube and In case you wondered what fist of the North Star is actually about as opposed to what we said It's about this is the third half of the third half the third section the third third of the first episode of Fist of the North Star
Speaker 1: the first episode ever.
Speaker 0: Pretty much it explains everything that matters about this show in the course of about three minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah having you know here people constantly talk about the show.
Speaker 1: knowing about the show knowing it's an important piece of anime history Playing a fun video game based on it and such and such we decided it was actually time to try to watch it.
Speaker 1: So we went to YouTube and we watched the first episode and is the part that everyone who's an anime fan Should watch whether you like it or not.
Speaker 0: yep And all I've learned is that one.
Speaker 0: it is generally hilarious to watch a man's head explode And I could watch that over and over again for a great time to come.
Speaker 1: I think it's just the way they animate the head exploding.
Speaker 0: It's like they put more effort into animating the heads exploding than they do anything else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like the people just stand there.
Speaker 1: They don't talk much.
Speaker 1: They don't move much, but when the heads explode that's when the action is.
Speaker 0: But as far as I can gather I can't ever see myself Liking this show in a non-ironic fashion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have to agree.
Speaker 1: I mean it is hilarious to watch the fights even though There's no interesting fight choreography at least not in the fights that we've seen.
Speaker 1: But in the plot.
Speaker 1: the overall plot seems to be interesting.
Speaker 1: You know there's a big post-apocalyptic world where stuff happens, and there's dangerous shit going down etc.
Speaker 1: etc.
Speaker 1: That is interesting, but any individual episode seems to just be a formulaic shown.
Speaker 0: in fighting There's a guy.
Speaker 1: There's a guy Trouble.
Speaker 1: we must fight.
Speaker 0: and the thing is it's not like choreographed fight scenes because I've seen a lot of anime that were dumb But I'd really good fight scenes.
Speaker 0: I've seen anime that were really good and had really good fight scenes and bad.
Speaker 0: fist of the North Star is a fighting anime.
Speaker 0: Ostensibly though, I guess it isn't really because there aren't fights.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much just two muscly guys going.
Speaker 0: I'm the blob blob blob and what.
Speaker 0: the other muscly guy just stands there with his heavy eyebrows clowering and then With his crap animation.
Speaker 0: it's just garbage.
Speaker 0: I gotta say it.
Speaker 0: It's garbage.
Speaker 0: It's not good.
Speaker 1: It's old 80s animation.
Speaker 1: So yeah, yeah, it's not as bad as this other animation that we're not gonna talk about yet cuz the secret.
Speaker 0: Oh that fucking thing.
Speaker 0: yeah, oh my god.
Speaker 0: You guys are in for a treat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, eventually we saw something.
Speaker 1: we saw something.
Speaker 0: We're not even gonna hint at what it is.
Speaker 1: Nope, except this bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So if nothing else watch this bit and you'll know everything you ever will need to know about fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: And if you find yourself Liking this you think hey, I want to see the show that has this plots.
Speaker 0: Well, I'd recommend just searching on YouTube for Hokuto no Ken watching the first 15 non anime music video videos that show up Non video game.
Speaker 0: also, yes down video game and that's really all you need to do when you when you see a man Who has a shotgun and the only reason that he doesn't just kill Kenshiro is that when Kenshiro punched him earlier?
Speaker 0: He did it in such a way as to mess with the guy's body Is that every time he tried to shoot the gun the gun spun around and pointed at him instead?
Speaker 0: That's what fist of the North Star is.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean that has nothing to do with the overall plot of the show of folks.
Speaker 1: post-apocalyptic world.
Speaker 0: Self hilarious Overall plot is only awesome If someone explains it to you or spoils that or just tells it to you like it's a story.
Speaker 0: if you actually watch it It's really not so cool.
Speaker 1: Imagine getting this giant awesome plot and then having it being doled out to you in the tiniest portions Possible like one word at a time like a word a week.
Speaker 1: That's that's what mr.
Speaker 1: North Star hits.
Speaker 1: Worse than one piece and I may be well, maybe not as bad as one piece.
Speaker 0: anyway You know what this is what in regards to all these fighting shown in whatever shows I would rather watch all of fist of the North Star then watch even half of one piece or bleach or Naruto at this point.
Speaker 1: No, it's it's got to be tough because I haven't watched enough of any of them to really say which one would be the most tolerable.
Speaker 0: I think fist of the North Star is because I can take it in a purely Laughable way if I view it as a comedy and not as a serious show.
Speaker 1: It is so much more tolerable All right, so we've used funny Japanese prank videos as things of the day before.
Speaker 1: we had the one with the Guy tries to pee.
Speaker 1: guy tries to pee in the porta potty and it lifts him up out of the roof.
Speaker 1: We've had the one at the snow mountain where people You know sit down in like a massage chair or whatever it was and it just sends them out onto the to the the mountain And they start sliding down the hill.
Speaker 0: Well, the problem with these videos was that while they were awesome There was a lot of buildup and explanation and they only actually showed them getting like four or five different people and they showed the Same prank every time.
Speaker 1: so it's like once you were onto the third or fourth guy.
Speaker 1: It was just like all right.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing as before just a different reaction shot.
Speaker 0: granted They always saved the last one for the guy who got injured or the guy who got stuck or hitting the head or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah Here is a Japanese prank video that mixes up a lot of different pranks.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, first they've got like a stuffed animal of some sort that makes a horrible roaring noise.
Speaker 1: They've got a guy jumping out of a trash can you don't realize he's in there.
Speaker 1: They've got a fake snowball that they roll down a hill at.
Speaker 0: people Snowballs the best one.
Speaker 1: they've got a fake rock that they roll down the street and a guy as he comes around the corner on The salaryman comes around the corner suddenly behind him Indiana Jones Boulder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though it's fake.
Speaker 1: They've got.
Speaker 1: Some guy was bowling and he had a fake bowling ball.
Speaker 0: That one was great because even though I knew this was a video of pranks They were obviously were all pranks and not like prank with a tire iron but real pranks.
Speaker 0: Thanks that don't kill people.
Speaker 0: and for I flinched when the bowling ball went back because for a second my mind said that's a bowling ball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all I gotta say is I need me a fake bowling ball.
Speaker 0: Oh hardcore I mean, so I mean we have that fake rock that we've gotten almost everyone we know with it's really not.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna ruin it now.
Speaker 1: No one's ever gonna get caught by the fake rock ever again.
Speaker 1: now No, but the fake bowling ball fake bowling ball could work.
Speaker 0: You got to be at a bowling alley though I don't think either one of us should ruin what the last prank is.
Speaker 1: I don't remember what it is.
Speaker 0: So awesome when they put something in the bathroom.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, the prank is.
Speaker 0: guy is trying to pee.
Speaker 0: There is something in the bathroom with him.
Speaker 0: I remember now Who thought of that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: crazy Japanese people.
Speaker 1: They think of all this crazy shit.
Speaker 1: I mean they have funerals for fictional people.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: This is nothing compared to that.
Speaker 0: so tonight since there has been due to popular demand a Demand that was a poorly phrased way to open this very for us to do comics a little bit since we do mostly Anime and manga lately partly because Scott reads more comics than I do which isn't that many and I read
Speaker 1: and most of the comics I read or manga
Speaker 0: and I read almost zero non manga comics.
Speaker 0: So every now and then it's gotta leave something on my desk and if I ever get to it I'll read it and then we'll do a show on it eventually.
Speaker 0: and such a thing has happened and I finally read a comic Oh my god rim read economy.
Speaker 1: So DMZ on the ground and while on the ground is the name of the first trade paperback The second trade paperback is named something else.
Speaker 0: I say specifically on the ground because now they one of us have read anything but on the ground from DMZ.
Speaker 1: Yes, I would read the second trade but I have not bought it yet.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know idea what happens in it.
Speaker 1: needless to say DMZ is a comic published by vertigo written by Brian would.
Speaker 1: The artist is an Italian name that I don't really want to attempt to say.
Speaker 1: Do you want to attempt to say it?
Speaker 0: It says John Doe in parentheses.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go with that.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: Wow That's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Ricardo Bertielli.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently it's the first American comic he's ever done really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Now the story or I guess the story is one thing and then the background to the story is something else.
Speaker 0: and I'll say right now that I really like this and I am generally cynical about comics.
Speaker 0: So for me that says a lot.
Speaker 0: to get me to say after I read a comic that it was tolerable is quite a feat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean this comic.
Speaker 1: I read it not knowing anything about it.
Speaker 1: I bought it because it was the first bird.
Speaker 1: It was in volume one of a vertigo series.
Speaker 1: So they're usually cheap and You can get to know whether you're gonna want to read the rest of the thing or not.
Speaker 1: And it was also pretty popular.
Speaker 1: So I said hey, I'll see what this thing's about and if I don't like it I just won't buy anymore.
Speaker 0: It's also set in Manhattan and we all seem to have a general fondness for things that are set in places We live or know.
Speaker 1: well I think most people.
Speaker 1: you know when something is set where they live or they they kind of like to go read it because then You can look in it and see stuff Like if you have been to Manhattan, you can see places in this book and you're like, hey, that's a building I seen that's a building.
Speaker 1: I was in.
Speaker 1: that's a street I was on.
Speaker 0: see that's a dangerous road to follow because I Still kind of want to see eight mile just to see if it's actually like eight mile.
Speaker 0: Get stabbed, but at the same time I don't want to.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I ever told the story about the stabbin.
Speaker 1: They're fake stem.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I did.
Speaker 1: I think we did because we told the movies.
Speaker 1: you see guys, too.
Speaker 0: Maybe we just told him.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't remember anyway.
Speaker 0: So the the background here to this story is a little bit far-fetched.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna read from the back because this puts it together very succinctly with overseas wars bogging down the Army and National Guard, huh?
Speaker 1: Politics coming into this little bit loving.
Speaker 0: the US government mistakenly Neglects the very real threat of anti-establishment militias scattered throughout the United States.
Speaker 0: Like a sleeping giant middle America rises up and violently pushes its way to the shining seas Sparking a second American Civil War coming to a sandstill Standstill at the line in the sand Manhattan or as the world now knows it the DMZ.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you look at like the first page of the trade it shows this little map and on the map There are three areas.
Speaker 1: Basically, there's New Jersey in England, which is the free states.
Speaker 1: There's Manhattan, which is the DMZ and there's Brooklyn Queens Long Island and the United States.
Speaker 0: Now aside from the fact that right there the setup that they have contrived to make Manhattan the place where this actually takes place is a little bit far-fetched Yeah for a number of reasons.
Speaker 1: I mean seriously what kind of armed United States Revolution is gonna conquer all the way up to New Jersey Not get over the Hudson and then the United States is somehow not gonna be taking Manhattan And taking only the parts East and then Manhattan itself is gonna be all weird and in the middle.
Speaker 0: now granted There are a lot of anti-establishment militias in the United States.
Speaker 0: there's actually far more of them than you would probably ever believe.
Speaker 0: I grew up in Michigan and there are a lot of people living in the.
Speaker 0: They have to rise up and be true patriots.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well Those crazy people can stay in their fortresses.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: the thing is even if you got all of them together and they somehow coordinated despite the fact that none of them trust each other at all I Somehow doubt that these militia could do anything in the face of the United States military Which pretty much would just cruise missile them.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, regardless of the feasibility of the premise of this story the story itself is actually pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you see the story is one of a little kid named Maddy Roth.
Speaker 0: He's not a little kid.
Speaker 0: He's some college punk.
Speaker 1: Yeah He's 20-something.
Speaker 0: a quote naive aspiring photojournalist lands a dream gig following a veteran war correspondent into the heart of the DMZ.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically you have this guy who's like the greatest journalist in the world.
Speaker 1: He's like the king of journalism.
Speaker 0: He's also a total cock.
Speaker 1: he's also a total asshole Yes, and he's going into the DMZ to get the story of the century, you know to do a huge Photo write-up video everything.
Speaker 1: and they've got a helicopter and they've got a bunch of equipment and a bunch of guards and they they got Everything.
Speaker 1: and this guy is 20-something college kid is the intern and he's going into the DMZ with his big crew - cuz no one goes in the DMZ.
Speaker 1: It's like this incredibly dangerous area in between these two war like at war forces.
Speaker 1: So no one goes there.
Speaker 1: I mean Manhattan Like right now has millions of people in it and in the story the DMZ is down to like four hundred thousand people in it.
Speaker 1: There's no one there.
Speaker 0: Well, there are evacuation routes and there are theoretically plans and systems in place to evacuate all of Manhattan in fairly short order.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder how well those would actually work, but that's beside the point.
Speaker 1: regardless in the story There's only four hundred thousand people there which leaves it pretty sparse and these guys are going in to get the story because no one Else goes there now.
Speaker 0: minor spoiler, but this happens right away.
Speaker 1: It happens like on the first page.
Speaker 0: This is the.
Speaker 0: the plot is they land in by helicopter And are immediately attacked by just people in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: the entire crew just about is killed Including the stupid cock reporter guy Yeah, and the only one left alive is the intern.
Speaker 0: the intern and all of the equipment is still there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so now he's freaking out.
Speaker 0: He's trapped in this war zone.
Speaker 0: He doesn't know what to do.
Speaker 0: One thing leads to another and the story of DMZ is that he is now living in the DMZ on his own Covering.
Speaker 0: what's going on there?
Speaker 1: He's the only reporter there.
Speaker 1: He's the only reporter to ever be there.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess since it was normal Manhattan and He's just some intern punk with a lot of equipment and he's trying to get by.
Speaker 1: and It's pretty cool because you've actually got like two different things going on.
Speaker 1: You've got the story of the world and the setting that you don't know much about and this guy is Reporting on it.
Speaker 1: and as he's reporting on it and learning about it You're learning about it, too and you've also got the story of the guy and how is he not gonna die today?
Speaker 1: and They sort of go hand in hand.
Speaker 1: It's like Pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I mean I really do enjoy it though the plot moves along at just about the pace.
Speaker 0: that'll keep me going and give me interest.
Speaker 1: actually The one thing that kind of bothered me though, is that?
Speaker 1: Obviously this thing was written originally as separate comic book issues and you can you know You it's marked where the issues begin and end but the plot definitely jumps in between issues like in the first issue He kind of meets someone and the second issue.
Speaker 1: It's like they were best friends and they skipped a whole bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: But granted I'm glad they skipped that because they skipped all the parts that usually I find tedious or take forever or Get on with it.
Speaker 0: I want to see what's gonna happen later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a. I definitely don't mind it but it is slightly jarring like what?
Speaker 1: Oh, they just skipped a bunch of stuff, you know as opposed it doesn't feel a hundred percent natural.
Speaker 1: It actually takes me out for like a second and I go.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, they must have skipped some stuff.
Speaker 1: That's not so important.
Speaker 0: All right, I get back into it.
Speaker 0: I feel the opposite to me by skipping that I feel like the relationships are a lot more real and natural Because now I didn't have to rely on direct continuous storytelling of building the relationships and all of these things that and then it gets right to the meat and Instead of having the imperfect memory of what was written down.
Speaker 0: It was just skipped and I just don't even worry about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I agree.
Speaker 1: It's just that I notice it Like I noticed that it was skipped and that takes me out of it for a second.
Speaker 0: I didn't really notice at first like I just totally blew by it.
Speaker 1: Oh, see I totally noticed like whoa Why are they acting all super friendly all of a sudden?
Speaker 1: they weren't acting super friendly five pages ago.
Speaker 1: They must have just you know, oh, it's in the future some all right.
Speaker 0: The other nice thing is that it really doesn't follow the kind of stereotypical plot You would expect and the situation progresses fairly rapidly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems like each issue like shows you a different aspect of what's going on in the DMZ.
Speaker 1: It's like in one issue They show you these guys who are defending Central Park and another issue They show you this guy who's a sniper aiming across at New Jersey where there's a girl and he's like, hey, what's up?
Speaker 0: I love those two.
Speaker 0: their relationship consists of shooting at each other.
Speaker 1: That's pretty awesome, right?
Speaker 0: Now it gets a little far-fetched at times that like there's one group of people who hold up I think near Central Park in the zoo and they've basically got their own society and their own science and their own agriculture and Some people have Restaurants and tofu garden things set up on the roofs of buildings and a lot of it's a little bit far-fetched.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but while it's far-fetched, it's entertaining.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like, okay This would never be.
Speaker 1: if this if you're trying to tell me this is real then I'm not going to believe you.
Speaker 1: But regardless the idea of this is awesome and I am happy that I am reading it, you know it's like.
Speaker 1: I would never expect there to be a tofu garden or some guys hiding in Central Park if Manhattan suddenly became like the most war Crazied place in the entire world, but if there was that would be totally awesome.
Speaker 1: and reading about it existing It's sort of like a nice little fantasy world like woohoo.
Speaker 0: And there's a bit at the end of this volume Which I don't really want to go into it because it was really cool and I don't want to spoil it for you But suffice to say they go about a way of revealing a whole bunch of story.
Speaker 0: Not so much story is what's going on with the plot but story as kind of the overarching Where this thing's going the direction of it how the characters have evolved over time and it all revolves around this chase That culminates in not really a cliffhanger, but definitely set up for the next volume.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah I really can't say more without ruining it, but I think Scott knows what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: I think it's really cool.
Speaker 1: it is pretty cool and It's sort of crazy to think about where it could go because it can go so many different ways.
Speaker 1: It's like they're sort of revealing that they're going to reveal as opposed to just revealing and I kind of like that.
Speaker 0: Yep, the one thing I got to say is that the manga got the manga.
Speaker 0: the comic is definitely manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it looks like and it generally goes along the lines of yeah these rebels are bad But you guys the u.s.
Speaker 0: Are just as bad with the things you're doing.
Speaker 0: but everything I look at so far I Would be under the impression that the rebels are bad in almost every sense and I'm pretty much Entirely on the side of the actual still standing United States so far.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean politically speaking I mean if you look at this as a commentary on the real-world politics I would probably agree with you, but in terms of the book itself, you know Where politics are not real and it's totally fake and it's just a fantasy world I find myself just siding with the people in the DMZ and everyone else sucks because most of the time you see you're hanging out In the DMZ where people are just trying to scrape by and you sort of feel bad for them.
Speaker 1: And yeah they're the ones who are having the hard time.
Speaker 1: and there you see you.
Speaker 1: actually those are the characters you get to know.
Speaker 1: and You know, I'm sure if it took place say in the US and you got to know those characters.
Speaker 1: It's like as soon as you get to know people you're on their side and in the book the people you get to know more Than anyone.
Speaker 1: or of course the reporter guy and the people in the DMZ.
Speaker 1: yeah, of course you're on their side.
Speaker 0: at the same time a lot of the people in the DMZ are Really fucked up.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: there's Mad Max tribal societies and scary people and
Speaker 1: constantly talk about like which neighborhoods you can't go to because people just shoot you and how to like approach people who haven't seen you before because people will recognize you because there aren't so many people around and It's
Speaker 0: it's really cool.
Speaker 0: Oh as the plot goes on He starts becoming famous in the DMZ and everyone kind of knows him and they just let him to his devices.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the trademark actually of the thing is the the press jacket.
Speaker 1: It's like oh he's wearing the press jacket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a good scene where in a stroke of genius They spray paint in white press on his back.
Speaker 0: So a sniper doesn't shoot him while they tend to some wounded guy.
Speaker 0: Yep, plus he's got an actual legitimate press pass a badge that he carries around.
Speaker 1: There's actually a t-shirt you can buy but I think it's sold out.
Speaker 1: but some comic book store in LA was selling it for A little while.
Speaker 1: they might have it again where it had like sort of a DMZ logo on the front And if you turn the shirt inside out, it would say press on the back.
Speaker 1: It was I kind of wanted one but when I went and they were sold out I just stopped trying.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, yeah Yeah Well be a semi short episode tonight partly because there's not much more we can say without going into the plot or ruining it Or anything and we'll definitely have to save that for some final thoughts after we read the rest of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, DMZ.
Speaker 1: It's a comic about a civil war in the United States.
Speaker 1: It's a survival tale of a guy stuck in a crazy war zone.
Speaker 0: The story is dark.
Speaker 0: The art is dark.
Speaker 0: It's pretty violent.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's a political commentary and It's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: And everyone should read it.
Speaker 1: if you have.
Speaker 1: how much does it cost like 10 bucks?
Speaker 0: Yep, 10 bucks pretty cheap plus goddamn.
Speaker 0: I'm actually planning to read a lot more comics now.
Speaker 0: Oh Nois Yeah, well the thing is I normally I always drive into work so I was rocking the podcast.
Speaker 0: but since I went into Manhattan last night and I realized something when I woke up this morning and went back to work and I did the reverse commute You know, I woke up went to Grand Central and I took a train north to my job and it was pretty awesome To wake up and shower and then walk out a door and immediately be immersed and see if people in downtown, New York City Mm-hmm, like it's not down downtown, but you get the idea and then I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like the train.
Speaker 0: So I'm starting to take the train to work.
Speaker 0: now I'm just leaving my car parked down in the Bronx and I'll just take the train to it every what.
Speaker 0: if you need the car Here, when do I ever need my car here?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you have to go somewhere where somewhere where am I gonna go?
Speaker 0: Plus I'm gonna take the car back on weekends.
Speaker 0: I still gotta get the car repaired.
Speaker 1: Yeah car needs some repairs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but man if I could afford it I would live in Manhattan in a second.
Speaker 1: Yeah I just hope it doesn't become a terrible war zone and you'll be alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if Manhattan becomes a terrible war zone moving back to Beacon.
Speaker 1: But what beacon was a war zone and in the last revolution?
Speaker 0: No, it really wasn't.
Speaker 0: beacon was just us.
Speaker 0: I don't know if any battles happened here.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: pretty sure there was a battle.
Speaker 0: No The the most history of beacon I've seen is that whatever British troops are on the move They lit signal beacons at the top of Mount beacon to war in Washington.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a. there's a statue of George Washington like over by that corner.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, even though this is the saddest thing Up at the top of Mount beacon the Daughters the American Revolution the original ones way back Erected a monument to commemorate everything that had been done in the Revolutionary War and it wasn't that long ago that Vandals for no apparent reason knocked it over and destroyed it.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah and one last bit here.
Speaker 0: I didn't really do a news because this is definitely the earliest of tenuous information But an anonymous source has informed us that people have been talking about Otacon.
Speaker 0: this year might have some bigger important guests and The word on the street is say you all right that could mean any number of things depending on how you look at it.
Speaker 0: I can think of a few people who might fit that description.
Speaker 0: That would also be big-name guests or maybe troops of people.
Speaker 0: I guess that's all I know.
Speaker 0: It's not like I can say anything more other than wild rampant speculation.
Speaker 1: I mean that really shouldn't matter to you Because if you can go to Otacon you should already be going regardless of what the word on the street is.
Speaker 0: See the thing is when it comes to Otacon I keep abreast of what's gonna happen there.
Speaker 0: What's gonna be there what music act will be there because I like to know ahead of time and it makes me excited about it But I'm gonna go no matter what.
Speaker 1: so it's not like I would go if they said yeah Otacon We don't have any guests this year because we fucked up.
Speaker 0: We'll see the Otacon even if the con Didn't happen somehow.
Speaker 0: if all that the con was one year.
Speaker 1: Oh it was rent.
Speaker 0: the BC was the BCC rented out and no events and it was just 25,000 anime geeks in a building together for three days.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much what it is now.
Speaker 1: anyway It's not like I go to many panels Yeah, oh and speaking of going to things this Saturday, so three days from now April 21st 2007 is gaming for hope at Marist.
Speaker 0: I think right yeah Marist College in New York.
Speaker 1: Yes in Poughkeepsie ish area I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's not hard to get to.
Speaker 1: you can go to the website.
Speaker 1: I think it's like gaming for hope org.
Speaker 0: Yep, I linked to it yesterday.
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah, so if you go to front row crew comm there's a link to it.
Speaker 1: It's gaming for hope org.
Speaker 1: if you are anywhere near that area the area near us.
Speaker 1: You should go.
Speaker 1: It's from 1 p.m.. To 1 a.m..
Speaker 0: We went last year, and it was pretty badass.
Speaker 1: It's also free Yeah, basically they fill the gymnasium with consoles and Tables for LAN parties, and I'm sure they'll be.
Speaker 1: you know guitar heroes and DDRs and all those sorts of things and they have some raffles and they have And they have some food they sell and you can give donations and all.
Speaker 1: they give all the money to Child's Play And it's a fun time one day of gaming and fun.
Speaker 0: Yes in fact That was the first time we played a big game of Kayla's last year, and it was indeed.
Speaker 1: yeah We'll be bringing some board games and playing them there and also de-essing it up and such and such.
Speaker 1: yeah If you're anywhere nearby you should go if at all possible, and I don't think we're gonna be there in an official context But we'll be there just because we were gonna go just like you should go.
Speaker 0: yep And also we mentioned it last week.
Speaker 0: But keep an eye out and if you have any plans consider going to Connecticut because we're going to be there Rocking the goddamn house with a bunch of events.
Speaker 0: once I finalize it will have more information about that
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's a ways out so don't worry about it,
Speaker 0: and of course if you're in the North Carolina area I'm going to be at an amazement this year And if you're gonna be in the upstate, New York area at least myself probably not Scott.
Speaker 0: It's going to be at toricon up at RIT.
Speaker 1: That's at the 28th right.
Speaker 0: yep next weekend Yes, pretty much, and I looked at my calendar because remember last year We complained for about seven months, but we never had any free weekends, and then we suddenly had a whole bunch of free weekends.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: It looks like starting this weekend.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna get any rest until winter.
Speaker 1: yeah, I would have gotten more sleep last night But I had to do laundry because there was no way I could have done it this weekend or any other day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you also probably played some pokemons.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I didn't I just did laundry and as soon as laundry was done I dropped it in my room went to bed.
Speaker 1: really yep wow yep.
Speaker 0: I had s'mores in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: great There's a little restaurant.
Speaker 0: They actually bring a little fire out But it's this pink goop, and they light it on fire.
Speaker 0: We asked him what it was and they weren't sure other than that It's toxic.
Speaker 0: But they light it on fire in the middle of the table, and then they give you a bunch of marshmallows and chocolate.
Speaker 0: It was pretty badass.
Speaker 1: I gotta say I guess you could if you could think of it.
Speaker 1: You'll find it somewhere.
Speaker 0: I love Manhattan until there's a civil war Yeah, but then I can be some sort of awesome geek nights reporter And I'll wander around with a press pass and no one will shoot at me because I'm just so badass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, such a badass right yeah, well until the SWAT team strips me naked because they think I'm a sniper exactly.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.