Speaker 1: It's Tuesday January 2nd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we review a great game guitar heroes.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, I suppose we're back after the I don't know how many days hiatus over the holiday.
Speaker 0: Yeah Sorry Monday people and yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Thursday people.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Sorry Thursday people also, but sorry more to Monday people.
Speaker 1: you've missed two shows Yeah, but that's fine because now we have plenty of Mondays to make up for it and We yeah.
Speaker 1: You see you might have thought oh, they'll definitely do a show on New Year's Day.
Speaker 1: They they already skipped a day for the New Year's holiday.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna skip another day.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: We had more people in our house than our house can hold.
Speaker 0: We had it all about that, but we did.
Speaker 0: we were nearing maximum capacity We had.
Speaker 1: we couldn't have had any more people and still have had enough room to do anything We could have done.
Speaker 0: it just depends on what we were gonna do.
Speaker 1: Oh if we all want to sit around quietly sipping tea and watching Jane Eyre then yes, there was plenty of room.
Speaker 0: yes, exactly, but for playing Wii Sports or Playing guitar hero mostly Wii Sports playing regular tycoon.
Speaker 0: There was not enough room Yeah for those of you who don't know there was barely enough room to play.
Speaker 1: like San Juan We had our annual not quite a bacchanal like some of our other friends tend to throw but definitely a giant party.
Speaker 0: It is quite the party.
Speaker 1: Yeah We're not gonna talk about the party today because there's quite a bit to say and I imagine we will get to that Thursday or possibly next Tuesday.
Speaker 0: Mmm, that sounds good.
Speaker 1: Well, we got some party topics.
Speaker 0: since a lot of people don't seem to know how to throw a party I bet you a lot of people don't even know what a party is.
Speaker 0: people think a party is like those You know what you see on television and all those like teens You know what?
Speaker 1: Those are the same people who thought that high school was going to be exactly like Saved by the Bell and they were gonna have Adventures just like Zach Morris did.
Speaker 1: Okay, we're just gonna jump right back in business as usual.
Speaker 1: none of that.
Speaker 1: happy new year BS.
Speaker 0: No, because it's just an arbitrary changing of clocks and calendars to a new number.
Speaker 1: Well, see that's the nice erudite explanation.
Speaker 1: The actual truth is that we're exhausted and some bunch of our friends are still here and we're gonna go play some board games as Soon as we're done with this show.
Speaker 0: take that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we care more about playing board games and we care about doing this And yet we still not managed to get four of these out a week.
Speaker 0: I don't know how that happened.
Speaker 1: You know, really?
Speaker 1: I don't either.
Speaker 0: No, I guess we did really care more about playing board games.
Speaker 0: We just wouldn't do it today and we'd go play board games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could stop right now.
Speaker 1: So right into the news and actually very much related to the holiday season and somewhat tangentially related to video gaming You know being gaming day a lot of people got HD TVs and HD TV Paraphernalia over the Christmas and New Year's break.
Speaker 1: a lot of people.
Speaker 1: sales were very very brisk because prices have come down a lot and people seem to think that they know about this Stuff or that you know, now it's now's the time to buy it.
Speaker 1: It's mainstream.
Speaker 1: and now according to this in several articles Many of the retailers that sold these products and many of the companies that make these products are being flooded with complaints from people who?
Speaker 1: Are realizing that the HD TV they brought home doesn't look nearly as good in their house as it did In Circuit City or at Best Buy.
Speaker 0: Well, there are many reasons for that but chief among them is people don't add hookup HD TVs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I've talked about a news guy.
Speaker 1: This is like six months ago where based on telephone surveys less than half of all people who own HD TVs Actually see HD TV content either because it's not available or they don't have their HD TV even hooked up, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and now a lot of new people bought TVs and remember the last generation of TVs before Component and all these different digital things and everything.
Speaker 1: you had either coaxial or the little RCA dealies.
Speaker 1: Yep, you just plugged them in color for color worked automatically.
Speaker 1: No, every TV worked with every piece of equipment and it worked perfectly and there was nothing you could mess up.
Speaker 0: And then you know whenever they came out with a new connector, they just got rid of the old one.
Speaker 0: You know, we used to have those UHF VHF prongs.
Speaker 0: Then we got rid of those and replaced it with coax.
Speaker 0: then we got rid of coax replaced it with RCA.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems like every TV always had the current connector and the previous connect.
Speaker 0: But then as soon as we got as video we still have as video and we still have Component and we still have HSD PA which is the new one.
Speaker 0: So it gets really confusing for people.
Speaker 0: They just see all these plugs and they don't know how to hook their own shit up, which it really isn't that hard.
Speaker 1: Well, I have a sad anecdote.
Speaker 1: when I was well, actually it was the freshman year after Well after the summer after our freshman year of college I went back to Michigan.
Speaker 1: I lived there for the summer.
Speaker 1: That was the last time I lived in Michigan.
Speaker 1: a bunch of my high school friends Realized midway through the summer that I was around and tried to get in touch with me.
Speaker 1: I ended up going to a gathering at one of their houses.
Speaker 1: They decided oh, let's watch a movie.
Speaker 1: and then they call me into the room and you know I expect we're gonna watch a movie.
Speaker 1: and they say rim.
Speaker 1: Can you help us?
Speaker 1: We don't know how to Make this work.
Speaker 1: We've never gotten this thing to work before now.
Speaker 1: When they said this thing I expected to see some like early adopter crazy HDTV set up or something weird.
Speaker 1: I discovered a normal TV with RCA holes in the front and a DVD player with RCA holes in the back and an RCA cable.
Speaker 1: Okay, and I was like, what's the problem?
Speaker 1: And they said well, we don't know how to hook this up.
Speaker 1: It won't work.
Speaker 1: so I plugged in the RCA cables and I hit play and I think the comment one of them made was something to the effect of see.
Speaker 1: that's why he went to tech school.
Speaker 1: He knows this shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah So the thing is is Really if I was the manufacturer of televisions or HD televisions or anything I would definitely try to get rid of.
Speaker 0: you know some of the older inputs and I would try to discourage people who make DVD players and you know game consoles and such from using Older connectors.
Speaker 0: I mean sure the Wii doesn't do HD So it doesn't really, you know RCA is just fine for it.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: There's no reason they couldn't send their lower resolution stuff over a nice component cable and it wouldn't really make it that much more expensive.
Speaker 1: Except a lot of people don't even have component capabilities.
Speaker 0: I know I mean Americans TV has component but it's not HD.
Speaker 1: The fact that DVD took off as well and as quickly and as amazingly as it did is kind of a big deal because no Technology has really taken off like that.
Speaker 1: Well, no consumer technology since then and people have this expectation that televisions and video game consoles and Things that allow them to watch movies are appliances.
Speaker 1: They're not computers.
Speaker 1: They're not complex.
Speaker 1: They're not difficult.
Speaker 1: They just work.
Speaker 1: you plug them in you hit play and that is so not true with HD and people just aren't ready for that At all.
Speaker 1: No, and the manuals are terrible HD manuals I mean, they're not written technically well for someone like us, but they're not written dumb down enough for people who aren't like us.
Speaker 0: I think a big part of the problem is if you look at the manual for any DVD player or television or anything like that It always gives you little diagrams Like if you have this set up plug them in like this.
Speaker 0: if you have this set up plug them in like this.
Speaker 0: You know and there's a bunch of different things.
Speaker 0: The problem is a lot of people have these home theaters now Especially people who are buying big-screen HDTVs.
Speaker 0: They have these home theaters that have a whole bunch of components and the way it says to hook them up in the book is Not necessarily, you know, your TV book says one thing your receiver book says another thing.
Speaker 0: you're you know, your DVD book says another thing and you don't know which one to listen to and It's it.
Speaker 0: people who don't understand input and output and the separation of audio and video Which isn't really that complicated when someone tells it to you are gonna have a problem.
Speaker 1: Well, I get the feeling to bring this background to video games right away that part of the ill will towards the PlayStation 3 that is probably going to be coming out a lot more in the weeks to come as people get their hands on ps3 since according To the internet as a whole there are a lot of places where ps3s are just on the shelves
Speaker 0: Supposedly haven't seen it.
Speaker 1: I imagine they're not places like New York City or LA but they're places like I don't know Podunk, Iowa where they got the one ps3 and no one can afford it.
Speaker 1: or yeah Or they've got the three in the Walmart in an area where just no one wants a ps3 Or people don't even think that they could get one there.
Speaker 1: Well, there's also the fact that there's a million of them on eBay going for pretty much retail.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep, but people, you know They get a ps3 and they get a brand new HD TV and they hook it all up And it doesn't look so hot because they're not actually using the HD properly.
Speaker 0: So 60 has the same problem and that seems to be working.
Speaker 1: Okay, but the thing is the Xbox 360 while it is HD and all that.
Speaker 1: They didn't market it so much like oh HD.
Speaker 1: this is the best possible.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: They marketed it more as Xbox Live online gaming video games Yeah, and I think Sony really shot himself in the foot on this.
Speaker 0: I think it's mostly gonna be ill will like continued against the Electronics retailers like Best Buy and Circuit City.
Speaker 1: See Circuit City's starting to cash in.
Speaker 1: They're starting to and a couple other retailers are picking up.
Speaker 0: Well, they what they did is Best Buy bought the geek squad, right, but that's mostly to handle computer problems.
Speaker 0: Circuit City bought what's it called something dog or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's called.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, the point is they're starting to.
Speaker 1: you know, buy an HD TV and hey for 50 bucks We'll send someone over to hook it up right for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's a good idea.
Speaker 0: and it also sells them extra cables.
Speaker 0: because you go over there and you say oh you need this game on This cable.
Speaker 0: Yep hundred bucks Yeah You need.
Speaker 1: you need the clearly superior monster digital cable as opposed to the clearly inferior yet electronically identical non-monster digital cable.
Speaker 1: exactly All right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: All right, so I got two sort of related stories.
Speaker 0: the first one Apparently there's a Sonic the Hedgehog game for the 360.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that But this guy put up a video of a bug in the game where he basically sits there loading for 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: Does this happen often?
Speaker 0: I don't know but it there's a problem in the game and It's everyone's going.
Speaker 0: OMG What are you doing with that gun?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a. I'm a little distracted here.
Speaker 1: I'll let you all in on the secret.
Speaker 1: Our friends I don't.
Speaker 1: Conrad got us as a gift a sack of potatoes And then as we're puzzling over the sack of potatoes the other gifts they gave us were potato guns And I've been fiddling with it and shooting little spuds on my carpet for the last five minutes, but I'm gonna have to clean up.
Speaker 1: So anyway, come with your news.
Speaker 0: well there's also a Bubble.
Speaker 0: bobble DS has this famous bug in it where F's you get to a certain boss and the boss never appears and you're stuck There forever and you can't beat the game.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's just fantastic.
Speaker 0: and Apparently the recent release I'm glad I didn't pay for it of military madness on the Wii and the virtual console.
Speaker 0: It's an old turbo graphics game is a little broken.
Speaker 1: how broken I Can't.
Speaker 0: no one.
Speaker 0: I can't exactly say how broken it is because I haven't found the article.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I didn't buy it yet.
Speaker 1: Then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was planning.
Speaker 0: it says, you know But here the article I'm gonna link to is this one that talks about dungeon explore Which is a game they were supposed to release on the Wii virtual console on Monday, which they didn't.
Speaker 0: but Apparently dungeon explorer if you haven't noticed is not available on your virtual console on Monday.
Speaker 0: It's not available now either.
Speaker 0: Apparently they're having some trouble getting that game to work properly.
Speaker 1: at least they recognize there's a problem and they didn't put it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I've noticed a market increase in the amount of bugginess in console game releases.
Speaker 1: You know that worries me.
Speaker 1: I mean PC games went through the same evolution Early PC games.
Speaker 1: you didn't release a PC game with a bug because getting a patch onto a PC game was pretty much impossible.
Speaker 1: No one had the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah If someone had a video game magazine Then they could get the CD in it which might have the patch on it for the game They were playing.
Speaker 0: so that was rare.
Speaker 1: like games were tested to hell and while bugs still occurred.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not gonna pretend that was some mystical age of gaming where there weren't bugs.
Speaker 0: No, come on.
Speaker 0: Even Mario 1 has a bug with the minus world.
Speaker 0: It's not really a bug but you know.
Speaker 1: But the bugs in games back then tended to be obscure difficult to invoke and not terribly annoying.
Speaker 1: Then as the game industry started not doing so well Well, actually no it started when the game industry was doing really well and people started rushing games out just to you know capitalize on the profits.
Speaker 1: and then the industry started collapsing and people started rushing games out to get them out cheaper and recoup their losses.
Speaker 1: and They stopped testing games so much.
Speaker 1: and then as the internet got faster they started saying Oh, well, we can just patch the games.
Speaker 1: and now pretty much any PC game that gets released isn't actually a game release It's basically a public beta.
Speaker 1: and then you expect hundreds of megabytes of patches over the next six months.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and all these online games, you know, I can understand Downloadable extra content.
Speaker 0: I have no problem with that.
Speaker 0: You know, hey everyone.
Speaker 0: Here's a new level.
Speaker 0: Hey, here's a new mod.
Speaker 0: That's all cool.
Speaker 0: But when there's patches that you know, or maybe you know You just it's an online multiplayer game and you want to change the rules like counter-strike decided to change the weapon price system.
Speaker 0: You know, I can understand that a little bit too, but when you have severe Can't play the game problems Like there's a loading screen for 20 minutes or the boss doesn't appear and not even that is a PC game.
Speaker 1: All right, just put the patch out and it just will automatically.
Speaker 1: but when it comes to console games there's always been kind of this a console game.
Speaker 1: part of the reason that they've been successful and the reason that they eventually superseded PC gaming at least so far now has been that console games just work because it's not easy to patch them.
Speaker 1: if you put Out a Nintendo cartridge or I don't know a PlayStation 1 game and it was broken you either had to recall that mofo or Basically piss off all of your customers forever.
Speaker 0: and it's happened before.
Speaker 0: there were some PlayStation games with just broken discs.
Speaker 0: That didn't work and everyone sent the discs back and got new ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was a rare occurrence and when it did it was a huge deal.
Speaker 0: It was a huge deal.
Speaker 0: But now that consoles have I mean even that really really bad mountain bike game for the Super Nintendo Didn't have bugs in it other than the fact that it existed.
Speaker 1: If you I mean I would consider the basic gameplay mechanic of that game to be a bug.
Speaker 0: Yes However, it worked as intended by the developers.
Speaker 0: We can only assume Assume that was what they intended to create.
Speaker 1: Well, they created a monster.
Speaker 1: I did indeed but console games are supposed to just work.
Speaker 1: I mean computers.
Speaker 1: while it'd be nice if they just work that's not something that we can expect for a long time to come.
Speaker 1: HDTVs don't just work for stupid reasons, but console games have always just worked.
Speaker 1: That's the point.
Speaker 1: if console games because of the fact that consoles can get updated online Start not working and requiring patches like, you know, PC games have needed for the last five to ten years I don't think it's gonna end well for the console gaming industry.
Speaker 0: Here's another thing.
Speaker 0: when it comes to like the Xbox Live arcade or the Wii virtual Console or you know these or like a lot of games on Steam where it's a cheap downloadable game You know, basically what they're selling me, but mostly the virtual console is selling me is like here You could emulate this game, but that's kind of hard.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's it's not, you know, it's not a large amount of effort, but it is tricky and it won't be perfect.
Speaker 0: Here is perfect exact emulation of an old game for a slightly overpriced amount of money.
Speaker 0: If that has bugs in it, and it doesn't work perfectly Then I might as well emulate it because that was the same effort either way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I got to say we got the mario 1 on the virtual console and it feels really good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, I've been playing Mars ever since.
Speaker 0: let's see I haven't played mario 1 in an actual NES in a long time.
Speaker 1: We tried to about four months ago and we discovered that every NES we own is broken.
Speaker 0: Yeah so I used to play Mario on an NES then I played it on a Game Boy Color and then I played it emulated on A computer for like the longest time.
Speaker 0: and just now I played Nintendo.
Speaker 0: I mark Super Mario Brothers 1 on the Wii virtual console and Even on the best emulator on Windows on the fastest computer with the best Everything and the best gamepad.
Speaker 0: the one on the Wii is still better.
Speaker 0: That's the best mario 1 I've ever played.
Speaker 0: It's even better than Mario all-stars in the Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: So it was worth $5.
Speaker 1: things of the day.
Speaker 0: How can you be so?
Speaker 0: I'm tired.
Speaker 1: What are you?
Speaker 1: so I'm absolutely freaking exhausted, but I can still keep up the NIG.
Speaker 0: Yeah, is that because of Red Bull or something like that?
Speaker 1: Well had some Red Bull but that was like two and a half hours ago.
Speaker 0: It's still doing something Red Bull.
Speaker 1: I'm totally wasted Except you don't drink alcohol either.
Speaker 1: I'm spent, you know, you actually got a pretty decent night's sleep.
Speaker 0: No, not really.
Speaker 0: I got woken up at like 8 by what people want me to drive them to the choo-choo.
Speaker 1: Oh, do you mean the thing that we'd planned on you doing?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, but I you know, my body wanted to sleep longer and it didn't.
Speaker 1: yeah I figure I'll get a good night's sleep Bob.
Speaker 1: this we get maybe next weekend.
Speaker 0: No, not.
Speaker 1: next week We got to clean the house up.
Speaker 0: That's all you know.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I'll get right into this being video game day as I keep saying since we're getting a lot of new listeners and not everyone seems to be aware of the Fact that we have four different nights where we talk about four different topics and geekery Yeah,
Speaker 0: so
Speaker 1: I'm saying it again
Speaker 0: Do not be aware Come on
Speaker 1: because people don't listen to that closer but at the end where we explain everything or they don't notice the fact that I'm dig.
Speaker 1: there's Five feeds like anime.
Speaker 1: world order is sandwiched between two geek night speeds.
Speaker 0: Well, if you don't listen to the end of the show then you don't deserve to know about our other days of the show.
Speaker 1: yeah, however, we're not gonna pull any chicanery and have Stingers at the end after the music to trick people into listening to it.
Speaker 1: No other than that one time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this is a video of something that I desire more than just about anything on earth at the moment.
Speaker 1: Why are you aware for the Wii?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Why are you aware for the Wii?
Speaker 1: Exists it is out there.
Speaker 1: people in Japan not only are playing it right now But have been playing it for some pretty sure everyone.
Speaker 0: but North America has it but I could be wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: There are people here who probably imported it and imported a Wii from Japan and are playing it there might be.
Speaker 0: this has got to be At least one guy now.
Speaker 1: WarioWare, I mean we know how the game works.
Speaker 1: WarioWare micro games.
Speaker 1: That's not a big deal But here is a long video that one shows you a butt ton of all these micro games And I gotta say they all look fantastic Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I like how it shows you.
Speaker 0: right before you play a mini game it for like a second It shows you this is how you hold the wiimote for this game.
Speaker 0: This is how you hold the wiimote for this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that allows them at least in my eyes to do a lot more with the micro games without making the game just stupid and Angrifying.
Speaker 1: Yeah But there's an interesting mode that none of us out here in Gaijin land knew about until the weekend when we saw this video.
Speaker 1: there is in fact a 12 player mode in WarioWare.
Speaker 1: It is single elimination 12 up to 12 people pass around one wiimote and they play micro games and if you ever mess up a micro game Your little angel character falls to his death or something.
Speaker 0: so now this is the best thing ever because if you don't know the first WarioWare was a game a GBA game and it Was one player and it was just waste your time playing little micro games and it was okay.
Speaker 0: Then they released the same exact thing for the GameCube, but they tacked on some multiplayer and some you know, not much else You can even you could even play it with a Game Boy Advance by connecting it to your GameCube with the cable.
Speaker 1: that multiplayer Catapulted WarioWare from pretty cool and distracting to one of the best party games ever.
Speaker 0: Yep, then they came out with what WarioWare twisted and WarioWare touched.
Speaker 1: Yeah, touch can die in a fire great concept but the lack of multiplayer the the crippling Warioware touched is for the DS.
Speaker 1: It's really fun.
Speaker 1: If you find it for less than five bucks, you know, someone who has it just take it.
Speaker 0: Warioware twisted is a GBA one that has like a thing where you can tilt your GBA back and forth in some of the games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you really don't want to play that in the DS.
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: You'll be totally backwards actually if you did.
Speaker 1: Yeah But just check out this video.
Speaker 1: If you have the same cravings for Warioware that I have and you'll not only get a touch of it But you'll see this 12 player mode that at least as far as we're concerned is necessary.
Speaker 1: I mean over the weekend, we didn't have any video games that were more than four player.
Speaker 0: It's like we're sitting around we've got like 20 people in the house and we've got a Wii and we're like, alright Let's have some fun with this Wii.
Speaker 0: The only fun we could really have is Wii Sports.
Speaker 0: I mean excite truck.
Speaker 0: the multiplayer is kind of bleh.
Speaker 1: Well, the multiplayer is really fun in excite truck, but still two-player.
Speaker 1: Two-player guitar heroes is great.
Speaker 0: two-player guitar heroes is great.
Speaker 0: It's got a lot of play but two-player there's not.
Speaker 1: and monkey ball ass.
Speaker 0: monkey ball is crap.
Speaker 1: and sports was fun.
Speaker 1: But if the problem was alright, we say hey who wants to play Wii bowling?
Speaker 1: and I don't know ten people raise their hands.
Speaker 0: So what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: You're gonna make people sit there and watch everyone else have fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like okay Warioware.
Speaker 0: the Wii is like the ultimate party machine.
Speaker 0: Everyone knows it.
Speaker 0: That's what it was made for.
Speaker 0: Why weren't there the party games at launch?
Speaker 0: We need these party games.
Speaker 0: bring Warioware out soon.
Speaker 0: Warioware can hold us over until we get Smash Brothers Mario Party Mario Tennis, whatever.
Speaker 1: I mean bring it a when we break the GameCube out.
Speaker 1: Well before the Wii came out we broke the GameCube out at parties.
Speaker 1: It was pretty much just.
Speaker 1: Warioware is the game we would break out occasionally.
Speaker 1: Mario Tennis Yep, and Smash Brothers and soccer Mario Party less occasionally.
Speaker 0: Mario Soccer is really good.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be Mario Soccer Wii the What's it called Mario Strikers, uh, I forget what they call it.
Speaker 1: I'm all about that.
Speaker 0: I gotta say yeah We saw videos of it.
Speaker 0: This guy could be coming out sometime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Wii is not gonna disappoint on the party front.
Speaker 1: It's just a matter of the Japanese letting us have these things before we storm that island and take him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Reggie promised there wouldn't be a drought.
Speaker 0: We'll see how much he keeps up on his promise.
Speaker 1: Well considering that I'm already content with ice hockey and Mario 1.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Metal Slug by the way awesome, but also two-player.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually we'll just give an allusion that next week Instead of talking about reviewing a specific game or something We're gonna talk and we're gonna do it today, but a little tired here.
Speaker 1: Don't want to have to think too much and the game we're gonna review is real easy to talk about without thinking.
Speaker 1: But we want to talk about the logistics of if you're throwing a party about geeks and you know geeks tend to have computers and Video game consoles and a lot of interest in those things if you've got a lot of people in your house for a party or Even if you're running an event somewhere How do you juggle having games available without ruining the vibe of the party and getting that situation where one guy's playing like?
Speaker 1: DDR in the middle of your living room and the other 28 people are standing around in a circle Watching him and slowly drinking themselves into a stupor.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right, but anyway my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I found this game today.
Speaker 0: It got a lot of links from all kinds of people called Samorost 2.
Speaker 0: Yes, there was a Samorost 1 which is a very similar game that I all just found but Let me name some of the reasons that Samorost 2 was all over the internet.
Speaker 0: today It has been nominated in the best web browser game and excellence in visual art category for 2000 independent games festival.
Speaker 0: Flash-forward film festival 2006 winner.
Speaker 0: soul net festival 2006 winner four out of four point five out of five stars by adventure gamers, etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 0: All right This is an award-winning amazing flash game.
Speaker 1: If I describe it in two words, the first word would be slow.
Speaker 1: The second word would be artsy.
Speaker 0: Yes It's basically this really artsy kind of cute looking outer-space alien guy and He's on sort of like these asteroid, but it's like a tree.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's really weird because you're in outer space and there's things floating around.
Speaker 0: They look like asteroids But they're made of wood and there's like stuff growing on them and things living on them and they have little rocket ships that are Pretty cool and it's one of those click adventure games or what you.
Speaker 0: you just have to click at stuff in the right order In order to get to the next screen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not like, you know, your your scum adventure games.
Speaker 0: No where you have to choose, you know, look at that.
Speaker 0: pick that up use it on that person.
Speaker 0: No, it's click on the things in the right order, you know and think like the right number of time.
Speaker 1: for anyone is old enough to remember all the a lot of those Multimedia adventure games that came out during the multimedia PC era.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a lot like that grow game that a lot of people play Where you just had to.
Speaker 0: there's like eight things to choose from and you click them all in the right order to get the biggest Possible planet.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep It's sort of like you go to a screen and you on that screen you click on things in the right order to get to The next screen and watch as the art scene is continued.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid We called games like that hover games because all you did was move the mouse around and the icon the cursor would change Whenever there's something you could click on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you basically click on everything.
Speaker 0: That's how you find what to click on.
Speaker 0: but it is much more difficult to find What to click on, you know, what order to click on them and how many times.
Speaker 1: yes Don't click in the wrong order.
Speaker 0: or and also it's difficult to find, you know You check the whole screen for stuff to click on.
Speaker 0: then something else might be able to be clicked on After you click on one thing and that'll mess you up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So the rest of the world said it's good.
Speaker 1: We didn't play it enough to say it's good.
Speaker 0: I played it for a minute or two And I think it could definitely occupy a day at work.
Speaker 0: Right, it's got a little bit of slow loading action going on though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might just be because it's super popular right now.
Speaker 0: I think it could be so.
Speaker 1: during our party one of our friends you see we had pretty much with few exceptions the entire front row crew in our house and one of the people brought guitar heroes to And one yes and one we really don't play one so much.
Speaker 1: Well thing is we knew guitar heroes was popular.
Speaker 1: Everyone loved it and we never actually got a chance to play it every time we went to for all the longest time It would be there there'd be people playing it.
Speaker 1: We didn't be guests of the con.
Speaker 1: We could have just cut to the front of the line and played if we wanted to.
Speaker 0: but I was.
Speaker 0: I was never saying Uh, that's again.
Speaker 0: I don't want to play.
Speaker 0: It was just never I'd ever wanted it to play it so badly that I would play it.
Speaker 0: I had to wait it.
Speaker 0: basically though the amount of resistance required for me to actually play the game Was more than the effort I was willing to put into it until recently.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean it was an uber con for about two years in a row.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like I didn't have.
Speaker 0: if I had a ps2 I probably would have gotten it, you know.
Speaker 0: but to buy the system and To buy the game and the controller is like way more effort that I'm gonna put in for one game.
Speaker 0: Unless someone puts the game in my face I wasn't gonna play it, but even though friends that it was great and played it constantly and got really good at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I didn't disagree.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know be money games I like be money games and that's made by red octane, which they're basically the American masters of be money.
Speaker 0: I trusted them and you know, I could imagine it would be fun to Pretend you're a rock star rocking out with a guitar, you know to real awesome music.
Speaker 0: good stuff Yep.
Speaker 1: So after having finally played it on two separate occasions We can say with certainty that guitar heroes is fucking fantastic.
Speaker 0: Oh man, guitar hero is an awesome game.
Speaker 0: If you have a ps2 and you don't have guitar hero Why do you even have a ps2?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's really no point.
Speaker 0: It did.
Speaker 0: There's no there's no purpose.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: I don't think it would be enough for me to buy.
Speaker 1: I mean guitar heroes alone would not be reason for me to buy a slim ps2.
Speaker 1: No, however, we also want to play Kingdom Hearts and Kingdom Hearts 2 press a press.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I really want to play Kingdom Hearts 2, but I know I want to play Kingdom Hearts 1 Yes, and I want to play Okami real badly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people send the good stuff about that one.
Speaker 0: It seems like a Zelda type game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: you brought around feeding animals and it looks really cute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also really badass.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: So now there's enough reasons to buy a ps2.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna wait for the price to drop one more time I think and for all the games I've got to go out of style.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean as much as I love guitar heroes, and I want to play all these other games.
Speaker 1: I Haven't even gotten past the first little bit of Zelda because I just haven't had time to play it.
Speaker 0: Yep There's no way I'm going out to buy a system and more games when I've got a system and games to play that I haven't Been.
Speaker 1: but I cannot recommend guitar heroes enough.
Speaker 1: I mean, especially a lot of people would probably like games like DDR But they're either in a kind of house where you can't really play it or you're in an apartment where you can't jump around A lot or I don't know you're fat or you're not very athletic and you can't dance around very much.
Speaker 1: Guitar heroes gives you all the fun that DDR gives you without the workout.
Speaker 0: Yeah, another thing is a lot of people, you know who would normally like DDR.
Speaker 0: I know some people like this where you know, they're like, ah DDR and you know somewhere in there.
Speaker 0: So, you know they would like it if they actually tried it.
Speaker 0: But they won't try it because you look stupid you they don't like the music etc, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: Like Pete for way way back.
Speaker 1: We're trying to give his feet to play DDR with us.
Speaker 1: I was like now no, it's dumb No, no, no, and then one day he finally plays it with us at the arcade and he's like, you know what?
Speaker 1: This is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Thanks for ruining my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah Guitar hero has all that but it's not hard to convince people to try it because they go.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want me to fucking rock out to some songs that I already know that are awesome.
Speaker 0: sure thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's the.
Speaker 1: that's probably the greatest point of success in guitar heroes and guitar heroes to is that they read octane Knew their audience and they picked the exact music that the audience they were aiming for wanted in a game.
Speaker 0: Well, they also they.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's music that I could think of a billion songs that they would have probably would have tried to Get but just to cause too much money to ya.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but despite that the music they got is definitely the music I want.
Speaker 0: yeah, another great thing about guitar here that it is like I discover all kinds of new music in it, you know It's like.
Speaker 0: sure there's the songs that I already know that are in there, you know And those are pretty cool to play them a couple times.
Speaker 0: I played war pig like four times Yeah, but you go in there and you see like, uh, what the hell's this song.
Speaker 0: less talk more rock.
Speaker 0: That's a fucking awesome song.
Speaker 0: or this song Freya.
Speaker 0: That's a freaking awesome song.
Speaker 0: Who is who are these people playing this song?
Speaker 0: Oh, that's who those people are.
Speaker 0: Let me go and visit their website, you know, and that's pretty cool, too.
Speaker 0: Considering I'm not discovering new music Guitar heroes my number one source of discovering new music recently.
Speaker 0: How's that?
Speaker 1: also one thing this game does well that other attempts in similar games have done very poorly and DDR Does it well, but for some reason I see people having trouble with DDR's curve, but the learning curve of guitar heroes is perfect Mmm and it's I mean an individual mode.
Speaker 1: you you make between easy and what difficult Yep, and you like medium.
Speaker 1: There's always there's different levels of difficulty.
Speaker 0: It's easy medium hard and extreme.
Speaker 1: now if you put it on easy It's really really really easy, but it's not stupid easy like beginner on DDR where it's just useless Yeah, and DDR like the lowest setting is so easy that it's not fun.
Speaker 0: It's like left left, right, right Like you learn how to play the game, but it's not fun at all.
Speaker 0: It's just Boringly easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah beginner mode in DDR doesn't give touch teach you anything that the opening screen doesn't already teach you Yep.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is the rate.
Speaker 0: basically in DDR.
Speaker 0: the trick mode however Which is the second difficulty is too difficult for someone who's never played before.
Speaker 0: they just get on and play.
Speaker 0: you know and like.
Speaker 0: I couldn't play trick mode until I had played the Somewhat boring basic mode for like days.
Speaker 1: Well, you mean beginner?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah basic not beginner beginners.
Speaker 1: One arrow per song.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: But you know guitar hero There are five buttons on the on the guitar and the strummy thing and the whammy bar Which isn't.
Speaker 0: you don't really need to use the whammy bar ever, but it's good to use it.
Speaker 1: It's also fun to use it.
Speaker 0: It is to beat the beginner mode.
Speaker 0: this easy mode in guitar hero uses three Buttons and there's not a lot of strumming to do so.
Speaker 0: it's really really really easy But there's enough action that it's actually fun to play even if you're like the master of guitar hero.
Speaker 0: Playing easy mode is kind of fun because you still feel like you're playing the song.
Speaker 1: See, I think one of the reasons that people have so much trouble with learning DDR right away Is that the feedback you get for doing well or doing poorly is not obvious to non gamers and you don't feel Like if you start failing a song this health bar just starts going down and you just get flustered and
Speaker 0: quit and people go boo
Speaker 1: Boo, but in this game, there's so much feedback if you miss a note you the song whatever part you were playing Doesn't get played.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's I guess that's cuz.
Speaker 0: DDR is a dancing game and not it.
Speaker 1: The feedback is so intuitive that people who even people aren't gamers if they hit the wrong note in the middle of I don't know Led Zeppelin song
Speaker 0: which is there are no Led Zeppelin songs and guitar hero regretfully, which is it which is the only problem with the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want stairway in there so badly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but as an example and you're doing stairway, let's say and You're playing that opening a little bit and you mess up and you just hear a bad note.
Speaker 0: And then yeah, there's what stairway up like doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 0: Sorry, so that we've five notes, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you don't hit the third note.
Speaker 0: You won't hear doo doo.
Speaker 0: You won't hear stairway.
Speaker 0: You'll hear doo doo doo doo and you go Oh shit, and like if you just stop if you just stand there you turn on guitar.
Speaker 0: here you say, alright I'm gonna do that song and you start playing but you don't do anything.
Speaker 0: You just stand there with your hands in your pockets.
Speaker 0: You won't hear shit.
Speaker 0: It'll just be quiet and then you'll fail.
Speaker 0: It's pretty without that feature without the fact that you are playing the song and unless you hit all the notes You will not hear the whole song.
Speaker 0: you every note you miss will be missed.
Speaker 0: guitar here wouldn't be half as good.
Speaker 0: That's what makes that game.
Speaker 1: Yep Also - because now once you figure the game out and you start playing well You hear the song while you're playing and you feel like you're playing the song and it really feels good.
Speaker 0: That's
Speaker 1: like board games for if you even if you're doing something even on an easy easy easy mode You feel like you're playing that song
Speaker 0: I'm telling you without that single thing Just that that's half the fun of the whole game is is the fact that you feel like you're playing it.
Speaker 0: You know DDR.
Speaker 0: you don't really feel like you're dancing.
Speaker 0: You feel like you're playing DDR But guitar hero really makes you feel as well as can be done without some wicked Futuristic ghost in the shell shit that you're a rock star Rocking out on stage.
Speaker 1: and I I mean I'm at the point now I can play medium Scott and I both.
Speaker 1: we can just play medium songs.
Speaker 0: hands down I can play the hard songs that are at the top.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the hard songs down near the bottom.
Speaker 0: I just die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course then all our friends who've been playing this game for the last few years.
Speaker 1: It can are really really good at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of them are really good.
Speaker 0: If I own the game, I'll become really really good I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: but yeah, the easy mode is you know, there's three.
Speaker 0: you only have to use three buttons the top three buttons and You know, but there's still.
Speaker 0: you're still feel like you're playing the song.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the way they'll do it like say in easy mode.
Speaker 1: You only have the three buttons.
Speaker 1: So you're playing some guitar solo.
Speaker 1: It'll kind of approximate.
Speaker 1: like the notes don't correspond directly to the guitar.
Speaker 0: I can play a lot of notes.
Speaker 0: It's only five buttons on this thing.
Speaker 0: You cannot play every note a guitar can play.
Speaker 1: So what it'll do is it'll approximate like if the next note or set of notes was going up or higher You'll hit a higher note or a lower note on the thing and it's all relative.
Speaker 1: So the same button might play a different note at different parts of the song.
Speaker 1: But because it moves relative to the music you still feel like you're playing the song and as you get harder difficulty It just matches the song closer.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It's also a lot of tricks in guitar here that are very forgiving.
Speaker 0: Like let's say the song is green green green.
Speaker 0: What's the next color?
Speaker 0: red red red red?
Speaker 0: You can play.
Speaker 0: you hold down the green button you strum three times.
Speaker 0: Then you know the thing you would think in your brain would be just hold down the red button and strum three times.
Speaker 0: But actually if you hold down green and red because green is above red It doesn't make a difference whether you hold it down or not.
Speaker 0: You could hold green three times then hold and just add the red to it and go three times and stay.
Speaker 0: it's you know.
Speaker 0: And unless there's a chord that'll work as long as you can hold down any button above.
Speaker 0: So let's say it's orange orange orange orange.
Speaker 0: You can hold down all five buttons and go strum strum strum strum and that'll hit it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and right along with that.
Speaker 1: I mean since it's not DDR It's more like a guitar the strumming mechanism is what triggers it not the frets.
Speaker 1: So you can just dick around on the frets all the time as long as you're not doing it when you're strumming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you can play ahead of time and it just it feels like you're playing a guitar.
Speaker 0: The game also kind of only punishes you if you strum when there's no notes Or if you strum the wrong notes and or if you notes come by and they didn't get strummed.
Speaker 0: That's the three ways that you can mess up now.
Speaker 1: because we're tired We'll crack out this a little bit short but suffice to say Guitar heroes is freaking fantastic for all the reasons.
Speaker 1: We mentioned it has good music in it.
Speaker 1: It's a great game.
Speaker 1: It's a good game to have around when you're having a party and what else could I really say about it?
Speaker 0: Well, I think there's a couple informational things.
Speaker 0: the first thing is that the guitar this the guitar that comes with guitar hero 2 is Significantly better than the guitar that comes with guitar here.
Speaker 1: There is no reason to get the guitar hero 1 guitar if you can avoid it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because there's a. basically if you lift the guitar vertically, you know, it does it activates the star mode Which is sort of necessary and helpful in the game.
Speaker 0: the guitar hero 1 guitar You got kind of had to shake it about pretty hard to make it do that.
Speaker 0: The guitar hero 2 guitar.
Speaker 0: you just lift it up and it activates the star mode.
Speaker 0: Also, the whammy bar the guitar hero 2 guitar has a different amount of feedback on it, but that's not a big deal.
Speaker 1: It feels a lot better though.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I didn't really notice the difference with that.
Speaker 0: The other thing guitar hero 2. it's like some of the songs and guitar hero 1, you know you really wish they were in guitar hero 2. obviously they can't fit them on the disc, but And guitar hero 2 has much much better Multiplayer so much better that the guitar hero 1 multiplayer is basically useless Which is kind of sad because you want to play some guitar hero 1 songs in the good guitar hero 2 multiplayer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you can play competitively you can play cooperatively There's all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: co-op mode is the one that gets played most breaks it up also into like lead and rhythm or lead And bass.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and they're all different and I actually really enjoy playing bass Yep, but yeah, the co-op mode is definitely where the action is, you know The playing the versus mode isn't really that fun because everyone knows who's better than who else.
Speaker 0: so You know who's gonna win isn't gonna change too often.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well just like in DDR I mean none of us at least and most of the people we know ever bothered actually competing with each other on DDR.
Speaker 1: We just would both play DDR next to each other for fun.
Speaker 0: Yep, and What else is difference?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah guitar hero 2 is has is significantly harder.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not harder all across the board But if you're looking for the extended difficulty if you're the master of guitar hero 1 there is stuff waiting for you in guitar hero 2. so if you're looking to you know Build up the skills and become the master beat all of guitar hero 1 and then go to guitar hero 2 and then you will Master that as well.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.