Speaker 1: It's Wednesday September 12th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We review superspy by Matt kint.
Speaker 1: Let's do this All right, so yesterday.
Speaker 1: We didn't do a normal show.
Speaker 0: we did the special show because Scott decided to go see some circuses.
Speaker 0: No after his bread.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, that kind of circus Yeah, I guess what.
Speaker 0: when have I ever used the word circus in any context other than bread and circuses?
Speaker 1: when you're talking about trapezes and clowns?
Speaker 0: When was the last time I talked about those things?
Speaker 1: Anyway, I went to see the baseball.
Speaker 1: it was a pretty bad baseball But I'm glad I went because the way it works is think first of all the game.
Speaker 1: We weren't sure if it was gonna rain out cuz it was pretty rainy.
Speaker 0: Scott's complaining to me over the the Gmail.
Speaker 0: just uh I don't want to show up.
Speaker 0: if it's gonna get rained out and my dad Doesn't show up cuz then I'm stuck and I have to take a crap train home.
Speaker 0: But if it doesn't get rained out, but I don't go then I don't get to go to another game, but if I do go Yeah, so I'm glad I did go because it didn't rain out.
Speaker 1: in fact pretty much as soon as the game started It was close to starting it stopped raining, and it didn't rain at all the whole game, and they played and But they got killed.
Speaker 1: it was not pleasant and We went home before the game was all the way.
Speaker 1: well We didn't go home.
Speaker 1: you went home before the official end of the game But when we left it was over.
Speaker 0: I do however note that there's one instance where?
Speaker 0: We were at a sporting event you me and a few other of our friends or in this case I can't refer to them as friends, but maybe dumbasses And the team the home team we were rooting for was down By a lot and there was like a minute left of play, and it was obviously over.
Speaker 0: so everybody walks out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, screw this.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna win.
Speaker 0: It's over and If I'm second left correctly with two seconds left They tied it up.
Speaker 0: they tied it up And they wouldn't over time and they won it over time.
Speaker 1: everyone was crazy for like ten minutes.
Speaker 0: I still have the ticket in my wallet.
Speaker 1: I still have the ticket in my room But anyway, oh it also one time.
Speaker 1: I went to a Mets game must have been like 99 I think and it was like against the Phillies and Kurt Schilling was pitching and it was raining and The game was freaking delayed for like an hour or two because of the rain.
Speaker 1: but then they eventually played.
Speaker 1: but it was getting so late that we went home plus the Mets were losing.
Speaker 1: and Then on the way home.
Speaker 1: We listen to the radio and they came back.
Speaker 0: see it's weird because I mean you'd think oh I want to see my team win.
Speaker 0: But it's kind of like what happens in the count of Monte Cristo where if you go to see a sporting event and the team You're rooting for isn't just losing but getting their asses handed to them you kind of you're brought down to the lowest of the low the most despair you can get out of a sporting event.
Speaker 0: and Then if they turn it around and win it, it's the best thing ever.
Speaker 0: because now it's not just from neutral to win It's lose to win.
Speaker 0: That's an extra step.
Speaker 0: That's like double yelling.
Speaker 1: It's all relative.
Speaker 0: It's all relative it is But unrelated to that entirely Emily and I finally got our own Etymotic 6i isolator earbuds.
Speaker 1: Oh now you will not go deaf.
Speaker 0: So well, I wouldn't have anyway because master Keaton is actually very quiet and rarely even has background music.
Speaker 1: That's true But at least now you can hear master Keaton.
Speaker 0: when there's crying babies or Trains going by or subways It's usually loud indignant woman on a cell phone talking about something that happened to her recently that made her indignant.
Speaker 0: Yep or Every morning if I depending on its there's always at least one old man Who took a peak train and tries to pay with his old man fair and the conductor always explains the same monotone?
Speaker 0: There's no such thing as an old man fair on the peak train and the old man says I've been riding this train for 20 Years, you don't you're not the boss of me.
Speaker 0: and the conductor says yeah pay me or I'm calling the police.
Speaker 1: Well today Connecticut train into the city because I was you know in Connecticut after the game.
Speaker 1: Oh the Connecticut trains the ones that have the overhead lines Yeah, but the because the Connecticut people have a different train etiquette.
Speaker 1: So they were all talky as opposed to the Hudson line.
Speaker 1: people which are all quiet on the morning train Like they should be.
Speaker 0: the Harlem line was actually kind of weird the few times I took that in.
Speaker 1: but yeah Yeah, it's funny how the different train lines all have different etiquette.
Speaker 1: It's like the Connecticut people are all chatty.
Speaker 1: the new up upstate New York.
Speaker 1: People are all quiet and you know tired.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Hudson line serious business is serious business though granted now that school started a lot of people are taking that train for school like in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: on the train I take mm-hmm and Everyday there's two factions punk kids talking to each other about their pokemons in business and Businessmen who are super pissed off at them for making noise.
Speaker 1: Why don't those kids take the subway or the bus is cheaper.
Speaker 0: Ah Not depends.
Speaker 0: It's a lot faster to take the metro north and there's a city ticket thing where it's like three bucks.
Speaker 1: Ah, there you go.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So how?
Speaker 1: those headphones?
Speaker 0: they're really great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I said I didn't have to listen to any of that business.
Speaker 1: So I got.
Speaker 1: so my I've been.
Speaker 1: you know, we need to do the show.
Speaker 1: we wear headphones that we can hear ourselves talk.
Speaker 1: I don't know why we do that.
Speaker 0: Well, we used to not.
Speaker 0: I mean, well, I always did because early in the days You know, we didn't have a compressor way back or anything.
Speaker 0: we just had our little mixer and I had my little things plugged into it and I thought I was using it all cool and I knew about audio and I always saw that, you know I wore the headphones like everyone does on TV or when you see someone in a recording studio and I'd hear myself talk and I'd hear Scott talk and I try to use that to you know.
Speaker 0: Make the audio levels good, but Scott because he didn't have headphones on Couldn't react to things the way I did so I always had to fiddle with his volume And once I got him a pair of headphones, I didn't have to fiddle with his volume anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is I don't conscious the thing about wearing headphones and recording a podcast.
Speaker 1: I think it's actually essential because even though I don't consciously listen in the headphones to try to hear things or anything like that Just having them on has this sort of subconscious effect on how I talk and how we do the show.
Speaker 1: And I think if we did the show without the headphones then did the same show again with the headphones You would notice a big difference.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well part of it is just you hear the relative like if suddenly your voice sounds really loud in yours.
Speaker 0: You know that huh?
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm a little too close to the microphone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe I'm pulling a Dave Riley here.
Speaker 1: The thing is you can't use.
Speaker 1: I would use my etymotics, but they can't.
Speaker 1: they don't have volume control on them.
Speaker 0: The only volume control is up with me in the little mixer setup and Partly because we use a splitter because it's a tiny little mixer.
Speaker 0: The volume is all the way up.
Speaker 0: Yeah all the way up.
Speaker 1: so I had these cheap like 15 $20 Radio Shack things that is separate volume for left and right and they They haven't been working.
Speaker 0: So well one that that's kind of crappy anyway, yeah, and now I'm using these free headphones.
Speaker 1: We got with the Marantz recorder thing and they also suck.
Speaker 1: But at least they work because the Radio Shack ones are broken for the longest time and it's kind of weird to actually have Working headphones now.
Speaker 1: I can I can hear things on my right ear.
Speaker 0: It's strange Yeah, but one thing I want to say.
Speaker 0: this comes up a lot in the forums and it comes up every now and then in the show.
Speaker 0: but if you listen to iPods or anything or podcasts and I imagine you listen to podcasts at least one or two and You're ever in places where there's background noise get a pair of etymotic 6i isolators or
Speaker 1: at least some sort of isolation or noise cancelling headphones that actually work because
Speaker 0: otherwise you're gonna lose your hearing pretty quick
Speaker 1: or you're not gonna be able to hear what you're Listening to because you you know, you don't want to turn the volume up because it'll hurt your hearing.
Speaker 1: So you you force yourself to keep the volume low so you don't hurt your hearing.
Speaker 1: but now this background noise and you can't hear what's going on because using the The the buds that came with your iPod or something, right?
Speaker 0: But enough of that.
Speaker 0: it is in fact anime night Oh man's animes and I don't know there wasn't so much anime news.
Speaker 1: You know the con seasons over everyone made their big announcements.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna get big announcements again for many months you know, there's gonna be a new anime season and then Then we'll get a bunch more news.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean on one hand the one news I saw that it was I thought was funny was that Tetsu Ohara is gonna do a children's anime called a morino senshi bono alone.
Speaker 0: Tetsu Ohara for those of you who are unaware is the man who created fist of the something something Yeah, something like that, yeah.
Speaker 1: So that's pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: problem is all I can say about that is hahaha.
Speaker 0: Look it's happening.
Speaker 1: I know it's always funny when someone doesn't work that you like you don't expect them to do.
Speaker 1: You know, like if someone is known for making like you like Takashi Miike made like mr.
Speaker 1: Rogers, you know It's like.
Speaker 0: I know exactly that would go.
Speaker 0: it would start with mister mr Rogers pissing on the corpse of his dead mother maybe and then the yakuza would come and there'd be a fight in the street.
Speaker 0: It's like it's gonna be all like realistic and a bunch of people would have died and it'd be really sad.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like when Jim Carrey, you know He's known for his crazy comedies and then he tried to make a non crazy comedy people were like what and then it was Actually kind of okay and good, you know some of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well when I saw eternal sunshine all I could think is god damn Why didn't he tell us he was an actor before and I didn't like that one that much?
Speaker 1: I think it was overrated.
Speaker 1: I mean it wasn't bad, but I think it was overrated.
Speaker 1: I'm talking like Truman show.
Speaker 0: It was overrated compared to the hype but as a movie it was badass.
Speaker 1: It wasn't badass.
Speaker 1: It was good.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's better.
Speaker 0: It's better than time cop.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: But yeah, well, I really think it's always interesting when someone who is known for making You know art in a particular style or genre breaks from that and tries to do something else.
Speaker 1: And that's really when you can tell if they actually have artistic talent or not Or if they're just a one-trick pony who is you know, perfected one thing.
Speaker 0: We've seen that in sports when Someone we might all remember tried to play a different sport than he was used to.
Speaker 1: yeah Think about it's really hard.
Speaker 1: in sports.
Speaker 1: I mean pretty much two people ever that I know of have successfully played two sports.
Speaker 1: Well, and that's Bo Jackson and What's his name?
Speaker 1: Hey, I just had his name John Sanders.
Speaker 0: I play both air hockey and counter-strike.
Speaker 1: very well I'm talking about professional sports Bo Jackson Deion Sanders or it that that's like the end of the story.
Speaker 1: No one else.
Speaker 0: Hey, don't don't did cuz in terms of air hockey now that we know exactly how I'm not arguing whether or not it's a sport.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, no.
Speaker 0: No, I'm saying that in terms of air hockey I think that if we own an air hockey table within a year we could be in the professional air hockey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not but that's not you know, a professional sport.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess yes, it's a professional sport But it's not one of the professional sports, you know period it's not You know, well considering even the big tournaments look like they ran out the holiday in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I got some news here and I thought that was your news.
Speaker 0: No, I just wanted to bring that up.
Speaker 0: All right this news.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna.
Speaker 0: let's see if we can follow this.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read partly from anime news network because I don't want to try to summarize Oh reading anime news network.
Speaker 0: So awesome Oh, yes, so awesome.
Speaker 0: So, uh a while ago there was a press release announcing that a TV Which owned a part of genie on entertainments us a genius or Jenny on I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've heard both from people in the industry and out of the industry.
Speaker 1: It's pioneer Yeah, pioneer and it's also.
Speaker 1: it's also physical plant and capstone and it's the Nintendo revolution.
Speaker 0: That's the Phoenix web browser.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna read straight up here The genie on anime production.
Speaker 0: Say Yes, awesome had started business as pioneers.
Speaker 0: LDC laserdisc subsidiary before pioneers sold it to Dentsu in July of 2003 really?
Speaker 1: How do you spell Dentsu?
Speaker 0: Dntsu, it's not then setsu which you were probably thinking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe you know what I read.
Speaker 1: so they say Ken before it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no fungus ambition Right, so, uh, the Mitsubishi conglomerates D rights Subsidiary then entered a joint venture with Dentsu to acquire a 34% equity stake in genie on entertainment in June of 2006. with Mitsubishi's divestment genie on is now a wholly owned subsidiary of Dentsu.
Speaker 0: again It goes on with.
Speaker 0: there's another percentage and a couple more company names like sojits wait Let me translate works, which is a wholly owned subsidiary of sojits.
Speaker 1: I think I can translate this.
Speaker 1: you ready I can translate it into two sentences.
Speaker 0: Oh, can you now?
Speaker 1: Yep number one Japanese business is complicated, you know more complicated than American business.
Speaker 0: It's no more complicated than the car industry perhaps.
Speaker 1: Yeah his sentence number two.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 1: Genie on is not doing so.
Speaker 0: well See, maybe that wouldn't have been the case.
Speaker 0: He could have said oh, it was just a business gobbledygook.
Speaker 0: But as part of this merger genie on did lay off like 20% of its workforce.
Speaker 0: So like five guys yeah, really it's.
Speaker 1: it's a TV is sort of conglomerating a lot of the anime industry into itself and you know, it's pretty much like a TV and funimation are going big and Media blasters kinda, you
Speaker 0: know, it's weird But it seems like back and when I was at RIT in the early days when I was in high school Who put out an anime who made an anime company wise?
Speaker 0: Mattered a lot to me because I saw trends like.
Speaker 0: it seemed like anything that said Bandai or pioneer was good But nowadays for a long time now Really been ignoring that and I care a lot more about who directed the anime.
Speaker 1: That's what you get when you learn stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, plus it doesn't you know, but ADV is still known for doing all the bouncy booby animes and you know, it's Yeah, also the manga companies like viz and you know It's really.
Speaker 1: it's the viz funimation combination is is rocking everyone's boat because they have all the big Licenses and they have the big partnerships with the Japanese companies and it's really tough to beat the Shonen jumps.
Speaker 0: Hey Yeah, though what I'm curious about?
Speaker 0: Dave Riley a fast karate for the gentleman has been called a man with a sexy voice many times in the past and I remember At one point on their show someone said that he could read pretty much anything and it would sound sexy.
Speaker 0: So my challenge to him, I'm throwing the glove.
Speaker 0: I want you to read this on your show in a cell.
Speaker 0: the boys the business This whole business talk gobbledygook.
Speaker 1: I want to hear it You know, I really don't care.
Speaker 1: I want to hear think about it.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I'm fundamentally opposed the idea of playing, you know podcast promos or podcast networks or anything like that.
Speaker 0: But I kind of like Dave and Joel and that's the only way I can promote them without actually Promoting them is bring them up in tangential kind of way.
Speaker 1: All right, can I can I do a news now?
Speaker 0: I guess so.
Speaker 1: digital manga publishing who is a manga publisher in the US?
Speaker 1: and they publish a few things that are cool Like they publish those robot anthologies and some stuff like that, right?
Speaker 1: They have a new.
Speaker 1: they did they licensed a bunch more manga, right and in the agreement for licenses for these manga They have agreed with the Japanese publishers to put the logos of the Japanese publishers on the manga.
Speaker 0: Prominently, this is a good thing.
Speaker 1: This is this is really strange too.
Speaker 1: Cuz I mean like you look at Something like viz right and they put the viz logo all big and they put they put the shonen jump thing on there, too.
Speaker 1: But that's because that's actually a brand they use in the US.
Speaker 1: but they don't put like shoe Asia on there.
Speaker 1: or you know No one puts like katakawa or anything on there on their animes or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You know It's it's the Japanese Companies.
Speaker 1: the publishers over there are sort of kept a secret from us and only like the uber fans know what they are.
Speaker 1: And I think that if more Japanese companies Force the American companies to put the Japanese publisher logos on their manga People will start to see you know like a Tokyo pop that has one logo and then a digital manga publishing book that has the same logo on it and it's like People begin to realize.
Speaker 1: Oh and then they'll start to buy, you know, like if I see the you know, the Big shonen spirit logo on books over here.
Speaker 1: I'm like, aha.
Speaker 0: I know I want that book And then we do that.
Speaker 0: now we go to like in Okuniya and you just tell by the logo.
Speaker 0: I want that wall.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want that wall desperately.
Speaker 1: that's one thing that actually American comics and Japanese comics sort of have in common.
Speaker 1: is that the the publisher or at least the imprint?
Speaker 1: You know the the late the label on the book that says who who made it?
Speaker 1: Sort of tells you something about what the book's gonna be.
Speaker 1: if something says shonen jump You can be pretty sure it contains a story about kids or at least younger people with some sort of magical or supernatural Powers usually with some sort of fighting in maybe not the physical sense, but some sort of fighting.
Speaker 1: You know whether it's Death Note or One Piece or Naruto and you can tell if something says You know vertigo on it in the u.s.
Speaker 1: That it's gonna be some sort of serious adult possibly gory sort of drama like like an HBO television series in comic form.
Speaker 1: so Nowadays because we have in the manga in the u.s Like Tokyo pop and viz and whoever they just license as much manga as they can and they put their label on all of it.
Speaker 1: Just cuz something says viz doesn't mean you're gonna like it.
Speaker 1: just cuz sentence says Tokyo pop.
Speaker 1: that tells you nothing about the manga itself.
Speaker 1: and While I sorta on the one hand I'm sort of against the genre publisher link up.
Speaker 1: It is kind of useful from a purchasing perspective and being able to tell What you might also like and you might miss out on some things and you also might you know Get some things you don't want.
Speaker 1: so if we get the Japanese labeling which is sort of tied to genre in a way Then it'll be easier for Americans who pay attention to it to purchase manga they want and avoid manga.
Speaker 1: They don't want because knowing something is published by Tokyo pop tells you nothing.
Speaker 0: things of the day.
Speaker 0: So this probably would have been better yesterday.
Speaker 0: But Scott was at the baseball game and we put up a special and I guess it's an amount till today.
Speaker 1: So you couldn't have done it yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I could have done it yesterday by traveling back in time or by doing it next Tuesday.
Speaker 0: All right, but you know how.
Speaker 0: Team Fortress 2 the game that I've waited for for about a decade.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's coming We're gonna play on Monday.
Speaker 1: that I already pre-loaded on my computer just now that I could activate if I just knew some bits.
Speaker 0: Game that's coming.
Speaker 0: Well, they've been doing a marketing campaign where they've been releasing one by one Videos entitled meet the and then the name of one of the classes from the game It started with.
Speaker 1: so if it was World of Warcraft It would be like meet the paladin meet the night meet the wizard and the first one is still the best one.
Speaker 0: meet the heavy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I am heavy weapons guy.
Speaker 1: Can you name all the classes without looking?
Speaker 0: Honestly, I can name them all in weapons factory, but they're almost the same, you know, there's heavy weapons guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's marine whatever the soldier but a same class.
Speaker 0: It's the same in all those games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's the Engineer which is named the same thing everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the arsonist slash pyro pyro.
Speaker 0: There's the Spy.
Speaker 0: Yep, the sniper.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the demolitions man.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I think there might be the medic.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, the medic or the nurse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the medic nurse.
Speaker 1: There might be another one.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I actually played more weapons factory than I did any other capture the flag game ever.
Speaker 1: I Capture the flag.
Speaker 1: I never really play tribes to have more than most capture the flag.
Speaker 0: You never played any like.
Speaker 1: TFC is a big.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: when I played TFC I mostly played the hunted.
Speaker 1: I didn't really well the VIP mode.
Speaker 0: TFC was the weakest of all the team fortresses Yeah, but the VIP mode was the strongest mode.
Speaker 1: So I never played the capture the flag.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I digress there very much plus I was the best VIP.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: I always made it.
Speaker 0: The third one of these is out.
Speaker 0: it is meet the engineer and all I'd really like to say is that the best part of this video is When he pauses waiting for his rockets to land and then there's just this very kind of Happy contented smile as he hears them explode in the distance.
Speaker 1: The only thing I say about this video is that it makes me sad that some 3d model can play the guitar better than me.
Speaker 0: These things are worth watching even if you're not a video gamer or a PC gamer at all.
Speaker 1: Well, it'll also make you buy the game.
Speaker 1: So you might not want to watch of course the game.
Speaker 1: You can buy it now for $45 on Steam.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Is it like the best deal of the century?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is gonna be probably one of these seminal works of PC gaming.
Speaker 1: Yeah I have a feeling that Monday will take the day I remember.
Speaker 0: if this game doesn't live up to what we're all making it out to be I imagine it's gonna be like the greatest track.
Speaker 1: There was just a thing online today like the 10 flat to.
Speaker 1: It was like.
Speaker 1: it was like the 10 flops in gaming and they were like.
Speaker 1: these are games that were you know hyped up but then they flopped like and they were talking about Mario Sunshine and stuff you say.
Speaker 1: right and If this doesn't go a mate if this game isn't amazing It'll be the greatest video game flop ever like the next day.
Speaker 1: I usually hate it when something happens like a few days ago and people immediately start putting it on like top 10 lists.
Speaker 1: like You know, oh, it's the biggest flop ever even though it just happened.
Speaker 0: Well, like Bioshock is already being lauded as one of the top 10 best games ever made.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wouldn't do that.
Speaker 1: It would put a top 50 maybe but it if TF2 isn't perfect.
Speaker 1: That's the biggest flop ever.
Speaker 0: I mean, it might even displace Daikatana as most infamous game ever.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know Daikatana I think just came out on just came out.
Speaker 1: No, no, was it on game tap or one of those services you can?
Speaker 1: you can get it now.
Speaker 0: But is it?
Speaker 0: it wasn't worth playing then?
Speaker 0: it's not worth playing now.
Speaker 0: It was terrible.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: Why did you do that to me?
Speaker 1: Alright, so I do my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I guess alright.
Speaker 1: so you know how people like to take the high-speed photographs.
Speaker 1: they get a camera the camera takes a lot of pictures really fast and Then you know you like shoot a bullet through a pane of glass or you shoot an arrow through an apple or you Drop something in a bucket of water and you can see like all the water the glass moving around Like in super slow motion.
Speaker 1: It's way cool, right?
Speaker 1: Well, this guy did something a little better than that.
Speaker 1: Not only did he have a ludicrously high-speed camera, right?
Speaker 1: But he had a dark room and he had a flash, you know Like an incredible flash that would just be like super bright for like a second like, you know an incredibly short amount of time.
Speaker 0: You know, it is comic night.
Speaker 0: I I almost made a joke about the flash just standing there in the room causing trouble.
Speaker 1: and then he had he had a trigger Set so that when there is noise right any audio will set off the camera to take a picture and set off the flash with the perfect timing to get Exactly one high-speed photograph, right.
Speaker 1: and then he did a bunch of things in front of it but the ones that are really cool is.
Speaker 1: he took these ceramic figurines of.
Speaker 1: You know people, you know in Stances or scenes doing various Asian martial arts like this one Like a guy's getting ready to do a kick and there's one where a guy is kicking another guy and the guy is blocking it And there's another one with like this girl doing some Tai Chi and there's another one with a girl doing Tai Chi and whatever And he took these ceramic figurines and he put him in in front of the camera and he dropped him.
Speaker 1: So you get this picture like just as they hit the ground and they're shattered But they're not like totally shattered yet and it's like at the exact moment in time that it's.
Speaker 1: it's awesome Just looking at these pictures man.
Speaker 1: They're pretty cool.
Speaker 0: You know for some reason.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I'm kind of reminded of that video We linked to was the thing of the day a while ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are some other things that he took pictures of.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: I think it's called.
Speaker 1: I think they call this like at the moment of impact or something But these are definitely.
Speaker 1: he gets the best effect with these because you see like this guy kicking and his leg is in like three Pieces, but they're all still in the air kicking but like all the stuff near the bottom of the sculpture is like completely shattered.
Speaker 1: So it looks like a really awesome scene from like a kung-fu movie or something It's like and it's high-resolution, too Right.
Speaker 0: So it is anime manga and while we don't do it often comics night.
Speaker 1: Oh my god It's time to like get your sweater when you're getting ready to go to hell cuz rim read a comic.
Speaker 0: Oh my god that clock never rings ding.
Speaker 0: Now tonight we're gonna talk about super spy by Matt kint.
Speaker 1: Yes It is published by top shelf is published this year.
Speaker 0: top shelf is known for doing all those indie style Kind of awesome comics.
Speaker 0: They're the people who were always at like every comic convention with the awesome indie kind of booth and the indie kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they generally like a lot of what they put out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this book is $20, but it wasn't $20 for me, but it'd be $20 for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I have an opinion as to how much money it's actually worth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a one self-contained Comic that's broken up into like a whole bunch of smaller stories But they all sort of go into one another.
Speaker 1: when we were at mocha Matt kint was actually there and I had heard of this book before going But I decided not to buy it there because it would have cost $20 and I bought it Later, you know with my pre-orders for much less money like $12 or $14 I don't remember.
Speaker 1: and they also had a limited-edition hardcover at the mocha arts festival, but I don't think we need that.
Speaker 1: I don't think we need the hardcover.
Speaker 1: I think the soft cover is just fine and in fact better.
Speaker 1: So this book super spy it is about spying during the Second World War And there are many characters who are all spies of some sort.
Speaker 0: sadly I just read it and I can't name a single one.
Speaker 1: Yeah Shay something those one guy named super spy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I don't remember the names of any of the other ones.
Speaker 0: well, here's the real issue that the comic is set in World War two and It's very much has the feel of a World War two or actually more.
Speaker 0: it almost feels more like a Cold War era East Germany spy thing just the way the spy.
Speaker 0: the spying is like stereotypically of that ilk.
Speaker 1: it definitely it's a lot.
Speaker 1: It's like the spying you see in old spy movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah or in old Like noir movies that kind of spying is yeah, we're talking like the poison trap with the code book and the cyanide tooth You know.
Speaker 1: or like the two spies, but they don't know the other guys a spy sort of Hitchcock in a way But without the twist ending all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and a lot of double-crossing and double agents and triple agents and quadruple agents and stuff going on and stuff going down and Germans and good guys and bad guys and all you did mostly Germans.
Speaker 0: this is it Germans Germans, but The story there actually is a story here and that's interesting that it is that way.
Speaker 0: because well I know Scott gave this to me to read and I'm reading it on the train and I'm enjoying it.
Speaker 0: I'm digging it.
Speaker 0: I generally like stories like this.
Speaker 1: you get all these little vignettes and each one, you know You read one after the other and in the front of the book It has the table of contents, which is actually really well printed.
Speaker 1: It's it looks like a moleskine, but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're moleskins.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it tells you the names of all the different chapters and what page they're on.
Speaker 1: But it also gives a DSR number for each chapter.
Speaker 1: and like a dossier yeah, like the dossier number.
Speaker 1: and the thing is the Two chapters are printed in the book in the order that Matt Kent wants you to read them in.
Speaker 1: so that's the order.
Speaker 1: I did read them in.
Speaker 1: but if you look at the dossier number you can Figure that you can figure out by by arranging the stories by dossier number the chronological order.
Speaker 1: So you don't read the stories in chronological order, you know, and I bet if you did read the stories in chronological order It would be quite a different experience.
Speaker 0: yeah, of course it'd be tough because a lot of stories kind of branch and like one will end like a scene will happen and Astoria will keep going.
Speaker 0: but if you read another dossier later That one starts right when that scene ended with one of the other characters in that scene going off and doing something else at the same Time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that a lot of the stories sort of aren't directly like Continuations like some of them happen way before everything else and some of them have it way after everything else.
Speaker 1: So if you just read read them in chronological order Some of them are just gonna seem so out of place.
Speaker 1: So I do think you should read the order in which they are printed.
Speaker 1: but it is I guess cool.
Speaker 1: I kept looking like the first few chapters I read.
Speaker 1: I kept looking back To see what order they actually happened in and tried to keep it straight in my mind.
Speaker 1: And then after about ten chapters I gave up on that because it wasn't worth it.
Speaker 0: But like I was gonna say before all that it really there's a problem with this book And I guess because I just went into it.
Speaker 0: reading didn't read the back or the contents or anything.
Speaker 0: I just started reading it.
Speaker 1: I read the front thing in the book, but that was it.
Speaker 0: I got about a third of the way through thinking that it was just a bunch of totally unrelated vignettes about spies and Then one of them happened to end and then begin with like the same character from the previous one in another situation.
Speaker 0: and then I started flipping back through and I realized that all The characters from all the stories keep appearing in each other's stories and it's all this contiguous plot But the way the art is.
Speaker 0: I didn't notice that for the longest time and even after I knew about it It was really hard to keep track of which character was which and sometimes it was really hard to even Know what was going on.
Speaker 0: in a scene like I see a character die and then I see that character alive But clearly after the fact and oh wait, no, it's a different guy cuz the.
Speaker 0: oh I have to look at the mustache.
Speaker 0: He has a mustache.
Speaker 0: There's a little tiny there and I really couldn't tell who was who.
Speaker 1: yes I knew earlier on in the book like a chapter or two in that I was like, hey, wait a minute Like I saw a guy who kind of looked like a guy I saw before.
Speaker 1: So I flipped back and forth and I was like, is it the same guy?
Speaker 1: Is it the same guy?
Speaker 1: and I decided that it was and I was right.
Speaker 1: But I wasn't like a hundred percent confident and it wasn't easy to recognize.
Speaker 1: So a lot of the time like I was enjoying the stories and I actually enjoy the aesthetic style of the art But a lot of the reading of the book was sort of Hindered because I had to spend so much effort trying to say is that that guy?
Speaker 1: You know, is that that guy or is that a different guy?
Speaker 1: Did this happen before after that?
Speaker 1: I was spent so much time as if I was a spy I guess trying to make sense of all this code that I couldn't actually Enjoy the contents fully and even even if I read it again I would still have a hard time recognizing the characters so much.
Speaker 0: The issue I definitely had and that I could see now.
Speaker 0: wow This is really complex and cool and there's all these Interactions.
Speaker 0: and this scene would probably mean a lot more to me if I remembered exactly which character this was and exactly why she's in this situation now.
Speaker 0: But I just made because the characters weren't distinctive enough and they didn't use a lot of proper names or anything in the story.
Speaker 0: You really can't easily keep a thread of all the characters at all times and you'll end up missing out on a lot of the subtler details.
Speaker 0: and frankly Don't worry about that because once I stopped caring just gave up and just kind of read it and just if I wasn't sure who Her character was I just didn't care and kept going.
Speaker 0: It was much more enjoyable.
Speaker 1: Yeah the only time it really mattered is when you get to the end.
Speaker 1: there's like these five chapters at the six chapters at the end called The end one the end to the end three the end for the end five and six and those that sort of like.
Speaker 1: they wrap up all the different characters that have been continuing along and As long as you recognize like two or three of the most easily recognizable ones, you'll be alright at the end It'll be cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah Even if you forget half the things they did in the middle of the story as long as you know who they are by the End it works.
Speaker 0: It's sort of though.
Speaker 0: My favorite character is the spymaster who we only really see at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of like a catch-22 this book in a way in that it's cool because it's such a complex interwoven story of Spies, you know do getting tied up in each other and tied up in this other business and all this crazy stuff going on.
Speaker 1: And that's a way cool story that you want to experience.
Speaker 1: but because it's so complex It's so hard to digest that the difficulty of having that story delivered to you and the complexity of it Ruins the awesomeness of the complexity.
Speaker 0: But if you recognize that fact and you have to read this the same way, I am playing Final Fantasy Tactics advance because you could.
Speaker 0: you could care a lot about the exact details of what's going on and trying to figure it out just like you Could care a lot about finding all the secret characters and doing all the you know level everybody up to get all the classes business and Final Fantasy Tactics.
Speaker 0: if You don't care if you miss something and you just kind of go in expecting some fun You'll have a lot of fun and you won't miss.
Speaker 0: so as much as you might think you'll miss and you won't care about the Things that you did miss.
Speaker 1: Alright, so did you have any particularly favorite memorable stories in here?
Speaker 0: See it's.
Speaker 0: I really like just the aesthetic of how each story was in such a different style and was all these different takes on spying.
Speaker 0: I think my favorite one was early on where It's one that shows one spy and this other spy and it keeps cutting back between two of them kind of their inner monologues Going through the same motions, but thinking different things.
Speaker 0: the one the one guy who's like the one guy like it starts out And he's like spying is an exacting science.
Speaker 0: It is a precise planning blah blah blah blah, and then it cuts to the other guy and he's like spying is an art.
Speaker 1: You have to just kind of wing it by the seat of your pants And one guy is sort of like the fast and loose sort of more like, you know liberal-ish kind of guy You know, he's.
Speaker 1: he's dressing like a bum He's riding his bike all around town and the other guy is like a clean-cut businessman kind of spy doing the same routine every day.
Speaker 1: You know the other guys like hiding in plain sight.
Speaker 1: the other guy is hiding, you know, for real.
Speaker 1: I like that story.
Speaker 1: That was a good one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean each individual story is really really good.
Speaker 0: Another one I really liked is the one with the guy who's about to be executed for being a spy and he asks for one Last cigarette.
Speaker 0: Ah, I mean it was a twist ending.
Speaker 1: I saw coming but I didn't see that one coming actually got me see.
Speaker 0: I saw it coming But the thing is it's one of those rare ones where you see it coming and you know But you don't care that you know because you just want to see it actually happen Like you're just waiting for the bomb to drop even though you know, it's been dropping the whole time.
Speaker 1: My favorite one is the one it's actually in a slightly different artistic style than the others Like it has.
Speaker 1: like there are a few that just have different styles to them like different way He colors them and so like a black outline around the page this guy like gets in a car accident and somehow He gets stuck as like a spy.
Speaker 1: and like they thought like the resistance picks him up and Forces him to do a job for them.
Speaker 0: That one was super Hitchcock.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: and like they end up like drawing like the secret map on his for on his head and then his spoilers Yeah and then they he grows his hair back so no one can see and Like he gets super injured like he loses an eye and it's sort of like wow Wow One of those tragedies, you know where someone's forced into a tough situation They just deal with it and they get they come out.
Speaker 1: the other end, you know, and it's just like, ah Honestly, I mean I'd say it's not terribly realistic.
Speaker 0: You can't say that.
Speaker 0: It's real.
Speaker 1: No, this is not.
Speaker 1: I mean some of it I guess could be realistic.
Speaker 1: But at the same time there are some hints of you know things that really happened in history.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah There's a. there's one part where like there's a guy who's a code breaker as a bunch of shelves and it says like enigma on The shelves.
Speaker 0: Well, I was thinking more of the one The guy who served in a uni I don't want to ruin that one story in case someone doesn't see it coming The guy who was a spy in World War one and he then he served in World War two in his own unique way.
Speaker 0: Yeah that because that was based on a real event obviously, but uh, but while it's not realistic It's at least kind of self consistent in terms of what is possible at how spying works.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like that Cold War game we have where it follows the rules of movie spying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, however, there's one character that really kind of annoyed me Shayla Whatever her name was the shark.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was sort of I couldn't understand like what her motivation was.
Speaker 1: She seemed sort of inconsistent to me like in one scene.
Speaker 1: She's doing this another scene She's doing that and I'm like, what are you really doing here?
Speaker 1: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: I think the worst thing was that she was too badass for this story and for this world.
Speaker 0: It was kind of a let's make this super strong amazingly badass female spy and he just totally didn't fit with everything else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, really didn't.
Speaker 1: everyone else was a very down-to-earth sort of James Bond like the books kind of spy where you know You can get beat up and killed and they died really easily.
Speaker 1: a lot of these people die just up you're dead.
Speaker 1: Yep, you got shot you died.
Speaker 1: But except for her she was like, you know, like some super danger actually a super spy.
Speaker 0: funny How the most badass character is the least interesting least engaging and the one I just I skipped a lot of her stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, meanwhile, there's a guy actually named super spy and early on in the book.
Speaker 1: He's a super spy and you don't see him until you always.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: I knew he was gonna show up again and I learned how to recognize him because you know He was the guy they called super spy and that's the name of the book.
Speaker 0: I love what happens to him.
Speaker 1: What happens to him?
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna spoil it is so terrific.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I mean cuz one thing happens and then in the end another thing happens and it's just yeah the guy there's only like two or three chapters that have him in it and it's just I like.
Speaker 1: as Small as his part was, you know, the book was named after him.
Speaker 1: I go he was named as the same name as the book.
Speaker 1: He was definitely Pretty good right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I don't know I the art is the styles good But it I think it really kind of hinders.
Speaker 0: It's it forces you to read the book just really fast and loose if you try to get any more detail than that.
Speaker 1: Well, the alternative is you can read the book slowly and carefully and it will be difficult.
Speaker 1: I think I mean it.
Speaker 1: we're pretty smart.
Speaker 1: We yeah at a heart at least without like taking notes or something or at least just like really caring It's just or really paying attention.
Speaker 0: putting that very slowly putting that effort in will make the book less enjoyable.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like you could get.
Speaker 1: in order to get everything this book has out you have to put a lot more in and Putting it in was not fun.
Speaker 1: Only the getting out is fun.
Speaker 0: However, and I do think that despite how stylized and everything it was I Think you can adapt this into a pretty damn good movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, you can make a pretty awesome it with the movies.
Speaker 1: if it was a live-action movie or something You could you'd see the same people and you would totally recognize them.
Speaker 1: Yeah be awesome.
Speaker 0: and it's kind of set up like Storyboards almost and you could totally make a movie about this.
Speaker 0: that would kind of in the style of Sin City.
Speaker 0: I think I just think something like that would be amazing and I see someone do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is sort of like reading like like a movie script in a way Like it would be more like a Pulp Fiction in that you have all these small bits that are like Sin City.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kinda.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like either one of those where you have a movie made of smaller movies But the same characters show up again and you know, and they tie together into the bigger story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean all I do is those kind of movies.
Speaker 0: I'd take out the shark cuz.
Speaker 0: I like snatches just Snatch.
Speaker 0: we ever talked about snatch.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: on the show.
Speaker 0: We've had to have mentioned it I know but I don't think we've ever actually done a show on it.
Speaker 1: That is the stone.
Speaker 0: There's the stone Right, so Let's not get into that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this book is good.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed it, but I'm gonna be blunt I don't think it was worth $20 because I read it in like a half hour.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think it's worth $20.
Speaker 1: but if you can get this book with some sort of say just let's go look at the Amazon price.
Speaker 0: If one of your friends buys it and then you borrow it or if a bunch of you pay for it and then just kind Of pass it around or something.
Speaker 1: It's definitely worth borrowing because especially if you like spy stuff Oh, if you like spy stuff, you should probably just buy it.
Speaker 0: If you're a spy fan like a fanboy of spies if you like the that noir style femme fatale Cyanide pill in the coffee kind of spying with knockout gas.
Speaker 0: This is so up your alley.
Speaker 1: All right on Amazon It's only $14.
Speaker 1: All right, it's worth $14.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's $14 ain't so bad especially cuz you know you can just sell it on Amazon after you buy it for like $12 used.
Speaker 1: so there you go.
Speaker 1: Sadly.
Speaker 0: I don't have much more to say.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't want to bring up any of the stories of the characters because it's kind of pointless.
Speaker 1: Yep There were some chapters in the book actually that had like a lot of text and they weren't really so Comicky and they sort of dragged a little bit cuz like they took longer to get through than some of the other chapters that had Little to no text in them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I skipped a lot over Polly the paragon.
Speaker 1: Oh, no by the very green is awesome.
Speaker 0: I liked it.
Speaker 0: I like the art and I like the style and everything.
Speaker 0: It's just the story itself.
Speaker 0: I mean I read it.
Speaker 0: I just didn't really.
Speaker 1: I thought the paragon was one of the good parts.
Speaker 0: I didn't linger over it.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry You suck.
Speaker 0: It wasn't as good as some of the other parts.
Speaker 1: It was okay.
Speaker 0: thing is I would probably read Polly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if there was a book just Polly the paragon, I would totally read this kind of like Ollie kind of like Ollie But for kitties, oh, oh, he's also for kitties before and for our spy kitties.
Speaker 1: So, yeah super spy by Matt kint is not bad Not great not stellar not excellent, but it's no watchman.
Speaker 1: But then again, it's no underwear pervert.
Speaker 0: It's definitely if you're a comic fan worth reading.
Speaker 0: It's really all I can say about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it's hard.
Speaker 0: I mean if we review something that we don't love or hate or disagree on it's kind of hard to say more than that.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's the thing is.
Speaker 1: I wanted to really felt like we weren't doing enough reviews of things that weren't Disagree on love or hate, you know.
Speaker 1: And it doesn't seem like any other podcasters really seem to do them either because it's very hard to review something that's met.
Speaker 1: I mean, what do you say?
Speaker 1: this book is average?
Speaker 1: It's you get some enjoyment out of it, but it's not gonna like make you like fall over, you know in ecstasy.
Speaker 1: It's also not gonna bore you to death.
Speaker 1: It's it's just a book.
Speaker 1: It's good it's possibly worth your time depending on how much time and how much money it costs.
Speaker 1: and now I think the problem here is that Reviewing something that's man doesn't make your podcast So entertaining or interesting unless you start going off on a tangent talking about things that are met and reviewing them Like I am right now.
Speaker 1: But at the same time I kind of want to give exposure to this because I think this does deserve some exposure.
Speaker 1: Yeah There are people out there who are gonna love this book and they probably never even heard of it until now and I want to do a podcast on it.
Speaker 1: But the podcast can't be that entertaining because I don't love hate or disagree with this book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all I can say is that I wanted to get more exposure because I really want someone to option it and make a movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, like.
Speaker 1: please if you are a movie maker You should go to Matt Kent and say we would like to option your super spy because He will probably go.
Speaker 1: Yes, please.
Speaker 1: I would love to make money.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of thing where if I had the kind of money to invest I and there were a project about this I'd invest in it because I think it would succeed.
Speaker 1: Oh man a movie like like I would.
Speaker 1: it doesn't get me to go to the theater often But if someone made a movie of this I'd be in the theater and that's that's saying a lot.
Speaker 0: Yes It is Scott doesn't like going to.
Speaker 0: what was the last non anime movie you saw in the theater and the theater?
Speaker 0: Cuz the last anime.
Speaker 1: but well the last movie we go to see the Lewis black Robin Williams movie.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we went to see man of the year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could have seen that on DVD and been just fine.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It was worth it just for the fact that no one in the theater knew what a sucky bus was except us.
Speaker 1: I think it was worth it only because there was nothing doing that night and we had nothing better to do.
Speaker 1: and like the timing Was just so perfect that yeah
Speaker 0: I happen
Speaker 1: to be eating at the restaurant right next to the movie theater and we happened to get out of dinner and the movie Happened to be starting walking
Speaker 0: over and we're like, you know, I kind of want to see that movie.
Speaker 0: if it's starting It was next two minutes.
Speaker 1: Let's go see and it was starting in like five minutes.
Speaker 0: So we're like, huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah, any less convenient?
Speaker 1: I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: even then we were like You wanna?
Speaker 0: Yeah, screw it.
Speaker 0: Let's do it.
Speaker 1: I think before that Did we see episode three?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: I'm glad I did.
Speaker 0: I wish I hadn't seen episode one in the theater That's for sure.
Speaker 1: and I think about this episode three in the theater.
Speaker 1: I walked right in.
Speaker 1: It wasn't as good as episode four five six was worth it, you know, yeah, it was episode one.
Speaker 0: I waited in fucking line got episode one.
Speaker 0: I we were there the day before.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, great.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile Lord of the Rings we were there for the opening showing and a crazy That was worth it.
Speaker 1: No, that wasn't worth it.
Speaker 0: That was exceeded expectations.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right Topic too much I met can't.
Speaker 1: top shelf?
Speaker 1: You should also anything.
Speaker 1: you should look through the top shelf catalog because top shelf publishes a lot of awesome books some of them by Alan Moore the guy who we're at Watchmen and some of them not by Alan Moore and Many of those books are good not all but many and worth reading.
Speaker 0: I guess the thing you should do is look at what they put out, you know Look at the cover art maybe read a little bit about it And if it's about a topic that's up your alley or if the art is a style that you like It's worth risking it and just buying it because on average top shelf stuff is pretty top shelf
Speaker 1: and they generally Print published comics that are not underwear perverts and are usually a higher brow in some way or another.
Speaker 0: Low brow, but I'm quite low brow.
Speaker 1: I'm high brow, but sometimes low brow.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.