Speaker 1: It's Tuesday February 6th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We at least nominally talk about video game difficulty.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Man, I was finally getting things done in my life.
Speaker 1: I had free time.
Speaker 1: I was reading again.
Speaker 1: I got a book.
Speaker 1: I'm reading I was my finances were almost all together.
Speaker 1: everything was great And then Scott had to give me the second Phoenix Wright game, haha Phoenix Wright it trumps all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except luckily.
Speaker 1: I'll probably done with it by tomorrow, and then I can get back to my real life.
Speaker 0: I still got the hotel desk over here But I haven't even started playing it because I'm still playing your stupid portrait of ruin.
Speaker 1: Hey, you didn't have to borrow it from me.
Speaker 1: That was entirely your decision.
Speaker 1: I haven't even beaten that game yet.
Speaker 0: It's not as good as the the other cat.
Speaker 0: was that the DS or the first DS dawn of sorrow?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Donna sorrow is actually my favorite non Simon's Quest Castlevania game so far.
Speaker 0: I know I still got to play some of the other ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't really make a judgment because they're just so many of them.
Speaker 1: I've seen the gameplay and I've talked to people who've played them And I don't think that I think Castlevania DS is pretty much the next logical step in that kind of game.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, but your ruin is this parallel dead-end road that Yeah, portrait Owen sort of takes like two steps forward and three steps back.
Speaker 0: You know they get rid of some bits I didn't like like the soul collecting and the Drawing on the screen to seal the bosses.
Speaker 1: see I actually kind of like the drawing on the screen to seal the bosses.
Speaker 1: I wish there had been more of that in the game.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: I don't I didn't like the way It was done.
Speaker 0: It could have been used in a better fashion.
Speaker 1: I wish you could have drawn different kinds of seals and done different things and used them outside of just bosses or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that like hey if you pause the game and draw you can draw a seal to do something.
Speaker 1: No, not even pause the game real time.
Speaker 0: No that sucks because if I'm drawing a symbol I can't also control the stupid game at the same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what now You know how that wizard felt trying to cast a spell while there's a fighter right there trying to hit him.
Speaker 0: That's right bad, which makes it sucks.
Speaker 0: No, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm probably gonna beat it Right now I'm going back with some facts to get a bunch of arbitrary annoying secrets that there's no way you could possibly know about Without a fact.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean cat the fur DS.
Speaker 1: I played that one and I found like 90% of the secrets.
Speaker 1: on my own maybe 95.
Speaker 0: I found more than 90% of the secrets.
Speaker 0: the problem is this stupid quest mechanic where you need that extra 10% of the secrets.
Speaker 1: See I didn't bother once I got the royal sword.
Speaker 1: I just stopped doing quests.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this guy says you know go fight the dodo, and I'm like where the hell is the dodo.
Speaker 0: see now There's no way I could possibly know where the dodo is without cheating.
Speaker 1: so you got to think about it like for example You know the Castlevania DS right well the original when you you want to get the Yeti the abominable snowman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there.
Speaker 0: There was actually a little bit of hinting because it's in an area that stood out like a sore thumb This game.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of different areas, and you traverse them pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what they don't really stand out.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of a whole lot of repeating terrain going on.
Speaker 1: however I would note that there's actually a lot there and the game's not as Arbitrary as you make it out to be my.
Speaker 0: it's not super arbitrary, but it's pretty Well.
Speaker 1: the evidence I put forth is that I lent you the game and aside from bitching about everything else like what do you?
Speaker 1: Mean I have a partner.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: I knew I had the partner, but I didn't want to have to use the partner which is there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really want to play that DDR game, but I don't want to move my feet.
Speaker 1: That's right but that one quest you know get me some ground beef.
Speaker 1: go to the butcher.
Speaker 1: and Didn't you just think hey?
Speaker 1: I'll go to that place where all that meat was hanging.
Speaker 0: I hadn't been to the place of the meat was hanging Is it?
Speaker 0: go to the butcher shop, and I'm like where is there a butcher shop?
Speaker 0: There's only one shop in this game, and it's right behind you.
Speaker 1: so you got to think a little bit more laterally like oh But your shop hey well There's a butcher shop.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: basically what it is is the game rewards you if you go slowly and pay lots of attention to it.
Speaker 1: I didn't pay a lot of attention.
Speaker 1: I Wandered into that room looking for secrets because you know it's a Metroid game.
Speaker 1: basically you go everywhere at least once And in that room there is a bunch of meat hanging from sticks.
Speaker 1: when I hit that meat it flew around.
Speaker 1: It was it was obviously a something here.
Speaker 0: I didn't go to that room.
Speaker 0: I never had this swinging meat, so how was I supposed to remember that?
Speaker 1: how would you have not gone to that room?
Speaker 0: I didn't I just he turned to the right and said it to the left.
Speaker 1: So you completed that whole place and left without going to that one area.
Speaker 0: I guess I passed through it But I didn't go it.
Speaker 0: the meat is actually to the left.
Speaker 0: you don't have to go over there to get to the boss Yeah, but if I just burn straight for the boss.
Speaker 0: I don't stop and you know poke anything.
Speaker 0: that isn't obvious.
Speaker 1: I poke everything.
Speaker 1: I mean that piano.
Speaker 1: luckily I looked on game facts right away and DS and found out that the piano doesn't do anything.
Speaker 1: otherwise I probably would have sat there for a day playing every single song.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile there's a piano in the stupid in some room somewhere.
Speaker 0: I did find a piano, and I found a cross and there's no quest for those yet.
Speaker 0: So I'm like.
Speaker 0: I want to know what to do with those, but you didn't give me the quest.
Speaker 1: yeah the quest.
Speaker 1: I think we're a good idea.
Speaker 1: They just could have been done a lot better than they were.
Speaker 0: it could have been like.
Speaker 1: the idea is solid.
Speaker 1: it adds a lot To the game.
Speaker 1: it's just the way they did.
Speaker 1: you know the quest all come down to have three Particular random items on.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's the owes the ones that really get me.
Speaker 0: right now I have two quests right one one of the quest.
Speaker 0: one of the quest says where the thick glasses.
Speaker 0: I'm like.
Speaker 0: I sold the thick glasses before you gave me this quest.
Speaker 0: There's no way for me to get the thick glasses again.
Speaker 1: Oh see I knew when I got all these items the game I thought I'll bet some of these are gonna be for quest because the quest looked like they were going in that direction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was just supposed to know.
Speaker 0: yeah It seemed obvious that some random crap item that is worth a lot of money if I sell it But doesn't increase my stats at all is gonna be useful for a quest would.
Speaker 0: never has there been a quest requiring an item.
Speaker 1: yet The quest that require items are pretty early on in the list of quests.
Speaker 0: I didn't I haven't.
Speaker 0: I didn't really done any quests at that point.
Speaker 1: I also like a video game logic.
Speaker 0: if you find an item that doesn't appear to have video game logic Hey, this guy is selling items, and there's no way to get money.
Speaker 0: I should sell all these extra useless items.
Speaker 1: I've got what are you talking about?
Speaker 1: I'd look practically invented money just from walking around.
Speaker 0: I barely have any money.
Speaker 1: Did you buy healing potions a few?
Speaker 1: That's your problem.
Speaker 0: even so I didn't buy that many.
Speaker 0: I mostly use the food that I find lying around.
Speaker 1: see I save all the food, too.
Speaker 0: How the hell do you heal?
Speaker 1: I don't get hit.
Speaker 0: I got you gotta get it sometime now.
Speaker 1: I learned how to not get hit and I use my partner to do stuff for me.
Speaker 0: I'd use the partner sometimes now But only when I have to and it's really it's.
Speaker 0: it's a lot more fun If I just go straight through the game.
Speaker 0: if I actually was careful enough to just not get hit instead of burning through the game It wouldn't be worth playing.
Speaker 0: it would take so long.
Speaker 1: so you want the game to be easy So you can just burn through it without having to.
Speaker 0: I don't want to be easy.
Speaker 0: I just don't want it to take so goddamn long.
Speaker 1: It doesn't take that long.
Speaker 0: It doesn't?
Speaker 0: I burned right through it.
Speaker 1: Even if you don't I mean I don't get hit I still burn through.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway games not that hard.
Speaker 1: the only annoying part was the sanctuary spell bit.
Speaker 0: that was the least annoying part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's cuz.
Speaker 1: you already read how to do it and listen to me say how I did it unless to everyone else on the Internet.
Speaker 0: I think the game just suffers from a few problems.
Speaker 1: whatever see I think it suffers from a different set of problems.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in the news totally unrelated to, Castlevania It looks like among all the other awesome games that are hitting the Wii.
Speaker 1: We're gonna get Dance Dance Revolution on the Wii.
Speaker 0: There's a big surprise.
Speaker 1: Actually it kind of was.
Speaker 1: I didn't really expect this.
Speaker 1: I always kind of hoped this.
Speaker 1: now my forlorn hope is guitar heroes guitar heroes guitar fucking heroes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but just buy a ps2.
Speaker 1: yeah, but I want it on the Wii.
Speaker 1: I want a guitar that I stick a wiimote into or guitar that just connects bluetooth Lee to the Wii or something awesome like that.
Speaker 0: It's not that much more awesome, I don't want a wire.
Speaker 0: the wire on the guitar has never restricted me So it's not a problem.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess I got to deal with the fact that if I were playing a real good as
Speaker 0: long as the wire doesn't come out the top of the guitar
Speaker 1: But if I was rocking out on a real guitar There'd be a wire there
Speaker 0: at least true and the wire comes out at the same place on the guitar controller that a real guitar Would have the wire coming out.
Speaker 0: yeah now.
Speaker 1: I'm real hit or miss on this DDR on the Wii because it's not just DDR, and we don't know much about it yet But one.
Speaker 1: I get the impression that it's going to be an entirely new soundtrack meaning none of the old good songs.
Speaker 0: I hate it when they do that.
Speaker 0: They're really just.
Speaker 0: there's really no reason other than the cost of license.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean the primary reason yeah that they don't just.
Speaker 0: they put every DDR song Ever in one DDR game all of them will it take multiple discs.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: I'll switch them up.
Speaker 1: the problem Is that most of those songs were never licensed into America and in fact none of those DDR machines are licensed to be in America.
Speaker 0: They're all here illegally isn't it awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well recently it seems like they've been accommodating the u.s.
Speaker 1: A lot more, but I remember back in like the fourth mix fifth mix days.
Speaker 1: those machines would before you started.
Speaker 1: every time They would say in English this game not licensed for use in America.
Speaker 1: You were breaking the law you asshole Yeah, and they expected us to.
Speaker 0: why did they even give us shit?
Speaker 1: DDR USA DDR USA was the first DDR machine I ever played on though They are the assholes.
Speaker 1: if you ask me that game had like eight songs.
Speaker 0: Why are these people pirating our machine?
Speaker 0: Maybe it's because we're not supplying their demand is they're not really the problem isn't with Konami?
Speaker 1: They know these things are going over to the u.s.. They ship them here.
Speaker 1: It's just kind of this time.
Speaker 1: you know the songs aren't licensed to be out in the u.s.
Speaker 1: They weren't licensed for use in this way in foreign countries And it would cost so much money to license them that no one's gonna do it.
Speaker 1: But if you just get this machine over here, it's all in English anyway.
Speaker 1: It's not like you're gonna have a problem and thus DDR just came to America regardless, and it's just kind of a wink and a nudge.
Speaker 1: Yep, but also it makes use of the wiimote.
Speaker 0: well How do you get where how you can use the wiimote with DDR?
Speaker 1: How do you think you're gonna use the wiimote with DDR?
Speaker 1: you're gonna be like left right left left up?
Speaker 1: Up up up.
Speaker 1: not forward up, but up up.
Speaker 1: It'll do things like it'll show an icon that says shake the wiimote here on the beat.
Speaker 1: Now actually this could be cool if one it's optional and every song can be played without it and doesn't suffer from it too if they do it well.
Speaker 1: and three if they do it sparingly or if they only make like special modes where you do it.
Speaker 1: Because some of these multiplayer modes look cool where you've got a bunch of people play.
Speaker 1: There's actually the.
Speaker 0: having this in the main mode Would be like having the yelling in Bomberman be part of the main game as opposed to the optional mode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'd better at least have the salt like.
Speaker 1: the song should all have light medium heavy or you know light trick maniac.
Speaker 1: And then I don't know wiimote wiimote maniac or some separate whatever thing kind of like with those Extra arrows modes in like fourth mix.
Speaker 0: all they need to do is put the wiimote on and off in this in the secret options menu.
Speaker 1: oh The secret options menu that everyone knows about.
Speaker 0: that's right a secret options menu that even modern DDR machines Tell you how to get to it.
Speaker 1: But I said a bunch of people because the one awesome thing is that this version of DDR looks like it's going to support four Simultaneous players, I think that is the greatest thing about it.
Speaker 0: The problem is you're gonna need a sturdy floor to support that or you're gonna have to play in your basement or garage or something.
Speaker 0: See the thing is though.
Speaker 1: I've never until now lived in a house that didn't have a sturdy enough floor.
Speaker 0: Well, let's see in colony.
Speaker 0: We played in a basement.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you know what if we'd lived upstairs We could have played it because those buildings were sturdy.
Speaker 0: they were.
Speaker 1: I mean, what did it take?
Speaker 1: it took our upstairs neighbors?
Speaker 1: Having a knockdown drag them out.
Speaker 1: They live fight for us to hear them banging around.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh well Yeah, but I mean my all my houses just seem to do it.
Speaker 1: I can think the house we live in just has really thin floors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well once we get a basement will be actually
Speaker 1: you know It probably really doesn't the fact that the living room is one gigantic room with no structural support anywhere in it and Directly above that my bedroom is one giant room of the exact same size with no structural support anywhere in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no nothing under.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, cuz if we play in the hallway it works But we're not gonna put a video game system in the hallway.
Speaker 0: That's just or outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we get ruined.
Speaker 1: We can tilt the TV and put our pads on the back deck and play through the the sliding door.
Speaker 0: That's a bad idea.
Speaker 1: I might do that in the summer.
Speaker 1: You're crazy Of course, I said I might do it last year and I didn't.
Speaker 1: but still four players at the same time solves almost every problem I ever had with DDI actually gives home DDR an advantage over arcade DDR and it makes DDR tournaments more efficient.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not only that but just the fund.
Speaker 1: I mean, I remember when we'd play DDR and with all our friends It'd always be two people playing and you know Two or three other people wanting to play and we'd all have to take turns.
Speaker 1: now four people playing at a time.
Speaker 1: We a lot more people get to play a lot more people have fun.
Speaker 1: We get a lot more DDR.
Speaker 0: I mean like if we go to an arcade, it'll be two people over here two people over there when there's multiple machines But four on the same machine is different than two machines with two each.
Speaker 0: It's a lot better actually.
Speaker 1: if you ask me Yeah, I'd agree it also in terms of yet a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: there seems to be a kind of mode where say you You all have to agree on a move like put the wiimote to the right or put the wiimote up and you all have to Do the same move whenever the wiimote icon comes up and I that's why I'd imagine the icon doesn't come up often Or you could turn it off hopefully.
Speaker 1: So then you know you all agree on a move and then you know You're doing your dance in unison and then you all have to like point up or point disco in unison Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: if done well, how come DDR?
Speaker 0: we can support for remotes at once and Wario where can't?
Speaker 1: Because the people who made Wario where are sadistic assholes who run a ruin everything good in the world and Konami is slightly less Sadistic, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I I have such high hopes for this But I had such high hopes for Wario where and the four player thing looks awesome.
Speaker 1: But I'm leery of this entirely new song set Especially since DDR ninth mix has an amazing song set and also it looks like these Wii dance pads are probably gonna be the same as the GameCube ones.
Speaker 0: this demo version They were playing was using the GameCube ports with Mario DDR dance pad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I can't use a red octane ignition pad There's no reason in the world to ever give this a second.
Speaker 1: Look.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean good God I'm done with those crap pads.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how much money.
Speaker 1: we probably spent more money on those crap pads.
Speaker 1: We could have just bought hard pad.
Speaker 0: We spent 40 bucks on those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 40 bucks one for 20 and then about another one for 20.
Speaker 1: We went.
Speaker 1: I will our group our group of friends if we include Luke and all them to probably went through Like 20 or 30 of those things in the course of our life.
Speaker 1: that many the whole group Maybe 15.
Speaker 1: I went through five.
Speaker 0: you didn't go through five.
Speaker 1: Yes I did.
Speaker 1: cuz I had two pads that I bought that summer after our freshman year when I bought DDR and I wore two of them Out in my house over the course of July and August alone, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah And I bought two more before I came to our IT and I wore one out and then you eventually wore mine out.
Speaker 1: I repaired two of them.
Speaker 1: In fact, I took a bunch of Luke's busted ones and repaired them.
Speaker 1: Remember I used to cut him open and it wasn't 20 pads.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you count everyone.
Speaker 1: we knew who played DDR.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, yeah, it's a. it's a bit of exaggeration I don't know.
Speaker 1: I might not have been.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: You're crazy.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we still used a lot of those things.
Speaker 0: They were cheap.
Speaker 0: They were 20 bucks and they disintegrated after a few months of play.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, the thing is they were 20 bucks or more.
Speaker 1: give or take plus shipping from eBay.
Speaker 1: That was the only place you could get him at least in those days.
Speaker 0: now every freaking store has one and they're all the same Crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but really just get an ignition pad.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to use anything else unless you can get a real hard pad Yep, or an arcade machine only 20 grand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you can get him for less.
Speaker 0: Amazon's got a deal.
Speaker 0: So the University of Rochester, hey, isn't that near where we went to school but not where we went to school?
Speaker 1: Well, yes in a radio voice it is.
Speaker 0: Well, they do actual science there.
Speaker 0: Like I remember they did some study about some like light based computing or something?
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: but anyway They did a study recently that has been completed where they figured out that playing action video games Specifically unreal tournament can improve your vision.
Speaker 0: Now you might think wait a minute.
Speaker 0: That doesn't make sense.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't staring at a screen hurt your eyes?
Speaker 0: Well, it really doesn't improve your vision in the eye department.
Speaker 0: It improves your vision in the brain Department, uh-huh Take that video game haters.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: and Apparently what they did is they had some people play Tetris and they had some people play unreal tournament for like an hour a day and they gave him a bunch of eye tests involving standard eye charts.
Speaker 0: this thing where there's two teas and the top tee is upside right and the bottom tee is upside down and there's a tee in the middle and you have to Tell whether the tee in the middle is upside right or upside down and it can trick your eye from distances You know and you won't be able to tell.
Speaker 0: and the people who played unreal tournament had much better scores on these tests over time and the people playing Tetris did not.
Speaker 0: uh-huh and They're pretty sure that playing action video games like unreal tournament Trains your brain sort of like exercising the optical parts of your brain.
Speaker 1: I think that's been fairly well known.
Speaker 1: I mean there were a lot of studies in the past about you know If they had doctors play certain kinds of video games before they perform surgery They perform the surgeries better or could do surgery that has to do with manual dexterity and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah But all these things in general.
Speaker 1: obviously playing video games is not the entirely Passive thing that a lot of people make it out.
Speaker 1: to me watching TV is mostly passive But playing a video game you have to interact with the world and solve problems.
Speaker 0: yeah, you know you have to use some part of your brain to play a video game even if you're not using your physical muscles so much and Whatever part of the brain you're using is getting some exercise and will probably be improved because of it Even if it is the eye part of the brain.
Speaker 1: Yes That part of my brain that tells me that if I find a rooster shaped key I can stick into a rooster shaped hole is Probably gigantic.
Speaker 0: oh my god that explains that lump.
Speaker 1: So for anyone who listens to I don't know just Tuesdays or any combination of geek nights nights that does not include Monday I'd recommend you go back and at least watch my thing of the day from yesterday because this week I've thrown down.
Speaker 1: my dukes are up.
Speaker 1: I have my own theme week, and we'll see if Scott can top my theme next week.
Speaker 0: We'll see I'm coming up with some ideas of a theme for next week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well for those of you also who are unaware my theme this week for various reasons is titled simply Hitler was born to be Alive, I'm sure you all at least hopefully saw yesterday's thing the day Which was in fact Hitler born to be alive?
Speaker 1: Tonight.
Speaker 1: my thing is something very much related to.
Speaker 1: that is a music video done to a techno remix of that song.
Speaker 1: However, it is not about Hitler.
Speaker 1: It is about it's not.
Speaker 0: I thought that was Hitler's childhood.
Speaker 1: Now you know if anything Hitler was that bully.
Speaker 1: Okay now it's one of those cheesy videos.
Speaker 1: the best way to describe it is take Napoleon dynamite and Distill it into the plot line that ends with him dancing on stage Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: the plot of this thing of the day is basically Dancing will solve all of your problems and make you awesome And of course I can't believe people need to be taught that lesson.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's the solid truth of life Dancing can solve any problem.
Speaker 1: I mean You know pole pots marching in killing people left and right.
Speaker 1: if everyone just come together and gotten down that would have been the end Of pole pot exactly.
Speaker 0: Hitler couldn't have done anything against the electric slide Dancing rules and the only people who didn't like disco were people who couldn't dance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really wish disco would come back All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this watch this video.
Speaker 1: It might seem cheesy.
Speaker 1: Bear with it.
Speaker 1: It is worth it for the payoff in the end, especially when the real breakdancers come out.
Speaker 0: Now here is um a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: That's kind of scary and kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh I don't know if this is from anything.
Speaker 0: It might be from Digimon or one of those types of things that I don't pay attention to.
Speaker 0: It's a DS game holder.
Speaker 0: It appears though that it can only hold One DS game.
Speaker 0: it might be able to hold more but it appears that it can only hold one.
Speaker 1: How much larger is it than a single DS game?
Speaker 0: quite larger because it is also some sort of retractable toy sword.
Speaker 0: if you look over here Wow It would take up your entire pocket.
Speaker 1: If not more to use a phrase.
Speaker 1: I haven't used in a while.
Speaker 0: God damn It comes in two varieties also the blue variety blue and yellow and white and the black and red and white.
Speaker 0: The blue yellow and white one says on it wind Liger and there's a picture of what I must assume is the head of a wind liger as opposed to a fire Tigan.
Speaker 0: No, the black and red one says shadow wyvern.
Speaker 1: Oh, I like wyverns a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, um, I don't know who the hell would buy this.
Speaker 0: They're much more efficient ways to hold your DS games like altoids tins and What else did that?
Speaker 0: actually?
Speaker 1: I got to say I'm very happy with the official Nintendo DS caddy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it holds all my DS games that I'm playing at the moment very well And I don't carry around all the ones I'm not playing at the moment.
Speaker 1: It also has room for DBA games and all that and I got it on sale because the Circuit City lady screwed up and scanned In the wrong barcode.
Speaker 0: Ooh awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is just kind of weird.
Speaker 0: It's like okay I could understand.
Speaker 0: you know, this would be cool if maybe it hold a whole mess of DS games.
Speaker 0: You'd be like, aha.
Speaker 0: I hold all my DS games in a toy sword.
Speaker 0: Hahaha But I don't know man who the hell would buy this and why I don't get it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: 12 year olds You got to be less than 12 man.
Speaker 0: This is for eight year olds that for sure.
Speaker 1: So a while ago I was bitching about a certain point in Castlevania portrait of ruin and then for a conversation happened in the forums which basically led us to a discussion about Video game difficulty and we decided there would probably be a good topic for the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's a lot of different things to say about video game difficulty.
Speaker 0: I mean like have games really gotten easier over the years?
Speaker 0: have they gotten harder?
Speaker 0: You know how?
Speaker 0: you know, some video games are harder in different ways than others, you know It's quite more complex than it first appears to be.
Speaker 1: Yep And I guess I'll start just to kind of show how that.
Speaker 1: I want this conversation to go and also to defend myself Because I didn't really make myself clear when I bitched about that one sanctuary spell thing in portrait of ruin.
Speaker 1: The rest of the game was I mean it was difficult as insofar as the game like that can be but it was actually pretty easy.
Speaker 1: But the thing is the whole game was one kind of difficulty and then I get to the sanctuary spell and I was suddenly Presented with a entirely different kind of difficulty the likes of which while I could beat I was not prepared for and not really particularly looking forward to deal with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I think the first thing you gotta examine when looking at the difficulty of any video game is What skill is the game testing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Lolo is a good example or Lolo one and Lolo two mostly Lolo one are straight-up puzzle games.
Speaker 1: They're testing your logical ability to make decisions to solve puzzles to move a little guy around.
Speaker 1: There wasn't so much temporal time-based stuff.
Speaker 1: you didn't have to.
Speaker 1: I mean there were occasional puzzles where you might have to time something in that you have to run away from something or once you if you put the things right, then you have to run away from the one guy, but it was mostly a Infinite time.
Speaker 1: figure the puzzle out game.
Speaker 0: Yep, you figure out the puzzle.
Speaker 0: then as soon as you've figured it out in your brain You've solved it.
Speaker 0: Executing it is not a problem.
Speaker 0: You just push the buttons.
Speaker 0: It's not hard to push the buttons It's obvious and simple, you know, it's not testing your reflexes Whereas I don't know a fighting game like Street Fighter.
Speaker 0: pretty much just testing your reflexes and reactions and you know Your mastery of manual dexterity of pushing certain buttons and things, you know, there's no puzzle solving There's no sitting and thinking.
Speaker 0: a completely different kind of difficulty.
Speaker 1: Now those are both in and of themselves great.
Speaker 1: one of the problems I always run into is when a game has one kind of difficulty and I'm going along with it and I like that I'm ready for it.
Speaker 1: I know, you know intrinsically how this game is gonna roll and then suddenly out of the blue The game will throw at you a different kind of difficulty that has not had any precedent in the game.
Speaker 1: My example is Lolo 3. there were puzzles in Lolo 3 that were somewhat random and time dependent where the only way to beat them was to get like a Randomly moving guy to stop at a specific spot by bumping into him.
Speaker 1: So you had to wait and time it and all this timing based stuff that was totally out of place for what was should be just a puzzle solving game.
Speaker 1: and While if the game had been that from the start at least I would have known it was common I would have expected it.
Speaker 1: I would have dealt with it But it wasn't the kind of difficulty I wanted if I wanted that kind of difficulty I would have played a different game.
Speaker 1: I wanted a puzzle game and that is when I stopped playing Lolo 3 and said fuck this and played Lolo 2 again There.
Speaker 0: now there are plenty of games out there that do have multiple kinds of difficulty.
Speaker 0: yet do not suck.
Speaker 0: Look at something like a Metroid, you know, it's got the exploration Puzzly, how do I get through here?
Speaker 0: Where do I go?
Speaker 0: difficulty?
Speaker 0: And it also has the shoot.
Speaker 0: the bad guy don't get hit difficulty combined at once You know without causing you trouble because you're dealing with both of them all the time.
Speaker 0: pretty much Yep, or it's not?
Speaker 0: like Metroid is an exploration game and then suddenly at the end of the game There's a terrible boss where you have to shoot really accurately and it sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd be like if I was playing arrowbiz and the games.
Speaker 1: just you know I buy on my airplanes and I buy my stock and I talked to my board of directors.
Speaker 1: I love that game and then suddenly 9/11 happens and now I'm a fireman in a first-person shooter trying to put out some fires.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or what's the game?
Speaker 0: act razor?
Speaker 1: Oh my god thing is.
Speaker 1: act razor was a brilliant game.
Speaker 0: It was brilliant.
Speaker 1: I mean what genius thought of that.
Speaker 1: they take the kind of game I love build cities and mess with people, you know a minor simple sim game.
Speaker 1: add into that Exploration, you know trying to find stuff on the mat.
Speaker 0: add into that side scrolling with the sword Sides going with the sword really doesn't fit.
Speaker 1: The thing is it was okay and I enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: and I like to act razor a lot both the city thing and the side scrolling even though the side scrolling was really weak compared to the city and the city part was infinitely better.
Speaker 1: and Then when I heard actors at who was coming I thought hot damn They're gonna fix their mistake and make either the side scrolling better or make it just the city.
Speaker 1: I don't know if any of you played act razor - but it's literally just the side scrolling and nothing more.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I almost cried when I found that out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I didn't know.
Speaker 1: I rented the game expecting something awesome And I was so sad because my parents wouldn't let me rent another game.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's terrible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I had it.
Speaker 1: I didn't even play it.
Speaker 1: I just moped around.
Speaker 1: I took the game back in three days.
Speaker 0: Oh when I Said no, but you know different skills being tested by the game aren't really a big deal, you know.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's really a matter of preference.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like.
Speaker 0: I like shmups.
Speaker 0: I like reactions and dodging and pushing buttons a lot or I like Civilization games.
Speaker 0: I take a lot of time.
Speaker 0: I think about stuff and I met.
Speaker 0: I micromanage a lot of things, you know And it's basically what type of skill are you good at?
Speaker 0: What do you like doing is not really a big difference?
Speaker 0: You know some things are obviously harder for some people.
Speaker 0: none of this.
Speaker 0: My mom can't play a fighting game, but my mom can probably play Wario where yep or a case in point.
Speaker 1: I Suck at shmups as Scott can attest if we're Scott's plan is small.
Speaker 0: I also suck compared to the awesome people, but I play them enough that I'm pretty good.
Speaker 1: I stuck compared to Scott.
Speaker 1: I never even beat Gradius 3.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm in that class of shmup players where you know, I have the standard set of you know.
Speaker 0: But as soon as the game, you know Ramps up, you know, I have to start memorizing and such.
Speaker 1: but yet at the same time Scott can't play those Gemfire style bunch of numbers on the board moving troops around.
Speaker 0: that's just cuz I I probably could play them.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: I really don't like reading all those numbers and I really just I don't want to had to pay attention to them.
Speaker 0: I ignore them and I just want it to be Deal with it.
Speaker 1: What do you want it to be?
Speaker 1: Different game.
Speaker 1: I don't like those games like Gemfire would be a lot better if it was actually Mario World.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: It would be because Mario World is awesome.
Speaker 0: Jetfire sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got you to play arrowbiz a couple times though Though you hate it every second I barely fit the only numbers.
Speaker 0: I paid attention to an arrow biz where.
Speaker 0: how much is it gonna cost me to do this?
Speaker 0: And how much money?
Speaker 0: money get from it?
Speaker 1: And that's why your airline went out of business and the Philippines went underserved For a number of years before I finally stepped in with cheap affordable air travel.
Speaker 1: Yeah This is more rim talks about arrowbiz than anything.
Speaker 0: All right, so Obviously, whatever skill a game tests.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it tests it more, you know, for example, let's see Gradius one is a relatively easy shmup game.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not the easiest but it's pretty easy.
Speaker 0: Ikaruga is quite a bit more difficult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Ikaruga is.
Speaker 1: I mean Dave from Dave and Joel's said this.
Speaker 1: I kind of agree with this.
Speaker 1: It's almost not a shmup It's like this other class of game.
Speaker 0: it is because it does sort of test your memory more than it tests your shmup abilities.
Speaker 1: Water that down with sort of Ikaruga is DDR for your fingers Kind of but I don't know.
Speaker 0: G Darius is more difficult than Gradius one, you know.
Speaker 0: or our type.
Speaker 0: Our type is more difficult than Gradius tends to be.
Speaker 1: it will depends on VR type and it's a.
Speaker 0: our type 3 is more Difficult than Gradius 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll agree with that.
Speaker 0: Well Gradius 3 was pretty but they're both testing the same skill set Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: or Mortal Kombat No, I don't know if that's more difficult.
Speaker 1: I guess it's just the only thing that bothers me when it comes to that is when a game tests a skill out of place Or out of character for the game or in a way that is annoying or you know Anything like that any game that just knocks you for a loop and it isn't an interesting loop
Speaker 0: Of
Speaker 1: course, then there's all the different class.
Speaker 1: I mean you might hear this phrase from pretty much people our age like our whole generation.
Speaker 1: Nintendo hard and that doesn't really apply to modern games.
Speaker 1: It really only applies to NES and SNES games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean back in the day.
Speaker 0: It wasn't just the games, you know were difficult.
Speaker 0: I mean there are some difficult games now.
Speaker 0: It was that games Punished you.
Speaker 0: you had to start over all the time like Ninja Gaiden.
Speaker 0: All right It's a Ninja Gaiden.
Speaker 0: you play level 1 you play level 2.
Speaker 0: It's like dude.
Speaker 0: I got to level 3 and then I died.
Speaker 0: Well now back at level 1 again you would.
Speaker 0: you had to basically had to master the game from beginning to end and you played the beginning parts a bajillion times and The end parts you only played once or twice because you hardly ever got there Whereas nowadays you play all parts of a game equally and the difficulty gradually increases instead of being constantly Killing you all over the place.
Speaker 1: Not only that but it seems like a lot of modern games.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying this is a good or a bad thing But there's been a shift toward this idea that completing the game is a foregone conclusion.
Speaker 1: Like you play even Super Mario World had this not not problem?
Speaker 1: I don't want to call it a problem but this idea where you basically have infinite lives infinite continue Whatever you can just keep playing forever and you're eventually gonna beat the game if you put in the requisite effort in time And there's no worry of am I gonna beat it or am I going to fail?
Speaker 1: The only way to fail is to just stop playing the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean your skill does have to increase in order to beat the game because the later levels are harder than the earlier levels.
Speaker 0: But you're not forced to play the early levels over and over again and master beating them You know in a shorter and shorter amount of time and getting you know.
Speaker 0: No one cares if you get more points when you beat the game or no one cares if you beat the game better or Faster than anyone else except for people who go for the speed runs.
Speaker 0: But those guys are using machines and not they're doing it themselves.
Speaker 1: Well, no remember a lot of speedrunners try to do it themselves.
Speaker 0: some of them some of them I think they actually have like.
Speaker 1: they call those other things machine assisted or tool assisted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of the ones I see your machine is I don't care.
Speaker 1: I just want you know why because the ones where people do them usually aren't interesting.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: It's not interesting to watch they're just interesting to give respect to the person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I remember watching those two guys race in Mario 1. that was fantastic.
Speaker 0: But as a result of these games that you know pretty much assume that you're going to beat it sort of like watching a movie.
Speaker 0: You're assumed to see the ending at some point.
Speaker 0: You know it.
Speaker 0: just the games don't punish you they just keep letting you play.
Speaker 1: so as a result It's weird that like Princess Peach Near the end of the game like say you screw up a boss or something and you die You just keep trying it again and again and again again.
Speaker 1: So there's no kind of penalty for dying.
Speaker 1: so you can almost brute force the game all the way through and just keep playing keep playing just keep playing and you're gonna win.
Speaker 0: and Also unless you're really dumb.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to be really dumb.
Speaker 1: The other interesting thing is that this kind of takes away one aspect of old games, which was that?
Speaker 1: Magical mystery of getting too hard to get places or rare places or weird places.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I mean in Mario World, right I can go to any level I want at any time.
Speaker 0: getting to the star world is no big deal because I Can you know.
Speaker 0: once I find out where it is I can go there.
Speaker 0: but imagine if you played a game?
Speaker 0: straight through from beginning to end with no saving or stopping.
Speaker 0: you would have to know where the star world is and you might only Have like a very small chance of getting it.
Speaker 0: and if you get it, holy crap like Mario 3 I was just about to bring you get the white ship.
Speaker 0: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: You got the white ship.
Speaker 0: You know hard that is.
Speaker 0: you only get one chance at it like per world and you have to get a whole bunch of coins In a very small amount of time and under very extremely strict circumstances.
Speaker 0: And if you mess up the only way is to start the whole game over again.
Speaker 0: There's no saving.
Speaker 1: I mean early on before I knew where all the warp whistles were I'd get to that giant world or you know world 5 and the castle in the sky and I would just spend time like Marveling at this strange place that I so rarely get to see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty freakin awesome And nowadays you don't really appreciate it because you don't.
Speaker 0: the games aren't the same way they used to be.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's definitely a different vibe like nowadays you beat a game and it's like well I have finished my 60 hours into this game or whatever.
Speaker 1: and it's not.
Speaker 1: I never feel this That sense of awe that I used to feel when I was a kid and I beat Zelda for the first time.
Speaker 1: I called all my friends and I went crazy nuts.
Speaker 1: and I I was as a kid.
Speaker 1: if you saw me I was just this blur.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I beat Zelda And tell the head saving and it's still crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the other Thing you had to notice when talking about game difficulty is not just.
Speaker 0: you know It's good when a game tests a skill and then gives you harder challenges of that skill, you know We're gonna test your reflexes.
Speaker 0: Okay for this part.
Speaker 0: You're gonna need faster reflexes than you needed in the previous part.
Speaker 1: Now you're gonna need even faster reef or now you're gonna react to something that's gonna be harder to react to.
Speaker 0: Yeah you're gonna have to have more precise controls or enter a more complicated button combination or you're gonna have to solve a Puzzle that has more parts and might take you a longer time to figure out.
Speaker 0: that's all good.
Speaker 0: In fact, that's expected.
Speaker 0: What's not expected is the big no-nos of game difficulty?
Speaker 0: The number one no-no is arbitrariness.
Speaker 1: now I don't want to bash crystal chronicles because Final Fantasy crystal chronicles provided to me Perhaps my greatest gaming experience ever.
Speaker 0: I don't want to go that far but it was.
Speaker 0: we had a good time I don't know.
Speaker 1: all told it's definitely in the top five of Total gaming experiences.
Speaker 1: if you take that entire weekend and count it as one experience It was a great weekend and I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: I don't know top five Weekend to be remembered.
Speaker 1: you gotta admit top ten.
Speaker 0: Um, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but crystal chronicles the game was mad, but we played it in a way that made it.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: That's about.
Speaker 0: that's pretty accurate.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'll agree with that.
Speaker 1: The game itself wasn't so great.
Speaker 1: The idea behind it was so solid though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, okay, just so people know.
Speaker 0: when crystal chronicles came out We had four people me rim Pete and katsu and we spent an entire weekend And we only took breaks for sleeping and eating.
Speaker 1: yeah And by sleeping we basically fell asleep at the game and died and then we slept for like four hours six hours.
Speaker 0: Then we tried to all reconvene and started playing again and we beat the game from beginning to end in as short a time as we Possibly could in one straight.
Speaker 0: go of it with four people for Gameboy advances.
Speaker 1: We started early in the morning on Saturday.
Speaker 1: We played straight.
Speaker 0: I thought we played Friday night.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I don't remember either.
Speaker 1: are we started as soon as we could all get off of work in class.
Speaker 1: We played straight through.
Speaker 1: we stopped briefly to go to a hockey game that I was so tired at from playing this game.
Speaker 0: I didn't remember going to that hockey game.
Speaker 1: I could barely yell.
Speaker 1: I was just sitting there like Gotta heal life life and conscious like river not playing.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh but life.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, so that's enough of that store.
Speaker 0: That's why crystal.
Speaker 0: that's why we have a higher opinion of crystal chronicles and other people is because we set up an interesting scenario For ourselves to play it outside of the game.
Speaker 1: But if and the game was really beautiful atmospheric and whatever.
Speaker 1: but yeah the game had all these side quests.
Speaker 1: now Here's the problem one.
Speaker 1: I Didn't even know the side quests were finishable.
Speaker 1: The game did not actually let you in on that secret that you could finish these side quests - they were so arbitrary.
Speaker 1: It was like talk to this guy go back to this village talk to this guy.
Speaker 1: But it wasn't like someone would say you should go back to the village of blah and talk to blah.
Speaker 0: see Zelda games.
Speaker 0: The reason Zelda games are so great and enjoyable is because they completely lack arbitrariness.
Speaker 0: Some guy will say take this to error and you go.
Speaker 0: Hey, there was a guy before.
Speaker 0: he said I am error I'll go give this to error and you do.
Speaker 0: Imagine if there was just an item somewhere in the forest you picked it up and it was like the rare item, right?
Speaker 0: And there was a guy in town and he said I am error.
Speaker 0: There's no way to know that you have to give that item to error to get some secret weapon.
Speaker 0: There's no possible way you can ever know outside of a fact.
Speaker 0: Yet if you give that item to error you get a secret weapon.
Speaker 1: now look that is Arbitrary, there aren't that many games that are that arbitrary and usually there's something.
Speaker 1: a lot of times someone will say something arbitrary But it just meant that they actually weren't paying attention to the game, but there are sometimes yeah, it depends.
Speaker 1: But crystal chronicles like you talk to a girl like oh dear the princess is missing and I thought great I can save the princess and I talked to him again.
Speaker 1: He says oh dear the princess is missing and I talked to the next person.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, the princess is missing and apparently I could have saved the princess But I had no way of knowing how and I read game facts.
Speaker 1: It was just stupid.
Speaker 0: I think my favorite example of arbitrariness in video games is ogre battle 64. someone you never you never played it.
Speaker 1: I knew not to my.
Speaker 0: I played it a little bit and my brother owned it and I don't remember if he ever beat it, but apparently he got the Strategy guide at one point and I looked through it for a bit and there was a little sidebar about how to get like these most powerful angel paladin characters or whatever right and Apparently you had to go to this town on a map on a certain date in the year at a certain time.
Speaker 0: now the game Had a built-in calendar and clock and talk to a certain person and give him a certain item.
Speaker 1: I was like how the hell are you supposed to know that?
Speaker 0: there's no way to know that no one will ever tell.
Speaker 0: it's impossible to know that without the strategy guide.
Speaker 0: and While there are very few games that are as arbitrary as that I have noticed an increasing level of arbitrariness over the years And I don't know if I want to say there's a conspiracy to sell strategy guides But there might be a conspiracy to sell strategy guides.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean even old games.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like that.
Speaker 1: strategy guides were just this awesome thing that you got after you beat the game Just because it was cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I got that Mario 3 strategy guide.
Speaker 0: I didn't even ask for it I just got.
Speaker 1: I remember how Nintendo parties gave it to you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't have Nintendo power really I don't know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I would look at it and go holy crap There's all the levels I didn't go to and there's secrets in the levels.
Speaker 0: It was just cool to see all the maps.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it also had all this.
Speaker 1: like the history of Mario.
Speaker 1: here are all the death icon animations from all the different Mario games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know it was fun.
Speaker 0: Now the strategy guides.
Speaker 0: a lot of games make them sort of necessary like here's the where the secret is with the awesome weapon You couldn't possibly ever know about without buying the strategy guide or reading game facts and that sucks.
Speaker 1: That's a bad game design right there I mean granted that's not to totally give a pass to a lot of the old games that weren't arbitrary But they suffered from video game logic to the degree that you know, there's hard and there's Nintendo hard.
Speaker 1: I would say there's a video game logic and there's Nintendo logic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there are different levels of arbitrariness.
Speaker 0: I mean you could be completely arbitrary like the example I just gave with error, which isn't you know.
Speaker 0: But you can be sort of arbitrary like there's one guy who gives you a very vague hint at something But there's no way to know exactly.
Speaker 0: you could say well the guy gave you a hint.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but it wasn't enough of a hint, you know, it is.
Speaker 0: there's a point at which it's not arbitrary, but it's still Unreasonably unknowable without a strategy guide.
Speaker 1: I think the line for me the in terms of figuring stuff like that out the Absolute bare end line of arbitrariness is most exemplified in Castlevania 2 Simon's Quest which also happens to be one of my favorite games ever.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's an unpopular opinion.
Speaker 1: I know you can all die in a fire.
Speaker 1: Castlevania 2 was great But anyway the game like what to get?
Speaker 1: some things like you have to take Dracula's heart and Go to this as dead end somewhere and kneel down for five seconds and then a whirlwind will appear Like what's the fuck?
Speaker 1: and all sorts of weird stuff like that.
Speaker 1: and you know to get Dracula's body parts you have to go to these orbs and stab them with steaks that you can buy from scary old dudes and All that stuff while it seems really weird and arbitrary like hit your head on this rock a bunch of times and something will fall out of it like randomly in one part of the game.
Speaker 1: if You talk to the people in town They basically tell you all of this and you can figure it all out logically if you just pay attention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, effects an ado is the same way, you know There's a lot of weird stuff in that game But people in town tell you everything you need to know right up until the end.
Speaker 1: Yep It'll be like go pray at the blah Cemetery.
Speaker 1: All right, so I go to that Cemetery nothing there.
Speaker 1: So then I kneel down and wait a bit and then oh something happens.
Speaker 1: Hooray.
Speaker 1: I'm smarter than a video game Yep, and the other one Final Fantasy 1 which isn't.
Speaker 1: it isn't really arbitrary at all.
Speaker 1: It's the same idea though near the end of the game.
Speaker 1: I mean I know most of you if you played Final Fantasy 1 either played the GBA one or played it with a fag or with that Awesome strategy guide that Nintendo put out that tells you what's in every chest and everything.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy 1. at the end of the game you beat all four fiends Spoilers, by the way, and you got all four crystals.
Speaker 1: and that's supposed to fix the world.
Speaker 1: You know the earth is rotting and you've solved this.
Speaker 1: You've got the four crystals like everyone said.
Speaker 1: you figured out what happened to the warriors of the sky.
Speaker 0: Everything's great.
Speaker 1: You're done But the game doesn't end and you go around and people say things like huh?
Speaker 1: How come the world's still shitty?
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 0: what's going on, you know?
Speaker 0: walking around the world in Final Fantasy 1?
Speaker 0: It's not so shitty except for the monsters everywhere.
Speaker 1: Well now until you go underground and the world is just like this marsh poison filled death cave.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean most of the towns the big towns on the surface or they're nice You know, even let's see what's going on lefty.
Speaker 1: Well, we know the story of what happened to them.
Speaker 0: The pirate town is nice except for the pirates.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is actually?
Speaker 0: the pirates make it nicer.
Speaker 1: yeah, it was shitty and you save that town and God that there's that other town.
Speaker 1: No, I don't need a.
Speaker 0: pirates were making it.
Speaker 0: Nice You make it worse when you get rid of the pirates.
Speaker 1: Yeah Alright, alright all the buildings are hollowed out and empty.
Speaker 0: That's just cuz you can see through the roof.
Speaker 1: also because there aren't any shops you can go into in those buildings.
Speaker 1: They're just empty.
Speaker 1: but yeah, you can walk into them.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but you go to Melmond and it's been totally destroyed by that vampire and you know bad stuff.
Speaker 1: So you've you've fixed it.
Speaker 1: You've got all the orbs and the rod is still happening.
Speaker 1: all the the world is still decaying and you're like What do I do now and no one can tell you?
Speaker 1: Well, if you'd paid attention in the game and you put all the clues together And there's so many clues all over the place that point to the actual plot and the thing is it's not exactly obvious.
Speaker 1: if you didn't read a strategy guide and I remember when I was playing Final Fantasy 1 and I wasn't sure where to Go and I'm wandering around and eventually I go back up into the sky tower just to loot it And I go back to that window because in the sky tower there's this window and you can look down from this from space basically and see the earth and I look down and I actually read that flavor text and it says something along the lines of blah blah blah the swirling vortices of the forces of the world.
Speaker 1: you almost get the sense that they're converging at the center of Their being or something like that.
Speaker 1: So then I'm thinking yeah, huh?
Speaker 1: So I cast the spell.
Speaker 1: I learned, you know Push B select to get the world met and I'm looking at it and I noticed something interesting.
Speaker 1: the four temples where the four evil things were and where the four orbs were are in a perfect square and Exactly at the center of that square is the temple of fucking fiends.
Speaker 1: from the very first part of the game Yeah, so I marched my ass over there and that's where everything happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that wasn't arbitrary at all.
Speaker 1: That was just awesomely difficult and it required paying attention.
Speaker 1: and you know all the stuff that I like in an RPG.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know there is another kind of difficulty that sucks.
Speaker 0: besides just arbitrariness and I guess it's sort of related is Unreasonable difficulty.
Speaker 1: how Silver Surfer?
Speaker 1: Yeah Silver Surfer.
Speaker 0: Yeah Silver Surfer Friday the 13th not arbitrary It's a game of you know reflexes and moving the Silver Surfer.
Speaker 0: It's a shoot-em-up aside scrolling and also up scrolling shoot-em-up.
Speaker 0: The thing is you die in one hit.
Speaker 0: Also, the Silver Surfer is slow and he does not shoot rapidly.
Speaker 0: bad guys are hard to kill Even grazing slightly grazing any part of the map, you know any terrain.
Speaker 0: anything solid will kill you instantly.
Speaker 0: You don't have that many lives.
Speaker 0: There's no continues in order to beat it you.
Speaker 0: if the game is beatable The thing is in order to beat any of it your level of skill has to be so ludicrously high.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you that it's essentially Impossible if you say you just play this game.
Speaker 1: I remember every time I tried decided you know what I'm gonna be a badass.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna beat the Silver Surfer and I sat down and I started playing and I died in eight seconds.
Speaker 1: I tried again died in eight seconds tried again.
Speaker 1: I made it like three more seconds.
Speaker 1: I tried again.
Speaker 1: I died in four seconds because I wasn't paying attention.
Speaker 1: It's just there's no fucking way.
Speaker 1: What are they?
Speaker 1: that game was marketed at me when I was you know that age when it came out.
Speaker 1: I was like 12.
Speaker 1: That game a 12 year old can't beat that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's not arbitrary.
Speaker 0: It's not like you need.
Speaker 0: there is some fact that can provide you with some information that you didn't know and suddenly the whole game Is easy or oh, that's how it's done.
Speaker 0: If I only would have known that piece of information There was no way I could have known, you know, the game is beatable.
Speaker 0: No, you just need to have a level of reflexes and Memorization of where everything is in the game.
Speaker 0: That is beyond any It's just not.
Speaker 0: there's no point.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: I've never met a human being who can beat Silver Surfer.
Speaker 0: I Remember when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: the kid down the street actually had the game and he could get.
Speaker 0: I think he could beat a few levels maybe but that's about it and I'm sure if I saved and loaded with an emulator I could get pretty far.
Speaker 0: the problem is I might accidentally save and then in a spot where I'm dead no matter what.
Speaker 0: So I'd have to do it like segment by segment.
Speaker 0: I'd only be able to save in a situation where I'm guaranteed not to die within two seconds.
Speaker 1: I decided to beat Castlevania 2 just while I was bored one day back when I was living alone in the mountains.
Speaker 1: So I just had one save slot in the emulator and I just you know Saved the state whenever I wanted to take a break.
Speaker 0: So you saved it when you're about to fall into a pit and then every time you loaded you fell in a pit.
Speaker 1: Well, I was walking and then I was cooking some dinner and I was just you know Running around fighting and I heard the thing go off for food.
Speaker 1: So I just turned to hit f5, you know save my state and I walk over to get my food.
Speaker 1: I walk back over to the game and I see that my character is dead.
Speaker 1: I think okay, whatever if I got pushed off the ledge I hit f7 to restore my state and there's a fireball Right there hit about to hit me and it hits me and knocks me in and I died.
Speaker 1: It was my last life.
Speaker 1: Ah, I Determined empirically that there was no way out of that situation.
Speaker 1: So I Sucked it up.
Speaker 1: I had to continue.
Speaker 0: I guess there's one other kind of difficulty I just touch on quickly and that's not the difficulty of skill but the difficulty of effort, you know For example World of Warcraft where it's not hard.
Speaker 0: Anyone can do it, but that's not effort.
Speaker 1: That's just time.
Speaker 0: It is it.
Speaker 0: that time is effort, you know, you have to work.
Speaker 0: It's not hard.
Speaker 1: No, no, because if it was just effort.
Speaker 1: if you put more effort in per unit time you would get more reward.
Speaker 1: But the cap on the amount of effort you can put into any MMO versus the relevant reward the cap is real low.
Speaker 1: It's like super compressed audio.
Speaker 0: Well, there was that guy.
Speaker 0: he was.
Speaker 0: he did it more quickly than anyone else.
Speaker 0: So I imagine you know with some arbitrary knowledge that you could learn from the internet and with some effort and Concentration you could do it faster, but you you can do it just by spending time.
Speaker 0: It's not a matter of skill.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we ever really point here.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah new games are in a lot of ways better than old games and in some ways they lack things old games had.
Speaker 1: I don't know what direction gaming should go.
Speaker 1: in One hand I'm disappointed at how easy a lot of games are these days and how I just don't feel like I can fail and Like no matter how badly I do.
Speaker 1: eventually I'll always just plug ahead and win and people always know.
Speaker 1: Oh, well the game is 60 hours and at the same time.
Speaker 1: I really don't miss the days of Dying in the second level of Contra like nine times in a row and then finally getting to the third stage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, without the I'm not sure where I stand, you know, it's like I'd like a game to not be stupidly easy.
Speaker 0: I like a game to test certain skills and I don't like games that test other certain skills.
Speaker 0: Arbitrariness really pisses me off if a game is unreasonably difficult.
Speaker 0: It's not worth my time to play.
Speaker 0: And what rim just said, you know if a game is you know old games I kind of liked how they were hard and new games.
Speaker 0: Sometimes I'm kind of sad that I beat it and then it's over so soon.
Speaker 0: But if I play an old game these days, I just get really frustrated because it's just so intolerable.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on the game.
Speaker 1: and here's a point that I just thought of and I realize is kind of relevant.
Speaker 1: It's your main to the design commander Not just bionic commando.
Speaker 1: But I think back to all the games the old school games that I love the ones that I just love to death kaboom Yeah, all those games kaboom bionic commando Zelda - whatever.
Speaker 1: and I remember as a kid all the wonder because I had infinite free time.
Speaker 1: I was a kid playing Zelda - you know spending the crazy amount of time and effort it took to get good enough to even think about trying to get that hammer and The amazing sense of accomplishment I felt when I got that hammer and when I play the game now today I still have that skill.
Speaker 1: So when I play Zelda - it doesn't seem as hard as it originally was when I play bionic commando It doesn't seem like it's that bad Because I forget the fact that I spent probably two or three years of my life becoming the grand master of these games
Speaker 0: Mmm,
Speaker 1: so I get all the benefit of spending that time as a child and all the wonder comes back through nostalgia.
Speaker 1: I also get to enjoy the game on a higher level because I'm good enough at it to enjoy it on that level.
Speaker 1: but at the same time no one new to this game is going to be able to enjoy it in any of those capacities except the capacity of childish wonder and Little kids today.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess a six-year-old today or an eight-year-old.
Speaker 1: I love Zelda - if you gave him the time to play it, but any I guess you explained to him that it was good.
Speaker 1: I don't know if he'd be distracted by fancy new games But I think we tend to have a glowing perspective on old games as good as they were just for the fact that We're good at them.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't seem as hard as it really is.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's part of it.
Speaker 1: I mean find anyone who's never played bionic commando before and Let him beat even one level within.
Speaker 1: I don't know 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I definitely Have a feeling that the the sense of wonder has been lost over time.
Speaker 0: for me like I just I beat Twilight Princess.
Speaker 0: what a few weeks ago and That wonder really wasn't the same as the wonder I wrote like.
Speaker 0: I can recall the wonder from Zelda 1 You know and I can recall the feeling but I can't get it.
Speaker 0: You know, it's the same feeling but it's not the same intensity that was when it was actually happening.
Speaker 1: Well part of it was there weren't distractions and you could play whenever you wanted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and now you know Twilight Princess I beat it But at no time did I have the same feelings that I had when I played Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: See now the thing is I don't know cuz while I don't have the same feelings Maybe just cuz I'm not as jaded as you but playing Twilight Princess I get an equivalently powerful feeling of wonder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not the same feeling It's not that feeling of like almost frightened awe that I'd get in like.
Speaker 0: that's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem.
Speaker 1: that feeling I think came partly out of the fact that as a child I didn't really understand how video games worked.
Speaker 1: maybe and I never thought like oh you dump the ROM and you can figure out What's behind that block.
Speaker 1: I'd come to a dead end and I'd wonder to myself seriously I wonder what's back there and I'd throw holy water at the wall hoping that maybe I can get back there.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: that in Metro I'd bomb down.
Speaker 1: remember that one spot in Metroid in the bubbly area We could bomb down for like like two screens at the bottom was just a dead end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was just kind of like a glitchy area.
Speaker 1: You just go down there.
Speaker 1: I was obsessed with that area.
Speaker 1: I was sure there was something down there and even when I didn't find anything I was just kind of.
Speaker 1: it was like exploring new territory.
Speaker 1: I was an explorer and now I can't get that sense of wonder because I know exactly how video games work on a low level.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 0: I'd read something really interesting a long time ago How about video games like demystified the television.
Speaker 0: and it's all about once you know, what's really going on All the mystification of it is gone and you totally can't be wowed or you know Sort of deceived or tricked or amazed by it anymore.
Speaker 0: I mean sort of like if someone shows you how the magic trick is done That.
Speaker 0: or someone shows you how like a really cool set piece and a play works.
Speaker 1: Now when you go see it, you just go instead of going whoa See now there's where video games can go because I think Penn and Teller have the right idea.
Speaker 1: you do magic trick, right?
Speaker 1: Like if you show how David Copperfield does his trick it's not interesting anymore.
Speaker 1: But Penn and Teller sometimes they'll show you how they do the trick a bunch of times and then they'll do the trick and you'll still Be amazed because it's not.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know how they did that.
Speaker 1: It's wow.
Speaker 1: They actually did that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there's a way because I think video games as a whole are better than they used to be a lot better.
Speaker 1: But they're better in different ways and I think the things that they've lost can be made up for with equivalently good But different things.
Speaker 0: I Think the way to go is you know, there's a lot of different courses of game design that people are taking You know in different directions, and I think we just need I don't know I don't think we need something some completely new game design because every time someone tries to do that It's it's really hit or miss.
Speaker 0: you either get like a one-hit wonder like a katamari.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or you get a crap nothing game.
Speaker 0: That's completely useless.
Speaker 1: We just I want to know we should somehow figure out exactly what it was that caused that Frightened sense of wonder we would have as kids playing video games that I get Glimpses of every now and then in new games like even in Twilight Princess when I got when I turned into a wolf Spoilers and went to that other world for a second.
Speaker 1: I felt this twinge of wow What's this?
Speaker 1: and it went away like that?
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's just because I'm an adult or because I'm now immune to it or because I know That some guy sat there coding this game and someone did the art and then they compiled it and put it on a disc and Shipped it to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the only games that really kind of get me now or like the the half-life twos I think those are the most recent games to really kind of kind of grab me with the whole immersion thing where I'm like whoa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well Twilight Princess really is grabbing me and whenever I sit down to play it I really really really get immersed and I really really really really like it.
Speaker 1: Of course that might be that I didn't play much of ocarina.
Speaker 0: That's about that's what I was saying.
Speaker 1: But the thing is I try Korean of time actually did it a lot for me way back when Even every time I tried to play ocarina time, it just wasn't polished enough and I just didn't like it.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're screwed up because everyone will tell you ocarina of time is the greatest than it is.
Speaker 0: I think it's better than Twilight Princess.
Speaker 1: Actually, if you say everyone we just had this discussion two weeks ago and you people are crazy And I believe multiple of us other than just me Express the same opinion.
Speaker 1: The Twilight Princess is generally a more polished game.
Speaker 0: Yeah polished.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So if you take it doesn't make a difference, it's still not as good as ocarina of time.
Speaker 1: I think it's better so far.
Speaker 0: Oh, what do you know?
Speaker 0: You didn't play ocarina of time.
Speaker 1: I've still played more ocarina of time than I have played of Twilight Princess.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what do you know?
Speaker 1: I know what I played.
Speaker 0: That's the best the forum.
Speaker 0: What's the ocarina of time or Twilight Princess?
Speaker 0: What's better?
Speaker 1: All right Because so far everyone we've talked to has agreed with me not say all you people who haven't played ocarina of time.
Speaker 1: No out of us have played.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a good game.
Speaker 1: It's just Twilight Princess feels more solid to me and I get more of a sense of wonder from it.
Speaker 0: Yeah The exact opposite.
Speaker 1: Well, you're just generally a jaded prick.
Speaker 1: anyway You're jaded about every video game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I mean, what do you think else to say?
Speaker 1: No, not really except that Bitch a lot about video games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we like to bitch a lot about video games particularly you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the thing I bitch about most in video game everything any game you're playing you sit there like this game sucks.
Speaker 1: What the fuck.
Speaker 0: this is all that.
Speaker 0: because the problem is if a game sucks completely, right?
Speaker 0: I just go.
Speaker 0: I don't even bother playing it because it's so bad.
Speaker 0: My problem is that I'll play a game that is so much promise and has so many elements of fun and gets just a few Things wrong that are constantly irking me.
Speaker 0: It's like imagine if you're eating this great apple pie right and then someone came and shook like some nasty spice on it or something and it's like Oh, this is such a great pie and you put this thing
Speaker 1: Ah,
Speaker 0: it that it irritates me even more than just a bad game because if a game is completely bad Don't need to play.
Speaker 0: if a game is so close to perfect yet.
Speaker 0: There's something constantly annoying you.
Speaker 0: it's like oh my god I really want this part, but I can't get rid of that part.
Speaker 1: and see now Here's the problem because I can't name a game in the last like four years other than Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: You didn't constantly bitch about it while you played it.
Speaker 0: whether it is so many games are far from perfect.
Speaker 1: Name a game then that's I mean, it seems like you can't even enjoy games anymore.
Speaker 1: I can.
Speaker 1: Are you actually enjoying portrait of ruin?
Speaker 1: or you're just beating it so that you can be done with it?
Speaker 0: See I really like walking around and hitting guys and exploring areas and fighting bosses and you know All that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: Are you enjoying the game as a whole?
Speaker 0: I'm enjoying it more than some other games like what like Let's see.
Speaker 0: What's worse more than Princess Peach.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Princess Peach was okay until I got to the end.
Speaker 0: I just stopped playing Princess Peach in the middle.
Speaker 1: No, the kiss actually later levels are really good not hard like hard hard.
Speaker 1: The problem was the game made me go back and do some bullshit and I just gave up at that point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's it's it's good.
Speaker 0: It just has some things that constantly annoy me and if they only change them the game could be awesome Which is why I appear more pissed off.
Speaker 0: It's like my level of pissed off in this is not directly related to the goodness of the game.
Speaker 0: I'll be more pissed off at games that are 99% good than a games that are 50% good.
Speaker 1: I can agree with that at least on WarioWare.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's so close.
Speaker 0: a game will be 99% good and 1% bad And I will bitch forever about that 1% bad because it could have been a hundred percent good.
Speaker 0: It would have been the best game ever and that lack of potential pisses me off.
Speaker 0: Whereas a 50% good game I don't even play it.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't bother me Anyway, since we as always have gone a little bit long.
Speaker 1: Whoo in conclusion Twilight Princess is better than Ocarina of Time.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.