Speaker 0: It's Tuesday September 18th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: team fortress.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Alright, we gotta get this done quick so I can get back to playing team fortress - which I've been playing pretty much non-stop until Just now.
Speaker 0: I played two rounds this morning.
Speaker 0: I got home.
Speaker 0: I Tweaked it a bit, and I've been playing up until now.
Speaker 0: And this is why we're recording the show at 9 something I haven't done in a long time.
Speaker 0: actually.
Speaker 0: we used to record the show At 930 so this isn't too bad or even later than that on many occasions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so actually pretty good all right Yeah, but our team fortress - I got it.
Speaker 1: I got to play more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll be do.
Speaker 0: we'll be playing.
Speaker 0: Think this game from now until probably we die will be available for play.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not gonna pull the tribes - the thing is I will get into this when we talk about it.
Speaker 1: But I do want to say while this game is pretty fun already The experience is not even close to the first days.
Speaker 1: experience of tribes - No, like not even it's not a perfect.
Speaker 0: plus is the beta first of all as I could.
Speaker 0: of all you know the game is Great, but it's not perfect.
Speaker 1: so in the news a bunch of FPS nut balls freaked out because the team forgers 2 beta Didn't come out when they wanted it to come out.
Speaker 1: it came out some hours later.
Speaker 0: All right, so let me let me give you the whole story.
Speaker 0: I went around collecting information from various sources, and this is the story that I collected.
Speaker 0: I am not going to like you know stand by.
Speaker 0: this story is a hundred percent true But this is what the evidence tells me.
Speaker 0: all right They said they would come out with the beta on Monday yesterday, and of course.
Speaker 0: They're in the Pacific time zone.
Speaker 0: So we assume it means Monday Pacific time.
Speaker 0: so of course a lot of people are like they're gonna put it out it.
Speaker 0: you know midnight Pacific like immediately is the day as soon as the day starts.
Speaker 0: and that didn't happen.
Speaker 0: and As the day went on it the game didn't come out.
Speaker 0: it didn't come out.
Speaker 0: right people are like Where is the game?
Speaker 0: They're not coming out with it.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: They said they come out with it today.
Speaker 0: They're not coming.
Speaker 1: They're a bunch of crapo dig stores like vel fucks all their customers.
Speaker 1: takes money doesn't give game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like dude.
Speaker 1: It's a beta.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 0: It's a beta.
Speaker 0: You're lucky.
Speaker 0: They're giving it to you, and they didn't promise a specific time.
Speaker 0: They just said today, so you're lucky you're getting it at all.
Speaker 0: So after some digging not digging with two G's with one G I have discovered that it is most likely situation that they're having a problem with the Linux dedicated server.
Speaker 0: The game itself.
Speaker 0: they've got going.
Speaker 0: the certain the Windows Server They got going but the Linux server They didn't get going.
Speaker 1: now This is something a lot of you who play PC games and use Windows might not realize because you think oh the games are all Only in Windows, and that's true, but the majority of FPS is out there.
Speaker 1: the majority of the servers are running Linux.
Speaker 1: well It's generally easier and better.
Speaker 0: well when you play game like World of Warcraft right all the servers are run by Blizzard.
Speaker 0: they run all the servers.
Speaker 0: You know I don't run a server in my house, but for a game like Counter-strike valve doesn't run any servers at all.
Speaker 0: they run zero servers.
Speaker 0: this saves them a lot of money.
Speaker 0: They got how much World of Warcraft pays granted all those servers?
Speaker 1: the first server I connected to playing team for just when I got home claimed to be the official valve.
Speaker 1: play test server.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe they have a couple for the testing But I don't think they're not.
Speaker 1: they're gonna turn those off as soon as I probably but that I mean it clip for all.
Speaker 1: I know It was some punk kid who just said that.
Speaker 0: maybe you know you have no idea But all the servers of for counter-strike are Run by just people who like counter-strike.
Speaker 1: I mean we ran one a really crappy one.
Speaker 0: All right valve gives you the software to run a server for free.
Speaker 0: You can't play the game with that software even though it's pretty similar software But you can run all the servers you want as long as you have computers that have internet connections.
Speaker 1: now You might think why do people just run these servers for free?
Speaker 1: when do all this work?
Speaker 1: and the answer is Because they're in college, and it's a power trip to be the admin of a server.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get to be the admin and also you can reserve slots so that way you can always play the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah You can have a private server where you and your friends can play without like random people on the internet coming in and fucking Around with you and also while you can run a server on the same machine as you're playing the game on.
Speaker 0: that's really bad For performance.
Speaker 0: you definitely want to have a separate computer that runs the server on its own and someone's got to run that.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, just the physics and the engines and everything.
Speaker 1: servers for games actually take quite a bit of processing power.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's mostly CPU and network that you're worried about when really yeah, you're not gonna need the video card with that a term.
Speaker 0: No, no, you're not.
Speaker 0: so The Linux server the most popular OS for running game servers especially valve game servers because while they don't release their games for Linux They put the servers for Linux because people run in servers like to run Linux.
Speaker 0: And I remember back in the half-life days if a server was a Linux server They actually had like a little tux icons.
Speaker 0: You would know that that was a better server And they usually were better.
Speaker 1: servers say tribes to it had the little icons and Every.
Speaker 1: all the Linux servers were usually better and faster.
Speaker 0: Yep, so They're having trouble coming out with the Linux server.
Speaker 0: you can and download it right now But it only downloads the content which is sort of like the stuff that you can download.
Speaker 0: while you're waiting for the real server To come out it doesn't actually download like the executable things you need for the server.
Speaker 0: So you can't run a Team Fortress 2 server on Linux right now.
Speaker 0: Because basically what valve did is they tried all day Monday to get this to work.
Speaker 0: they couldn't.
Speaker 0: So at the last minute at like 11 30 p.m.. Pacific time They put the game out like they promised so that they wouldn't go back on their word And they're just holding out on the Linux server until they get it to work.
Speaker 1: the net result They're like 12 Team Fortress servers in the world.
Speaker 0: there are barely any Team Fortress servers because they're only Windows servers and all.
Speaker 0: as far As I can see all the low ping servers that I can get to are full Constantly and the only servers I can get on are very high ping servers which kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: So I either need to like brute force my way into one of the low ping servers or wait for the stupid Linux client to Come out, and then we can turn our servers on and we'll be in business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean the only real news here Is that a lot of people are really you know down on valve and blaming valve saying oh, how dare you betray?
Speaker 0: Well, it's like what they do is they create this own expectation in their minds of what they want and then they they act as if valve Promised them what they expect.
Speaker 1: I mean if valve had said the game will come out in September and the game wasn't out by mid 1201 on September 1st.
Speaker 1: They'd freak out just as much.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: That is true all right.
Speaker 1: so in much more Happy news that you might know that Nintendo has had various forums and social things over the years.
Speaker 1: But there were the insider forums.
Speaker 1: I'll get to my opinion on those, but they're gone.
Speaker 1: They're dead.
Speaker 1: They're done.
Speaker 0: Yep Well the official Nintendo forums at nintendo.com for insiders insiders to Nintendo Basically, they've decided that they're gonna redo their whole website to go with their Wii and DS explosion Which I think is a great thing because the Nintendo website is kind of shitty.
Speaker 0: yeah It's full of flash and the interface is kind of cluttered and really small and hard to deal with.
Speaker 0: and the only thing I use That site for is to register vidya games when I get them because occasionally that means I get prizes.
Speaker 1: now They might think why is it news that Nintendo shut down some forum somewhere?
Speaker 1: the answer is kind of frightening.
Speaker 1: I don't know if any of you have ever delved into the insider forums But they were a cesspool a fest off.
Speaker 1: They were the worst thing in the world.
Speaker 0: if you ever wanted to see.
Speaker 0: you know you think up in your mind the stereotype of An AOL using ten-year-old pokey kid with his mudkips that has got six pikachus in his team.
Speaker 1: I guarantee it.
Speaker 0: take that stereotype to the extreme Multiply it by a few thousand and make a forum that consists of those people and only those people.
Speaker 0: that is what these forums were.
Speaker 1: They were Absolutely unusable.
Speaker 0: It was nothing, but ten-year-olds yelling at each other and They were saying like some of the dumbest shit you could possibly imagine like like imagine when you were in fifth grade.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess if you're as old as us imagine when you're in fifth grade and like kids would be saying stuff about Nintendo.
Speaker 1: I heard Mario fives coming out.
Speaker 1: I got a copy and the copy looked at me.
Speaker 0: Yeah I got a super duper Nintendo from Japan.
Speaker 0: It's coming out next week.
Speaker 0: I imported it, and I'm playing Super Mario World 4 and there's a secret level and you can play as Green Luigi toad.
Speaker 1: yeah, but like three warp whistles.
Speaker 0: I got nine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of stuff that goes on in the insider forums.
Speaker 0: No Exaggeration.
Speaker 1: and on this the worst part is.
Speaker 1: I mean these forms are bad on a number of levels and they might.
Speaker 0: I Wouldn't hesitate to put them on like a top 10 list of worst forums on the net.
Speaker 1: I mean the penny arcade forums are assess pool.
Speaker 1: They're pretty bad, but they're not.
Speaker 0: they're not at least in the penny arcade forums.
Speaker 0: There are a few shining lights here and there of.
Speaker 1: you know the penny arcade awesome But there was none of that in the inside here.
Speaker 1: They had no redeeming value.
Speaker 0: You take the worst of the end of the penny arcade forums the absolute worst And you spread it thickly over an entire surface.
Speaker 0: that is the insider forum.
Speaker 1: You know I would rather go to a forum hosted by the style Project than ever delve into the inside.
Speaker 0: I would go to the something off of forums and fortune.
Speaker 0: Before I went to the insider forum.
Speaker 1: I might watch the meat spin for I don't know two or three rounds before I killed myself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, rather than go into the insider forums.
Speaker 0: That is also true now.
Speaker 0: I'd rather have a Buffalo.
Speaker 0: I take a tire.
Speaker 1: You know we just can't be filthy like the anger video game.
Speaker 1: nerd is filthy now.
Speaker 0: We can just copy his filth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can't actually come up with new similar filth.
Speaker 1: Nope right, but they're even worse than that for a number I mean one.
Speaker 1: they were one of those forums from what I can gather where you got more privileges based on how much you posted and
Speaker 0: The more of an insider you were the the more like they give you stuff like custom I can't and title
Speaker 1: or stuff like the ability to edit one of your posts after you post
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a shame that the the the forum was sort of run by Nintendo You know, but it was the official run by Nintendo the company but it was.
Speaker 0: it seems like all the moderators ran the forum as if it was like some punk kid crap forum.
Speaker 0: and For how the forum was run I think reflected on the user base, you know If you run a forum in a certain way It's sort of like look at our forum.
Speaker 0: our forum could easily devolve into mudkips.
Speaker 1: It would already if we hadn't gotten mr.
Speaker 0: It's all about the way you run.
Speaker 0: the forum determines the kind of people that use it.
Speaker 1: well the world and how the community is like this form works like a lot of forums do where post counts matter.
Speaker 1: it always says like so and so has made a hundred and ninety eight thousand posts and that makes them cool.
Speaker 1: and the I think what summed it up for me the most was that a lot of these kids Join dig to comment on the story.
Speaker 1: No, man, and the story in dig was probably the worst Commented story in the history of dig and it was just all lowercase.
Speaker 1: 10-year-old screaming about other forum was gone and one kid one solitary kid It.
Speaker 1: it was the example that made me want to just put a bullet right through my eye.
Speaker 1: This is all lowercase and I'm quoting verbatim.
Speaker 0: Oh, no from memory.
Speaker 0: I might want to close my ears.
Speaker 1: Oh Man, this is really sad.
Speaker 1: This sucks Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Those fuckers can't do this.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyone know how I get mana and red?
Speaker 1: or god It was mana and whatever which is whatever you get like.
Speaker 1: the post counts like mana and post counts from Nintendo forum imported into other forums.
Speaker 1: a Little hint out there to anyone who ever runs a forum If there is any sort of stat that your forum keeps as to how many posts a user is made do not make that public.
Speaker 1: That only encourages idiots to post more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also, uh, don't turn your forums into a game.
Speaker 0: if your forums are a game people You will.
Speaker 0: you know you that game that you put on top of your forums will sculpt the behavior of the people in those forums And usually encourages bad behavior.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even slash smart people won't play that game and stupid people will and thus stupid people will post more.
Speaker 1: remember back in the day I used to I played the slash shot game where I decided to fill my entire history with nothing but plus fives and I discovered That slash shot is indeed a game is trivial to do that and it encourages a certain type of behavior.
Speaker 1: Anyway enough of that.
Speaker 1: It's time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: Oh, man I'm not gonna talk about this much But you know, there are two kinds of videos of people getting tasered on the internet.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: the first kind the kind I Enjoy only because it proves that citizen Surveillance of police officers and public officials can do some good It's when someone who totally doesn't deserve to be tasered gets tasered by some jerk cop.
Speaker 0: I hate it when there's a video of someone getting tasered who didn't who shouldn't have been.
Speaker 1: no I love it because whenever that happens that means that now there's a record and there's accountability.
Speaker 0: I know but I don't like it because I see the video and I just go ah It's.
Speaker 0: it's so painful for me to see like an innocent person Getting like police brutality or like jailed when they didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: But then there's the second kind of video of someone getting tasered on the internet, which this one is.
Speaker 1: it is when someone?
Speaker 1: Totally deserves it.
Speaker 1: and these videos are characterized by the following thing The person will be resisting arrest and has already committed some sort of crime and they get lots of warning.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: the the funny part and I crack up every time is The person's always laying on the ground like resisting arrest and yelling something crazy and the police officer tends to just keep saying Stop that or I'm going to tase you stop resisting or I'm going to tase you.
Speaker 1: I am going to tase you if you don't stop resisting and they'll say this for like a minute or two straight.
Speaker 1: Just I am going to loudly Clearly multiple times and there's always that when they say it the last time like this is your final warning.
Speaker 1: I'm going to tase you right now unless you stop resisting arrest.
Speaker 1: They always have this look like Kind of like that judge with the eyebrow.
Speaker 0: You can tell when it's police brutality because I mean you can just tell looking at someone especially when there's a video, right?
Speaker 0: Guys only when there's a video you look at the video and you can tell immediately That cop was looking for a reason to tase him.
Speaker 0: He wanted to do it or this person didn't want to do it.
Speaker 0: They had to because the person was going.
Speaker 1: there's always just the Always sigh right before.
Speaker 1: yeah The reason I bring this one up is there's a video of it.
Speaker 1: The video is kind of bad, but you'll see there was internet outrage about this.
Speaker 1: because look at the police state.
Speaker 1: Look at how these cops got this protester and tasered him for no good reason.
Speaker 1: But if you watch the video one the guy was obviously a crazy conspiracy nut.
Speaker 1: he was Disrupting a John Kerry thing like super loudly.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: He's being disruptive super disruptive.
Speaker 1: He was asked to leave and the police had already been called.
Speaker 1: He refused to leave.
Speaker 0: so that the Here's the thing, right?
Speaker 0: He's like, what did I do?
Speaker 0: What did I do?
Speaker 0: and if you if you don't really pay attention you think oh this guy just got up Even if he said crazy batshit even twice as crazy as the batshit He said.
Speaker 0: right going up and asking a crazy batshit question is not enough to get you tased or arrested or anything.
Speaker 1: I mean, I didn't get tased when I asked Magic Johnson if you remembered working with Captain Lou Albano in the Super Mario.
Speaker 0: He could have gone up to that microphone and said Hibidi jibidi jibidi jibidi jibidi and that's not enough.
Speaker 1: I believe you meant hibidi habidi jibidi jibidi.
Speaker 0: Anyway, if he goes up and says that you know that there's not it's not any and they just tased him for saying that That's not cool.
Speaker 0: The thing here is that they came up to him and they said they asked him to leave.
Speaker 0: You can be asked to leave.
Speaker 0: This wasn't like public property.
Speaker 0: This was like an event.
Speaker 0: they can ask anyone to leave But if you don't leave you're now trespassing which means they can arrest you for trespassing.
Speaker 1: Such the funniest part.
Speaker 1: as soon as you resist that arrest game over because while the cop is saying it You can't hear it too clearly just because of the video The moment when the police take the guy down he starts yelling like what aren't you good?
Speaker 1: something like somebody.
Speaker 1: help me Aren't you seeing this?
Speaker 1: and as soon as the cops actually get him to the ground the crowd cheers because they shut him up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this one guy on.
Speaker 0: I think there was one applause from one other conspiracy not in the audience and you can tell John Kerry is just like oh god He handled it.
Speaker 1: Well because at the end he's like, well, I'll answer the young gentleman's question.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah I mean like.
Speaker 0: if I was John Kerry, I probably would have handled it in similar fashion like being all groany like And then being like, alright, I'll answer your question.
Speaker 0: you conspiracy nut after you too bad.
Speaker 0: You're not here to hear it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so while there are videos where people get tased undeservedly and they're upsetting and there are videos where people get tased deservedly And I guess they're refreshing and that I don't feel so bad.
Speaker 1: The police have tasers Well, it's more that you can't say all cops are bad and all cops are good at credit.
Speaker 1: There's the common wisdom that 99% of cops give 1% of bad name.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this particular video is is interesting in that it is one where people think it's a taser Didn't deserve it video, but it's actually a did deserve it video, right?
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: Let's get this quick.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about team fortresses.
Speaker 0: I got a double thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes There's the actual thing of the day I'm linking to but the site that it's on is Also a thing of the day in and of itself.
Speaker 0: There is a man called named Greg Castilian.
Speaker 0: I think I pronounced his name right if I didn't.
Speaker 0: well, sorry.
Speaker 0: He's an awesome guy.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize until recently I knew there was a name called a name of a guy Greg Castilian, right?
Speaker 0: I knew this was a cool guy and I knew that he made Paranoia the awesome RPG.
Speaker 0: I knew there was another guy who made this independent video game thing called manifesto games, right?
Speaker 0: I didn't realize it was the same guy.
Speaker 0: This guy is like three times as awesome as I thought he was before.
Speaker 0: Like I used to think there were like two or three awesome guys.
Speaker 0: They were actually all the same guy doing the same.
Speaker 0: So this guy's super awesome.
Speaker 0: and he has this new blog Called play this thing and the blog sort of works.
Speaker 0: or people suggest games video games role-playing games all sorts of indie You know free cheap ish games of all sorts mostly Indie shareware freeware ish PC games for Windows and Mac.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen too many.
Speaker 0: Linux is on there but I guess there might be one or two and He writes a little blog post about them and 90% of them are shit awesome.
Speaker 0: So that's this blog.
Speaker 0: That's the first thing of the day.
Speaker 0: The second thing here today is this particular game that he has suggested called Dokkutsu Monogatari, which is also called cave story.
Speaker 0: Aha.
Speaker 0: Yes It is a Japanese sort of platformy shooty.
Speaker 0: ish Metroid is not really so much Metroid RPG ish game and you can get this PC, you know English translation is totally free.
Speaker 0: you can also play it on the Mac English or Japanese and I've been playing it and It's pretty awesome game.
Speaker 0: It's one of those games.
Speaker 0: That's sort of like Like.
Speaker 0: one of those games is sort of like an underground Japanese video game in a way But now it's in English and the translation is really good and the game just works and it's really fun.
Speaker 0: The only thing is I think you kind of have to play it with your keyboard.
Speaker 0: I couldn't find out how to play it with a gamepad so much even though that might be possible.
Speaker 0: I just haven't found out how yet.
Speaker 0: So this game is worth playing.
Speaker 0: if you are cheap have a PC Can't afford to play any other games and you're looking for a game to play.
Speaker 0: This game is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: It's pretty.
Speaker 0: the coolest thing about the game is that the graphics are like done in an old-school 8-bit styling Sort of like a commander keen kind of thing, but they use like modern, you know It's 32-bit color with like alpha blending and all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: So it's this really cool.
Speaker 0: Look to the game and I really like those kind of nouveau retro game.
Speaker 0: Yeah And the game otherwise is really cool and has some really cool mechanics that I've never seen in any other games before.
Speaker 0: Like any weapon you can collect these things to level the weapon up to level 3 But getting hit while a weapon is out reduces the level of the weapon.
Speaker 0: So and you got all these different weapons to switch between the games do things like that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool I like it.
Speaker 1: I mean how many shooters were?
Speaker 1: you level up the weapon you get hit and the weapon weakens it goes away or changes.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this game is cool has a cool plot play.
Speaker 1: So speaking of cool games team fortress 2 is out and the beta is out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well effectively the game is out.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they're gonna be a lot of changes but and there's a lot of bugs already.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really want to give my impressions of the game and we're gonna you know, kind of early review it.
Speaker 1: We'll review it in depth as it goes on.
Speaker 1: We'll keep doing a beta.
Speaker 0: - so yeah take that is you.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: we realize that a lot of people particularly after I tried to play some fortress forever Last weekend and learned that most people out there Never actually played most of the games that led up to team fortress 2
Speaker 0: and most people don't even really know Like what the deal is with team 4.
Speaker 0: Yes, or why it's significant or popular or why it.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of people out there Like team fortress 2. where's team fortress 1?
Speaker 1: I mean I'll say it really simply and then we'll go into the history.
Speaker 1: if you think the team fortress classic was the original you are sadly Mistaken.
Speaker 1: team fortress classic in my opinion.
Speaker 1: Well, I talk about I agree.
Speaker 0: I agree mostly with rim on this.
Speaker 1: I am of the mind that team fortress classic is the absolute worst implementation of team fortress on any platform.
Speaker 1: Name a worse one.
Speaker 0: It's the worst one that I know of.
Speaker 0: there could be a worse one out there.
Speaker 0: I well - it's the worst major one to its credit.
Speaker 1: I never bothered with the unreal based ones, but all the people I knew who played them hated them.
Speaker 1: I don't know why they played them, but they hated him while they played him.
Speaker 0: Yep I do.
Speaker 0: I do want to say though in the defense of team fortress classic that the hunted mode is okay.
Speaker 1: It is actually.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed the hunted mode, but the actual answer the flag mode sucks.
Speaker 1: So team fortress actually began like right as I was going into high school.
Speaker 1: It was like 1996 Yeah, and a couple of guys wrote a mod for quake wine quake one.
Speaker 0: now get this right.
Speaker 0: yet Wolfenstein 3d no multiplayer.
Speaker 0: doom 1 and doom 2 and all the other dooms.
Speaker 0: They had some multiplayer going on, but it was all deathmatch or co-op.
Speaker 0: beat the game together It was no.
Speaker 0: there was no team play.
Speaker 0: There was no objective play.
Speaker 0: It was just either multiplayer deathmatch every man for themselves who gets the most kills instantly respawn the simplest most bare-bones gameplay mode you can imagine or Beat the game with some friends.
Speaker 0: help quake one came around and you know doom you could mod But quake one you could mod like much more significantly than any other game previous.
Speaker 0: I mean there was Duke Nukem 3d, but you couldn't really mod that I mean.
Speaker 1: quake 2 was similarly model.
Speaker 1: I think the point is more that quake 1 was the first game that that really was model accessibly to people.
Speaker 0: first FPS.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that was also multiplayer and able to be played online because I mean doom was super model.
Speaker 0: I made mods for doom and doom - but you couldn't make you couldn't really mod multiplayer games in a significant way.
Speaker 0: You know you could like make a map and you could change some weapons and you could change some bad.
Speaker 1: actually someone made a really Good rocket soccer team mod for doom.
Speaker 0: Wow, that's crazy.
Speaker 1: I actually played it.
Speaker 1: It was pretty fun.
Speaker 0: Most of the mods like Barney doom, but yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the first the thing about team fortress that was so significant.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of things significant about it.
Speaker 0: But not only was it like the first major mod for quake one.
Speaker 0: It was the first major multiplayer team FPS mod ever that was significant.
Speaker 0: I mean there might have been like one here or there but no one played them and I can't find any evidence to even suggest Any existed but they might have.
Speaker 1: this was the one that was played by actual humans a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it might even been the first one.
Speaker 0: I just the only reason I'm not saying it definitely was is because I don't have any evidence that there You know were or were not any others before it.
Speaker 1: now there is the the history of team fortress itself and the evolution of this original game and the iterations.
Speaker 1: and Eventually, there was mega team fortress, which in my opinion is the second best implementation of a team fortress game ever.
Speaker 1: Yep That would take a whole show in and of itself to cover all the details of that and we'll probably do it someday because it's Actually kind of fascinating.
Speaker 1: but suffice to say that was the original and then from there we had you know mega team fortress Which was just improvements on that.
Speaker 1: and then there was quake 2 and there was the weapons factory mod Which was like the super super complex version of the same basic concept.
Speaker 0: There are also lots of similar mods that weren't called team fortress for like there was just capture the flag for quake 1 and just Capture the flag for quake 2 which were team FPS is where you sort of did a similar thing to team fortress.
Speaker 0: It wasn't exactly like team fortress which why they didn't call it team fortress, but they were team multiplayer FPS.
Speaker 0: I mean you could play action quake or action half-life and get a game mode similar to team fortress going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I mean just back in the day, but when I was like super into PC gaming.
Speaker 1: I just remember that the three games I played all the time were mega TF weapons factory and action quake - yep But to skip all that history what we're really talking about is this whole genre of game that effectively could be just called a team Fortress game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: What is a team fortress game have?
Speaker 0: first of all, it's an FPS.
Speaker 0: if it's not an FPS It's not team fortress - you have classes.
Speaker 0: This is the other significant thing I mean.
Speaker 0: there are games that it classes before.
Speaker 0: we've had classes in games since the original Dungeons & Dragons But classes in an FPS where you start the game and you choose a class and depending on the class you choose You'll have a wildly different set of weapons available to you.
Speaker 0: I mean think about in the doom Multiplayer everyone had the same weapons pistol shotgun rocket launcher plasma BFG Whatever chain gun.
Speaker 0: now there was an FPS where everyone had different weapons, you know It was your flamethrower versus my rocket launcher versus shotgun versus machine gun versus laser and that was pretty significant.
Speaker 1: and The real fun part of these games was just that it was team-based and because of these classes and because there was an objective It wasn't just kill the other people.
Speaker 1: It was get in there get that flag get it back without them getting your flag.
Speaker 1: The game took on this kind of life of its own and new modes of gameplay.
Speaker 1: I mean the idea that you could play an FPS multiplayer Where you were gonna sit in the base and defend the ramp room that leads up to the flag.
Speaker 1: And that was what you were gonna do.
Speaker 0: you weren't gonna attack anyone.
Speaker 0: you were gonna go to try to kill anyone.
Speaker 0: You were just gonna not let anyone past a certain point you were not in shall pass You think about.
Speaker 0: up until then if you're playing an FPS Your only goal was to get from point A to point B without dying and probably killing as many things as possible.
Speaker 0: Now you were still playing an FPS be it a completely different goal doing something completely different Developing a completely different skill set within the same, you know I Don't know though.
Speaker 0: I lost a word idiom.
Speaker 1: Yes It was just that because of the classes you know people would kind of fall into these roles and people would specialize and a lot Of emergent team play started coming about.
Speaker 1: I mean clans are a whole different fact.
Speaker 1: We're not getting into that but in public service.
Speaker 1: just people play in this game not affiliated with each other didn't even know each other.
Speaker 1: Team play would start to emerge and it start out with simple strategies like let's all rush now Or they're getting
Speaker 0: the flag everybody
Speaker 1: defend and things like that, but it started getting complicated, you know, all right We'll have a bunch of snipers to guard the Midway and then suddenly we'll rush through here and do this and that and centuries Hidden in these corners and oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now the last significant thing about team fortress that really sets it apart from other games at least other capture the flag games Especially is that let's say I run in the base and they get the flag and I'm running I'm running I'm running I'm running.
Speaker 0: It's a two-fort map.
Speaker 0: Which is a two-fort map?
Speaker 0: means there's a fort on one end a fort on the other end at a big open field in the middle.
Speaker 1: that's very specifically.
Speaker 1: there's a Open field in the middle of water in a river a bridge across and there's also a sewer entrance that goes between the two.
Speaker 0: Yes That is what a two-fort map looks.
Speaker 1: there is a lot of nomenclature and if you talk to some of those old hardcore Grizzled mega TF players they'll speak a language.
Speaker 0: I met few men today understand But anyway, so it's a two-fort map.
Speaker 0: I go into the top of the enemy base I jump off the freaking rafters, you know with a rocket jump and I'm going I'm going I'm going and then slowly Snipes me and I die in midair and I fall to the ground.
Speaker 0: The flag falls to the ground in the middle of the field.
Speaker 0: now some of these stays there.
Speaker 1: Well some of these.
Speaker 1: the flag stays there until a teammate touches it and then it returns.
Speaker 1: some of these.
Speaker 1: it stays there for a time.
Speaker 1: There's all sorts of different ways.
Speaker 0: This could work but the point is is that it stays there and a lot of other CTF games would be you die the flag Returns, you know, yeah, and someone has to actually make the whole trip at once.
Speaker 0: the fact that the flag stays there, right?
Speaker 0: It does like two or three important things to the strategy of the game.
Speaker 0: first of all It encourages the team play because now it's not a matter of is there one guy on our team who can go and get the Flag for us?
Speaker 0: it's can the team get the flag?
Speaker 0: because if you die someone can pick up the flag and keep carrying.
Speaker 0: Yep, you can go with you and defend you while you're getting the flag.
Speaker 1: so the arsonist and the engineer sitting in the base defending the flag are just as important to your victory as the Recon or the scout and the heavy guy who are running forward trying to capture it.
Speaker 0: Secondly it changes the dynamic of the game.
Speaker 0: mid game I mean, okay the both flags are in the bases.
Speaker 0: Everyone plays a certain play style.
Speaker 0: while both flags are in the bases suddenly someone gets one of the flags in the middle of the field.
Speaker 0: the game completely changes as all these defenders move out to the Middle of the field and all the offense completely changes this direction and the game goes crazy and people have to adapt to all these Crazy situations depending on where the flag happens to end games
Speaker 1: like this or games where momentum matters And that is probably one of the biggest factors in the enjoyment where if you get a foothold in the enemy base Like you've pushed them back to their border and you're now like at their gate and
Speaker 0: you guys we got turrets in their base where?
Speaker 0: They spawn and they can't leave.
Speaker 1: Yeah My favorite was in weapons factory the heavy weapons person could make a laser like you stick it on the wall And it's just a death laser that goes out in one direction doesn't move.
Speaker 1: Of course on some maps you can put a few of these right across from the enemy spawn.
Speaker 0: Yes Now another thing these games did.
Speaker 0: is they pretty much at least at the quake very the quake based ones.
Speaker 0: is they required To be good?
Speaker 0: an extremely high level of PC FPS proficiency?
Speaker 1: I'm not just that.
Speaker 0: if you couldn't rocket jump like across the field and the to fort you were gonna die trying to walk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you couldn't bunny hop and I'm not talking quake to bunny hopping which was pretty easy.
Speaker 1: Try actually bunny hopping in quake one It was kind of a glitch but it was one of these like in Smash Brothers where like the super tournament players Do things that are barely legal and are almost a glitch and that's how they play the game.
Speaker 1: That's just how good players play.
Speaker 1: These games are a lot the same way at least especially the older ones.
Speaker 1: they think the skills got to such the point and the margins were so thin among the good players that it would come down to.
Speaker 1: I Have got the precise timing to bunny cock jump and get in and get the flag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you think about the way the game works is an example to show you just how much FPS skill meant The scout was the fastest.
Speaker 0: if you just picked all the classes you just ran the scout was the fastest.
Speaker 0: Someone with FPS skill and the medic could go faster than anyone even with the scout someone if they use the scout It'd be slower than if they were with the medic because of the way it worked.
Speaker 1: So What version would that be true?
Speaker 1: I could never.
Speaker 1: you're gonna make a scout car go slower than the other people.
Speaker 0: No, you wouldn't make the scout go slower.
Speaker 1: You can make the medic go really fast But the scout with the same person with the same skill can make the scout go faster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were like sir.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think what team fortresses have you played?
Speaker 0: I played Team Fortress classic mostly but I The other ones a couple times.
Speaker 1: one's name some.
Speaker 0: I played the original Team Fortress like two times and played the mega TF two times.
Speaker 1: Oh, so you had quake world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had quake one.
Speaker 0: I doubt you know the open source, whatever You know, there's like five open source engines that let you play it.
Speaker 1: Ah Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but that's what it says on the internet also, so I'm not just making it up.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah Regardless that's that's the way this kind of game was is that your FPS skill could go above and beyond And take you to a higher level.
Speaker 1: the skills that were required not just skills in terms of FPS but in terms of you had to understand the game and Understand the mod and it was actually super complicated to play some of these because you had to buy.
Speaker 0: factory was twice as come Factory.
Speaker 1: you had to bind a million keys to a million different things and every class had like a bunch of different kinds of grenades that were all specialized and different weapons and
Speaker 0: you needed like to set up scripts for a lot of these games so that you Could you know shoot your pistol in your left hand?
Speaker 0: But then like throw a grenade and without having to like switch weapons throw a grenade switch weapon.
Speaker 1: Well, that was specific to the fact that mega TF and game and the other games grenades were offhand.
Speaker 1: You could just throw a grenade while you had your gun out quick to didn't have that Facility you had to switch to grenade and then throw it.
Speaker 1: So me and many other people who played this game wrote scripts where by hitting a button it would swap Weapons throw a grenade and then swap back to the weapon.
Speaker 1: I just been using very quickly.
Speaker 1: Yes
Speaker 0: these games while awesome in their day were very obtuse very inaccessible and pretty much only the hardest core of people who not only had PC skills the willingness and determination to deal with like, you know quake scripting and Also mad FPS kills and crazy reflexes and all that such could have any chance of actually doing.
Speaker 1: well It was it was just the bar was set so high But anyway fast forward TFC sucked and I'm just gonna leave it at that.
Speaker 0: Well TFC.
Speaker 1: I'll just say what it was is Well, I want to get to Team Fortress 2 the interesting part.
Speaker 0: when half-life 1 came out, you know They had they needed a Team Fortress game for it.
Speaker 0: So they made Team Fortress classic which is supposed to be a throwback to the original Team Fortress and it kind of was.
Speaker 0: But it was really simplified kind of slow kind of crappy and it was just Team Fortress for half-life.
Speaker 0: But there was a play mode called the hunted where you protected the VIP and that was fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is Team Fortress classic was really shit.
Speaker 0: It was really shitty.
Speaker 0: It's silly.
Speaker 0: She's right You can still play it.
Speaker 1: So before Team Fortress 2 came out, you know, there's a mod called fortress forever.
Speaker 1: They just came out like a four days ago Which is oh I've played it and I know a lot of people in the forums have played it and I also played it.
Speaker 1: It's a lot like TFC and it's just really crappy and not worth it at all.
Speaker 1: It wasn't fun.
Speaker 0: It does have better class differentiation and variation than TFC and it is more polished than TFC.
Speaker 1: But other than that, yeah Yeah, it's just it's not fun at all.
Speaker 1: I didn't enjoy it.
Speaker 0: one whit they didn't.
Speaker 0: they concentrated I think too much on just like following the Team Fortress formula and they didn't actually think about that.
Speaker 0: The gameplay and then like, you know making it interesting and they didn't think about the maps too.
Speaker 0: Well either.
Speaker 0: so it's really.
Speaker 0: It's like they get the basic like they got like the peanut butter and the bread, right?
Speaker 0: But they didn't get the subtle flavor of the jelly.
Speaker 0: Oh, like all the detailed work in making that mod good is just totally lost.
Speaker 1: But anyway, totally enough history Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 0: would you want to say why it took 10 years to Team Fortress 2 to come out?
Speaker 1: I think we could do a separate like historical show on that.
Speaker 0: Well go to rim dot weights dot Tia.
Speaker 0: for Basically they kept promising the Team Fortress 2 would come out.
Speaker 0: the guys who made the original Team Fortress made a company.
Speaker 0: They said they were gonna make Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 1: I think everyone on the internet knows this.
Speaker 1: We've talked about this several times.
Speaker 0: I'll give it Team Fortress.
Speaker 1: I think we can skip it and I think we can skip it.
Speaker 1: They may think we can skip it.
Speaker 0: I think you just talk about something else.
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of we've talked about this before more than once.
Speaker 0: it took ten years.
Speaker 0: Yeah game finally came out like us last night.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's the beta came out last night after ten years.
Speaker 1: So initial impressions.
Speaker 1: I it's fun.
Speaker 1: Well, let's talk about the visual style first because that's the one arena where I don't think anyone can complain.
Speaker 0: Well the first time I ever saw the visual style, right?
Speaker 0: I was like what the fuck?
Speaker 0: What are they doing?
Speaker 0: And then the second time I saw it.
Speaker 0: I was like, that's the awesome.
Speaker 0: That is exact that the the visual style.
Speaker 0: while usually don't care about the graphics and games and I still don't The point in this game is that the aesthetic?
Speaker 0: the way the aesthetics are in Team Fortress 2 is it is a visual representation of the Style of gameplay and the attitude of the gameplay that the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've actually talked about that too on the show.
Speaker 1: if you wanted the example I watch I believe the trailer number two to Team Fortress 2 which Exemplifies everything that should be in a good Team Fortress style game.
Speaker 1: And if you watch the video to a certain point the music changes and that was the moment When I had a nerdgasm and decided that I would do anything to have this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Team Fortress 1 had the same feel in the play, but it looked like quake 1.
Speaker 0: You know weapons factory had the same feel in the gameplay But it looked like quake 2 Team Fortress classic feel.
Speaker 0: gameplay same I guess but crappy but it looked like half-life.
Speaker 0: This looks the way it feels and that is a awesome.
Speaker 1: Yes, because it meant to me that the people making this game know what's important.
Speaker 1: So the visual style of the game is perfect.
Speaker 1: every single thing You can see in the game while you play is just I. I can't see anything they can improve.
Speaker 0: Yeah Looking at the game makes me feel like I'm playing it and that means that the people making the game They have the same idea about what the game should feel like.
Speaker 0: that I do because it can't get better than the characters.
Speaker 1: facial expressions are right the engineer looks down and like kind of Everyone just looks perfect and whatever they're doing the heavy weapons guy is laughing his ass off as he's firing that weapon.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's so organic feeling and just so there's this sense.
Speaker 1: That's obviously artificial of Camaraderie where you hear your teammates yelling things to each other.
Speaker 1: not you know voice chat but the characters that they're playing in the game just kind of yell into each other and Medic and on taunting each other and get the same feeling is in the natural selection ready room.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah while you're playing which is awesome All right.
Speaker 1: And I think my favorite little bit is that the spy if a spy.
Speaker 1: I mean this has been a problem with all Team Fortress Games that have spies or anything like that where it's hard to not shoot at spies on your own team.
Speaker 1: Yeah in this game if a spy is on your team disguised as an enemy He still looks like a spy from your team But he has a paper mask over his face with the face of the enemy drawn on it.
Speaker 1: Yep, but if it's an enemy, it looks just like their engineer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they figured out all sorts of you know Within the game there, you know, like I said the old Team Fortress games were very inaccessible to normal people.
Speaker 0: They have polished the interface of this game in the audio and the video.
Speaker 0: They added visual cues and the controls pretty much in every aspect so that there is no all the problems of a Team Fortress game that make it inaccessible or difficult to figure out are totally gone.
Speaker 0: like You know the used to be like it for example fortress forever, right?
Speaker 0: You want a cloak.
Speaker 0: you push a button it says you are now cloaking and then a few seconds later It says you are now cloaked down in the chat area.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: You have no indication of whether you're cloaked or not anymore or how cloaked you are in this one.
Speaker 0: You push one button the spy picks up a wristwatch pushes a button on it and he keeps his wristwatch up in front of his Face, but his arms totally get cloaked and you can see that you're cloaked with your eyes.
Speaker 0: And then when you get uncloaked you can see that you're uncloaked and you can see that you need to recharge your little cokey thing now along those lines and this is something that is absolutely brilliant.
Speaker 1: a lot of classes have a special power.
Speaker 1: in Team Fortress 2 you bind a key to that and Every class is special.
Speaker 1: power is activated by that same key Unlike say weapons factory where you had to have a separate script and a separate set of key binds for every single class.
Speaker 1: in this Game you need to worry about any of that.
Speaker 1: the middle whatever button you bind is the special power of anyone.
Speaker 1: you play them.
Speaker 0: I know class has more than one special power.
Speaker 0: So you push like Q when you're the spy and you will cloak if you're the medic And you have your energy thing charged all the way up.
Speaker 0: you push Q and you use the invincibility.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: you push one button.
Speaker 0: good So what else about tf2?
Speaker 0: well?
Speaker 1: There's this interesting effect where when you move the mouse really quickly the world blurs.
Speaker 1: now on one hand it looks kind of cool But on the other hand I almost feel like that might have been added Partly because the game is gonna be on consoles.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's tough to tell.
Speaker 0: I mean you look at this game, and you can play on your PC with your Xbox 360 controller.
Speaker 0: You know you can.
Speaker 0: it's it's.
Speaker 0: you know the game for the Xbox 360.
Speaker 0: I'm assuming it's gonna be the exact same game as that we're playing now.
Speaker 0: You know only fixed and such.
Speaker 0: But I can't like I move the mouse around and I'm like okay.
Speaker 0: This is a PC FPS.
Speaker 0: I have full control.
Speaker 0: I'm not being auto aimed I'm not being limited or anything like that.
Speaker 0: But it feels like when I play the game that they've done something Like.
Speaker 0: I guess it feels like there's some accommodation for console.
Speaker 1: Oh, I can tell you exactly I can't put my finger.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of factors.
Speaker 1: one the faster you move the mouse around the screen blurs while you're moving it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the blurriness though.
Speaker 0: It could just be an.
Speaker 1: That's not the only thing.
Speaker 1: in general and this game is almost barely an FPS because you're FPS skills and precise aiming mean jack and shit in this game.
Speaker 0: well They mean a little bit.
Speaker 0: I mean when I was playing a little bit.
Speaker 0: all it means is they don't mean enough.
Speaker 1: they have to point in the general direction of the enemy and you're probably gonna hit him because People move kind of slowly and like the Rockets take forever to get where they're going.
Speaker 0: yeah, most of the guns have really wide spreads and Sniping headshots don't mean anything it appears at least I can well.
Speaker 1: for snipers it seems to.
Speaker 1: the problem is that sniping is just Absolutely trivial and it's also kind of not fun because the zoom is just on and off.
Speaker 1: It's not like a slow zoom in and it's not lift up the button to shoot its click.
Speaker 0: Yes anyone has ever played an FPS on the PC?
Speaker 0: the way sniping should work always is where you when you hold the mouse button down for Shooting right it zooms in and then when you let go of the button it should actually shoot only for the sniper rifle.
Speaker 0: It should do that because think about it You're sniping right.
Speaker 0: if you had to push the button to shoot the mouse might move a little bit.
Speaker 0: when you push the button in But you sort of hold the button on someone and let go and they die.
Speaker 0: That's how sniping should.
Speaker 0: it just feels so much better that way and that's that's I can't imagine any other way.
Speaker 1: But just the way the game like the way Characters move and how fast or slow they are in the way all the weapons work it.
Speaker 1: FPS skill means very little in this game, but even worse.
Speaker 1: I hate to say it But the way the game is now in its current state Team play doesn't matter either.
Speaker 1: the game is basically just two mobs of players push against each other until one wins.
Speaker 0: I can't see any strategies beyond the Blindingly obvious ones like have a heavy guy with a medic Following having a heavy guy with a medic following him if the heavy guy isn't stupid and one of my friends now?
Speaker 0: Well, I basically when I had as someone who was good at being a heavy and I was the medic and I followed them We just kicked all kinds of ass like destroyed the other team almost entirely was amazing.
Speaker 1: Just the only other thing that really bothers me aside from the fact that the FPS in is not so hot.
Speaker 1: It's just The the weapon selection.
Speaker 1: while it's good they've I mean they got rid of grenades.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that and every class is just like bare-bones.
Speaker 1: It is exactly what it is.
Speaker 1: It is iconic of what it is.
Speaker 0: Yes, they have pretty much taken the Team Fortress formula.
Speaker 0: They removed all the cruft and they boiled it down to just the essence which I think is good because it exemplifies What makes a Team Fortress game a Team Fortress game?
Speaker 0: But in some ways they took off too much cruft the fact that every character effectively only has one Weapon.
Speaker 1: that's good for their class.
Speaker 1: Everything else is just kind of nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like everyone.
Speaker 0: It's I mean the heavy weapons guy.
Speaker 0: He has his heavy weapon.
Speaker 0: Then he's got like the shotgun in his fists and that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: and no character has more than one special power or special Anything or special weapon.
Speaker 1: and I'm not saying I want the weapons factory world where I've got a character that has like nine different things they can do.
Speaker 1: no no no see but I don't want a game where I Feel like my class is so limiting to me that I don't have any tactical decisions.
Speaker 1: It's not like oh, I'm in close quarters got to use this.
Speaker 1: It's just this is my weapon and everything else is a backup shit weapon.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean the thing about that they've done right is they've made every class.
Speaker 0: It's an asymmetric game.
Speaker 0: You know when asymmetric game is where people have different things to work with.
Speaker 0: right, you know, not everyone is equal.
Speaker 0: It like chess is a symmetric game, you know, this is not because you have different classes, you know.
Speaker 0: at the same thing They've made each class super min-maxed Which is what they should do.
Speaker 0: like the scout is really good at going Running into the base and grabbing stuff.
Speaker 1: Even though the scout is way too slow in this game.
Speaker 0: He is way too slow.
Speaker 0: He needs to be a lot faster.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: He can't even outrun the lowest level sentry turret.
Speaker 0: He just gets killed if there's one there period which sucks.
Speaker 1: Actually what I'm kind of thinking is that if you just need to double the moving speed of every object in this game Yeah, and the game would be a lot better.
Speaker 0: It would be a lot better.
Speaker 0: it see the game doesn't feel.
Speaker 0: It's like they didn't slow it down to the point at which I'm like, this is too slow.
Speaker 1: It's not like these.
Speaker 1: when like weapons factory was released on quake 3 The way quake 3 engine is the game just felt so slow and boxy that it just it was unplayable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they slow.
Speaker 0: it feels like it's like a tad slow.
Speaker 0: It's like I need to be moving a little faster here a little faster people, you know.
Speaker 0: But the scout is super fast and but that's what he is.
Speaker 0: He's super fast and he can double jump and that's.
Speaker 0: he's super good at that.
Speaker 0: But he's super weak.
Speaker 0: and in actually fighting now, that's fine.
Speaker 0: But just if I feel like every class needs one more special job like the heavy guy He's super good at his mowing people down and he has super good at not dying because he has lots of health But he's moves really slow.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: He's that's his min and his max.
Speaker 0: He's max at killing a lot of guys and defending your base from like an onslaught of enemies and doing a lot of damage take A lot of hits.
Speaker 0: and he's min at doing anything else that it requires moving or dodging or anything.
Speaker 0: His only weapon is The heavy machine gun.
Speaker 1: now that give him another game play be ready for gameplay purposes.
Speaker 1: That could be fine.
Speaker 1: the problem is that it actually gets Uninteresting really quick because you don't have any options and your only option if you get bored with using that one weapon is to play A different class.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I was changing classes a lot just because it got really uninteresting to play the class I was playing.
Speaker 0: but also depending on the situation in the game I would change classes as opposed to sticking with one class and changing my strategy because They've min max them so which is good because it makes the game interesting But they've boiled them down to where they're.
Speaker 0: they only have one.
Speaker 0: You know thing they can do.
Speaker 0: so you have to change Classes when you want to do something differently rather than having another option in how you can play now.
Speaker 1: this ties in with another issue That there's been a lot of quote unquote controversy on the internet.
Speaker 1: No one has grenades in this game with the exception of the demo man power is he has grenades.
Speaker 0: If you've played Team Fortress games before pretty much everyone had a grenades all over the place.
Speaker 1: now The reason for that is actually pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: I mean all these old games were mods of existing games and to do interesting things you oftentimes had to get around the Programmatic just difficulties or limitations of the engine in the game.
Speaker 1: you were you.
Speaker 0: I mean a quick one.
Speaker 0: Everything was either a gun or a grenade.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: so to make a class interesting.
Speaker 1: I'll use uh, I don't know It doesn't matter just I won't even give an example.
Speaker 1: I'll just say you've got a class right.
Speaker 1: He's got like two weapons that are unique to his class And then he's got all the normal weapons, and then he has say two or three different quote grenades.
Speaker 1: One of them's a normal grenade, but the other one or two are actually special things like oh I got a good one in weapons factory.
Speaker 1: you have the marine right and his main weapon was the rocket launcher.
Speaker 1: But he also had another kind of rocket launcher that was crook slightly so and those are like his two main weapons.
Speaker 1: He also had one kind of grenade I forget what it did and another kind of grenade Which was actually a little floating turret, and you threw it and it made a little turret that floated there for like two minutes
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm
Speaker 1: and this was a way to super differentiate all the classes.
Speaker 1: so each class would have a bunch of different kinds of grenades that were all unique to that class and gave you a bunch of tactical options in that class and In addition you had one or two unique weapons or special weapons for that class.
Speaker 1: so each class was very versatile within the scope of what it could do or what it was supposed to do and I think a good team fortress game should kind of mix the two boil it down But at the same time don't boil it down too much.
Speaker 1: You got to have a bunch of tactical options, but not so many tactical options that you start overlapping other classes.
Speaker 0: Yes, you look at something like fortress forever right and they pretty much gave grenades to everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they gave.
Speaker 0: everyone has piles of grenades.
Speaker 1: Everyone has a normal grenade in a special grenade.
Speaker 1: now the special grenade is fine because I think that adds a lot to the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like ooh.
Speaker 0: I'm the engineer I have a special like engineer grenade that does something special that Everyone also had just a normal grenade and that what that does is it sort of removes the differentiation between the classes because now Everyone can make things explode.
Speaker 0: so normally for in team fortress 2 if you're let's say an engineer you build a turret.
Speaker 0: well Normally someone needs a grenade to you know to blow up that turret or to really screw with you.
Speaker 0: So they call in the demo man or maybe the soldier with his rockets But like a scout really can't take you out cuz you have turret there.
Speaker 0: What's he gonna do about it?
Speaker 0: But in fortress forever the scout can just throw a grenade over there.
Speaker 0: cuz everyone has grenades another engineer can just throw a grenade over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, granted fortress forever is a really shitty game.
Speaker 0: It is really shitty, but that's what I'm trying to.
Speaker 0: I'm comparing the good and the shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah Is is that giving everyone grenades removes the differentiation between the classes so that there's no reason to pick one over the other Whereas team fortress 2 has super differentiation, which is good But they've also.
Speaker 0: the classes are so narrow in their purpose that you have to keep changing them to do anything different at all.
Speaker 1: So the end result is that the game is fun But it definitely has a lot left to be desired and I hope they change a lot of things because in the end All right The characters all move really really slowly and as a result FPS skills don't actually matter that much.
Speaker 1: in addition You don't have any options with classes other than the basic weapon and as a result, you don't have any strategies except the absolutely basic obvious ones.
Speaker 1: and the end result of all of that is that the game just ends up being Lines of people kind of throwing is themselves at each other and there's no interesting duels.
Speaker 1: There's no interesting rocket fights.
Speaker 1: It's all really kind of milk toes.
Speaker 0: I think all you know It'll end up being if you know The game will boil down to where people execute the same really simple strategies over and over again.
Speaker 0: It's just a matter of who can execute them faster and better.
Speaker 1: I mean the argument for old games because a lot of this kind of thing would happen in pubs and even other team fortress kind Of games.
Speaker 1: the argument was yeah, but skilled players, you know, they play a real game.
Speaker 1: They use actual strategies.
Speaker 1: Even if I had full control over everyone on my team, there's no interesting strategy worth a dick so far.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least that I can tell.
Speaker 0: I mean there isn't because the only strategies I mean They kind of even tell you like you use these classes for the offense use these for defense use these first support.
Speaker 0: You know, it's kind of like alright and you do that And that's pretty much the best you can do.
Speaker 0: have your engineers and your heavies and you know stuff and stay around your base Defending with your medics on your heavies and then you know Maybe an engineer goes and does the teleporter thing so you can get to the enemy base Then rush in with like the scouts and the pyros and the soldiers to go and try and get the flag.
Speaker 1: There's just.
Speaker 1: the game like I said before is barely an FPS and it's barely a team fortress game.
Speaker 1: It has everything going for it.
Speaker 1: It's just it's not there yet.
Speaker 1: Nope It needs to.
Speaker 1: I seriously think all they need to do is give every single class One more thing that is unique to that class.
Speaker 0: and well, maybe not the engineer The engineer has because he has the teleporters and the turrets and the shotgun.
Speaker 0: I think that's.
Speaker 0: I think the engineer has enough but I don't.
Speaker 0: every other class every other class needs something else.
Speaker 0: You know spy I think is okay, too But everything else needs to be and a spy is actually like the most well done spy ever I must got.
Speaker 1: the spy is like super awesome.
Speaker 1: It's better than any spy in any team fortress game ever like for example, the the the sniper, right?
Speaker 0: He's awesome at long range, right?
Speaker 0: That's his that's his strength.
Speaker 0: So he has the sniper rifle.
Speaker 0: Give him another long-range weapon Maybe like I don't know a fire a crossbow or something, right?
Speaker 0: You know some other sort of maybe like a rapid-fire long-range weapon of some sort or like a railgun or a laser Painter or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, give him something that you know doesn't make him, you know Like every other class that doesn't even the tables and say oh I might as well be a snipe because the sniper still has to Be super weak at close range and super strong at long range.
Speaker 0: Just give him something else to do even like a shot like a special little shot.
Speaker 1: That's like the sniper You don't have as many bullets with it But you shoot it and it goes out and when it hits a wall or something It has a little bit of shrapnel that goes to the sides get people around corners a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something something like that anything just I can't think of anything specifically.
Speaker 0: That would be real.
Speaker 1: or like the murder the long-range attack the marine guy Just give him another kind of rocket like maybe a laser-guided and a normal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, give him like.
Speaker 0: you could also give the marine guy like, you know some sort of like shorter range Because the you know, the Rockets are good at long and short range, you know.
Speaker 1: Also make the Rockets faster because the Rockets are really slow.
Speaker 1: I think the whole games too slow and I think that is the game's biggest failing that the characters move way too slow The guns move way too slow.
Speaker 1: The gameplay is way too slow and it removes a lot of the skill from the equation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz now if you have super slow reaction times, you can beat the people with really fast reaction times.
Speaker 0: That's sort of the main thing in an FPS.
Speaker 0: I mean like.
Speaker 0: I could probably kill fatality in this game, even though his reaction time is like 10,000 times now.
Speaker 1: You might say all rim and Scott you're just being overly critical of a not super complicated game and one this game is great.
Speaker 0: Well, well, well perfect.
Speaker 1: well No What I'm saying is that there's evidence that everything we've said is true in that from what I've seen Most games end in a stalemate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they go to sudden death and they Death I gotta say is actually really cool.
Speaker 1: It depends because the sudden death still has a time limit it does.
Speaker 1: if that expires then oh everybody loses play again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that the sudden death that the sudden death is a cool idea because what they do is they say Alright, this game has gone on long enough.
Speaker 0: We don't want to sit here for hours and hours.
Speaker 0: Just you know playing and doing no one's getting anywhere.
Speaker 0: We're gonna say no one can respawn.
Speaker 0: now everyone respawns at the beginning of the map.
Speaker 0: Everything's reset and if you die You're dead now.
Speaker 0: It's like counter-strike right and then we'll see who wins.
Speaker 0: so that's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't really work because the the real strategy there then is don't die No Super camp your base as a group and defend and hope the other team stupid enough to attack because that way Worst case scenario it ends in a draw best case scenario.
Speaker 1: They attack you and die.
Speaker 0: The other thing is I think there shouldn't be a time limit on the sudden death.
Speaker 1: No, because then then both teams just camp until one team gets sick of it and dies.
Speaker 0: maybe The other thing about the sudden death is that if you die early in the sudden death, you know Let's say you you're gonna be brave.
Speaker 0: You're gonna go be like the sniper and sudden.
Speaker 0: That's probably why they have the timer in it - yeah you Die right away and now you have to sit there and wait.
Speaker 0: now waiting and counter-strike isn't so bad because around a counter-strike Lasts at most.
Speaker 0: what five minutes waiting in the sudden death can really suck.
Speaker 1: It only lasts like a couple minutes.
Speaker 1: It's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's still kind of bled to sit there and I mean in counter-strike.
Speaker 0: you expect that when you die You're dead and then another round will start soon in team fortress.
Speaker 0: So you've been you've been respawning the whole game and now suddenly you're sitting there not doing anything and it's pretty boring and annoying.
Speaker 1: I just feel like without some fundamental changes to gameplay The game has a very very very low skill camp and everyone who has any Talent or skill or practices at all is going to maximize their skill in relatively short order.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think they're already optimal players at this game.
Speaker 0: I think there are two.
Speaker 0: there was a guy named scruffy.
Speaker 0: He was just he was the soldier and he was owning everybody and I think he figured it out And there's not much to figure out.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I Mean, the only reason I'm not disappointed is because it's a beta and I'm sure they're gonna make a lot of changes before the game Actually comes out.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.