Speaker 0: It's Thursday, August 9th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight how to not suck at slack and all.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So rim anything happen today.
Speaker 1: a bunch of boring stuff at work.
Speaker 1: I could go on in depth about everything that I do at work, but it's really not that interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got nothing either, so I just do the show.
Speaker 1: Guess we don't have any of those wacky stories from our day to talk about today.
Speaker 0: I guess not all right then.
Speaker 0: so news time.
Speaker 0: So that Barry Bonds he hit that 756 home run there.
Speaker 0: He's hit more home runs and majorly baseball than any other single person.
Speaker 1: all right I can't say that I care at all.
Speaker 1: I barely know who.
Speaker 1: that is no.
Speaker 0: some guy named Matt Murphy a college student from Queens caught the ball all right and which is funny because he was in San Diego and went to the game on a whim and I didn't see a Television of course because I did not watch television, but apparently he was making a fool of himself being like.
Speaker 0: I'm Matt Murphy from Queens.
Speaker 1: I'm Matt Murphy from Queens.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the story here.
Speaker 0: Is that the ball has an estimated value of Half a million dollars, maybe a little more like that.
Speaker 0: if I were him I would pretty much at least if you sold it You know yesterday when he when he or two days ago when he caught it.
Speaker 0: I'm not exactly sure.
Speaker 1: well I would have done.
Speaker 1: I would have put it on eBay immediately.
Speaker 0: ahem technically according to the laws the United States That's a taxable income right there even if he doesn't sell the ball Even if he just gives the ball back to Barry Bonds even if no matter what he caught the ball Even if he just like handed it to the person next to him.
Speaker 0: right Technically, it's taxable income.
Speaker 0: and that immediately puts him into the highest tax bracket and on the ball alone They estimate that he would have to pay $210,000 in tax even if he gave the ball away, huh?
Speaker 0: United States tax system so awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm really glad that I have not run into the more intricate issues of the day.
Speaker 0: not only that not only that.
Speaker 0: but if he Holds on to the ball for even a day if the ball appreciates in value Technically, he'd have to pay a capital gains tax on the appreciation.
Speaker 1: See the thing is technically don't I have to pay?
Speaker 1: I would actually be paying capital gains taxes on all those Nazi coins and Things I have.
Speaker 0: I know it's that's the problem with the tax system is have all these?
Speaker 1: yeah granted while there are problems with the u.s Tax system I want to say right now before anyone gets any ideas that all those people for fair tax or flat tax or any F-star tax they're morons and those ideas are stupid.
Speaker 0: those ideas are stupid.
Speaker 0: the tax system is bad.
Speaker 0: That doesn't mean your equally bad idea equally bad or possibly worse you bad.
Speaker 1: Put that fair tax anywhere near the realm of sanity.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's probably one of the worst ideas a human being has ever had.
Speaker 1: the only thing I got is that hobo who shoved a fork In his eye not so bad compared to fair tax.
Speaker 0: So this guy though He doesn't have much to worry about because apparently when Mark McGuire, you know hit his home run for his different home run record You know if home runs in a single season Someone from the IRS was like, yeah, you got to pay tax on that.
Speaker 0: and then someone else from the IRS was like No, we're just kidding after politicians, you know made it said.
Speaker 0: Hey, that's pretty stupid right there You know that gives me heart.
Speaker 1: at least it proves that there are some politicians who are not some sort of skin spy But are actually human being yep.
Speaker 0: So hopefully if the IRS tries to tax this guy I mean if he does sell the ball, right?
Speaker 0: I do believe Personally that he should be taxed on the money He gets for the sale.
Speaker 0: not you know, whatever people say the value is.
Speaker 0: so he sells it for a dollar.
Speaker 0: Sure, make him pay, you know, 35 cents in there.
Speaker 1: Honestly what I would probably have done is Said I was keeping the ball sell it to someone under the table for cash Like some collector.
Speaker 1: you get another ball to replace it Even if it was far less and then just say I lost it.
Speaker 1: cuz I didn't care about baseball.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know, wait a minute wait a minute.
Speaker 1: if it depreciated in value or I lost it couldn't I claim some sort of Tax boon as a result.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: if you lose something valuable You know what you could do, you know You know how you could get money by losing it.
Speaker 0: if you got insurance on it, and then you lost it Yeah, but then technically it's insurance.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying, which is that there's no way to make money.
Speaker 0: There's no way to get money by basically setting money you have on fire.
Speaker 1: There's no way to get more money than on Unless you're a business and you play shady games with the taxes.
Speaker 1: I had a friend who explained to me in great detail How the best way to make money off of a business is to every few years lose a whole bunch of money on paper Whether or not you actually lost a bunch of money.
Speaker 0: The only way I've seen to successfully make a lot of money and avoid you know with that That sort of scam and avoid insurance fraud would be to say have a contest get some prize insurance Right.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to explain how prize insurance works.
Speaker 0: You should figure it out.
Speaker 1: I think it's pretty self-evident.
Speaker 0: Get.
Speaker 0: you're not allowed to have people in the company or your friends or your family enter the contest because you know They obviously figure that scam out right.
Speaker 0: but if someone else wins the contest and then they're so generous They just give you the money.
Speaker 0: That's a way to get money from insurance without.
Speaker 1: Well, they'd still have to give you the money.
Speaker 0: So you have to do all sorts of surreptitious shady things or you just have someone who's really dumb and you're like Yeah, you have to give that money to me.
Speaker 1: Okay, you know a much simpler way is to have the person killed and steal the money.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I don't know what's a worse crime Murder or telling someone to murder or hiring a hitman versus insurance fraud?
Speaker 0: What has the worst penalty?
Speaker 1: but at the same time?
Speaker 1: The evidence shows time and time again that if someone only commits a single murder their odds of being caught are very low unless they're Stupid.
Speaker 0: Oh, what are the odds of getting caught if you commit a single insurance fraud?
Speaker 1: Probably much higher.
Speaker 1: the thing is I've noticed that I most of the people you see getting caught with insurance fraud are Not the brightest people and they're not engaged in the.
Speaker 1: let's say the Sherlock Holmes is not on the case.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't think Sherlock Holmes is on any case.
Speaker 1: I think we can simplify this further.
Speaker 1: the best way to make money is to already have money.
Speaker 0: yes, and you know, even if Basically, I think what the law does even if you follow the law and pay the tax on the ball It pretty much encourages Anyone who catches the ball who's not already rich to sell it.
Speaker 0: So it pretty much Garrett.
Speaker 0: the tax law in the United States if followed to the letter Basically guarantees that the bought anything valuable that is suddenly created will always end up in the hands of someone who is already rich.
Speaker 1: You know, I did interestingly enough learn not too long ago about how China's tax system works.
Speaker 1: How does it work and particularly how Kong Hong Kong works?
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna get into the details It's kind of complicated.
Speaker 1: what I can say is that people look at the u.s.
Speaker 1: You know well we tax the rich more in order to even out and the top x percent of Americans paid like 90 percent of the taxes in China.
Speaker 1: in Hong Kong it's that times a million like I think 40 or 50 percent of the people don't pay any tax at all and Then the wealthy pay almost all the tax.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's why they have so many Chinese mafias to avoid.
Speaker 0: paying those tax will not also be rigid.
Speaker 1: as a result Unless you are one of those people who pays those taxes, you can't vote.
Speaker 1: So it's not one vote one person.
Speaker 1: It's basically pay taxes get a vote.
Speaker 1: So only basically like doctors lawyers and educators can vote and no one else can.
Speaker 1: The thing is there's this big argument in Hong Kong about universal suffrage and mostly it's poor people who want it saying that we should get a vote and A lot of other people are saying that that would ruin the system because if people who don't have to pay the taxes at all And don't have to in any way deal with the consequences of government that spends more money Have control over the government's purse strings that they'll spend more money if people that they don't have it just it wouldn't break.
Speaker 1: I Disagree with some of that but at the same time I imagine a world where only people with an IQ above say a hundred and thirty get a vote.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I don't know how I feel about that.
Speaker 0: It's real tough because we used to have a system in the US where you pretty much had to take a literacy test to vote And it was ruled unconstitutional because it was basically being used right out to keep black people from voting.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a real literacy test.
Speaker 0: it was like black people can't vote.
Speaker 0: we're pretending it's a literacy test.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that's bullshit.
Speaker 0: That is quite the bullshit.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like the Civil War in the US.
Speaker 1: I was with the South on pretty much every issue Except that whole slavery bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if it hadn't been about slavery yeah war of northern aggression But you know what.
Speaker 0: why is it so hard to do a good thing without doing a bad thing?
Speaker 1: I mean look we get people who assert their rights Oh, but they're asserting their right to have slaves.
Speaker 1: Oh look States rights.
Speaker 1: any time someone asserts States rights It's almost always to do something regressive and stupid.
Speaker 1: Any I mean, but I think we should bring the literacy test back.
Speaker 0: if it's a real literacy test And there's no corruption then yes the problem is because there is guaranteed to be horrible corruption.
Speaker 1: No The thing is maybe what if the tests were just published ahead of time with all the answers?
Speaker 1: Then I mean there's straight-up.
Speaker 1: like I had a teacher in school who did this a bunch of times He'd give you like the week before the test Every single question that was gonna be on the test and the answers to every single one of them Clearly and openly and he'd say as much.
Speaker 1: and people still failed those tests and it and at that kid.
Speaker 1: in that case While you wouldn't get a lot of people the people who weren't allowed to vote because they didn't get those questions, right?
Speaker 1: I don't think they have any right to be voting.
Speaker 1: I do think I'd say offered in any language.
Speaker 0: I do think that an ideal system would have some sort of way to determine to fairly determine That some people's votes count and some people's votes do not.
Speaker 0: for example if someone votes for say Joe Schmo and they can't tell you what Joe Schmo's platform is I don't think that their vote for Joe Schmo should count.
Speaker 0: however There is no fair way to test them and thus in Reality.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's a practical and pragmatic way to implement such as this.
Speaker 1: but Scott I thought it was easy.
Speaker 1: All you have to do is only give the vote to white males who own land.
Speaker 1: Oh That system works really well, didn't it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so well.
Speaker 0: Anyway, speaking of voting I wouldn't even be able to vote.
Speaker 0: I'm a white male who doesn't own land.
Speaker 1: My family owns a little bit of land.
Speaker 0: You don't own land.
Speaker 0: I have a claim to that land but then their vote your dad's vote represents you.
Speaker 0: you don't get to vote.
Speaker 1: My dad votes the same way.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: You did the same.
Speaker 1: you don't get to vote But someday I will when I inherit that land.
Speaker 1: I am the eldest.
Speaker 0: if you inherit land I might they might just you know.
Speaker 0: Let the land go and you inherit something.
Speaker 1: else thing is the land will be valuable because it's I won't get into that anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, uh, the courts ruled on a case that's been around since the year 2000 about so old.
Speaker 1: that's pretty old considering what it was about.
Speaker 1: Basically some people set up voteswap2000.com and the way the site worked was.
Speaker 1: you could say I Want to vote for Ralph Nader, but I don't want to throw away my vote and let Bush win the elect.
Speaker 0: Oh you tied it in somehow.
Speaker 1: So to the previous news the site was set up where someone who was in a state or a district where their candidate was pretty Much guaranteed to win no matter what could swap votes with someone in a contested area.
Speaker 1: So let's say I'd swap my vote because I live in a place where if a non-democratic Person ever won in any time the presidential votes of New York State I can't imagine that happening.
Speaker 1: So my vote doesn't count in this state at all.
Speaker 1: My vote has no effect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait Elliot Spitzer got what 75 plus percent of the vote.
Speaker 0: He couldn't lose governor.
Speaker 0: He couldn't possibly lose.
Speaker 1: Yep, so say I mean I know that I don't know whoever the Democratic candidate is going to win New York No matter what in 2008.
Speaker 1: But let's say I want Ralph Nader's party or the libertarians or one of those third parties To get my vote not because they're gonna win.
Speaker 1: I know they're not gonna win but in order to get that five percent or whatever of votes that they get federal funding I Can swap my vote with someone in Ohio a swing state so that person will agree to vote for my candidate in, Ohio And in return I will vote for their third party candidate in my state.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the site was sent a bunch of letters from the California Secretary of State informing them that their website is illegal and it's corruption and blah blah blah and the site was shut down.
Speaker 1: and then a giant court case started and the court case Is finally over.
Speaker 1: it was ruled that there is nothing wrong whatsoever with vote swapping.
Speaker 1: Anyone who said otherwise is an idiot and that's the end of that.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean what could possibly be wrong with it?
Speaker 0: First of all, there's no way for them to like verify that you actually swapped your vote.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm sure some people did and some people didn't but there's no way to guarantee It's basically just a bunch of people saying stuff on a website and it doesn't have any real meaning at all.
Speaker 1: Well here on the first I'm of the mind that Anyone
Speaker 0: who
Speaker 1: votes currently because currently the system is any citizen can vote regardless of my feelings as to literacy and whatever I'm of the mind that if you are letting someone vote you Cannot ever tell them What factors they should consider.
Speaker 1: if someone has the vote and decides to vote for Bill Clinton because they like a saxophone playing I don't think there's anything wrong with that.
Speaker 1: I mean I might disagree but people should be able to vote on whatever factors they want and if someone decides that they want to give their vote to someone else or Just vote randomly flip a coin in the toll, but there's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: No, you can vote however you want.
Speaker 0: if you can't vote however you want It's not really a free vote and you're forced to decide based on someone else's decision.
Speaker 0: You're not really voting You're just doing something someone else told you to.
Speaker 1: so frankly I'm fine with people straight up selling their votes five bucks a vote, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah and the beauty of the system in America is that You cannot get a receipt of who you voted for.
Speaker 1: you cannot bring proof out of the booth.
Speaker 1: That way while people can do all sorts of things and decide however They want you can't be forced to vote for someone no matter what.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you go into that little booth or you go and do whatever and there's a curtain behind you.
Speaker 0: No one knows who you vote for.
Speaker 0: if you don't look and you just vote with your eyes closed You won't know who you voted for.
Speaker 0: you'll never know.
Speaker 0: It'll be a complete mystery and I should do that.
Speaker 0: There's no way to prove it to yourself for anyone else.
Speaker 1: I should walk you to the booth So close my eyes go flicker flicker flicker flicker and pull the lever you should.
Speaker 0: it'd be fun.
Speaker 0: do it.
Speaker 0: I'm like an off year.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I mean this coming one exactly.
Speaker 0: so Any sort of you know corruption in the votes usually involves election workers or Having dead people vote or something or bad machines or bad counting.
Speaker 1: that was actually like adding in beacon during the last round of elections.
Speaker 1: There's this old lady and she was you know showing people in to vote and she kept saying everyone who came up don't forget to vote on the open spaces in this initiative.
Speaker 1: don't forget to vote for the open spaces initiative.
Speaker 1: and Finally the like the real election person noticed and walks over just like what you're doing is in violation of federal law.
Speaker 1: I could have you arrested blah blah blah blah blah and scared the living shit out of this old woman.
Speaker 1: Yep, but the thing is the old woman also was kind of indignant Like I should be able to.
Speaker 1: it's an important issue and people should vote.
Speaker 1: and yeah Yeah, the sad thing is this thing is a lot.
Speaker 0: The thing is yeah, she was while she was.
Speaker 0: It would be okay if it was like.
Speaker 0: hey remember there's a question to vote for at the top, you know Don't just vote for the people.
Speaker 0: There's a question also on there.
Speaker 0: Don't forget to look at it.
Speaker 1: No I don't even agree with that because now because she is saying that and no other polar is she's skewing the votes by reminding.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is that pretty much that I think you know.
Speaker 0: If there's something on the ballot that is off or the people might not notice I don't think there's a problem with them drawing attention to it.
Speaker 1: However, there is a problem if they lean slightly in either direction or if the method methodology of the election is broken by The fact that any one election official is doing something different from the other ones.
Speaker 0: That is correct.
Speaker 1: Like if if there happens to like say I go into the booth and I just highlight Barack's name while I'm voting.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, I will say I actually despite the fact that I hate the Democratic Party almost as much as I hate the Republican Party.
Speaker 1: I registers the Democrat just so I can vote in the primary for Barack Obama Whatever Barack attack.
Speaker 0: Okay, so Basically, I don't give a shit about what you do outside the voting booth in terms of elections at least the United States because if it's corrupt it's corrupt and your vote doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: and if it's not corrupt then it doesn't Matter.
Speaker 0: what you do outside the booth is no one knows that you who you voted for.
Speaker 0: You could just be full of shit.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: So Blah, I am very glad that the courts ruled properly and there's a quote.
Speaker 1: They said they violated the appellant's First Amendment rights.
Speaker 1: Aha Things of the day.
Speaker 0: So a while ago there's this video on the Internet's of some youth pastor who's you know.
Speaker 0: I mean the guy seems like a nice enough guy, but he's a youth pastor.
Speaker 0: So, of course, I'm gonna be anti him because I don't know those Jesus people.
Speaker 1: you didn't seem really that he seemed really like one of those overly excited people exactly.
Speaker 1: I don't like those people at all.
Speaker 1: I can't stand their presence because it's such an affected excitement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it doesn't seem like he's bad.
Speaker 0: Like what those evil pastors were like out to get everyone's money.
Speaker 0: He seemed like he was genuinely believing he was just.
Speaker 0: you know The excited and sort of crazy kind of that guy is a youth pastor.
Speaker 1: That guy is the g4 TV of Christianity.
Speaker 0: pretty much so.
Speaker 0: This guy was like talking about lot and something like that and he was talking and waved his unsexing stick.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: He's sexy De-sexing.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: It was de-sexing stick most unsexily exactly.
Speaker 0: So he was waving around his de-sexing stick and basically the guy was talking about lot like pitching tents or pinching tits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and basically he accidentally said pinching tits and it was a funny video on the internet.
Speaker 0: so some other people saw this video and they said hey, I got an idea and they went pretending to be FCC agents and They went up to him and they went to his church and they put on a whole big thing and they totally fooled him Into thinking that he was gonna have to pay a $50,000 fine at least and that they were gonna have to you know take away the church's nonprofit thingy and the guy was like freaking out and sweating all over the place and He's really got a fire under his ass.
Speaker 0: and it's pretty funny now.
Speaker 1: that in and of itself is funny.
Speaker 1: I love a good prank.
Speaker 1: It's not quite as good in my mind as it's a good night for flying but it's still a good prank.
Speaker 0: No The best part about this particular prank video is they actually show you when they tell the guy that it's a prank And he has like he's reaction is like ah And that's a good that's a good part.
Speaker 1: Well, that's that's a good reaction to.
Speaker 1: nothing bothers me more than someone who gets angry After a prank has been pulled on them.
Speaker 0: He doesn't get angry.
Speaker 0: He's sort of like he seems like he's containing Any anger that is there.
Speaker 0: like he starts just like rushing the guy and then he just sort of like Jumps around or at the room all wisely.
Speaker 1: and oh, I thought the way you portrayed that I thought that he laughed.
Speaker 1: I thought it was awesome.
Speaker 0: He sort of thought it was awesome sorta guy.
Speaker 1: It's hard to tell.
Speaker 1: so he ran around the room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was pretty Excited in and had a lot of kinetic energy when they told him see that that was the g4 creeping out.
Speaker 0: That's exactly what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: So it's it's it's kind of freaky.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you should still watch this because it's funny and is a good prank Especially considering the irony that you know A church person is the kind of person who would tend to agree with the FCC and such.
Speaker 0: So having them get burned by the FCC is sort of a way to show them the light that they're wrong.
Speaker 0: Oh See now they show them the light about a religious thing.
Speaker 1: That is that was good.
Speaker 1: But the thing that really bothers me is that it's kind of sad that we live in a country right now.
Speaker 1: That is a very viable and credible threat.
Speaker 1: it is indeed that the FCC does have the power to do that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they do Okay, well actually in this case, they didn't really I mean have anything against this guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, but I mean had he been on the radio or on TV.
Speaker 0: I mean if a radio like radio people did rebroadcast what he said The problem is he's not responsible for that.
Speaker 0: the radio people are.
Speaker 0: so yeah yeah, but you know, it was easy to trick him into thinking he could get in trouble for it and It's pretty believable, especially since they executed the prank very well.
Speaker 0: They had a very high production value with some good cameras and some good acting and all kinds of good stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: but for whatever reason.
Speaker 1: when you said executed I immediately expected you to say him that I don't know why.
Speaker 1: oh well Anyway, oh well Luckily, right.
Speaker 1: So this is a video.
Speaker 1: Well a movie from 1951 or 52 now 51.
Speaker 1: Okay, and this is a video Teaching you.
Speaker 1: well nominally teaches you about table manners and all that crap in, you know, classic 1950s way.
Speaker 0: but that is not and cover.
Speaker 1: that is not my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: The video is merely the vessel for my thing of the day much Much like before when my thing of the day was the om nom nom nom nom nom.
Speaker 1: So In this video is perhaps the worst sweater that has ever been made in the world.
Speaker 1: I how bad is it?
Speaker 1: The fact that this video is not in color is probably the only reason that I'm still saying or the reason that you're not blind This is the worst sweater ever.
Speaker 1: I can't stress to you enough how hideous this sweater is.
Speaker 1: It's these two mooses around a Christmas tree and it's.
Speaker 0: are you sure they aren't reindeer?
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's a fire.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're demons.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: And the fact that that was the extent of knitting technology in the 50s.
Speaker 0: What do you want?
Speaker 1: the fact that there are two people wearing this identical sweater?
Speaker 1: One of whom is larger than the other.
Speaker 1: thus there were at least two sizes of this sweater.
Speaker 1: At least two of them were made one to rule them and in the darkness bind them, right?
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 1: Oh and the video is kind of funny.
Speaker 1: It's about table manners.
Speaker 1: It's really dumb.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty dumb.
Speaker 0: I mean table manners.
Speaker 0: It's it's kind of funny because the kid comes down from upstairs or wherever and he exhibits bad table manners And then they tell him that he should do better and they then they go to explain how to have better table manners.
Speaker 0: but his table manners and his attitude that he has in the beginning of the video where it's supposedly the bad part is like a God compared to like I don't know me.
Speaker 0: every day or most You know, it's kind of like watching Happy Days.
Speaker 1: or leave it to Beaver where there's the bad kids like Fonzie.
Speaker 1: Fonzie was the most good-natured nice lovable well-mannered person in the world Compared to the average kid today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know freaking like a hundred years or now People are gonna look at Mike Tyson and be like, oh what a nice guy.
Speaker 1: He's so nice Right, so we should just stop here and not do the rest of the show.
Speaker 0: Ah Good idea Lots of better things to be doing.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'm not gonna try to make that a clever segue any more So than I already attempted.
Speaker 1: but tonight we're talking about something that someone requested a while ago.
Speaker 1: yet again You see Scott and I are.
Speaker 1: I mean we slack off, but that doesn't really do it justice.
Speaker 1: I would say that we are professional slackers.
Speaker 0: I just adjusted my angle of reclining.
Speaker 1: I'm reclining back right now.
Speaker 1: I got a slightly different angle myself, but pretty much from middle school on Scott I have done very little real work in the world.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, I mean in elementary school, they always told me your grades matter so much.
Speaker 0: You won't get into honors classes in middle school.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, and of course my parents are like you don't get all A's You're stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then in middle school, they were like, well also in elementary school They told me I should take notes and study and I didn't even know what study meant.
Speaker 0: Like I knew that study meant somehow that you prepared for a test or an exam But I didn't know what you did to study.
Speaker 0: like I'm like, what do I do?
Speaker 0: I don't know what the physical thing I'm supposed to do is and I always got excellent grades doing nothing.
Speaker 0: And I they said take notes.
Speaker 0: and at first, you know taking notes meant copy down onto a piece of paper Everything the teacher writes on the overhead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I realized pretty much right away that that served no useful purpose.
Speaker 0: and then When it you know at first that was like an assignment like you had to do it and it was graded.
Speaker 0: but then later they're just like remember to take notes and I didn't
Speaker 1: the thing that really scattered in high school in all the like AP classes There were a lot of overachievers in the classes who would bring little tape recorders and record every day's lecture while they took notes.
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't get it.
Speaker 0: All right, and basically as time went on I didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: My grades were just fine I didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: My grades are just fine.
Speaker 0: And then eventually I realized grades don't matter that much.
Speaker 0: It's all a lie.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go to college no matter what I'll be fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, doesn't matter if this I get a C or a B in freakin calculus.
Speaker 1: I mean I tried.
Speaker 1: I actually tried right up until about the first quarter of ninth grade in high school my first year of high school the first quarter and I had all A's and I've been doing all my homework and I realized suddenly that like Scott I'm going to college no matter what Nothing's gonna stop me.
Speaker 1: Wow, I don't care about any of this.
Speaker 1: and I suddenly stopped doing homework.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I basically know When I say I stopped doing homework, I actually told my teachers I'm sorry, but I have a no homework policy and I seriously did not do homework ever I.
Speaker 0: my policy was I didn't do anything that wasn't graded.
Speaker 0: So if it was, you know do this project or write this essay, there's a grade on it.
Speaker 0: It's an assignment that counts.
Speaker 0: I did it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I did not do it no matter what.
Speaker 1: Well, it really depends.
Speaker 1: I mean it started out like that, but then we got even worse in college and a little bit in high school.
Speaker 1: It wasn't just that it was more.
Speaker 1: Alright, so that assignment is worth what five percent of my grade, but I can still get an A and not even bother Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then it got worse.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, alright That's worth ten percent of my grade.
Speaker 1: if I skip that and I do moderately well in the rest of the class I'm guaranteed a B. All right, if I also skip the first midterm Can I pull off a C?
Speaker 1: Because if I skip the first midterm, I can skip the whole first half of the class.
Speaker 1: Amen and it just went downhill from there.
Speaker 0: I remember one time in 11th grade 11th grade and I was in my social studies class, which was actually like current events something No, what.
Speaker 0: I forget exactly what it was But it was a really cool teacher.
Speaker 1: in high school the word social studies class always meant just usually nothing.
Speaker 0: It was actually a really cool teacher in a cool class.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was one of the better.
Speaker 0: He was actually a libertarian and stuff.
Speaker 0: It was cool.
Speaker 0: And basically During the class once the guy sitting behind me, you know football guy who was actually not a bad guy He was you know, the teacher goes over to him and says why aren't you taking notes?
Speaker 0: And he's like Scott's not taking notes And he's like Scott gets A's you take notes.
Speaker 0: That's beautiful.
Speaker 0: That was a fun time.
Speaker 1: See the best was all the classes that had curves.
Speaker 1: I mean, especially like all the AP calculus.
Speaker 1: whatever classes they were graded on a straight-up curve.
Speaker 1: whoever did the best in the class got a hundred percent and it just went downhill from there.
Speaker 1: and Homework was worth like twenty five percent of our grade.
Speaker 1: So but there's only one class of us.
Speaker 1: so we realized Hey, what if we collaborate then?
Speaker 1: None of us have to do the homework ever and it won't matter.
Speaker 1: So we all stopped doing the homework.
Speaker 1: An unnamed individual secretly did the homework and secretly turned it in all year, but I won't get into that Alright, so basically when it comes to slacking off, especially in school.
Speaker 0: You have to determine a few things.
Speaker 0: Yes everyone.
Speaker 0: What is the minimum?
Speaker 0: Actual work you have to do to get by because you can't do absolutely nothing and get by.
Speaker 0: that's never gonna happen.
Speaker 1: And also you at least have to show up to like one test at the minimum get by Can vary because it's not just get by on the bare minimum Period it's get by in terms of what are your goals?
Speaker 1: What do you want or need to accomplish?
Speaker 0: How can you accomplish said goals with minimum efforts and you determine the exact minimum amount of work time?
Speaker 0: You're gonna have to spend doing things in order to achieve that What you need to achieve and once you figure that out you spend Exactly that amount of time working and not a second more.
Speaker 1: now schooling particularly pre college schooling So high school middle school elementary school is a very special case because especially in America You're gonna graduate anyway, and the way college admissions work as long as you do well on various standardized tests You're gonna get into college.
Speaker 0: Anyway, unless you want to go to Harvard or somewhere like that or Yale really badly You don't need freaking a zillion a.
Speaker 1: well even then a high standardized test score But when I say hi, I mean really high will make up for almost any failing for many schools.
Speaker 0: Wow Yeah, it's it's kind of true.
Speaker 1: I mean look at our IT.
Speaker 1: because of my test scores They didn't even look at my high school transcript for all they know.
Speaker 1: I never graduated from high school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and like you're freaking like College essays and stuff unless you're applying to be some sort of like literature major They're barely reading that.
Speaker 0: you think about its admissions.
Speaker 0: people looking at this stuff not teachers.
Speaker 0: They got a pile of things and they're processing them and they're just gonna process them as quick as they can.
Speaker 0: It's like yes.
Speaker 0: No, yes.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: No, they have like a formula that tells them hat what to say yes, and when to say no.
Speaker 0: and Interviews and stuff are mostly ways for them to advertise their school to you and not ways to pick you out from the other people Except they're really small schools.
Speaker 1: Actually, that's a very important thing to remember because I know a lot of our listeners are near the end of high school.
Speaker 1: The colleges you are looking at before you are a student are not your friends.
Speaker 1: They are trying to sell to you the idea of going to their school.
Speaker 1: they don't care directly about you until you are already a student.
Speaker 1: and if a man if a man plays a trumpet for you and Tries to convince you through his trumpet playing that IT is the major that you want to go into You got to step back and think if that's really the way you want to decide on your major.
Speaker 1: because I made that mistake.
Speaker 1: Fund but I put up in a. IT is great, but I put up in a. you'll make six figures But that doesn't take any work.
Speaker 1: and then the dot-com bust happened like six months later Fooled by the the Pied Piper so to speak.
Speaker 1: yes, but anyway Pre-college I mean your goal in high school is either to get a job or go to a trade school go to college whatever and Outside of that nothing you do in high school with rare exception is going to matter your grades in high school once you get accepted To college mean less than nothing Less than nothing
Speaker 0: unless you really have to go to Harvard or something really badly
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So in that case
Speaker 0: or unless your parents were like stab you for real Not like threaten you and yell at you But like actually stab you
Speaker 1: So well I guess one of the biggest things if you want to be a true slacker that you have to be able to do is figure out your true goals and figure out the true requirements of achieving those goals and Willing and able to cast aside all of the distractions that will not get you to your goal.
Speaker 0: Yes, and you also.
Speaker 0: the next thing you have to do is Not worry ever about.
Speaker 0: you have to basically Do enough work so that you won't worry.
Speaker 0: if you worry for even a second like oh, maybe I didn't do enough work Maybe I won't achieve my goal if there's any uncertainty you have failed completely.
Speaker 1: This is especially true when you were skipping class.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of you fry never skipped a class.
Speaker 1: A lot of people never skip a class and Lee or at least rarely skip a class.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: I've seen people who would finally get up the testicular fortitude to skip a class And then they spend the whole hour or two that there's you know, they're skipping this class Worrying about the fact that they skip the class and as a result, they don't really get the enjoyment They should have gotten if you were going to skip a class if you were going to forgo Important work.
Speaker 1: if you're going to do anything like that You'd better get everything you can get out of that skipped work.
Speaker 1: or why did you even bother?
Speaker 0: If you decide that this homework is not necessary to achieve your goals and you don't do it and you spend all night Worrying about the fact that you didn't do it You should have just done it because you would have spent maybe a half hour doing it instead of you know eight hours worrying and then worrying the entire next day and then still worrying some more.
Speaker 0: you didn't get any fun during the time you Saved you just freaking worried I mean.
Speaker 1: when I skipped class in high school the first couple times I was a little anxious like they're gonna get me but I never really thought about the specific consequences.
Speaker 1: They could lay upon me.
Speaker 1: I just thought skipping class.
Speaker 1: You can't do that.
Speaker 1: How are you gonna get away with it?
Speaker 1: They'll know it's high school And then one day I just didn't go to English class and then I just another day I went out to Arby's and hung around in the mall for a couple hours.
Speaker 1: one day I just didn't even go to school and I realized that there were no ramifications at all and no one cared.
Speaker 0: Yeah, look at that.
Speaker 1: granted granted I because of the the attitude that many of the teachers had toward me it turned out later that most of them just assumed that I was in the band or I was doing something important or that I Was excused and they never bothered to check up on it.
Speaker 1: So if you're gonna be a professional slacker Not just an amateur slacker you have to go do more than just do the minimum to accomplish your goals.
Speaker 1: You also have to Accomplish in the eyes of others a lot more than you were actually Accomplishing.
Speaker 0: and this this is why there's some very important rule of slacking and that is the greater your abilities The less you have to do.
Speaker 0: because if you're real let's say I'm really good at my job.
Speaker 0: Right, I can.
Speaker 0: if I'm super good at my job I can either find a harder job which in which I will have eight hours of work to do each day or I Can do a lesser job right and since I'm so good at it I can do the whole job in like 10 minutes and Slack the rest of the day.
Speaker 0: a professional slacker.
Speaker 0: watch out for these people people who are getting by without doing any work Sort of like Homer Simpson, they are secret geniuses.
Speaker 0: They have awesome abilities and they're using like their immense power to do the bare minimum They have to do to get the job done and the rest of their time They're doing whatever the hell they want and they're not looking like genius.
Speaker 1: I mean think of this say I don't know an essay for an English class.
Speaker 1: You have to write an essay right.
Speaker 1: think about how much work it takes you to get the a paper Right the a paper the good paper the paper that is as good as it's gonna be not the a plus but the a. now think about how much less work it takes to get the B and Think about how much less work it takes to get to get the C.
Speaker 0: now think about how much less work It takes to get the C If you have the ability to write the a in like a half hour.
Speaker 0: think about how long it would take you to write the C even better.
Speaker 1: if you have done the all the professional slacker things and you've created in the eyes of the people who will be judging you the idea that you are brilliant and Awesome at everything you do then if you do a subpar job and you write the B paper or the C paper There's a good chance They're gonna give you the a anyway because they know what you're capable of or at least they think they know what you're capable of.
Speaker 0: Yes, you a slackers.
Speaker 0: next best thing is always figure out loopholes in the system.
Speaker 0: If there's a teacher who's not actually grading the papers and just sort of grading based on your name and then not reading them You need to take advantage of that.
Speaker 0: Just put your name on the paper and fill the rest of the page with words.
Speaker 0: put some real words at the beginning real words at the end and just gobbledygook all the way in between.
Speaker 1: I've I often in high school.
Speaker 1: I put in the middle of a lot of papers a single nonsense Sentence something about like I don't know cable ties and dogs and plus.
Speaker 0: if there is a way there's a situation in which there is work to be done and you can save a significant amount of time by making it look like the work was done when it was not and Nobody and everyone will be fooled by this Fucking.
Speaker 1: do it now.
Speaker 0: remember don't worry that you did it.
Speaker 0: if you worry it won't work.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Remember the key here is that no one will notice because if no one notices and no one could care and it doesn't affect anyone Then the work wasn't worth doing in the first place and you effectively did the work.
Speaker 0: Yeah It was the only work that they really assigned you was make it look like you did the work not to actually do the work
Speaker 1: Because in the world of a slacker Everything you do is not the sum of what you actually did But it is the sum of what other people have appraised of what they think you have done.
Speaker 0: It's basically doing the least you can possibly do to get what you want in The least amount of time.
Speaker 1: now the wonderful part of all this is sometimes to be a true slacker.
Speaker 1: You have to put forth Uncountable amounts of effort early on in order to get the massive payoff later.
Speaker 1: For example say for the first quarter of your senior year of I don't know AP English class.
Speaker 1: I don't know why I keep using English maybe because I skip that the most.
Speaker 1: You do crazy awesome work.
Speaker 1: you go above and beyond on every possible assignment.
Speaker 1: the teacher now thinks you're the golden child for the rest of the year.
Speaker 1: you can do jack shit and you'll still get an A and I did that straight up my senior year to the point that I remember we did a presentation.
Speaker 1: this was like a huge part of our year like we spent months on it and All the quote-unquote smart kids who are also professional slackers with one exception.
Speaker 1: We all got ourselves into the same group Mostly by begging and asking despite the fact that they were supposed to be random and we put together Something that I mean it wasn't bad in the I don't know MD Geist way It was just.
Speaker 1: it was something that a C student would put together.
Speaker 1: It was garbage and we got an A just because our names were on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, awesome and Other people in the class knew they could tell but what were they gonna say to the teacher?
Speaker 1: What did they possibly have said?
Speaker 1: the teacher was already enamored?
Speaker 1: She had already fallen for our guiles.
Speaker 1: There was no way out.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's not much more to say about slack in really other than think.
Speaker 0: Oh, I know one thing.
Speaker 0: another key thing for a slacker is Not to want too much.
Speaker 0: remember before I was talking about how yeah You don't need all A's unless you want Harvard.
Speaker 0: the more you want the more work You're gonna have to do to get it.
Speaker 0: the less you want the less work you have to do regardless of your ability.
Speaker 0: So if you have a lot of ability and very few wants you don't have to do much Now.
Speaker 1: at the same time you can be a professional slacker and still want a lot.
Speaker 1: It just means that you go.
Speaker 1: you are going to get all of the things that you want With the least effort that you can possibly get.
Speaker 1: all of those things Yep.
Speaker 0: But if you want too many things that least effort still might be all goddamn day every day.
Speaker 1: the other thing you really have to worry about and this is probably the biggest thing is that When you are a professional slacker you have to realize that you're walking now a Razor thin line and that there is now very little room for error in college.
Speaker 1: I mean we said I make the determination of all right.
Speaker 1: that Assignment that project that I don't want to do is worth 10% of my grade.
Speaker 1: Alright, I can still get an A if I do everything else perfectly.
Speaker 1: now a single screw-up drops you to the B. a single Screw-up, there's no more margin.
Speaker 1: It's like when you're car racing the faster you go around that corner the less chance you have to recover if you fuck something up.
Speaker 0: and thus the key to being an excellent slacker of the highest caliber is to Simultaneously walk the razor's edge and not worry about falling in either direction Despite the fact that falling in either direction can happen at any moment.
Speaker 0: Wow, I guess we kind of made it's.
Speaker 0: it's like you have to not worry when you should be worrying the most.
Speaker 1: You have to be like Lancelot in that you have to have a movie where Sean Connery played giant testicles such you know confidence and fortitudes.
Speaker 1: Right, uh we could say more, but frankly I'm kind of lazy, and I don't want to bother me either.
Speaker 0: plus I kind of want to do a geek bite because you know we started this new segment last week And I got a really good one.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna bother putting music in yet because I still have to figure out what kind of music I want to use for this segment, okay, so I'm gonna do a geek bite about an anime video Podcast.
Speaker 1: now notice.
Speaker 1: We're not doing this on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: That's purely entirely by chance.
Speaker 0: yep There's an anime video podcast called track shun TV track - Shun like track or shun dot TV now.
Speaker 1: I saw it on dig.
Speaker 1: That's the only reason I knew about it because while I don't like the dig podcast thing It's still the best podcast thing in the world as far as I can see.
Speaker 1: yeah So I use it and I saw that at the bottom with a couple of digs a long time ago And I never really saw it go anywhere.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you the story.
Speaker 0: so at Otacon was the first time I heard of this because I saw an advertisement For in the Otacon program and then at our podcasting roundtable panel the guy who does it was like hey I'm that guy who does it and Aaron from the Ninja Consultants was like whoa you're that guy you should be up here blah.
Speaker 0: And I didn't know anything about this guy.
Speaker 0: I don't even know the guy's name And I watched the show.
Speaker 1: all I knew was that the last time I looked he had like five digs.
Speaker 1: so I thought wow Yeah, anyway, I think currently he has let's see are you gonna look?
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 0: It's on his page.
Speaker 0: Oh Hold on well.
Speaker 1: I don't get the people who put the like the amount of digs.
Speaker 1: They've gotten on their own website.
Speaker 0: It's on our website is it?
Speaker 0: it's on the right side.
Speaker 1: I don't actually look at our website.
Speaker 1: I don't like that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, it's the thing that it lets you dig it when you click on it.
Speaker 1: I like the letting you dig it, but I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't like the idea of touting thing is for podcasts on dig right now There's no other way.
Speaker 1: Anyway, well, I still don't like it.
Speaker 1: I'll go on the record saying that but whatever yeah, so it has 55 digs right now.
Speaker 0: anyway There was an ad for it in the Otacon program guide and the guy who does it was sitting in the back of the panel Room and he said that he you know does a video podcast.
Speaker 0: he does ads.
Speaker 0: he said he had like a zillion listeners.
Speaker 0: his website says that He's the most popular anime video podcast on iTunes and it also says he's had over a million downloads something something something uh-huh.
Speaker 0: and he has 55 digs.
Speaker 0: and He said that he gets paid by his advertisers $500 an episode.
Speaker 0: That's what he said at the podcasters roundtable panel.
Speaker 0: We have a recording of it.
Speaker 0: I can go back and listen to it.
Speaker 0: It's not like it's also.
Speaker 0: you can listen to that.
Speaker 0: I think our five central put it up and the Ranger cast also put it up.
Speaker 0: So in either one of those podcasts you can listen to the podcasting roundtable panel.
Speaker 0: So this guy he did this show and I completely forgot about it after Otica.
Speaker 0: So Gerald IIM's me today and he says hey this traction thing Have you heard of it?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, it sounds familiar.
Speaker 0: and he says it's that thing from the guy at Oticon.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh that thing.
Speaker 0: and I decided on the way home today.
Speaker 0: I was gonna download every anime video podcast except for anime podcast net which I watch and I know And I'm gonna watch him on the way home.
Speaker 0: and there were three I downloaded and traction was one of them.
Speaker 0: I downloaded episode 50 of traction and I downloaded another episode maybe 48 I don't remember and I watched them on the way home.
Speaker 0: I Expected something bad, you know just cuz.
Speaker 0: obviously it's me.
Speaker 0: What was I gonna consider?
Speaker 1: this?
Speaker 1: I'd say 99% of the podcast I have tried to listen to were god-awful like a solid 99%.
Speaker 0: So this is an anime video podcast I expected bad Right, and I'm about to describe to you the format of this show and I won't need to describe anything else after I describe the Format of the show.
Speaker 0: that's all I need to say.
Speaker 0: you're ready But I don't want rim to say anything until I say.
Speaker 0: and that's the end of the episode.
Speaker 1: I will not say a word until Scott bids me to.
Speaker 0: okay, the episode opens with the episode intro and The guy who does the show is sitting next to his giant television with his laptop on his lap and He's wearing obvious You know anime merchandise hat and shirt stuff You'll see out for sale at a convention usually and he'll talk for maybe I don't know 30 seconds telling you which three shows He's going to review.
Speaker 0: Then he will show you Five minutes of the first anime he's going to review.
Speaker 0: He'll just show you the anime like here it is and I'll show you like a good five to ten minutes of the first episode.
Speaker 0: Then he will come back on screen for maybe Ten to thirty seconds to tell you, you know What Japanese snacks he's eating this episode because he eats three Japanese snacks each show right which is also Merchandise he's trying to sell.
Speaker 0: Um, then he'll show you Five to ten minutes more of that same first episode.
Speaker 0: So I watched a show where he reviewed claymore So he showed a good Almost like a good almost half of the first episode of claymore Maybe even more than half of the first episode of claymore.
Speaker 0: just straight up like copied the fansub pasted it into his episode.
Speaker 0: After the episode is over.
Speaker 0: He'll come back on screen and he'll say something This is just.
Speaker 0: you know, I'm gonna pretend to do a review in the way.
Speaker 0: He does a review of a show, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say he just watched.
Speaker 0: I don't know Nakano.
Speaker 0: no, he just he just watched a he.
Speaker 0: one of the things I saw him review was a harem show, right?
Speaker 0: So he said up a typical harem show one guy bunch of girls.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's not really any different than any other kind of harem show, but it made me laugh.
Speaker 0: So I'll give this one a track.
Speaker 0: That's that's the entirety of one of his reviews.
Speaker 0: he pretty much either gives a show a track or a shun which is good or bad and He reviews a show in like five seconds and doesn't say much about it other than like.
Speaker 0: hey This is a robot show and it wasn't as good as that robot show.
Speaker 0: I watched last week shun.
Speaker 0: That's the review He gives after reviewing a show.
Speaker 0: He shows a j-list ad because j-list is a sponsor and He will you know, he makes the ads that he puts in the show.
Speaker 0: So he made an ad for j-list and he put it in the show.
Speaker 0: It's a good minute long.
Speaker 0: then he'll continue talking about j-list for like 10 more 30 more seconds and He will repeat that episode showing and review process two more times.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna get three j-list ads three like 30 second intermissions in the middle of the episodes of him saying Japanese snack something something and you're gonna get 10 second reviews at the end of the episodes of him saying track or shun and you're gonna get a j-list ad at the end of each episode and you're gonna get like 20 minutes or like 15 minutes 10 minutes maybe of the first episode of the fan-subbed anime that he watched.
Speaker 1: I gotta say I'm three.
Speaker 1: Ah, I gotta talk.
Speaker 0: that is the entirety of every single show This guy makes the end.
Speaker 1: What the fuck is?
Speaker 0: who would?
Speaker 0: Imagine if instead of reviewing baka no We just played the audio of baka no for say 20 minutes and then said we liked it.
Speaker 0: Have a good night.
Speaker 1: All right I'm gonna let I mean I'm not angry.
Speaker 1: There are only two ways I can look at this.
Speaker 1: This guy is either an idiot or a genius and he is either lying or a scumbag.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now here are the reasons either.
Speaker 1: He's an idiot and he's just a pawn of the advertisers and nothing more or He realizes that advertisers are stupid and he is milking them for all their worth in the true slacker way with minimal effort Possible.
Speaker 0: Yep, either Jlist is like hey this tool is basically making a video podcast That is nothing more than an ad for us and he's only doing it for $500 an episode.
Speaker 0: This is so much cheaper than paying someone to actually do this job like a video podcast consultant or something.
Speaker 0: This is awesome.
Speaker 0: Or this guy's saying oh man, this is so easy.
Speaker 0: Jlist is giving me $500 for an episode for doing shit.
Speaker 0: Who cares?
Speaker 0: Whoo?
Speaker 1: Now?
Speaker 1: and the other thing in terms of how much money he makes.
Speaker 1: I Really wouldn't be surprised if he was lying but at the same time I wouldn't because I've talked to advertisers in the past and we've been propositioned a couple times and They really have no clue.
Speaker 1: They really have no idea at all.
Speaker 1: They they're just stupid as far as I can see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just I don't understand this show.
Speaker 0: I don't know why it's so popular.
Speaker 0: Well, I do.
Speaker 0: it says on his website.
Speaker 0: He has more than a million downloads.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute when he was featured on iTunes.
Speaker 1: more than a million downloads.
Speaker 1: We have more than a million downloads.
Speaker 0: I know well know.
Speaker 0: how many episodes do we have?
Speaker 0: 400 about times how many fingers.
Speaker 1: thing on how he counts the stats because if you like if you count the raw raw raw stats of Total downloads from our libsyn.
Speaker 1: It's almost a million.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he only did 50 episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know Yeah, but even then I just I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't trust his stats too much and even if I either I think it's also mostly because he was featured on iTunes.
Speaker 0: It basically means a million downloads right away.
Speaker 0: Much.
Speaker 0: anyone who was reported that they have been featured on iTunes on that front page of the podcasting directory has Always gotten a huge jump in people paying attention to their show.
Speaker 1: The thing is I wonder how many of those people actually continue to watch.
Speaker 0: well judging by his 55 digs Not many of them are dig users.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is a show like that.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be perfectly blunt.
Speaker 1: only an idiot would watch it.
Speaker 0: I just don't get it.
Speaker 1: So either there are a lot of idiots out there both as advertisers and his content watchers or the guy is milking and Exaggerating his initial figures in order to trick advertisers into giving him his only advertisers j-list.
Speaker 0: so he's either milking j-list or j-list is milking him or So one of them is taking advantage of the other or they both think they're taking advantage of the other.
Speaker 0: and I don't know what's going on here, but You should not waste your time watching track - on TV The anime review video podcast because there's no reviews.
Speaker 0: He's just showing you like 10 to 15 minutes of new fans of anime and then saying yes or no to them And that's it and then showing you j-list ads.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I'm reasonably certain that what he is doing may or may not burn foul of the law.
Speaker 0: That's what I was thinking as well.
Speaker 0: I forgot to mention it just now but when I watched it on the train He's just showing.
Speaker 0: he's basically copying and pasting significant portions of you know basically new fansub to anime Into.
Speaker 1: his video podcast sounds like he is stretching the idea of fair use quite to its limit.
Speaker 0: yes, not only that but his is show is released under the attribution non-commercial no derivative Creative Commons 2.5 lice.
Speaker 0: Really I don't think you can take a copyrighted work like that and put it out under Creative Commons license because people aren't allowed to freely share those fansub.
Speaker 0: it's not legal and I mean if it could it is fair use to show something when you're reviewing it.
Speaker 0: However, if you watch Siskel and Ebert or any like, you know movie critic.
Speaker 0: on TV They show a clip from the movie.
Speaker 1: However, I think the operative word there is a clip and I wonder what the courts would have to say about shows.
Speaker 0: at least It's got to be 10 minutes I got.
Speaker 0: I'll actually count and figure out the exact minute counts of things, but it's not worth my time.
Speaker 0: But the vast majority of the show I would say in the entirety of the show the up to two episodes.
Speaker 0: I watched about Less than five minutes of the show is the guy talking.
Speaker 0: that's not an advertisement.
Speaker 0: There's about less than five minutes maybe five minutes total of advertisements including the guy talking and saying advertisements and the rest of the show is just Fansub to anime straight up like two Really big portions of an the first episode of a show.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I think I can sum this up very succinctly.
Speaker 1: I give it a shun.
Speaker 0: I also give it a shun a big shun.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.