Speaker 0: It's Monday November 19th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: We begin a series about Google by talking about the world before Google.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, we're still alive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the weekend didn't go quite as badly as it could have.
Speaker 1: no it could have been much worse.
Speaker 0: I was very tired yesterday, but I slept a whole lot because somehow yesterday You know I find it interesting that you see we went to this party which now if Last year's or the last time a party like this happened was to be believed.
Speaker 0: We were expecting to Basically have to fend off a horde of Visigoths or in this case Possibly Ostrogoths in the corner of the house hoping not to be vomited upon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that I mean this.
Speaker 1: this exact party has happened once before and we didn't go because of other reasons.
Speaker 0: well because the we came Out and we were here to get it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but oh wow Yeah, it was exactly a year ago, so Yeah, because the we as I think a year old today or something like that Regardless the the same party happened before and the tails were Vomitacious.
Speaker 0: they were they were of a myth vomit ik widis All right, they were vomitoriums.
Speaker 1: And so we expected that since we're going to the party for the second time It's ever happened that it would be a similar event.
Speaker 1: yet It was not.
Speaker 0: it was quite enjoyable, but I think that the most telling thing was that at the end of it all Scott did not drink and Alex did not drink.
Speaker 0: I drunk quite a bit But yet in the morning and the rest of the next day the three of us had the same hangover.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there wasn't too much sleeping going on now not so much We had.
Speaker 0: we stayed up until like three the first night playing apples to apples then arguing about crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I generally just got the same bad feeling you get whenever you don't get enough sleep and do too much stuff And then the next night we were gonna go to bed at like three.
Speaker 0: everything was all set And then we stayed up another hour arguing with some guy about Comics.
Speaker 0: now issues are kind of to suck and collecting comics is kind of dumb if you're trying to make money off of it.
Speaker 1: yeah, especially if you're doing it for money, but The point is is that you know I had to drive home and everyone else is sleeping in the car And then he finally got home, and then we went out to eat.
Speaker 1: We came home, and it was actually really early like nine ish.
Speaker 1: so after finishing reading the the book I was reading which didn't take very long.
Speaker 1: I actually went to sleep stupidly early, and I got enough sleep to revive and Thanksgiving I'll need to work two more days before I'm off again, so yeah, and I got the Friday off.
Speaker 0: So I'm doing my annual go out to Rochester go to Millennium kind of pilgrimage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what we want there.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna email the Millennium guy ahead of time and see if he can get me a copy of Dune before I get there.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a good call.
Speaker 0: I'll pretty much sell him.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to pay up to like 150 bucks.
Speaker 0: That's a good call, but anyway, let's just get into the news.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to get done with the show and go to bed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, super tired.
Speaker 0: I just actually want to continue to be well-rested.
Speaker 1: I just want to read a bunch of manga and stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get so much reading and coding stuff done with the Thanksgiving and all the business and no it's gonna be good times.
Speaker 1: but for now Tech news always slow in late November.
Speaker 1: I mean every tech podcast is like oh, what are we talking about?
Speaker 0: But what about all those rumors of a 14 or 13 inch MacBook?
Speaker 1: Those were like a weeks ago.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: and whatever happened to that?
Speaker 1: the rumors don't believe anything until you see it people.
Speaker 0: Oh, I know.
Speaker 0: I don't believe it.
Speaker 0: But at the same time not that Apple cares about me.
Speaker 0: But I have to say if that comes to be true I'm probably going to buy one pretty quickly if it's true.
Speaker 1: It's probably not a bad purchase.
Speaker 1: I might have purchased one if I had needed a laptop when around now instead of around back And I kind of need one now.
Speaker 0: now that I'm really happy with what I got now that I'm once again a flushing money And anything that I can spend money on that'll make my life better is worth it.
Speaker 1: Yep Alright, so what kind of news you got over there?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I got to start Alright, so I find this interesting because I saw this article on slashdot and I read it and I had thoughts about it.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile Scott read an article on dig that was about something that actually happened because the article on slashdot was basically just Wouldn't it be bad?
Speaker 0: if is it stupid - should we worry about?
Speaker 0: and Scott's article was?
Speaker 0: X happened it sucked.
Speaker 0: We should have worried.
Speaker 1: I don't know about the reliability of either of that article, but whatever I didn't read it.
Speaker 0: I didn't see it.
Speaker 0: Scott told me about it.
Speaker 1: I just saw a headline and I inspected it very cursor Lee Uh-huh, so but he definitely did it what there was an article that did say what we're about to say.
Speaker 0: But anyway, you might be familiar with these websites like tiny URL at Alia.
Speaker 0: There's a million of these things.
Speaker 0: It's you know, you type in your most popular.
Speaker 0: You type in a URL on the little site and it'll give you back a shorter URL like I type.
Speaker 0: www.scott makes inappropriate URLs that imply homosexuality.
Speaker 0: calm and shortly good gobbledygook gobbledygook gobbledygook gobbledygook and it shortens the two tiny URL comm slash Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I hope that isn't something real.
Speaker 0: I don't even I'll go see.
Speaker 1: it is something I'll go find out.
Speaker 0: but These sorts of services are kind of a mixed bag and even though tiny URL is kind of known and respected and trusted at the same time my personal opinion is that there is really never been a Useful purpose for anything like this.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of P. and the worst thing is I see people using it not even for the real.
Speaker 0: I guess the only legitimate thing I could see it for which is trying to tell someone a URL over the phone or trying to tell someone a URL in a radio show or something, but I See people posting tiny URLs in Forums because they don't know how to make a link.
Speaker 0: So instead of using HTML or bbcode or whatever they post a tiny URL in text in a forum.
Speaker 1: Well, it'd be easier would be a website where you go to and you You just type in the crazy URL and then it makes you an HTML link that you can copy and paste.
Speaker 0: That is kind of sad if you need that.
Speaker 0: It's the internet.
Speaker 0: I know I know I'll be perfectly but to me HTML or at least bbcode is pretty much the language You need to understand to be wiki code to count at the internet.
Speaker 0: You don't count if you can't do one of those as far as I could tell.
Speaker 1: Well, at least not at the internet but on the web.
Speaker 1: But you can't you cannot operate on the web if you don't at least know the basics of HTML and or bbcode.
Speaker 1: It's just not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: You need to know how to at least make a link a href whatever.
Speaker 0: but I mean I mean, I'll say pretty much straightforward I feel that people who use these services use them poorly and stupidly and I really see no legitimate reason to bother with them.
Speaker 0: James Randi always uses it I know and he shouldn't.
Speaker 0: The worst thing in the world is when there is ever a link in a website that uses a tiny URL Why all you did was add a layer of possible failure?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if tiny URL goes down now your link doesn't work Even if the site that you were trying to link to in the first place is still up.
Speaker 0: also I'll say that I just in principle do not click on those kinds of URLs because Who knows where they can go?
Speaker 0: I don't know what's on the other side and while I am NOT I was going to say immune but then I said not and I'm so.
Speaker 0: I am NOT immune to Being Rick rolled because I'm on to Linux and to Firefox.
Speaker 0: But nonetheless if I see a URL and I can't tell where it goes I'm not going to risk going to a site that might try to Rick roll me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you part a very important security feature of web browser.
Speaker 1: You hold the mouse over the link and the URL shows up in the bottom and you know You look at that URL of where the link is gonna go and you say aha I know where this link is going and if it says the link is going to like yahoe.com You're like yahoe.com.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure that's totally legitimate and free of evil.
Speaker 0: Sorny magnet box.
Speaker 1: Oh Look at all these great name brands.
Speaker 1: but yeah, so the fact if you you can take a tiny URL and Point that to say some horrible evil website of doom and then someone hovers over and they go Oh tiny URL.
Speaker 1: I guess I have to click.
Speaker 0: granted evil someone who trusts tiny URL Probably wouldn't have figured out that yahoe.com slash gobbledygook is somehow bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 0: or the famous microsoft.com slash whole bunch of stuff that actually just redirects you to evil.com.
Speaker 1: Ten euro useless We don't.
Speaker 1: if you're using it stop just learn how to make a link.
Speaker 0: The wonderful thing is there's this slash dot article I'm linking to where people are all.
Speaker 0: should we worry?
Speaker 0: Is this gonna break the internet?
Speaker 0: and I'm gonna answer all those questions one.
Speaker 0: Should we worry?
Speaker 0: No, it only hurts people who suck - will it break the internet?
Speaker 0: No, in fact, it'll make the internet better because if you link to it with a tiny URL probably wasn't worth linking to.
Speaker 0: yeah Three and this is my favorite thing.
Speaker 0: a lot of people on slash dot and other places discussing this Effectively made this point that I see coming up a lot all the time on the internet and it's always always made by high school kids or Freshman IT CS people where they'll say oh well
Speaker 1: tiny
Speaker 0: URL blah DNS broken blah DNS bad blah DNS last legs blah something something DNS Obsolete.
Speaker 1: people don't understand the DNS like the open DNS guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah DNS is just fine and even worse is the.
Speaker 0: the one argument I saw that it was infuriating and I had to resist the urge To type furiously at this person was well, maybe we didn't use all these so-called content management systems that make Indecipherable URLs.
Speaker 0: now I don't know.
Speaker 0: for some reason a URL that includes the date of the post or the title of the post isn't so Indecipherable to me.
Speaker 1: I think the problem is is that a lot of the context but content management systems Right are built on top, you know, people are running these things on Apache and it's it's quite difficult to you Know you need an HD access file.
Speaker 1: You need to do extra work to get clean URLs on You know with an Apache web server Because one I mean unless you're doing something clever with the URL like delicious or the.
Speaker 0: all those sites.
Speaker 0: All the web 2.0 slash something does something for you.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm People don't need to know the URLs of specific things.
Speaker 0: DNS you only need to know the top page.
Speaker 0: if you ever want to go deeper than the top of something.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you bookmark it?
Speaker 0: Maybe you're following a link.
Speaker 0: No one calls you and says hey, man You should go to devour ag org slash blog.
Speaker 0: They said they will one.
Speaker 0: you shouldn't call someone.
Speaker 0: tell them URL anyway.
Speaker 1: Yep, you just email them.
Speaker 1: send my link.
Speaker 1: if they're on the internet and they can go to the link You can email or I am it to them or they'll see it in a forum or something.
Speaker 0: Yep, podcasters and fury me with this as well since a lot of podcasters will be like they'll mention something in the show And they say oh, yeah, I go to tiny URL something now Why not just put the link in your show notes?
Speaker 0: because if they if the person listening can get to the internet To follow that tiny URL that you just told him they can get to your website.
Speaker 1: And if they're good, there's more likely that they're going to remember the website of the podcast They listen to often than it is.
Speaker 1: they're going to remember the URL that was said in the middle of a podcast That they listen to often.
Speaker 0: So yeah Tiny URL is kind of dumb and I guess it was useful for like a span of six or seven months Back before email and I am kind of evolved to being working as opposed to not working.
Speaker 0: But they didn't really exist back then.
Speaker 0: so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's never been a use.
Speaker 1: No, tiny URL bad useless stupid if anyone can think of actually legitimate use for it.
Speaker 1: I'd like to hear that I defy you to give me a legitimate use of tiny URL and You know pretty much the only thing you're gonna come up with is makeup for user and confidence.
Speaker 1: Okay, so there was another story on slash.
Speaker 0: that Another story on slash.
Speaker 1: when it when it's slow tech news Slash that is the only place you can go because they are the only people who have somewhat real tech news every day.
Speaker 0: Not only that but it updates on a set like it just updates on this regular like tick tick tick.
Speaker 0: It's not a precise tick like every 1.8 hours.
Speaker 0: There's a story but you know Especially from people like us back when slash dot was the only real game in town if you're bored sitting somewhere You know how much time has gone by and you think well, it's about time for a new slash dot story.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So there's a story on slash that says the fat.
Speaker 1: it's called the fastest processor You can't run.
Speaker 1: and basically what they're talking about is like Oh, man's AMD put out this Barcelona chip and Intel is trying to push it out of the news by releasing the Intel core 2 extreme ship.
Speaker 1: that's crazy fast and it's $1,200.
Speaker 1: but it's stupid because you can't even use the Intel core 2 extreme shit because it won't work in any motherboard.
Speaker 1: And that way.
Speaker 1: that's what the story on slash that is saying.
Speaker 1: the first thing I have to say is That the story is wrong.
Speaker 1: You can get a motherboard that can hold that chip.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at one a new egg right now.
Speaker 1: Let's see aces p5e3 deluxe.
Speaker 1: Oh look front side bus 1600 megahertz.
Speaker 1: What was this chip again?
Speaker 1: 1600 megahertz front side bus.
Speaker 1: there on the slash start article It says the fat.
Speaker 1: blah blah blah the lack of any motherboards that support a 1600 megahertz at front side bus.
Speaker 1: a new egg 1600 megahertz front side bus.
Speaker 0: Well was that statement made in the submission or by some editor in the submission?
Speaker 0: Oh Outstanding.
Speaker 0: Yeah, remember how I laughed?
Speaker 0: Yeah double that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the other thing.
Speaker 1: I got to say this because this is alright while in this particular instance This chip is actually runnable on a ludicrously expensive motherboard.
Speaker 1: It's a ludicrously expensive chip that you should not buy.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying anyone should buy this.
Speaker 1: do not do that.
Speaker 1: Unless I guess if you win the lottery and you're a nerd you might want to buy this.
Speaker 1: but that's about it.
Speaker 1: anyway people have been selling Unusable computer parts at ludicrously high prices for a long time.
Speaker 1: specifically or most of all is memory.
Speaker 1: I go on new egg right now and let's see Patriot.
Speaker 1: memory is selling the Patriot extreme Performance two times one.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: How many X's are in the name extreme one?
Speaker 1: Yes, it's actually spelled correctly.
Speaker 0: Oh They're selling to one less thing to make fun of.
Speaker 1: they're selling to one gig sticks of DDR 3 1866 RAM, which is PC 3 15,000. ha ha ha it runs.
Speaker 1: get this Faster than a 1600 megahertz bus.
Speaker 1: this RAM goes faster than any motherboard can handle.
Speaker 1: oh And by the way, this motherboard that can handle a 1600 megahertz bus only does that with you know the overclocking Huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah, huh?
Speaker 1: So Like it's officially supported overclocking, you know, so this motherboard can handle DDR 1800 memory but this is DDR 1866 memory and It caused ludicrous amounts of money and it's completely useless.
Speaker 1: I don't understand who buys these sticks of RAM that are faster than any motherboard can handle.
Speaker 1: It's like on the same website on new egg comm.
Speaker 1: they are selling a stick of RAM That is faster than any motherboard on new egg comm can use.
Speaker 1: I Don't understand it.
Speaker 1: It's just crazy Stupid nerdy people who they just like to have.
Speaker 1: you know The best computer because it means they've a bigger penis or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've just I've always bought kind of.
Speaker 0: you know, there's the curve of diminishing returns or you know Dollars per unit awesome and you know It comes up like a hump and then it goes back down in terms of how worth it Actually is and right before it peaks is right where you want to be.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know the.
Speaker 1: What are the people thinking?
Speaker 1: who are buying the stuff that's ludicrously expensive and marginally faster or not faster You know what?
Speaker 0: They're thinking they're thinking well with this computer if I turn off half the settings I might be able to play crisis Things of the day.
Speaker 0: So last week I kind of said that I wanted to you know only do awesome stuff that isn't already on the top of dig and already on the top all those sites.
Speaker 0: and That's kind of hard to do because even if something isn't on those sites It will be long before I get to talk about it tonight.
Speaker 1: not only that but think about how much time it would take you to Dig the pun not intended through all the you know What video sites and stuff to find a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: actually my secret what I really need to find an obscure thing of the day has been pretty much to go to the Hot sites of yesteryear that for some reason still exist and they post stuff that's so old or so out there That no one knows about it and no one who reads dig goes to those sites anymore.
Speaker 0: I mean if you ever really want to find something obscure just go around through meme pool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean before dig back in the olden day there were other sites that would collect links to cool stuff And BB spot mostly yes sites like that.
Speaker 1: So if you're looking for things of the day that you know are not elsewhere That's that's the business,
Speaker 0: but I'm gonna try a different tack now with my things of the day Instead of trying to find things you haven't seen no matter what and then telling you to watch them I feel like I'll just talk about the best thing I've seen which you probably have seen.
Speaker 0: if you go to dig I don't know every couple of weeks because it doesn't update so frequently anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, the videos don't anyway the only part I care about now.
Speaker 0: Yep, but um, well, I'll go back to a whole commentary where I assume you've already seen it.
Speaker 0: now you can hear my thoughts on it.
Speaker 0: and What better to start with than one of my new favorite music videos Knights of Cydonia?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So Knights of Cydonia is a song in guitar hero 3 and I really like the song.
Speaker 1: Yeah I was playing through all the songs in guitar hero 3 and I knew most of them because they're legends of rock but this is One that I did not know and liked a great deal.
Speaker 1: Well is what I was looking for?
Speaker 0: sadly guitar hero 2 a lot more of those than three does as Gojo and Lara proved to us by showing it to us at their party.
Speaker 0: the music video to this.
Speaker 0: now This isn't some like fan made a music video.
Speaker 0: This is the music video Let's see kung fu Western unicorn laser guns robots.
Speaker 0: It's up my alley.
Speaker 0: The only thing I can say though.
Speaker 0: The only bad thing.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it's good in a way.
Speaker 0: I found out who stole my mustache.
Speaker 0: I Mean his isn't quite as majestic as mine was.
Speaker 0: it's a little bit raggedy But at the same time describe your former mustache is majestic.
Speaker 0: I got one picture where it's quite majestic the one where I'm wearing that tiara.
Speaker 0: It's not in that picture that mustache is majestic.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: it only became non majestic when it started rolled around the side and became more of a molest ash Instead of a mustache.
Speaker 0: It was always a molest Is either molest ash or a Hitler's - what it was only a Hitler's - when I finally shaved it off and I'd never.
Speaker 0: I'd never shaved my must my nose where mustache goes my entire life.
Speaker 0: when I finally shaved it the first time Of course, I shaved a Hitler's - yeah, and then you shaved her as well.
Speaker 0: I I wore the Hitler's - for like four hours and my landlady came in and said She she looked like she was about to act like she was offended and she was about to say something Like what but she cracked up before she could.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: Alright, I feel bad that Hitler ruined that.
Speaker 0: yeah, it used to be the chaplain.
Speaker 1: He ruined a lot of things.
Speaker 1: like the swastika was okay before Hitler.
Speaker 0: Yeah now people freak out about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even the backwards one.
Speaker 1: Well, you know It's like anyway You know anyone who you can you anything can be misused and demonized.
Speaker 1: that anything that some bad things can also be glorified and made I guess to appear good.
Speaker 0: Yeah aggressive and militaristic Germany Hitler got rid of that.
Speaker 0: No one will stand for that anymore.
Speaker 1: The real thing that's bad is what you know, swastikas and Hitler mustache is symbolized not the things themselves not these symbols.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean like.
Speaker 1: even if Christianity is bad the cross is just a cross.
Speaker 1: It's not hurting anybody It's just a crime.
Speaker 0: Well, I believe The exact Unless they're using it on you in the prescribed manner.
Speaker 1: Right, you know, I can't do my thing Dana.
Speaker 0: No, so this video is Excellent most excellent, it's pretty excellent.
Speaker 0: And this is the kind of thing that's up my alley and I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 1: Wow, it's a great commentary.
Speaker 0: All right, what else can I say?
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: If you disagree with me, you're not awesome All right, so, you know the Mona Lisa, right?
Speaker 0: Some paintings some famous guy did it baby something like that, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, you know people like me you're not so knowledgeable in the ways of the arts.
Speaker 1: knowledgeable is computers not so much the arts.
Speaker 1: So I know the Mona Lisa is all great and important and whatever.
Speaker 0: Well, it's really hard to get arts installed and working properly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know I did freaking conflicts and viruses whatever.
Speaker 1: but so is a cool video I found on the YouTube.
Speaker 1: I might have found it on dig.
Speaker 1: I don't remember and it's basically called Mona Lisa.
Speaker 1: Why so famous?
Speaker 1: and this guy explains to.
Speaker 1: he puts a picture of the Mona Lisa up there And he explains to you in as much detail as any common person should know Why it's important and why it's awesome.
Speaker 1: and it I guess now after seeing this video the Mona Lisa is more awesome to me than it was before and If you ever wanted to know you could go watch this video.
Speaker 1: It's like five minutes.
Speaker 1: It won't hurt you and you guys look at the Mona Lisa, which is nice looking.
Speaker 0: Is it just?
Speaker 0: I haven't watched you yet.
Speaker 0: Is it just one shot of the Mona Lisa?
Speaker 0: Does he pay?
Speaker 1: No, like he's moving the camera around and he's like drawing easy, you know superimposing things on it to demonstrate things.
Speaker 0: and well I can just imagine that he's drawing on it like Much like the most recent Perry Bible Fellowship.
Speaker 1: No, he's superimposing on you know, an image of the Mona Lisa to demonstrate why it's superimposed.
Speaker 1: And you know, he has other imagery he uses to explain why it's so awesome and important and everything.
Speaker 0: I'll probably watch it before I go to bed tonight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well go downstairs and watch it after the show cuz I want to see it again - I guess Re-instill some of the ideas in my brain.
Speaker 0: That's why I really want to see what that Van Gogh movie that's coming out.
Speaker 1: This is a Van Gogh movie.
Speaker 0: Not the Van Gogh movie the DeGoya movie.
Speaker 1: I don't know who DeGoya is.
Speaker 0: You can see how much we know as Emily just corrected me.
Speaker 0: But yeah all I remembered was I saw a preview for a movie that was said a long time ago and involved guns in Spain and art and religion and Historical drama which is also up my alley almost as much as Cydonian Nights and their mustaches.
Speaker 1: All right, Netflix Q it is I don't know.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to see that in the theater, right?
Speaker 0: So speaking of seeing things in the theater Google Google Google.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Good night.
Speaker 1: So we needed some show ideas and we came up and Emily actually we sat down.
Speaker 0: We're like, what are we gonna talk about this week?
Speaker 0: Cuz we're only doing three shows this week.
Speaker 0: hate to break it to you.
Speaker 0: But in America, there's this holiday called eat until you feel sick and that's Thursday.
Speaker 1: So no show Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless you want the eat until you feel sick Yeah, you know you're gonna hear.
Speaker 0: you're gonna hear.
Speaker 0: I wish I hadn't ate so much.
Speaker 1: You're gonna hear Turkey leg in football.
Speaker 0: I Get to watch the Lions lose.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I get to you know, you know, you know happen on Sunday?
Speaker 0: Did the Lions lose to the Giants?
Speaker 0: Oh, man I never said that I'm a fan of the Lions.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter my city I don't root for the Lions.
Speaker 0: The Lions are nothing more than a Thanksgiving tradition in my family where we watch them wear their old-ass uniforms.
Speaker 1: They're actually, you know did in all seriousness.
Speaker 1: They're actually better this year than they've been in like a zillion years.
Speaker 1: They're not great.
Speaker 1: They're not win the Super Bowl or anything, but they're better than they've been in a long time.
Speaker 1: So you might see them win on Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: that that would ruin a tradition of my.
Speaker 1: I don't know who they're playing.
Speaker 1: It does matter.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna win.
Speaker 0: It's Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: I've seen them be up by like 30 and then lose it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it happens, but they might anyway, uh, wow.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: The geeks are talking about football.
Speaker 0: Okay, so we were trying to come up with ideas and the original idea was good But we spawned that off into like a bunch of shows to do later, but we could just talk about Google.
Speaker 0: We realized we've never talked about Google straight up in terms of you know What it is really where it really came from why it's awesome Why all those SEO people can die in a fire, but at the same time why Google is awesome?
Speaker 1: because they always thwart them Mm-hmm, but then I said hey Why don't we do a show about what it was like before Google?
Speaker 1: and then people fully understand why Google is awesome now.
Speaker 0: We have talked about this often in the past, but I don't think we've done an actual show about it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So maybe we should all right, so oh by the way Detroit's gonna is playing Green Bay on Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: so uh, yeah, they're gonna lose.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay, but they're gonna eat like a 13 legged turkey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe 1230 on Fox.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, you know back in the day the internet was a collection of you know, 14 to 16 things Mm-hmm, and that was pretty much it.
Speaker 1: Well, are you talking about the web or the Internet?
Speaker 1: because the Internet was like well, you know what different things.
Speaker 0: It's true for both because originally the Internet was a very small number of computers that could talk to each other That's true.
Speaker 0: And then they added stuff to it.
Speaker 0: And then there was the way I mean.
Speaker 0: I guess we should really talk about what the web is.
Speaker 0: briefly I mean people always a lot of people use the web or the world wide web to be synonymous with the internet and that is Absolutely, not true.
Speaker 0: The web is just if nothing else the easiest most obvious most well-known thing that the internet is used for.
Speaker 0: The web came long after the internet.
Speaker 0: the web was newfangled.
Speaker 0: for a long time the web evolved.
Speaker 0: the web used to not have pictures.
Speaker 1: Yep The internet is a bunch of computers connected to each other on a network and they can send data to each other in in many ways and They're they you can do.
Speaker 1: you can have all sorts of different methods of sending data.
Speaker 1: I mean I could connect from one computer to another computer with SSH.
Speaker 1: I do it every day.
Speaker 1: I can connect from one computer another computer with IRC protocol.
Speaker 1: I don't do that very often at all.
Speaker 0: Gopher!
Speaker 0: I could use gopher.
Speaker 1: You could use gopher.
Speaker 0: I did use gopher.
Speaker 1: You could use Telnet you could use shoutcast.
Speaker 1: You can use all sorts of different protocols.
Speaker 0: RSH.
Speaker 1: Yeah all sorts of things and HTTP is just one of those things.
Speaker 1: However, HTTP which is the hypertext transfer protocol Which in my age is the web which basically will send usually HTML which is an SGML.
Speaker 1: Yes HTML is hypertext markup language.
Speaker 1: So HTTP is a transfer protocol for the transfer of HTML.
Speaker 1: So basically the web is.
Speaker 1: there are servers and you go to the server and with HTTP There are pretty much three things that there used to be more things that you could do with HTTP like put.
Speaker 1: But nowadays all you can really do is get and post.
Speaker 1: Get says give me that page.
Speaker 1: So you go to a web server and you say get and the web server And the web server sends you the HTML.
Speaker 1: so when you type in google.com Your web browser sends packets to Google.
Speaker 1: that says get and then Google sends you Google.com the front page in HTML format and then your browser goes get get get get get to get the pictures and then loads the Pictures and that's it.
Speaker 0: So and also the only other thing I really say is that www the acronym stands for the World Wide Web, but www.something does not mean you're on the web.
Speaker 0: that www is the name of the computer that is called www that is at the rest of that URL.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just so happens that people often name computers with web servers running on them www because it kind of makes sense, don't you think?
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe so take that Godot.
Speaker 0: Who wouldn't listen to me and argued with me on Gmail for a while about that and not the Phoenix Wright guy?
Speaker 0: No, not the awesome guy Who's also awesome, but loses points for arguing with me about an IT issue when he's a juggler.
Speaker 0: Also, why does he have time to argue with me?
Speaker 0: I I was just some guy on the internet and yet he just kept responding because he makes his living Juggling at once a night.
Speaker 1: He doesn't do anything all day.
Speaker 1: He has time to bike the Tour de France on a stationary bicycle in his house.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, I forgot about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I remember Penn Jillette used to have a podcast.
Speaker 0: It was kind of good.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, so forget all that the web.
Speaker 0: How do you find stuff on the web?
Speaker 0: I mean back in the day You could go to the bookstore and this was before I even had access to the internet.
Speaker 0: This is back when I had prodigy but there was an internet that I theoretically could have gotten to though I didn't know how you could buy yellow pages of the internet that pretty.
Speaker 0: they were in the bookstore and they had Pretty much every website in the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean there weren't that many of them only so many people had the ability to set up a web sir and the knowledge to Set up a working web server get it connected and keep it running properly you might say in the world.
Speaker 0: What about the rest of the world outside of the US?
Speaker 0: There really was no internet to speak of at least not like it is today.
Speaker 1: Was made in the US and it's still.
Speaker 1: most of it is in the u.s.
Speaker 1: U.s.
Speaker 1: Now it's spread out.
Speaker 0: the u.s Invented it.
Speaker 0: the u.s.
Speaker 0: Has the majority of its infrastructure.
Speaker 0: the u.s Has the majority of the control over it and I don't see that changing anytime soon.
Speaker 0: No, not really but back then I mean it was just.
Speaker 0: There were very few things that weren't just websites in English and you could go buy a book and you could search for Games.
Speaker 0: and under games you find like six URLs and they were all there and they didn't change.
Speaker 1: Yep, cuz I mean people who did set up a web server.
Speaker 1: I mean there wasn't that much advanced stuff you could do.
Speaker 1: you could pretty much set up static pages that didn't change.
Speaker 1: not like you Know you go to Amazon you can reload the page and it's different because it's a computer is automatically Generating that HTML based on data in a database and other information.
Speaker 1: They didn't have that technology originally.
Speaker 1: It was just someone made a web page and put it there.
Speaker 1: so it was basically like that would be.
Speaker 1: it was easily the same as Downloading a Word document and reading it and that Word document never changed unless someone manually changed it with their hands.
Speaker 0: and remember in the early Web, there weren't pictures There was nothing here.
Speaker 1: You were lucky if you had colors let alone pictures and of course escape 2.0 gold.
Speaker 0: I Don't know if this is gonna turn to an ossiligist fest for blink tags and and Java's.
Speaker 0: remember those early like chat boards that were in a website that just Basically, we're a web page that refreshed every 10 seconds with what everyone had posted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then crashed.
Speaker 0: Yeah I used to hang out in those things all the time.
Speaker 0: Geoshitties.
Speaker 0: All right, but I had a Geocities site, but based on me to stuff at least realm It was a ROM site.
Speaker 1: I was in Times Square Castle.
Speaker 0: I was in Times Square dungeon Mm far 8716 I don't remember.
Speaker 1: but anyway The point is is that there were web servers and you needed to know the URL of the web server.
Speaker 1: And if the web server had multiple pages You needed to know the URL of those pages and it was.
Speaker 1: there was no way to find this out and mean less someone told You or how would you know?
Speaker 1: How would you know the URL of something?
Speaker 0: I mean, so, you know how people got around the internet.
Speaker 0: there was there's a term that was used in the 90s And it's pretty much ceased to exist.
Speaker 0: It is not a thing that people do anymore.
Speaker 0: It's kind of this archaic terminology.
Speaker 0: You didn't just use the internet.
Speaker 0: people used to surf the web which been very specifically Go to a website.
Speaker 0: every website had a links page because that's how the internet was.
Speaker 0: and after you know, I'm looking at this web page and I'm bored with it.
Speaker 0: I'm done with it.
Speaker 0: I read it.
Speaker 0: What now internet like?
Speaker 0: click on links and it was usually a collection of things that were either related or Things that the person who made that web page thought himself or herself were interesting.
Speaker 0: So I'd go Oh bunnies I click on that and I'd read this page about bunnies for an hour and then I'd look down and say huh a link to a site on Military something something that sounds interesting.
Speaker 0: click and you just go website to website in a line.
Speaker 0: There were no tabs.
Speaker 0: you could open multiple windows, but Good luck with that with your 16 megabytes of RAM About three windows before it crashed if your dialogue didn't go first.
Speaker 1: Yep In addition to that people eventually made web rings.
Speaker 1: now what a web ring was?
Speaker 0: is you a collection of broken links?
Speaker 1: Basically, you would let's say I was I made a website about video games.
Speaker 1: I would go and I would find a web ring for video game websites and I would paste this code on my website and That so on my website to be this giant block of HTML like this big table and it would say video game web ring.
Speaker 1: click here.
Speaker 1: and basically, what it would do is Everyone else who joined that web ring would have this web ring thing on their site and you would click next on the web ring And we take you to the next site in the ring.
Speaker 0: Yep Next previous or random or you can look at the list but the list never worked on any of those stupid things.
Speaker 1: yeah, most of the sites were broken, but you could go around and go to every website of People who had joined this particular web ring and the idea was that hey if our sites are similar We all put this thing on our site.
Speaker 1: anyone who comes to any one of our sites will go to all of our sites.
Speaker 1: But I keep clicking next next next next next.
Speaker 1: I Put web rings on my old Geo city site for a while.
Speaker 1: I never went through a web ring.
Speaker 0: I went through web rings all the time partly because I wanted to find out stuff about anime.
Speaker 0: So I went on all these anime web rings and I download picture galleries that I didn't do the anime until I find like a MIDI File of the opening theme to Tenchi and that was hot shit.
Speaker 1: Yep now also in this day Eventually there came like there was.
Speaker 1: what was that called link exchange?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah exchange was basically like the beginning of banner ads.
Speaker 1: what you did is you went to link exchange and you made a banner in MS Paint or whatever.
Speaker 1: you uploaded it and you put your URL in there and Then you would put this link exchange thing on your site and whenever anyone visited your site It would randomly select an image to show in the link exchange banner.
Speaker 1: It would be a random banner and the ideal was if you allowed a random banner to show up on your site every time someone visited then your banner would randomly show up on other people's websites and Hopefully someone would clink on the click on that random banner and end up at some other websites
Speaker 0: or they'd clink after the modem died.
Speaker 1: But yes but basically the point was There were people were trying to get more links to URLs on the web because it was impossible to find anything any other way.
Speaker 0: Now I do want to point out something.
Speaker 0: I don't want to go into detail about this.
Speaker 0: this is obviously a topic for another show, but Notice how nothing we've said generates revenue for jack all anyone.
Speaker 0: yet Not so much talk about ads or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Look the only.
Speaker 1: where's some ads going on?
Speaker 0: many.
Speaker 0: But look the only thing we're talking about here that was close to an ad was this kind of open Free thing that people mutually used to try to help each other out.
Speaker 0: No one made money off of that.
Speaker 1: I think you could pay the link exchange.
Speaker 0: eventually at one point It all became about money but much of the web was pretty much just people posting interesting things and linking to other interesting things.
Speaker 0: There weren't pop-ups yet.
Speaker 1: No, not yet.
Speaker 1: Not yet.
Speaker 0: Anyway, no one had even thought what if I made a pop-up?
Speaker 1: I wasn't.
Speaker 1: it's like an escape three or four that says stuff was going on.
Speaker 0: Those were dark times because there's no way out.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's popovers.
Speaker 1: so the next thing that happened was Yahoo came about and Yahoo was a big deal because Yahoo was one website that you could go to And they had so many links to other websites and most of them were good and not broken.
Speaker 1: It was amazing.
Speaker 1: and the way Yahoo worked originally was you would submit a website to Yahoo with a description And everything.
Speaker 1: you had to fill out this form and people at Yahoo would manually look at that site Decide if it was good enough to be on Yahoo and if it was they would add it to Yahoo in the appropriate category.
Speaker 1: So when you're looking for gaming sites Gaming area on.
Speaker 1: Yahoo had like 50 links to different gaming websites and that was a big deal Especially when like new links showed up there you'd be like all man's.
Speaker 0: so up and the internet started getting bigger.
Speaker 0: There were more things around.
Speaker 0: things started changing moving.
Speaker 0: Suddenly pretty much every link on Yahoo was broken Yeah, and and new sites appeared far faster than they could keep up.
Speaker 0: Yahoo became nothing.
Speaker 0: it just became so useless pretty much.
Speaker 1: It was like for a time you would use Yahoo and then after a while you would go there to be nothing new for you at all.
Speaker 0: and You just like oh, but at the same time it didn't matter that much because internet culture was different.
Speaker 0: back then I would have a list of like 20 or 30 sites that I hung out at.
Speaker 0: Those were the sites that I went back to.
Speaker 0: I went to websites on purpose now.
Speaker 0: I just go to content aggregators.
Speaker 1: Yep, all right, so then there was stuff like Alta Vista and web.
Speaker 0: Really fuzzy about the chronology because you don't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure we're saying things chronologically out of order But that doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: Well, what I'm saying is that there was kind of then this Power vacuum where suddenly there's no real.
Speaker 0: I mean you could use this Lycos thing which searched the internet in one way.
Speaker 0: I think their claim to fame was that we have more pages index than anyone else because we did by it was it was all About the number of pages you had.
Speaker 1: right because there were certain numbers of pages on the internet and the way people were making these Search engines that the primitive search engines was with crawlers and the crawler would visit one website Then visit every website that that website linked to and so on and so forth and it would keep track of every website It could see and try to make a giant database of every website.
Speaker 1: There was so that way, you know the more sites they had in their search engine because there weren't so many sites.
Speaker 1: I mean there was a lot of sites thousands upon thousands and thousands But there weren't so many that there would be something about everything, you know.
Speaker 1: So that the idea was that the more sites we have indexed if you search for something You're likely to find what you're looking for with our search engine because we have more sites in day.
Speaker 0: However, you couldn't find dick and the reason was computers weren't that fast back then and search algorithms weren't all great back then And no one had been done anything really clever.
Speaker 0: So most search I mean, how does a website that's gonna search determine whether or not this site about kittens or this site about kittens is better?
Speaker 0: The only metric most people could come up with back Then was the number of times the word kittens appeared on the website and
Speaker 1: people are doing things like they would say All right Everyone put these meta tags at the top of your page with the keywords that you want to be known for.
Speaker 0: So then other sites would weight those things really highly.
Speaker 0: like if I make a video game ROM site my meta tags were video games ROMs illegal where's?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and literally in those days you could make a website right and at the top of the website you could be like meta space Keywords equals video games video games video games video games video games video games video games, etc.
Speaker 1: Like a hundred times.
Speaker 0: and then do slash meta and then at the bottom your website You got a white background in white text.
Speaker 1: You have the word video games a million times Yep, and basically now any sir almost a bunch of search engines.
Speaker 1: if someone typed in video games your site would be on top And that was how it worked.
Speaker 0: and right about then is also when ad sites started really springing up and there was the whole Dark age of advertising on the internet that we could probably do a separate show about.
Speaker 1: probably let's not talk about the advertiser no, let's talk about the searching right and The search engines were largely useless.
Speaker 1: and the worst thing about the search engines was that you would search for something and even if it Looked like a good link showed up link would be broken.
Speaker 1: It would just be you click and it would take you nowhere before or for.
Speaker 0: search engines were not Intelligent.
Speaker 0: if you type cats and the best cat site in the world had cats in it But never said the word cat you're not gonna find it.
Speaker 0: Nope, and Also, you really had to know your logic.
Speaker 0: A lot of people didn't realize that you know you this and this or this.
Speaker 0: you had to really.
Speaker 0: It was kind of an art and a science to craft a search that would find what you want What you wanted.
Speaker 0: you would never find it.
Speaker 1: Yeah The way you searched was a lot like the way you searched on the original CD-ROM encyclopedias.
Speaker 1: you had to say I want websites that have cats not pets.
Speaker 1: Yes Eating and try to find out like what wild like.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: maybe if you're trying to find out like what what?
Speaker 1: cats eat as opposed to what pet cats eat something like that.
Speaker 0: and of course in addition to all that this was right about the era where a Good quarter of the time any link you clicked on was actually pornography.
Speaker 0: unexpectedly All sorts of crazy porn out there and it was low-resolution Pornography - but porn would just pop up all the time no matter where you went.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like whenever I searched I had a club text thing open and anytime I search I type my search terms.
Speaker 0: They're like plus kittens plus kibble and then I'd paste Minus sex minus porn minus xxxx minus hot girls minus a million things to try and see a little bit less porn.
Speaker 0: Well, I searched for kittens and kibble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was how it was and all the way all the searches were kind of Eventually, I think Alta Vista was probably the best one.
Speaker 0: I don't
Speaker 1: know that but like you'd come up with a search and you would try it at all the different search engines because they'd All give you completely different results and maybe you'd get lucky
Speaker 0: And even then you'd have to dig down you'd pretty much assumed that the top four pages were useless and I'd be going to like the 80th page of links and Lycos and Yeah, and Alta Vista was pretty much the best of them and all the I guess geeky smart people tended to use Alta Vista.
Speaker 0: Failing that they use Yahoo pretty much or Lycos.
Speaker 0: the Lycos turned into a porn crawler web crawler.
Speaker 1: There was hot spot that right.
Speaker 1: There's all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: and then people made things like I think dogpile is the one people knew best where all it did was Submit your search to all the search engines I thought and it would search through those results.
Speaker 1: a dogpile is still around and there are many.
Speaker 1: there were.
Speaker 1: there were many sites like dogpile back in the day.
Speaker 1: So then eventually right Yahoo started getting a lot more users and it was actually they.
Speaker 1: you know They stopped doing the directory and it started doing search.
Speaker 0: Well, they still had the directory to decide the directory for a while But they remote.
Speaker 1: they were doing search.
Speaker 1: now real search and at first I think they'd had.
Speaker 1: the search was powered by the hotspot But later you would go to the bot.
Speaker 1: you would search on Yahoo because it was pretty much became the best.
Speaker 1: He would scroll to the bottom and it would say Yahoo powered by Google and I was you know You'd see that down there.
Speaker 1: You'd be like, okay There's some people named Google that are making Yahoo work and eventually people figured it out.
Speaker 1: They clicked on that word Google down there and it took him to Google and the internet was never the same not ever again.
Speaker 1: basically, Google was Always the same as it is now pretty much in terms of the search engine.
Speaker 1: It was a text box and a button with no shit in the way.
Speaker 1: pretty much I didn't what you wanted and you got what you want.
Speaker 0: anyone who?
Speaker 0: Went to Google and search for something.
Speaker 0: pretty much never used another search engine again.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean you typed in what you want and there was the best thing in the world right at the top every time.
Speaker 0: and I Think we'll end on that that and think of this as part one of a fair.
Speaker 1: You want to talk a little bit about why Google was that way?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to save that for the show about Google.
Speaker 0: Just talk about Google for the whole show.
Speaker 0: All right, you know why it's good why it's still good Why it was good.
Speaker 0: then how awesome it is how much I like it.
Speaker 0: I want you to have its babies.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: I already had its babies.
Speaker 0: We can talk about the history of it Which is also kind of interesting and why it was called Google and what it was originally called.
Speaker 1: and I have to study my Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: You may may All right.
Speaker 1: So yeah Anyone who wasn't using the internet back in those days that we were you missed out on I guess stories and nostalgia.
Speaker 1: but consider yourself lucky and Such.
Speaker 0: and if anyone complains about Google There's nothing better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyone's complaining about the state of the internet?
Speaker 1: now Welcome to my 1998 time machine.
Speaker 1: Let me show you a world.
Speaker 1: you are taking for granted what you have now, so shut up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to see what the internet was like back then?
Speaker 0: We'll go.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of other countries like the wayback machine.
Speaker 1: Yeah God Go to the wayback machine which lets you look at websites that are old and go look at like Yahoo from like the late 90s.
Speaker 0: or even just go to a lot of websites outside of the United States and Europe and they look a lot like the internet did in 1995.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're there.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: yeah, go to myspace.
Speaker 1: It looks like 1999.
Speaker 0: See that's the scariest thing.
Speaker 0: myspace is like this Antediluvian hold back.
Speaker 0: it's like the internet evolved and myspace just went back for the roots of the ancient.
Speaker 0: It's a trilobite in the sea of modern sharks, but I like travel bites, but only myspace.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio Feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.