Speaker 0: It's Christmas Eve 2007.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nides.
Speaker 0: tonight in the Christmas spirit We talk about time synchronization among disparate computer clocks.
Speaker 0: Let's do this So 4 a.m.
Speaker 1: Oh The time when the worst things in the universe can possibly happen.
Speaker 0: We'll probably link to it But there was this TED talk about how 4 a.m.
Speaker 0: Is pretty much the worst possible time in the world.
Speaker 0: And I kind of agree because you know I think about it, and if I if I wake up if I stay up until one two Three o'clock, it's awesome.
Speaker 0: It's man.
Speaker 0: I stayed up till three o'clock last night.
Speaker 1: I don't know I. actually my feeling is more that like three or three thirty is like the worst time.
Speaker 1: like Four is like people are almost gonna.
Speaker 1: Maybe wake up if they're.
Speaker 0: That's the worst thing cuz I have a crazy early job.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 1: I wake up at 445 Yeah, but like three three is like you should have been in bed now and no one's waking up now.
Speaker 1: It's like that time when you know the highest percentage should be sleeping And that's why I think three is the worst and not four.
Speaker 0: but apparently art people in art and literature think four is the worst And I agree with them because I remember we were in college And we'd stay up like I used to go to bed around midnight.
Speaker 0: Ish when I was in high school that just seemed like That was as late as you stayed up and staying up later than that was always kind of silly I mean.
Speaker 0: granted I could sleep in class, so it's not like I had to worry.
Speaker 0: But at the same time just I didn't stay up later than that.
Speaker 0: and then in college You know we all hung out and every night as we were hanging out We'd end up staying up later and later and later, and oh man.
Speaker 0: It's one o'clock.
Speaker 0: and then a few months later oh, man, it's two o'clock and then two o'clock felt like one o'clock used to and Right around when we hit 3 a.m.. It was like all right.
Speaker 0: That's the end of this.
Speaker 1: That's what I say.
Speaker 1: cuz three is the worst three.
Speaker 0: No three is the worst.
Speaker 0: three is the limit.
Speaker 0: staying up until three in the morning is The end point where staying up that late could have been something awesome.
Speaker 1: no for me now.
Speaker 1: It's like 2 a.m.. It's like all right I'm going to bed.
Speaker 1: if I go to bed late It's gotta be somebody at time between two and three.
Speaker 1: if it's three.
Speaker 1: It's it's over.
Speaker 0: That's just because you're an old man was yeah I'm sure you see if you stood.
Speaker 0: it is possible where if you stayed up until 3 a.m.. Doing something That you had an awesome night if you stayed up until 4 a.m.. Doing something you had a shitty night.
Speaker 0: odds Are I think it's a statistical correlation things that keep you up?
Speaker 0: Until 3 a.m.. Are less likely to be shitty than things that keep you up till 4 a.m I still think the worst time is sometime around 3 30.
Speaker 0: Now cuz that's leading up to it 3 30 is when you go to sleep after staying up till 3 a.m.. No Anyway, but so at 4 a.m.. This morning 45 minutes before I wake up to go to work.
Speaker 0: I'm awakened to the sound of and my brain is also awakened horribly.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: you never had that situation where you wake up and your brain isn't quite sure what the hell's going on like.
Speaker 1: I was quite Sure, what was going on almost immediately now?
Speaker 0: I was too after about five seconds, but only because I'd been primed by events prior.
Speaker 0: oh But you know sometimes you wake up to an unexpected stimulus like you're laying in bed, and you hear Something and you think it's your alarm clock, but no it's your cell phone, so you're hitting your alarm clock And it doesn't turn off and then you realize it's your phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's happened a few times, so I'm laying there in bed going.
Speaker 0: What's that noise?
Speaker 0: Why can't I read my alarm clock?
Speaker 0: It's it's not on where to go and then wait a minute.
Speaker 0: power outage UPS.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I crawl out of bed, and I sit in the air on and I try to turn on my monitor.
Speaker 1: Why won't it turn out?
Speaker 0: Oh wait?
Speaker 0: I only plug the computer into the UPS cuz I don't plan for the power going out out.
Speaker 0: I plan for the power blipping like when the air conditioning comes on.
Speaker 0: yep Because we're very geeky and a very non geeky house.
Speaker 0: There's like one circuit in this house.
Speaker 1: It's like three.
Speaker 0: Barely okay.
Speaker 0: if I vacuum downstairs the lights upstairs dim and my UPS goes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yep, so I just turn.
Speaker 0: I hit the power button on the front of my PC thinking all right I hope I told it to gracefully power off and not ungracefully power off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just freaking pushed all the buttons on all the UPS is to shut them up.
Speaker 0: I I at least gracefully powered down my PC.
Speaker 1: I really don't care.
Speaker 0: I did a little bit because I already corrupted my NTFS partition with this these shenanigans earlier.
Speaker 1: You see that's shitty ass NTFS.
Speaker 1: What can you expect?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it all started?
Speaker 0: You know we got this mixer, and I'm setting it up over the weekend.
Speaker 0: the new xenix.
Speaker 0: I'm all excited about it, and I'm twiddling knobs and going testing one two three testing one two three and then my computer crashed and I couldn't make it boot.
Speaker 0: and The only thing that had been happening at all recently were problems with UPS is.
Speaker 0: So I had taken my computer off the UPS to do full testing and I hadn't put it back on the UPS.
Speaker 0: And then the power went out a bunch of times and it fucked up my NTFS.
Speaker 0: Hey, I don't know why I was booted into Windows, but I don't know why either.
Speaker 0: I wasn't gonna play a steam game.
Speaker 0: I have time for that nope, but yeah yesterday.
Speaker 0: There was a a Thunderstorm in the winter.
Speaker 1: well it was snowing and then the snow stayed around It was cold, and then it rained way too much, and it winded way too much.
Speaker 1: And there's a little bit of thunder and lightning, but not much.
Speaker 0: see it only rained a little bit I wasn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't.
Speaker 0: oh no.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: It's raining.
Speaker 0: It was like.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's sprinkling and it's uncharacteristically warm kind of like last year's.
Speaker 0: we go grocery shopping and And Don't bring umbrellas Partly cuz the Internet's down unrelated to all that.
Speaker 0: so we couldn't check the weather other than to look outside.
Speaker 0: And I didn't expect a thunderstorm.
Speaker 1: No, but we got at the grocery store man.
Speaker 1: There was a lot of rain coming down.
Speaker 0: It was raining.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there were there a few like.
Speaker 1: there weren't power.
Speaker 1: I guess it was a power outage, but very short power outages like off on Off on.
Speaker 0: I think the best part is we're trying to play dune through all this.
Speaker 0: the power keeps going out And of course there's no flashlight anywhere near us.
Speaker 0: so the power is out And I stand up ready to hurt myself stumbling through the house looking for a flashlight.
Speaker 0: And the power came back on.
Speaker 0: so I found a flashlight.
Speaker 0: power goes out.
Speaker 0: I turn the light on look at the dune board.
Speaker 0: power comes back on.
Speaker 0: So we're sitting there and the power is on and we're just looking at each other and meanwhile my Harkonnen are poised to destroy The benna guesser hit.
Speaker 0: yeah great for the second time because the two-player game is broken.
Speaker 1: Super broken that two-player.
Speaker 0: You know the two-player dune game is.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you how it works.
Speaker 0: It's called the Harkonnen win.
Speaker 1: I don't know there's some other guys in there, but no one else has that much of a front game advantage.
Speaker 1: That's true, and it's it's very difficult for one person to hold them off.
Speaker 0: Yes, but uh so the power is on and we're sitting there is looking at each other with the fly.
Speaker 0: I have the flashlight in my hand and I turn the flashlight on and at that second the power goes back.
Speaker 0: yep, so I'm sitting there with a flashlight on and we're both thinking it's not Nintendo.
Speaker 0: logic dictates that if I turn this flashlight off the Power will come back on.
Speaker 0: and sure enough power came back on just as I turn the flashlight off.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm pretty sure that flashlight was controlling the power.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the power came back on and it stayed on and then we went to bed.
Speaker 1: and then at 4 a.m.
Speaker 1: I see thing.
Speaker 1: I recommend buying a UPS for your computers or whatever because if the power is not super awesome in your house You know then what's gonna happen is the power will go off on and your computer will go what the fuck and get screwed up.
Speaker 1: But you have a UPS.
Speaker 1: you'd be okay.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to get a big UPS because and not even to plug your monitor into it because if the power is going off for more than a blip you're fucked.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you're not gonna be home.
Speaker 0: You don't care.
Speaker 0: It's and also I know that when I was a kid I never had to deal with this because I all the power lines where I lived were underground and at RIT We never had to deal with it because we had a power substation on campus.
Speaker 0: The power went out like once and when it went out it went out for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but when I lived in Connecticut, the power lines weren't above ground and there wasn't a substation either But the power was much higher quality.
Speaker 1: So if it went out it was out and it was on.
Speaker 1: it was on.
Speaker 1: there.
Speaker 1: wasn't this like power dimming or you know Sort of sort of running out or turning off for a second?
Speaker 1: It was just.
Speaker 1: either it was working great or it was not working at all.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was a windy yesterday - Crazy windy kind of scarily windy like I'd be sitting here and the front door would suddenly be ripped open as hard as it could.
Speaker 0: bang bang bang bang bang bang bang bang bang bang.
Speaker 1: I hate that front door.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should probably fix it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, my guess is that all these power out, you know short power outages.
Speaker 1: I think the power guys went out to work on the on the wires or something And of course they chose 4 a.m.
Speaker 1: Because sure enough when that power went out see my clock was on the UPS.
Speaker 1: So while the UPS was screaming that the battery was in use the clock said 4 a.m Exactly, and I'm like, there's no way the power would go out at 4 a.m.
Speaker 1: Exactly the guys.
Speaker 1: there has to be guys working on it.
Speaker 0: well, the thing is I remember it was two years ago and I was here alone for some reason and I was sitting in my room and I see a bunch of flashing lights.
Speaker 0: I look outside and I see the power company and they're like they're doing something and then and they're over at the other end of the street and I see him up on the pole working and then they go further up the street to the next out pole and This is the pole that is but like the main pole for our street and they go up there and I'm thinking I sure hope They don't turn the power off on me and then immediately the power went off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was watching those guys and basically there's like on that one pole There's this switch and it's literally just like this lever.
Speaker 1: and they pulled the lever out with this big long wooden stick and they pulled Lever out and it turns the power off on the whole street.
Speaker 1: And then when they were done working, they plug the lever back in and I was like fuckers You're just controlling the whole power for the whole street here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not even warning us.
Speaker 0: now The best thing is powers out.
Speaker 0: I once I'm awake enough I realized to turn off my fucking UPS and go back to bed and I hear that Scott's done the same.
Speaker 0: But I still hear UPS going off.
Speaker 1: That was the the hallway one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz.
Speaker 0: then I thought oh, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: That's the UPS for the networking equipment.
Speaker 0: Hey Scott will deal with it.
Speaker 0: I went to sleep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had a hard time going to sleep after You.
Speaker 0: I had to be up in 45 minutes.
Speaker 1: Well, you should have stayed up.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: well, the best part is.
Speaker 0: then I get up and I go to the train but Holiday schedule.
Speaker 0: the train didn't come when I thought it was gonna come I knew it was a holiday schedule and then to make today just like extra awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm at work.
Speaker 1: There's like ten minutes before I'm gonna go home cuz I'm working a half day And of course another isn't because you had the train wasn't gonna come at the normal time.
Speaker 0: Well ten minutes before I catch that train like I'd planned it all.
Speaker 0: I didn't care.
Speaker 0: I took a long launch I dealt with it.
Speaker 0: Hey, and uh, I Fucked something up and something's crashed and I know it's a race against the clock to get this thing going before I can go home.
Speaker 0: That was awesome, yeah, yeah, I'll tell you this VMware ESX server not the most well documented thing.
Speaker 1: No, usually those proprietary things documentation can't be supposed to be like enterprise awesome Which means it's not.
Speaker 1: it's documented even less because they want you to pay them to take care of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like that time way back at IBM when I we had redhead enterprise support theoretically.
Speaker 0: So I called redhead to try to get some support and that didn't end.
Speaker 0: Well, nope Alright, that's enough of our personal lives.
Speaker 1: So yesterday I go to the grocery store right right when it was crazy raining.
Speaker 1: I needed some shampoo, so I bought some shampoo or what I thought was shampoo.
Speaker 1: So in the shower today, I tried to use it first shower in three days, you know, it's vacation and The shampoo doesn't shampoo like.
Speaker 1: I can't get it to go in my hair like it just won't move.
Speaker 0: it won't Water water if I you sure it was shampoo.
Speaker 1: No, when I look at the bottle it said condition.
Speaker 1: I was like fuck no one.
Speaker 0: I Contend that you might have been doing it wrong because conditioner goes into your hair easy.
Speaker 1: It didn't go into my hair very and easily at all.
Speaker 0: kind of conditioner you use it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: you try it and tell me if there's something wrong with it.
Speaker 0: Screw you.
Speaker 0: I use vo5.
Speaker 0: I'm not using that fructose BS.
Speaker 1: It smells like fruit.
Speaker 1: That's the reason I bought it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what my vo5 smells like lavender.
Speaker 0: That's bad.
Speaker 0: I like the smell of lavender.
Speaker 1: Well, see that's because you are a fruit.
Speaker 1: I just like to smell like fruit.
Speaker 0: I also have one.
Speaker 0: It's chamomile and lavender.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's even worse and I have that pomegranate Mango body wash.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's okay.
Speaker 1: That's fruit.
Speaker 0: I stopped using that though.
Speaker 1: You guys stopped using the fruit.
Speaker 0: Well, I got lavender Notes the trend bad.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I read the directions.
Speaker 1: I've never used conditioner on my life and nor did I want to put it in your hair rinse it out That's what I figured.
Speaker 1: and it says shampoo first then do it.
Speaker 1: So I'm like aha because I know sometimes when you shampoo two times the second shampooing is like much different, you know Because the oil is all out of your hair.
Speaker 1: So the chemical thing happens more easily.
Speaker 1: So I say okay So I take the last of my old shampoo and I shampoo and then I try to conditioner just to see how it goes.
Speaker 1: See if it's bullshit or not.
Speaker 1: conditioner Still a pain in the ass to get it in my hair.
Speaker 1: It just doesn't do its thing.
Speaker 0: I contend that you were doing it wrong.
Speaker 0: conditioner is a wonderful thing is not?
Speaker 1: it didn't work.
Speaker 0: So I'll tell you what.
Speaker 0: just to compare.
Speaker 0: cuz I don't want to put that fructose crap in my hair.
Speaker 0: You can try my nice conditioner once just a little bit.
Speaker 1: I don't know I'm not gonna smell like lavender.
Speaker 1: Fuck that.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with lavender?
Speaker 1: It's it sucks.
Speaker 1: It smells like shit.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah the conditioner still wouldn't go in my hair in any non Irritating way.
Speaker 1: so I rinsed it out and I was just and I went.
Speaker 1: I comb my hair.
Speaker 1: My hair was no different than it ever is.
Speaker 1: I'm like, it's fucked shit.
Speaker 1: He's useless.
Speaker 1: He doesn't even do anything.
Speaker 0: Conditioner is usually meant for people with long hair so you can untangle it and such either way.
Speaker 1: I I got a bottle of conditioner if anyone wants it only used once and right times Right and I went to the store today and I bought some shampoo.
Speaker 1: That's actually shampoo.
Speaker 0: So to talk about technology a little bit.
Speaker 0: I Need a laptop.
Speaker 0: I've been needing one pretty much ever since I had money for seven years again.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't have money seven years ago since they existed and I didn't really need a laptop back then.
Speaker 0: I mean, you always needed one.
Speaker 0: You know it when I was at RIT one I could get a computer pretty much anywhere on campus that I needed.
Speaker 0: and if I really needed a laptop I could go to the library and just get a laptop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those weren't the yeah plus.
Speaker 0: remember when I worked for ITS they gave me that Gateway Awesome tablet.
Speaker 0: you barely used it because I didn't need a laptop.
Speaker 0: I had no reason to use it.
Speaker 1: I think you have a problem.
Speaker 0: I never really needed a laptop because anywhere I was gonna compute I had a computer and My commute was a car.
Speaker 0: So it's not like I was gonna use the laptop in the car.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: That's an awesome thing to do.
Speaker 1: cops do it and they shouldn't be should be.
Speaker 1: so, uh, they do better policing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So now that I have a train commute a full long train commute in the city And now that I need to do more geek nights work it and I have tons of money now It's time to get a laptop and I like Scott's laptop and I looked in.
Speaker 0: I can get Scott's laptop But a lot faster for about the same that he paid now a little faster.
Speaker 1: Well two cars instead of one Yeah, but that only helps you so much.
Speaker 1: It's not like it's double powerful.
Speaker 0: Well, it's double powerful if you do certain very specific things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but um, it's a good deal good price.
Speaker 0: I I was gonna buy it.
Speaker 0: I just decided screw it.
Speaker 0: I got money.
Speaker 0: I'm buying it right now.
Speaker 0: That's about when the pot with the internet went out So I didn't buy it.
Speaker 0: So now I'm looking at Fujitsu's new Possibly pen rain laptop.
Speaker 0: that's gonna come out in January.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's one of those who knows.
Speaker 1: Well, I kind of thing if it comes out.
Speaker 0: I'm getting this one instead.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you know that There's like Mac world, whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's soonish and you know There's all those rumors of 12 and 14 inch MacBooks and things which could also be pen rain possible.
Speaker 0: I know cuz this is I understand for the first time ever.
Speaker 0: what kind of person would ever be excited about when Apple is gonna announce something?
Speaker 0: because if You don't care or you already have an iPod.
Speaker 0: You don't need a new iPod.
Speaker 0: You don't need a new Apple thing you don't care.
Speaker 0: but I'm in the market for a laptop and I can see what Apple offers.
Speaker 0: but I know That if you're gonna buy an Apple thing You might as well wait until the next Apple thing comes out and then buy it.
Speaker 1: because the thing is we were most excited about That stuff.
Speaker 1: or people already have their Apple stuff and they just want to buy the newer one.
Speaker 0: See, I don't get that I don't get that but I am excited to have something that works.
Speaker 1: What do you need something else for?
Speaker 0: I am excited about the next Apple thing just because they might announce a product I want in which case I'll just buy it or they might not and if they don't I'll probably buy this laptop.
Speaker 0: And if they don't and this laptop is not what it appears to be or doesn't come out in time.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna buy Scott's laptop only with the dual core and with a little camera in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe hot pink.
Speaker 1: I don't think you want.
Speaker 1: the pink one doesn't come with a dual core.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't But it's pink.
Speaker 1: that's you can get.
Speaker 1: you can get that pink laptop and your lavender conditioner.
Speaker 0: now I'm gonna get the black laptop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right alright.
Speaker 1: So yeah In China, you know the people in China and the government and the giant communist bureaucracy of Sun.
Speaker 0: Oh, I know you're gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: you know about that right the the communist bureaucracy.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna talk about the fraud website?
Speaker 0: Maybe all right, let's go.
Speaker 1: basically they're corrupt as any giant bureaucracy of course has corruption.
Speaker 0: now I contend it is my personal opinion based on what little arguable knowledge I have about world affairs is that China is not the most corrupt in rapidly industrializing power in the world.
Speaker 0: I think that India's and Pakistan civil infrastructure are far more Talking about the amount relative to other countries.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about the absolute value.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of corruption Absolute value parentheses corruption Exactly.
Speaker 1: and China has of course a. What any corrupt giant behemoth bureaucracy does when there's a problem is create another bureau To uh to solve the problem.
Speaker 0: So someone else to bribe in the chain of bribery, right?
Speaker 1: So there's a. there's a National Bureau of corruption prevention the NBCP.
Speaker 0: I really want to work there, right?
Speaker 1: They were set up on September 13th, and the Minister of supervision is the head of it.
Speaker 1: His name is Ma Wen or maybe it's her name I don't know And the bureau has been entrusted to collect and analyze information from the banking land use medicine adult Telecommunication sectors among others and share with prosecuting organs courts and police.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So this NBCP set up a website where people can go and report corruption.
Speaker 1: ha in the government, huh yeah, and Let me first of all the news story.
Speaker 1: Is that so many people want to report corruption?
Speaker 1: the website broke down.
Speaker 1: The number of visitors is very large and beyond our expectations.
Speaker 1: he said.
Speaker 1: Okay, as of 4 p.m.
Speaker 1: Yesterday visitors had left 22 pages of messages in the guest book You know.
Speaker 1: while many of them referred to report specific cases of official corruption Those were redirected by the webmaster other sites such as ministry supervision.
Speaker 1: others made calls for the strengths of the government's anti-corruption efforts and Comments about the head for special attention be given to cases blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: the corruption problem in China is a fatal illness.
Speaker 1: Establishing more institutions will not solve the problem.
Speaker 1: one comment read ha I Just think that when you look at all the pieces of this story It like it comes together to be like so many from so many hilarious angles, you know, it's like there's corruption.
Speaker 0: So they make another government organization and then a bunch of people report corruption.
Speaker 1: In so much corruption people report to that government organization and the government nation.
Speaker 1: It's so clumsy bureaucracy.
Speaker 1: nous fails to get the website up because it's so corrupt and They think it's probably corrupt itself.
Speaker 1: Who knows it is just.
Speaker 1: it's just so terrible and it's the.
Speaker 1: I think this is the shining One greatest example that I've ever seen of what happens with a giant giant bureaucracy of corruptness.
Speaker 0: I guess that's why Soviet communism didn't do so.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's something else.
Speaker 1: I noticed about this.
Speaker 1: There's something I from looking at a bunch of different communism's, you know, Soviet Russia Cuba North Korea,
Speaker 0: right
Speaker 1: They all have something in common in that they try to build Great projects usually buildings or other pieces of infrastructure like bridges or things like that And they always seem to not finish them like in Cuba.
Speaker 1: There's some buildings that were like big and fancy buildings, but they are unfinished in Soviet Russia big fancy things unfinished.
Speaker 1: in North Korea They got the biggest baddest fanciest unfinished things you've ever seen and China.
Speaker 1: here you go this website sort of a big fancy unfinished thing and It seems like communism is like if you want to have a country full of big projects that don't get completed.
Speaker 1: But you know that if they were completed would be awesome.
Speaker 1: Communism's the best way to do that.
Speaker 1: as far as I can
Speaker 0: See I'm a big fan of public works and that sort of thing in infrastructural investments and I think the majority of Western history has shown that civilizations who invest in civil infrastructure tend to do better off in the long run as long as they don't invest in it to the detriment of other more important things
Speaker 1: Food.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe or maybe trying to invest in civil infrastructure when you don't have anything to invest in the first place That's also bad.
Speaker 0: imagine if the u.s.
Speaker 0: Invested in civil infrastructure on that scale.
Speaker 1: Haha, yeah, I don't want to have a bunch of unfinished buildings around it or like half bridges.
Speaker 0: We'd probably finish it all.
Speaker 0: but the thing is we'd pry of 70s syndrome where everything built in the 70s is ugly.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's true.
Speaker 0: Anyway, speaking of overly corrupt evil dictatorships and such.
Speaker 0: I'd like to talk a little bit about our friends in Australia Because Australia's government is really kind of I don't know eerie to me and I generally am afraid of how often Fascist they seem to be when it comes to it technology issues.
Speaker 1: It's so weird because Australia is like this totally backwards and forwards place simultaneously.
Speaker 1: It's like in half of everything they do.
Speaker 1: They're awesome and they got cool people and it's a wonderful semi tropical place with beautiful buildings and wonderful things going on and it seems great.
Speaker 1: and Then you look at the other half and it's like this horrible fascist place with these draconian laws and big brother and scariness.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what it coming.
Speaker 0: I had a friend who was Australian.
Speaker 0: He explained it to me.
Speaker 0: thus in Australia.
Speaker 0: The government is incompetent when it comes to anything modern.
Speaker 0: They don't get it They just they can't deal with it and they freak out moral whatever about everything.
Speaker 0: But at the same time the majority of us Australians just completely ignore what the government says.
Speaker 0: So it all works out.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm But Australia is at it again and I'm not.
Speaker 0: I don't need to talk about this much.
Speaker 0: That's why I felt it was okay to go on forever about.
Speaker 0: you know The meaningless minutiae minutiae of our lives and the power outages.
Speaker 0: the ACMA the Australian Communications and Media Authority Has decided that the government has to force all websites or web providers that have mature content either for 15 plus or 18 plus to Verify the ages of people who will see this content.
Speaker 1: Oh Unenforceable laws.
Speaker 1: you are always hilarious.
Speaker 0: Point the first this is impossible and stupid.
Speaker 0: point the second.
Speaker 0: This is impossible.
Speaker 0: Point the third.
Speaker 0: This is stupid.
Speaker 0: there is no way they can enforce it without making a registry of everyone and given it like making a Some sort of standard way of verifying age.
Speaker 0: and then you basically just be giving the government this gigantic Database of every person and a bunch of data about them.
Speaker 1: and even then what if I use someone else's computer when they're not Looking?
Speaker 0: Oh snap.
Speaker 0: Oh snap, and uh, what about?
Speaker 0: I don't know a website in China the u.s.
Speaker 1: Brazil?
Speaker 1: hey, you're Australian laws don't mean anything to my website.
Speaker 1: In fact, I should make a website and just put like one porn one porn photo on like a page hidden on the website.
Speaker 1: You say up there it is.
Speaker 0: I'm breaking laws I I don't get you Australia.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just vote these people out?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if the people are all cool and whatnot and they ignore the government.
Speaker 1: Why don't you mean you're voting there, right?
Speaker 1: It's not a you know Dictatorship or anything.
Speaker 1: vote away these people vote new people who are cool and not stupid who know about computers.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it is time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: You ever seen that movie?
Speaker 1: Ghostbusters, uh, mayhaps mayhaps, you know that scene.
Speaker 1: early on the movie were in the hotel and the dye in the fancy dining room and You know does that trick where he pulls the tablecloth out from under all the dishes.
Speaker 0: you know, I think of all the scenes in that movie.
Speaker 0: that is actually My favorite scene.
Speaker 0: you think so because I mean the movie's going on.
Speaker 0: It's a good movie It's really funny, but just that scene they're uh, they're in this fancy room and they're.
Speaker 0: they basically destroy everything in the room on purpose because it's fun and They're just such jackasses.
Speaker 1: Let's go watch it.
Speaker 0: I think we should.
Speaker 1: Anyway That scene is funny because he does the tablecloth trick and just guts all the dishes all over the floor instead of pulling the tablecloth out from under the dishes without them moving which is where you're supposed to do.
Speaker 1: and You know the reason.
Speaker 1: that trick works.
Speaker 1: Physics learn it.
Speaker 1: So here's a guy.
Speaker 0: Well, it doesn't always work as I I proved to my parents Really?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 0: I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I'll tell that story another time.
Speaker 0: You know, I don't need to tell the story.
Speaker 0: it's pretty simple.
Speaker 0: you can guess what I did.
Speaker 0: I was like eight.
Speaker 0: I said hey mom watch this and I broke a whole bunch of dishes.
Speaker 1: You need to do it really quickly.
Speaker 0: Oh, I did it as quickly as an eight-year-old.
Speaker 0: can you realize I didn't even get it all the way off the table Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: My arms weren't long enough.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this guy he he sits he's there He's got a table with tablecloth and a bunch of dishes and he's gonna do the trick.
Speaker 1: He pulls the tablecloth out from under right and you think oh man, this is such an old lame trick, whatever.
Speaker 1: and Then he doesn't do it and he goes through.
Speaker 1: what I can only say is the best build-up.
Speaker 1: Basically, he has his lame trick But he makes it unlame by building up to it in this crazy way and it makes you the way he does.
Speaker 1: It makes you really really really want to see him do this lame old trick that you already know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: you know, it's kind of like a. He talked a lot about how to make people Really get into a magic trick especially if it's dangerous.
Speaker 0: and the trick is and you see a lot of street performers doing this and Actually, I'll warn you once you know that people do this It actually takes away a lot from future performances of you know, death-defying things.
Speaker 0: if you do a trick That's very difficult to do but looks like it's easy to do then.
Speaker 0: No one's impressed at all.
Speaker 0: magicians are but no one else is.
Speaker 0: No, no audience gives a shit.
Speaker 0: they think wow that looked really easy.
Speaker 0: Now if you do something that looks incredibly difficult to do even if it's really simple people are super impressed by that.
Speaker 0: Yep, so a technique that a lot of you magicians.
Speaker 0: I almost said musicians use is they'll build up a trick by making it look really dangerous.
Speaker 0: and even I've seen some like jugglers with knives and things Screwing it up a couple of times and like bailing out at the last second be like, oh, well Let me try that again or like almost fucking up or just acting like like screwing up on purpose to make it seem like it's This crazy thing that if they pull it off It's the most amazing thing in the world and it just builds up the suspense and the suspense and the spent.
Speaker 0: Is he gonna do it?
Speaker 0: and then you do it and even if it's something lame people just eat it Up.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so this guy builds up this incredible amount of suspense and in a wonderful way to the pulling the tablecloth trick.
Speaker 1: and Then he does one more thing which is even better than that that you didn't see coming the whole time and that's why he's awesome And I saw it coming about 15 seconds before he did it.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: He's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, uh Chernobyl Don't go there.
Speaker 0: Actually much of the area is kind of safe and there I meant, you know, don't go in there Don't go into block four.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, uh, this is really old and some of you may have seen it But if you haven't this is kind of fascinating.
Speaker 0: This is an old BBC Horizon documentary about the scientists who had been toiling inside Chernobyl and studying it and basically trying to figure out Where all that nuclear fuel went after it blew up because no one knew.
Speaker 0: we didn't know where it went.
Speaker 0: We couldn't find it all do?
Speaker 1: they have cancer.
Speaker 0: a lot of them have died.
Speaker 0: actually Yeah, don't go there, but at the same time this is from 1996. this is like 11 years old, but this documentary is frightening and fascinating and I think the thing that it's very I don't know Inspirational get at the same time horrifying is when they explain what the bio robots were.
Speaker 0: Essentially This was you know This was a disaster of unprecedented proportions and the u.s.
Speaker 0: And everyone in the world tried to help.
Speaker 0: and they were trying to use robots because basically there's this big smoldering pit of radioactive death and Strewing around.
Speaker 0: it was radioactive material and they had to get all the radioactive material back into the pit before they could seal it all up and the robots failed.
Speaker 0: they could not push it in with mechanical means and they eventually They decided that the only thing they could do was to use bio robots.
Speaker 0: now a bio robot is a very brave human volunteer and They were only allowed to go into this area for one minute or less at a time.
Speaker 0: these were military volunteers who basically were briefed and they show you one of their briefings an actual briefing from this unit and It's fright.
Speaker 0: I mean these people basically had to run into a radioactive area with minimal protection and Shovels and just throw as much of this crap into a hole as they could.
Speaker 1: why didn't they have more protection?
Speaker 0: because it was Soviet Russia.
Speaker 0: and the other frightening thing is the BBC is there and they're documenting, you know, all the modern efforts in 1996. and When you look at what the Western reporters are wearing for safety equipment Versus what the Russians are wearing and it's not even what the Russian government gave them It's what they were using on their own because they're nuclear scientists and they were smarter than the Russian government.
Speaker 0: I mean the the BBC people are wearing respirators and actual shielded equipment and these scientists are basically duct-taping plastic around their legs And they were in cloth filters.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, it's uh, it's frightening.
Speaker 0: I could go on and on about Soviet Russia.
Speaker 1: But then again, I actually you know, there's no question that radioactive stuff is is, you know Horrible and deadly and such.
Speaker 1: but I actually read this study that was somewhat recent and it talked about how radio Radiation horrible and deadly.
Speaker 1: Yes, but not quite as horrible and deadly as we thought, you know It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like if there's a piece of plutonium like, you know Maybe sitting in a parking lot You can like sort of run by it really quick and you probably won't get cancer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just depends on how much of a dose you get and that's heavy.
Speaker 1: But then again, if you take some plutonium and you sort of play catch with it, you're in trouble.
Speaker 0: Well, it also depends on if it's in the air is dust.
Speaker 0: because yeah Yep alpha emitters can burn you at close range, but they can't really hurt you beyond that.
Speaker 0: But if you inhale alpha emitters, you basically are dead.
Speaker 0: There's nothing that can be done.
Speaker 1: basically They examined like you know Statistics and stuff from all these different instances of people being exposed to radiation throughout history and tried to figure out you know Were people really getting cancer?
Speaker 1: were they really getting deformities?
Speaker 1: were that you know?
Speaker 1: And yes, they were.
Speaker 1: but it wasn't.
Speaker 1: like anyone who like, you know stood near it for a second was doomed It was like, you know, well, it depends on what the sources it does.
Speaker 1: It depends on many factors.
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: I mean there there were a lot of accidents even in the US but more so in actually in World War two era Germany and in the Soviet Union where they would Accidentally have a critical mass and someone would be standing too close to it and there be a flash and then feel fine.
Speaker 0: And then two days later, they just die.
Speaker 1: Yep, but then again, you know, that's something there's a critical mass or something going on.
Speaker 1: Well, yes, if there's just like a rock of uranium sitting there you can sort of like, you know Fool around with it a little bit, you know, hold your guy I can count in here and go.
Speaker 1: he Just don't do it for like, you know days.
Speaker 0: Well, what one thing it does come down to is that generally the more radioactive something is the less time It's going to spend in that ultra radioactive state because it is emitting energy.
Speaker 0: It's not like you're just emitting nothing and it stays radioactive forever.
Speaker 0: Yep So theoretically the more dangerous waste is the less time it will spend being dangerous.
Speaker 0: But that's all relative and we all show about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah less time.
Speaker 1: So this one has a half-life of a year and that was a half-life of two years.
Speaker 1: great.
Speaker 0: But the the end thing here is that you should watch this documentary because it's fascinating and frightening And it also is very inspirational because one thing I can say Chernobyl was the worst nuclear accident in the history of humanity and
Speaker 1: They handled it with basically no resources and lots of incompetence and a lot
Speaker 0: of people were harmed very seriously by this.
Speaker 0: but at the same time we've learned a lot and It's almost impossible If not impossible for modern reactors to have a problem.
Speaker 1: even close to this magnet and thinking about Chernobyl Which is a shitty-ass reactor had this problem only because people were incredibly stupid.
Speaker 0: Well, it was a combination of people doing things without following proper safety protocol coupled with the fact that the reactor was designed Very poorly and the failure mode was explode.
Speaker 0: Modern like pebble bed reactors the failure mode is fizzle out and just sit there.
Speaker 1: All right, so your computer there, right?
Speaker 1: It's got a clock.
Speaker 1: All right, you ever wonder how that clock works?
Speaker 1: So I'll tell you how that clock works.
Speaker 1: on your motherboard There's basically a wristwatch equivalent of a wristwatch and there's a battery.
Speaker 1: and that's it.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it depends your computer.
Speaker 1: It might be slightly better than a wrist.
Speaker 0: Well, no your computer with that little wristwatch that is only used really when the computer reboots or is turned off.
Speaker 0: Yep, it lets the computer when it's off.
Speaker 0: There's a little battery in there and it keeps track of the time To within only a resolution of I think one second.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's basically it's not too accurate It just it just keeps the time and when you turn your computer on your operating system like Windows or Linux or whatever Mac Looks at that wristwatch equivalent and sees what time it is and it starts keeping track of time itself.
Speaker 1: So now when your computer's on and you're using it your Pentium chip or whatever is keeping track of the time.
Speaker 1: And then when your computer you turn it off and you shut it down It writes the time back It tells it sets the wristwatch equivalent again to whatever time it thinks it is because it's probably more correct than the wristwatch Which is kind of shitty.
Speaker 0: Now this is okay.
Speaker 0: But what if you want your computer to actually I don't know Keep track of time all the time?
Speaker 0: you want to know that your computer will always have the right time and always have good Accurate time.
Speaker 1: Well, you can get one of those things where you know, it's you don't have those atomic clocks.
Speaker 1: So it's not actually an atomic clock in your house, but you know, the the National Institute of Standards and Technology Broadcasts on radio waves the time in it with a special protocol.
Speaker 1: so you can buy a clock that reads those radio signals from the air and Synchronizes itself to the atomic clocks and you could get something like that in your computer.
Speaker 1: So your computer will always have a good time because it listens to the radio now out.
Speaker 0: There's a problem with that.
Speaker 0: Those signals are actually kind of inaccurate and not that useful.
Speaker 1: Well, that's true.
Speaker 1: But I mean for a computer who really cares if you have that exact a time You don't need any.
Speaker 1: that exact the time do you?
Speaker 0: well one a lot of people do.
Speaker 1: but before we go I want to talk about the people that do all right.
Speaker 0: well before we get to that those clocks are actually not super accurate and that kind that time is mostly used by like Wall clocks that you don't want to have to set the time for.
Speaker 1: yep It's not something you can rely on if say, you know to launch the space shuttle at the right time.
Speaker 0: now Most people don't really care as long as like they look at their computer clock as long as it's relatively accurate They don't care.
Speaker 0: and even further a lot of people if you want to set the time They just go into like the gnome thing or in Windows and they click some checkbox that says Keep my time up to date and maybe they put in a name of a server or something and a lot of times There's a default there and they never think of it beyond that.
Speaker 1: Yep, and You know some people, you know, unlike you or me they need to have exact time.
Speaker 1: Why would you need exact time on a computer?
Speaker 0: Well for one This is the easiest one and this is one I think everyone can understand because even if you're not a big computer guy It's really useful.
Speaker 0: There's something in your computer called the log Log.
Speaker 0: keeps track of what your computer's done in Windows.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna talk about it.
Speaker 0: It can get can die in a fire.
Speaker 0: It's the most useless goddamn Pete whatever.
Speaker 0: anyway in Linux There's logging and we should do a show about that because a lot of people don't know how to rotate logs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's do a show on logs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 0: so any time something goes wrong with your computer anytime anything happens in your computer it may or may not make a log entry and If your time is inaccurate Let's say your computer is 10 minutes fast and your computer's logging and going on and the one day you decide oh crap I'm gonna set my computer clock, right?
Speaker 0: So you set it now for 10 minute.
Speaker 0: now for 10 minutes It's a logging things in the past.
Speaker 0: So it's trying to put log entries in before other log entries and all sorts of bad shit can happen when that happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah or Like you might have a file on your computer and the file says I was let I was created at 10 o'clock and I was Last edited at 1030. you.
Speaker 1: but then you realize oh shit My computer's messed up and you set the clock to 950. then you try to edit that file and it says This file was created in the future.
Speaker 1: What the fuck.
Speaker 0: or Say you have a thing that automatically back stuff up based on timestamps or Always gets the newest version of a file and puts it somewhere like an r-sync kind of deal.
Speaker 0: if your time Changes it might put a file.
Speaker 0: You don't want where it shouldn't be.
Speaker 1: Yeah Let's say you write a script and it says if the file on the server is newer than the file on my computer get The file from the server.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh the clock on your computer is fast.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna work properly.
Speaker 1: You're gonna write over the server with a bad file.
Speaker 1: You're gonna lose data.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: or if you're using a Fancy authentication like if you're using Kerberos authentication or like Windows Active Directory stuff if the time isn't reasonably accurate Between all your servers and clients.
Speaker 0: You just won't be able to authenticate.
Speaker 0: You'll have all sorts of problems.
Speaker 1: It'll say hey, you can't log in your time is all screwed up.
Speaker 1: I can't trust you.
Speaker 1: You can't even tell time.
Speaker 1: How do I know you're even a computer?
Speaker 0: Yeah tell ten times It's all ten times now even beyond that A lot of people.
Speaker 0: this was a big problem in the 486 days and the Pentium one days where Your computer clock would always just get off for like 10 or 15 minutes.
Speaker 0: And even if you didn't have any of those other problems It was always kind of a pain in the ass to have to keep setting your computer clock and just always knowing that your computer Clock which is supposed to be a billion times faster than that alarm clock on the floor.
Speaker 0: The alarm clock was always a lot more accurate.
Speaker 0: You always had to keep setting it and people always used to complain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my computer's shitty The clock is always all off and there.
Speaker 1: it's even worse when you're someone who actually needs precise time Like what if you're a stock person, you know the market the market has the correct time or what?
Speaker 1: If you work at a school the school has this, you know time when the bell is gonna ring And if you're a teacher and the clock you're using is off you're gonna go shit And you're not gonna teach your class at the correct pace.
Speaker 0: Actually when I was in middle school that happened once because there was a master clock and it controlled all the slave clocks in the Mm-hmm and some kid for a prank on April 1st Reprogrammed the master clock to run backwards.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: and it was possibly the most epic thing ever because the Basically it had.
Speaker 0: it had like start the bell at this time.
Speaker 0: stop the bell at this time so it's going backwards.
Speaker 0: it would get the stop event right and Then it would get the start event and it wouldn't stop for another 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: It took him an hour to figure out what happened and fix it.
Speaker 0: Two years later a kid was much cleverer.
Speaker 0: He basically just set the clock.
Speaker 0: He set the clock like five minutes ahead Every period so we all got out of school like 45 minutes early.
Speaker 1: Alright, so the bottom line is people need to have accurate time in their computers.
Speaker 1: Some people need hideously accurate time in their computers.
Speaker 1: And how do we do this?
Speaker 1: Well, there's a simple way.
Speaker 1: the simple way is this you have one computer connected to an atomic clock with perfect time And then we're not gonna talk about how atomic clock clocks work.
Speaker 1: All you have to know is that they're atomic and they have perfect time now not just atomic clock.
Speaker 0: You can actually do this.
Speaker 0: You can buy devices that are like they connect to the GPS network and listen to that or they get the time from somewhere.
Speaker 1: There are many methods of getting highly accurate time but atomic clocks with you know Degrading radioactive materials in them are the best so far anyway.
Speaker 1: So let's say we have a computer connected to the atomic clock directly with a wire.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'll just tell you they don't do it based on the degradation so much as the oscillation.
Speaker 1: But that computer has perfect time because it's connected directly to an atomic clock.
Speaker 0: Well perfect time in so far as the atomic clock is correct as far as far as humans have.
Speaker 0: Actually, this is important.
Speaker 0: We should talk about this because Time is an arbitrary thing.
Speaker 0: We've made up.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is so.
Speaker 0: as a result ho-hum the absolute real work like the time the actual time is Something arbitrary and we can't actually be accurate to the absolute time.
Speaker 0: We can approach the time much like you approach the limit of an equation in calculus.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so it's I'll get to that more when we talk about these protocols because Synchronizing time is something that no one really cares about except one guy.
Speaker 0: Yes, and apparently me.
Speaker 1: Alright, so we have a computer connected directly to a per Effectively perfect clock.
Speaker 1: that computer has perfect time.
Speaker 1: Alright now I want my computer to have perfect time and I can't afford one of those perfect clocks to connect it to nor Can I fit one in my house.
Speaker 1: nor would anyone let me because it's radioactive.
Speaker 1: So what do I do?
Speaker 1: Well, I go on the internet and I tell my computer to ask that computer what time it is.
Speaker 1: So my computer goes hey perfect clock computer.
Speaker 1: What time is it?
Speaker 1: And that computer says 1030.
Speaker 1: Then my computer says okay 1030.
Speaker 1: Guess what that is not going to be horribly perfect.
Speaker 1: I mean, that'll be pretty good, especially if I ask that computer often what time it is.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem is it takes time for my question to get from my computer to that computer.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not just that the problem.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know worse is the problems are real bad, but we're talking about just the beginning problems.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: This is the first toe in the pool of Let's say my computer every hour just says all right.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make my time be whatever the atomic clock says.
Speaker 0: so Basically every hour my time shifts by some arbitrary amount.
Speaker 0: that could be a large amount depending on how accurate my computer's clock is And we get all the same log problems if I'm doing it manually Yep, and also, you know, you got this big delay.
Speaker 1: So the time I'm asking for the answer I might I might get could be 30 seconds off could be a minute off It could be like an hour off.
Speaker 1: I might ask you get the answer way later.
Speaker 1: Who knows it's totally not accurate at all with this crazy Unreliable internet in between me and the very reliable computer with the good clock.
Speaker 0: So there is in fact a protocol.
Speaker 0: This is the world standard basically for distributing time among Computers.
Speaker 0: it is called the network time Protocol.
Speaker 1: now gee, that's a creative name there.
Speaker 0: I am somewhat intimately familiar with the network time protocol because I was basically the only person Who was stupid enough to sit down and read all this bullshit and figure out how it worked back at IBM And make a network time protocol in architecture.
Speaker 1: Look at you.
Speaker 0: and then I get to my new job and they say all blah blah blah NTP.
Speaker 0: and I said, oh I kind of know some NTP.
Speaker 0: and then I'm doing the same thing here and I know a lot about NTP.
Speaker 1: It's gonna become an NTP specialist.
Speaker 0: Well, let me put it this way NTP is probably one of the oldest oldest old school protocols for anything Network wise that is still in use.
Speaker 1: It's pretty crappy and old.
Speaker 1: It's not crappy That's why it works, but it's crappy and its implementation is from a user perspective.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is from a from a computer perspective.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll get to that.
Speaker 0: You see the net.
Speaker 0: to sum this up because I could go on forever about this the network time protocol was basically written developed Implemented by and is to this day maintained by one guy a man named David L Mills And he's a professor at University of Delaware.
Speaker 0: David L. Mills is also famous for I believe making the first ever FTP Yeah, implementation For making the exterior gateway protocol Yep And that's according to Wikipedia and because I remember this from my history of computing class at RIT The fuzzball router which was basically one of the first routers.
Speaker 1: This guy is a pretty important not so well known computer guy.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should try to interview him or something I kind of want to.
Speaker 0: I I have I have indirectly spoken with him in the past.
Speaker 1: He's definitely one of those old Unix Santas.
Speaker 0: Yes, he's also into ham radio, which is definitely indicative of what kind of person he is.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now he cared unlike most other people about how accurate the time is and not just you know Is the time the same as the time on that other computer?
Speaker 0: because you can do that in a million ways.
Speaker 0: You can just say I want my time to be the same as that computer.
Speaker 0: But what if you want your time not just to be accurate but to be verifiably accurate?
Speaker 0: Now this is the idea Like that you could use the clock for science Or that it's not so much that your time it's the difference between precision and accuracy.
Speaker 0: Yep And you can have something that is precise and you can have something that is accurate.
Speaker 0: But you can have something that is very accurate but it's not very precise And you can have something that is very precise but it's not very accurate.
Speaker 0: Yep And verifiability matters to a lot of people.
Speaker 0: What if you're in some sort of government military thing And you need to be able to not just say what time it is But you need to be able to say that I am confident to within this percentage That the time is this accurate?
Speaker 0: You know like statistics You want to be able to go to an auditor or go to a report and say I can vouch mathematically that the time was accurate to this degree at this time.
Speaker 0: And that's kind of recursive like the rocket equation.
Speaker 0: The time was accurate to this degree at this time.
Speaker 0: But how do I determine that time?
Speaker 0: oh snap And basically the method of doing that is incredibly obtuse.
Speaker 0: You see if you ever think oh I just want my time to sync up to another computer And you think oh I'll just run NTP and it'll just work Well you're in for a. you're in for a journey You're in for an epic quest to go through the fact that the documentation for the network time protocol Has effectively not changed since it was written by David L Mills And in fact I believe he still maintains the official NTP website.
Speaker 1: You should write RIMS better than David Mills NTP documentation.
Speaker 0: You see I'm not going to get into all this but NTP is complicated Suffice to say Well mostly because NTP doesn't just keep you know clocks accurate.
Speaker 1: It's a system by which every computer in the world that's connected Could theoretically in a distributed fashion all help each other to keep correct time.
Speaker 0: So to sum it up really really really lightly And it may be someday we'll do a few a show just on NTP As opposed to on time sync in general because I think I could fill a whole hour with this.
Speaker 0: Basically what you have is you have the root source which is like NIST And then you have a stratum one source And the stratum will go up.
Speaker 0: So stratum one is like the NIST computer that's connected to the NIST atomic clock.
Speaker 0: Then you have stratum two devices which are like NTP.pool.org Those people.
Speaker 0: that's like an open source time pool And then your computer would be stratum three let's say Because it connects to the pool and the pool connects to NIST And this looks at its atomic clock.
Speaker 0: You can't query the atomic clock directly because You're not there Yes and you shouldn't query the the stratum one NIST server directly Because everyone in the world's trying to look at that thing.
Speaker 0: And if you if your piddly little network keeps hammering this thing They're just going to block you.
Speaker 0: they don't care.
Speaker 1: So you
Speaker 0: want to and also it's not really that useful to query that thing Because the way NTP works is that even though you're you know Four five six stratoms away from the atomic clock The NTP system is such that you can still say that your time is verifiably accurate.
Speaker 0: And in fact even very far away from the stratum zero atomic clock You can guarantee that your clock will be accurate to within 100 milliseconds or so Which is good enough for 99 of human beings.
Speaker 1: Yep even military people are just fine with that.
Speaker 0: Uh well yeah it depends.
Speaker 0: And scientists?
Speaker 0: Well again it depends It does.
Speaker 1: I'm sure the people would say the hadron collider need better time But maybe the guy in his lab you know timing his uh incubating uh flu is fine.
Speaker 0: But the way NTP works in a very very uh simply described way Is that instead of just changing your clock on intervals It will use a bunch of math to figure out how different it is from whatever your time source is.
Speaker 0: And also it'll try to figure out if you have multiple sources Which of those sources is the most likely to be accurate.
Speaker 0: And then from all this information it'll figure out who wants to sync to And it'll make sub tick like these gradual changes to your clock over time To keep it always accurate to within a certain degree.
Speaker 0: It'll add fractions of time so small that your logger would never even be able to tell the difference.
Speaker 0: So as a result your computer cannot tell that the time is changing.
Speaker 1: Yep like if your computer let's say your computer's a minute slow right It won't just add a minute of time to your computer It'll add like a fraction of a second and then add another fraction of a second And then maybe a little while later add another fraction of a second And it'll make your computer slightly faster and faster and faster until it has the right time.
Speaker 1: And then if your computer's running say you know your computer thinks one second is this long But really a second is a little bit longer than that.
Speaker 1: It'll just add that little bit of a second every every second or so.
Speaker 1: And then you you know every hour whatever And your computer from you.
Speaker 1: look if you looked at your computer's clock and sat there watching it You would never know that the time was changing.
Speaker 1: It'd be like one two three but portions of a second would be being added and subtracted From that clock all the time or pretty frequently.
Speaker 1: so the clock was always accurate.
Speaker 0: So to skip over all the details beyond that I am going to do a show on this in the future If you're interested because I think the world needs a simple explanation of how to Test and query and use NTP because it's easy to make it run.
Speaker 0: It's hard unless you read the documentation to know if it's working properly.
Speaker 1: Windows if you want to have if you want your computer to sync up you go to date and time And you there's a button that's like synchronize with my time with internet servers And Ubuntu does the same thing.
Speaker 1: you say synchronize my time with internet servers And that's it.
Speaker 1: you're done.
Speaker 0: hooray Now that'll work.
Speaker 0: okay but if you really want to have a good set of time what you really should do Is basically on a linux server and you can run NTP on windows and it works just fine.
Speaker 0: But on linux just edit the file it's etc.
Speaker 0: and then NTP.conf.
Speaker 0: It's pretty simple.
Speaker 0: just look at it and there'll be a directive like in there you'll see The word server a space and then just a DNS name of an NTP server.
Speaker 0: What you want to put there is something like NTP.pool.org NTP1.pool.org.
Speaker 0: Put a bunch of NTP pool whatever servers I'll probably link to something that explains this And then make sure by whatever means you do on your linux distribution that NTPD is running And that's it.
Speaker 0: and you might wonder but how is it working?
Speaker 0: is it working well?
Speaker 0: is it doing?
Speaker 0: Don't worry about that it's working just don't just just go with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah the worst is when you know you think it's working but like you know it's running yet somehow Your computer's clock is just completely batshit crazy.
Speaker 0: Well actually the thing that'll cause that most often is if you Are dual boot between windows and linux.
Speaker 0: yeah because you see the hardware clock will save it.
Speaker 0: You'll basically save the time to your hardware clock when you shut down the computer.
Speaker 0: Windows and linux will save it in a different format.
Speaker 0: windows will save it in the local time And unix will save it in uh Greenwich mean time universal time yep.
Speaker 0: so as a result if you boot Between windows and linux oftentimes the clock will just go ah shit and go all over the place.
Speaker 0: Now the way around that is basically if you're dual booting you should probably just tell linux To save everything in local time because you're not going to change windows's mind.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think Ubuntu uses local time but something like Gentoo might not unless you can.
Speaker 0: definitely doesn't you have to configure it properly.
Speaker 0: Yeah well yeah I'm pretty sure Ubuntu does because I've rebooted into windows and I haven't had a Problem when I came back into linux.
Speaker 0: yep yeah beyond that if you have questions about this You can just post in our forum and I'll answer them all.
Speaker 0: but uh beyond that if you want to hear How NTP really works or how to use all those don't try to read the NTP website.
Speaker 1: good god just start Yourself.
Speaker 0: if you really want to know let me know.
Speaker 0: we'll do a show about it.
Speaker 0: but basically there's NTP queue and there's NTP DC and they both do the same thing kinda and there's NTP stat which is Probably the easiest one to use but at the same time it's not the greatest tool.
Speaker 0: and uh but yeah I guess the moral here is that magic just to tell time.
Speaker 0: the moral here is that sometimes things that You would think should be simple and easy you know synchronizing a clock to another thing Are actually behind the scenes incredibly complex because there's all these factors that If you just thought about it on a superficial level you wouldn't think about.
Speaker 0: you wouldn't think About the logs or the file creation dates being out of sync because these are all very Like minutia details problems but yet they're very very important and a lot of people don't realize That a lot of things in computing are like that.
Speaker 1: yep and that's what separates the high quality Computer people from the low quality computer people.
Speaker 1: you'll see someone who thinks about those Things you know will go to change something on a server and they'll think about it and they'll Figure out every possible side effect and then when they change it nothing will go wrong.
Speaker 1: yet Someone else will go and just change something on a server.
Speaker 1: then all these side effects happen and There's a problem.
Speaker 0: they can't figure it out and then they find it later they go oh and then you Get those posts and forums like uh why my logs back date.
Speaker 0: i use ntp.
Speaker 0: this has been geek nights With rim and scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website At www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our And links to all the rss feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: mondays are science and technology tuesdays we have video Games board games and rpgs.
Speaker 0: wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and thursdays are the catch Alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: you can send us feedback by email to geek nights at www.frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that Says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch The last 100 episodes in itunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the Website which has everything.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution Non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as You give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio And no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.