Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Monday October 1st.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm sky and this is geek night Tonight tech conventions, and why we avoid them.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well last week We started asking for questions to do another week.
Speaker 1: well a week as opposed to just a day of ask rim and Scott and I got to say You guys kind of impressed me for once.
Speaker 1: we actually got some intelligent questions.
Speaker 0: Yes, but regardless of the fact that we got intelligent questions.
Speaker 0: We need more Intelligent questions because we can never be sated.
Speaker 1: we were always be wanting more questions plus We're gonna hold out until we get questions for every day of the week.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we said too clearly, but basically at some point once we have enough questions We're just going to in a week or two probably yeah every day one week.
Speaker 1: It'll be a theme week.
Speaker 1: It'll be we answer the questions for each day on each day or not?
Speaker 0: So all you people who are like you know not listening to what I'm telling you and going back to the archives instead of just Listening to new episodes and only listening to old episodes that might interest you based on you know the titles.
Speaker 0: if you're doing that thing Where you're crazy?
Speaker 0: You're gonna miss out on your chance to ask a question And you're not gonna get another chance for a long time, and you're not hearing this because you're not doing what I told you to.
Speaker 0: Why would you tell people they can listen however they want they can't but I suggest you do it the way I say Because that is the way of not crazy people.
Speaker 1: I don't know the way.
Speaker 1: if I were listening to this show what I would probably do is I'd listen to the new episodes and I'd probably just randomly search through the old episode.
Speaker 0: That's what I was saying people should do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think there are people though who are apparently starting at the beginning and listening to each one in order Which I think is crazy.
Speaker 1: however why I mean all right, so you've written this up now in this show.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna hear this for a couple months.
Speaker 0: I know and they're missing out.
Speaker 1: So this is a haha to everyone who's crazy But they'll still get the questions answered and do you really think those people are gonna ask the kind of questions you want to answer?
Speaker 0: Anyway, they're not missing anything Maybe but maybe All right, so yeah make sure that your questions are not answered in a previous show of geek nights Or at least hope that we forgot that we asked it already.
Speaker 0: yes Don't have incredibly long answers.
Speaker 0: I mean there's a lot of good questions that take an entire episode to answer and that kind of we.
Speaker 0: that kind of sucks because We want to answer it.
Speaker 1: a question like episode idea.
Speaker 1: How do I set up a myth TV box is not good?
Speaker 1: Why should I use myth TV is good?
Speaker 0: yes See also don't ask questions like rim just said.
Speaker 0: that could be answered on Google because I'm not gonna Just go search on Google for the answer for you.
Speaker 0: You can do that yourself.
Speaker 0: You don't need to ask me.
Speaker 0: you ask us things that are like discussion topics or opinions or something like that like What was your first computer?
Speaker 0: Yes?
Speaker 1: Why do you like the Commodore?
Speaker 1: whatever?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and make sure it's a question involving science or technology.
Speaker 1: at least when did you stop beating your wife?
Speaker 0: Right after you told your parents you were gay.
Speaker 1: All right right, so what are you been up to Boring this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, no.
Speaker 0: So yes since I haven't been doing anything.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna do some news right now.
Speaker 0: Alright, the news is the newest version of Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: yes the gutsy given gotten to do that in a while.
Speaker 0: The gutsy given beta is now available.
Speaker 0: now it is a beta and it is pretty beta.
Speaker 0: I must say I had the live CD that you will download if you if you want to use this is very beta.
Speaker 0: However, it's been my experience in the past with Ubuntu betas that if you install the beta and then update it and then keep updating It it will work pretty well and eventually become the stable version.
Speaker 0: So you won't have to like reinstall when the final version comes out.
Speaker 0: You'll just update straight into the final version and you won't be a problem.
Speaker 1: I haven't had a chance to try it yet, but I'm excited since it has a new kernel and My hardware is barely supported by the current kernel I'm using.
Speaker 0: well I see I put it on my laptop and I had a little bit of a problem because it like I was getting some error Messages indicative of hard drive failure.
Speaker 1: Oh wait what from smart?
Speaker 0: No from the Linux kernel.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh It was like having problems.
Speaker 0: So I tried it again and I was still getting problems.
Speaker 0: and I was.
Speaker 0: I tried like a feisty CD and there were no Problems and then I tried the gutsy CD again and there were problems.
Speaker 0: so I installed Windows Vista on my laptop just you know to Clear everything up because that's what came with the laptop and it worked perfectly.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 0: there was no problem with my laptop whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So I was a good game gutsy.
Speaker 0: So I was able to confirm that You know Which problems on my laptop were because of Linux and which were because of hardware and pretty much any problems were all Linux.
Speaker 0: So I reinstalled the gutsy and now it was working just fine because I did it like a full scan disk with the Vista.
Speaker 0: and It's gutsy in a lot of ways is better than feisty in a lot of ways not so much different and in some ways a little bit worse Most notably.
Speaker 0: I think the one thing that's worse and I'm not sure if this is Ubuntu's fault Is the.
Speaker 0: there's a thing called the deskbar applet, which I use a lot.
Speaker 0: I really like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Apparently someone's project for Google Summer of Code was to sort of Refactor the deskbar to make it better.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: And in many ways they made it better.
Speaker 0: It doesn't crash.
Speaker 0: It's very much more stable It's faster.
Speaker 0: It's it's better in a lot of ways and good for them in other ways.
Speaker 0: They've ruined the user interface of it.
Speaker 0: It's now really in all honesty.
Speaker 0: It's no longer a deskbar It's just a button that you put in your in your bar And if you push that button or push the keyboard shortcut for that button, it pops up a window.
Speaker 0: Literally all it is is a button that makes a window show up.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the way I have it now.
Speaker 1: It's just a window pops up, but that window has a dialog in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean that windows sort of it's not like a separate window.
Speaker 0: It's like sort of attached to the button, right?
Speaker 1: So now it's not attached.
Speaker 1: just kind of pops up in the middle of my screen.
Speaker 0: It could have a pop-up anywhere on your screen that you want.
Speaker 0: It's a window like a full-on window with a closed button and everything, you know I feel like they're just trying to do too much with it.
Speaker 0: I think they are trying to do too much though.
Speaker 1: The reason I like it is that I just.
Speaker 1: it's simple.
Speaker 1: It's like launchy and windows.
Speaker 1: It's just yeah run any program.
Speaker 1: I want without having to think about and I can extend it.
Speaker 0: I like how I can make it do more or less, but I prefer to make it do less.
Speaker 0: So the fact that they make it this whole window is sort of annoying.
Speaker 0: but good things about the Ubuntu gutsy.
Speaker 0: Of course newer kernel runs faster runs better more things work.
Speaker 0: some things that will accept Scott's hard drive.
Speaker 0: It works fine.
Speaker 0: Some things that used to not work Do work now.
Speaker 0: some things that used to not work still don't work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a check.
Speaker 1: I got a test it.
Speaker 1: when I get a chance Hopefully my the network card built into my motherboard will work with this kernel.
Speaker 0: Well, why don't you?
Speaker 0: what's wrong with the one that you bought?
Speaker 1: I'm using that one now, but I'd rather use the embedded one since I have two of them.
Speaker 1: All
Speaker 0: right, but the The one thing that's a big change the biggest thing you're gonna notice is the addition by default of the comp is fusion uh-huh, uh-huh, which is the super eye candy desktop window managing thing that everyone's showing off all the time and Basically if you just don't have 3d.
Speaker 0: So if you have let's say here you you have an Nvidia card, right you install gutsy.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be disabled not working.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be off.
Speaker 0: you have two choices.
Speaker 0: You can set it to normal or crazy.
Speaker 0: And in order to set it to normal or crazy You're gonna have to install the Nvidia Drive, which is very easy.
Speaker 0: You click one button.
Speaker 0: It's pretty.
Speaker 1: you should do that.
Speaker 1: No matter what there's no reason not to install the Nvidia driver now.
Speaker 0: You can set it to normal or crazy.
Speaker 0: normal is what I like.
Speaker 0: It lets you have just like the drop shadows on the on the windows and like fading menus and you know Just the subtle stuff right.
Speaker 0: crazy advanced makes the wobbly windows and all the stuff you can't handle right, but there's a secret you can do apt-get install comp is settings something and you can choose custom and Basically, it gives you this extra control panel to configure.
Speaker 0: comp is right and I did this at work today Pretty much all day on my work computer.
Speaker 0: This is crazy.
Speaker 0: It takes you days probably just to set up all these crazy settings, but you can do crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: There was even a thing.
Speaker 0: it lets you like draw on your screen and then like erase it.
Speaker 0: instead of having to touch your screen you can like draw on it and There was stuff to like.
Speaker 0: do you could browse through your windows the same way you browse through like albums on an iPod where it?
Speaker 0: Kind of goes whoosh whoosh whoosh.
Speaker 0: you can do the expose like on a Mac you could do expose of your virtual desktops.
Speaker 0: Is all I like that one right there, there's all kinds of crazy action going on.
Speaker 0: if you bother to futz with it That's definitely a step up spinning cube.
Speaker 1: If you try to use the desktop effects in feisty I mean, it looks like it works this little dialogue.
Speaker 1: and hey, do you want this?
Speaker 1: Do you want this?
Speaker 1: and it doesn't give you many options obviously, but it just breaks your computer That is.
Speaker 0: one thing I must say is that there is much less breakage.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a little breakage like on my laptop.
Speaker 0: It takes a little while for like the taskbar at the bottom to appear, you know When I started up.
Speaker 0: so I turned it off on my laptop because it was eating the battery But it worked really well.
Speaker 0: with my shitty Intel laptop video card.
Speaker 0: It just worked out of the box of the live CD.
Speaker 1: ah cuz God.
Speaker 1: and feisty I mean if you enable anything with the desktop switching it just completely destroys your desktops and gives you two and overwrites everything you change.
Speaker 0: my only major complaint with this release is that it really screws around with your Keyboard shortcuts because you have keyboard shortcuts for compass keyboard shortcuts for gnome keyboard shortcuts for the deskbar Keyboard shortcuts for individual applications.
Speaker 0: They're all separate.
Speaker 0: They're all all over the place.
Speaker 0: They're all conflicting with each other.
Speaker 0: Nothing knows what's going on and it's really beginning to be like with everything.
Speaker 0: Yes So luckily the only way the comp is the keyboard shortcuts are like ten times worse than they were before.
Speaker 1: See the thing is for that.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't use many of the only keyboard shortcuts I need if I had expose and all that I could get buying them easily, but the stuff inside a few applications I use and the deskbar but that's the thing is like the deskbar.
Speaker 0: I used to use window tab as my deskbar shortcut.
Speaker 0: Can't do that anymore.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work.
Speaker 0: I used you know, it's really getting on my nerves here.
Speaker 0: So I had to go around and it took me like a half hour just to figure out all these like in to get The keyboard shortcuts to be intuitive just for the simple things like change desktop or open terminal.
Speaker 0: I couldn't find the setting that was intuitive and non-conflicting Between all this crazy stuff all over the place.
Speaker 1: honestly for all that stuff because I do have one of those semi fancy logitech keyboards I just bind those two Reasonable looking things on the keyboard that aren't otherwise keys.
Speaker 0: I see I like to use the window button in combination with other buttons because that's not used for anything in Linux Yeah, so I like hold like right now to change desktops.
Speaker 0: I hold down window and I push left and right and the arrows I see for me.
Speaker 1: You know I have like the next track previous track play pause all those arrows and crack that I'm never gonna use.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I use those for play.
Speaker 0: pause next track previous track.
Speaker 1: I don't do that by listening to music I'm just listening to music.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I don't bother with and if I really want to change tracks or something I just go into XMMS or whatever.
Speaker 1: I'm playing with and click the next track.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's what I used to do back in the day when I had those buttons.
Speaker 1: now with my happy hacking keyboard I don't have those buttons anymore, but I use the arrows to switch between desktops and it's actually really nice.
Speaker 1: Yep All right, right.
Speaker 1: So in somewhat scarier news slash dot is about 10 years old.
Speaker 0: That's better.
Speaker 1: How old are you a decade?
Speaker 1: Well, I am 15 years older than slash job Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So when you were 15 slash that came about.
Speaker 0: uh, yeah give or take Because I didn't really read slash dot till I was like 17 or 18.
Speaker 1: So I got memory in high school The second or third year.
Speaker 1: a few people said like oh they talked about slash dot But I didn't really read it or know much about it.
Speaker 0: I heard of it, but and I went to it a few times before college But I only seriously went to when I got to college.
Speaker 1: It was weird.
Speaker 1: at RIT where I've been I've read slash dot pretty much two days after I was at RIT.
Speaker 1: But you talk to people and it was this dichotomy of pipe.
Speaker 1: people either read all of slash dot or had never heard of it.
Speaker 1: So you sit there and you're like, yeah blah blah blah and slash dot.
Speaker 1: and people would either say oh I already read that or they'd say what what are you talking about?
Speaker 0: Yeah And now we have dig and Fark and all this.
Speaker 1: luckily They all people.
Speaker 1: I remember when dig came out people thought oh, that's the end of slash dot.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of things that came out.
Speaker 1: and every time people said oh slash shot will die While slash dots not doing as well as it used to be and it's no longer Definitely gave it a nice punch to the gut.
Speaker 1: slash dot is no longer the definitive and sole source of technology news for geeks And in a way, I think that is good.
Speaker 0: We needed more sources of news for geeks.
Speaker 0: You know that we're void of rolling peak Bailey, but he's back.
Speaker 0: I don't think he's back.
Speaker 0: I don't think he went away.
Speaker 0: I think we just stopped paying attention and stopped seeing him.
Speaker 1: Yeah the thing is slash dot.
Speaker 1: the reason I think it's still around is that it offers something that those other sites don't offer and it's that The comments are not useless.
Speaker 0: Well, not anymore not since all this useless.
Speaker 0: people went to dig.
Speaker 1: even then they weren't that useless because the moderation system actually worked Pretty well.
Speaker 1: And yeah I can say that I never read slash dot articles because I never needed to any article.
Speaker 1: if you want to know what the article Was actually about whether or not the article was true and what the gist was All you had to do was go into the comments and it was clear almost immediately exactly what was important.
Speaker 0: Another thing about slash dot is that unlike dig did slash dot goes by its tagline.
Speaker 0: It is news for nerds.
Speaker 0: Yep stuff that matters.
Speaker 0: and While the editors are not perfect and they put up dupes and they put spelling errors and rollin
Speaker 1: peak pale
Speaker 0: and stuff like that They really do most for the most part only post things to slash dot that matter in some way and you're not gonna get those like, you know freaking stupid stories like Someone gone
Speaker 1: Paul gold standard
Speaker 0: alien.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that shit.
Speaker 0: doesn't go on slash dot if it's not April 1st.
Speaker 0: So I guess that is one thing in slash that's favorite Even though it doesn't get the news right away and it doesn't get all the news and it doesn't get.
Speaker 0: you know You might miss something here or there or it might put something up.
Speaker 0: That's kind of a you know.
Speaker 1: I've noticed one thing though about slash dot.
Speaker 1: that I just realized is now thinking about it.
Speaker 1: slash dot used to be really funny like I remember.
Speaker 1: I'd read it and it would be really insightful comments and it'd be really funny stuff.
Speaker 1: and now a it seems like all the people who would say something funny have gone to dig and Fark and they say they're funny things there.
Speaker 1: because The only humor left on slash dot is either the tech
Speaker 0: Well, it's
Speaker 1: either the tech equivalent of filk where someone will like Post song lyrics that match up that they wrote about the Linux thing or they make a really lame exchange of dot like just really lame humor But seems to fit with that vibe or the old standard boring cliches of first post.
Speaker 1: Natalie Portman grits cowboy Neil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never got the Natalie Portman grits thing.
Speaker 1: That's just.
Speaker 1: I never found that funny.
Speaker 0: I also do not understand it.
Speaker 0: Plus I came up with that one.
Speaker 0: That was like only old people in North Korea.
Speaker 0: old people email you.
Speaker 0: What remember?
Speaker 0: there was a thing with like North Korea?
Speaker 0: No South Korea and all.
Speaker 0: yes people use email.
Speaker 0: Yes, because I'm sure in North Korea anyone uses email But it was South Korea and only old people are using email.
Speaker 0: and I combined that with the Soviet Russia and I oh I see what you did that I had.
Speaker 0: that was it was my thing on slash that I was your thing and people it was.
Speaker 0: It was cool because I posted it first before anyone else and then people actually carried it into other threads without me doing it Was.
Speaker 0: it was the one time it was good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: slash out.
Speaker 1: I still find useful.
Speaker 1: I still read it.
Speaker 1: I I actually read slash dot as opposed to dig where I just go there to get whatever the news is and I ignore what?
Speaker 1: People post.
Speaker 1: Yep things of the day Bo de ga bo de go de ga bo de ga bo de ga.
Speaker 1: So I think Emily is the one who found this.
Speaker 1: I found it you found it.
Speaker 1: All I know is I was out of town and I come back and I found it actually like over a week ago.
Speaker 0: I just didn't show it to anyone until more recently.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: The opportunity did not arise.
Speaker 1: This is so perfect.
Speaker 1: And now that's been around a while.
Speaker 1: There's starting to be internet buzz.
Speaker 0: Is there internet buzz?
Speaker 0: I didn't notice any.
Speaker 1: I saw it on dig.
Speaker 0: It was on dig when I found it.
Speaker 0: days and days ago Got more digs.
Speaker 1: All right, so but anyway, and also I saw an article on FARC about it.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh Nice, I think these people might get some press in the end just because New York City, you know, you know.
Speaker 1: But FARC there's this cliche.
Speaker 1: anytime New York City's in the news it's always like something minor and everyone always.
Speaker 1: this wouldn't have been in the news if it wasn't about New York City and There's got it.
Speaker 1: There's like this amplification effect Like an ESPN.
Speaker 0: would they get that same sort of thing?
Speaker 0: Like I listen to this one sports podcast and whenever they talk about like the Yankees or the Red Sox or anything like that People are always like, oh they keep talking about those New York sports Not paying attention to our middle of nowhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's just you know more people living here than in the rest of our state combined.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's all and ESPN's in Connecticut really close to New York Plus.
Speaker 1: also it's kind of relevant to what's going on in the world today just because this is a video made by two awesome guys about Bodegas.
Speaker 1: now this might be a foreign concept to people who don't live in the Bronx or New York City or downstate New York because it's kind of I haven't seen this sort of thing elsewhere there.
Speaker 1: There are analogs.
Speaker 1: I mean you go to the hicktown in the middle of nowhere You'll find like the local not quite a 7-eleven that has some food But it's also a gas station and a general store.
Speaker 1: But this is really something special.
Speaker 1: It's the bodega in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: If you are walking around or in Queens or Brooklyn They have these all over the place.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I spent a lot of time in the Bronx and there's a lot of them in the bra.
Speaker 1: Oh there are often like two or three next to each other and the price varies by location.
Speaker 0: like this some of these near My work in Soho, but you did the prices are much higher.
Speaker 1: So what makes a bodega as opposed to just I don't know a convenience store?
Speaker 1: I think number one and as you'll see in this video very specifically is the quarter water Quarter water water water.
Speaker 0: if you don't got a quarter water, you're not in the bodega.
Speaker 0: I've never actually drunk that stuff I But I think my friend people who lived across the street from me when I was a kid Used to like buy it like a whole bunch of it from BJ's and stuff and I drank it a couple times.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute good buying that from BJ's that's kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah already only a quarter.
Speaker 1: How cheap is it there?
Speaker 0: It was it was when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I would go over there and drink it and it'd be no good and I think they called them like teenies or something.
Speaker 0: They didn't call him quarter water, but and my mom wouldn't buy it for me and I didn't want it.
Speaker 1: cuz tastes like shit You know, I think that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: if you see that for sale, it's probably a bodega.
Speaker 0: at least if it's 25 cents You're in the bodega.
Speaker 1: Just watch this video and all I have to say is it.
Speaker 1: it might not be funny if you don't live around here and you haven't seen this before.
Speaker 1: but Going into these things and eating some of that food sometimes and just being in it.
Speaker 1: It's such a fixture of the Bronx and it's just.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: I just like the general vibe I get from these guys in that it's sort of like the same vibe as the.
Speaker 0: you can't catch 10-pokemon's video.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 0: and at the same time these guys are being all silly chilling in the bodega But they're also making a point.
Speaker 0: but they're not making the point like we're making a point.
Speaker 0: It's like they happen to make a point.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 0: their point like not even trying to make a point.
Speaker 1: but the economy was what fuck the fuck up.
Speaker 0: economy is still Fuck the fuck up.
Speaker 1: Oh shit What's really funny is there?
Speaker 1: obviously they're doing this kind of for the camera so they're playing it up a little bit, but People talk like that in the Bronx.
Speaker 1: if you walk into a bodega, you'll hear conversations that sound almost exactly like that Shit.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, you got some ice cream sandwiches And I actually eat those things all the time.
Speaker 0: They're 25 cents.
Speaker 0: You can't go wrong.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they're 50 cents, but they're better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and where I live where I work, it's like $2 for two cookies with ice cream in this cuz you work in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I work in the Bronx, Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Oh Manhattan yes, well weren't you the one who didn't know where the word Manhattan came from?
Speaker 0: I do now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you do now.
Speaker 0: I couldn't find it on the Internet's though.
Speaker 0: I asked the internet.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: it didn't know.
Speaker 1: I did so.
Speaker 1: you asked the internet where the word Manhattan came from and you couldn't find anything.
Speaker 0: Not in the Wikipedia for Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Oh, so so apparently Wikipedia is the Internet.
Speaker 0: No, but that was the easiest place to look and it didn't say anything.
Speaker 0: and I was like what the fuck?
Speaker 1: you sure didn't say Anything.
Speaker 1: did you actually read the article?
Speaker 0: No, but I was.
Speaker 1: I skimmed the important parts because I worry now that Someone listening is thinking oh, I should go to the Wikipedia and look this up.
Speaker 1: and hey There's a section here called origin of the name Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Well, that's story.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah I looked at the article But you go to check the edits.
Speaker 0: cuz I looked at the article five seconds before the edit it was made.
Speaker 1: that added that Yes, that edit was made two and a half years ago, yes, yes quite Regardless this video will teach you a lot about what it's like to live work or be anywhere near the Bronx.
Speaker 0: Oh and one thing about these guys.
Speaker 0: I think their names are like Dallas and Rafi Rafi and Like in this video they have URLs like separate for each of them.
Speaker 0: But now I think they call themselves like the Internet's also the Internet's celebrities.
Speaker 0: That's what they call themselves.
Speaker 1: That's so perfect for them.
Speaker 0: and they made some other videos.
Speaker 0: like in one of the videos They talked to hammer.
Speaker 0: like for real hammer is they're talking to them man.
Speaker 0: We should try to interview hammer Yeah, but there and hammer was saying cool stuff even though he wasn't too eloquent.
Speaker 0: I think it's cuz they caught him off guard, of course it's a hammer but that's why the video was so cool is because he was being all just Talking and these guys are.
Speaker 0: these are cool guys.
Speaker 1: So these guys, you know, actually I think part of our YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: They remind me a little bit of Dave and Joel just in terms of it just banner.
Speaker 0: They do have a little Dave and Joel going on.
Speaker 1: I must say we kind of lost the banner as we I don't know we didn't commercialize but a lot of people accuse us of Having done so.
Speaker 0: All right So my thing of the day Hey rim bodega, if you're at sea on a boat Yeah, and it's the olden times and you do not have computers to tell you the weather or anything, right?
Speaker 0: Right, and you just looking at the water and you can't see anything but water and the boat and this you don't even have any Sails out because you're not sailing right now.
Speaker 0: You're just floating, right?
Speaker 1: Even if you're just floating you have to have sails out.
Speaker 0: Do you can't just float with no sails?
Speaker 1: Well, it depends.
Speaker 0: you can't like tie them all up and just have the sticks.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you put a sail up just to keep your position.
Speaker 0: Okay, anyway Here's looking out over the water and you want to know how fast the wind is going.
Speaker 0: Well, you tell.
Speaker 1: well What I do is first I look at the exponent for my sea wise and then I roll that many dice against say an obstacle one.
Speaker 0: How do you really do it if you're on a real boat in real life and not playing a game?
Speaker 1: I just know because I'm an awesome captain.
Speaker 0: No Apparently I did not know this.
Speaker 0: I learned something today.
Speaker 0: There is a thing called the Beaufort scale.
Speaker 1: I thought you were gonna say bodega.
Speaker 0: No the or maybe the Beaufort scale be a ufo RT Beaufort Beaufort.
Speaker 0: the Beaufort scale is a way to tell how fast the wind is going based on looking with their eyeballs and taking in other sensory data.
Speaker 0: with your five certain senses you can estimate the Speed of the wind and you know how dangerous that wind will be on sea and land.
Speaker 1: now, this is interesting.
Speaker 1: I mean think about it.
Speaker 1: There was a time ladies and gentlemen before there were fancy computers and things and people didn't have cup anemometers.
Speaker 0: It was so primitive.
Speaker 1: people still had to know things like how fast the wind is generally and it wasn't just.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's fast.
Speaker 1: It's not fast, but you had to at least be able to say All right, is it faster now than it was five minutes ago?
Speaker 0: yeah with the scale there's like 12 different like settings on the scale and You can get the wind speed within five knots or six miles an hour.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like how they used to figure how they figured out how fast tornadoes go and it's kind of sick.
Speaker 1: But at the same time it's kind of just.
Speaker 1: it's an interesting thing.
Speaker 1: Tornadoes, you know, they've ripped through farm country a lot and a farmer.
Speaker 1: I've heard this tale from someone else on BBC So I blame the BBC if this is not entirely accurate.
Speaker 1: and they noticed that sometimes when tornadoes went through you know chickens and things get killed but the chickens were also short of all their feathers and Sometimes they weren't.
Speaker 1: so they took dead chickens and put him in wind tunnels and they discovered that on a dead chicken the feathers come off at a Certain speed of the wind and based on that after a storm came through they could look at the storm and know that Whether or not the wind in the tornado was faster than or slower than a given point.
Speaker 0: if they had the technology for a wind Tunnel, why didn't they have the technology for an anemometer?
Speaker 1: The reason is tornadoes come through really quickly and they're so fleeting.
Speaker 0: if you live in a tornado place Shouldn't you have an anemometer?
Speaker 1: So what are the odds that the anemometer is one in the path of the tornado?
Speaker 0: tornadoes are very narrow Obviously didn't see twister?
Speaker 0: You're supposed to put it in the way of the tornado with your truck While holding on in a room full of many many sides more size than any farmers you ever own.
Speaker 1: It's an f5 You know, I I just I would like to say because I didn't that movie was the second worst movie I've ever watched why I only ever qualified.
Speaker 1: qualified by the fact that I watched it all the way through.
Speaker 0: I watched it all the way through like two or three times because they made us watch it in school and it was so dumb.
Speaker 0: It's a dumb movie.
Speaker 0: There's nothing good about.
Speaker 1: worst thing is if there's this whole idea of the storm chasers And I believe this was invented by the Weather Channel.
Speaker 1: Yeah where they're like check out these cool people.
Speaker 1: their job is to chase tornadoes with fancy equipment in veins and look how cool and dangerous it is.
Speaker 1: and Not only does that profession barely exists, but it's not like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly they just kind of fly airplanes through hurricanes and the airplanes are flying high and not in any real danger most of the Time and they have instrumentation on them that collects all the data and then they fly out.
Speaker 1: though speaking of bad movies I over the weekend had the displeasure of watching the first nine minutes of Silent Hill.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, yeah I don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: So yeah before it scale before it scale, however, you pronounce it.
Speaker 0: if anyone learns it You're way cool.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna learn it cuz I'm lazy.
Speaker 1: It's pretty.
Speaker 1: I mean you look at it and the neat thing is a system like this is very.
Speaker 1: All the points are very specific things Like if you see small twigs breaking off of trees, then the wind is about this fast.
Speaker 1: It's very objective.
Speaker 1: Yep right, so We talk a lot on Tuesdays about gaming conventions.
Speaker 1: We talk a lot on Wednesdays about anime conventions and comic conventions But how come we haven't talked about any science or technology convention Scott cuz they kind of suck most of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well this week was Friday.
Speaker 0: I think I went to digital life, which is It's pretty small.
Speaker 0: It's in the Javits Center, which is weird for being small.
Speaker 0: in the Javits Center It's run by things.
Speaker 0: if Davis and I'd been to it once before I think I went to it two years ago Which I think was the second one now the first time I went to it It was actually a lot bigger than it was this Friday and it's about it's sort of like this tech convention But it's sort of targeted at consumers.
Speaker 0: so it's like here's the consumers chance to come and look at all this cool stuff that usually people only see a trade shows not allowed to go to.
Speaker 0: and You know, you see mostly it's about half video games, you know.
Speaker 0: So like there's like a LAN party going on and the army has their little.
Speaker 0: you know Humvee VR type of thing going on and you could play Guitar Hero 3 there and stuff You could play.
Speaker 0: crisis and Bioshock there and Nvidia's there and Intel.
Speaker 1: but and the other hand I can play Intel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other hands the other half is sort of like technology for normal people.
Speaker 0: so they'll be like cell phones and HP is there and Microsoft is there showing off their stuff and Toshiba's there with their laptops and you know that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: So on Microsoft, it's Vista and a zoom.
Speaker 0: Yep, now the first time I went there like the year the you know, there were.
Speaker 0: there was big booths Right, which is and then there were the small booths and there were a lot of small booths.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of small people and the small people that year were mostly give it were mostly selling iPod accessories.
Speaker 0: cuz like the iPod nano had just come out cuz I remember I was there looking for like an iPod nano case Cuz.
Speaker 0: there weren't any and I just got in the nano cuz.
Speaker 0: it's brand new and I think they're also Like.
Speaker 0: Nintendo was there with the DS cuz.
Speaker 0: the DS was super brand-new.
Speaker 0: That's how old this was.
Speaker 0: I missed that one, too yeah, and the one this Friday was sort of like just the big booths and there weren't small booths and it was kind of sad.
Speaker 0: and and it was most of the attention was on the video games and stuff and I think the only Significant announcement that happened there was like palm had a new device or something.
Speaker 0: That wasn't too exciting and it was just kind of yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I've seen all this stuff.
Speaker 0: I could see the stuff online.
Speaker 0: Okay, cell phones that I know exists.
Speaker 1: I think that's the big thing.
Speaker 1: a lot of these trade conventions Existed back in a time.
Speaker 1: I mean it was for you know, there wasn't an internet.
Speaker 1: You couldn't find out about stuff that quickly and now You really only need one or two journalists to see something and then everyone else in the world knows immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like why do they?
Speaker 0: I mean this?
Speaker 0: I can understand cuz it actually lets consumers get hands-on with some stuff that they otherwise Couldn't get hands.
Speaker 1: What did you get hands-on with it?
Speaker 1: You otherwise couldn't.
Speaker 1: well I played with like a Nokia n95 for about a minute But when when are you gonna be able to play with that in a store?
Speaker 0: Never never.
Speaker 0: it's like a $700 phone.
Speaker 0: They don't really sell here that much.
Speaker 1: Oh, so you're not gonna buy one.
Speaker 0: No $700.
Speaker 1: so playing around with it enrich your life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you feel better about that.
Speaker 0: Well, I actually I thought it's a lot smaller than I thought it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought it was too big and that's why I never really wanted one.
Speaker 0: now I realize whoa, that's like if anyone is out there with a fistful of money and you want the phone that does everything.
Speaker 0: Get.
Speaker 0: spend $700 on a Nokia n95.
Speaker 0: It does everything.
Speaker 0: You don't need to unlock it You don't you know, you can buy an unlocked one from Nokia.
Speaker 0: It does everything everything Absolutely everything you want it does and it's really small much smaller than I thought.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh But other than that, I mean I didn't want to wait in line to play guitar hero 3 cuz.
Speaker 0: I could just play what it.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to sit around and play in a gaming tournament or anything.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to you know play with laptops that I could play with at the store.
Speaker 0: It's really just kind of a. the most exciting thing was I was walking around and there was some music and I go over there And it was MC Frontalot was there.
Speaker 0: Ah, but it was.
Speaker 0: he wasn't you know, he was just kind of.
Speaker 0: it was kind of sad actually, like no one was really Watching him or cheering or anything and he was just.
Speaker 0: I think he was there like someone was paying him to be there you know.
Speaker 0: and He was kind of sad like that guy at Kineticon who was in the panel room before us.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah It was kind of sad like that.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh poor MC Frontalot That's just what happens when you you take someone who was popular in one arena and pay him or for whatever reason just have them In another arena trying to get those people to switch arenas.
Speaker 0: Well, it was his arena.
Speaker 0: I mean it was super video game sponsorships, but but it wasn't super video games.
Speaker 1: Hey, it's a weekend party where all the penny arcade types would come.
Speaker 1: It's all the people who are in the city and want to see consumers.
Speaker 1: tech would come.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think many people thought oh crap video games.
Speaker 0: Well, actually no is mostly video games.
Speaker 1: But how many people thought all video games and went?
Speaker 1: how many people even knew this was happening?
Speaker 1: They did.
Speaker 0: they did advertise around the city with various signage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but not so much on the internet.
Speaker 1: I don't many internet people knew much about this unless they really follow the website.
Speaker 0: second gadget knew about it But that's about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like the penny arcade reading vidya gamer No idea whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Plus it doesn't sound like it was their kind of event.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a hangout and play games all weekend.
Speaker 1: It was standing in line and play guitar here hero three once.
Speaker 0: Yep, pretty much.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it really just wasn't that exciting and it wasn't worth any money to get in.
Speaker 0: but Emily got in for free and I Got in.
Speaker 0: see the thing is the first year I went to this.
Speaker 0: I got in for free because someone on a blog Posted a code you could use to get a free ticket.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason I went in the first year that well the second year two years ago This year I went up and I was gonna pay to get in right.
Speaker 0: So I walk up and I don't know I did.
Speaker 0: I see a sign.
Speaker 0: This is self registration.
Speaker 0: So I walk over I type in my information then I see a sign.
Speaker 0: This is printing station and I go over and my badge is printed out and they hand it to me and I'm like should I pay?
Speaker 0: They're like no No.
Speaker 0: later I was standing around waiting for Emily and I saw there was a booth that said cashier that was before the self registration booth that I just didn't see that cashier booth Wow, and The cashiers obviously didn't notice.
Speaker 0: No one else noticed.
Speaker 0: I didn't notice and I just got in for free without even like I stole a badge basically without even realizing it.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, you should see this is when I was glad because if I would have paid I would have been pissed.
Speaker 1: It was They recognized me and they gave me a badge.
Speaker 1: I got in for free.
Speaker 1: Yeah geek nights blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I'm a journalist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was just kinda
Speaker 1: Hey Wow I wish I could have done that for Ohio con -
Speaker 0: and that's why I missed the Friday night party line mostly cuz I It was weird cuz like I was at work, right and I was like, alright Am I gonna go home and do Friday night party line?
Speaker 0: Am I gonna go to this thing?
Speaker 0: And I was like, oh wait I'm gonna do the Friday night party line.
Speaker 0: and then later in the day Emily was like we gonna go to this thing.
Speaker 0: and I Was like do you want to?
Speaker 0: and she's like, yeah, and I totally forgot about the Friday night party line.
Speaker 0: If I'd remembered I probably would have gone home.
Speaker 1: if I recall.
Speaker 1: I believe I don't know she'll hit mad or laugh But I think she had an ulterior motive and getting you to go to that.
Speaker 1: I think she just wanted a ride home from the train station.
Speaker 1: Maybe it probably worked out though because it sounds like it was worth it to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever point is is that?
Speaker 0: At least to give you something to talk about on the show, yeah Yeah, I guess the broader thing is you able to talk a little bit cuz?
Speaker 1: Scott went to one of these things that when it comes to science and technology The conventions that exist are not like the conventions for anime and video games and Star Wars Trek and Star Wars and all those Things.
Speaker 0: Oh, by the way, I heard from Gerald of anime world order.
Speaker 0: There is going to be a convention down south somewhere.
Speaker 0: that is going to be but get this ready the Naruto and Star Trek Convention.
Speaker 0: what I'm not joking why I don't know but that's all I'm gonna say about it for now.
Speaker 0: Well, he continued about the tech conventions.
Speaker 0: god.
Speaker 1: I'm out of the loop.
Speaker 1: Yeah Right, but there seem to be two kinds of tech.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess three kinds of tech conventions.
Speaker 1: one of these kinds is a scam, but I'll get to that one last Because I mean the one Scott went to.
Speaker 1: these happen all the time.
Speaker 1: They're just a consumer slash press event where I guess they let.
Speaker 1: they usually let the public into these things just as a way of making more money and As a way of making some buzz.
Speaker 1: but largely these events are for the press, you know The company will announce we're releasing the cell phone.
Speaker 1: blah blah blah XD XD six.
Speaker 0: It's like e3 was supposed to be.
Speaker 0: yep Where.
Speaker 1: so the press will go and they'll take all their press photos and they'll take the press kit and they'll interview like the four engineers were standing there with canned statements ready to be interviewed and then they go home and they write their little article about the new Thing that came out and all the articles are the same.
Speaker 1: but that doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: and that's what those events mostly are that a lot Of times the public gets let in just to hey we can make some money just by letting people in and hey The people who are setting up and showing stuff off They'll be happy because now they can also hawk their wares to normal people.
Speaker 1: instead adjust to the press.
Speaker 0: That's what a lot of the for-profit comic book conventions do is they have it like an industry night or like a preview day or something like that where You know the people are in the business They're supposed to get in and not other people and so that they can do business and then they let.
Speaker 0: while everyone has these booths Why not let normal people in we can charge them for admission and then sell shit to them or put the cashier where no One will notice it and then not charge people for admission.
Speaker 1: That's - I guess I can say pretty it's clear.
Speaker 0: Actually, it was kind of sad that I missed the cashier was pretty big and obvious, but they missed me.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Sometimes because there was a time in my life when if I had an opportunity to either talk my way into or somehow get a free badge Regardless of how shady it was I probably would have just done it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like try bypassing the cashier to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know, I'll bet we could have if we really wanted to.
Speaker 0: yeah I think the failing that they had was they didn't have the badge giveaway as the person who gives you them takes your money.
Speaker 1: Well, I figure one they probably didn't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and two they probably just didn't even think.
Speaker 1: nope Anyway, yeah, the sad truth is it's not that hard to get into any convention free if you're willing to be a shady, dude.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about the different types of like science tech conventions, right?
Speaker 1: Well aside from the one we just talked about which Scott went to there all I can say about them beyond what we've already Said is that they're usually not worth going to know
Speaker 0: because anything
Speaker 1: you would get to do there You'll be able to do in the real world pretty quick.
Speaker 0: Right now the major kind that you're gonna see most often are these kind where you're supposed to like conferences.
Speaker 0: You're supposed to learn something, right?
Speaker 0: It'll be like Pycon or OSC on or something like that and some of those are actually good stuff.
Speaker 0: You will learn things if you go there and you want to learn and they have people giving speeches and presentations and workshops and you Know birds of a feather thingies going on.
Speaker 1: I remember it a penguin con.
Speaker 1: I learned a lot about PGP.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this stuff to learn right?
Speaker 0: the thing is they're usually aimed at people with jobs and they charge a lot of money to get in and Everything costs a lot of money cause like hundreds of dollars to go.
Speaker 0: We're not talking like 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: You think that's a lot of money?
Speaker 1: No, these things are like it's 500 bucks to get in and you got to stay there for like five days and each different thing You want to see that's just to get in.
Speaker 0: if you want to go see like speech one two and three you have to pay Separately for each one of those things and most of these events there.
Speaker 1: These are the ones that are kind of scams.
Speaker 1: They're not marketed to people because very often except for the exceptional rare ones that are actually worthwhile most of these are marketed to Corporations and they market them as.
Speaker 1: send your employees here tax breaks whatever because of you know training and it'll make your employees better.
Speaker 1: if you don't send your employees bad things will happen.
Speaker 0: and what happens is companies spend a lot of money and this company that does the presentation convention makes a lot of money and Employees basically get off work get a free business trip.
Speaker 0: They don't actually really learn anything.
Speaker 0: They mostly hang out with the other people they're drinking and having fun in hotels and whatnot.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a scam that gets.
Speaker 1: it's good for everyone But the corporations that send their employees off which who cares?
Speaker 0: that's your boss What do you care if they get up?
Speaker 0: I mean unless you are the boss.
Speaker 0: It's scary.
Speaker 0: Don't send your employees there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just remember most of these tech conferences not just tech.
Speaker 0: They're even doing it for podcast.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like podcasting expos and things like that.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're growing and they're putting them all over the place and they're like come learn about podcasting Give us a lot of money and you'll listen to like a few workshops about podcasting for a weekend.
Speaker 0: and it's like give me a break Dude, you're just you're ripping everyone off.
Speaker 1: these events are almost all worthless.
Speaker 0: and these companies like they catch on to the latest trends and then they start conferences about the Latest trends and then you know, they'll keep switching them up as much as they can to keep up with with the times to get More people to show up.
Speaker 1: Yep along the same line.
Speaker 1: sometimes what they'll do is they'll have a timeless generic thing like leadership training or team building or anything like that and it's all $2,000 to send you.
Speaker 1: and if your boss ever asks you if you want to go to one of these things say yes Because here's what it really means for you.
Speaker 1: one Like Scott said you get off work for a bunch of days because they usually you'll notice scheduled during the week and not on weekends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's very on purpose because otherwise people wouldn't want to go.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm to all expenses.
Speaker 1: paid vacation to somewhere.
Speaker 0: three.
Speaker 1: It could be right next door to your house, but vacation three these places often don't take Attendance so you don't actually have to go to the events unless they're checking and you'll find out right away if they're checking or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know if you want to learn something there's usually is an opportunity to learn something.
Speaker 0: if you don't want to learn anything What do they care if you paid and didn't show up?
Speaker 1: Yeah Honestly, usually there's not much to learn.
Speaker 1: I mean if you go to it one of these things about I don't know web 2.0 whatever business PR you're not gonna learn anything You didn't already know.
Speaker 0: and also if there was something to learn all the good ones.
Speaker 0: You can listen to the presentations like months after the conventions on the IT conversations podcast network for free.
Speaker 0: So if you want to hear these kinds of you know presentations that learn something and you don't want to pay money Go to IT conversations.
Speaker 0: They have all these things up there to download and listen to.
Speaker 1: the rule when going to.
Speaker 1: one of these is the one in Rome Approach.
Speaker 1: if you go to one and you see that everyone else there or the majority of them are going to all the events Go to all the events.
Speaker 1: if you go and you immediately see everyone heading out to the bars Head out to the bars and while you're there network with all those people because that's the only real purpose of yes I don't network for your business.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 1: No, don't even say what company you work for just unless you want to.
Speaker 0: I mean network for yourself.
Speaker 0: Mostly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're there for you.
Speaker 0: Take advantage of your company's spending money.
Speaker 0: Actually, no way your company was only gonna ask you when you got back.
Speaker 0: What did you do there?
Speaker 0: Did you learn anything?
Speaker 1: Yes, I learned how to energize my synergies.
Speaker 0: Yes just make up some bullshit.
Speaker 1: and Seriously, if you're looking for a job in your industry and you want to get out of where you are Go to one of these things and you'll find someone who's gonna hire you.
Speaker 0: most often if you're actually trying to meet people Yeah the other kind of tech conference that you're gonna see is actually the kind that's sort of worth going to and that's sort of You know the by geeks for geeks kind of deal penguin.
Speaker 0: well penguin was weird.
Speaker 0: and then it was a science fiction Linux gaming convention all in one, right?
Speaker 0: So even if the the tech Linux part of it failed, it would be science fiction and gaming which is worth going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was primarily Linux.
Speaker 0: It's primarily Linux though.
Speaker 0: And basically during the day you had People who are really cool, especially that Mozilla guy.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: He was really awesome.
Speaker 0: It's talking.
Speaker 0: you could go and sit and listen to the talk about all this awesome Linux stuff and then at The end of the day at night everyone sits around playing board games and drinking.
Speaker 0: Yeah free beer.
Speaker 1: Well, that kind of convention is the kind I like.
Speaker 1: it's the same as the video game anime whatever conventions.
Speaker 1: It's just a convention where it's about a topic nominally or it's about a field of interest or some way to get a bunch of like-minded people together.
Speaker 1: But regardless of what is going on at the event The point is you've got a bunch of people with similar interests in a hotel somewhere and they can talk to each other and hang Out.
Speaker 0: Yep, similar conventions would be like Def Con in Vegas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's very similar.
Speaker 0: They also.
Speaker 0: there are other things.
Speaker 0: there are other open source things You can go to that are pretty cool in a similar way like bar camp or things like that Where basically what it is is a bunch of open source type Program where people get together and like they work on stuff and teach each other things.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of thing you can go to if you actually want to learn and do Technology for a weekend or something like that.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get.
Speaker 0: I mean, there'll be some drinking and some playing and some fooling But it's primarily gonna be technology and learning and it's mostly for open source cool hip people and not so much the businessmen.
Speaker 1: Yep the one thing I can say at least if the internet and my Experiences at penguin con are any indication and I think they are if you think that the people at anime cons drink a lot or the People at sci-fi cons drink a lot Good God, it seems like Linux people.
Speaker 1: for some reason There is a very strong correlation between them and vast quantities of micro brewed beer Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean penguin can't head as part of admission if you had a badge infinite free beer for the whole weekend.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you remember that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've never been to another comment had that they made like there was that like colored Alcohol they were given.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the pangolactic gargle blaster the supposed peg.
Speaker 0: I that wasn't really.
Speaker 0: it was just like God.
Speaker 1: it wasn't really the pangolactic gargle blast.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was just Vodak and Kool-Aid.
Speaker 1: What is the pangolactic gargle blaster?
Speaker 0: It's not Vodak and Kool-Aid.
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 0: I gotta look it up.
Speaker 0: I know it's from this the The hitchhikers whatnot.
Speaker 1: It's not real is what it is.
Speaker 1: I know Most recipes I've seen are made up and usually involve Everclear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now this is like Vodak and Kool-Aid.
Speaker 1: It was it was a big cooler.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: you know You go to a party and there's that blue drink and everyone knows not to drink it unless they're prepared to not remember what happened.
Speaker 0: Many people drank it and didn't remember what happened.
Speaker 1: I believe there was a drink like that at Scott Johnson's bacchanal.
Speaker 1: Bacchanal you say the one we didn't go to because the Wii was coming out.
Speaker 0: All right that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look at us.
Speaker 1: All right It's either go to a crazy drunken party that a friend of ours is throwing and he's gonna get his Wii at the drunken party or Just stay at home and do nothing and then get a Wii as soon as it comes to me.
Speaker 0: What was I gonna do?
Speaker 0: try to play the Wii with all these drunken people or try to play the Wii?
Speaker 0: Quietly in my own home.
Speaker 1: Well, you play with your Wii quietly in your own home all the time.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so it was the next logical.
Speaker 0: Are there any other kinds of tech inventions going on we could talk about?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I I honestly avoid them.
Speaker 1: the only one.
Speaker 1: I'd love to go back to penguicon because the thing is I'm looking at penguicon.
Speaker 0: It's currently penguicon 6.0 is gonna be in Troy Michigan April 18th through 20th, but not Novi All right.
Speaker 0: No, but the the guest list is actually looking much sadder.
Speaker 0: I think the year we went was the peak.
Speaker 1: I think That was what 2.0.
Speaker 1: Yes, I think penguicon 2.0 was the perfect storm of Linux.
Speaker 1: I mean think about all right.
Speaker 1: It's a Linux convention and we happen to live in Rochester.
Speaker 1: So we could just drive through Canada and be there wasn't that far.
Speaker 1: Neil Gaiman happened to be there.
Speaker 1: He wrote it he read us a story and then he got drunk with everyone.
Speaker 1: Steve Jackson just happened to be there.
Speaker 1: What's-his-name from slashed out just happened to be there.
Speaker 1: It was just not cool.
Speaker 0: Mozilla guy was there.
Speaker 0: our friends were there.
Speaker 1: It was nothing but cool people.
Speaker 0: pretty much all the people that we know that were like super techie went with us.
Speaker 0: It was like the super tech crew.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like me you Alex.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz we took his van took his van James James and Steve Pomeroy and he not Most open-source people in in the front row crew away on our way to penguicon.
Speaker 1: We had a cell phone connected to the internet and then we had an ad hoc wireless network shared from that cell phone and the First laptop to everyone else in the van.
Speaker 1: It was it was all the open-source nerdy In fact, we wrote the SS ID down and put it out the window And we were hoping that if someone came by next to us if they just drove next to our car They could have connected to our land.
Speaker 0: They could have.
Speaker 0: no one did.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think.
Speaker 0: many people drove from Rochester to Novi through Canada And we learned how to play tickers and Euphrates at that convention from a guy who worked for Mayfair game.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah forgot about that.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: it was quite the perfect storm penguicon 2.0 and I don't.
Speaker 0: I think if we went to another penguicon I think it would be a repeat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would be a disappointment.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing I think it was especially considering the distance we'd have to trap.
Speaker 1: it still would have been worth it to go if we still lived In Rochester, I think so.
Speaker 1: Yes, and it would have been worthwhile to go if we lived here.
Speaker 1: But it had the guest list from penguicon 2.0.
Speaker 1: I'd fly out for that exact same con.
Speaker 0: I would also especially with my 20/20 hindsight.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, especially I mean remember Steve Jackson came over and said hey I've seen that game Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: I didn't know.
Speaker 1: And we say alright scary, dude We're kind of busy right now.
Speaker 1: Just leave us alone.
Speaker 1: And then some guy comes up says ah guys, that was Steve Jackson You just blew off.
Speaker 0: Oh And then we tried to suck up to him for the rest of the weekend and then drama happened, but whatever.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the drama we're not gonna tell.
Speaker 0: the drama story Guess is one other kind of convention and that's like really targeted.
Speaker 0: They're not really conventions so much but conferences more often.
Speaker 0: But for example PyCon.
Speaker 0: it's all about Python or Ubuntu live.
Speaker 0: It was all about Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: or our friend Steve We just talked about went to something in the city recently that was all about Drupal.
Speaker 0: so if you have a really specific interest like WordPress or Something like that.
Speaker 0: like one project a lot of these projects like MySQL or PHP a lot of them have a big meeting somewhere that you can go to and all the big people in that Project sort of get together and and really make something happen like once a year or something like that.
Speaker 0: So this is a particular project that you were like really deep into.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're really deep into.
Speaker 0: I don't know Moveable type which is a blogging thing, you know There's probably some sort of convention conference for that that you can go to somewhere in the world.
Speaker 1: Yep, the only problem with these is if you're not really into that thing, it's not that oh, well You won't have as good a time.
Speaker 1: It's you can't have a good time.
Speaker 0: There's nothing for you to do there.
Speaker 0: cuz imagine going to a place You know what people work on and talk about and help each other with WordPress for three days.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's what it's gonna sound like an anime con where you could hate anime and everything involved with anime and still have a really Great time at an anime.
Speaker 0: or go somewhere where people talk about, you know, drew Paul It's software architecture how to use it how to make it making patches to it current bugs the future of drew Paul the past The history, you know for three days, huh?
Speaker 0: Unless you're really into drew Paul.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not gonna be worth your time.
Speaker 0: But if you are really into drew Paul totally go.
Speaker 1: Yep, of course that is it's interesting I mean.
Speaker 1: by the same token you look at the anime video game sci-fi world and there aren't the focused conventions or the focus.
Speaker 0: you can go to the.
Speaker 0: you can go to the convention.
Speaker 0: that's just for You know Gargoyles the animated series.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but from what I've read on the internet, that's just a giant sci-fi nerd party.
Speaker 1: generally I mean not.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like everyone there likes gargoyles a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean, I like gargoyles a lot, but you know, I have really watched it really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's actually really good.
Speaker 1: It's it's tough.
Speaker 1: I'm not yeah, I'm just saying it's.
Speaker 1: it was one of those rare cartoons Quote-unquote for children.
Speaker 1: That was actually pretty damn good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I kind of want to watch this one.
Speaker 0: I think there was something else on when it was on so I didn't watch it too much and I mostly watched Something else.
Speaker 0: I liked more and I didn't take a risk on it when I was a kid someday.
Speaker 0: Well Netflix and none of my friends were really into it either.
Speaker 0: So it was like.
Speaker 1: most of the fandom for gargoyles was actually a little bit younger than us.
Speaker 1: We were kind of on the early edge of that fandom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I was watching like beat ass instead.
Speaker 0: Why Batman the animated series?
Speaker 1: Oh, I've Gotta stop hanging out with these comic people cuz You can't call things things like that beat ass.
Speaker 0: It's beat ass.
Speaker 1: No, it's Batman.
Speaker 1: I say Batman.
Speaker 0: That's the problem is is I know I know You know what?
Speaker 1: My answer to that is as far as I'm concerned with the sole exception of the movie where Michael Keaton plays Batman Batman the animated series is the only Batman.
Speaker 0: What about that?
Speaker 0: See if you just say Batman people think you're talking about Adam West.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know but you know what?
Speaker 1: I don't care When I say that man, I'm West watch out.
Speaker 0: I like Adam West a lot.
Speaker 0: We done talking about tech conventions and conferences and how they're not quite I think we're done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that the secret of this show was we have our geek nights calendar where we list, you know Every show we're gonna do.
Speaker 1: we plan sometimes a month or two in advance But there has there's nothing in Monday at all for a long time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we filled up the calendar But I think what's gonna happen is a lot of the questions people ask that take a whole episode to answer.
Speaker 0: We'll fill in the Monday calendar.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So once again all week and a prior all next week - we're taking questions for all Four nights of geek nights.
Speaker 1: if you have an anime question a video game question I guess in anything question for Thursdays and doesn't anything.
Speaker 1: that's not Monday Tuesday or Wednesday should go Thursday And it doesn't just have to be questions about the tech or about the anime like well so-and-so directed blah.
Speaker 1: But what do you think about the other blah?
Speaker 1: he did.
Speaker 1: they can be questions like so What do you think about blah?
Speaker 1: or what was your first blah?
Speaker 0: Yeah, any question just ask us any any question that's related to anime, you know, whatever in any way.
Speaker 1: But the real secret of course was the tonight We didn't really have a show to do it all and we just kind of came up with this on the fly.
Speaker 0: I mean I was thinking of using the digital life as the opening bit and then using the yeah, but - is the news Like vice versa thought
Speaker 1: we were gonna talk about do a how computers work and talk about RAM But we realized that the history of RAM is boring and doesn't matter and the current technology of RAM is actually very straightforward.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could talk about how RAM works and stuff like that, which is kind of interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's five minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so bits go in capacitance Capacitance.
Speaker 0: Oh Noah's We have to go clean the kitchen to eat some food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the house is kind of a disaster.
Speaker 0: We've only really the kitchen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a living room is better because I worked on it.
Speaker 0: I didn't put my laundry away, but that's about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I exploded all over the living room and I had to unexplode.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and I found bits of explosion still.
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh, yeah, you did explode in living room.
Speaker 1: Yes, I did.
Speaker 1: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.