Speaker 0: It's Monday December 10th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We have a little chat about people asking us to fix their computers.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that'll give all our new listeners the best impression possible of our show.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah Yeah, but you guys quoting a bunch of other guys who are much funnier Oh kind of like how we did at our panel.
Speaker 1: Maybe we kept having these like Simpsons seizures where we just start quoting things to each other Jojo Shabby gabbo gabbo and the audience like half of them be like ah Simpsons and the other half to be like what?
Speaker 1: What's what's what?
Speaker 0: But and then you know who's gonna be a geek nights listening who's not here?
Speaker 1: but seriously to all of you who are new listeners because of the New York anime festival and if our Podcasting live panel was any indication.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of you.
Speaker 1: I want to warn you about something I don't know if you read our little flyer, but geek nights is four nights a week and Mondays Tuesdays Wednesdays and Thursdays.
Speaker 1: every night is kind of like a different topic like a different show.
Speaker 0: It's almost as if we did four different shows each, but each show was weekly so Monday night tonight the rest of the show.
Speaker 1: you know the show format is kind of straightforward.
Speaker 1: We talked about.
Speaker 1: you know we do some news in the beginning after our little like hey Scott.
Speaker 1: How's your day going my days going?
Speaker 1: Fine how about yours?
Speaker 1: Then we do some news things of the day.
Speaker 1: you'll figure out what.
Speaker 1: that is pretty quick I hope.
Speaker 1: and then we talk about whatever.
Speaker 1: the topic of the night is.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology and Linux and neckbeards.
Speaker 0: So if you're you know you were at the anime festival.
Speaker 0: presumably if you're a new person to the show Which means your mind is a chance you might not be interested in technology But you're probably more likely to be interested in anime and such.
Speaker 0: so maybe you only want to listen to Wednesday.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe you do want to listen to Monday.
Speaker 1: Yeah But just so you know and so you don't you know hear us talking about neckbeards and Linux and think I thought they were Doing anime.
Speaker 1: Why were they at the New York anime festival?
Speaker 1: Mondays you know Linux and all that.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays might be up your alley.
Speaker 1: It's vid you games video games board games German board games role-playing games gigawing and such.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are the night you care about.
Speaker 1: anime manga comics.
Speaker 1: It's uh the number one or two anime podcast in the world who knows well at least in the English-speaking world.
Speaker 1: You know I assume there's some Japanese podcast about anime.
Speaker 1: That's just awesome.
Speaker 0: There's no way to know.
Speaker 0: with those web stats.
Speaker 0: there could be a million listeners to like you know Joey Jojo's anime podcast.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I'm pretty sure I know who the top five or six anime podcasts are and I got to say after the top three Or four it's a sharp decline.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: That's for certain.
Speaker 1: and Thursdays well if you want to hear us argue about things that's probably when you want to listen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz usually that's also the day where you can't think of anything to talk about and we just go.
Speaker 1: So if you thought we were you know hot and awesome at the anime con And you want to hear some anime episodes go to our website.
Speaker 1: You know www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: I'm assuming you got there because you're here listening and to all of our normal listeners.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry we got to go through all this but We'll only be this week next week, we'll stop talking about this bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least until we go to another con in February.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, that's all right.
Speaker 1: But you know that all our archives are on the website.
Speaker 1: It's just mp3 so you can just download them and in the iTunes or whatever feeds the RSS They're all in there, and I'm sorry people with dial-up.
Speaker 0: Yeah easily can't listen to podcast if you have dial-up.
Speaker 1: Well not yet.
Speaker 1: I mean I'm kind of thinking about making a dial-up Slash low bandwidth feed.
Speaker 1: so I guess for all of you out there If you think that that would in any way be of interest to you or anyone you know let me know.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't take that much effort for me to make an extra like eight megabyte.
Speaker 0: Put it in a separate feed though.
Speaker 1: I got some ideas all right Right.
Speaker 1: so uh in the news.
Speaker 1: I'll let Scott go first.
Speaker 0: Okay, well I basically have all tech things of the day and no tech news.
Speaker 0: So I'm just like uh.
Speaker 1: But fortuitously We acquired an item that we've been looking for for a long time and Scott is probably the the biggest person in terms of getting This done.
Speaker 0: well basically you know we have in our living room the TV, and it's the only TV in the house.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't actually get television.
Speaker 0: It's just what it's got a Wii and a Mac hooked up to it as a Wii and a Mac mini connected to it.
Speaker 0: The only thing is that the the speakers on the TV are not so great.
Speaker 0: I mean they're fine for sitting there playing video games.
Speaker 0: They're fine for sitting there.
Speaker 0: You know Listening to music or watching a movie, but very often.
Speaker 0: I would find myself say cooking in the kitchen wanting to listen to some music and TV speakers not cutting it.
Speaker 1: no the worst thing before that we did have hooked up to the TV.
Speaker 1: You know you go to like Best Buy, and you see those Stereo systems that they sell to a punk kid to put in his room.
Speaker 1: It's like a gigantic stereo with two speakers coming off of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like a boombox, but on crack, and you can't actually move it.
Speaker 0: You just sort of put it on like your dresser or on a shelf And it just works from.
Speaker 0: and you can also like bring it to the beach or whatever.
Speaker 1: I had one of those from when I was in you know like middle school.
Speaker 0: I have one of those.
Speaker 0: It's still in my room am I?
Speaker 1: so it was hooked up to our TV for the longest time until Well one day Scott knocked it over and then Kate knocked it over another day and one thing Because you put it on this precarious thing which is much smaller than it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I'll admit it wasn't too stable.
Speaker 1: I mean if someone kicks it as hard as they can I think it's gonna fall over.
Speaker 0: no matter what I do kidding if Breeze of wind blew in the wrong direction that thing would fall over.
Speaker 1: You know we did fine You can't put.
Speaker 0: you can't put a vase Like balancing on top of a pyramid and then blame someone.
Speaker 0: if you they knock it off.
Speaker 0: Stereo on top of a milk crate against the wall a very small milk crate balanced precariously on top of another small.
Speaker 0: It was very precarious.
Speaker 0: You just for some reason wobbled back and forth with like.
Speaker 1: yes Yeah, I'll admit it wobbled when you kicked it.
Speaker 0: no What plus it was directly at the foot of my bed where my feet go?
Speaker 1: Suffice to say that stereo is no more.
Speaker 1: It is ceased to be.
Speaker 1: I think it still had some CDs in it when I threw it away.
Speaker 0: It is gone to meet its main thing the best part about that stereo.
Speaker 1: It had a CD changer which back in when I was in middle school was like The hot shit if you hadn't nailed it to the milk crate.
Speaker 1: But It stopped working one day.
Speaker 1: like it was this cartridge based thing like it had cartridges inside of it as I found out when I Smashed it open one day to throw it away.
Speaker 1: You know whenever you throw away technology you smash it open first.
Speaker 0: It's just what you do, but especially technology We have no idea what the hell's inside.
Speaker 0: I mean a computer.
Speaker 0: I know it's inside a CD changer.
Speaker 0: who knows how the hell that thing moves those CDs around.
Speaker 1: I was kind of surprised.
Speaker 1: It was a lot less Robust than I'd expected, but then again.
Speaker 1: I should have expected much because it hadn't worked for like three years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's the thing.
Speaker 1: it hadn't worked for like three years.
Speaker 1: like one day It just stopped working and anytime I hit the button it would like chug chug chug inside and nothing would happen.
Speaker 1: And I had a couple CDs there.
Speaker 1: I couldn't get out and I couldn't get more CDs in.
Speaker 0: so whatever It was the day of mp3s.
Speaker 1: We didn't give a shit, but the thing is you know we used it And we left one of our friends home one day.
Speaker 1: She was sick while the rest of us went out to get child Japanese food.
Speaker 1: and She calls me she's like yeah, I put a CD in your stereo, and now it won't play and it won't come out.
Speaker 1: And I'm like wait a minute.
Speaker 1: What stereo.
Speaker 1: We don't have a stereo.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know the one in your living room.
Speaker 1: How the hell did you get a CD in that thing?
Speaker 0: hey it wouldn't come out as we share.
Speaker 1: somehow She got it to take a CD.
Speaker 1: Yeah Magic, I guess, but yeah, it's gone and the TV speakers weren't cutting it.
Speaker 0: no So we're sitting here, and what are our options for TV speakers?
Speaker 0: right well?
Speaker 0: We could go and get some crazy surround sound thing, but what the hell's the point of that?
Speaker 0: see now?
Speaker 1: We did a show about that before and I guess I should clarify that There's nothing wrong with surround sound.
Speaker 1: I guess pretty cool.
Speaker 1: But for our house and the kind of things we do in our house is not worth the time and the effort and our incredibly Poor acoustic living room.
Speaker 1: yes There is suffice to say I said that phrase a lot of times.
Speaker 0: so if I say it a million times every show I do There is mr.
Speaker 0: Suffice shall we say say rim says suffice to say a lot if I may.
Speaker 1: There's an echo in our living room as it is.
Speaker 1: we don't need five speakers echoing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically all we needed was some speakers That would be loud enough to where you could hear them in the next room and also Maybe be a little better than the TV ones you know for a movie or whatever.
Speaker 1: now every Receiver we looked at was even if we were only gonna use it with two speakers Was months.
Speaker 1: it was monstrosity.
Speaker 1: it was bigger than everything hooked up to.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean come by I got my dad's old receiver cuz he got a new one right and the thing is huge.
Speaker 0: Remember under our television is a Mac Mini and a Wii two very small things.
Speaker 0: The receiver would have been bigger than both of those combined.
Speaker 0: We're bigger than like.
Speaker 0: it's as big as like eight Mac Minis.
Speaker 1: Maybe no big as like two or three Ataris.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's as wide as like Nine wheeze.
Speaker 1: it's almost as big as your mom.
Speaker 1: It's huge.
Speaker 0: It's like two VCR stacked on top of each other.
Speaker 0: It's ginormous Right.
Speaker 0: so putting that under there, especially with the amount of electricity a thing like that takes It's just like forget about it.
Speaker 1: That is that is not yeah like we plug it in the lights dim.
Speaker 0: Yeah another option we can go and try to buy some like PC speakers or something like that.
Speaker 0: You know a little 2.1 system you meant for computers.
Speaker 0: use that but you know that speakers be so small?
Speaker 0: You know physically like where would we put them really?
Speaker 0: I mean where you know this is the TVs on this stand.
Speaker 0: You know we need speakers that can go on the floor on us on the wall or something While
Speaker 1: I have a subwoofer in my room for music and all that Just because most of the time we spend with our friends in the house is hanging out and playing video games and stuff.
Speaker 1: We don't really need the big subwoofer.
Speaker 0: and also the subwoofer would buy.
Speaker 0: the lady understood downstairs.
Speaker 1: But most of all like computer speakers for some reason the subwoofer is bigger than like every speaker combined.
Speaker 1: It's gigantic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 0: maybe you know if I lives if I got a bigger room.
Speaker 0: I could use because my computer I have a 5.1 system that was larger than I thought it was gonna be when I bought it.
Speaker 0: I would have gotten a smaller one, and I mistakenly bought a larger one.
Speaker 1: the box came Like what did Scott buy?
Speaker 1: a mini fridge?
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 1: Why it's huge right?
Speaker 0: I would have bought a smaller one, but oh well Why don't we buy a mini fridge?
Speaker 0: Because we don't have a. we don't have a big enough house yet to warrant one yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway.
Speaker 0: So what am I gonna do here right?
Speaker 0: I needed a 2.1 or 2.0 speaker system.
Speaker 0: That'd be good for a living room.
Speaker 0: So you go shop around for these things and the prices on them are ludicrous or the size of the things is ludicrous.
Speaker 0: There was just.
Speaker 0: no matter where I look there was no sufficient product.
Speaker 0: You know I mean eat.
Speaker 0: the only things that I saw that were almost acceptable.
Speaker 0: You could get like you know like we had before.
Speaker 0: one of those meant for like your dresser in your bedroom.
Speaker 0: stereo systems are meant for the you know to put on the shelf stereo things.
Speaker 0: they have A CD changer, and they play mp3 CDs.
Speaker 1: Open those things.
Speaker 1: there's not so much inside of it was kind of like the V. It's just a couple of little circuit boards a lot of empty space because they wanted to look big impressive for the 14-year-old to buy him.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's like it's like a whole stereo unit as he might even have a cassette tape slot.
Speaker 1: No, it won't.
Speaker 1: some of them do not anymore.
Speaker 0: You know has an FM AM radio in it, and it's got all this shit I don't want right.
Speaker 0: all I want is audio in Speakers out.
Speaker 0: that's all I need right?
Speaker 0: So I'm looking for such a product and the only product I can find is this thing called the sonic t amp.
Speaker 0: It's just an amplifier.
Speaker 0: it takes in.
Speaker 0: you know the say it takes the audio.
Speaker 0: stereo audio goes in.
Speaker 0: you know with the same plug You use for like headphones on your iPod and then speaker wire comes out to two speakers.
Speaker 0: You could even power.
Speaker 0: you can plug it into the wall, or you can put eight double A's in it So you don't even you can use this like on the road.
Speaker 0: It's like if you go somewhere in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: you can put some batteries in this.
Speaker 0: Take a little wire plug your iPod into it, and then have speakers And you can get it to be loud, and it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: now the deal is it's basically a digital amplifier.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much all it is.
Speaker 1: and now some audio files out there.
Speaker 1: out there might say But you can hear the difference with the harsher sound Strangely enough right.
Speaker 0: this product Which is not Randy or audio file in any way is sort of lauded by audio files.
Speaker 0: They are like hooray this thing is awesome.
Speaker 0: They don't really say it's awesome.
Speaker 0: like you know I would use it for my stereo system in my house.
Speaker 0: awesome Cuz you know they're audio files, and they have to get a $5,000 stereo system with the tubes.
Speaker 0: But they say it's awesome for the value.
Speaker 0: They're like oh my god for 80 bucks.
Speaker 0: This is this is better than things that cost a few hundred dollars not better than things That's knows.
Speaker 0: at least that's what audio files say.
Speaker 0: so in the real world this thing is fantastic.
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: I'd say what else do you need?
Speaker 0: you?
Speaker 0: freaking is unless you want surround sound is as good as it gets 80 bucks.
Speaker 0: Stereo sound comes in speakers come out, and it gets pretty loud.
Speaker 0: That's the one worry I had.
Speaker 0: I mean it's only like 15 watts per channel plugged in and I think 10 watts per channel.
Speaker 0: if you're using battery power and If your speakers are kind of crummy you might not be able to get it to be very loud Or you might not to be able to get it to be very loud.
Speaker 0: You know with without a lot of noise on the lawn and that you know that's sort of it's like great.
Speaker 0: if it works You know that's one thing, but if I can't hear it and I have to crank it up all the way It's basically not working.
Speaker 0: But to my surprise I bought these two big America speakers.
Speaker 0: It was two speakers for a hundred bucks a bottom on Amazon.
Speaker 1: the only problem with them Is that they are much too heavy to bring to a convention and put on a table?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're pretty heavy, but they're you know they're just nice wooden bookshelf speakers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not coming to Katsu Ka.
Speaker 0: no there were two of them.
Speaker 0: They were hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: I plugged him in.
Speaker 0: I got a spool of cheap ass speaker wire from Radio Shack like nine bucks for because the only better speaker wire you're gonna find is straight-up lamp cord.
Speaker 0: No, they had monster speaker wire there.
Speaker 0: That was it actually surprisingly was only $15 for the spool of monster speaker wire.
Speaker 0: Wow there's only slightly more money.
Speaker 1: You know why I'll bet.
Speaker 1: I know why because the kinds of people who buy monster cables and think they're better Aren't the kind of people who are gonna buy a spool of wire?
Speaker 1: They're going to buy a piece of wire that has connectors on both ends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't actually see those there But I'm sure they were somewhere.
Speaker 0: Regardless I bought the cheap speaker wire on a spool.
Speaker 0: I cut it myself I plugged it in and we're good to go.
Speaker 0: So if anyone out there wants stereo sound or perhaps you know you think about buying one of those iPod docks.
Speaker 0: Or you're thinking about you know something along those lines.
Speaker 0: I recommend to you the sonic t-amp.
Speaker 0: There's a pro sonic t-amp But I can't really figure out why it's better than the regular t-amp and this.
Speaker 0: actually I bought the second generation of the plain T amp.
Speaker 0: there's now a new version of it.
Speaker 0: So just go to think geek and you'll be able to.
Speaker 0: you'll be sure you get the right one.
Speaker 0: It's not too hard.
Speaker 1: so I Was reading law.com the other day.
Speaker 0: law.com you say.
Speaker 1: well actually I was reading slash jot And they linked to law.com not grok law.com.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I've never been to law.com before alright, but Articles like this come up pretty regularly.
Speaker 1: It's like every year.
Speaker 1: Maybe every half year depending on what's going on an article pop up somewhere talking about how People write stuff in email, and they forget that other people might have a copy of it.
Speaker 1: Yes, but this is talking about.
Speaker 1: it's basically general counsel's talking to you know employees and people and saying alright Listen if you send something in an email.
Speaker 1: There's a record of it.
Speaker 1: Don't say incriminating things if you're gonna be in a lawsuit hahaha, and it goes on and on and I still I don't know I This really kind of bothers me that even to this day I mean email has been around for a long time.
Speaker 1: But a lot of people just when it comes to electronic communication don't seem to get it like.
Speaker 1: they don't seem to just quite understand The fact that if you put something on a computer.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much there forever Especially if it's on someone else's computer - especially if someone wants it to be around forever.
Speaker 0: You know like you've got a business where they want everything to be around forever or where there's some sort of server That's keeping everything around forever.
Speaker 1: Yep, though.
Speaker 1: I think the worst thing is kind of tangentially related to this.
Speaker 1: But there's been a lot of stories of late about Congressmen or various companies.
Speaker 1: you know oh we lost all the email, so I'm sorry We can't give it to you.
Speaker 1: And there's really almost no way that can happen unless shenanigans are happening.
Speaker 1: and even in a in a fairly incompetent IT environment.
Speaker 0: you really can't just lose email especially in that quad unless you do it on purpose And you need to get like.
Speaker 0: it's pretty hard to do it on purpose.
Speaker 0: Especially like if you don't know about computers Then it it then there's no way you could have gotten rid of the emails You would have actively had to do something to get rid of them.
Speaker 1: now even better.
Speaker 1: See I remember I had arguments with people in our IT a lot.
Speaker 1: I haven't had this argument recently, but I wonder if anyone out there is going to say something, but I you trolling.
Speaker 1: I Have a record of every conversation I've had online either an email well except I lost some emails when I switched from our IT's account, but I keep everything now.
Speaker 1: But every email I am chat everything anything any text anyone ever sends me.
Speaker 0: I still have yeah all my at least all my gene anything anyone's ever sent me or I've said anyone on Gmail I still have except for spam and I lost all.
Speaker 0: I had chat logs, and I lost him.
Speaker 0: I had chat logs.
Speaker 0: I lost him, but now I have chat logs at least with people who are using jabber.
Speaker 0: I have those chat logs forever.
Speaker 0: I can google.
Speaker 1: I mean I remember way back.
Speaker 0: Google also has them forever.
Speaker 1: I remember I looked and I saw I had that the first message I'd ever sent to Scott when we were freshmen in college, and I was like hey I'm that guy who did blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: or you want to go to that anime club something something get dinner at Gracie's with all the other cool people and I had already been to that anime club something.
Speaker 1: yep I had missed that anime club because I had to go to that economics class that I promptly dropped haha.
Speaker 1: But enough of that.
Speaker 1: I don't really have much more insightful to say about email, and it is time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: Okay, have you got a good one actually?
Speaker 1: I think I do.
Speaker 1: I came across this kind of randomly, but it's pictures of people and other things.
Speaker 1: But the first two are people made of people and that's not so special.
Speaker 1: There's been a lot of times where someone gets a bunch of people together to make a shape or something take a picture of it.
Speaker 1: These are from World War one like 1915 1917 era and they're super old and it's kind of cool to look at What everyone looks really kind of sad and frumpy in these pictures, but that's how you'd be if you were in World War one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at the same time.
Speaker 1: It's really kind of fascinating to look at these things.
Speaker 1: They're very nationalistic and very I don't know.
Speaker 1: Check them out and I'm not sure exactly what I have to say about them beyond that other than it's kind of interesting to look back in time and see
Speaker 0: people thought of this a long time ago, and
Speaker 1: well, you know People thinking of things a long time ago has never surprised me and
Speaker 0: it's people are still doing it today And it's still kind of cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but a lot of people look really kind of in these pictures.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're being forced to do it because they were in some sort of army.
Speaker 1: I think they're all US Army folks.
Speaker 1: I didn't read the full story But these are some old pictures and some of them are pretty well done as in.
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of crowds doing things like this today.
Speaker 1: that did a much worse job.
Speaker 0: Yep All right, speaking of military actions, you know, sometimes there's something you don't know a lot about but you see it And you know that it's somewhat odd, you know that it's awesome and special, but you don't know enough to explain why.
Speaker 0: Aha, like you don't know anything about painting but you see a painting and you know That's like one of the best paintings there is but you don't know any words or you know You can't tell someone why because you never studied art, you know, something like that.
Speaker 0: No Well, basically that's sort of that's what my thing of the day is.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about fighter jets whatsoever except they fly and they have jets and they can shoot missiles and have guns.
Speaker 0: Sometimes and sometimes one person flies it and sometimes two people.
Speaker 0: But this is some Russian jet called the su-30 MK And I'm watching videos of this thing flying and here's a whole bunch of them here and From what I can read in my limited understanding of it This is pretty much the most capable flying machine ever created and it's pretty amazing.
Speaker 0: And one of these videos is funny because it shows them Blowing one of them up by accident because they scraped the ground but during like a French air show or something But the guy eject.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty funny watching them eject But because they're so close to the ground when they eject it's it's okay.
Speaker 0: But the other videos actually show the thing flying and in one of the videos it flies around With like these Reds, you know red smoke coming out of you know The the wing tips.
Speaker 0: that way I guess if you're down on the ground you can sort of tell how it's moving based on You know the red smoke and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Also, it looks cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah also looks cool and this thing can fly in ways that remind me only of The Valkyries from macro.
Speaker 1: I was about to ask if you were gonna say something about macross.
Speaker 0: perhaps it also, you know from what I understand I'm not sure if I'm correct.
Speaker 0: This thing flies the same way.
Speaker 0: the Valkyries and macross fly.
Speaker 0: It's got the two jets that point backwards and the things that aim the jet whatnot.
Speaker 0: So it looks like it's basically thrust vectoring.
Speaker 1: Yes, that's been around in fighter jets for a long time Scott.
Speaker 1: Well, anyway, the most fighter jets use thrust vectoring.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway, this one is better than any other one supposedly at least anyone.
Speaker 0: That's not secret that you can watch videos of on the Internet's right?
Speaker 1: So I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: I think we did a show similar to this before.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna search right now.
Speaker 1: Well, we're gonna take a slightly different tack here.
Speaker 1: But a lot of you out there may or may not be technology people or you know like the local Linux guy or the guy who your friends all think all he knows about computers, but a lot of people ask us Personally to fix their computers for them and it's a little bit not so easy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean really.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, this is that old stereotype of you know, I will not fix your computer for you.
Speaker 0: Do not ask the computer guy to fix your computer.
Speaker 1: you know the Bafa the bastard operator from hell which if you don't know who the bastard operator from hell is I Suggest you look for that.
Speaker 1: I'll make it my thing of the day in the future.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe it should have been.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the thing is I assume everyone's read that.
Speaker 1: I mean I read that when I was in like middle school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't remember when I read it, but I read it.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know about computers, but I understood.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway So yeah, I haven't found any old episode of us talking about this.
Speaker 0: So let's just go with it.
Speaker 0: And even if we've talked about it before it was so long ago It had to be one of the earliest episodes.
Speaker 0: It's it's good enough to do a recap.
Speaker 1: well the thing that happens the most I think this is the.
Speaker 1: the interesting part for me is that a Lot of people will ask me or you know people who are IT or CS professionals like hey, I got a computer problem can you fix it?
Speaker 1: and They always seem amazed that usually we can't fix it or that they're like man your computer guy.
Speaker 1: How come you don't know how to do X?
Speaker 1: and I think there's a lot of reasons for that.
Speaker 1: Shall we get into all the reasons?
Speaker 0: Okay, and reason number one that I have is that people just have a problem where there may be a fix.
Speaker 0: But the fix is sort of not possible or not Satisfactory or not complete or you know, it's not what they want.
Speaker 0: For example.
Speaker 0: Hey, I got my computer full of viruses.
Speaker 0: Can you restore it to new?
Speaker 0: they're assuming that it can be restored to like new.
Speaker 0: it's like no pretty much.
Speaker 0: It would take me if that was possible, right?
Speaker 0: It's like what's the most you can do?
Speaker 0: You can run some antivirus You can run some spywares and adware remove or
Speaker 1: I could spend four hours Backing everything you have up and then reinstalling windows
Speaker 0: and then scaling
Speaker 1: all the patches Scanning everything that I took off your computer putting it all back on in that amount of time.
Speaker 1: Well, not in that about us.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna do it.
Speaker 1: I don't have four hours to kill.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's like that's not really a satisfactory solution because it's like, you know You got to back up all this stuff or maybe a lot of the stuff is lost, you know.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, hey my engine seized.
Speaker 0: Can you fix my car?
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: yes, technically I can if I'm a mechanic.
Speaker 0: I'm going to replace your entire engine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's wonderful.
Speaker 1: Great Yeah, I guess it's just that a lot of people Expect computer people to be able to work miracles like their expectations are a lot higher than what the reality is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's definitely what and also the other.
Speaker 0: the other problem is a lot of people.
Speaker 0: The problem I encountered the most is that even if someone has a fixable problem Is they cannot effectively communicate the problem and I'm pretty sure we did talk about this on a show before.
Speaker 1: I think we did so.
Speaker 1: we don't need to go into detail.
Speaker 1: But if someone messages me and says my Ubuntu broke my question is well, that's my answer is well that sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fix it for me.
Speaker 0: I mean you have to be in order for me to accurately Figure out what exactly is wrong with your computer and exactly how to fix it.
Speaker 0: I need Incredibly detailed information.
Speaker 0: I mean I need to know like the exact like models and names of your hardware exactly how they're configured lots and lots of configuration options in your operating system and your software and What software you have installed.
Speaker 0: most people don't know these pieces of information.
Speaker 0: if they knew those pieces of information Then it's likely they'd be able to fix the problems themselves and they wouldn't need computer people because they be computer people.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: this is this does present a very big problem in that How is someone who doesn't know about computers because not everyone knows about computers going to get their computer repaired Because they can't communicate the problem effectively and as a result anyone who knows how to fix it is not willing to spend the time It would take to diagnose the problem on their own.
Speaker 1: You have to free.
Speaker 0: you pretty much have to go to one of those places where you pay someone you give them the computer.
Speaker 0: So they can figure it out.
Speaker 0: you know because I can figure out the problem if I have hands-on access no matter what and Pay the money because it's not gonna be worth their time Otherwise,
Speaker 1: but even then there's also another problem where a lot of times people ask me how to do something with a computer Like how do I do this?
Speaker 1: or how can I make this worker like this was broken?
Speaker 1: How can I fix it?
Speaker 1: and I really don't know the answer like they'll ask things that like I just like something about Microsoft Word and I just I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I don't run into these problems.
Speaker 1: What's a good spyware remover?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: None of them don't get spyware.
Speaker 0: That's the only answer.
Speaker 0: don't get spyware Don't be stupid.
Speaker 0: all spyware removers suck and are imperfect.
Speaker 0: So sure some might protect you once in a while, you know, but none of them are perfect.
Speaker 0: None of them are like this universal panacea that will protect you from all spyware.
Speaker 0: But you see the only way to protect you from all spyware is to not be stupid.
Speaker 1: But that's what I'm getting at a lot of people like they look at like us.
Speaker 1: like I I mean, I'm an IT professional.
Speaker 1: I have never every job I've ever had has been like enterprise IT support like crazy big companies and all this like Stuff that I don't even do this stuff at home.
Speaker 1: Like I don't repair computer.
Speaker 1: like if a computer is a bad sick of RAM.
Speaker 1: I would just call some vendor to replace it.
Speaker 1: for me I wouldn't even think about opening the computer and fixing it myself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and as a result if someone has a spyware problem or like my hard drive is dying I got to get the data off my aunt.
Speaker 1: my answer from just my work experience is well You should have had a raid five.
Speaker 1: just replace one of those 10,000 rpm scuzzies.
Speaker 1: There's a pile of them in the back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind of like how.
Speaker 1: here's a good analogy.
Speaker 1: a lot of times people say like oh People who use calculators in school will never like they won't be able to do the basic stuff anymore Or they'll be dumb about math I won't be able to add.
Speaker 1: but at the same time having a calculator means you can attack Very difficult problems that might have otherwise been beyond human ability or beyond the time It would take for someone to calculate these things.
Speaker 1: But if someone does super high-level math, they might be bad at low-level math And they might not know anything about low-level math Do they not?
Speaker 1: might not be able to?
Speaker 1: Multiply two three digit numbers in their head quickly because they don't do that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: They're busy working on much more difficult problems And in a way a lot of computer repairs.
Speaker 1: the same way like the people who are the most qualified to fix your computer Problems are the people who are working on problems that are so far beyond Anything that any person is gonna have in their house that it's kind of useless in the real world outside of businesses.
Speaker 0: And here's the other thing right?
Speaker 0: So okay.
Speaker 0: You have a problem with your computer.
Speaker 0: Let's say it's it's a tricky problem You know let you know it's something that's gonna require some knowledges to fix right?
Speaker 0: So you take it to the local computer place, you know And you're gonna pay someone whose job it is to fix it.
Speaker 1: to fix it right you do with your car.
Speaker 1: if my car Makes a weird noise I Can pretty much look and see if there's a potato in the exhaust pipe and then I can look under the hood and make sure nothing crawled up in there and died.
Speaker 1: Beyond that I I gotta pay someone whatever they ask to fix it for me because I don't know.
Speaker 0: but now look at the world Of mechanics.
Speaker 0: right car mechanics because we keep using them because they're like the greatest analogy.
Speaker 0: There are mechanics of all shapes and sizes from everything from the guy who fixes cars at the local gas station To the guy who you know engineers for at Formula One, right?
Speaker 0: There's a there's a full range But there there is a large number of mechanics in the world.
Speaker 0: enough that demands.
Speaker 0: there's demand for mechanics with great skill and demand For mechanics with medium skill and demand for mechanics with low skill.
Speaker 1: I mean to kind of put that into very sharp relief.
Speaker 1: My car is kind of old.
Speaker 1: It's like a 98 Sunfire and it runs.
Speaker 1: Okay, barely I put a lot of miles on that thing and the front shocks are pretty much completely shot.
Speaker 1: When it had some problems about a year ago, I I didn't want to spend money on it.
Speaker 1: I pretty much just wanted the car to keep going barely.
Speaker 1: So I found a crappy mechanic who didn't charge much and did just enough to make the car keep going.
Speaker 0: Yep, and there is also a supply.
Speaker 0: there's a supply and a demand of mechanics of all levels of skill With computers.
Speaker 0: there is a supply of high-level people and this supply of low-level people.
Speaker 0: But but this problem is there is a demand the demand is applied You're not quite match up and what ends up happening is you have this Demand of computer home computers that need fixing and the only people who are really qualified to really fix them are people who are getting paid a lot more money a year to do things like programming or Network engineering or something like that.
Speaker 0: and you know because you know They're doing much bigger things and they happen to know how to fix desktops because it's sort of a prerequisite knowledge.
Speaker 0: and the people You know who are less skilled than them who are actually, you know, not Incredibly wealthy or incredibly gainfully employed in a fancy job that pays a lot of money a year.
Speaker 0: They don't might not have the skill to fix all the desktop.
Speaker 0: So there's very few people in the world who are In a position where they know enough to fix any desktop computer problem you may have or the most of them.
Speaker 0: But they somehow aren't able or don't want to get a big high-paying job to where fixing a desktop computer Would be a waste of their time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean think of this in most jobs I've had.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: I remember one time at one company I was working for my desktop computer like broke.
Speaker 1: it didn't boot and I'm sitting there.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to fix it.
Speaker 1: I'm like, alright looks like the Rams bad.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get this going and my boss comes in.
Speaker 1: It's like what are you doing?
Speaker 1: Like my computer broke?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna fix it.
Speaker 1: He's like, what are you crazy?
Speaker 1: We have people that are paid like a quarter what you're paid to do that for you.
Speaker 1: You go use some other computer and I'll call someone to fix this.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's like it's not for companies.
Speaker 1: It's not worth the money to even pay someone who works on high-level things.
Speaker 1: even look at a low-level thing.
Speaker 1: They hire a low-level person and there aren't enough of those people.
Speaker 0: No, because I mean think about it if you know how to fix most problems with a desktop I think about that low-level person that your boss probably called.
Speaker 0: Probably took like twice as long to fix your computer as you would have might not have even you know.
Speaker 0: They probably just got it by fooling around or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean I could have fixed it as fast as I could have and As fast as I was working.
Speaker 1: it still wouldn't have been worth it to my employer for me to spend time working on that.
Speaker 0: It's worth it more.
Speaker 0: It's worth more to them to have rim.
Speaker 0: keep doing this fancy thing and have someone Take twice or three times as long to fix his desktop computer who doesn't know as much as rim does And that's just in a company.
Speaker 1: What about home people?
Speaker 1: I mean you're no.
Speaker 1: your home user is willing to pay 40 50 60 90 dollars a half hour to have some high-powered enterprise IT guy Come and fix their computer for him, but there's no one else who's qualified to do it.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like the only person who's qualified to solve.
Speaker 0: Imagine if it's like if everyone was driving f1 cars and the only people qualified to fix them were these f1 Mechanics and there weren't so many of them and they were all working for formula one getting paid hundreds of millions of dollars.
Speaker 0: So what are all these normal people who have f1 cars?
Speaker 0: What are they gonna do when their f1 cars break their SOL?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they can have someone who's kind of crappy try to fix it and do a shitty job for a little bit of money But that's never gonna be a perfect solution.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have to just give up eventually and this is why I think we're seeing a lot of people like when they get spy we're on the computer they just throw it out and buy a new one and Computers are kind of cheap.
Speaker 0: It's almost not a bad idea as long as you know Someone smart can rescue that computer from the trash because nothing wrong with it.
Speaker 1: Yep, of course the easier way instead of throwing it out.
Speaker 1: Just convince it like go to someone say yeah for a hundred bucks I'll fix your computer and then just you know reinstall windows and give it back to them.
Speaker 0: Yep That's the problem though is you know the solution like fixing your car right is if your car breaks What's the solution?
Speaker 0: get it to drive again?
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: it's not like you'll ever have a problem where I get your car to drive again.
Speaker 0: But now your air conditioning is broke, you know, you have to choose one of the other but with your computer Sometimes it can happen where well I can get your computer to work again, but you're gonna lose all your word documents.
Speaker 0: That's the only you know.
Speaker 0: It's a choice you're gonna have to make and that sort of compromise is sort of like, uh, it's all.
Speaker 0: it's like you're screwed.
Speaker 0: There's a point at which you're just sol that there's nothing you can do to get it to be perfect.
Speaker 0: There's no perfect fix.
Speaker 0: It's not possible.
Speaker 0: It's not worth anyone's time money or effort to implement a perfect fix if it is positive.
Speaker 1: a lot of people I think we said this before so I'm not gonna dwell on it But a lot of people they think about their car and they kind of owning a car The cost of periodic repairs and oil change and maintenance and all those things.
Speaker 1: It's kind of assumed like they know they got to take it to get an oil change periodically They gotta pay someone to do it, but they take some they take it to get an oil change and they pay someone else.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: But when it comes to computers people don't have the same perception.
Speaker 1: They buy a computer and they don't think about the fact that someone has to you know Effectively change the oil periodically and do routine maintenance on it.
Speaker 0: You don't really need to change the oil so much you just need to not screw it up.
Speaker 0: It's it's like it's.
Speaker 0: it's like a car just in its natural use even if you drive it nicely and carefully and you're good To it, you know and you you warm it up and you know, you're you drive very nicely.
Speaker 0: You don't need to warm up modern car No But it's gonna need an oil change just because of wear and tear.
Speaker 0: a computer doesn't get worn and torn unless you Specifically do things with the computer that you know break down the system like installing shitty software or Configuring something poor or even little things like not organizing your files.
Speaker 1: I mean I would say that's kind of.
Speaker 1: the difference is that computers require a lot of Proactive maintenance as opposed to reactive maintenance like on a car.
Speaker 0: I don't really consider it proactive maintenance more as not smashing it with a hammer.
Speaker 1: You have to really just kind of be careful, but that's only if you know if you don't know I mean when I got my first computer 486 I broke that thing on a daily basis, but there was no one to fix it for me.
Speaker 1: So I fixed it myself and I got to fix it.
Speaker 0: Well, that's sort of a take the clock apart and put it back together.
Speaker 0: method of learning more than a.
Speaker 1: yeah You know breaking by breaking by accident I mean I hate to say it but I think I do actually have a solution to this whole problem and I think just Society is changing rapidly.
Speaker 1: I mean the the computers and the internet I think are going to be as I think they already have had as much of an effect as the Industrial Revolution and it's only getting faster.
Speaker 1: Not like maybe this last generation will be the last one but starting with the next generation.
Speaker 1: like people who are kids today I just being computer illiterate or not having just the most basic of computer skills is going to be the same as being Completely illiterate in the mind the future world you I think society
Speaker 0: think about right now what it's like for a person who can't read Or write to live and not reader, you know not read or write any specific language, you know Spanish and something that
Speaker 1: we're talking about.
Speaker 1: or when I started my new job and I'm all pop Python and they're all pearl.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm talking about someone who cannot read or write any language.
Speaker 0: Think about what their life is like and how hard it is.
Speaker 0: They can't get a job.
Speaker 0: They can't even like do work at McDonald's, right?
Speaker 0: It's they basically are.
Speaker 0: they're incapable of functioning within society above like the lowest levels.
Speaker 0: That's what it's gonna be like for someone who doesn't know how to you.
Speaker 0: in a few years Someone who doesn't know how to use a computer is gonna have that same trouble.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna be able to do anything or interact with society Above the lowest levels and I can be able to get any job.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna be able to do anything meaningful or nothing.
Speaker 0: They do will be worthwhile.
Speaker 0: They'll be a useless person that won't be able to do anything productive won't be able to earn money won't be able to Conduct business in any way until they learn and it's it's gonna suck for those people.
Speaker 1: And I think in the end this problem is only gonna solve itself just by the general public having a basic Understanding of how computers work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that's the one thing with cars is because of the way cars are.
Speaker 0: I mean you do need a car at least in the US, you know in most parts of it.
Speaker 0: Anyway outside of you know, incredibly densely populated urban areas where there is public transportation Yeah, even though there should be more public transportation.
Speaker 1: That's a separate show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should do man.
Speaker 0: We are the separate show show.
Speaker 1: talk about Roger Rabbit.
Speaker 1: Yep, and cloverly.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you know you need a car But you don't need to know how to take care of a car.
Speaker 1: because you set up this sort of infrastructure Cars, I mean, I think the only the analogy can kind of work.
Speaker 0: There is no Imaginable infrastructure we can set up around personal computers to where people wouldn't have to know anything about them.
Speaker 1: I think we could if there were just a Slightly higher basic understanding like the way computers are now would be.
Speaker 1: imagine if now I mean people know how to drive cars Generally before they were allowed to drive cars.
Speaker 1: imagine if like the average person didn't know you had to get oil changes and didn't know that you had to use a turn signal and it never heard of a headlight and didn't realize that you have to Close the door to the car after you get into it when before you start driving Mmm, and you know people just driving backwards cuz like their mom did it that way and they don't know better.
Speaker 1: so they do it that way too.
Speaker 1: and that's what the computer world is like now.
Speaker 1: and Computer repairmen have to deal with that sort of thing the same way that mechanics would have to deal with no one in America knowing That they have to change their oil and engine seizing up.
Speaker 0: You know mechanics do sometimes have to deal with that level of stupidity, but not as often but not very often You know, the valve lean is always crowded.
Speaker 0: people are getting their instant oil changes, you know.
Speaker 0: But computers you got this.
Speaker 0: you still have people putting their coffee cups in the CD room.
Speaker 0: It still happens.
Speaker 0: It's pretty sad.
Speaker 1: But I mean at the same time look at it this way and right now if you know a little bit about cars You can save a lot of money on car repairs by knowing a little bit.
Speaker 1: Like if I go to a mechanic and say cars making a funny noise That's gonna cost me a lot of money to get fixed.
Speaker 1: if I go in and say the cars making a funny noise I think it's because my distributor coil is cracked.
Speaker 1: Look I sprayed some water on it in the car stalled.
Speaker 1: I think that's it.
Speaker 1: It's gonna cost me very little to get that fixed.
Speaker 0: Or even if it doesn't cost you any less to get it fixed it'll get fixed a lot sooner All right.
Speaker 1: I think we've ran it about that enough.
Speaker 1: I hope we didn't do a show about this in the past But I don't think we'll need to do one again in the near future.
Speaker 0: No, it just keeps coming up lately.
Speaker 0: cuz you know, there's more and more people, you know asking at least lately like hey fix You know, I guess happens in the holiday season when families get together and you know people like there's a lot more people going home To their families and then they their family computer has a problem and they they ask someone they know Hey my fan, you know, I'm at my mom's house.
Speaker 0: Whatever lately.
Speaker 1: My answer has been Which if I were a dentist, would you ask me to operate on your tooth right now?
Speaker 0: Yeah, my uncle's a dentist and you know sometimes, you know, people don't ask him to operate on the tooth right now But they'll say, you know, hey, I've been having a whatever whatever and he said, you know what?
Speaker 0: He always says make an appointment appointment.
Speaker 0: I'll take a look at.
Speaker 1: I would however trade services.
Speaker 1: I mean if I knew a mechanic and it was like I'll fix your computer you fix my car.
Speaker 0: I'm happy to fix someone's computer.
Speaker 0: the problem, you know, the problems are when they.
Speaker 1: well, the problem is opportunity cost.
Speaker 0: Yeah opportunity cost.
Speaker 0: and can I actually fix it?
Speaker 0: and how long is it gonna take?
Speaker 0: and am I just you know?
Speaker 0: If it's gonna take if it's possible see if a problem it's possible to fix perfectly and I'll.
Speaker 0: that'll take six hours.
Speaker 0: Reinstalling Windows takes one hour.
Speaker 0: installing Ubuntu takes 30 minutes.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna spend the five hours, even though it's possible find someone else forget it.
Speaker 0: It's not happening.
Speaker 1: Alright, I think we're done for tonight.
Speaker 1: I'm still kind of wrecked from the New York anime festival.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm pretty wrecked too.
Speaker 0: I gotta go.
Speaker 1: by the way If anyone is still listening and cares we will be talking about that extensively on Wednesday and possibly on Thursday, too Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at Frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.