Speaker 0: It's Monday November 5th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about information technology warfare.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Anything else going on?
Speaker 1: no no nothing.
Speaker 1: Just want to like do news?
Speaker 1: or yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've been sitting here for the last half hour waiting for you to be ready to do the show.
Speaker 1: I was watching the video waiting for you.
Speaker 0: I said you want to do the show.
Speaker 0: you said no.
Speaker 0: after I watch this video You want to do the show now after I do this thing you want to the show now?
Speaker 1: whatever I Got all this.
Speaker 1: I got all this stuff to like.
Speaker 1: take care of because my credit card expires in like October.
Speaker 1: Oh wait, but because it like before they renewed it it was going to expire in October.
Speaker 1: Oh seven like certain places think.
Speaker 1: my credit card expired so I had to run around changing it But I didn't have passwords or account numbers because I don't actually do them.
Speaker 1: I do everything automatically with no mail, so I don't know the number.
Speaker 0: That's the benefit of one.
Speaker 0: I have two credit cards one that expires you know regularly It's a normal credit card and one that expires in like 2014 and I use that just for recurring things.
Speaker 1: yeah, and then I've got.
Speaker 1: You know I got like get some tires for my car before it snows probably this weekend.
Speaker 1: I got laundry to do which I was gonna do yesterday Which I didn't do which is gonna do today, which I didn't do.
Speaker 1: so I'm gonna have to do it tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you do it?
Speaker 0: I didn't Haha, did.
Speaker 0: uh perhaps it was because of Mario 3 maybe because Mario 3 partially, huh?
Speaker 0: I was really surprised to come home and find you not playing Mario 3.
Speaker 1: I got to.
Speaker 1: you know I got to world 3 and then I sort of stopped.
Speaker 0: You know you got a war to world 5 the best world.
Speaker 1: Well, I was going to.
Speaker 1: I told myself I said if I if I rim cut walked in the door.
Speaker 1: I said you know what.
Speaker 1: I have a plan.
Speaker 1: I'm going for the shoe and just have the shoe open when I get there Maybe but I was I was gonna.
Speaker 1: I think what I do is I'm gonna go through worlds 3 & 4 and then get the shoe.
Speaker 0: see that's the thing.
Speaker 0: now That's on the virtual console.
Speaker 0: I'm probably gonna play through the whole thing in order just because a Lot of parts that game are really really fun like world 4 world 5.
Speaker 1: right now I'm in my most hated world, which is the world in world 3 where you can get infinite lives of the locky - Yeah, I wanted I wanted to try try to get the infant lives and I gave up.
Speaker 0: I did the infinite lives in world 2 with the goombas that keep coming out of the pipe.
Speaker 0: boo.
Speaker 1: That's the shitty way you got to do the bouncing back and forth turtle shell with the locky - throwing spiny's in I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like the because it takes skill to keep hitting those goombas in just the right pattern whatever Any anything else thing?
Speaker 0: Oh, no Let's just get right into it because we've been going along actually a lot lately and we're pushing the lips in to the max.
Speaker 1: Oh, so let's keep it short.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we can do that.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right, so we'll save Scott's news because I Got a. I bought one.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm gonna buy one or maybe one wasn't able to be bought or we'll get into that Once again, the internet is wrong and dig is wrong and gadget is right, but my news I'm not gonna talk about you think I'm gonna talk about but I'm in terms of.
Speaker 0: There's this article here on slash dot and there are similar articles in every, you know Copycat crap blog everywhere about how cell phone jamming is on the rise.
Speaker 0: now people are buying these.
Speaker 0: You know They're so frustrated with people who just yap on their cell phone in public places or in movies or in stores or on trains or In subways that they're buying these portable devices that jam cell phones.
Speaker 0: Now aside from the fact that one that's illegal - it's stupid.
Speaker 0: three Just deal with it.
Speaker 0: or four go to places where they have policies that just say you can't use a cell phone.
Speaker 0: They kick anyone out.
Speaker 0: who does?
Speaker 0: but I'm what I'm gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: it's not so much that technology, but the fact that Funny how all these articles suddenly appeared and how oh, there's actually products that are kind of associated with this.
Speaker 0: This is once again.
Speaker 0: I if I am not mistaken an example of a fake market.
Speaker 0: It was not really a fake bar That's all it is.
Speaker 0: it's a fake not really grassroots but like they put a bunch of buzz out.
Speaker 0: Pretending the buzz says that this thing is getting really popular.
Speaker 1: if you haven't already heard Yeah, if you buy your local newspaper and in it you see an article that says cell phone jammers Controversy, you know, they're their.
Speaker 1: cell phone jammers are made by the following companies This company makes this one and this company makes this one.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: That's not some reporter at your newspaper going out and getting the scoop on this that say that same Article or a similar articles in every newspaper and the companies that make those products went to those newspapers and had those articles written.
Speaker 1: That's how PR works.
Speaker 1: Welcome to the world.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I mean, I think the worst example I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: I was in Yonkers reading some Yonkers paper.
Speaker 0: I'm just flipping through.
Speaker 0: it is a terrible paper.
Speaker 0: But then there's this article about the rise in popularity of renting handbags.
Speaker 0: That's right can't afford the four thousand dollar like super fancy handbag.
Speaker 0: You can rent it for a hundred dollars a week for as long as you need it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if that's not PR, I don't know.
Speaker 0: it is Yeah, and they talked about how this is like really popular among the nouveau riche God, yeah, regardless cell phone jamming.
Speaker 1: It's illegal illegal and it should be.
Speaker 1: yes I mean if you need a reason I could argue for like an hour of why it should be illegal.
Speaker 1: But I'll just say one thing Nine one one I win.
Speaker 0: Yep, or even doctors with pagers.
Speaker 1: I win again.
Speaker 0: Yep, firemen the real issue is people.
Speaker 0: a lot of people complain about cell phones being used in public places.
Speaker 0: But there are two kinds of people that complain.
Speaker 0: the first kind is called evil.
Speaker 0: No, that's that's the third kind.
Speaker 0: So there are two kinds three three guys The people.
Speaker 0: But the first kind which is kind of legitimate is When you're on the train You're in the restaurant and there's that one guy in the corner and you hear the following.
Speaker 0: So I says to him.
Speaker 0: Hey, can you hear me?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I says to him.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm yelling.
Speaker 0: I'm yelling into my cell phone.
Speaker 1: The problem there is not the cell phone.
Speaker 1: The problem there is someone being loud in a quiet place like in a library being loud Cellphone or not.
Speaker 1: cell phone is not the problem.
Speaker 0: The loud and quiet place is the problem or not even loud and quiet but also inconsiderate jackass among non inconsiderate non jackasses Uh-huh, and the cell phone is just an enabler.
Speaker 0: It's not the root cause Yep, but to the other kind of people complain about people just using cell phones and not like oh he's driving with the cell phone.
Speaker 0: But I've seen people and I've been with people who complained about someone who's just walking down the street or in the grocery store Talking quietly no louder than if they'd been talking to someone next to them on a cell phone.
Speaker 0: How is that any more annoying than someone just talking to someone?
Speaker 1: I think that's that's the old people, you know They just did say young whippersnappers doing your newfangled.
Speaker 0: We got a core.
Speaker 0: much like when we say fat people We don't be like.
Speaker 0: we mean, you know, when we say old people we don't need mean old of age We mean old of spirit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and not the cool venerable like respect your elders old of spirit.
Speaker 0: I mean crotchety of spirit The crotch.
Speaker 0: there's a.
Speaker 1: I'm playing the Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: I guess it's why we talk about so much about games on Monday, but there's a crowd.
Speaker 1: There is a character who is crotchety and old in spirit.
Speaker 0: But there's also a character who was sexy and awesome despite the fact that he has scientific eyes.
Speaker 1: No there.
Speaker 1: but there are sexy women characters Trying to avoid that one anyway, so Everyone knows if you pay attention to the Internet's that so-called Google phone something was gonna be announced today.
Speaker 0: But wait according to dig it was announced and it's free.
Speaker 0: It makes puppies.
Speaker 0: every time you make a call and the puppies are free and don't need to eat you can fly.
Speaker 0: It solved world hunger.
Speaker 0: it works on Verizon.
Speaker 0: it's the same as the iPhone only better.
Speaker 0: Right now it has Bluetooth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm a to 11 a BGN X. All right, you're done.
Speaker 1: The point is is that Engadget knew what was going on.
Speaker 1: They said what was going on.
Speaker 1: people decided to say more was going on than when Engadget said thinking they knew better.
Speaker 1: Engadget put up the story today with the real scoop, which is exactly what they said It was gonna be which is what happens every time Anything like this happens.
Speaker 1: Engadget knows a hundred percent because they have their inside secret sources.
Speaker 0: pretty much It's coming down to.
Speaker 0: if you see news on dig about technology and the first place and only place you see I saw it was dig.
Speaker 0: It's probably not true.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So what is the story with this Google phone of some sorts?
Speaker 1: Well, there's two stories here.
Speaker 1: The first story is that Google bought a while ago.
Speaker 1: They bought this company called Android.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows they bought this company called Android.
Speaker 1: It was public news.
Speaker 1: they didn't make a big deal out of it, but it happened and it was publicly available information and That company was making a mobile platform basically an operating system for phones much like Symbian or palm or any of those or Windows mobile and Google bought it and it's Linux based and they're gonna put it out and it's gonna be open which means People can make applications for it and people can modify it and all that business.
Speaker 1: Also, there's the second bit of news is that there is an open handset alliance They have formed of 33 different Companies that are involved in phones in some way and all these people have vowed to support this platform in some way.
Speaker 1: you know, they're all.
Speaker 1: they're all in on this right and Microsoft palm Apple not so in on this I know Not so in on it, but everyone else in.
Speaker 0: so yes everyone else the vast number of people Who have power in this industry.
Speaker 0: Well, no 33.
Speaker 1: It's basically 33 It's basically all the small guys and Google verse the four big guys.
Speaker 0: The thing is if all the stated like if it works if all this comes to be really then I think they'll win.
Speaker 1: Well, no, you see because the thing is while they're gonna you know, it's gonna be a Linux based operating system of whatever, right?
Speaker 1: but You know and if you you could get a copy of it probably off the internet and you could make software for it.
Speaker 1: But there's nothing that says say if t-mobile puts it on their phones that it'll be available You know not locked down so you can modify it like on your phone.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: no you know, it's it's it's no.
Speaker 1: it's basically saying yeah, there's gonna be yet another operating system for phones and Supposedly this one is better than all the other ones out there except for I guess iPhone or maybe hopefully better than iPhone I don't know.
Speaker 0: Well iPhone would be better if it included certain specific features Basically that you know It's.
Speaker 1: I think what's just gonna end up happening is there will be yet another phone operating system That will be better than all the other ones And you know at least in terms of interface and features, but who knows exactly how far it will go?
Speaker 1: I don't really think it's gonna be the promised Savior.
Speaker 0: Well, I think one it is definitely a step in the right direction That's for sure.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is a problem as a whole that can't really be solved in one fell swoop without government interaction, which is Obviously a loaded event that is probably not desirable in the end.
Speaker 1: loaded.
Speaker 1: It's like three times.
Speaker 1: It's not just loaded.
Speaker 1: It's like elites.
Speaker 0: There's two of them but if this were say coupled with lobbying efforts that eventually forced Interoperability or non lockdown this or any sort of thing like that.
Speaker 0: Then suddenly this becomes a very big deal Becomes a very big deal.
Speaker 1: You know someone did ask during the thing about the the 700 megahertz auction Which maybe we should talk about sometime exactly what the deal with is, but if I do a show on that Yeah, but the whole idea of like the FCC and controlling frequencies and what what?
Speaker 0: yeah, let's do that.
Speaker 1: The general idea is that doesn't?
Speaker 1: there's gonna be a spectrum auction for the 700 megahertz spectrum Which is a pretty hot spectrum.
Speaker 0: and if Google seriously think of this is I think the BBC used the term beachfront property.
Speaker 1: Now Basically, all you need to know about this right now cuz I'm not gonna talk anymore about it Is that if Google wins the auction we win too.
Speaker 1: if anyone else wins the auction we lose.
Speaker 1: So if you have money to buy Google shares, which are like $700 apiece, I think yeah.
Speaker 0: I remember I wanted to bid on their IPO and I thought like what's the most?
Speaker 0: I cuz it was a weird IPO Where you had like bid an amount of money.
Speaker 1: it was like a Dutch auction thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah It seemed to work out for them because then when it happened like I tried to guess at what the price would eventually end up At and I was off by almost two orders of bag.
Speaker 1: It's not the close of trading today, November 5th.
Speaker 1: Google shares are seven hundred and twenty five dollars and sixty five cents.
Speaker 0: Well, uh, I guess if I use my credit card, I could buy a few I And full of them.
Speaker 0: I Feel like I should buy one.
Speaker 1: Well, the more you buy the better chance Google has of winning the auction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we should really do a show about that because a lot of people are can feel like you said really confused by what?
Speaker 0: These auctions mean and also why the 700 range is so much I guess more important than the much more easily available high frequency bands.
Speaker 0: The real like real.
Speaker 0: long and short of it is this and long and short of it is kind of a pun.
Speaker 0: but Low frequency good penetrates things better high frequency bad blocked by your house.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's as simple as I can put it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's about good things of the day.
Speaker 0: So let's say someone took a picture at their wedding and then You know later they look at the pictures and they see that Their dog was like poking out from a stair railing over the guy's shoulder.
Speaker 0: Well, how do you how do you think you would react to that if one of your wedding pictures had your dog looking at you?
Speaker 0: In the background.
Speaker 1: No, that's not so bad.
Speaker 0: Well, uh Photoshop if it bothers you that much this family, I guess didn't recognize their own dog decided It was a demon freaked out called Fox News.
Speaker 0: Fox News does this story about oh my god creepy photo And it's clearly a dog like unambiguously a dog looking over the guy's shoulder.
Speaker 1: uh-huh, so What's the is that?
Speaker 1: is that it?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: But I mean, here's the Fox News breaking.
Speaker 0: It's a picture you really have to look at and when you do you notice something is not quite normal.
Speaker 0: In fact, it might be paranormal.
Speaker 0: Fox 31's Tammy vigil report.
Speaker 1: if it is I got a million dollars for you.
Speaker 0: Million.
Speaker 0: There are things like this all the time, but it's like you.
Speaker 1: I saw Jesus in my French toast.
Speaker 0: It's not even that it's a dog.
Speaker 0: It's so obviously a dog.
Speaker 0: you would have to be the rain mad would say it's a dog like you got one dog.
Speaker 0: But serious and even if it wasn't a dog it's still obviously not a demon.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, it was a demon at your wedding.
Speaker 1: Your wedding's cursed.
Speaker 1: You better break up You're gonna bring more stupidity into the world.
Speaker 0: I mean you could argue that me wedding was not meant to be.
Speaker 0: Maybe it looks like a champagne bottle, but no, it's a dog.
Speaker 0: It's a dog a dog.
Speaker 1: It looks like a champagne bottle.
Speaker 1: I can't see this picture.
Speaker 1: You need to rotate your chair.
Speaker 1: That's a dog.
Speaker 1: I Can see from here it's a dog.
Speaker 0: All right, so I'll just leave it.
Speaker 0: there's a video.
Speaker 0: you can see the people who took the picture reacting and these people are either lying for attention or really really dumb.
Speaker 1: Yep, well Everyone likes toilet humor.
Speaker 1: You like toilet humor.
Speaker 0: I am a man who for some four years read poop report every week.
Speaker 0: P Have I talked about poop report on this show?
Speaker 1: You will later.
Speaker 1: so Today I saw this video from the World Toilet Summit and Expo 2007 in New Delhi India.
Speaker 0: that sounds like an awesome place to be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like toilet Expo not New Delhi.
Speaker 1: It's like a big trade show for toilets and toilet and you know I guess what's it called septic technologies?
Speaker 0: so I have a question does this conference address the fact that the u.s.
Speaker 0: is Pretty much a third world country when it comes to having an enjoyable peeing experience?
Speaker 1: I think it might.
Speaker 1: in some places.
Speaker 1: they had a lot of very fancy and futuristic toilets.
Speaker 1: You know trying all sorts of innovation in the waste disposal, you know Futuristic.
Speaker 0: you mean they had him 40 years ago in Japan, right?
Speaker 1: Well, they actually had some stuff that you know You know actually new as far as the world is concerned.
Speaker 0: Yeah but but also I'm just really complaining about the fact that I can't have an enjoyable pee in the u.s.
Speaker 1: A lot of what they're focusing on though is the fact that most of the world doesn't have toilets.
Speaker 1: There are people without toilets and they're like, hey the UN is trying to get toilets.
Speaker 0: You know, see it's tricky because America has toilets, but they're old wasteful toilets or they're low flow toilets.
Speaker 0: Other than German toilets, I think we have the worst toilets in the developed world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe except for the completely absolutely no toilets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at least when there's that well I'm not gonna get into that because that's a whole other problem and I guess I should feel bad Complaining that my peeing experience is somewhat so optimal when there are people who pee in the water.
Speaker 0: They drink.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time I really think we could have better toilets in the u.s.
Speaker 1: If the only way if it was like a pond, right Why would I?
Speaker 1: I would just pee on the ground instead of the water in the ground?
Speaker 0: Okay Now there's a lot of people and they all pee in the ground and then it rains and that seeps into your drinking water And there's really no way around that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it wouldn't be as bad as everyone peeing directly in the war like in the movie the man who would be king.
Speaker 0: You know how he conquers all the tribes and goes up the river because every tribe downriver Hates the tribe up the river.
Speaker 0: cuz they pee in the river Cuz they don't care.
Speaker 0: Cuz there's not.
Speaker 0: obviously there's nothing downriver that matters except the other Sean Connery.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't see that movie.
Speaker 0: So that's the movie Jess was trying to make you watch cuz it's awesome.
Speaker 1: But anyway, you watch this and there's some pretty interesting Pee and poop technologies here that you can be amused by especially this one girl.
Speaker 1: She's like way younger than us.
Speaker 1: like she I think he's like a teenager But she invented some sort of cool way for trains to dump their waste without.
Speaker 0: you know The US wastes a lot of water Which is particularly bad because people in the south waste water that they're buying from the north that is depleting the Great Lakes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a real problem with just people insisting on living in places that don't have water.
Speaker 0: It's not even that because they could.
Speaker 0: there are ways to do that.
Speaker 0: very well.
Speaker 0: The problem is and as my mother put pointed out so angrily There are people who live in New York and they get sick in New York and they want to move out west.
Speaker 0: They moved to Arizona But then they decide that they want a golf course and a green sod lawn and they have a sandy golf course.
Speaker 0: No These people have greener lawns than I had when I lived in the suburbs in Michigan in the middle of the desert.
Speaker 1: I don't understand the obsession with what your lawn looks like.
Speaker 1: I really.
Speaker 1: I just don't get any.
Speaker 1: as long as it's not like a forest and you can't walk around because it's you know Full of ticks and things.
Speaker 0: my line the line between lawn is okay and law needs something done about it is When there are dead things hidden in the law.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty mad is pretty much the line that's my line also or when it's dangerous to walk across my lawn.
Speaker 0: But maybe if the US adopted some of these technologies, which we could but we don't for reasons that are very complicated.
Speaker 0: Actually, they're not complicated at all Like in America, right?
Speaker 0: We have high flow toilets and they're awesome.
Speaker 0: My poop goes away and that's probably time doesn't cloud the most important thing to me Yep, but then oh they're waste a lot of water.
Speaker 0: All right, let's use low flow toilets.
Speaker 1: now My poop is still there.
Speaker 0: I flush.
Speaker 0: He won't go away.
Speaker 0: He's still there.
Speaker 0: flush again.
Speaker 0: Poop still there.
Speaker 0: take like the Cardboard the toilet paper.
Speaker 0: bring the poo into you float you.
Speaker 1: now you've put flush so many times that you've wasted more water.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like the low flow showerhead great.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: I take a shower twice as long because I couldn't clean myself Yep, but there are places like Japan where they just have two buttons a button if you have a big thing and a button if You have a little thing and the little button uses low flow and the big button gets rid of my poop.
Speaker 1: I guess Americans are just too stupid to have two buttons.
Speaker 1: I mean, they can't even use like a computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we'll leave it at that you got.
Speaker 1: these old people can't even use a cell phone even though it's just like phones.
Speaker 1: They've used their whole.
Speaker 0: you know what they probably think like oh man back in the day toilets were great.
Speaker 0: What happened to this country?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh Old people making everything bad for everyone else.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So speaking of old people.
Speaker 0: I don't know speaking of Anything.
Speaker 0: our topic tonight is something kind of out of the blue because we couldn't come up with much else.
Speaker 0: Scott doesn't know much about science.
Speaker 1: I know about science averagely across the board.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about something that's in the news kind of often But yet I don't think a lot of people really understand and we're gonna talk about this in a very kind of non technical overview way just to get an idea of What it what does matter and what you should worry about but more importantly what you shouldn't worry about?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm people talk a lot about IT warfare or computer warfare internet warfare cyber war.
Speaker 0: China's got a cyber army ready to strike and yeah, you know Russia attacked Estonia a while ago, which is true.
Speaker 1: Yep, okay first of all You got to realize that the vast majority of this stuff is just fear mongering.
Speaker 1: people are coming up with words like cyber war To try to scare you and make you think that you know, there's dangerous hackers coming to get you.
Speaker 1: Oh, no running hide computers of the devil.
Speaker 0: now I'll say this you have to.
Speaker 0: you have a lot more to be afraid of by clicking on spam and being phished or Just having someone steal your credit card information from some company you shopped with five years.
Speaker 1: You have more to worry about Nigerian scams.
Speaker 0: I think you have more to worry about driving your car.
Speaker 0: Oh, definitely, but at the same time that what the real issue with cyber warfare is not OMG China's gonna get you.
Speaker 0: but the fact that cyber warfare is something that hasn't really been I guess vetted out by the armies and militaries of the world.
Speaker 0: and Eventually, there's going to be a war of some kind.
Speaker 0: Yep in the modern world I mean think of this.
Speaker 0: when was the last time there was a war between two powers that were both fully industrialized or at least equally industrialized and above the level of poverty?
Speaker 0: or third-world?
Speaker 1: Me me.
Speaker 0: Oh me.
Speaker 1: I'll get islands pop possible.
Speaker 1: Ah, yeah.
Speaker 0: And how did the Falken Islands go?
Speaker 1: not too well for either side?
Speaker 0: I Mean as a zero punctuation pointed out so eloquently.
Speaker 0: most of America's wars recently have involves stomping on people who can't fight back And then walking away merrily.
Speaker 0: Something like that, but it's very rare not?
Speaker 0: I mean the Falkland Islands and before that what World War two The Korean War and even then the Korean War was more a matter of the.
Speaker 0: well I guess the Korean War and the Falklands were similar in one regard.
Speaker 0: It was a super powerful country Extending its power very far away from itself and thus was only able to expend a very small part of its power and thus was able to be Held off by a technologically inferior foe like that Vietnam or that Iraq.
Speaker 0: Oh But There has not been a time really since and I know some military people might disagree.
Speaker 0: But I'm talking broadly in terms of technology.
Speaker 0: World War two was probably I mean that was when there were powers that were Relatively equal in technology.
Speaker 0: In fact, the Germans outpaced the rest of the powers pretty substantially in technology.
Speaker 1: The new boats watch out.
Speaker 0: new kinds of warfare appeared then and war was a very uncertain business because it wasn't like war had been Before.
Speaker 0: World War one was similar.
Speaker 0: It was a kind of warfare that had barely been tested.
Speaker 0: people didn't know what to expect.
Speaker 0: people tried old Things and World War two had that too.
Speaker 0: I mean the Majano line.
Speaker 0: that was hot shit.
Speaker 1: It was hot shit.
Speaker 1: That's why they walked around it because if they went in.
Speaker 0: Except theoretically the Majano line was so obsolete by the time it came into play that the Germans probably could have stomped over.
Speaker 1: Regardless maybe it's a tough call.
Speaker 1: well because the thing even though is obsolete it was still a lot of really big guns.
Speaker 1: and you know Even if I come in here with an obsolete old-ass gun, I guess they'll blow your brain.
Speaker 0: It was big guns but it was big guns designed to be used against a slow marching army and it was defense of.
Speaker 0: Well, it wasn't defensive death and if the Germans just paratroop it a bunch of people behind it, huh?
Speaker 1: They might.
Speaker 1: or maybe yeah, it would have been tough.
Speaker 0: I've read accounts both ways but the point is that I think the Germans had the better plan of walk around though to not go into a lot of Because I kept introducing topics and then realizing that I had a lot to say and trying to back out.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: the point is cyber warfare is a new kind of warfare that has not been tested and No one really knows what to expect and the the kinds of fighting that would go on are possibly Alien to even modern powers like the United States because kind of like how the great reason Napoleon was able to do So well was that he used very simple tactics that no just no one else had thought of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well cyber warfare pretty much boils down to this, right?
Speaker 1: When you're when you're at war with someone, you know for real, right?
Speaker 1: You generally want to hurt them or their infrastructure or you know them in some way.
Speaker 0: and yeah war is not like it was before the world wars where you know Two armies would march out to the field and talk a little bit and agree on a place and then stand nicely in line Shooting at each other for an hour.
Speaker 1: So, you know many industrialized countries in the world and even not so industrialized countries have a lot of technology be it You know computers on the internet or other things that they rely on Heavily.
Speaker 1: and if though, you know Like think about it if your computer if every computer in your house stops working for a week that bothers you a bit.
Speaker 1: Imagine if every computer at a company stopped working for a week.
Speaker 1: Alright now imagine if say every computer for the state government stopped working for a week.
Speaker 0: Well knowing the u.s.
Speaker 0: That would have no effect on anything.
Speaker 1: But I know.
Speaker 1: but the point is is that when you you know You depend on technology and even if you don't depend on it and you still have you know The backup of paper or whatever, you know It's it's.
Speaker 1: it is madly less efficient than we're used to and you're going to be hindered.
Speaker 1: and if your opponent Still has the efficient computers working and you don't you're at a disadvantage.
Speaker 1: So cyber warfare what really boils down to is Someone is using technology and there are things you can do to disable enemy technology and slow them down Damage them or make them less efficient than you.
Speaker 1: that aren't really.
Speaker 1: Don't really fit into the idea of classical warfare.
Speaker 1: blow them up or you know stuff or steal their stuff.
Speaker 0: and furthermore I mean it just comes down to if you're if it's an actual war total warfare the point where you were fighting Holy as a nation.
Speaker 0: No nations mobilized for war.
Speaker 0: in that case much like the carpet bombings of the days of yore You Generally try to do whatever you can to disrupt the economy and the daily lives of people in the country.
Speaker 0: You're fighting in order to disrupt the war machine prevent the bits from being made to be put in the other bits to be shot At you.
Speaker 0: Yep This we're not arguing for or against these concepts.
Speaker 0: No, this is just kind of like from the cold-hearted strategic perspective.
Speaker 0: this you know.
Speaker 1: This could range from anything such as using like EMPs in their cities to screw all their stuff up to You know spamming them so much that they can't read their email communications.
Speaker 0: So IT warfare is a very very broad thing and it can cover a lot of.
Speaker 0: it can cover everything.
Speaker 0: It's not like it's this special separate thing.
Speaker 0: It's just a new extension of existing war doctrine.
Speaker 0: The problem is it's untested and no one knows what to expect.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know think about it if you want.
Speaker 1: if back in the day, right you had tanks The other guy had tanks you want to destroy his tanks.
Speaker 1: There was only one way to do that.
Speaker 1: Boom That was it.
Speaker 1: That's that was your only choice.
Speaker 1: now The other guys using a tank but the tank has a computer in it.
Speaker 1: that depends on.
Speaker 1: so you don't really have to attack the Tank with boom.
Speaker 1: I mean you could attack computers with boom.
Speaker 1: that that's that's a valid strategy.
Speaker 1: But there are other because it's electronic.
Speaker 1: There are other ways that you can attack electronics.
Speaker 1: I have all these weapons that open up to you.
Speaker 0: Let's say the tanks of this power are Coordinated by a commander somewhere far away or by a flag tank and that flag tank or that commander communicate Wirelessly with all the other tanks in the area.
Speaker 0: I Disrupt that wireless signal now instead of having one large cohesive force.
Speaker 0: I have 50 Independent powerful forces, but they without that cohesion They effectively have to act semi independently or based on the last orders They got or whatever contingency plan they had and if my technology is still working I'm the win.
Speaker 0: or if they do the same thing to me and both of our Technologies are disabled now who wins?
Speaker 0: the battle doesn't come down to the traditional ideas but it comes down to either the ingenuity of the individual tank commanders or The robustness of the countermeasures.
Speaker 0: are the robustness of the contingency plans in case of said failings.
Speaker 0: Mmm and warfare suddenly becomes this kind of game counter game Technologically to the point that the war is almost decided before the bullets are fired.
Speaker 1: Pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know if you you know depend on the technology so much that you know It runs the whole show and without it, you know you basically only have this, you know X is all you can do if it all stops working and Then that sets really all you've got a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: The other stuff is just if any of it still works bonus I mean and this I'd look at the US what we invaded Iraq great.
Speaker 0: That was that was wonderful.
Speaker 0: I'm glad we did that.
Speaker 0: that worked so well for everyone, but it's fantastic.
Speaker 0: Look at how it played out.
Speaker 0: We had this technology and they didn't so effectively.
Speaker 0: We never didn't have to worry about this at all.
Speaker 0: There was the nation of Iraq had zero capability of projecting force outside of its borders and as a result We could basically have the majority of our power.
Speaker 0: our economy our command structure our planning.
Speaker 0: everything was 100% safe and could just sit there and make decisions.
Speaker 0: and because Iraq had no way to in any way Stop those decisions from being communicated Effectively we could fight a war at our leisure and just command units on a computer screen.
Speaker 0: Yep against a Real power like China that might not happen.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it definitely won't happen.
Speaker 0: well let's talk about specifics because that's the more interesting part.
Speaker 0: pick a few topics and Like I think satellites is actually the big one and a lot of people have been talking about this lately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean because generally, you know nowadays you think about it Not too many, you know, not many of the super generals.
Speaker 1: actually, you know, it's not like in the olden days.
Speaker 1: They're like, you know, the Czar would go out to the war himself, you know in Russia or anything, you know You communicate around the world very pretty much instantly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Bush or playing is not gonna be sitting in a tank.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what you do is yet the only way to communicate around the world like that is either some sort of you know cable Which is not so reliable because it goes through all these countries.
Speaker 1: who knows who's gonna you know be spying on that whatnot?
Speaker 0: or satellites and Or I guess ad hoc mesh network something fancy when I get into that.
Speaker 1: satellites I think are definitely the least susceptible to Interception because it goes from you to space to space to you as opposed from you know You to somewhere else on the ground to somewhere else on the ground.
Speaker 0: somewhere else on the ground You might think all right, but this is an asymmetric situation and it is but not in the way you think it is all right.
Speaker 0: US or Generic high-powered Western power has satellites everywhere and the military is linked by satellites and uses satellites for everything.
Speaker 0: and we can project force Anywhere on the globe.
Speaker 0: and we have force projection centers moving about all communicating centrally via these satellites You might think well, it's so hard to put a satellite up.
Speaker 0: Alright, therefore the US just wins because they have these satellites and no one else can protect force worldwide like that.
Speaker 0: Well, uh It's a lot cheaper to shoot some big heavy thing up that bumps into a satellite and breaks it.
Speaker 0: Then it is to make a satellite and put it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah satellites super fragile super expensive super Everything a rock cheap now.
Speaker 0: See now think of this the.
Speaker 0: you know if the United States went to war with China something I don't think would actually happen because I Generally think that the leadership of China is smart enough to realize that would be a bad idea.
Speaker 0: I generally think the leadership of Taiwan is smart enough to not suddenly declare independence even though they effectively are independent in all but name.
Speaker 0: and The China is certainly not stupid enough to no one's stupid enough to make that situation blow up.
Speaker 0: But if it were to happen just hypothetically, let's say the u.s.
Speaker 0: China decides to invade Taiwan China's right there.
Speaker 0: so they don't need global force projection power other than possibly nuclear submarines as a Engage externally or something, but we'll ignore that.
Speaker 0: for the second their infrastructures all local.
Speaker 0: They could get on probably pretty well without satellites because they could set up Locally some sort of relay communication network very likely to keep their military in Contact with the head of the military or at least to keep large units cohesive.
Speaker 0: Also, they would probably be projecting their force almost entirely at Taiwan with possibly some sort of maintenance action in the direction Of Japan or whatever powers nearby just to keep them off long enough for them to win the war.
Speaker 0: So they don't really need satellites US trying to get there and intervene.
Speaker 0: We need satellites.
Speaker 0: We need methods of our carrier groups to communicate with central authorities.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I'm sure the US military has plenty of plans like if the satellites don't work do this.
Speaker 0: It's not like don't do this, but one thing the US has done throughout his history.
Speaker 0: You know every now and then there's a news article like oh my god The US is planning to invade Canada.
Speaker 0: the US in order to train its military Strategists for since I think a long time ago a very long time ago Continually writes up contingency plans for everything.
Speaker 1: They have a plan guys who just sit around all day going.
Speaker 1: What if this crazy thing happened?
Speaker 1: Well write a plan for it.
Speaker 1: write a plan for it.
Speaker 1: and that way if a crazy thing ever happens?
Speaker 1: They go and they bring up this document that says here's what to do and they do what it says and they continually update these.
Speaker 0: Yep, but at the same time how the technology is changing so rapidly that I wonder how rapidly the US large system can keep up with it.
Speaker 0: and Also, how quickly can they deploy these technologies to a rapidly changing theater?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and how rapidly can they put up defenses to technologies that other people might use that they didn't think of?
Speaker 0: yeah It's it's a very tricky situation that makes war asymmetric But not in the traditional way of.
Speaker 0: you know we can project force to your country And you can't do anything return But oh you can project force in non-traditional ways by having gorillas or Terrorists or something that we can't fight easily against with a big army.
Speaker 1: I mean I mean you think about arms races.
Speaker 1: You know back in the day in the traditional sense, and it was like you know we made a rocket that goes farther.
Speaker 1: We made a rocket that goes farther and blows up bigger.
Speaker 1: We made a plane that can fly longer and drop more bombs.
Speaker 1: You know, but that's sort of that's easy to understand.
Speaker 1: What if it's you know and that that kind of stuff you looks like you invent it?
Speaker 1: You know month to month year to year.
Speaker 1: you know you and you.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: you know what the effects of that are gonna be.
Speaker 1: They're pretty simple.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be able to blow up more stuff.
Speaker 1: You know blow up something farther away We'll be able to defend against getting blown up some better.
Speaker 0: now Let's look at another kind of asymmetric information warfare.
Speaker 0: this one's a little more.
Speaker 0: I guess IT related Suppose all right the US or Western powers or large industrialized powers and Japan even China now to a degree Rely on their IT infrastructure for the majority of their business like the.
Speaker 0: the IT Infrastructure is extremely important to that country Not important to a relatively technologically non advanced or possibly third world power.
Speaker 0: Yep, so if that power is fighting an asymmetric war by using terrorists or gorillas or Irregular units or anything that a large power couldn't just straight-up fight against it's very easy for them to project small amounts of force on very vital things like transatlantic cables or specific infrastructure junk engines that crit that just cripple the Infrastructure.
Speaker 0: yeah things like that.
Speaker 0: now Blowing up a power plant in Afghanistan does not have nearly the impact of blowing up a power plant in a major urban center in say the United States or
Speaker 1: US you could blow up like a handful of power plants, and there'd be a blackout that would be enormous for a long time.
Speaker 0: No at the same time that sort of thing is not trivial to pull off.
Speaker 1: That's incredibly difficult to pull
Speaker 0: off, but at the same time I guess the real point I'm trying to make without getting into details because I don't want to elicit too many Arguments right now, and I want to be broad is that when we rely so much upon technology especially technology That's advancing so quickly
Speaker 1: and when we use technology so much to gain an advantage
Speaker 0: You can get into a situation where suddenly your force multipliers or the things that prop your economy up are single points of failure that can be Targeted with relatively little amounts of force or
Speaker 1: even if they're multiple points of failure.
Speaker 1: And you have this wonderful redundant system, and you thought the whole thing out and you're well.
Speaker 1: You know you you're you're well defended, and you thought of everything.
Speaker 1: even so you now have Another target set.
Speaker 1: you have a thing that is helping you win in some way and people can target that whereas before All they targeted was you directly and there really wasn't this sort of you know.
Speaker 1: aha We have all these other things to target You know
Speaker 0: but a lot of that is kind of moot because I'm of the opinion that that sort of warfare Barring something incredible happening is not a very likely possibility because history has shown that in the modern era Industrialized powers do not like to fight against each other because it generally doesn't benefit anyone.
Speaker 0: they like to fight against non industrialized powers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the democratic peace theory.
Speaker 0: We don't need to worry about.
Speaker 0: Let's not get into that.
Speaker 0: We don't need to worry about that.
Speaker 0: here is the IT warfare that we do need to worry about.
Speaker 0: I think they're going to be wars in our lifetime.
Speaker 0: We're.
Speaker 0: not a single bullet is fired and not a single death is caused directly.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have economic wars.
Speaker 0: We're going to have information wars.
Speaker 0: I mean imagine a war where China is trying to pressure the u.s.
Speaker 0: into recognizing the non-independence of Taiwan or something and The u.s.. Decides not to.
Speaker 0: and a war begins where China Starts flooding markets with spurious orders and starts cutting transatlantic cables and starts trying to bring down the global DNS structure because they've already built internally their own DNS structure or Because of the quote great wall firewall of China.
Speaker 0: They have an infrastructure that could exist semi-independent of the United States infrastructure.
Speaker 0: Yeah They can attack the United States economy by having a bunch of skilled people sitting in rooms with keyboards typing furiously.
Speaker 1: They could also attack the world's economy with straight-up economic warfare with their piles of dollars or they could do both Simultaneously.
Speaker 1: even worse suddenly
Speaker 0: call upon US debt that they own suddenly ally with Russia and flood the markets with something simultaneously attacking the US exchanges to bring down To bring their latency up and force people to not be able to deal with the changing market conditions Thereby creating an economic recession.
Speaker 1: you could do that.
Speaker 0: That's all generic and crazy But and I mean, I really can't get into specifics because I don't know and no one knows But I think that sort of warfare is kind of kind of be the future of war among industrialized powers.
Speaker 1: Yeah back in the day So the stock exchange was just guys running around with paper which it largely is still.
Speaker 1: but you know There's computers there now and you know, even when they had you know adding machines and such that you what could you do to the stock?
Speaker 1: You could have a guy sneak in and start putting false papers around or or a bank.
Speaker 0: you show up at a bank with you Know a bunch of faked purchase or what?
Speaker 0: I don't know how that all works.
Speaker 0: But yeah a bunch of faked.
Speaker 0: Whatever's.
Speaker 1: yeah You could you could try to do stuff like that sort of espionage type stuff But you couldn't like, you know Really attack the whole thing because it was just a bunch.
Speaker 1: you could you could I guess you could try to blow it up.
Speaker 0: Also, you couldn't attack it remotely over an internet.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Well, it's really hard to attack the New York You know, like the New York's access over the internet, but it's the same cuz.
Speaker 1: a lot of things just shouldn't be on the internet Aren't?
Speaker 0: yeah, like Pete, but this is the one fallacy people always say oh in an IT war They'll shut down the stock exchange and they'll turn off machines in hospitals and they'll make dams open up.
Speaker 0: Those things are generally not accessible by the internet.
Speaker 0: that can't happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, remember the best security you can have is just unplug the cable.
Speaker 1: You can have a computer.
Speaker 1: that remember before we had computers before we had the internet.
Speaker 1: There's no reason you can't have your computer on and not connect it to the internet with a wire and of any kind and no Wireless.
Speaker 1: and how is someone gonna hack it?
Speaker 1: They'd have to come in there and do something to it with their hands.
Speaker 0: Yep, and there's.
Speaker 0: there are parallel structures like internet 2 and the you know internet 3 that aren't as accessible as I guess Internet 1 and there are pipelines and methods of communicating that just aren't accessible to the outside.
Speaker 1: We go to the hospital they put you in you know Like the emergency whatever and there's machines hooked up to you.
Speaker 1: Those machines are computers.
Speaker 1: They're probably not on the internet.
Speaker 1: They might be on like the local hospital network But so that's it.
Speaker 0: I guess what we're saying it around about ways that wall, you know, theoretically all these things can happen.
Speaker 0: They could attack the economic centers of a country electronically.
Speaker 0: realistically, it's still a very difficult thing to pull off and As a result, it's really not something that the average person should really care or worry about at all.
Speaker 1: No, you really it's you really shouldn't worry about anything that they anything the news says you should be afraid of you probably shouldn't be.
Speaker 1: Well, unless they're like a gunman is loose.
Speaker 1: Well, okay your town or tornado warning now Hurricane coming next week or that broccoli ecolide.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that.
Speaker 1: Well, you shouldn't be afraid of that.
Speaker 1: You just don't buy the broccoli.
Speaker 0: Well, you should be afraid of it.
Speaker 0: If you just ate broccoli.
Speaker 0: That was bad broccoli All right.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess being a good just call the doctor I'd be a little afraid when I went to the doctor like I ate the bad broccoli, dude.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess since I wouldn't be afraid I guess I'd be more afraid if like I ate the bad broccoli days ago And I was having diarrhea already now.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's no real moral to all this.
Speaker 0: I mean I could go on a long diatribe about.
Speaker 0: Warfare is becoming abstract again And this is a good thing because it means less people being killed.
Speaker 1: and but then again It could mean actually a lot of people being killed by someone typing in a room.
Speaker 0: or then again it could mean a shockazooloo situation or a greece situation where Warfare becomes so abstract that it's meaningless and it's just a game.
Speaker 0: and then someone like Germany or Prussia back in the day when they said what if we just invaded forget the rules?
Speaker 0: What if we just invaded?
Speaker 0: What if we just fucking go there and then suddenly we go through the cycle?
Speaker 1: They went there and I don't know.
Speaker 0: All I know is that IT warfare is an interesting topic to debate about.
Speaker 0: it's not something to worry about.
Speaker 0: It's really all I can say.
Speaker 0: beyond that.
Speaker 1: yeah, I guess the point is is that you know you should as much as technology is super awesome and As much as you should use it as much as you can to make your life better and more efficient and easier in every Way and I encourage everyone in every organization to do so to the fullest extent that they can.
Speaker 1: You should all probably a backup plan.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know not a backup plan like oh no So what if the world ends but like, you know, can I continue existing and continue caring about my business inefficiently?
Speaker 1: You know if something happens like I don't know this power out for a few days?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and here's the thing in the IT world pretty much every important thing worth anything is So redundantly backed up ready to be available in case of all sorts of crazy disaster That it's not that big a concern.
Speaker 0: most of these scenarios Represented were almost entirely theoretical and not likely.
Speaker 1: Yeah things that are what's.
Speaker 1: what kind of thing would be likely though?
Speaker 1: that would be kind of big.
Speaker 0: the one thing that is You could bring down a lot of things for consumers or for average people.
Speaker 1: You guitar you could.
Speaker 1: if you if you target a specific Sort of service of some kind and you have a lot of resources at your disposal You can probably take it down, but at the same time if you're targeting it from China Well, the u.s.
Speaker 0: Controls most of the internet connections in the world.
Speaker 0: they can just stop that traffic coming pretty handily Yep, but maybe if they had an army of spam box, but spam box are used by script kiddies and spammers to send spam.
Speaker 1: They're not used by China to attack your stuff No, but I mean someone could set up a bunch of zombies on old windows boxes all around the world.
Speaker 0: Honestly other than you know The this crazy space warfare that I don't think we need to worry about right now.
Speaker 0: The only really viable situation that I can foresee but then again I could be wrong But I don't think we're that wrong would be attacks against say general internet consumer infrastructure in order to cause general Economic slowdown.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if someone starts attacking like bring down DNS in the US or Google or Amazon Amazon would hurt quite a bit.
Speaker 0: I mean it that sort of thing wouldn't be crippling but it would be very demoralizing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think about you.
Speaker 1: take out Amazon you someone you might think okay Well, obviously Amazon's gonna be hurt.
Speaker 1: Well, yes, but in addition, you know all those people making books Publishers Amazon sells everything, you know A to Z There's gonna be a lot of people who make stuff and sell a lot of products in Amazon.
Speaker 0: We're gonna get hurt and the stock exchange to go way down and even if you know It comes back up in two days.
Speaker 0: if then the evil Russians or whoever the enemy is at that time Just says yeah, that was us all cyber warfare style Then that scares a lot of people even though really the threat wasn't that bad at all.
Speaker 1: yep, but a lot of you know, a lot of things can happen as a result of scariness.
Speaker 1: because you know, like Greenspan said yeah, I cannot miss all about confidence and what people are thinking and not actually about anything else.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.