Speaker 0: It's Monday April 2nd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we talked a bit about April Fool's Day on the internet.
Speaker 0: Let's do this now Yesterday being April Fool's Day We had a plan for today that we'd made up about I don't know a long time ago when we were first trolling for logos For the show and our dear friend cat and made a really cool geek nights logo.
Speaker 0: And then as a joke because it fit she made a leak nights logo because back then That leak spin thing was all over the Internet.
Speaker 1: Yep leak spin was real popular.
Speaker 1: We talked about it for like three or four days on this show Maybe I've even two weeks and it was.
Speaker 1: it was all over the forums everyone couldn't stop posting different variations on leaks and leaks spinning and We even took a picture of rim and the grocery store holding a leak.
Speaker 1: So she made this leak nights logo and then rim said hey, we should do an actual show of leak nights.
Speaker 0: And the few people I told this to thought it was an awesome idea and Scott said it and left it at that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know, I wasn't particularly for or against this idea.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I my idea was that on April Fool's.
Speaker 0: what we should do is especially if it was a Monday You know a science and tech kind of day.
Speaker 0: We do the show straight up like a normal show.
Speaker 0: We have two news's or two things of the day.
Speaker 0: We do the main bit But the news is both have to involve leaks and the things the days are both leaks and then the main article Was all about leaks.
Speaker 0: but our normal episode except we do real well-researched real News and thing of the day as entertaining as we always are about leaks and we very subtly say leak nights instead of geek nights.
Speaker 0: I thought that would have been a great April Fool's definitely better than what slash dots done for the last decade.
Speaker 1: Oh, it would definitely been better than what slash dot is done ever.
Speaker 1: It would have been better than pretty much what any website has ever done.
Speaker 1: It's not good enough.
Speaker 0: Well, see I asked you the listeners would have been funny if we had done that.
Speaker 0: and we've done it straight up with the same Level of entertaining and quality and everything.
Speaker 0: We always have as opposed to uh, when earlier today while we're having some Japanese food at the neck Oh Scott says I don't like that idea.
Speaker 0: Let's not do it.
Speaker 1: I never really did like that idea that much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you didn't come up with any alternative Other than it.
Speaker 1: what you did want to do is go on and have this thing where if I don't like something I have to have an alternative.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it's no good.
Speaker 1: It's like I if an ugly person comes up and I say wow, you're ugly You're like well who's good-looking then?
Speaker 1: and if I can't name anyone good-looking and that person's not ugly somehow.
Speaker 0: Well, it has to do with the show.
Speaker 0: more cuz think of this.
Speaker 0: We've got to do the show on something.
Speaker 0: We need a topic every night four nights a week for the rest of our lives.
Speaker 0: We need a topic to talk about.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and Say we've got a topic that we've kind of decided on.
Speaker 0: maybe it's a crab people idea I don't know, but we got an idea.
Speaker 0: if you're gonna veto that idea And you'd better come up with something else to replace it because otherwise we got a default to the last best idea we had.
Speaker 1: Well, I wanted to do a compromise.
Speaker 1: No, I want to do it.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't want to do that, too.
Speaker 1: Yes, I wanted to do a compromise where we would have the leak news and things of the day and call it You know leak nights.
Speaker 1: But then the main bit I didn't think should have been a leak bit because that would have run out dry real fast.
Speaker 0: I don't think it would.
Speaker 0: if I think I could have been entertaining for a half hour about leaks What was I gonna say about leaks?
Speaker 0: I think you could have been entertaining for 15 minutes of that half hour.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: I think it would have been a challenge.
Speaker 0: Maybe that'll be a contest sometime in the future because I'm still disappointed in you guys over the Wednesday contest though I've been listening to some of those submissions from the Thursday contest and you might have all redeemed yourselves.
Speaker 0: You found some pretty goddamn bad.
Speaker 1: I didn't think there were podcasts that bad but there no god.
Speaker 1: I knew there were partners that the rim was playing them at iTunes on the TV and I was just like turn it up Turn it up.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I knew there were podcasts that bad.
Speaker 0: I didn't know there were podcasts that bad for the people didn't stop after a couple of episodes.
Speaker 0: Good God, I mean one of them.
Speaker 0: every episode is like two hours long.
Speaker 0: One of them was three hours long.
Speaker 1: I was gonna cry.
Speaker 1: It's good though because you know used to be if you wanted to torture someone you tie him into a chair and make him watch Barney or something like that, you know Barney the big purple dinosaur.
Speaker 1: now, it's real easy.
Speaker 1: You just get some of these podcasts put headphones on someone and put them in like a bed And then they have to listen to it.
Speaker 0: Well, you could always.
Speaker 0: I mean we were talking about the leak spin not to be confused with the meat spin.
Speaker 1: Oh god Oh God.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: instead we argued a bit with Alex.
Speaker 0: they're pretty much just watching amused at least.
Speaker 0: What are we gonna do?
Speaker 0: April Fool's Day on and we realized that There's really only one way to come out on top on April Fool's Day now one.
Speaker 0: you can have the awesome prank which usually will backfire because one if you do an April Fool's prank that's different from an April Fool's fool.
Speaker 0: a Prank is like I put a water bucket over Scott's door on April 1st.
Speaker 0: Haha.
Speaker 1: I love those.
Speaker 1: Those are great.
Speaker 1: or problem is I've tried that a couple times in my life and I've got it works.
Speaker 1: But the bucket always lands on the person.
Speaker 1: it hurts and I only want the water to land on.
Speaker 0: that's why You got to use a little plastic bucket because a little bit of water goes a long way.
Speaker 0: think say you're dressed up in business Clothes ready to go to work.
Speaker 0: if someone gets you with a super soaker Good.
Speaker 0: or get you with a bucket or get you with ten buckets.
Speaker 0: the end feeling you have is the same True.
Speaker 1: Did you see that video of in slow motion of a water balloon hitting a guy straight in the forehead?
Speaker 0: Yes, I did.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: Ah, there was a kid at my high school who took a water balloon to the face and ended up almost losing Mmm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, great.
Speaker 1: I took Santa the.
Speaker 0: I once granted that water balloon was thrown from a car going about 45 and The person who did it went to jail.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: Yes, but actually I heard.
Speaker 0: probably I mean I've seen some good April Fool's pranks in my life and sadly most of the best ones were done on TV and staged.
Speaker 0: But anyway, someone on FARC had the best goddamn idea and apparently he did this over the course of like five years.
Speaker 0: You know those jars of peanuts or whatever with the obvious fake label on it, but when you open the top Oh god, snakes pop out and everyone has a good.
Speaker 1: not even snakes.
Speaker 1: They're just like Springs with piece of plastic wrapped around them.
Speaker 0: So this guy on FARC when everyone else is bitching about April Fool's Day Apparently he took one of these with the fake label on it.
Speaker 0: but he took the snakes out and he filled it with peanuts and he gives it to his friend his friends looking at it like This is the fake freaking snakes and he turns it upside down.
Speaker 0: So the snakes don't hit him and he opens it.
Speaker 0: the peanuts fall out.
Speaker 0: What the fuck are you doing?
Speaker 0: I gave you those peanuts.
Speaker 0: So it is.
Speaker 1: this is the great I just got to say this story.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is about this story.
Speaker 1: But as soon as you start telling someone the story, it's obvious what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: It's the whole story is immediately obvious as soon as the person's telling the story says Candace snakes, right yet.
Speaker 1: It's still hilarious.
Speaker 1: Just to hear the story.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: well The thing is the guy was smart and he did it like every year for three or four years and every year that people think He's gonna get me.
Speaker 0: He's gonna get me and then always turn it over turn it upside down.
Speaker 0: one year He gives it to the guy guy opens it up snakes.
Speaker 0: It's just perfect
Speaker 1: snakes snakes on a plane,
Speaker 0: but since We we didn't actually get to do our April Fool's extravaganza, which in retrospect I think I really miss being at RIT mostly for the fact that at the RIT anime club We ran some motherfucking pranks back in our day.
Speaker 1: Oh, those are those April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: Then was I remember we sat there you me and James for like four hours preparing the next day's fool.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 1: It was the greatest fool I think ever and we discovered who was fools and who was not.
Speaker 0: basically we discovered that of the 200 or so people who were there for that showing maybe 12 of them had an IQ above 70 Either that it.
Speaker 1: I really like track and ball and Linkin Park.
Speaker 0: But then we realized that all right We can either try to do some half-assed April Fool's prank or maybe we can do that.
Speaker 0: Oh, we're web comics and we're all gonna draw each other's comics and won't it be delightful?
Speaker 1: or just like the newspaper comics do?
Speaker 0: or oh We're slash-dot.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have every single story be lame for the entire day.
Speaker 0: But then what could we do to stand out from the crowd to be different and better than everyone else on the internet?
Speaker 0: The answer is to not only shun April Fool's Day and not actually do anything for it But to to take a more intellectual standpoint and make fun of all the people who buy into this BS.
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: even though my sad reality is that I love April Fool's Day and every year of my life where April Fool's Day fell On a Saturday or Sunday I Was really sad that year because I wanted to be at school or at work to do whatever I was gonna do that day.
Speaker 1: The thing is my past two April Fool's Days, right?
Speaker 1: It would be April Fool's when I had a new job And or April Fool's and I was working in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, your first day on the job will be cushioned under the CEOs chair.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like at my work.
Speaker 1: now I mean, let's say I was at work today on April Fool's Day and I couldn't really.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'd be comfortable pulling A prank on people.
Speaker 1: I've only been at work with for a few weeks.
Speaker 1: You know, I'd have to next year.
Speaker 0: almost definitely I think I might be comfortable pranking some people but not now see the pranks at IBM usually just involved filling someone's office with Various items so they couldn't get into it or one time we replaced a guy's monitor cable with a busted monitor cable.
Speaker 0: So it worked but only yellow came through.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you gotta replace like computer mice with ball mice Or there's always out.
Speaker 0: there's always the obvious thing like we take an Ethernet cable cut off the end stick an antenna on it and instead stick it in a guy's computer and say yeah, we finally got you that wireless upgrade you've been asking for.
Speaker 1: take a Some a screenshot of someone's desktop.
Speaker 1: Ah make it their wallpaper and delete all their icons.
Speaker 0: That's so beautiful, except it doesn't work on rim Sean who types window key are or all space and then gets to work.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, actually though someone did that to a guy at my work at IBM back in the day And the guy was really old and he's smart, but he's not doesn't know about computers and he didn't know how to deal with that at all.
Speaker 1: And he was actually a program you can download now where you just run it and it does it.
Speaker 1: Wow, you don't need to go through the effort anymore of actually knowing how to take a screenshot or saving it and sending it As wallpaper or anything.
Speaker 0: Wow now couple that with some sort of time dependent logic bomb and you could hold a large organization hostage probably.
Speaker 0: Anyway in the news, I have no segue at all for that.
Speaker 0: You might remember I. can.
Speaker 0: they as far as you are all concerned regulate DNS names on the internet.
Speaker 1: It's the International consortium of Assholes and names and numbers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't remember.
Speaker 1: It doesn't sign names and numbers.
Speaker 0: Yes Something like that.
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 0: we're awesome.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like when you interviewed for Google and we know a lot about computers.
Speaker 0: But if you ask us something that we would have learned in school in a textbook, we don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't remember the I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's the internet corporation for assigned names and numbers.
Speaker 0: outstanding.
Speaker 0: Anyway, every now and then a bunch of people decide that we should have a dot xxx domain and it's always two groups of people.
Speaker 0: It's always the crazy Radical fundamentalist religious types who want to segregate all the porn on the internet into one place.
Speaker 0: They can easily block it and on the other side you have all the porn people who want a porn domains.
Speaker 0: They can have porn domain names.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now keep in mind the porn people.
Speaker 1: The difference here is that they want an xxx so that it's real easy for people to find porn.
Speaker 1: But they have no intention of giving up their existing dot-com porn addresses They're gonna keep those to the Christians.
Speaker 1: Of course want it to make it somehow illegal for Porn to be in dot-com net org or anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah They seem to have this fantasy that if we make a dot xxx domain we can force Everything objectionable on the internet to be there and not accessible any other way.
Speaker 0: that way all the net nanny and the nets Whatever's can block the dot xxx.
Speaker 1: You won't even need a software.
Speaker 1: It'll just work.
Speaker 1: Just be like a click check up.
Speaker 1: No xxx is.
Speaker 0: I don't think I need to explain why.
Speaker 0: that is an absolutely ludicrous crazy stupid pathetic Horrible idea that only a moron could dream of not only morally and legally and constitutionally, but also technologically.
Speaker 0: Yes Technologically impossible never mind the fact that it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the I can for all their problems are very smart and they have yet again rejected this idea.
Speaker 1: That is good I guess in a way is he?
Speaker 1: on the one hand?
Speaker 1: I would like for there to be a lot more top-level domains each handled by more people because really We could use some more things besides com net org biz u.s.
Speaker 1: Etc.
Speaker 0: See, I don't know I disagree a little bit cuz right now the way the internet is right.
Speaker 0: we had com edu gov int.
Speaker 0: or all those things.
Speaker 0: When biz was Kate was made.
Speaker 0: You pretty much know if you go to a website that ends in dot biz that it's either something really shady or a company that Doesn't know anything about the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so pretty much top-level domains don't gain acceptance at all among anyone.
Speaker 1: That's true, but I think there could be a few awesome ones plus someone can make a lot of money selling them to people.
Speaker 1: For example, let's say you let Google have dot goog or you had you let Wikipedia have dot wiki or something like that.
Speaker 1: You could really milk them for some cash and they would love it.
Speaker 0: Well, the other problem is having more top-level domains really defeats the purpose of why DNS is the way it is and why it?
Speaker 1: It does it does in fact all the people.
Speaker 0: really you shouldn't even be using something.com.
Speaker 0: it should be something dot something dot something dot something dot com and it should be segregated based on content and location and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: and It was that way for a short time and then people who didn't know or care about the way DNS was supposed to be used.
Speaker 1: Do we do a DNS episode?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: if we did it We're doing a DNS episode as soon as is convenient.
Speaker 0: and if we already did one then we're not because we already did one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless maybe we could do one if we did the history do the technical side.
Speaker 0: if we did the technical side do the history I'm pretty sure we haven't done one.
Speaker 1: So we're doing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, regardless.
Speaker 0: It's a bad idea.
Speaker 0: I can't agree at least nine people and I can't agree if I voted for it.
Speaker 1: Ah Good.
Speaker 1: All right, so we're at the grocery store.
Speaker 1: the other day and You know, remember we told you the story about how he found the koalas at the grocery store.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the grocery store seemed to be realigning all of its content.
Speaker 0: So we found a bunch of little gems.
Speaker 1: Yes, well there is one section in the grocery store that has sort of weird things.
Speaker 1: they have British candy.
Speaker 1: they have You know, it's next to the Goya stuff.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's all sorts of weird beverages and things that very few people want very niche products.
Speaker 0: granted I like a lot of that stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and they had a beverage called ribena R I B E N A ribena black current.
Speaker 1: black current is one word.
Speaker 1: Yes, basically what it is is black current juice.
Speaker 1: now black current is sort of like it's like a berry Raisin kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a long and cool history about black currents and odd for various reasons They weren't allowed to be grown in the US for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yes The black currents were illegal to grow in the US because they were responsible for spreading this tree disease That would have damaged the lumber industry and the lumber industry was more important than the black current industry.
Speaker 1: But eventually the right the law was returned to state jurisdiction and a lot of states in the Northeast like New York and such Have real loud black current growing.
Speaker 0: now, of course, this is America for all of you British listeners.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you're well aware of black currents because they became very popular there Apparently during World War two when it was difficult to get oranges into the islands.
Speaker 1: Yes, also they use black currents to flavor vodak in Russia a lot And the name black curtain actually comes from.
Speaker 1: it's like raisin of Corinth because you know Corinth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what black currents are outstanding.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, this beverage rubenna is made of black currant juice.
Speaker 1: Wait and the company that makes it is like a subsidiary of Glaxo Smith Klein, which is that pharmaceutical company?
Speaker 0: You know now I had never heard of this drink or anything about it until there was all that news on Fark a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hadn't heard of rubana black currents or anything.
Speaker 1: I'd heard of Glaxo Smith Klein, but that's it.
Speaker 0: See I knew about black currents because there's black current.
Speaker 1: I've heard of currents.
Speaker 0: There's black current.
Speaker 0: a lot of the wines I like.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, some girls in New Zealand were doing a science fair project and their science fair project was pretty much Hey, let's test a bunch of different drinks for vitamin C. So they went to the grocery store and they said oh Here's some orange juice.
Speaker 1: Here's some apple juice.
Speaker 1: Here's some water.
Speaker 1: Here's some soda.
Speaker 1: Here's some.
Speaker 1: Oh this black currant juice says on it that it has a whole lot of vitamin C a lot In fact.
Speaker 0: in some areas, it looks like they marketed as made with black currants Which contain X percent more vitamin C than oranges.
Speaker 1: black currents do contain a lot of fucking vitamin C too bad They weren't putting those black currents in the drink.
Speaker 1: Well, they were putting black currents in the drink.
Speaker 1: The problem is the vitamin C wasn't making it into the drink.
Speaker 0: Yeah what they were doing is they put like four or five percent black currant juice in the drink and then the rest of it was Processed concentrate and a byproduct of the processing was that it destroyed or removed just about all of the vitamin C.
Speaker 1: Yeah So these two girls in New Zealand doing a completely innocent science fair project Didn't detect any vitamin C in these supposedly high vitamin C rubenna.
Speaker 1: So they said something to the company and they said hey, there's no vitamin C and in this drink now This was years ago.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the company said what are you gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: So they went to a TV station and now there's news about these girls everywhere and it just shows you that companies lie and Science is real.
Speaker 0: just recently the company Pleaded guilty to all 15 charges that were filed against them and they were fined like two hundred thousand New Zealand dollars so far.
Speaker 1: Well, I saw rubetta in the store the other day and it did make many claims about vitamin C that are apparently not true.
Speaker 0: Even better Apparently they have been forced to purchase a great number of full page and half page advertisements in popular newspapers Apologizing for what they did and explaining what was wrong.
Speaker 1: They should be forced to like put things on the internet forever and such, you know, there's a useless newspaper I don't think the word is looking at.
Speaker 0: I don't think the word internet in the word forever can ever coexist.
Speaker 1: Also TV commercials might be good perhaps youtubes Anything just newspapers alone isn't good enough these days because only old people will find out about it.
Speaker 0: But the thing is all the people who aren't old found out about it already on the internet.
Speaker 0: the only people who aren't gonna know about this are the middle gap the gap between the old people who don't know about the Internet and us and frankly those people don't matter in the grand scheme of things anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, if you want vitamin C don't drink rubenna, but if you like black currants Ruben it might still be good for you if you want to drink that.
Speaker 0: Well, I really like black currants and I would say just in terms of promoting honesty in corporations I really like black currants and I like black currant juice.
Speaker 0: I would never buy rubenna.
Speaker 0: I'll buy some other black currant juice and it looks like black currants are on the upswing So they're probably gonna be a lot of competitors in the near future.
Speaker 0: Alrighty, especially since pomegranate juice is starting to take off more and more and it used to be.
Speaker 0: you could just get those little palm.
Speaker 0: I like them but they were expensive.
Speaker 0: I just bought a giant jug of pomegranate juice for very little money.
Speaker 1: The thing that upsets me though is, you know, while pomegranate juice is on the up actual pomegranates are not.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's so easy to get them in the best of Quality to the United States.
Speaker 1: I think that is correct.
Speaker 1: But when I went to Israel, I ate a pomegranate and it's sort of weird because you open it.
Speaker 1: It's all brainy and slimy.
Speaker 0: I was about to say it's like eating a brain is but it's damn good.
Speaker 1: If I could buy pomegranates I would but I don't see any at the grocery store things of the day.
Speaker 0: so I found this video that is basically an ad for a 1955 car and There are two cool things about this ad.
Speaker 0: one the primary selling point of this car.
Speaker 1: Is that it has Air-conditioning and heat and heat and they actually call it all season air-conditioning.
Speaker 0: Turn the knob to the left turn the knob to the right no matter what whether you're driving and it's gonna be great.
Speaker 1: That's pretty crazy that you know.
Speaker 1: I always thought about that because they know a model T doesn't have air conditioning or heating or anything and I always wondered like What were the first cars to have air conditioning?
Speaker 1: How did it work?
Speaker 1: What were the first cars to have heat?
Speaker 1: How did it work, you know.
Speaker 1: and all that because now every car is air conditioning and heat.
Speaker 1: You pretty much can't get a car without air conditioning and heat.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, my laser didn't have air conditioning, but it was air conditioning ready.
Speaker 0: It had.
Speaker 0: it was set up to take air conditioning.
Speaker 0: It just didn't have it.
Speaker 0: Hmm because the rice who had the car before me chose not to get air conditioning because he was afraid they would put too much Heat into his delicate system.
Speaker 0: Oh And my son fire currently no longer has air conditioning, but it's also leaking coolant and oil.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 0: But the other cool thing about this is that the character that is selling this car to you is no other than Brer Rabbit.
Speaker 0: Brer rabbit the racist Brer rabbit from the uncle Remus stories derived from African American folk tales in the southern United States.
Speaker 0: Now you might remember Brer rabbit from a bunch of stories and picture books But also from the famous movie entitled the song of the south.
Speaker 1: I always wanted to see song of the south never seen it.
Speaker 1: I saw parts of.
Speaker 1: okay I never saw the whole thing at once like somewhere.
Speaker 0: My mom has a tape of it because I remember we bought it and we watched it and I really liked it as a kid.
Speaker 1: It's a good movie, but it is a racist movie and therefore Disney has not Printed it on DVD or VHS or anything in a long time now.
Speaker 0: granted there was a rumor I don't know if I talked about on the show that it was gonna come out on DVD eventually.
Speaker 0: I saw it.
Speaker 1: didn't we see a Netflix pre-release or something?
Speaker 0: there was an Amazon pre-release that you couldn't order.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that's still there.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna look for it right now in our Netflix queue.
Speaker 0: It's still pending so it's definitely not out yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't see the Disney movie available on Amazon anywhere although I do see the adventures of bray rabbit 2006 which looks like a really crappy Directed DVD kids movie.
Speaker 1: that is nothing to do with song of the south other than the character of bray rabbit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, I thought this was kind of cool cuz I remember growing up as a kid reading a little bray rabbit stories.
Speaker 0: I wonder if I still have those books.
Speaker 1: I had one of those.
Speaker 1: I had a fisher-price tape recorder and it would come with a book and a tape and you could put the tape in and read the book at the same time and I had a bray rabbit one of those.
Speaker 1: not it was pretty good Alright, so there are a lot of forms of entertainment.
Speaker 1: You know out there in the world But you know vaudeville sideshow type things that aren't really popular today.
Speaker 1: I mean no one really likes to see a hypnotist so much.
Speaker 1: You know hypnotist is sort of like you might get him to do a bar mitzvah or a small party But God you know.
Speaker 0: there was a hypnotist at my high school all night senior party Yeah, and the guy was probably the second lamest thing I've ever seen in my life.
Speaker 1: You know all sorts of lame acts out there and ventriloquism is one of those lame acts.
Speaker 1: It's like no one wants to see a ventriloquist.
Speaker 1: I mean you know it's just a joke like gabbo Gabbo gabbo gabbo right it's like a ventriloquist.
Speaker 1: great And why?
Speaker 1: but the reason it.
Speaker 1: the thing is.
Speaker 1: back in the day ventriloquists are popular and with good reason.
Speaker 1: It was actually funny that people went to see them.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like.
Speaker 1: there was always Ventriloquism and people did it and no one liked it and people continued to do it just because they wanted to it.
Speaker 1: ventriloquism can actually be entertaining and Here is a great example of modern ventriloquism.
Speaker 1: That is pretty entertaining.
Speaker 1: I don't know when this is from but it must be recently and it's some event called tickled pink.
Speaker 1: That's taking place at Royal Albert Hall Which is sort of like Carnegie Hall in the UK or Albion.
Speaker 1: and this girl?
Speaker 1: She's pretty cute named Nina Conti.
Speaker 1: She does ventriloquism.
Speaker 1: She has a little monkey puppet, and it's pretty funny because the monkeys all acknowledging that it's just a puppet and It's it's pretty dirty It's.
Speaker 1: I laughed a lot when I watch this even though.
Speaker 1: It's just a ventriloquist.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: It's definitely funnier than the ventriloquist in the second Phoenix Wright game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the ventriloquist in the second Phoenix Wright game is just Stereotypically sad ventriloquist.
Speaker 0: Yes sad ventriloquist.
Speaker 1: and I noticed on YouTube There's a bunch of other links to videos with this girl.
Speaker 1: I might watch some of them.
Speaker 1: Maybe she tells different jokes.
Speaker 0: So April Fool's Day, it's here and every year It seems for pretty much as long as I have known that there was a site called slash dot.
Speaker 0: There's always this Pseudo Controversy about April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: I mean every year.
Speaker 0: slash dot is the same tradition all day from midnight until midnight.
Speaker 0: Every single story on slash dot will be ludicrously ludicrously false.
Speaker 1: Yes, and you know, it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: it's not funny because you read it and they're not fooling you.
Speaker 1: You know that the stories are fake and you're kind of pissed.
Speaker 1: because what if real news happens today?
Speaker 1: You got to go to a different site to find it because you're not gonna find it here.
Speaker 0: now It's not an issue anymore because now we have Google News and dig and all that.
Speaker 0: But imagine a time before dig and you wanted to know.
Speaker 0: it's like say we were doing the show I don't know four years ago, and we needed tech news and it was April 1st.
Speaker 1: What the fuck are we gonna do?
Speaker 1: We go to seen it.
Speaker 0: zd net or slash that Yeah, and slash dot is basically broken for 24 hours.
Speaker 0: granted I usually think they're not really funny in the April Fool's Way, but they're always funny in this onion kind of way.
Speaker 1: I The thing is the onion is actually clever and witty whereas the slash dot is sort of ham-fisted and corny.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is it's not always ham-fisted and corny because usually they're drawing from what other people have done and linking to it.
Speaker 1: Sometimes but sometimes not a lot of them are just people on April Fool's Day go to slash dot because it's slash That is all users submitted stories.
Speaker 1: So people submit you know stuff and then I guess the editors at slash dot pick which ones are worthy of being posted on April Fool's Day, but the thing is all those things are usually jokes that other people had on their sites.
Speaker 0: There are no original jokes on slash dot other than this year where well I mean, I guess they've done things before but I never noticed.
Speaker 0: but this year due to mostly the rivalry between dig and slash dot Slash dot added dig dot which is very much.
Speaker 1: They added a slash dot it Yes side there, which like rim said, uh last night, you know rim said, uh slash dot put their April Fool's up And I'm like they put digs did there didn't they?
Speaker 1: and rims like yeah, they did.
Speaker 1: I didn't have to look at the site and I knew what they had done already.
Speaker 0: now However, when you click on it The text that is given is probably the best indicator of the different philosophies in Content between dig and slash dot.
Speaker 0: your vote in the slash dotted system will help ensure the best stories are presented to our readers with hyper accurate numbers to indicate their relevance relevance and general awesomeness.
Speaker 0: only by requiring the Contribution of every random user of the internet.
Speaker 0: Can we guarantee the most scientifically perfect numbers will be generated?
Speaker 1: Yep, that describes dig pretty well.
Speaker 0: vote early vote often.
Speaker 0: Now luckily dig you can't vote often unless you're a gigantic tool and you put a lot more effort into within.
Speaker 0: any human being would Which you think wouldn't be an issue yet.
Speaker 0: I bury there.
Speaker 0: Ah Usually if I see a story that's dug up stupidly and I look at who dug it I'll find that there are a lot of accounts who seem to exist solely to dig stories from spam sites And I'll usually spend about 10 minutes systematically burying everything those users have ever posted and everything any friend of theirs has ever posted.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why you got mistaken for the berry Brigade.
Speaker 0: because I am a member of the berry Brigade I very dedicatedly bury things on dig.
Speaker 0: I probably bury 10 stories for every story I dig.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should bury all the April Fool's Day fake stories.
Speaker 1: that because you only want real stories.
Speaker 0: No, because I don't really care.
Speaker 0: I actually kind of enjoy the April Fool's Day stories.
Speaker 0: See the thing is about slash dot.
Speaker 0: That's not the story.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter that slash dot does this.
Speaker 0: every website does something except geek nights because we're above the fray but on slash dot Every year.
Speaker 0: it's like people don't see it coming and they don't remember that it happened the previous year.
Speaker 0: so the first story goes up and There's always a bunch of comments of people reacting in shock as to the news like the DMCA was repealed.
Speaker 0: OMG this is the best news ever blah blah.
Speaker 0: and then finally someone wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Oh Wow, those morons fell for it.
Speaker 0: Happy April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: and then in every single thread for the rest of the day It'll be half the people talking about how funny the joke is or playing along with the joke and half the people Bitching about how slash dot is useless.
Speaker 0: now these stories aren't funny and they put more effort into bitching that they could have just not Read slash dot for a day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually there was one really good April Fool's Day last year board game geek.
Speaker 1: They actually got me.
Speaker 1: I was totally punned.
Speaker 1: they on.
Speaker 1: you went to the site and it sort of logged you in as an administrator or it looked like it and you had all these controls there and you're like They broke the site and I'm logged in as administrator.
Speaker 1: I so I went to the board.
Speaker 1: I sent them an email like hey your sites broken you should.
Speaker 1: you should fix that.
Speaker 1: and then I Went back and I was like don't?
Speaker 1: Because it was so convincing it was actually fooling you it wasn't?
Speaker 1: you know some ham-fisted thing?
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it looked like the administrator login page in every single possible way.
Speaker 0: Fark did that actually almost the exact same way except the admin page They gave you looked like a straight-up admin page Like you could just bury things or blah blah blah and had all these secret options.
Speaker 0: but if you looked at it for more than a few seconds you realize that one it had total for our total FARC and ultra FARC stuff and Everyone knows that ultra FARC doesn't exist because anyone who knows about it and talks about it is summarily executed.
Speaker 0: Ah, and two you started noticing that a lot of the options didn't really make sense at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah See the thing is I was too good and I didn't actually bother to try to use the administrator interface.
Speaker 1: if I did I would Have gotten the haha message.
Speaker 0: The thing is the FARC one.
Speaker 0: if you didn't notice all the dummy entries you tried to use it.
Speaker 0: You thought it was working for a while because it wasn't easy to tell immediately if it worked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the thing is a lot of people.
Speaker 1: it's April Fool's Day.
Speaker 1: so people just do something Wacky instead of actually fooling anyone.
Speaker 1: and I really the wacky stuff That's so forced and a non-subtle.
Speaker 1: It just doesn't do it for me.
Speaker 0: See I very much I don't like the April Fool Fool part in the media Because I don't like the media to lie to me one day out of the year.
Speaker 1: I mean, what is true?
Speaker 0: What if the next 9/11 and Hiroshima happened today?
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: No matter who told me I would have said what yeah, right.
Speaker 0: what yeah, right?
Speaker 0: And it would have taken me a while to realize that.
Speaker 0: wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah I definitely agree that you know, the news shouldn't be doing fake stuff.
Speaker 1: the news You just.
Speaker 1: it's not that important that everyone should just be silly for everything.
Speaker 1: You know something.
Speaker 1: the news is more important than April Fool's Day.
Speaker 1: It's no big deal.
Speaker 0: The only kind of foolings I like are the things like if Scientific American on their April first issue Happen to have an entirely fake thing about an entirely fake thing Like the old spaghetti tree harvests.
Speaker 1: see fake things like that are okay.
Speaker 1: The thing for me is that when they're so obviously fake It's just not funny.
Speaker 0: but people fell for the spaghetti tree one.
Speaker 1: a lot of people that Might have fell for it back in the day as well?
Speaker 1: I don't know but you know I'm not saying.
Speaker 1: are
Speaker 0: you saying seriously that if someone showed you a documentary talking about the spaghetti trees of Italy and showed video in black and white of people from like the 1940s harvesting their spaghetti by hand before they came up with modern equipment and had this whole you would have believed
Speaker 1: it?
Speaker 1: It depends on a couple things.
Speaker 1: It depends what year it is.
Speaker 1: It depends how old I am because I did not know how spaghetti was made until I was maybe eight.
Speaker 1: So if I was seven and you showed it to me, I'd be like, oh, that's what the spaghetti comes from.
Speaker 1: But now that I know spaghetti is basically we put in a pasta maker.
Speaker 1: So you're not gonna fool me with your spaghetti tree.
Speaker 0: But very much more than the fooling because fooling is easy to do the more credulous your story is or the more subtle it Is it gets to the point where if you make it so subtle that it's this brilliant play and you'll fool everyone You fooled everyone and now no one realizes they were fooled and the thing you fooled them on is something They'll never even realize they were
Speaker 1: wrong.
Speaker 1: That is.
Speaker 1: the essential problem with April Fools on the internet is because April Fools in real life.
Speaker 1: You can go around being subtle and fooling people but then because you're right there you can go April Fools bitch.
Speaker 1: Yeah But on the internet, that's really hard to do because where are you gonna put that?
Speaker 1: Are you gonna post it later?
Speaker 1: They might not see it.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna post it in the same article?
Speaker 1: then they might see that before they get fooled What can you do?
Speaker 0: you lose all the satisfaction of getting someone?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't get to see their reaction of going.
Speaker 1: I got fooled.
Speaker 0: I mean plus if you're.
Speaker 0: if you're subtle enough It doesn't become funny anymore because the I got Scott this morning with probably the lamest April Fool ever.
Speaker 0: It was pretty lame mostly as a proof of concept.
Speaker 0: All I did was convince him that we'd left the charcoal from when we grilled outside Which
Speaker 1: is absolutely believable because we grilled last night and I didn't bring the charcoal back in
Speaker 0: and that it had rained and made A big mess and ruined the deck and
Speaker 1: which is believable because there was a slight chance of rain on the weather.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a perfectly believable April Fool and I got no satisfaction out of it whatsoever.
Speaker 0: I should have come in and said Scott your mom just died, but then he wouldn't have believed me.
Speaker 1: No, I would have been like, oh right.
Speaker 1: It's April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Therefore I'm much more fan of nowadays of the April Fool's Day prank where I'm basically and this is actually This is how I did it all through high school, too.
Speaker 0: I didn't try to fool people.
Speaker 0: what I always did is I pulled pranks because if you fall for a prank on any given day It's no big deal.
Speaker 0: you fell for a prank.
Speaker 0: It's hard to not fall for a prank unless you see it coming or the people doing it or idiots.
Speaker 0: But on April Fool's Day everyone's guards a little bit up.
Speaker 0: So if you can get someone on April Fool's Day with a well-constructed prank you sir are a god among men.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's just something about it Like, you know when someone says I'm gonna prank you and then you're on the lookout and they still get you It's like imagine if everyone was on high alert and you still manage to totally own someone.
Speaker 1: It's like double power.
Speaker 1: It's almost not worth it to prank someone in any other day because it's only normal prank power when the same exact effort could have gone into that same prank on April 1st and Gotten you 10 times the reward.
Speaker 0: I had a friend in high school and One thing that he did is he had this all day.
Speaker 0: He came up to this other friend of mine and he said I'm gonna get you today and it was April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: It's April Fool's Day and all day He kept reminding the guy that it was April Fool's Day and that he was going to get him.
Speaker 1: Wow Did he get him?
Speaker 0: No, he didn't do anything But he didn't even try And that kid Jordan Jones was probably the most paranoid fucker.
Speaker 0: I've seen in my entire life every time he saw the guy he'd be like Like he walked slow.
Speaker 0: every time we went to his locker He'd like he'd look at it to make sure that wasn't like Vaseline on it that we open it real carefully.
Speaker 0: He'd like open it.
Speaker 1: He's staying that in a way.
Speaker 1: That's the April Fool's.
Speaker 1: it's I'm gonna get you.
Speaker 1: Just kidding April Fool's.
Speaker 0: I was disappointed though because if he had been paranoid all day
Speaker 1: and he had been gotten that would have been the sweetest cheesecake ever
Speaker 0: like the best thing in the world would have been if he came home at night and he gets in bed and then suddenly feels something turns around and Nathan's laying there next to him.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I've know how that could have happened.
Speaker 1: But yeah, April Fool's Day is generally sort of like, you know Sometimes we play in a game and it's like alright this turn it's plus one to gold and this turn it's plus one to settlers.
Speaker 1: well April Fool's Day is basically plus ten to practical jokes all day.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'd say it's minus five to practical jokes because it's harder to pull them off.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's plus ten to the to your reward if you manage to pull them.
Speaker 1: but at the same time Unsubtle corny ham-fisted things are just annoying that don't even bother.
Speaker 0: Hey Scott, there's a spider on you.
Speaker 0: Ha ha April Fool's made you look made you look.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like for example Google did some.
Speaker 1: well Google did something last year also, but this year they did.
Speaker 1: I don't even I looked at it for like five Seconds cuz it wasn't funny, but they were basically like hey if you want Google's new awesome internet service provider Yeah, we just take this thing and tie it to a fiber optic cable and flush it down the toilet and then our Google guys will find your wire pick it up and plug it in and then attach this wireless adapter to the other end on top of your toilet and get super fast internet connection in your house and it's like Alright, you obviously made a page for April Fool's Day and it's not funny.
Speaker 0: then again I've known some people who would probably fall in for that and I'm dead serious.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, those people are just dumb.
Speaker 0: Yeah The thing is that's the other thing.
Speaker 0: getting a dumb person isn't funny at all.
Speaker 0: You don't get any satisfaction out of that.
Speaker 0: You gotta get someone smart.
Speaker 0: the smarter person the more prepared person the better the payoff.
Speaker 1: Yes, if someone is dumb, they probably don't even remember that it's April Fool's Day.
Speaker 1: they probably couldn't tell you which day April Fool's Day was.
Speaker 1: they wouldn't have the Ability to even consider a prank.
Speaker 1: they might even be so dumb that if you successfully prank them They'd be like what like you'd open a can of snakes and they they'd be like, huh snakes what what the hell?
Speaker 1: And you'd be like, ah, I just got you with the snakes and it didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: You got to get us.
Speaker 1: only a smart person go.
Speaker 1: Ah snakes.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh Plus the smart person will also gain humor from it.
Speaker 1: Even if they are harmed in the course of the prank.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends on how hard.
Speaker 1: yeah a stupid person might just be all indignant and make it not fun.
Speaker 0: I mean you can't prank someone with a tire iron.
Speaker 0: that moves a little bit beyond Frank.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh dude, I popped all the tires on your car.
Speaker 0: lol your mom's dead.
Speaker 0: I Killed her for real for real do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but anyway, I'm sorry if that was a kind of rambly show.
Speaker 0: You see since Scott totally copped out on leak nights At least we didn't do something.
Speaker 1: That was unfunny and lame or No one wants to listen to it or Anything dumb.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think about how bad this could have been next year.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll do something in the line of what we did at anime club.
Speaker 0: that might be difficult to pull off because we had a captive audience a projector a lot of time to prepare and Absolutely.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess now actually there's far fewer consequences because we were threatened with death a couple times after that April Fool's showing.
Speaker 1: Mmm, that's true.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: But since we had a bunch of people well, we had two people over over the weekend and I got work tomorrow I actually got a lot done this weekend.
Speaker 0: I didn't really.
Speaker 1: I tried to get my car fixed.
Speaker 1: I got a haircut.
Speaker 1: I bought a laundry basket.
Speaker 1: I did my laundry.
Speaker 0: I got up early when to get an oil course.
Speaker 1: I did the laundry before I got the new laundry basket.
Speaker 0: genius me couldn't get the oil change because the oil.
Speaker 0: I got the oil change because it just took forever.
Speaker 0: and then I go to the mechanic and the guys like.
Speaker 0: I Don't do that kind of work on these days.
Speaker 0: You got to come back tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Can you leave your car overnight?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, I gotta go to work, dude What kind of hours do you think people can?
Speaker 1: and he goes April Fool's and he's like, I'll do the workout.
Speaker 0: He left already shit But yeah I'm going to bed though expect tomorrow because we've got probably our first Legitimate hate mail and it occurred in another show that a lot of you listen to.
Speaker 1: are we gonna talk about that on Wednesday?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm gonna play a bit from it tomorrow because it's relevant.
Speaker 0: we're gonna talk about it on Wednesday But I gotta play it.
Speaker 0: I'm just too lazy tonight to play it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: All right, fuck it We did this way too late.
Speaker 0: We got to start earlier next time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well it's cuz Katsu was here and we played board games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well Alex isn't gonna come over for a few days.
Speaker 0: we had our ghost in the show.
Speaker 0: Well, they said it's gonna come tomorrow, but I wonder if it's gonna be scratch.
Speaker 0: What if it's scratch the last DVD?
Speaker 0: It's fucking to be scratching like the last episode Whatever.
Speaker 0: All right, we got to take care of that forum bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah You want to be hungry Joe.
Speaker 0: yeah, all right, I hate being Steve but HMT gay Steve is probably my best bet again.
Speaker 0: Probably.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could post his Ken but Ken Jura, but he's already.
Speaker 0: We got Alex on that.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't really care.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna go do what I got to do in good way.
Speaker 0: All right, how's this?
Speaker 0: I'll start a flame war about the hostage thing in Iran.
Speaker 0: Okay I'll either start a new thread or I'll put it in some other threat.
Speaker 0: I'll pick an unrelated thread.
Speaker 0: wait for someone to say the word Iran used to go with.
Speaker 1: it Sounds good.
Speaker 0: I think there might be one actually already.
Speaker 0: Oh great This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.