Speaker 0: It's Tuesday March 6th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We review.
Speaker 1: Phoenix writes This past weekend was a mighty good weekend of gaming.
Speaker 0: I must say yeah We haven't played some board games in a little bit, and we cranked out like four or five.
Speaker 1: I think right yeah Yeah, we even played one of my favorite games even though something horrible happened.
Speaker 1: We played motherfucking Shogun.
Speaker 0: We did an episode.
Speaker 0: well We did an episode in all the Milton Bradley game master series games at least the ones that we played.
Speaker 1: yeah But me Alex and Scott decided hey want to play Shogun?
Speaker 1: Yes Let's play Shogun.
Speaker 1: and we spent an hour learning the rules again because we always forget since they're kind of arbitrary.
Speaker 1: You know non-german game that tries to be all German style war game whatever.
Speaker 1: so we're playing and In the second round of the game it was the third round.
Speaker 1: I think might yeah It was the third round because I was leveled up a little bit.
Speaker 1: anyway right away I Scott built a little fortress, and he has his general is sitting there, and he thinks that he's perfectly invincible.
Speaker 0: He's on a coast, so I didn't think I was invincible, but I thought I was safe enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you were on a coast in a fortress with a moderately powerful army.
Speaker 1: However, I had set up this masterful swinging door plan where all three of my generals were gonna faint like they were just securing Territory and then in the third round they were all going to suddenly turn on.
Speaker 1: Scott I was going to utterly destroy him before Alex could even react Alrighty, and it was a beautiful plan.
Speaker 1: now Scott thinking he was safe in this fortress didn't worry too much and was utterly.
Speaker 0: I worried a little bit.
Speaker 0: I was looking over there.
Speaker 1: You were a little bit.
Speaker 0: I was a little bit worried, but I decided just go with it.
Speaker 1: You were a little bit Nonplussed when I said that my army was attacking you over the sea at your fortune.
Speaker 0: Well cuz I figured there was like a 20% chance you would do it and then when you did it It was like oh the 20% chance was actually 100%.
Speaker 1: whoa well the thing is I bought a whole bunch of Ronan right before that Battle.
Speaker 0: when you bought those Ronan.
Speaker 0: I was pretty sure you put them in that army.
Speaker 0: I was like 90%.
Speaker 0: sure.
Speaker 0: I You know sounds like But I just let it slide.
Speaker 1: yep, so the battle ensued.
Speaker 0: cuz I mean what was the alternative?
Speaker 0: I could have backed out of the already built fortress saved my daimyo and Given you a fortress.
Speaker 1: I. what I would have done is not built the fortress or put the.
Speaker 0: I had built the fortress many rounds Prior if it was that round and you had just built the Ronan.
Speaker 0: I would not have put a fortress there.
Speaker 0: I generally.
Speaker 1: I just in a many-player game.
Speaker 1: I would use fortresses, but in a three-player game I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: but anyway anyway.
Speaker 1: I killed Scott's daimyo.
Speaker 1: Well gawa marched up.
Speaker 0: well here's the thing is Scott fucked up.
Speaker 1: Oh, he fucked up.
Speaker 1: No, don't say we you didn't notice either Cuz your it was your duty as the defender to array all of your unit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't come yell at me for not noticing something you didn't notice cuz I didn't care.
Speaker 0: yeah, but anyway You know you probably would have beat me even if we had noticed.
Speaker 0: But we didn't notice that some of my guys were not counted and thus we had concluded the combat But we had done it incorrectly.
Speaker 1: yeah Scott had two extra spearman.
Speaker 1: he forgot to count.
Speaker 1: they would had almost no effect on the.
Speaker 0: they would have had a slight effect on the battle.
Speaker 0: almost no effect a Significant effect because they would have taken two hits before Two gunmen would have taken hits and they would have fired again, and yeah doesn't really matter it matters enough.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter a lot, but it matters enough.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter enough because it didn't matter at all.
Speaker 1: I was pretty much guaranteed to win that game anyway because I had a master plan set up and There's nothing to do with it.
Speaker 0: the point was the point was rim refused to recalculate the battle.
Speaker 0: that was not correct and Rather than play a screwed-up game.
Speaker 1: Well, it was more complicated than that because you see what happened was there.
Speaker 1: We couldn't replay the battle because I didn't remember exactly what was in the army when I started you the one always claiming that Your memory is so vastly superior.
Speaker 0: You couldn't remember something from two minutes ago.
Speaker 1: I never really claimed my memory is superior.
Speaker 1: I'm actually fairly forgetful hence.
Speaker 1: I forgot how many units were in that are.
Speaker 0: well now I got that recorded for a future you know.
Speaker 1: the interesting thing was that Scott admitted Then that even if he hadn't screwed up the combat he would have quit the game anyway.
Speaker 0: No I might not have.
Speaker 1: no you said very clearly and I have Alex to back it up that once you lost your are one of your three armies.
Speaker 1: you decided that the game was not fun and not worth playing and you were gonna the game that the Fun of the game did significantly decline at that point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, either way.
Speaker 1: I just think you have bad taste in war games Whatever.
Speaker 1: I mean you like battle are.
Speaker 0: the thing is Shogun is a really fun.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of fun, but the problem is it's not fun, but you're losing and you're no no It's nothing to do with losing even if you're winning.
Speaker 0: the game is not fun after like three or four rounds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not fun from beginning to end.
Speaker 0: It's like risk.
Speaker 0: It's fun, and that's not fun.
Speaker 1: I disagree.
Speaker 1: I've every time I've played it's been fun all the way to the end whether I was winning or losing.
Speaker 0: Every time I've played it has been not fun.
Speaker 1: about a third way through the game I think that's usually because you end up with one dime.
Speaker 1: You're hiding in the corner.
Speaker 0: I've won Shogun And it was still not fun.
Speaker 1: anyway Scott quit the game so Alex And I pissed Lee had to stop because there's no way we could continue playing.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 0: well, I mean is the is the dilemma right?
Speaker 0: let's say there's three people playing a game right and Everyone is enjoying the game.
Speaker 0: then suddenly something happens It doesn't matter what it is and now one person is no longer enjoying the game.
Speaker 0: in fact there It would be unfun.
Speaker 0: It would be upsetting to them.
Speaker 0: so they have to continue playing the game Should you know?
Speaker 0: obviously that person would be very nice if they would you know give some self-sacrifice to suffer for the?
Speaker 0: Entertainment of the two people who would still like to continue playing the game.
Speaker 0: But you know then does the question of huh well that maybe ruin the game if one person doesn't really care about it But they're still playing?
Speaker 0: just see it's sake of it.
Speaker 1: If you're a nice person or in any way upstanding if you commit to a board game You've committed to the end unless the majority of players agree to quit.
Speaker 1: so if you renege on that then you're a jackass.
Speaker 0: That's my standing an ass.
Speaker 0: you may be but if that if you were the guy you know would you do it?
Speaker 0: Would you guess why?
Speaker 1: yes?
Speaker 1: I've kept playing many times in a game where I had already lost and I didn't care or I was otherwise not having fun for Whatever reason because I would not renege on something that I had committed to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know It's tough.
Speaker 0: Maybe like you know there were some other factors like if we had not messed up the battle and I was still losing and still Not having fun.
Speaker 0: I might have continued to play also if it was earlier in the day I might have continued to play.
Speaker 1: whatever the point is you quit, and we couldn't play our game.
Speaker 0: That's true because it wasn't fun anymore.
Speaker 0: more important.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 1: We yeah, you suck.
Speaker 1: more importantly We played another game of Vinci.
Speaker 1: now Vinci is not a game Where ties are likely.
Speaker 1: the fact the odds of tying in a game of Vinci just considering how many points and rounds are involved?
Speaker 0: Pretty slim especially if you have few players Then it's real hard now.
Speaker 1: despite that in the two of the last two games There has been a tie First between myself and Scott and now between Alex and myself and the game and where Alex and rim tied the most recent game I only lost but I was behind them by two points.
Speaker 1: I think the three of us have played.
Speaker 1: this is one of those situations where the three of us have played a game enough to the point where we're all equally skilled.
Speaker 1: now, and it's just a matter of I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's just a matter of what civilization tiles come up in what combination and who takes them and when I think it comes I mean it comes down to Declining one thing.
Speaker 1: once one round too soon you lose.
Speaker 0: yep There was one thing in that whole game that I declined a little air But Alex on the next round declined to say his thing.
Speaker 0: a little air.
Speaker 0: So it evened out, and that's why I was you know right up there.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, but anyway before we do the news.
Speaker 1: I got to do a geek back because this is really important.
Speaker 1: now It's not even a normal geek back in fact.
Speaker 1: It's a reverse geek back.
Speaker 1: I'm geeking back to someone else because you know they're listening.
Speaker 1: I'm assuming they're listening.
Speaker 1: if they're not they'd better because this affects them directly.
Speaker 1: This is a call-out if you will.
Speaker 1: you see I listen to Dave and Joel's fast karate for the gentleman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, listen to that too.
Speaker 1: and the other day They were talking about various things and at one point the topic of air hockey came up And a comment was made that essentially said air hockey is a game of chance what?
Speaker 1: Now that's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: I was in my car where they were.
Speaker 0: they smoking weed during this.
Speaker 1: I was in my car, and I said what and I rewound it.
Speaker 1: I listened again to make sure that they had actually said that and then I stopped listening And I stewed about it for the rest of the day.
Speaker 0: all right all right.
Speaker 0: if air hockey is a game of chance Then if any two people on earth any to play against each other right any number of times Then they will each win about half the time assuming the table is symmetrical and working and such.
Speaker 1: now you can even make allowances like they might be.
Speaker 1: I mean they might have actually Meant that it's largely chance and a small bit of skill in which case still the odds of winning or losing are maybe 60/40 At most.
Speaker 0: however I know from experience that a skilled air hockey player will beat an Unskilled air hockey player almost 100% of the time.
Speaker 1: now We're not gonna do a whole thing about air hockey here because we're gonna say gonna do a separate show on air hockey in the Future.
Speaker 1: yeah, maybe a Tuesday Maybe a Thursday because it is a game, but also Thursdays are lacking for content, and it's not a video game.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna talk about air hockey video games which all suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the point is that they've made this statement And if it had been any other game if they had said this about anything.
Speaker 1: I would have not even noticed or cared.
Speaker 1: I would have laughed a little bit.
Speaker 1: But it just so happens that I'm really good at air hockey.
Speaker 1: Scott is also really good at air.
Speaker 0: We're both Really good at air hockey now.
Speaker 1: lately I've been on the uptick and I've been winning more than Scott.
Speaker 1: But there have been times when the opposite has been true And there will be times again when the opposite will be true.
Speaker 1: we oscillate back and forth But no one else can beat us except professional air hockey players.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically if me and rim beat it you know play each other in air hockey.
Speaker 0: We don't know who's gonna win and it tends to go in streaks.
Speaker 0: But if we ever play any of our friends in air hockey they have never beaten us.
Speaker 0: We have pretty much undefeated against our friends in air hockey except each other.
Speaker 1: yes now granted in some ways That's the small pond syndrome.
Speaker 1: I mean until I got to RIT my sophomore year I was in my life undefeated at arcade air hockey And then Luke Morgan beat me and I realized that I had been playing against chumps up until that point.
Speaker 0: Well, he had it.
Speaker 0: He didn't have a good.
Speaker 0: He didn't have a high skill at air hockey.
Speaker 0: He had a cheap and clever strategy.
Speaker 0: It was sort of like he was sort of like a punch-out boss like soda Popinski.
Speaker 0: He's not dangerous.
Speaker 0: once you learn his pattern you can beat him, but his patterns tricky if you don't know it yet.
Speaker 1: And it worked on me, and I couldn't believe it.
Speaker 0: and I came back and Scott And I trained and trained and once he figured out the pattern he couldn't win anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like soda pop in.
Speaker 1: since then I mean unless we enter an air hockey tournament Which we there aren't any near us that we have time to enter.
Speaker 1: but suffice to say gonna long story short Dave and Joel I'm willing to put my money where my mouth is because you have already said that you believe this is a game of chance.
Speaker 1: Therefore you have odds of winning what I'm about to put forth.
Speaker 1: you see if either of you can beat Either of us at any two out of three match of air hockey now Unlimited tries for the rest of your lives as long as you can find us and we can play a game We'll give you a hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: It has to be a real air hockey table.
Speaker 0: It can't be one of those $50 tables from like Walmart.
Speaker 1: gotta be a photon or photon equivalent tournament regulation.
Speaker 0: yet for anyone who doesn't know there is I Consider there to be only one legitimate manufacturer of playable air hockey tables and that manufacturer is Valley Dynamo.
Speaker 1: now There are other air hockey tables that we would accept for the purposes this challenge Just because it might not always be easy to find a photon table.
Speaker 0: Yes, well Valley Dynamo makes other air hockey tables besides the photon.
Speaker 0: the photon just happens to be my table of choice.
Speaker 0: But any air hockey any at least a seven foot long arcade style air hockey table that is full-size that is manufactured by Valley Dynamo and is in Good enough working order will count.
Speaker 1: so thus if either one of you can be either one of us It'll be $50 if you can beat me and $50 if you can beat Scott now Anytime you play against us.
Speaker 1: if we win you lose nothing.
Speaker 1: There is no stake of failure.
Speaker 1: if you win however you get the money.
Speaker 1: now There are two ways to go with this.
Speaker 0: you can only win the money once.
Speaker 0: you can't beat us again and again and again To take all our money.
Speaker 1: granted not that I'm too worried about.
Speaker 1: no Now I thought hey if we put this challenge out What if they decide to train and practice and become really good and you know what that?
Speaker 1: Proves my argument right because that meant that you had to train to beat me.
Speaker 1: that meant that you Answered your own question, and you said to yourself Dave I am NOT good enough to beat rim or Scott.
Speaker 1: Therefore I am going to train and add to my skill in order to beat them.
Speaker 1: therefore It is not a game of chance and therefore I win regardless of having to give you money.
Speaker 0: So basically we pay you to have you be shameful of your previous statement.
Speaker 1: of course I also just want to play air hockey against you.
Speaker 1: to prove you in horrible fashion.
Speaker 1: I mean people have watched us play air hockey against each other and the matches last 10 to 15 minutes sometimes because it's just nuts.
Speaker 1: But watching us play against anyone else.
Speaker 1: We'll do what.
Speaker 1: we're kind of assholes.
Speaker 1: We'll do things like not gonna score not gonna score.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna score right now bing Yeah, I played against a lot of people who can't shoot the puck straight into the goal from their side of the table.
Speaker 0: So I'll just you know I'll just be like uh and I'll take my hands up in the air and they can't put it in the puck in the goal And then I'll stop the puck and then they'll hold their disc right in front of their goal And I'll be like bounce it off the side in the goal And be like uh how'd that happen?
Speaker 1: never mind my special move which I actually overuse against Scott.
Speaker 1: He can block it readily, but no one else can block my special.
Speaker 0: where you reach out across the table.
Speaker 1: Oh, not that the one where I hit the side and put that English on it.
Speaker 0: whatever that fucker whatever.
Speaker 1: now We'll play whatever style you want clap or no clap.
Speaker 1: No it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: yep Yep, any style of air hockey playing you want you can make up the rules as well.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: of course the table rules is that you know seven goals usually wins.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's got to be some sort of legitimate air hockey some sort of photon table.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: clap or no clap.
Speaker 1: clap by the way is where you pick up the paddle and drop it on the puck Which is illegal in most tournaments, but it's okay in the Midwest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: I think it's enough about air hockey Yeah, but yeah anyone else out there who thinks they're good at air hockey.
Speaker 0: You should meet us and play air hockey Yeah, we'll play a game air hockey with you.
Speaker 1: in fact if anyone challenges us to air hockey We'll always pay for the game just to humiliate you, but then once you lose you have to start paying to try again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, unless we really cuz sometimes there's no one to play air hockey with.
Speaker 1: sometimes partly cuz no one will play against us.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 0: So news all right.
Speaker 1: I got a quick news.
Speaker 1: Among the virtual console games to have come out on the Wii this week Special mention has to go out to super ghoul go Ghosts and goblins ghouls and ghosts ghouls and ghosts.
Speaker 0: right I think it's super ghouls and ghosts.
Speaker 1: it was ghosts and goblins on the NES.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the super it's super ghouls and ghosts.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: I just want to say fuck that game.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is ghosts and goblins for the NES is one of the hardest games ever.
Speaker 1: yeah grant need it wasn't Unexpectedly hard for the era.
Speaker 1: I mean I knew exactly what I was getting into when I bought that game.
Speaker 0: It wasn't silver surfer hard, but it was pretty close to silver surfer hard, but yet I knew people who could beat it.
Speaker 0: yep super ghouls and ghosts for the SNES I think was a better game because I played both of them and while it was also stupidly hard I could get farther in the Super Nintendo game than I could in the NES.
Speaker 1: well You see I got all the way to the end one day, and there was no game facts back.
Speaker 1: Then I didn't other than a Nintendo power.
Speaker 1: I didn't really know much about the games.
Speaker 1: I was just playing through it I was getting good at it And then I get to world seven or whatever near the end and Princess basically says oh by the way Here's a magic necklace now.
Speaker 1: You got to go beat the whole game again before you can fight the actual boss.
Speaker 1: Oh, and by the way the games twice as hard now, and I said what I've never even gotten past like level two.
Speaker 1: I sold the game back to funko land that day.
Speaker 1: I was so pissed.
Speaker 1: All right granted.
Speaker 1: I kind of regretted that later because I realized that I still wanted to beat the game But it was too late, but that moment of anger sealed the game's fate and to this day I've never beaten it.
Speaker 0: so do you think who do you think should buy this game on the virtual console if you like?
Speaker 0: really hard old-school platformer shooters Okay, and when I say really I mean really really yeah, really, but sex Okay, so I think I did this as news before when they first announced it, but now it is happening.
Speaker 0: Counter.
Speaker 0: you might know if you are a player of steam half-life mods of the game called counter-strike the most popular Online shooting game the game that for a long time single-handedly dominated the online gaming world.
Speaker 0: Well, there are two versions of counter-strike that you can play at the moment.
Speaker 0: there is counter-strike 1.6 Which is a half-life 1 game and counter-strike source, which is a half-life 2 game even though they're pretty similar But also different in ways not noticeable by normal people, but very noticeable to gamers.
Speaker 1: Yes, in fact a lot of people who have the capacity to play the newer version play the old one because they prefer it.
Speaker 0: well I announced a long time ago on the podcast the news about them adding Advertisements to the old counter-strike, so you know a means to make money off of something which has always been free.
Speaker 0: Alrighty well guess what.
Speaker 0: now there's pretty much gonna be ads in it But only on two maps on dust 2 and Aztec.
Speaker 0: there will be ads.
Speaker 1: I just wait in the.
Speaker 0: in the non steam version the old game the old the steam one has no ads.
Speaker 0: It's the old one that has ads so only in those two maps.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Just don't run those maps I know.
Speaker 1: or run modified versions of those maps.
Speaker 1: run the old BSP.
Speaker 0: I got.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you can do that anymore.
Speaker 0: I think they have the vac what?
Speaker 0: I don't know how the shit works.
Speaker 0: But maybe you could run modified versions of the maps.
Speaker 1: The only reason you couldn't run one is if other people connecting to you didn't have it.
Speaker 0: yeah I guess instead of auto download.
Speaker 1: There's there's no way that could work unless they broke counter-strike.
Speaker 0: I have no idea how it works But they've got it.
Speaker 0: and it used to be that.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: some people would go into the beta test You know to get the ads the you know what.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you would do that beta.
Speaker 0: test the ads but Now it's not beta anymore and everyone sees the ads.
Speaker 0: but all the ads are for other valve stuff.
Speaker 0: They don't have any ads for other things yet, so you'll be walking around Aztec, and you'll see like you know.
Speaker 0: buy half-life 2 today.
Speaker 0: Please buy half-life 2 episode 1.
Speaker 1: see the thing is.
Speaker 1: the only reason this is even issue is because the way Counter-strike is set up it can't be played without their stupid authentication stuff.
Speaker 1: so if like quake 2 to this day you can still play quake 2 online and there are a Call them they don't have to do anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz there's no reason.
Speaker 0: if I want they could turn on server.
Speaker 1: I just run one and it just works And yep will know my IP address.
Speaker 1: they can connect to it and play quake 2 with me.
Speaker 0: Yep John Carmack could turn off every computer he and in software owns and you could still play quake 2 with your friends on the internet.
Speaker 1: But valve was so worried about piracy and probably about protecting their various revenues and cheating.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that you can't play counter-strike without crazy hacking or using their authentication servers.
Speaker 1: Yep, in fact they threat.
Speaker 1: They didn't really threaten openly But they hinted many times in the past at shutting down the old wand servers to force people to play the new counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically.
Speaker 0: I don't know there are good things about you know them having some sort of centralized Authentication tracking mechanism for all these games, but there's also bad things about it.
Speaker 0: And one of the bad things is now you might see some ads.
Speaker 1: See the thing is I'd care more if I still played counter-strike.
Speaker 1: I would still but at the same time the only reason I don't play counter-strike is that I no longer have a computer capable of doing so.
Speaker 0: Yep, well now even if you had a computer capable of doing so you wouldn't play counter-strike 1.6.
Speaker 0: You'd probably stick to counter-strike source or whatever.
Speaker 1: no I'd probably still play 1.6 and avoid the ads somehow cuz.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah But hopefully when Team Fortress 2 comes out they will not have ads in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm really looking forward to those days because I am buying a new computer specifically for PC gaming.
Speaker 1: I'm jumping back in I'm gonna buy all those games like Civ 4, and I'm gonna play him And I'm gonna talk about him.
Speaker 0: I am also going to buy all those games cuz pretty much.
Speaker 1: I've missed almost two eras of PC gaming now.
Speaker 0: You haven't missed much.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I really haven't.
Speaker 1: that's why I'm not.
Speaker 0: I mean this is one of the best years that's gonna happen ever because we've got three valve games coming out And we've got port um not well portals one of the three valve games.
Speaker 0: I haven't for spore.
Speaker 1: I haven't been this excited about the PC game lineup since quake 2 was announced.
Speaker 0: um Maybe that's true.
Speaker 1: Well the era when quake 2 and all those games were coming out, okay?
Speaker 1: I haven't been this excited since the 90s I mean, I think tribes 2 was the last time I was excited about a PC game.
Speaker 0: until now okay, so yeah since 2000 I haven't been excited.
Speaker 1: That was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: in 2000 I was still playing with a seven.
Speaker 0: there's been a seven year drought of PC gaming things of the day.
Speaker 1: So this is a video of someone analyzing with examples and video and Everything almost every aspect of super dodgeball for the original nes that you could possibly Understand know or care about while playing that game.
Speaker 0: I mean it also if you watch him play.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's basically a human controlled speed run.
Speaker 0: I mean he beats the game about as fast as he can possibly be beaten.
Speaker 0: I Don't see anyone doing it any more efficiently or any faster.
Speaker 1: I mean granted the stuff he talks about is really interesting.
Speaker 1: But if you read the instruction book to the game Which was actually pretty thick or if you ever looked at game facts, or if you actually played the game enough It's nothing new.
Speaker 1: But if you're one of those people who just always sucked at this game because the game isn't So intuitive especially if you didn't have the manual a lot of people never figured out how to throw those Ground attacks as opposed to the air attacks or things like that.
Speaker 0: yeah I think one thing about this game is that while you can get all the information You know that he says it's hard to understand what that information actually means in terms of the actual gameplay.
Speaker 0: So when he says it and he shows you video of what he's talking about at the same time it really helps you get a complete Understanding of this game in about five minutes.
Speaker 1: yes I was also very pleased that he chooses the same loadout that I choose when I'm playing the single-player game.
Speaker 1: The same reasons.
Speaker 1: he even says I don't pick John because while his endurance is awesome I don't need that because I don't fail to catch the ball.
Speaker 0: Yep, that is.
Speaker 0: one problem with that game is that you know there are these stats to make one team better than another but Humans can catch the ball no matter what player they're using or anything.
Speaker 1: so it's like yeah I mean my brother And I got really good at this game as kids and it would literally come down to where we were playing.
Speaker 1: No amount of playing would ever cause one of us to win and the game would last over an hour Until one of us got tired or just made a mistake.
Speaker 0: If I had made that game the one thing I would have done differently to mix it up is I would have had you know the stats so that certain players Like one guy is really good at catching.
Speaker 0: so even if you push the button a little late or early He'll still catch it.
Speaker 0: that would have been one and some other players would be not so good at catching.
Speaker 0: So if you had anything less than perfect timing they would be hit.
Speaker 0: Another thing I would have done is certain players would assert would have had sort of a catch endurance.
Speaker 0: It's like if they just caught the ball recently like twice and if they try to catch it on the next throw It's gonna be a lot harder almost impossible.
Speaker 0: so you have to have someone else catch it.
Speaker 1: that way you have to made cat automate a stamina stat and Basically when you get hit by anything stamina goes down and comes up slowly And you only take real damage when the stamina is zero.
Speaker 0: That's pretty new.
Speaker 1: catches drop stamina, but not as much as being hit.
Speaker 1: or maybe I got a bunch of ideas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think what we can both agree on is that super dodgeball is an old NES game that needs a modern remake Yes Cuz it was that in River City ransom are some of my favorite games ever pretty much every game made by What was those companies?
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 1: and regardless all those games are awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all the games that look like that you all know what those games are the soccer one and the the other one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah the other one I forget anyway.
Speaker 0: So if you thought that going to the movies and seeing ads before the movie was bad now well it used to be worse.
Speaker 1: They're lucky that this was about something.
Speaker 0: I have great nostalgia for yeah, so Back in the day Atari when they were still the company that made the Atari 2600 and all that other shit They put out an ad for a video game.
Speaker 0: They were making an arcade video game, and they put that ad in the movie theaters.
Speaker 0: It was like a pretty long ad.
Speaker 0: it was a few minutes long.
Speaker 0: It was produced on film and if you went to see a movie you see this ad before I presume Before the movie or maybe during the intermission which they don't have anymore or something like that.
Speaker 1: You know I've never been to a film that had an intermission except Hamlet.
Speaker 0: I did when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: We would go to the movies and like three like the first three times I ever went to the movies they had intermission.
Speaker 0: Even when I was a little kid there was no intermission like a real little kid like three like I wanted to see the Sesame Street movie and those intermission wow yep all the old.
Speaker 0: also the Care Bears movie.
Speaker 1: wow there wasn't an intermission at the Care Bears movie I remember clearly maybe I'm pretty sure it was the Care Bears movie.
Speaker 1: what there was however was the cartoon before the movie.
Speaker 0: oh Always a cartoon before the movie.
Speaker 0: anything else is unthinkable however.
Speaker 1: I got to say this this Dig Dug ad.
Speaker 0: oh Yeah, it's an ad for Dig Dug.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess you didn't say that yet.
Speaker 1: That's fine It's pretty bad and not like the Power Glove.
Speaker 0: No it's it's real bad.
Speaker 0: I mean I like Dig Dug a lot, but this this is not Dig Dug.
Speaker 1: I'm really see a lot of ads from that era are a lot like this And I don't understand them.
Speaker 1: even then I didn't understand them.
Speaker 1: They just don't seem like they're actually selling the product.
Speaker 0: well in the end They didn't really sell the product.
Speaker 0: that well did they?
Speaker 1: no Atari didn't do so.
Speaker 0: well No So I wonder if it was because they spent a lot of money on shitty movie theater ads that made Dig Dug look bad Instead of good.
Speaker 0: Yes, Dig Dug is awesome super awesome.
Speaker 1: I just can't imagine being a human being and seeing that in the theater before a movie especially back Then when there really weren't so many ads before movies.
Speaker 0: well I had an ad before my movie a Dig Dug ad.
Speaker 0: it was the style of the time.
Speaker 1: So we realized well, you know I mean originally I wanted to review XCOM UFO defense Which is in my opinion one of the greatest video or games ever made.
Speaker 0: XCOM UFO defense is a great game.
Speaker 0: however I have not played it that much because well I didn't have it back in the DOS days, and I'm not gonna play it anytime soon.
Speaker 1: yeah for me It was actually the first game that wasn't shareware that I ever got whoa.
Speaker 1: However I got it pirated.
Speaker 1: whoa just gave it to me on some discs crazy, and they gave me a piece of paper.
Speaker 1: They said the codes to start the game are on this piece of paper, and I remember thinking to myself that seems silly.
Speaker 1: Why would they do something like that?
Speaker 0: I thought the same.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I had no concept.
Speaker 0: you try to play star control - there was this big star chart And they you had to find a star at certain Coordinates in order to get the game to work.
Speaker 1: Quest for glory - is one of the few games that did it right.
Speaker 1: the copy protection was a big color map that came with The game and if you wandered off into the city streets good luck finding your way around without that map.
Speaker 1: However if you were badass or diligent you probably could find your way around.
Speaker 1: Well probably not because there's a really big city and most of its dead ends, but
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, so seeing as you weren't gonna talk about a game that only one of us knew enough about to do an episode on we tried to think of a game that we had not talked about in the show that we have both played.
Speaker 0: and Well we finally came up with the answer Amazingly enough despite it showing up in our archives like six times.
Speaker 0: We never actually talked about Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, we talked about it.
Speaker 1: We just didn't review it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, so let's do that.
Speaker 1: so Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: I'm sure many of you are aware of it But very briefly for people who haven't actually played it Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: Known in Japan is Gakuten Saiban is a game about lawyers.
Speaker 1: You're a defense attorney named Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: And you defend people who are always innocent against evil prosecutors who are always evil.
Speaker 0: Now you're.
Speaker 0: the game is called Gakuten Saiban in Japan because that means turn about courtroom Which is?
Speaker 0: that's basically what the game is about.
Speaker 0: you have these court cases and at some point in the case Everything turns about.
Speaker 0: sometimes it turns about a lot Sometimes it turns about a little but every case looks like it's going in one direction one direction one direction And then sometime near the end of the case right before you solve it everything you think is wrong and the whole thing gets turned on its head and the answer becomes apparent.
Speaker 1: and Hooray now depending on how smart you are you might figure out what the turnout is gonna be before it happens in which case it Feel like there's much of a turnabout at all.
Speaker 0: It just kind of feels like you figured it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the second game hasn't been doing it for me in that regard yet But I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe cuz I haven't been playing it in one straight shot like I did the first game.
Speaker 0: Yep Well in Japan, there are three GBA games, I think they're all GBA games I don't know.
Speaker 0: and there was a fourth one that is coming soon or is about to be out?
Speaker 1: I'm not sure way to have the information.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's basically each one has four episodes in it.
Speaker 0: So there are 12 episodes in the whole series and as soon as the fourth game comes out presumably There will be 16 episodes.
Speaker 0: now in the US They gave us the first GBA game as a DS game.
Speaker 0: in addition They added a rant of fifth episode to it.
Speaker 0: the fifth episode in the first Phoenix Wright in the US was not in Phoenix Wright 1 and the GBA in Japan and that's pretty obvious once you play that episode that it has nothing to do With the first four episodes.
Speaker 1: Well also considering that it uses the DS straight up and there was no way you could have done that On a GBA.
Speaker 0: Yep, all the other episodes except for episode 5 and the first Phoenix Wright Don't actually use any special DS features.
Speaker 0: All they do is let you play this otherwise GBA game with the DS stylus Which actually makes the game a lot more awesome and easier to play.
Speaker 0: But that wasn't the way the game originally was and it's not necessary, but it makes the game fun.
Speaker 1: I like it now the DS one that the the one that actually uses the DS at the end of the first cartridge is Basically an entire game in and of itself.
Speaker 1: It's so long and good that they probably could have sold it as a separate game And I would have paid the same amount of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah as I mean each game has four episodes, but the episodes get longer and better.
Speaker 0: It's like the first episode on any one of these is short and kind of simple and it's not really worth anything And the second one is kind of moderate like okay.
Speaker 0: Then the third one is like a real-deal episode and the fourth one is always some incredible crazy Climax episode that's really long.
Speaker 0: It's probably multiple days of trials and Of one trial and crazy things happen usually involving the plot.
Speaker 0: You know though what they tend to do is each trial each of the episodes in any particular instance of the game Will be separate, you know, this is a story of this killing that killing some other killing.
Speaker 0: They're unrelated But there will be this sort of background plot that is in the first few.
Speaker 0: at first three episodes like something else is going on Mmm, and then in the fourth episode they'll deal with that and it's like whoa.
Speaker 0: They're dealing with the plot that they've been alluding to the whole time.
Speaker 0: Holy crap had that happen.
Speaker 1: Now the game itself every bit basically gets broken up into one of two types.
Speaker 1: You're either collecting evidence and interviewing people or you're in the courtroom and they're both kind of equally awesome in different ways.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really sometimes feels a lot more like a detective kind of Carmen San Diego game.
Speaker 0: then it feels like a lawyer game.
Speaker 1: yeah, definitely has CSI syndrome where you're a defense attorney and You're the detective and you're the forensics guy even though there's a detective and a forensics guy, but they don't do much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the the the justice system within which you are working in Phoenix Wright is insane.
Speaker 1: effectively prosecutors exist to get a guilty verdict regardless of whether or not someone's actually guilty and The judge will just say guilty at the drop of a hat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the prosecutor will say something like.
Speaker 1: I can't think of anyone else who could have done this crime Therefore guilty and the judges say I don't see anything wrong with that argument.
Speaker 0: And then as you as the defense attorney if you don't open your mouth, it's just guilty right there and then you got nothing.
Speaker 0: You see you got to keep saying stuff to prevent the guilty verdict.
Speaker 0: It's like guilty until proven innocent, which is why that's not how our court system works because it would be very bad.
Speaker 1: yep, also the detective the police officers involved Basically work for the prosecution and their job is to make sure the prosecution gets a guilty verdict.
Speaker 0: It really sucks for the defense attorney especially since most of the time your clients are innocent.
Speaker 0: or else what would be the point of having you play a game as a Defense attorney with guilty as client?
Speaker 1: that could have been really cool.
Speaker 1: If you've got a client and you're trying to defend him and they're in the end.
Speaker 1: They are guilty and oh shit.
Speaker 0: So that would be crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially if you got him off anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now the game.
Speaker 1: I mean the two parts the.
Speaker 1: the way the game works is basically dialogue boxes with text characters in front of you talking Evidence areas where you poke around and look for stuff and then the courtroom which is a whole separate thing.
Speaker 1: So you run into a person and they'll be you know Like one two or three or whatever number of things you can ask them about and they'll give you interesting answers.
Speaker 1: Sometimes things you ask them will open up more things you can ask about.
Speaker 1: sometimes things they say will become evidence you can use later.
Speaker 0: Yep, the other thing is you have this like bucket of evidence.
Speaker 0: You can look at the evidence at any time you can read about it you know you can collect more of it and you can show it to people.
Speaker 0: and that always gets pretty fun because you'll walk up to someone and you'd be like alright and you'll show them every piece of evidence.
Speaker 0: and Sometimes you have to show them a piece of evidence to get them to say something that you need to continue with the game.
Speaker 0: But sometimes you'll just show them something and they'll say something interesting But most of the time they have a default thing they say which is annoying.
Speaker 1: Yep, that definitely seems to be the primary punishment mechanism of the evidence-gathering thing that anything you do that is wrong Just waste your time and annoys you but it doesn't hurt you.
Speaker 0: It's really hard to lose at Phoenix, right?
Speaker 0: It's possible but hard.
Speaker 1: I lost once because I wasn't really paying attention and I think it was the fourth one of the first game and I wasn't paying attention.
Speaker 1: So I used up a bunch of my strikes early on and then I got to an actually hard part and I had one strike Left.
Speaker 0: I was like, ah, ah Basically you have this sort of in the first.
Speaker 0: in the first Phoenix right in the US you have these strikes and every time you screw up in court like If the judge says show me the piece of evidence that proves X and you show the wrong one You get a strike and then you have to try again.
Speaker 0: If you get too many strikes, it's guilty and you lose.
Speaker 0: in the second Phoenix, right?
Speaker 0: You have this health meter and whenever you screw up depending on what you screw up like a little screw up It'll go down a little bit and a big screw up and it'll go down a lot.
Speaker 0: But then they added in this feature for the second Phoenix right game in the US called the psych lock.
Speaker 1: these are really cool.
Speaker 1: say you're talking to someone and Suddenly they get all defensive about something without spoiling how you get it.
Speaker 1: You have a psychic power Wherein you can see people's innermost secrets.
Speaker 1: So if someone's hiding something suddenly you'll see them surrounded by chains with locks on them.
Speaker 0: It's actually sort of scary when it happens, but what you have to do is You can attempt to break those locks and get them to tell their secret to you.
Speaker 0: to do it You have to go and find the quote keys to the locks, which are usually pieces of evidence or facts.
Speaker 0: So when you tell you know, you'll start pressing them on the issue you'd be like.
Speaker 0: so this secret you've got blah.
Speaker 0: They'll be like, I don't know nothing you like.
Speaker 0: Well, look at this All right, all right like
Speaker 1: I don't know Joey Jojo Shabbat when you say is a picture
Speaker 0: of you kissing him
Speaker 1: and then they go and one of the locks breaks then like You can't prove that's a picture of me and then you prove it's a picture that
Speaker 0: on the back is their signature and like a love Note or something?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and when you break all the locks they break down They usually cry or something and then they tell you what they were hiding from you.
Speaker 0: Yet the other cool thing is when you break the psych lock your health meter fills back up.
Speaker 1: But at the same time if you make mistakes breaking psych locks you take psychic damage and you can get close to dying.
Speaker 0: Yeah so it actually the.
Speaker 0: the mechanic of psych locks in the game kind of makes it nice because usually Investigate in between days of the trial.
Speaker 0: So if you suck one day at the trial you can make up for it by breaking the psych locks without screwing up.
Speaker 1: It also adds an interesting element to the evidence gathering because in the first game the evidence gathering you couldn't lose there.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a matter of screwing up It was just a matter of figuring out how to get all the evidence to make the day progress.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now you can get stuck.
Speaker 1: You have to worry you have to make decisions that might hurt you.
Speaker 0: I mean really when you look at the game It's just sort of telling you this story and you have to figure out what buttons to push to get the story to continue.
Speaker 1: It's more a puzzle game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's basically you're solving logical puzzles.
Speaker 0: Like alright, what do I have to do?
Speaker 0: You know to get this to happen?
Speaker 0: because that person is doing X and that person's doing Y and that person said this and I Have these items.
Speaker 0: What does this mean?
Speaker 0: Aha.
Speaker 0: Let me try to do this.
Speaker 0: That makes sense.
Speaker 0: Oh look now it's getting me further along in the game and eventually you get to the end of the game.
Speaker 1: Yep, a lot of the trial the trial sequence is really interesting.
Speaker 1: They often boil down to things like the prosecution will say something and then you'll want like it'll cut to Phoenix and he'll think to Himself.
Speaker 1: so is this worth pursuing or should I let it drop and you have to decide?
Speaker 1: and if you decide to pursue it But it actually wasn't worth it You'll back yourself into a corner or lose some health or get penalized or whatever.
Speaker 0: Sometimes the game will trick you and pull you into loops like in the first Phoenix, right?
Speaker 0: I noticed most of the time.
Speaker 0: if you made the wrong decision, it would just be like you're stupid.
Speaker 0: Try again.
Speaker 0: You just choose the other answer and the second Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: They like say you bluff you don't know and it's like should I press further?
Speaker 1: and you're like, yeah, this is important I'm gonna press it'll let you keep pressing.
Speaker 1: So then the judge will be like, alright show me the evidence that this is important.
Speaker 1: and now it gives you the evidence thing and you're like, ah
Speaker 0: And you try to you choose different pieces of evidence and they're all wrong because it was a trap and you actually should have said No, but if you'd say yes, and you don't realize that you were stupid You're just gonna keep presenting evidence till you're blue in the face and you die.
Speaker 1: So don't think that this is a lawyer game.
Speaker 1: It is actually a puzzle game.
Speaker 0: if you like Carmen Sandiego with plot then you'll like Phoenix, right?
Speaker 0: And if you want to learn a lot about something that isn't real as opposed to learning geography Yeah, well what's good about Phoenix, right that I think it makes it so super popular is that it is not a faithful Translation from the Japanese.
Speaker 0: I've looked and I've seen what the Japanese ones are about and the American ones are close But they're not nearly as close as 90% of the anime and manga that we watch
Speaker 1: partly because the humor is Often very distinctly Japanese or Whatever and they very much localized these games to a younger American audience,
Speaker 0: but they localized them.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like what they brought over here.
Speaker 0: is you know The way they translated it and rewrote all the dialogue is not the way it was in Japan But the way it is is good.
Speaker 1: It's kind of this equal but different thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also it helps that the music is still the same and the character designs are still the same.
Speaker 1: Yes, I mean the game itself is fun and the gameplay would keep me going for a long time.
Speaker 1: But what really makes this game shine?
Speaker 1: Aside from the fact that the stories are actually pretty good and the jokes while sometimes horrible and punny are still funny Sometimes but even when they're bad, it's bad in this.
Speaker 1: Ah Kind of way as opposed to this kind of way.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: But what makes the game shine is the characters.
Speaker 1: and if you want to encapsulate all that this game actually is That graphic on the front of Phoenix standing there with that finger in the air pointing it as hard as he can.
Speaker 1: Yep, this game is all about style characters yelling dramatic soap opera action intricate love triangles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you like choose your own adventure books, you're probably like Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Also, I mean Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: I think would make a fantastic anime.
Speaker 0: I think there's a manga coming out at least in Japanese.
Speaker 1: I want an anime.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it needs an anime.
Speaker 1: No, it's not a hole.
Speaker 1: It doesn't need a 26 episode show.
Speaker 1: It needs like a one episode OAV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would definitely work out.
Speaker 0: if there's a one up or maybe a movie I'll move you would maybe be alright.
Speaker 1: the movie would have to go a little bit darker.
Speaker 1: So then again the game with you would you move?
Speaker 0: you'd have to cover like like three cases or something like that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's tough.
Speaker 0: Oh, we didn't talk about exactly how the courtroom works.
Speaker 0: The courtroom is actually pretty fun when you're you know Cuz we were talking about your examine.
Speaker 0: you go around looking for evidence When you're actually in the court.
Speaker 0: the way it works is They'll just be sort of this.
Speaker 0: you don't really control anything and you get you know.
Speaker 0: the judge says stuff the prosecutor says stuff Phoenix says stuff.
Speaker 0: then they'll be a witness and Phoenix will get to cross-examine every witness.
Speaker 0: So the witness will first testify and they'll say a bunch of stuff and what they say will be broken up into like Individual sentences.
Speaker 1: so you look at each sentence or chunk of sentences and on each one you have an option to press meaning You're gonna push him for more information about whatever they just said or Present evidence meaning I have found a contradiction.
Speaker 1: I am going to now enlighten you and push you toward the truth by proving that you were wrong.
Speaker 0: So let's say rim is the witness and rim says I don't know.
Speaker 0: the body was found at noon.
Speaker 0: The body was a man.
Speaker 0: The body there was a wallet on the floor at the time.
Speaker 1: So then Scott presses me.
Speaker 1: the body was found at noon and I say I looked at my watch You saw that it was noon.
Speaker 0: and then I press him on.
Speaker 1: the body was a man and I'm like, yeah It was a man.
Speaker 1: I saw the short hair and the beard and then you you know, you have the autopsy report So you had present and say haha.
Speaker 1: It was actually a woman.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that's the kind of stuff you actually will find in the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know and sometimes like you'll you'll.
Speaker 0: basically the strategy I have in the game is that no matter what anyone says I will press on every single sentence because it doesn't hurt to press on every single say usually you.
Speaker 0: there are a couple Specific occasions where the judge will say don't press more than once or twice or I'm gonna get you or stop badgering the witness.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if he says that then you you don't want to keep pressing but most of the time 90% of the time you can just press every sentence they say to reveal another sentence of information.
Speaker 0: and You you know, sometimes they'll have to modify their testimony.
Speaker 0: and when they modify their testimony then aha They've added two sentences to the testimony.
Speaker 0: I know that those two sentences they've added one of those is wrong and I've got evidence that I have to present on top of Those you know and but you got to press them on those first to make sure.
Speaker 1: and yeah now the game will alternatingly make you feel very smart and very Stupid because sometimes you'll be following along and you'll see where this is going a mile away and you'll have your finger Itching.
Speaker 1: you need to throw that evidence that you've got it down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but sometimes you'll hit a point where you're sitting there and the judge is like, what's it gonna be Phoenix?
Speaker 0: and you're like, ah Yeah, the way the game works is they have the right amount of foreshadowing and plot structure and all that and you get to See the evidence and you get to hear all these things.
Speaker 0: people say well before they actually You know, I mean, it's sort of a reading comprehension game in a way and that you read all this stuff during the examination phase and then they question you on it in the court phase.
Speaker 0: and After reading all this stuff if you're reading comprehension is really good.
Speaker 0: You'll know the whole case beginning to end.
Speaker 0: You'll know what's going on.
Speaker 0: The whole story will unfold to you at least most of it.
Speaker 1: You might not get the final turnabout.
Speaker 0: You might not get the final one.
Speaker 0: Yeah But what'll happen is because even though you know the whole thing They will ask you specific things for specific evidences along the way and some of those specific ones.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't freaking know which.
Speaker 0: what the hell does that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like maybe you know that Joey Jojo is the murderer.
Speaker 1: you figure that out right away.
Speaker 1: But then you're back to into a corner where you got to prove that he's the murderer and you know He's the murderer and you're like this piece of evidence.
Speaker 1: the judge is like What about that piece of evidence?
Speaker 1: then it cuts to the evidence now?
Speaker 1: Pick what part of the evidence is actually gonna prove it.
Speaker 1: that really sucks Yeah, but at the same time it's awesome Like that's where the game really shines.
Speaker 1: cuz.
Speaker 1: then the music changes.
Speaker 1: whenever something big is happening You can always tell when you got it, right?
Speaker 1: because if you present the proper thing the music will usually stop and then all their music will smell.
Speaker 0: you usually hear like Today or you'll like.
Speaker 0: the music will change if it's just silent after you Present the evidence or if the music just keeps playing without changing then you've probably got it wrong and the music and the energy There's like this vibe.
Speaker 1: the courtroom starts out pretty tense but slow and every case kind of builds and builds and builds to this climax where The last like five minutes of you playing will be objection objection objection back and forth Yelling and screaming and evidence evidence evidence.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The music will get crazy.
Speaker 0: The witnesses will start getting really crazy.
Speaker 0: It's pretty fun.
Speaker 1: Now also it plays out a little bit like a fighting game in that whenever you get a good dig in against the prosecutor Or witness they show damage like a robot like they'll take a hit or they'll start looking differently the body posture change or they'll like Like you punched him in the face when actually you just showed him a piece of evidence.
Speaker 1: and every single person witness evil prosecutor whatever judge when you Defeat them when you prove them wrong when they have lost they basically have a death animation.
Speaker 1: Not gonna ruin them, but they are all hilarious Super hilarious, I mean one guy's head basically explodes.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So if you have a DS well, if you don't have a DS what's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: The DS is like the number one console.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean, I love the Wii but the DS is still my number one console.
Speaker 0: DS is number one right now and Phoenix Wright is probably it might be the number one game for the DS.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Don't forget Advance Wars DS.
Speaker 0: It's true You know regardless.
Speaker 0: if you had a DS, you don't got Phoenix right.
Speaker 0: something's wrong.
Speaker 1: The Phoenix Wright franchise is easily in the top 10 of DS games right now.
Speaker 0: There's no question about it.
Speaker 0: So Phoenix Wright one and two in the United States.
Speaker 0: You should get both.
Speaker 0: if you speak Japanese go and get all the GBA in the original games because you speak Japanese.
Speaker 0: Why are you buying the American one for?
Speaker 1: Avoid reading spoiler sites because crazy things happen You really don't want to ruin.
Speaker 0: also avoid like just watching like videos like even watching Phoenix wrongs where you'll see characters that you don't know about yet is sort of a spoiler because part of it like the Goodness of this game is like when a new character appears.
Speaker 0: you see because the character designs are all really awesome and hilarious.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa a new character.
Speaker 0: Whoo is a big deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there's one character who appears in the fifth part of the first game and when he appears before he says anything Just the design.
Speaker 1: when you look at him, it's in a shiver up my spine.
Speaker 1: So I I felt something wrong about this person.
Speaker 0: yeah, so It's pretty important not to see much of the game before playing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah granted that means I have to be very careful when I'm around our friends.
Speaker 1: I don't Conrad because they Have a thing for this feat these Phoenix Wright games far beyond what you could ever imagine And they know far more about it than any human being should.
Speaker 0: yeah I've beaten both games because I pretty much blasted through him.
Speaker 0: rim beat the first one and he's only like halfway through the second.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a little over halfway through.
Speaker 0: All right, so don't spoil the end of the second one for him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I swear to God I'll make you at your parents lol.
Speaker 0: Okay, Phoenix Wright's awesome and got anything else to say.
Speaker 1: Uh, no, that's about it.
Speaker 1: I was thinking of starting a contest for Tuesdays, but we already got those contests going for Wednesday and Thursday Which by the way, we've gotten a crazy number of entries for.
Speaker 0: so if you want to win you better Step up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: You can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.