Speaker 0: It's Thursday April 12.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we'll reminisce about one of our favorite toys the super soaker.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Not only did it rain all day, but it's supposed to rain for the next five or six days pretty much continuously here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not good.
Speaker 0: I mean the first work softball game.
Speaker 0: I thought was last.
Speaker 0: Friday's is actually tomorrow and It's probably gonna be rained out Which would kind of suck if I stayed in the city for nothing and then got home late for nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the thing is I'm sure they would know if it's gonna be rained out ahead of time.
Speaker 0: You know disorganized these things can be.
Speaker 1: well if it's that disorganized then half the people Probably won't show up if there's a chance of rain, so don't even chance it.
Speaker 0: well the thing is if they don't show up And we do it wins.
Speaker 0: you got a show that that's the way it works, but who cares?
Speaker 1: it's a little league.
Speaker 1: It's not like the winning or losing matters.
Speaker 1: You only show up because you want to play softball.
Speaker 0: I think it actually does kind of.
Speaker 0: I think there is like a prize.
Speaker 0: It's like a city league thing.
Speaker 1: Why do you think you're gonna win?
Speaker 1: you think you're good enough to win the city league who knows?
Speaker 0: I think the the advantage that our team has though is that we're young people and we'll probably Mostly playing against middle-aged men well might be able to beat them.
Speaker 1: while you are young people I know how fast you can run.
Speaker 0: you don't have to run Very Long hit.
Speaker 1: when is the last time you swung a bat?
Speaker 0: I can I can hit a ball.
Speaker 1: It was the last time you swung a baseball bat at a projectile and a wiffle.
Speaker 0: that doesn't count I don't remember, but I was always good at hitting relatively.
Speaker 1: Do you own a baseball mitt or a softball mitt?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: Where is it my parents house?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh?
Speaker 1: We'll see how well this goes.
Speaker 1: yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: if I were you I wouldn't bother showing up.
Speaker 0: Okay, there's a couple games that are gonna be on Fridays at like five something.
Speaker 0: So I'll probably go to those games for sure unless it rains.
Speaker 0: well Yes, but the next game isn't until like a month from tomorrow, so it's not a problem.
Speaker 1: I think the point is this weather sucks, and I don't like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What's the deal?
Speaker 0: It's supposed to be spring It's supposed to be warming okay granted It's finally not stupidly cold, and it's finally not snowing which is I'm glad for that.
Speaker 1: plus We can't complain.
Speaker 1: no April showers May flowers It's still.
Speaker 0: it's not cold like goddamn.
Speaker 0: I'm cold, but it's still too cold.
Speaker 0: I need a coat.
Speaker 0: It's it's wet.
Speaker 0: I can't just go outside and do what I want.
Speaker 1: actually it's really not that cold.
Speaker 1: I was wearing shorts yesterday and the day before it's not warm enough.
Speaker 0: I can't go driving around everywhere with all my windows in my car open and no shirt on and be comfortable all right.
Speaker 1: But I finally it's nice out and I get to climb the mountain And I got this camera and I take a bunch of pictures.
Speaker 1: and then Immediately now that I'm all set to go hiking every day and all that fun stuff It just rains every day, and you can't exactly go hiking in the rain, especially I'm not well one on the mountains when it rains.
Speaker 1: It's just mud and muck everywhere.
Speaker 1: There's no trail other than the mud and muck trail also.
Speaker 1: It's dangerous.
Speaker 0: so go through the mud and the muck.
Speaker 0: is it gonna hurt you?
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, cuz I'll probably fall off the mountain Suck.
Speaker 1: then I'd like to see you get up there in the rain.
Speaker 0: I die well in my all-terrain vehicle.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's no road that goes up that one, and I'm sure there's a road somewhere.
Speaker 0: I'm not not on that one.
Speaker 0: Maybe on the other side.
Speaker 1: No maybe on another mountain in the ridge I'll just have to make a road.
Speaker 1: I'd like to see you try my chainsaw anyway chainsaw chainsaw on the rocks.
Speaker 0: Oh My dynamite chainsaw makes roads out of rocks.
Speaker 0: I Think we're done here.
Speaker 0: Let's move on to some news and nuts.
Speaker 1: There's no news.
Speaker 1: my thing of the day is crack because I couldn't find anything better.
Speaker 1: My news is lame because the only news was that Kurt Vonnegut died.
Speaker 1: and all I have to say about that is I really like Kurt Vonnegut.
Speaker 0: I Really like Kurt Vonnegut, and I'm sad.
Speaker 0: He's dead.
Speaker 0: usually when people like famous people die I go Oh that famous person died, and it's kind of rare when it's actually someone where I go.
Speaker 1: oh great Yeah, I mean I felt the same way when Hunter S. Thompson died.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I read less Hunter S. Thompson that I read Kurt Vonnegut so I cared less, but I still cared.
Speaker 1: Yep, though was interesting.
Speaker 1: at work I was futzing with something and I ended up moving someone's printer And I noticed they had printed out an article about Kurt Vonnegut.
Speaker 0: really that's how you found out.
Speaker 0: You know how I found out?
Speaker 0: I was I was standing waiting for the sixth train to go to work and Someone standing next to me had the newspaper open and that article was right there.
Speaker 1: Actually, I really found out on FARC, and then I just noted that someone else also cared about Kurt Vonnegut at my work.
Speaker 1: Granted it was at the one place where all the cool people seem to be you know all the metal people and the Scottish stuff And the people who know about computers at least a little.
Speaker 0: yep Oh, so didn't I did I say on the show about the guy in the subway who was reading samurai executioner?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: you told me.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's there's been a trend recently if I see people reading comics on the subway I think the subways and comics go hand in hand.
Speaker 0: and then yesterday I saw a guy on the subway, and he was reading samurai executioner.
Speaker 0: I didn't know which volume so I just went over to him.
Speaker 0: I was like hey Kazuo Koike and he was like yeah, and that was that.
Speaker 1: see what you should have done is you say that That's like the first test like do you know who wrote the thing?
Speaker 1: you're eating mm-hmm, and if he says yes, then you say Go to guy.
Speaker 1: They said because then you've started the conversation because now that person's either gonna think wow this guy knows going guy Or he's gonna think I better figure out what that thing he just said is because it must be somehow related.
Speaker 0: I should have said Ryuichi Ikigami.
Speaker 0: Then today I saw some lady and it looked like her son or maybe grandson.
Speaker 0: I couldn't really tell.
Speaker 0: what do I know?
Speaker 0: they're strangers And they had it's not a good comic, but they had a Superman showcase Which is basically a big fat black-and-white book of a bunch of old Superman comics And she was reading them to her kid, which is pretty cool, so yeah
Speaker 1: Actually, this was like three days ago But I was walking around in the Bronx and I ended up standing by a traffic thing and there was a kid walking with his Mom.
Speaker 1: he had a DS, and I heard some Phoenix Wright music.
Speaker 1: So I and I look and I look at the kid and I can kind of see his screen.
Speaker 1: He's obviously near the end of the first Phoenix Wright game.
Speaker 1: So I say if something smells it's usually the butts and the kid is like Hahaha, and the mother looks at me with this look of what did you just say to my child?
Speaker 1: And she just stares at me because I'm this 20-something guy who just said something about a butt to her kid.
Speaker 1: It was like 11.
Speaker 0: What did the kid say?
Speaker 1: the kid didn't say anything?
Speaker 1: He kind of laughed.
Speaker 1: at the same time he seemed a little weirded out that someone talked to him.
Speaker 1: It wasn't his mom on the street.
Speaker 0: Hey it happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though Yeah, I think this should be a trend whenever you see someone who is engaged in some form of media.
Speaker 1: That is fairly rare Compared to normal people.
Speaker 1: that is something that you like.
Speaker 1: it's kind of a way to pick out the cool person in the crowd.
Speaker 0: I think we just need a jet.
Speaker 0: like if you're at a can anime convention or any sort of geek convention Everyone's doing something geeky, but when you see something doing something geeky that you like you always say hey I like that thing.
Speaker 0: you got there.
Speaker 1: Hey, I see you like mudkips.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard you like mudkips.
Speaker 0: So we got it sort of bring that out into the real world.
Speaker 0: where in the real world?
Speaker 0: Well the non convention part of the world because conventions are still the real world.
Speaker 0: Yeah No, this fantasy world exactly when you see someone doing anything geeky at all and a non geek environment You have to say hey, that's the rule.
Speaker 0: you have to say something or else It sort of makes the world feel like there are the correct number of geeks about.
Speaker 0: you know how many stealth geeks there are.
Speaker 0: We got to unselfify them.
Speaker 0: Yeah pirates must win over the ninjas.
Speaker 0: you have to be all flamboyant and wear your geekery on your sleeve.
Speaker 1: I mean that's part of the reason you have all that social currency business with Nintendo and everything I carry on my person at all times various artifacts of my interests just in the hopes.
Speaker 0: That's why you gotta put stickers in the top of your laptop And you got to put buttons on your bag, you know, we're a nerdy t-shirt.
Speaker 1: in all the jobs I have ever had Never once has any co-worker ever seen any of the things I carry around and in any way Recognized what they might possibly have been.
Speaker 1: Yep at most at best they'd ask me like so what the hell are those plastic things?
Speaker 1: All over your desk?
Speaker 1: or what's that stupid blue circle on your keychain?
Speaker 1: They Know what Mario is some of them, but that's about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of my one of the four partners who runs my business has a lot of Mario action in his office.
Speaker 0: So fear.
Speaker 1: Oh, you should have seen my office in IBM.
Speaker 1: I had PVCs and wall scrolls and posters covering pretty much everything on my side of it and nothing No one.
Speaker 1: every now and then one guy be like, I think my kid likes that stuff that you got on your wall.
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 0: So I have the Mario diorama in my office the one raised infinite lives in world whatever.
Speaker 0: but When I'm gonna eventually move to a different desk and when I do that, I'll probably bring some more pimpage, but not much.
Speaker 0: I like to keep it light and tasteful.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about getting a retro robot.
Speaker 1: So in the news that isn't depressing, you know, not people we like to died.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about this mostly because I have a little thing to say about.
Speaker 1: I think I mentioned this before but Chicago is Talking about banning cocaine the energy drink not cocaine the drug that is already banned.
Speaker 1: Yes, now on one hand.
Speaker 1: I think the rationale for it isn't that it's dangerous, but that it promotes drug use Which is probably the stupidest thing ever.
Speaker 0: that is pretty goddamn stupid.
Speaker 0: That's like saying they're going to the cookware store prevents promote smoking weed.
Speaker 1: What.
Speaker 0: that's like saying that going to stoners pot palace promotes marijuana.
Speaker 1: So you're making a joke about Oh if people go and buy a pot, but then you didn't say pot.
Speaker 1: you went one step more Ambiguous to the point that you just you didn't make a joke.
Speaker 1: You just kind of joke.
Speaker 0: It was barely a joke anyway.
Speaker 0: Yes, if there are two things that are Advertising there are two things that are called pot buying.
Speaker 0: one does not suddenly make you want to buy the other.
Speaker 0: if there are two Things called cocaine buying one isn't gonna make you buy the other unless you're a kettle.
Speaker 0: Yes, you are.
Speaker 1: I think my joke is much better than your joke.
Speaker 1: I could go one step further about.
Speaker 1: I miss calling the kettle black pot something I could go on a roll with this.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna.
Speaker 1: I think it was a great idea.
Speaker 0: You know, you didn't even know I'm as was until yesterday.
Speaker 0: So what do you who can't really make jokes about him?
Speaker 1: Why can't I?
Speaker 1: he suddenly appeared in the media because he was mentioned on FARC for saying something silly.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, now while I'd say that these reasons for banning cocaine are stupid I will point out that the energy drink cocaine.
Speaker 1: I've tried it.
Speaker 1: it tastes like an asshole.
Speaker 1: It's the worst thing I have ever put in my mouth.
Speaker 1: I'm dead serious.
Speaker 1: I've never tasted anything worse than this ever.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't and I ate a rotten apple.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I don't drink energy drinks, but I've smelled Red Bull and Red Bull smells like cough syrup.
Speaker 1: Red Bull tastes like wonderful.
Speaker 0: Anyway rim seems to like that.
Speaker 0: So if he doesn't like cocaine and I don't like the smell of Red Bull I can only imagine Cocaine was pretty bad.
Speaker 1: the smell of cocaine.
Speaker 1: if you just open it and take a sniff of it It smells like vomit.
Speaker 1: I smell it.
Speaker 1: I just feel like I'm gonna vomit.
Speaker 1: I just it makes me nauseous.
Speaker 0: That's not good.
Speaker 1: I drank a sip of it and I sat there going god.
Speaker 1: Ah.
Speaker 1: And then for some reason I took another sip like.
Speaker 1: maybe the first sip didn't work.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's gonna taste different this time.
Speaker 1: It tasted exactly the same.
Speaker 1: I think I talked about this before.
Speaker 0: Take a third sip.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: No, I let it sit there in my two times For like five minutes cuz I didn't want to throw it away cuz it cost me like 325.
Speaker 1: Oh you bought it.
Speaker 0: I thought you got it for free.
Speaker 1: No, I bought it.
Speaker 0: Uh, uh Bad move.
Speaker 1: Well, I needed a Red Bull cuz I was really tired.
Speaker 1: and then hey, there's that cocaine drink.
Speaker 1: I've never seen it outside of the city and I'm really tired.
Speaker 1: and it's not much more than Red Bull which is horribly Marked up at the drugstore.
Speaker 1: I happen to be at.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Red Bull is a lot of money big mistake.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if Chicago bands cocaine, I'm really not at all Mad about that even though they're banning it for the wrong reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really don't like banning things.
Speaker 0: I want to have as much freedom as possible.
Speaker 0: So or as much freedom is as reasonable.
Speaker 0: So banning something that there's no reason to ban is not so it's not something I'm in favor of.
Speaker 0: but you considering the cocaine Tastes bad is probably bad for you and isn't always bad.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get worked up.
Speaker 1: Oh, well cocaine is designed to actually simulate cocaine.
Speaker 1: So it has some sort of chemical in it that numbs your throats.
Speaker 0: Yes, it can't be good.
Speaker 1: It also has like 280 or 300 milligrams of caffeine in it which is way too much caffeine.
Speaker 1: and That's coming from a guy who likes caffeine a lot.
Speaker 0: There's a guy at work who drinks a pot of coffee before he comes to work.
Speaker 0: a pot a pot.
Speaker 0: They were asking him.
Speaker 0: he was drinking coffee at like three and they were like, hey how much coffee did you drink today?
Speaker 0: He's like, this is cup number something actually how much you drink?
Speaker 0: before you came to work and he was like pot.
Speaker 1: He was.
Speaker 1: there was a guy back at IBM who drank gallons of coffee every day.
Speaker 1: He just carried around this gigantic thermos that he's had for like 20 years everywhere Golly refilling it.
Speaker 1: but here's the thing.
Speaker 0: It was the cup on his belly.
Speaker 1: It was decaf.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 1: So, I don't know why he was drinking it because it's not like decaf taste good in the first place And you're not getting the primary benefit, which is caffeine.
Speaker 1: You're basically drinking bad tasting water.
Speaker 0: That's fucked up right there.
Speaker 1: That's like drinking sugar-free Red Bull.
Speaker 1: What's the point?
Speaker 0: My boss drinks free sugary and free Red Bull.
Speaker 1: He comes into work every day carrying Why half the rush of Red Bull is that you just drank a whole bunch of glucose?
Speaker 0: I don't know man, but that's what he drinks All right.
Speaker 0: So, you know that awesome TV show on the BBC called top gear that we have to watch on YouTube and Google video?
Speaker 1: Yes, which actually I prefer watching it on Google video because it's not like I'd see it on TV Plus when you watch it on Google video, you don't have to watch the whole episode.
Speaker 0: You can just watch one segment that you want to see and the other segments You don't have to see is not?
Speaker 0: every segment is exciting and entertaining.
Speaker 0: Some of them are kind of okay.
Speaker 1: I really only want to watch them do stupid things to cars and I want to watch the Stig race.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it seems like they might be in a deal to bring this show to the US without and judging by reading of this Article they're not gonna modify it too much too much.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, they're gonna.
Speaker 1: well they get.
Speaker 1: they gotta localize it.
Speaker 0: I mean they are.
Speaker 1: those people in England speak this weird-ass language.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the old they're basically gonna keep the show format the same.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they'll keep the same host.
Speaker 0: They might do that.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: they're still gonna have people racing against the Stig and Just like in Britain where they have British famous people race You know the normal cars around the track to try to beat each other.
Speaker 0: They're gonna have American Famous people race cars around the track, huh?
Speaker 1: You know if it doesn't have the same hosts, I really won't care about it at all me either.
Speaker 1: But it might because I mean I'm interested in the cars.
Speaker 1: But the hosts of that show are the only reason I actually watch because they're really funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like hey And they're not.
Speaker 0: the thing that makes that show so great is that you have these really funny really entertaining guys.
Speaker 0: but they're guys who actually know and care about cars as opposed to Famous people who were you know professional hosts just happened to hosting a show about cars.
Speaker 0: They're actual car guys Which is why the show works which is the same reason why blogs beat the newspaper because the newspaper people who are journalists They don't actually usually know about the thing they're writing about.
Speaker 1: I think it also helps that they have albionic accents which in America as we've talked about before tends to give the perception of Increased intelligence and among a lot of people things just seem funnier when they have that sort of accent probably because a lot of us Grew up on Monty Python.
Speaker 0: It might be it might not be who knows.
Speaker 1: I think that's definitely part of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if the show comes to America I hope it's still good because that'll just mean more top gear for everybody and maybe they'll just show the British show in America.
Speaker 1: That's what I really want.
Speaker 0: That would be fine because then more people in this side of the water would know You know what?
Speaker 1: No, I don't want that because if they do that Then they're more likely to start taking the episodes off at YouTube And then I'm less likely to actually see them because a TV show?
Speaker 0: I don't think I do.
Speaker 0: they gotta put a DVD box set to this thing so we can Netflix it.
Speaker 0: That's right Netflix top gear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you only need to see an episode once.
Speaker 0: if they do that.
Speaker 0: That would be hot.
Speaker 0: Hey British people.
Speaker 0: Do you have top gear DVDs?
Speaker 1: If so, send them to Actually if any of our Albionic listeners out there.
Speaker 1: I just like saying Albion and Albionic.
Speaker 1: It's not really a word.
Speaker 0: I don't think I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just gonna edit.
Speaker 0: the only word is Albion.
Speaker 1: Well Albion is the noun.
Speaker 1: so by the rules of grammar and conjugation and such I can add.
Speaker 0: But we're talking about words from the other side of the ocean where those rules don't apply.
Speaker 1: So I'll be honest albinish albinites.
Speaker 1: Anyway, if you know from that island There Could in some way copy and then send to us DVDs of top gear.
Speaker 1: if you in fact have DVDs of top gear We will shower vast riches upon you though.
Speaker 1: Such vast riches may or may not exist.
Speaker 0: I'll check amazon.co.uk.
Speaker 0: you do that top gear box set 25 pounds 25 pounds.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: for how many DVDs?
Speaker 1: Hold on That's less than an episode of freedom cup noodle.
Speaker 0: It contains back in the fast lane revved up and winter Olympics, huh?
Speaker 1: It's still a better deal than freedom cup noodle, but not by much Things of the day.
Speaker 0: Hey rim.
Speaker 0: Do you have your own blog?
Speaker 1: Actually, I was gonna ask you to put one on the up on our server.
Speaker 0: I will as soon as I as soon as I switch it over to the Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: But if you had your own blog, would you read it?
Speaker 1: probably otherwise, why am I doing it exactly now?
Speaker 0: This is a website.
Speaker 0: I'm linking to is my thing of the day is a pretty shady site.
Speaker 0: It's one of those SEO sites that where they tell you how to you know, get more people to come while that BS right but it actually does have on this site a semi serious blog on the topic and this guy his name is Ahmed Bilal and He wrote a very short thing and the short thing that he wrote is really good And that's the only reason I'm linking to it.
Speaker 0: He says would you read your own blog if you wrote a blog?
Speaker 0: Would you read it?
Speaker 0: Would you subscribe to it and read it?
Speaker 0: If not, then why are you doing it?
Speaker 0: What's what the hell's the point if you don't want to read it?
Speaker 0: No one else freaking wants to read it either.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean granted you have to take it with a little bit of grand assault that you might not want to read something that you Just wrote.
Speaker 1: that sort of yes.
Speaker 0: This is why also in the short bit He gives you a test and he says a simple way to test whether your blog provides value to the community is to put Yourself in the shoes of your readers and ask yourself the following questions ready.
Speaker 0: one is the blog unique?
Speaker 0: Does it provide any information that I cannot find anywhere else?
Speaker 1: How many blogs?
Speaker 1: Literally don't do anything except post everything that engadget posts and then add like one comment or they.
Speaker 0: you know Someone reads dig.
Speaker 0: they find the comments the the links on dig every day that they enjoy and then they write a little thing About them that there should have been a comment on dig but instead a separate blog.
Speaker 1: now Why would you go to that when you can just go to day and read the comments?
Speaker 0: To is the blog original?
Speaker 0: does it offer personal opinion instead of regurgitating or echoing views that other people share?
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of people when they write their opinion of something or just sort of like, you know They're sort of joining the crew on one side or the other.
Speaker 0: so it was like a ps3 or we thing.
Speaker 0: They'll just be.
Speaker 0: they'll write a blog post.
Speaker 0: That's like we is awesome or we sucks.
Speaker 0: They won't be saying anything new about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a point that had.
Speaker 0: all you do is make a few points that aren't in the debate already or be funny.
Speaker 1: There's always the option of being funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah funny.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're writing about mudkips, maybe you like him Maybe you don't like him, but you got to say something about him.
Speaker 1: Maybe make a joke about a mudkip maybe have an insightful like.
Speaker 1: well mudkips are actually useful for blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Yes, you have to say something that no one else is saying regardless of whether.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, the third thing he says is the blog essential?
Speaker 0: if I unsubscribe from this blog today What would I lose out on?
Speaker 0: Yeah, see I look.
Speaker 0: that's how I look at my RSS subscriptions is you know I whenever I I go down the list of things I'm subscribed to and I say if I unsubscribe from this What would I be losing?
Speaker 0: and most of the time when I act when I actually bother to ask myself that question Like a bunch of things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I went through that with podcasts like three or four times where I'd look at a podcast that I'd been listening to and I Think did I actually enjoy listening to that and all the time?
Speaker 1: No, I didn't.
Speaker 0: and why?
Speaker 0: yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: it's so weird that this whole subscription thing You have all the.
Speaker 0: you subscribe to all these things and you listen to them or read them or maybe you don't but you subscribe To them and if you just look at them, you know casually you're just used to seeing them there and your subscription list.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like pen radio did that I got kind of sick of pen radio for a good two months fan But the episodes kept coming.
Speaker 0: Yeah But if you actually carefully consider the things you subscribe to you'll find that a lot of things will be off your list mighty quick.
Speaker 1: Yep, a lot of thing on geek nights.
Speaker 1: A lot of things are very redundant.
Speaker 1: I mean if I read dig and Fark I don't need to ever go to slash dot because everything on slash dot will be on one of those two.
Speaker 0: Yep, so this is just a word to everyone out there who blogs or podcasts or anything of the sort.
Speaker 0: Think about whether you would read Your blogger listen to your own podcast if you weren't the one making.
Speaker 0: if someone else was making the exact same thing You're making would you subscribe and listen to it?
Speaker 0: If the answer is no, you should probably change what you're doing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I am thinking about having a blog just lately.
Speaker 1: I never really had one.
Speaker 1: I had the slash job thing I think I posted in it twice Uh-huh, and I think one of the things I posted I also published in the awesome newspaper at our IT.
Speaker 0: Oh So awesome.
Speaker 1: Remember that thing?
Speaker 1: I actually got hate mail for that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That was cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I generally yeah I'm not gonna get into that.
Speaker 1: That's a story for another day a whole episode on that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, we should.
Speaker 0: What's your thing?
Speaker 1: But I've just been feeling this desire to blog lately.
Speaker 1: I have things to say that really don't fit into geek nights or maybe I don't want to say them out loud.
Speaker 1: I'd rather write them and now that I got a flicker and Now that my delicious and my dig streams.
Speaker 1: I could combine them all into one and have just the rim feed Sounds good.
Speaker 1: Yep anyway my thing of the day is very much germane to the topic mostly because I couldn't think of a thing of the day and Everything I looked at on the internet today was totally lame.
Speaker 1: So this is the video that inspired us to do tonight's episode.
Speaker 1: It is a video with Lonnie Johnson the man who created the super soaker the man who in?
Speaker 1: 1989 57 or 58 revolutionized the world of water sports.
Speaker 1: and by water sports, I mean Squirt guns not swimming and diving.
Speaker 1: see many of you might be too young to remember this But there was a time when squirt guns sucks.
Speaker 0: It's like most of my life.
Speaker 0: No, not most of my life, but a significant portion of my life pretty much every year until I was fifth grade.
Speaker 0: It's
Speaker 1: kind of like the cavemen who didn't have any tools yet the monkeys and they're just rolling around doing their monkey thing and then You know when they have a monkey war They just kind of claw and bite at each other and one day one of the monkeys picks up a stick and he hits another monkey with the stick and that stick is so Superior to any weapon the monkey had ever had before that he is now effectively a new being in warfare.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, let's talk about this video and then get into it.
Speaker 0: in the video It shows the guy who invented the super soaker and it tells you how he invented it.
Speaker 0: He was like working at the NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory or something like that.
Speaker 0: He was some sort of genius And he ended up accidentally Discussed, you know, he was playing with water or something and it scored it out and he said hey What if I use that principle to make a water gun?
Speaker 1: You know what proof that the space program is infinitely valuable to human culture.
Speaker 0: Yes So he invented the super soaker and with all the money He made from inventing the super soaker and selling the patent to Laramie the company that made the super soaker physically He bought himself a lab and he never has to work again except for fun in his own personal lab.
Speaker 1: now see this guy exemplifies Everything that people should aspire to.
Speaker 1: not only did he do something that well not only a he was a genius.
Speaker 1: Well, he did something that impacted the world in a tangible way for a lot of people.
Speaker 1: I mean he didn't end hunger or cure AIDS But he created something that did not exist at all and he revolutionized a small But I'd say important to my childhood industry.
Speaker 0: It was it was actually an invention and worthy of patents do?
Speaker 1: he made a bunch of money off of it And instead of just pissing the money way or doing whatever he put that money toward his worthwhile pursuits.
Speaker 1: He put the money into having a lab.
Speaker 1: just like if I had a million dollars, I'd make a real recording studio And I would make a computer lab and a video game lab and many other labs I just like.
Speaker 0: where my lab coat and not much else.
Speaker 0: Okay I'll just let you it was a Lewis black joke.
Speaker 0: Remember he was like I did the experiment in my laboratory Oh the lab coat at the time.
Speaker 1: I do recall that.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I do recall that Lewis black joke.
Speaker 0: anybody listen so black.
Speaker 1: There was a time when squirt gun fights Consisted.
Speaker 1: there were basically three different levels of squirt gun and that was it.
Speaker 1: first There was the 50 cent or dime squirt gun.
Speaker 0: This is pretty much the only squirt gun I had until the super soaker existed.
Speaker 1: It was a little clear plastic thing.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: they were like bright green transparent or pink.
Speaker 0: yellow is shaped like a gun.
Speaker 0: It looked like a real gun in shape But it was some clear pat plastic and you popped open a little hole in the back
Speaker 1: with this piss poor little white Plug that had a little T on the end of it that kept it from falling out even though it always fell and
Speaker 0: you would Turn the kitchen sink faucet on real low so that it would drip into there to fill it at the maximum rate and
Speaker 1: you'd stand There or you
Speaker 0: use a funnel.
Speaker 0: you'd stand there for like 10 minutes trying to fill the stupid thing And when you finally filled it and plugged it up you would squirt it and it worked at the same mechanism as like a spray Bottle of glass plus.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: The thing is you had to pump it or squirt it a bunch of times before it even works at All.
Speaker 0: yeah, we had to squirt on the air out before it would squirt water.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the same way you have to pump like a liquid soap before the soap actually comes out.
Speaker 1: these things shot I don't know maybe 11 feet and they shoot very far at all.
Speaker 0: They shot this piddling amount of water.
Speaker 1: It was so little water that if you got shot with it, you didn't even notice squirt.
Speaker 0: You didn't even notice or care.
Speaker 1: I mean squirt gun fights.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid with these before the super soaker came around Effectively always ended in either some kid bringing a hose God I swear to God this kid David we were having a little squirt gun fight and Dave well, basically we realized that with these little squirt guns The only real tactic was to shoot other kids in the eye.
Speaker 0: The eye I was about to say the ear is good too.
Speaker 0: If you get real close here is good.
Speaker 1: The eye was pretty much.
Speaker 0: eyes is the weak spot.
Speaker 0: That's what gets the boss down.
Speaker 1: Yep So this kid we're having a little squirt gun fight and can't shot in the eye like eight times.
Speaker 1: So he just ran away.
Speaker 1: We're like, ah, it's so much for him and we're fighting.
Speaker 1: we're fighting and for fighting and we see him run around the corner.
Speaker 1: He's it wasn't that far away like 20 minutes later and he's got something.
Speaker 1: and then we see we realized at the last Second when we're all it's already too late that he is connected like for extension hoses to his house And that kid owned us.
Speaker 0: Why didn't he just use it at the house you were at?
Speaker 1: Because we would have noticed and stopped him.
Speaker 1: there's rules about that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: if someone went for the hose That's a stabbing.
Speaker 0: See you even in the super soaker days You would go for the hose.
Speaker 0: The hose is the ultimate weapon in water fights and you always go for the hose no matter what it always gets down to the hose.
Speaker 0: Eventually, you might as well go for it right away But without the hose.
Speaker 0: the bet even better than a super soaker was the water balloon, which has always existed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except for having to clean up after the water balloon.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is they always had those ones that were shaped like grenades and look like grenade.
Speaker 1: Those are the worst.
Speaker 0: worst ones that they're meant to be water balloons, but they're the worst at being water balloons.
Speaker 1: For some reason they always broke when I tried to fill them, but when I throw them at people they just bounced off.
Speaker 0: Yeah my favorite thing actually to do is to get the long ones the ones the clowns use and then you throw them.
Speaker 1: they kind of Spin in the air and wrap around someone's face.
Speaker 0: Well, no that I put one like down my pant leg.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it'd be summer.
Speaker 0: I have a short leg.
Speaker 0: Sneak up on someone and you rip it out and you smack them with it While I did often smack people with them.
Speaker 1: But I usually have it like stuck to myself somewhere like tied on a little piece of floss or string.
Speaker 1: you see that would break off and Depends or I just I carry one like a sword and then I have my little bag full of the normal one.
Speaker 0: if you carried It like a sword it would bend over because it was too heavy and then it would just break wouldn't break.
Speaker 1: You gotta get quality water balloon.
Speaker 0: I guess if your balloon is quality enough Then it won't break.
Speaker 1: see the problem was when they were too quality They'd either not break when you threw him at someone or you'd have to fill him to the such a breaking point.
Speaker 1: It was such an amount of water that they'd either hurt someone or just break on you.
Speaker 0: hurting someone is great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how many times have I held a water balloon in my hand?
Speaker 0: They would just break it.
Speaker 0: That's the worst.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 1: It's like those weapons in video games that damage someone else a lot But they have a chance of damaging you just as much.
Speaker 0: I don't have a link but there's a video that was on the internet Recently somewhere that showed a guy getting hit directly in the face of the water balloon in like super slow mo.
Speaker 1: It was all right.
Speaker 1: So so these guns obviously sucked and basically it was like the ancient Greeks having war.
Speaker 1: it wasn't advance.
Speaker 1: The war was kind of this honor bound.
Speaker 1: the kids all line up and you basically would run up to another kid put the squirt Gun in their eye and pulled the trigger as much as possible And then they would cover their eye run away come back and do the same thing.
Speaker 0: your finger
Speaker 1: would start hurting because the
Speaker 0: only thing We're not ergonomic at all No
Speaker 1: They weren't
Speaker 0: and you had to keep pulling the trigger to squirt like you'd pull the trigger once and go squirt any good thing Let go and pull it again
Speaker 1: And you pull it harder and squirt it harder and they broke and on the beach they get sand in him and stop working.
Speaker 0: I mean literally you would buy a big sack of these things from the dollar store because they were maybe Half of them in.
Speaker 1: the sack would work at all Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then during the fight you'd have to have like four in your pocket because otherwise they'd break and you would but the one in Your pocket would inevitably leak down your pants.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so god they'd leak her on your hand while you were shooting.
Speaker 0: So sometime around fourth or fifth grade, which must have been I don't know what year I'm not even gonna bother to figure it out sometime in the 90s.
Speaker 0: Maybe the late 80s.
Speaker 0: I saw it in the circular.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're not gonna talk about the other better squirt guns that like the evolution.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, okay briefly We won't go into detail.
Speaker 0: Like there were squirt guns that were battery powered and these are a kind of crazy and cool.
Speaker 0: kids had them But they actually sucked worse than the sucky ones.
Speaker 1: They were always shaped like an Uzi.
Speaker 0: They were shaped like an Uzi and they were bright orange Usually and you'd fill them with water and you put two batteries in the in where the bullets would go on an Uzi.
Speaker 1: in the Actually mine you had Magazines with holes in and that you filled with water.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's plan.
Speaker 0: That's real bad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it was all bad.
Speaker 1: Awesome Yeah
Speaker 0: And you would pull the trigger on it and we go tick tick tick tick tick tick tick tick tick and it would basically shoot wussier shittier squirts than the handheld Finger-powered one, but it would shoot a lot of them and you could just hold the trigger down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course battery would run out real quick.
Speaker 1: The battery lasted like two minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was such an inefficient electric motor in there with the shittiest pump.
Speaker 1: These things were expensive.
Speaker 1: I mean think about it.
Speaker 1: These things were like 10 or 15 dollars and a normal squirt gun was like 10 cents.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is these things mostly broke pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: after two water fights you threw it out.
Speaker 1: The first one I got broke in the car on the way home.
Speaker 1: Oh man, I cried And we took it back to the store like right away.
Speaker 1: cuz I was in Consolable.
Speaker 1: I got another one and I was so careful with it and I brought it to his work on fight.
Speaker 1: and I'm shooting some kid.
Speaker 0: It broke.
Speaker 1: it didn't break right away.
Speaker 1: I shot him like four times and then He hit it with his squirt gun and it broke and the end broke off and all the water went.
Speaker 0: push See what I always wondered is why doesn't someone make a squirt gun, right?
Speaker 0: where there's a tank of water about some sort of battery a trigger and One of those the thing that's kind of water squirting motor that they use to spray windshield wiper on your windshield Cuz that's pretty much a constant stream of water.
Speaker 0: That's pretty powerful.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just have the equivalent of a super soaker with the equivalent of an air compressor?
Speaker 0: that would work, too.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, so then the only other kind of squirt gun.
Speaker 0: Oh the one we go.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep, Scott just demonstrated it, but the only other weapon these are the one shot.
Speaker 1: These are ancient Greeks and this was like the spear.
Speaker 0: that the one shot actually is still a great squirt gun.
Speaker 0: And if you can find them, I don't think they make them.
Speaker 1: I'm saying I see him.
Speaker 1: It's basically a bazooka where it's long tube and you stick it in water the nozzle and you pull it and now you have got a tube of water a large cylinder of water.
Speaker 1: and the thing is they're always ever like there'd be one or two kids never squirt gun fight who would have?
Speaker 1: you know, all the little squirt guns and they give thick thick thick thick thick thick at each other and Then there's always be the couple kids that also on their back had one full bazooka.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see now the bazooka.
Speaker 0: I sort of equate it to sledding with a dish as opposed to sledding with a sled.
Speaker 0: It's like the bazooka is this weird water gun?
Speaker 0: It's not like the other water guns But actually it can do a lot more than it looks like it can do just like the sledding dish can go real fast Even though it's different from everyone else with their normal sleds.
Speaker 1: whenever the kid dropped his sidearm and pulled that thing out Everyone would pause and back up because you knew he only had one shot But you didn't want to be the one shot with it cuz that thing got you wet.
Speaker 1: It was the only squirt gun that got you.
Speaker 1: Yes
Speaker 0: Cuz the thing about it is even when super soakers came out the bazooka was still a useful weapon because you would basically Pull the two ends of it together and he would fire the entire Cylinder of water like almost a gallon of water at once at one person real
Speaker 1: fast.
Speaker 0: It was a wasn't like you could do about.
Speaker 1: it was awesome.
Speaker 0: It's still awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was definitely a valid part of any.
Speaker 1: you know what.
Speaker 1: it's one of those weapons that stood the test of time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so one day, you know when you're a kid you look at the toy circular.
Speaker 0: The newspaper comes on the weekend and there's a little advertisement that says hey Here's all the toys.
Speaker 0: that toys are us or toy works or kb or wherever your toy store is and you look through that for new Toys you go.
Speaker 0: Ooh, I want that action figure.
Speaker 0: Ooh, look at those new video games.
Speaker 0: It's actually how I found out about new video games before Video game magazines that I was looking at toy circular and look at the pictures of the video games.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I saw a water gun in there, but it was all weird-looking.
Speaker 0: It was first of all is yellow and green and I was like what and had this weird Bulb on it.
Speaker 1: It looked like an alien weapon.
Speaker 0: It did look like an alien ray gun and I said I looked at the picture and I said that's corny as hell.
Speaker 0: who that Would want that thing?
Speaker 0: and I didn't want it.
Speaker 1: It was also expensive.
Speaker 1: I mean every kid knew that those Uzi's were crap because every kid had one and then it broke.
Speaker 1: so it was still you know $1 work it.
Speaker 1: maybe you get the $2 nicer one.
Speaker 1: I was made out of slightly thicker plastic.
Speaker 1: what kid was gonna convince their parents to drop 25 bucks on a squirt gun?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like good $25.
Speaker 0: my mom's not gonna buy me that.
Speaker 0: what the hell.
Speaker 0: there's no way.
Speaker 0: So, of course eventually a kid on the street got a Super Soaker 50.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they started with calling it the 50 as if there was a Super Soaker before the 50.
Speaker 1: so they Because then they made the 25.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's right that I remember why they called it 50. because it could supposedly shoot 50 feet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the hundred gets you a hundred feet and supposedly could shoot about 80 feet.
Speaker 0: It could shoot pretty damn far.
Speaker 0: I mean you really had to get that thing going.
Speaker 0: to get it shoot the number of feet It was advertised at shooting but it could shoot hella far.
Speaker 1: to give you an idea What the first squirt gun fight where a kid came with the Super Soaker was like when Shaka Zulu?
Speaker 1: Broke the rules of warfare ran over to the other side and killed all those dudes.
Speaker 0: It was like the in being Invention of the Maxim machine gun.
Speaker 1: It's like in the myth in the middle of a Roman battle between the Romans and the Persians One guy walked over with a sawed-off shot gun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see I remembered the first battle in which he kid down the street had the service ochre 50 and we did not.
Speaker 0: we ended up running to the house a lot getting lots of water balloons coming out and running back into the house because Basically, he couldn't be stopped.
Speaker 0: He wasn't by far the best water fight kind of her.
Speaker 1: He didn't have that get it in your eyes skill.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't need it anymore.
Speaker 0: He had an automatic weapon by sheer possession of weaponry alone.
Speaker 0: Nobody even like five kids were no match for the one kid with the Super Soaker 50.
Speaker 1: I mean we'd all thought all right.
Speaker 1: He's gonna run out of water.
Speaker 1: Look how much water he's shooting.
Speaker 0: Good God, if we had a whole tank of water We had a tiny gun of.
Speaker 1: if we all just surround him He can't get us all and he would just get us all anyway.
Speaker 1: Cuz it shot so much water and it never seemed to stop shooting.
Speaker 0: and if he needed to stop He would be go to the hose to get water.
Speaker 1: and where you would never approach someone at the hose See what we always did is we always took the shooting thing off the hose.
Speaker 0: So it was just uh, yeah, so you put your thumb on it cuz you're not an idiot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thumb method wasn't that effective.
Speaker 0: and you suck at the thumb method.
Speaker 1: No Why it's not that effective cuz it's real easy to run over and just grab the kids hand and now he's soaking wet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: Some kids would bring those special like nine different nozzle attachments.
Speaker 0: Those ones are no good.
Speaker 0: The only the only ones that are good at this that straight ones because they have the best Single jet of high-power mode that the multi mode ones don't have.
Speaker 1: or sometimes we just get rid of the hose.
Speaker 1: It was just all the faucets on the house.
Speaker 1: Ooh Cuz then if you were really desperate you put your thumb on that thing.
Speaker 0: Well, actually remember there were a lot of different systems that they eventually invented.
Speaker 0: We'd put a thing a special thing at the end of the hose and you would stick the front of your water gun into it.
Speaker 0: It would fill your water gun.
Speaker 0: Those came a lot later.
Speaker 0: I never tried them So I don't know how reliable they are, but supposedly I guess they still sell them.
Speaker 1: I got to say though This is a side.
Speaker 1: We're not talking about water balloons.
Speaker 1: That's beyond the scope Yeah, but nothing was worse than trying to fill water balloons with a full-on hose.
Speaker 0: It was just like You had to fill it at a sink in the house and then put him in like a trash bag and carry him outside.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus the enemy of the hose was always the kink in the hose.
Speaker 1: But the super soaker kid was unstoppable.
Speaker 0: He was a centurion in full armor and I had sticks.
Speaker 0: So as in every other arms race in the history of man Everyone else as soon as one kid and your block had a super soaker Everyone had to get one or be eternally wet.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the thing is all right now everyone had one and the playing field was equalized.
Speaker 1: but now Super soaker changed the nature of squirt gun warfare because now we were all equal again.
Speaker 1: But water fights had this completely different dimension.
Speaker 0: You'd be far away from people.
Speaker 0: Everyone would get soaking wet.
Speaker 0: Everyone would take a break at the same time to refill their water.
Speaker 0: It was you would be far.
Speaker 0: you run around a lot more.
Speaker 0: you wouldn't have to get right up in people's faces.
Speaker 0: People would stop to pump.
Speaker 0: It was kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: I pumped continuously.
Speaker 1: I also stopped pump.
Speaker 1: I also pumped continuously, but that meant you ran out of water faster, which well I wasn't shooting continuous Even if I wasn't shooting was always pumping right until I heard that little valve thing inside the pressure release start releasing.
Speaker 1: Then I knew that I'd pumped it to the max Mmm.
Speaker 1: I realized later after I had long since lost and broken all my super soakers and gone to college that I could have just Gotten rid of that valve and made a super soaker that was either real powerful or would have broken.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, so when did you actually go and get your super?
Speaker 0: so your mom just like get you one or pretty much?
Speaker 1: I think my parents actually said hey There's this new super soaker and I didn't care.
Speaker 1: and then I came back from the first work on fight where someone had one.
Speaker 1: I was like I need a super soaker and my parents said alright, then they got me a super soaker 50 Yeah, see.
Speaker 0: and then he had a different situation where because like I said, I wasn't into it right away I didn't really want one when they were available.
Speaker 0: And then it's all the other kids figured out the day before me and they were sold out everywhere.
Speaker 1: So you showed up just fights and you didn't have a super soaker.
Speaker 1: I take it.
Speaker 1: No, no No.
Speaker 0: But we eventually went to a toy store that said they were gonna have him in and my mom actually drove me to a toy Store like early in the morning when they opened as the shipment came in or whatever.
Speaker 0: See the thing is and they didn't get any 50s.
Speaker 0: So I got the unthinkable.
Speaker 0: I knew it existed but no one had one be crazy to have one.
Speaker 0: No, no one's parents would actually buy them it but my mom bonded the hundred.
Speaker 0: See I got the hundred and not the 50 because that's what the store got in that day.
Speaker 1: See, I actually got the hundred almost immediately after getting the 50 and I always carried both.
Speaker 0: Whoa You were rich and spoiled.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah mostly due to credit card.
Speaker 0: I was boiled with a hundred but goddamn Oh the hundred was so great.
Speaker 0: No one we knew had the hundred but me.
Speaker 0: it was crazy.
Speaker 1: the hundred Unlike the 50 which had one little tank and you pumped it up and it put air in the tank.
Speaker 0: It had the special bulb.
Speaker 1: Yes, it had the bulb.
Speaker 1: So what you did is you had a tank and when you pumped it it forced water into this other Tank and it pressurized it there and that is where the water came out when you shot.
Speaker 1: Now the key advantage of this other than of course a lot more power a lot more water Was that you could take the tank off the front and you could still shoot the water that was in the reserve.
Speaker 1: So you could defend yourself while refilling no matter what your source was.
Speaker 0: Yes The other thing is the bulb in the back that held the pressurized water.
Speaker 0: See the super soaker 50 pressurizes the water in there in the tank.
Speaker 0: That is also the supply tank.
Speaker 0: so if you take that thing off you lose all your pressure and you have to refill and everything.
Speaker 0: when you Pressurized in a separate tank that's never going to be removed from your gun.
Speaker 0: that tank is made out of much stronger plastic than the refill tank is made out of and You could get a lot more pressure into that little thing than you could.
Speaker 0: you could imagine also You could pump it so much that there would be no air left in there and it would just be water Solid wall.
Speaker 1: there was actually air in there.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, yes work because water is not compressible I know but it would be under such incredible pressure.
Speaker 1: I mean I realized when I'd shoot it and it came out with such force that it didn't come out in a straight line anymore.
Speaker 1: It kind of spattered at the end.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Hey, I didn't have that problem.
Speaker 1: Well, it wasn't.
Speaker 1: it was more that I'd pump it until the release valve was hissing inside of it And I'd keep pumping while I shot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like they say in the instructions like pump it X times.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, you pump it until you can't physically pump it anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just keep pushing it harder and harder.
Speaker 0: He couldn't break it there.
Speaker 1: if it hit a certain pressure It would just start leaking internally.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That was a safety mechanism So it wouldn't explode or hurt you or anything also see wouldn't break it immediately Because you know, otherwise every kid would just pump it until it broke.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was one thing while super soakers did break and did require replacing with future models.
Speaker 0: They didn't break quite that often.
Speaker 0: I mean the Uzi ones were incredibly unreliable compared to the super soakers.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean the only super soaker that ever broke on me was my 50.
Speaker 1: Started not working so well, and then it broke and I kept repairing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my hundred lasted me several summers.
Speaker 0: I replaced it with like.
Speaker 0: I replaced it with one of those ones that had two side-by-side tanks And that lasted me a few summers.
Speaker 0: Oh, I never got that.
Speaker 1: I stopped at the hundred though a kid in my neighborhood got the 200 the day it came out.
Speaker 0: Wow Yeah, I had like this one.
Speaker 0: I replaced the hundred with was like the XPS something something and had like two side-by-side Tanks and the jet of water it shot was like four times as thick and powerful as the one.
Speaker 0: the hundred shot.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it was but pretty much by the time all those super soakers started coming out was right about when I gave up on sport guns and Water fights all together and almost entirely into water balloons and nerf combined.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see I that was the last one for me.
Speaker 0: But my brother went one step further and he got the one that was basically It was basically it looked like this giant laser rifles like the CPS something thousand.
Speaker 0: It was ludicrous and you would pump it a whole lot and had this purple tank on the back and when you fired it it fired like an inch radius jet of water that was like six feet long like the jet of water that came out was six feet long and it would go far and If it hit you it was like getting hit with five water balloons.
Speaker 0: But you could only shoot it about three times before you're out of water.
Speaker 0: But it was pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: now super soakers have continued to evolve and I used to think man These new super soakers aren't like the old ones their crab because they look really dumb.
Speaker 1: a lot of them.
Speaker 0: A lot of them look like they're made of shittier plastic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, have lots of gimmicks on them that are just gonna break and aren't actually gonna help you out.
Speaker 1: However in terms of actual power, I'm gonna read a quote here From the new one of the new kinds these constant pressure systems Which actually have a rubber chamber that expands and exerts pressure on the water as you pump it.
Speaker 1: Wow Yeah quotes in larger models.
Speaker 1: The resulting blast is forceful enough that recoil can be felt.
Speaker 1: So Scott and I have seriously been considering buying just two of the best Normal-sized easy to deal with super say not the monster xxx xxx xl I vix now But probably the modern equivalent of the 50 or the hundred and just keep them around.
Speaker 0: Well, I did buy one of those When I was a camp counselor after my freshman year of college That particular instance of being a camp counselor our cabin had like a huge water fight because you know Of course all these kids brought super soakers to camp and never used them.
Speaker 0: so we had like people up on the roof of our cabin and all around our cabin making water balloons and water everywhere and None of us seem to think there was a problem and none of the people running the camp thought there was a problem but counselors Of the other cabins didn't like it because they thought we were being irresponsible or something Uh-huh, and they got upset that our cabin was having fun and theirs wasn't and they were also getting wet and we're like just don't Come near our cabins.
Speaker 0: But yeah at that time I just went to the grocery store and bought the super soaker they had there which was like an XPS 100 something something it was pretty good for the standard cheap super soaker.
Speaker 1: Yeah See it said.
Speaker 1: but I think the reason I dropped out of all this stuff pretty much right after the hundred like at the end of the hundreds run was that by then I was becoming more competitive in my life and Me and all my friends realized that with nerf battles you can have an actual game where if you're hit you're out.
Speaker 1: or if you hit you can't use that body part or Three hits and you're out or capture the flag.
Speaker 1: if you're hitting you're out.
Speaker 1: You have to give up the flag or whatever and we played actual Games instead of just get each other.
Speaker 0: and if paintball and airsoft did a bit around you would have played that instead.
Speaker 1: Well paintball was around and I wanted to play paintball.
Speaker 1: It was just expensive and it's cheap now.
Speaker 1: Yeah now it's cheap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, actually we're really thinking about getting into paintball and airsoft in the near future.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll see how it goes.
Speaker 1: in the very least We've already decided we're gonna buy a bunch of cheap airsoft guns and play some airsoft.
Speaker 0: Yes, I don't know if you really want to do that.
Speaker 0: We already know I'm the laser tag god, so am I just Playing airsoft.
Speaker 0: You're all gonna get hurt for you were the god of laser quest style laser tag.
Speaker 1: However in the team based cues are I know that I won two tournaments that the biggest cues are in the world in Tennessee.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mostly because you were just carried by your team Because usually I was the one who was taking people out invading the base blowing up the base and getting out.
Speaker 1: Plus I was one of the few people who figured out how to use the grenade because they didn't tell you.
Speaker 1: But I read the thing and it said how to use the grenade.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, we got to do a show on laser tag.
Speaker 1: So I guess that don't let us forget to do a show on laser tag.
Speaker 0: You want to wrap this show up?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess the only other thing to say about super soakers is that there's a lot of people modding them for great Awesome.
Speaker 0: I mean when I was a kid we used to think hey What else can we put in here besides water?
Speaker 0: Well, we put in ammonia.
Speaker 0: Haha.
Speaker 0: No one ever actually did it.
Speaker 0: Of course, you know everyone gives like what do we filled with P?
Speaker 1: Hey, oh remember those squirt that those they were the cheap crap squirt guns.
Speaker 1: But they had the gimmick that they came with blue or red disappearing ink.
Speaker 0: I remember those.
Speaker 0: there was not a Nickelodeon toy.
Speaker 0: I think it was.
Speaker 0: I remember I remember seeing commercials on Nickelodeon.
Speaker 1: It didn't really work.
Speaker 1: It either stained your clothes or it disappeared immediately.
Speaker 0: It was no good.
Speaker 0: one kid had one and no one cared because the super soaker was God.
Speaker 0: Yeah came through a water fight with one of those people.
Speaker 0: just get pissed off at you and only attack you.
Speaker 1: Well one kid thought of the great idea fill a super soaker with that.
Speaker 1: then he realized how expensive that stuff was.
Speaker 0: Well, it was just like any other, you know thing where they charge for refills the toy store.
Speaker 0: It's overpriced and a ripoff Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah, I hope Everyone out there who where it's not warm enough yet to have water gun fights is now Really sad because it's not warm enough to have water gun fights.
Speaker 0: and here we are talking about super soakers and their awesomeness.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: as long as you give us credit Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.