Speaker 1: It's Wednesday December 26th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek night.
Speaker 1: tonight We finally get around to reviewing Batman the Dark Knight Returns by Frank Miller.
Speaker 1: Let's do this So anyone who's known us for any amount of time knows that?
Speaker 1: One of our favorite things to do especially back when we were in college was uh go to the video barn get some random possibly violent possibly involving Yakuza or swords or something Asian movie and watch it well.
Speaker 0: that trend began because at Otacon many years ago we watched each of the killer which was a. it's a movie directed by Takashi Mika who is Sort of famous director from Japan and he makes many violent movies, but also some other not violent movies.
Speaker 0: He makes all kinds of stuff, but mostly he's known for his violent Yakuza stuff And the theme did a lot of TV.
Speaker 0: but the first three movies he did were like the black society trilogy with through these three Yakuza movies or Yakuza related movies and They all were there.
Speaker 0: They're not like other mob crime movies.
Speaker 0: They're much more Terrible in the.
Speaker 0: you know what happens on screen.
Speaker 0: But in some ways it seems more like that's the way it really is in the mob as opposed to like the glorified way The mob is insane.
Speaker 1: That's one thing I mean when we watched rainy dog, which I think is my favorite work of his.
Speaker 0: actually It's the second in this black society trilogy.
Speaker 1: It was very and he even talked about this in the When they talk like his biography that he likes to have action scenes separate from violence.
Speaker 0: So it's like in an American movie violence.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of violence, but violence is always part of action.
Speaker 0: It's like you watch the matrix is violence in the matrix But the violence is part of an action scene.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's like, you know punching and kicking and shooting violence.
Speaker 1: So there's always this element of glorification.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm in his movies when violent things happen.
Speaker 1: It's never in an action scene.
Speaker 0: It's all sometimes this, you know guys beating each other up, but even then it's not an action scene.
Speaker 1: It's not like some cool choreographed fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not shot as an action scene.
Speaker 0: For example, they'll have a scene where just the cameras pointed at the ground and a guy's getting like beat up with pipes And it's not like, you know cutting and moving around like it would in an action shot.
Speaker 1: There was actually a really good scene in the movie We're about to talk about more deeply as a geek bite where they're in this like mafia kind of Yakuza Triad hangout place.
Speaker 1: It's like their club and there's kickboxing there.
Speaker 1: So they keep every time they go back there.
Speaker 1: There's kickboxers doing choreographed fights in the background and practicing and it's like an action scene there all the time.
Speaker 1: Just these kickboxers.
Speaker 1: and then there's a scene where a real brutal actual fight breaks out while the kickboxers are practicing and you definitely see the contrast between The so-called Hollywood action scene and what a real fight is like because real fights are down and dirty and generally suck for everyone involved.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I liked rainy dog and I liked each of the killer, but I liked it for purely ironic reasons.
Speaker 0: But this the movie the first movie in the Black Society trilogy Which we just watched yesterday called Shinjuku Triad Society or Shinjuku Kuroshikai Chinese mafia Senso.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not I mean it was his first full-length movie ever.
Speaker 0: So I'll give him a break.
Speaker 1: but he was trying hard.
Speaker 1: There was a lot of symbolism in this movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you could tell he was trying hard and you could tell that there was something going on.
Speaker 0: But it just he wasn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't working for him.
Speaker 1: I guess what got to me was that I didn't give one shit about what any and what happened to any character in this whole Stupid movie.
Speaker 0: I do think that is the number one problem with the movie Is that I really just didn't like or care about anyone.
Speaker 0: I couldn't sympathize with anyone.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess I hated a few characters, but that was about it.
Speaker 1: I mean granted I could see that maybe that's what he was going for that This is a world this, you know, seedy crime infested world where there are no sympathetic figures.
Speaker 1: Everyone's an idiot and horrible, but I felt like I was supposed to like the main character Because he wasn't so bad, but see the movie was okay, and he was trying hard.
Speaker 1: There's like there's a lot there from a cinema.
Speaker 1: I mean if you want to study film or like Japanese Asian film or Takashi Mika's film you have to watch this movie.
Speaker 1: It's an academic exercise, but it's not the most Enjoyable movie to watch.
Speaker 1: there are two reasons for that Reason.
Speaker 1: the first is that there was only one female character basically and She's a gecky guy girl in the classic most horrible sense.
Speaker 1: I It I really didn't like that character and I really didn't like where they went with that character.
Speaker 0: I didn't like it at all.
Speaker 0: I like she was in like the opening scene of the movie.
Speaker 0: for a second I thought I was never gonna see her again, but then we saw her again and I was like, ah Why do we have to see her again?
Speaker 1: Go away and then the way she comes back into the plot is just so horrible and Misogynistic.
Speaker 1: and while that's probably the point I just it was it was cringe-worthy, but I think the number one thing that made me not like this movie There's another female character.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the grandma right exactly.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure is the grandma from Kamikaze girls.
Speaker 0: I'm a hundred percent sure cuz no wait.
Speaker 0: No, there was a third female character.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, grandma isn't the grandma from kamikaze girls.
Speaker 0: the the whorehouse mom the mafia lady the mafia lady.
Speaker 0: She is the grandma from kamikaze girls.
Speaker 0: Yes, there were three three female characters two old ladies in one young lady.
Speaker 1: I'll assume that she is in fact that the kamikaze girls universe is the same universe as Takashi mike's world and that that grandma Went on to be the grandma in kamikaze girl.
Speaker 0: It's a safe assumption.
Speaker 1: Yes, cuz the eye pageant everything Yep, but you know, I wonder if that was well anyway, that might have been slightly on purpose.
Speaker 1: You never know.
Speaker 1: The director might have been like hey a nod or maybe we're just reading a lot into that.
Speaker 1: The number one reason why I did not enjoy this movie was that there is an allowed amount of Forced sodomy that can be in a movie where I can still enjoy the movie.
Speaker 1: this movie Met that threshold in like 10 minutes and there was another hour and a half to go.
Speaker 1: So I knew this was downhill.
Speaker 0: it granted stuff.
Speaker 0: granted though It only had like one or two more for sodomies after across the line.
Speaker 1: So that was way too many forcible sodomies.
Speaker 0: But it was I. you know There were way too many for sodomies and it was horrible and painful to watch.
Speaker 1: I think that why it was top heavy.
Speaker 0: They were all close to the beginning of the movie.
Speaker 0: in this and later in the movie They were not really any.
Speaker 1: it's I guess to its credit if you start watching this movie in 15 minutes in your.
Speaker 1: if you try To project the amount of male on male or male on female for sodomy in this movie based on the first 20 minutes Be relieved that the number drops precipitously after that.
Speaker 1: Yep, however that one short judo guy who reminds me a little bit apart.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah What the fuck was up with that?
Speaker 0: Oh, that was like the worst thing ever.
Speaker 1: That didn't make any sense.
Speaker 1: Why did that guy rape that guy?
Speaker 1: Why was he?
Speaker 0: that's totally something out of a cosmo.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I know there's no.
Speaker 1: also It's scary, but that guy really reminded me of teller from Penn and Teller.
Speaker 0: He reminded me of the nerdy guy in sanctuary the short Ross Perot looking guy.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's like a mixture of the two because he had the same he didn't really talk at all And he had the exact same facial expressions that teller has.
Speaker 1: so I assume that if teller ever raped some guy That is exactly what it would look like.
Speaker 0: Anyway that movie.
Speaker 1: and now yeah I will point out too that I'm pretty sure every single character in this movie was homosexual.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the the only thing I'd say about the DVD is the best thing about this DVD was on the DVD There was a Takashi Miike biography and I actually didn't know much about the guy.
Speaker 0: But reading that biography really opened my eyes and I suggest everyone go read the Wikipedia About Takashi Miike even if you never go and see any of his movies just to learn about him because it's quite interesting.
Speaker 1: So if you want to see Takashi Miike's works I'd recommend you watch rainy dog and maybe ley lines, which I haven't seen yet, but Don't watch Shinjuku Kuroshikai unless you are really scraping the bottom of the movie barrel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's plenty of other movies.
Speaker 0: He's made.
Speaker 0: He's made a lot of things that you can go and say wow a lot.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the list right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so in a much more interesting news This is real brief and then I'll let Scott go because I don't have much to say about this.
Speaker 0: But I don't have much to say about mine either.
Speaker 1: You know those Death Note movies and the Death Note anime the Death Note live-action or the anime or the all of them.
Speaker 1: In the live-actions, they uh, they filmed a whole bunch of scenes Involving Matsuda who's perhaps my favorite character other than Elle.
Speaker 0: Matsuda's tough because like Matsuda is like he's that guy.
Speaker 0: It's like you can do it.
Speaker 0: Come on You can do it and it's like he's the guy with the will and the drive But not the brains.
Speaker 0: and there's other guys are the brains but not the will of the drive.
Speaker 1: Matsuda is all guts.
Speaker 1: Yep, and Basically, they cut all his scenes out of the movie.
Speaker 1: So to make up for that all those scenes are gonna be put together with additional things They shot later to make a new movie the that's tentatively called spin-off Matsuda.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be a television special all Matsuda all the way.
Speaker 1: Oh god, I think I'm gonna seek that out.
Speaker 0: It's all you.
Speaker 1: it could be fun.
Speaker 1: I My feeling my guess is that it will have the same kind of feeling watching it that Bayside shakedown head just kind of silly cop doing his cop thing full of guts and not many brains.
Speaker 0: It's all you granted.
Speaker 1: It won't have that song Don't Alright?
Speaker 0: so speaking of new things in Japan, whatever, you know Macross, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know Macross is real old.
Speaker 0: It's 25 years old.
Speaker 1: Hey, that's as old as me.
Speaker 0: It's as old as me.
Speaker 0: We're as old as Macross and I guess that's maybe that's part of why I like Macross so much because it's I've grown up With it sort of exactly.
Speaker 1: Are you sure it's not just Lin min?
Speaker 0: May I Back let Min May's the least favorite.
Speaker 0: Anyway to commemorate the 25th anniversary of Macross all about captain global.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they they've been making this new series Macross frontier.
Speaker 0: It's a direct sequel to Macross 7, which I haven't seen but that doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I've heard okay things about it.
Speaker 0: I think I saw an episode of it and I'm not too about to go and watch it but The first episode is out.
Speaker 0: It's also on the bit torrents.
Speaker 0: So I don't know.
Speaker 0: I really think that I Don't know if you should watch this.
Speaker 0: I haven't watched it yet.
Speaker 0: So I can't say if it's good or bad but Let me just use this as an opportunity to tell you to go and watch the original Macross TV series.
Speaker 0: you can probably get it for really cheap now.
Speaker 0: The whole thing is on DVD in the US and they're high quality DVDs.
Speaker 0: I bought the.
Speaker 0: I pre-ordered and bought the box set Originally came out for a shitload of money when I was in college and I was poor.
Speaker 0: So now that you know, it's cheap now and it much easier to get you don't have to pre-order anything.
Speaker 0: No reason not to get.
Speaker 0: at least try Netflix.
Speaker 1: Why I remember when you bought that you pretty much every day you watch one episode until you've seen the whole thing 39 It's a lot of episode.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I think the thing is like the 26th episode.
Speaker 0: you could you could just pretend that's the end and then because it was popular There are 13 more episodes.
Speaker 0: There's another end.
Speaker 0: That's the original Macross TV series, which if you're an anime fan I don't care if you like it or not.
Speaker 0: If you sort of just have to watch it You won't really understand like you whether you like Ava or not.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: you have to watch it or else you just really Won't have the correct perspective on any other anime you're watching.
Speaker 1: I mean some shows are definitely must watches.
Speaker 1: some shows aren't.
Speaker 1: a lot of shows aren't but there's some things that just It's kind of like in film.
Speaker 1: if you care at all about movies that you have to have seen Citizen Kane You have to like Citizen Kane.
Speaker 1: You have to have seen it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or else what you?
Speaker 0: nothing you say counts.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like if you go to a film class, right and you try to argue with the film professor about something You go blah blah blah blah blah and then people find out like you haven't seen Citizen Kane at all.
Speaker 0: You have never watched it.
Speaker 0: They'll be like nothing.
Speaker 0: you say counts.
Speaker 0: You don't know anything.
Speaker 0: So you nothing.
Speaker 0: you say counts about anime.
Speaker 0: unless you watch Macross and it's 25 years old.
Speaker 0: now I think if something's still popular enough after 25 years for them to make another show out of it Whether you like it or not I think that the fact that something is so popular should tell you that it's notable and meaningful enough that it deserves.
Speaker 0: You are watching once in your life I mean think about other crap shows.
Speaker 0: how many Naruto episodes have you watched?
Speaker 0: like a hundred something you can watch.
Speaker 0: 39 Macross.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm even need to watch 39.
Speaker 0: Just watch the 26.
Speaker 1: Alchemist was fun.
Speaker 1: is Fullmetal Alchemist going to be remembered as this great animation or this great show that touched the hearts of millions 25 years from now.
Speaker 0: No one of you remember 20 now.
Speaker 0: Seriously name any other anime that came out 25 years ago the same year as Macross.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna Alright, so in much more important news probably the most important anime news in a long time It has been announced and there's a trailer a streaming trailer that you can watch That there is in fact going to be a third season of gog manga biore.
Speaker 1: I I don't know what it is about this show Haddis, but Haddish the impact off, but I think we've talked about this before but if you have not seen we did a whole episode.
Speaker 0: I didn't we?
Speaker 0: god.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we did.
Speaker 1: gog manga biore Bi y o r. I find a torrent of it.
Speaker 1: watch the first episode from the first season now.
Speaker 1: You might have to watch it twice because this is Monza humor and it goes real fast.
Speaker 1: and the subtitles There's bit bit bit bit bit bit bit.
Speaker 0: episode 0 6 0 9 2 7.
Speaker 1: Gog manga biore, but uh gog manga biore is One of my favorite shows ever.
Speaker 0: It is one of my top five comedy animes of all time.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: the best part is.
Speaker 1: I didn't really realize this but the person who directed gog manga biore You know, we're still directing it was a guitar daichi.
Speaker 1: I guess I never looked up who directed it.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: I guess that was stupid or something.
Speaker 1: I know wrote it, but I didn't know directed it.
Speaker 1: Daichi also directed koto chow fruits basket and animation runner koromi Which has anime news network says he is known for bizarre plot setups and non sequitur humor.
Speaker 0: Oh, that sounds about right to me.
Speaker 0: that about sums up gog manga biore Bizarre plot setups and non sequitur humor.
Speaker 1: Just that first episode that sticker and it won't come off Seriously.
Speaker 1: the show is so worth watching.
Speaker 0: If you're not watching gog manga biore You're watching the butts.
Speaker 1: That was great.
Speaker 1: And if you're a fan subber Fan sub this I don't need four more translations of every episode of Naruto.
Speaker 1: I need this exactly things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I found this website here and I'm sort of torn.
Speaker 0: and whether this is a good website or a bad website website Let me tell you what it does and then you can decide for yourself.
Speaker 0: You ready?
Speaker 0: The website is woweeo.com.
Speaker 0: w-o-w-o W's o W I O Wow, yo like Oreo, I guess.
Speaker 1: is this about Wario?
Speaker 0: No, nothing to do.
Speaker 0: the Wario basically the subtitle under the under the word.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Yo says free books free minds On this website.
Speaker 0: There are indeed free books with paying no money.
Speaker 0: You can download PDFs of books Most and the thing that's especially cool about this website is There's a lot of comic books on this website that you can download and read for free.
Speaker 0: Absolutely, no money paid to them whatsoever.
Speaker 0: You just sign up for an account and you sort of to fill in a lot of information that I was uncomfortable filling in.
Speaker 1: but could you lie?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess okay and In the end free books.
Speaker 0: now The way it works is you go and you you go around the website finding books and you click add to queue and it goes to your queue right and then you go to your queue and your queue will show you of course all the books in your queue and I think every day you can download like three of the books for free and that should be enough.
Speaker 0: I mean right how fast you can read these books.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends got a train commute.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the books that you download are As far as I can tell DRM free PDFs, they're just PDFs.
Speaker 0: But at the first page of the book, there's an ad and the last page of the book.
Speaker 0: There's an ad.
Speaker 0: uh-huh, so and as far as I can tell When you download a book the person it like, you know Let's say I write a comic book, right and then I put my comic book up on Wowio and then you download it.
Speaker 0: I think I get some of that ad money.
Speaker 0: So you're basically getting free books and the people who made the books are getting some money and you're not getting any DRMs.
Speaker 0: But you can only download so many a day and there's an ad in there.
Speaker 0: the ones I got had Verizon ads.
Speaker 0: There was a big Verizon ad on the first page the big Verizon ad on the last page But none in the middle of the book where it would get in my way.
Speaker 1: That's not too bad.
Speaker 0: It's not too bad.
Speaker 0: I mean it could be a lot worse.
Speaker 0: There could be DRMs.
Speaker 0: There might be DRMs, but I haven't noticed any.
Speaker 0: And it's a PDF and it's free books and lots of comic books for free, especially comic books You're probably you know, I normally wouldn't read a lot of these if they cost money, but they don't cost any money.
Speaker 0: So I'm reading stuff.
Speaker 0: I normally wouldn't otherwise read and that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: So if you're looking for some free comics without some you know Bit torrents.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: No moral quandaries at all.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: so this guy has a pit bull and his pit bull likes nothing more than to chase the light from a Flashlight.
Speaker 1: sounds like every dog not every dog and not every cat.
Speaker 0: I mean, however, you get like the wristwatch reflection.
Speaker 0: You'd mess with the cats.
Speaker 1: well, I remember when I lived in that the condo when I first worked at IBM while I was still on co-op from our IT.
Speaker 1: and I lived in this condo and the lady was never there.
Speaker 1: who owned it.
Speaker 1: so I basically had the condo to myself and her two cats were just there and fed him every now and then whatever and They were content to ignore me unless I pulled out the laser pen.
Speaker 1: one of them went bad shit.
Speaker 1: That laser pen was the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: It would chase that thing forever.
Speaker 1: the other one either couldn't see the laser pen light or something because they would just look at the other cat like it was crazy and Basically hit it every time it went over the laser pen.
Speaker 1: Like what are you doing and keep it away?
Speaker 1: So of course hours upon hours of entertainment for him, you have cats love them laser pens.
Speaker 1: so This guy is a pit bull who likes the light.
Speaker 1: And you know, it doesn't have enough time to take care of the dog all the time You can't play.
Speaker 1: I mean while I would love to spend the rest of my life playing with puppies and doing nothing else I don't have time to play with puppies all the times.
Speaker 1: I've had a puppy and I needed to keep him occupied.
Speaker 1: What better way than to simply put the flashlight around his neck and thereby create a self-sustaining chain reaction?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like we should tape.
Speaker 0: someone needs to make a video stat where you tape a laser Crappy DVD a laser pen to the top of a cat's head Aiming forward.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just tape a crappy DVD in front of Scott Johnson's face?
Speaker 1: Oh We love you Scott.
Speaker 0: Don't worry.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe you do But I think the best part is the dog immediately chases this thing upstairs and disappears And then comes back down and runs in a circle, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's worth watching.
Speaker 0: Pretty funny stuff.
Speaker 0: those animals with the lights do right things.
Speaker 0: so I generally I like really like any sort of video where it takes an animal and then Combines it with human technology that it can't possibly understand to confuse it and make it do weird things.
Speaker 1: confuse a cat Confuse a cat confuse a cat.
Speaker 0: We should make a device that confuse a cat.
Speaker 0: turn it on.
Speaker 0: cats go crazy.
Speaker 1: It's called catnip.
Speaker 0: I know right.
Speaker 0: so Actually, I saw a great video of catnip.
Speaker 0: there was like a catnip tree and a whole bunch of cats.
Speaker 1: I saw that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw that those cats are like way stoned.
Speaker 0: Okay, you can do the main bit.
Speaker 1: There's no people nip.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess there is.
Speaker 1: it's called marijuana.
Speaker 0: I wish there was people nip.
Speaker 1: there is.
Speaker 1: it's called marijuana didn't require smoking.
Speaker 0: Like you just kind of pet it.
Speaker 1: you make brownies.
Speaker 0: That didn't require eating either.
Speaker 0: cats don't have to eat the cat.
Speaker 0: if they just kind of sit near and they go Hey What what can I sit near and get high without any side effects?
Speaker 1: Well, there was that time I shared a small diner with someone who was obviously smoking a joint the whole time in the other stall.
Speaker 1: but right, right.
Speaker 1: So, uh a while ago I've always just not had time to read comic books.
Speaker 1: Scott piles them up in front of me and I'm usually reading I don't know Word books.
Speaker 0: I read word books - what was the last word book you read?
Speaker 1: Star Wars Something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those those kind of a star with these on Star Wars.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read it a word book soon I promise.
Speaker 1: actually tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I'll have a geek bite about the most recent word book I read.
Speaker 0: maybe I'll have to read those Princes of nothing or something.
Speaker 1: You got to read one.
Speaker 1: either got to read the Dan Simmons books or the our Scott Becker books.
Speaker 1: It's one of the two.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Does that those the ones downstairs?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I love it.
Speaker 1: I've been trying to tell Scott to read this one book forever Ever since I read it because Alex told me to and Alex has been trying to tell him for the longest time to read these Other.
Speaker 0: well those other books I actually kind of wanted to read.
Speaker 1: I asked for him and he said he had him and Scott finally Realized that they're both by the same guy.
Speaker 0: it seems to be a lot of things that happen in my life where I see two things and they're separate in my mind and Then I realized oh they're both the same guy and then they become connected.
Speaker 1: or wasn't that?
Speaker 1: when everyone told you to read snow crash For like a year.
Speaker 0: I don't remember Anyway, so finally a while ago I picked up if you haven't noticed like even if something is something I'd like to do People telling me to do something usually works the opposite for me.
Speaker 0: I tend not to do what I'm told.
Speaker 1: Don't read word books.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'll have to go read some word books now.
Speaker 1: so finally I just randomly I need something to read on the train and I picked up one of the countless things Scott leaves in a pile for me outside my door all the time and it was Batman the Dark Knight Returns by Frank Miller.
Speaker 0: hallelujah Not only does him finally read an underwear pervert, but he reads pretty much The best Batman book there ever was or pot is still is.
Speaker 0: I contend that this is not only perhaps the second or third best Underwear pervert comic there is ever.
Speaker 1: I contend that while this is Undoubtedly one of the best Batman works ever.
Speaker 1: I think it is also one of the best Superman books.
Speaker 0: How many Superman books have you read?
Speaker 0: One so how qualified are you to really say that?
Speaker 1: a better one and I'll read it.
Speaker 0: Supposedly that Superman for all seasons is really good, but I haven't read it.
Speaker 0: So I'm not gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say for sure okay, but uh, I knew this is the kind of.
Speaker 1: this is something that I should have read for a long time because Everyone I've ever talked to who has read it has looked at me with the same Look that I gave people who had never seen snatch Ready.
Speaker 0: it's such a piece of like comics, you know history.
Speaker 0: I mean like there's so many things just based on it.
Speaker 0: Hey, like they there were darkwing duck episodes that directly parody this comic.
Speaker 1: That's how pervasive is the new Batman?
Speaker 1: Even gonna influence heavily by this.
Speaker 0: Well, the new Batman is called the Dark Knight and it does the Joker and it.
Speaker 0: but who knows?
Speaker 0: What the plots actually I saw.
Speaker 0: I mean, it can't be the same plot and it because the major plot point.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna sum up the plot real quick here.
Speaker 0: It's a Batman plot So right that he and I got.
Speaker 0: I want to spoil it because this is a review and not a final thoughts.
Speaker 0: So this book might deserve some final thoughts.
Speaker 1: I think it does.
Speaker 1: if Watchmen deserved one then this deserves one, right?
Speaker 0: Here's the basic story of the Dark Knight Returns.
Speaker 0: First of all, the story is not in a DC Universe directly.
Speaker 0: It's you know, one of those.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna tell a Batman story off to the side here deals.
Speaker 1: granted as far as I'm concerned This is fucking Batman.
Speaker 0: Yes fucking Batman.
Speaker 1: I mean both this and the animated series are Batman Exactly in my mind Batman and 1989 Batman.
Speaker 1: in my mind Batman's life was the animated series and then the animated movie happened And then this is the end of all that anyway.
Speaker 0: So Batman is an old geezer like 60 70 something and he hasn't been Batman in a long time.
Speaker 1: He's giving it up.
Speaker 0: He's giving it up because he's so old right.
Speaker 0: and of course Superman is still Superman because well, he's powerful and he's an alien and you know and Gotham City Commissioner Gordon's gonna retire cuz he's wicked old too, but he's not retiring quite yet.
Speaker 0: He's retiring soon.
Speaker 1: It's one of those, you know, the buddy cop movies where I'm gonna retire next month.
Speaker 0: Just got to solve this last case and the last case is this is gang of mutants like this?
Speaker 0: Well, it's not a gang of mutants is a gang called the mute.
Speaker 1: They're basically just jackasses.
Speaker 0: They're basically just jackasses and they're typical.
Speaker 0: They're stereotypical 80s punk assholes I like.
Speaker 0: they're the kind of bad guys you beat up in like Streets of Rage your final fight.
Speaker 1: I like their lingo so much.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's like my mom chicken legs.
Speaker 1: all lines are busy Chegg's my kind of nasty Rob Chegg's Billy Chegg's preg school mutant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, leader figure I squared you boys Mutants we slice the dices Bro, she don't shave.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they keep saying they don't shave anyway.
Speaker 0: so As soon as they you know Basically get rid of these mutants then the Commissioner Gordon will retire and everything will be cool, right?
Speaker 0: but Batman gets Stirred up.
Speaker 0: that old man, you know, he just can't you know sit down for too long.
Speaker 1: He tries that.
Speaker 1: that's.
Speaker 1: probably the best thing about this is that Batman almost never speaks in the whole thing.
Speaker 1: He's just thinking to himself quietly Yep, and it's interesting because whenever you see Batman like the animated series even the movies.
Speaker 1: He doesn't talk.
Speaker 1: He just he's this silent figure that's just beating people up and he's doing his thing.
Speaker 1: But he's always silent.
Speaker 1: and reading this you get this constant running commentary of what he's thinking.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you know what?
Speaker 0: That's exactly what Batman should have been thinking I'm not gonna go through the rest of the plot, but cuz I don't want to spoil it.
Speaker 0: But let let's let me give you the information and why this is such an important comic Even if the you know, the contents of the comic were terrible, which they aren't.
Speaker 0: Here's why this is so important, right?
Speaker 0: It was three comic book issues and they were came out in February March April May June.
Speaker 0: I think I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: it's three issues.
Speaker 0: You can buy them all in one trade.
Speaker 0: if you got.
Speaker 0: you can also buy absolute Dark Knight Which is a giant book that also has the Dark Knight Strikes Back, but you don't want that.
Speaker 0: You just want to get the little trade paper back.
Speaker 0: It's real cheap And it can.
Speaker 0: it collects three comic book issues that were come out in 1986. this comic book is from 1986.
Speaker 0: I was four years old when this came out.
Speaker 0: My brother was born.
Speaker 0: He was zero okay, and Basically Batman started out when Batman was a brand new comic in the 30s, you know as sort of this grim gritty underworld kind of deal, but eventually Batman became a Corny Adam West Silver Age Batman with you know Robin and tights and goofball, you know pow zach, you know kind of action.
Speaker 0: and That was not exactly The best or the most exciting.
Speaker 0: and it wasn't until 1986 when Frank Miller read some Kazuo Koike and then made this comic that Batman returned to being dark and gritty and underworld II and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: and You know in the early 90s in the late 80s and such when all those other dark and gritty comics appeared You know like the serious Ghost Rider and the Punishers and the Wolverines, which is also Frank Miller all those comics Only your cable all that stuff only existed because of this comic and all you go.
Speaker 0: and even still today There's still like within you know, the superhero comics in the u.s.
Speaker 0: This sort of or even in the non superhero There's that sort of sub Genre of the the dark and the gritty comics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want these dark gritty ones are over here and those exist because of this book and this book alone.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's a it's a pretty important comic.
Speaker 0: I mean really that 1989 Batman movie probably wouldn't happen without this comic.
Speaker 0: also a lot of the this if you look there's a list on Wikipedia of Like Oh mashes that have been made to this comic.
Speaker 0: There are quite a lot of them.
Speaker 0: like a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: we're talking like artists of all shapes and sizes have looked to this one comic just three issues only three issues here and Have paid it quite a bit of respect.
Speaker 0: So there is something here that is important.
Speaker 0: Alright, so the comic is written and drawn by Frank Miller Although the inking and the lettering and the coloring was done by other people like Klaus Janssen and Lynn Varley and people.
Speaker 0: But Frank Miller is the guy who wrote it.
Speaker 0: now you might heard of Frank Miller from such things as The 300 the Sin City, which is sort of where Sin City is sort of like the perfection Oh, I guess his perfection of the grim and gritty kind of stuff, you know It's like he started here and then he built on it and he got better at it.
Speaker 0: And then he he needs the Wolverine and then he did the Sin City, right?
Speaker 0: So if you notice they're turning a lot of his stuff into the movies there Maybe because he's pretty good at writing.
Speaker 0: of course don't assume that because something says Frank Miller on it that it's good because from what I hear a lot of his Newer stuff is not so good.
Speaker 0: And also the I hear that the Dark Knight Strikes Back Which I have not read which is the sequel to this is also not so good.
Speaker 1: See that was the thing because I said I read the Frank and Miller Batman to the comic geek speak people and all those guys at the NYAF.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the first thing they said is You mean the Dark Knight Returns, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't read anything else good God.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's not.
Speaker 0: Frank Miller is an awesome and very important comic person that you need to know about but by no means is everything He has ever made Amazing.
Speaker 0: and this is perhaps is you know, I guess the thing he will always be most famous for is basically Making Batman awesome again instead of being corny-ass Adam West Batman like he always was before then.
Speaker 1: I guess we could try to talk a little bit about exactly what it was that made this so good.
Speaker 1: I mean, I love this.
Speaker 0: Well, first of all, the arts is like the amazing.
Speaker 1: It's very Very I don't know simple and stylized and flat.
Speaker 0: it really feels Really like the time to me like it feels sort of like dark 80s, you know It's like I looking at it really reading this comic gives me the same feeling I get when I watch a really good Batman movie.
Speaker 0: it's like a really good Batman movie on paper and You know, it's sort of the way it's drawn.
Speaker 0: It looks just like that 1989 Batman movie or at least it might not graphically look the same But it gives the same feeling to me when I look at it.
Speaker 0: Well, it's take it into my brain.
Speaker 1: It's done very I don't know Cinemagraphically, I mean you look at it and it's just it's almost like it's storyboards for the movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this they always do this thing where they'll break a page down Especially when they they cut to these things where they show the news and there's people like talking heads on the news talking about Batman and stuff like that and they'll break the page down into a lot of little panels of like a TV screen with the narration and the narrations are always on top and you sort of have to read them left left to right and it can be A little confusing until you realize how it's organized.
Speaker 0: sorta I got messed up reading it and the in the wrong order a few times some of those.
Speaker 0: But when they cut to those TVs, it's always really interesting because it's like hey, here's what you know People are saying about Batman and it really brings back that whole.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Batman's a hero fighting crime and you know, but it brings that that sort of.
Speaker 0: you know Is Batman in line with the law?
Speaker 0: He's a vigilante He's actually a terrible horrible person kind of thing and it really brings that issue back to the forefront of Batman where it Completely was not an issue.
Speaker 0: I mean you watch an Adam West Batman or you read a Silver Age Batman comic and it's just like oh Let that there's a bad guy better turn on the bad signal.
Speaker 0: So Batman will save us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Batman saved us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it definitely has that sort of current social commentary, you know, the old guards going out I mean the mayor whatever Commissioner Gordon's retiring Batman was retired.
Speaker 1: everything the new worlds coming in the new 80s world is just all the new young kids.
Speaker 1: I mean they keep pointing out that all the young cops Barely, even believe that Batman ever exist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all the kids don't even believe me.
Speaker 0: Batman's been retired for 15 years or something like that and Superman Officially doesn't exist.
Speaker 1: So a lot of people don't believe that Superman ever even existed.
Speaker 1: Yeah And it's kind of like there's this.
Speaker 1: all the older people remember this world that the new generation just has no idea about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they talk about.
Speaker 0: yeah, they used to be heroes blah blah blah I mean in the introduction it talks about like this bar that you can't get to and there's people in the bar You know talking about a time when there are heroes and there aren't heroes anymore and there really aren't heroes anymore as far as Normal people are concerned.
Speaker 0: They don't believe in them They'd never see him etc, etc.
Speaker 1: And there's just a lot of a lot of very contemporary political issues from the time.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a lot of this idea of can criminals be rehabilitated?
Speaker 1: what's the line between Punishment and rehabilitation and reform?
Speaker 1: it's also cold war action going on and it all the thing I think what's beautiful about it.
Speaker 1: Is that every single one of these elements is Brought together into one coherent whole and they all mirror each other.
Speaker 1: The Cold War is kind of like this macrocosm.
Speaker 1: look at everything that's going on on the micro level in everyone's lives in this comic And the conflicts are the same just on different scales.
Speaker 1: and it's it's all these warring ideologies.
Speaker 1: I mean, what's the line that I think the biggest point is?
Speaker 1: what's the line between justice and revenge?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and what's the line between being a hero and being a god?
Speaker 0: The the one thing that really gets me is how Batman is always think like it starts like Bruce Wayne's driving in a race car And the car is like on fire gonna crash and he's thinking well, this wouldn't be such a bad day
Speaker 1: But not good enough but not a good enough day
Speaker 0: not good enough death.
Speaker 0: So he jumps out of the flaming car and then later on like, you know something's happening and he's pretty much like, huh?
Speaker 0: I could let you know, he's like, uh, I could die here.
Speaker 0: I could let him I could let someone die But then I wouldn't find out something.
Speaker 0: and he always comes like the verge of like killing himself or killing someone or letting himself Die.
Speaker 0: or you know kamikaze ing and he's always he's thinking about dying.
Speaker 0: It's like it's welling on his mind the whole time and he's really serious about it, but stuff Oh, it always turns out in a really weird way.
Speaker 0: But like at any moment you think he could just kill himself and that would totally make sense.
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of it is that he felt like when he retired when he was no longer Batman.
Speaker 1: He was Bruce Wayne He was dead and he was basically just waiting to die.
Speaker 1: And he just he couldn't bring himself to die.
Speaker 1: and eventually the Batman came back.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean basically show it.
Speaker 0: it's sort of trying to say look He is Batman can't change what you are can't escape the Batman.
Speaker 0: He's in you.
Speaker 0: You can't avoid him.
Speaker 1: Yes No, no they can't.
Speaker 1: But also I think what was interesting is every time he's fighting someone just that the dialogue that's coming That's in Batman's head and what he's thinking and why he does what he does.
Speaker 1: and you know in the in the comics or in The show Batman doesn't kill people.
Speaker 1: He's very just.
Speaker 1: he always does the right thing.
Speaker 1: But pretty much every time he's confronted with the scum of the earth He is constantly thinking I should kill this man.
Speaker 1: The world would be better off if I just killed this man.
Speaker 1: right now All I have to do is pull the trigger and this is over.
Speaker 1: I don't have to risk my life I don't have to fight him.
Speaker 1: I could just shoot him from here and everything would be better.
Speaker 1: No one would miss him.
Speaker 1: It would be nothing but a good act.
Speaker 1: and yet he can never bring himself to do.
Speaker 0: greatest part is where he's driving the Batmobile Up and he encounters someone who he knows is much stronger than he is and I'll probably beat the shit out of him, right?
Speaker 0: So what does he do?
Speaker 0: He's like, huh?
Speaker 0: You know that wouldn't be quite such a bad way to die and he gets out of the Batmobile to just fight the guy You know with bare fists and whatnot and knowing that he's totally outmatched and that's it really shows you like, huh?
Speaker 0: Something's going on in his mind there.
Speaker 0: He could be crazy.
Speaker 0: and they have this on the during the TV scenes.
Speaker 0: They always have you know, Lana Lang from the Daily Planet or not.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Daily Planet Daily bugle is spider-man, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: I don't know but It's always like, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Batman's great saving world heroes are great, you know, where would you be without them blood?
Speaker 0: We just get owned by all these crazy supervillains.
Speaker 0: and there's the psychologist guy who's like.
Speaker 0: no all these Supervillains are doing their thing because of Batman and they actually because of the way certain things play out in the show Not in the show.
Speaker 0: in the comic.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like the site the crate you.
Speaker 0: it's like this guy is saying Batman is bad.
Speaker 0: Batman is wrong Causes the crime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Batman gives these insane people a focal point and they even show you at one point in our you know It's Arkham Asylum, right?
Speaker 0: There's some supervillains in Arkham Asylum where they belong and it shows them, you know being sort of not crazy Just sort of being like, you know toted around.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not much spoiler because we know that the Joker is a villain, you know.
Speaker 1: And the Joker is just sitting there and if you don't even notice the Joker It's just some sad old guy in a sanitarium.
Speaker 0: and then they're you know It's the Joker because his face is white but well not really acting very Jokerish because they bring it up kind of suddenly.
Speaker 1: I mean it shows the Newscaster and then it shows these crazy people in an asylum and there's just one just crazy guy and they're all just kind of.
Speaker 0: Well, you saw him earlier in the comic, but he's just you're not you can't yell.
Speaker 1: You're not a hundred percent sure I'm a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, you see all these crazy people.
Speaker 1: They're just looking at the TV and being crazy and as Soon as the news points out that Batman has returned They just draw the guy's face completely differently and now he has green hair and it's the Joker.
Speaker 0: Yep He totally like Joker's out.
Speaker 0: So it's like hey, maybe bat, you know You're so against this psychiatrist guy who's so much political, correct?
Speaker 1: You shouldn't punish criminals ever which you know.
Speaker 1: That's a whole debate that we talk about more.
Speaker 0: and I guess the final thoughts because you look at you look at half the evidence The comic gives you and you're like this guy is so wrong If we listen to this guy the Joker be running wild blowing everyone up.
Speaker 0: But then you look and all the things he says, you know Like Batman caused all these criminals to be just by his mere existence.
Speaker 0: It makes it look like it's true and it's like ah, it's a brilliant comic.
Speaker 1: Now I really want.
Speaker 1: I mean we're skipping over a lot of the good parts about this comic and partly that's because you have To read it and then we're going to read it.
Speaker 1: a final thought some point in the next couple months.
Speaker 0: If you don't read any and if there's only if you only read one underwear perfect comic in your life It should be watchman if you read two underwear perfect comics in your life as you watch them in this.
Speaker 1: But I want to talk a little bit about Superman because in general I really don't like the idea of Superman.
Speaker 1: I just it's kind of this lame Relic of the 50s.
Speaker 1: Just what if I made it?
Speaker 1: Superman was 1939, but all the Superman stuff I know of okay, and it's just very kind of.
Speaker 1: he's really powerful and it's all kind of cheesy.
Speaker 1: And it's just.
Speaker 0: I like that soup live-action Superman show from when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Which one Lois and Clark.
Speaker 1: I like that show too, but that's cuz it was mostly comedy.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 1: but Superman is portrayed in a very interesting way in this comic and I just I Really like it.
Speaker 1: I I still think this is what this is.
Speaker 1: This is the best Superman portrayal I have ever seen because you've only seen like one.
Speaker 1: Well, I've seen your Superman movies all the Superman movie.
Speaker 0: No, I don't like the live-action Superman movies.
Speaker 0: Ah, no, no good.
Speaker 1: And I've seen Superman in various animations and things.
Speaker 0: The only Superman animation I like is those original ones cuz it was always like Superman vs.
Speaker 0: The Mad Scientist doo-doo-doo.
Speaker 1: But even they were kind of superficial.
Speaker 1: Superman is only ever shown in two contexts in the entirety of this comic.
Speaker 1: He is always larger than life.
Speaker 1: He is always gigantic.
Speaker 1: He always takes up the entire frame whenever he's there just big dashing close-ups, and he's very square jawed.
Speaker 1: he is perfect in every way.
Speaker 1: he is a god and Whenever.
Speaker 1: but that's just when they're showing him standing there talking Whenever he's fighting whenever he's doing his Superman thing.
Speaker 1: They don't even show it really.
Speaker 1: it's pretty much just silhouettes and The thought.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like you get the same Batman treatment of just his inner monologue But instead it's Superman and you see what's going through Superman's head and it's just black silhouettes with the red cape and just.
Speaker 1: the style Of all those Superman scenes is amazing.
Speaker 1: And actually I think very meaningful.
Speaker 1: But again, I don't want to really talk about that in any great depth.
Speaker 1: yet
Speaker 0: My favorite part with Superman is when basically someone tells Superman to go take care of Batman, right and You see the scene where Superman storms Gotham City, basically And he cleans up like three or four street crimes and whatever and you never actually see Superman during this whole sequence.
Speaker 0: It's like multiple pages.
Speaker 0: They don't draw Superman once they draw this blue beam Coming like into the city and like going right through walls and stuff and it's like someone feels a whoosh go by and then Like some criminal suddenly gets like their brains blown out and then you know Batman standing there and like the wall opens up and someone comes like blasting through the wall and you just see Batman there and like This
Speaker 1: blue
Speaker 0: whoosh goes by him and like there's a big hole in the wall behind him and he's just like.
Speaker 0: I don't have time For this.
Speaker 0: you've cost me a bunch of you wasted a bunch of you cost me like five hours of my time here.
Speaker 0: meet me Tomorrow at my house at whatever time and Superman doesn't say anything.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: and it's like, you know, the Superman came through like this storm like this Unknown force of nature that just totally, you know blew everything away.
Speaker 0: No one even knew he was there.
Speaker 0: No one knew it was.
Speaker 0: it was just.
Speaker 0: That's what Superman would be like you just sort of like this.
Speaker 0: You know force of nature that comes through and goes out and you don't know.
Speaker 1: you don't even know just whoosh and a lot of what?
Speaker 1: Makes this comic interesting is that you have Batman who is just a human being.
Speaker 1: there's nothing special about that.
Speaker 0: In fact, he's an old geezer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and yet he does all these things and he tries, you know, he does what he does.
Speaker 1: He's Batman.
Speaker 1: and yet Superman is a god and just the way the two of them handle who they are and what they do and their power and the Root conflict I think of this is between two ideologies and Superman represents one and Batman represents the other and neither.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not like the good ideology versus the bad ideology.
Speaker 0: It's like the half good half bad one versus the half good half bad one.
Speaker 0: You're like, ah, what do I do?
Speaker 1: but then there is a scene and this scene is just one of those scenes that sticks with you forever from any sort of work of art and to not really spoil anything basically in the middle of all this the Cold War is kind of coming to a head and They definitely give you the impression they show you bits that at one point the u.s decides to send Superman over to basically crush the Soviet military.
Speaker 1: mmm, and there are repercussions of this and a nuclear weapon gets lost somewhere and Superman goes to save the day.
Speaker 1: and just from that moment on that next like five or six pages of this comic Actually, I think is the next 15 or 20 pages are probably the best part of this entire comic.
Speaker 0: It's weird that in the Batman comic that the Superman part.
Speaker 0: because usually if you're reading the Batman comic You know, especially like if you're us, you know, you don't you don't like you.
Speaker 0: like Batman you want Batman action But there's really very little of that Batman action in this comic.
Speaker 0: It's not a lot of grappling hook I mean, there's only one batmobile scene really and it's really not much.
Speaker 0: It's not one of those, you know racing through the streets batmobile scenes.
Speaker 0: You don't really have the.
Speaker 0: you know batwing action is a little bit of helicopter and motorcycle action.
Speaker 1: Almost all the action is in this comic is people talking to each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean all that classic Batman action of swinging on the things and jumping down on people with the cape out does go boo There's not too much of that going on.
Speaker 1: And actually when there is you don't really pay attention to that.
Speaker 1: you pay attention because he's basically going through in his head and kind Of explaining why he does everything He does like how why he appears in a certain way and all the psychology of how he controls people and makes.
Speaker 0: and also He's an old geezer.
Speaker 0: He gets the shit kicked out of him constantly.
Speaker 0: So you're most I'm mostly concentrating on when I read it.
Speaker 0: like all the pain Batman is suffering.
Speaker 0: It's like this old geezer getting kicked around Constantly,
Speaker 1: but just the scene from when Superman goes to stop the new con Just the style of it and the way it's portrayed and just all that goes through Superman's head are the words 20 million die by fire if I am weak.
Speaker 1: Yep, and just that the way it's so perfect It's it's pretty much exactly how it would go epic it's saga it's it's just it's brilliant.
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: Plus I like how it shows like he sees sort of like Superman's powers are like just in the in the right because I know this in many different time periods, you know Many different Superman's because it's all crazy batshit, you know Superman's powers are at different levels and whatever, you know This is the original Superman could only actually jump.
Speaker 0: He couldn't fly.
Speaker 0: He just jumped really high.
Speaker 0: so it was like he was flying and you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: but This Superman like he's just right and that he can.
Speaker 0: you know, if he's storming Gotham City to you know Take care of a bunch of criminals.
Speaker 0: It's like whoosh and it's amazing.
Speaker 0: But if it's like fighting in the war, it's like he's actually sort of you know roughing it quite and you know fighting this nuke.
Speaker 0: He just can't go and throw it into the Sun like yes happened in so many other Superman's where you take like a net Well, I think catch a bunch of nukes in it.
Speaker 1: Part of the idea of all this is that you know, the world is changing technology.
Speaker 1: You know, the world is becoming the modern world that we live in today, you know from the 80s you know early 90s kind of perspective, but you know, the idea is that the world is changing and Superman and Batman are not changing.
Speaker 1: So these two figures are having to cut and Gordon and all these other people from the old world are Still around and they're coping with this changing world.
Speaker 1: and the world is catching up to Superman - it's not just catching up to Batman.
Speaker 1: The world is not what it was when Superman was doing his thing 40 years ago now.
Speaker 1: Technology.
Speaker 1: Superman is not a god as much as you might expect him to be Yep, and I really don't want to talk about that anymore But you should read this comic series.
Speaker 0: Everyone's got to read this comic.
Speaker 0: if you read no other Batman comic This is it Batman the Dark Knight Returns by Frank Miller, it's always in print.
Speaker 0: there's a reason for that.
Speaker 0: you can buy it anywhere.
Speaker 0: they sell books borders bars and nobles Amazon, let's check the Amazon price.
Speaker 0: It's a little orange book.
Speaker 0: Don't bother with the crazy giant hardcover absolute Whatever.
Speaker 0: you don't want that.
Speaker 0: you just want to buy this little orange book.
Speaker 0: It's the same try same size as every other.
Speaker 0: frickin You know comic underwear pervert trade paperback.
Speaker 0: it is Okay, why is it selling for $48 used on Amazon?
Speaker 0: That's not right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's fine.
Speaker 1: It's $14.99 according to the back of it right here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Let me search on Barnes & Noble.
Speaker 1: You've got to be able to get this.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine it's always in print.
Speaker 0: It's it like every bookstore.
Speaker 1: just go to Barnes & Noble or borders or whatever.
Speaker 1: You'll see it there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, here we go.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: I Barnes & Noble.
Speaker 0: $12 and 14 cents.
Speaker 0: Okay $13 and 49 cents if you're not a member now.
Speaker 1: if that wasn't enough of a I don't know Overly brilliant review of how random should rim you hates underwear pervert comics.
Speaker 1: I Hate underwear pervert comics.
Speaker 1: I really don't like them at all.
Speaker 1: You know what this comic book is amazing.
Speaker 0: It's very important that you should read this if you care about comics whatsoever.
Speaker 1: The only thing I warn you is don't flip through it.
Speaker 1: Just read it page by page.
Speaker 1: a lot of people like flip through a comic book and don't do that.
Speaker 1: You'll see things you shouldn't see.
Speaker 0: and even if you don't like comics real, you know If you like Batman movies any Batman movie?
Speaker 0: if he's any Batman movie you've ever seen and liked it not counting the Adam West one.
Speaker 0: Then you should get this and read it because reading it is Exact gives me exactly the same feeling as when I watch an amazing Batman movie.
Speaker 0: It's the exact same feeling in you.
Speaker 0: it's no different.
Speaker 1: and even if you don't like Batman if you are interested in I don't know Cold War politics or Cold War ideology or contemporary political issues from 1980s United States or criminology or anything like that like criminal psychology Police ideal anything.
Speaker 0: that's all that that all Batman's about criminal psychology.
Speaker 1: You know what everyone should read this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: I mean you don't like comic books period you don't like that and they don't like anything.
Speaker 1: I'd recommend you read this.
Speaker 1: I think you'll like it.
Speaker 0: It's definitely I don't know what else to say important super important.
Speaker 0: Like if there was a if there was a class in school that was like, you know studying, you know comics This would be on the reading list no matter what.
Speaker 0: Well, it had better be Else you're in the wrong class.
Speaker 1: All right I think that's enough of that because uh, it won't be too many days before the visigoths are here for the New Year's Extravaganza.
Speaker 0: I wonder how many visigoths have read this book.
Speaker 0: We'll make sure they've all read it so that they unvisigoth by just by reading it.
Speaker 1: We should always bring the Batman here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as if it got Batman will come and make them read about him.
Speaker 1: in his olden days This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.