Speaker 0: It's Thursday September 13th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: We explain in layman's terms to the best of our ability the Creative Commons.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Man, so now that I got headphones that aren't crappy I've been listening to a lot of podcasts and a lot of music was that?
Speaker 1: maybe that was what was holding you back.
Speaker 0: It's the thing is I'm not listening to any more podcast.
Speaker 0: I'm just listening to more episodes of the ones I currently listen to.
Speaker 1: yeah But you know I'm not listening to that many podcasts either.
Speaker 1: But I you know I have always pretty much kept up with the one with see I do ones I do.
Speaker 0: I did until I stopped driving to work.
Speaker 0: There was kind of this lead time now where I was taking the train to work But I didn't have good headphones, so I read manga and stuff and played GBA games.
Speaker 1: I'll see that was it then is he is my combination of driving or training plus having headphones.
Speaker 1: So as any time the podcasts were in the house even at work with the computer at work I was getting the podcast going on.
Speaker 0: so yep, though The thing is I was listening to a podcast.
Speaker 0: That's awesome.
Speaker 0: They haven't listened to in a while called Derek the Bandit Sound Republic Which I highly recommend if you like trance or any sort of electronic music from South Africa and the world and the letter Z Sound Republic.
Speaker 0: But anyway I I just this stood out so much that I really have to say something about it because it bothered me.
Speaker 0: So he has like kind of ad like things every now And then like blah blah blah he'll talk and I kind of just ignore him like I do any DJ.
Speaker 0: but then in the middle of his mix he played this promo for some podcast and One.
Speaker 0: the audio quality of this promo was really bad and to the podcast sounded really crappy.
Speaker 1: see that's really not so bad when you Read when you've listened to all his episodes because early on in his podcasting days He made a deal with this video game magazine in South Africa now this video game magazine.
Speaker 0: We don't know if it was good or not, but the ads it made The content it was like we're gonna review this game on Derek the Bandit Sound Republic.
Speaker 1: the deal He made is he thought that in order to get popular He made a deal with them that they would put his podcast on the CD that came with the magazine and in exchange They would do a small like audio bit like five or ten minutes of video game talk And he would put it in the podcast.
Speaker 1: Terrible really ruined it because you were listening to like this trance mix and then suddenly There's like five to ten minutes of stupid video game guys talking with bad audio.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it wouldn't be so bad because the content wasn't horrible.
Speaker 0: It was just that the audio quality was so terrible that it just I stopped.
Speaker 0: I couldn't listen.
Speaker 0: I just had to stop yep, and then he's doing it again with some crap podcast.
Speaker 1: Well cuz he's sort of part of the pod show thing.
Speaker 1: MTV guy and Dvorak now works over there and their pod safe music network crap.
Speaker 1: and yeah.
Speaker 1: So that's when that's.
Speaker 1: that's where that whole sort of culture of podcasting with the promos and the pod safe music comes from.
Speaker 0: You know more and more.
Speaker 0: I just don't like podcasting except my show and a few other shows.
Speaker 1: well It's pretty much like any podcast.
Speaker 1: That's is sort of in with that.
Speaker 1: You know Sort of like podcasting.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you want to call it dogma.
Speaker 1: Maybe that those guys have set up it.
Speaker 1: I really don't like it.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should do that.
Speaker 0: We should call these different movements like film people and music people do.
Speaker 0: that's dogma.
Speaker 0: now Maybe we'll call that dogma.
Speaker 0: and what we do is I don't know awesome, okay?
Speaker 0: Whatever doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I just it stood out so horribly and I mean it stands out in.
Speaker 0: you know other podcasts I listen to when they do it, but the disparity of quality between the normal show if you know awesome music and this promo which sounded like they record over skype was just uh all
Speaker 1: right, so We I got a sports news and a sports thing of the day today.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah real sports - not like.
Speaker 0: oh, so air hockey?
Speaker 1: No, yeah, exactly ping-pong.
Speaker 0: Yes thumb wrestling.
Speaker 1: So this is probably if you anyone who knows about American football knows everything there is to know about this already But I want to.
Speaker 1: I want to bring a new perspective to the table that I have not heard expressed in any other media.
Speaker 1: So the New England Patriots a football team that has been quite good this season and many seasons pretty well this season one game So far, but they've been really good for many years, and they're gonna remain being good They're.
Speaker 1: probably they might even win the Super Bowl this year who knows?
Speaker 0: I'll be honest.
Speaker 0: I had no idea.
Speaker 0: I don't even yeah really know what a team is.
Speaker 1: a lot of people who might know that.
Speaker 1: You know my favorite team is the Giants and my second favorite team is the Patriots And my most hated team is the Jets and my second most hated team is the Eagles.
Speaker 1: they might be like ah You're just uh.
Speaker 1: you're just saying what you're about to say because you like the Patriots and you hate the Jets when the game happened To be a Patriots vs.
Speaker 1: Jet game, but no that's not the case.
Speaker 1: cuz rim I think will agree with me.
Speaker 0: despite his not giving two shits about football I care a little bit a family tradition in.
Speaker 1: as long as I lie It doesn't count the Lions Lions don't gather night of a football team.
Speaker 1: the law qualifies the football team.
Speaker 0: The thing is there's something special about.
Speaker 0: every Thanksgiving my family sits around and watches the Lions lose.
Speaker 0: No, it's not watch them lose.
Speaker 0: It's watch them win.
Speaker 0: watch them Just soundly defeat another team and then fuck it up in the last three minutes somehow.
Speaker 0: And that was the game.
Speaker 1: that's the New York Giants.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about so?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so New England Patriots playing the Jets right and in football you have these people on the sidelines the Co-coaches and the coordinators of offense and defense and they have to tell the players what play they want them to do.
Speaker 1: you know do a Do a nickel defense or you know do some you know play action whatever or you know fake this punt, right?
Speaker 1: And in order to communicate with the players all right the coach will usually just talk to the quarterback maybe with like a headset something right and Then the quarterback will get in the huddle and tell the team what to do.
Speaker 1: well on defense There is no sort of quarterback on the field to tell everyone what to do.
Speaker 1: There's just all these sort of equal players.
Speaker 1: So the defensive coordinator on the sidelines You know we'll use some sort of signaling of some sort to tell the defense what to do.
Speaker 1: sometimes You know when they don't have a chance to just you know come over and talk.
Speaker 1: So you know of course you're playing a game like this.
Speaker 1: people are gonna look at the other team signals And you know figure them out.
Speaker 1: and sometimes you know you're sitting there playing a game And you might notice hey That's guys done like you know like a tee with his hands and then wiped his brow and every time he did that they Did this defensive play.
Speaker 0: yeah like every time he throws the shocker up?
Speaker 0: We know.
Speaker 1: yep, so some you know people notice coincidences like that, and then they'll tell their coach And then they'll get you know a little edge in the game.
Speaker 1: the New England Patriots not being complete dumbasses Videotaped the other teams.
Speaker 1: they like apologized for it.
Speaker 1: They did it the cut red-handed whatever.
Speaker 1: they videotaped the other team signals to figure them out And that is against the written rules of the NFL.
Speaker 1: so on the one hand they broke the rules they cheated on paper and They got punished for it, which I guess is the right thing to do.
Speaker 1: you break the rules you face the consequences.
Speaker 1: however I don't think that should be against the rules.
Speaker 0: I have to agree any time there is publicly available information Making an arbitrary rule to make this information no longer publicly available arbitrarily.
Speaker 0: I said that twice.
Speaker 0: it just there's.
Speaker 0: no I mean they could have gotten this information Cheating like this and not gotten caught.
Speaker 0: hire a hobo to film it and then get the tape from him.
Speaker 1: I mean yeah, it's it's really dumb and You know you're basically asking someone.
Speaker 1: alright.
Speaker 1: There's a way that you can get an advantage in this game But we're basically going to arbitrarily decide that you cannot you you cannot gain this advantage.
Speaker 1: That's standing right in front.
Speaker 0: It's not like we're gonna arbitrarily say you can't carry a spanner with you on the field.
Speaker 0: It's like we're gonna arbitrarily say that you can't look at that thing that you're looking at.
Speaker 1: yeah now The real reason I have a problem with this is that basically looking at the signals is not against the rules But videotaping them is well.
Speaker 1: Why are they still using signals like this?
Speaker 1: Why don't they just install headphones in every player's helmet and have encrypted radio broadcasts from the sidelines?
Speaker 1: end of story.
Speaker 1: No one can possibly break the encryption.
Speaker 1: no videotape is gonna.
Speaker 1: Help you no one could possibly hear what you're telling the players.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: End of story.
Speaker 1: the only thing you could possibly do at that point is to like steal.
Speaker 1: You know the other team's like helmet or something or you don't have a spy on their team.
Speaker 1: You know who's got a job working for them.
Speaker 0: wow you know what.
Speaker 0: having a spy on your rival football team's team is A lot like having a character in an MMO in the enemy guild.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know getting caught with that.
Speaker 1: That's actually you know pretty serious stuff that connect is not arbitrary to to block you know.
Speaker 1: so yeah I think this whole thing is kind of dumb.
Speaker 1: I think that if you know if you don't want people seeing your hand signals don't use stupid hand signals.
Speaker 1: technology exists.
Speaker 1: It's
Speaker 0: kind of like when a company opens up an API on the web for something and then as soon as someone uses it for Something they don't like they scream and bitch and piss and moan instead of just not letting the API do things They don't want people to do.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the EU.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty neutral on the EU.
Speaker 0: I mean I generally thought it was a good idea But at the same I'm not gonna get into my opinion of the EU But a man who is very influential on the EU he is the EU justice and security commissioner.
Speaker 0: His name is Franco Frattini.
Speaker 0: He's from Italy.
Speaker 0: I'll get into him in a second is basically saying that the EU should block from the internet all bomb-making material instructions and furthermore not let people search for terms such as Kill genocide or terrorism.
Speaker 1: wait genocide, so I can't if I have to do a report on
Speaker 0: actually Scott there's already a lot of laws like that in Germany where you just can't talk about Nazis in certain ways and you can't have certain books about him just because They have a lot of laws.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but those laws are mostly.
Speaker 1: I mean I know about those laws and I don't like them And you know they're anti freedom, but a lot of them are specifically to you know block people from being Nazis.
Speaker 1: But like you they still learn about Nazis in school, and you can you know still we were all on vacation.
Speaker 1: nothing bad happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly No, basically what this this guy is saying?
Speaker 0: that the EU in order to prevent terror should prevent anyone in the EU from knowing about terrorism.
Speaker 0: oh God this guy this guy it doesn't end there.
Speaker 0: I mean this is crazy and I could go on and on about all the details and the stupid things this guy has said but The rabbit holes a little bit deeper.
Speaker 0: Apparently this is the same guy who was trying to get rid of violent video games in the EU.
Speaker 1: It's I. how old is this guy?
Speaker 1: I'm betting over 70.
Speaker 1: He was born in 1957. oh, it's not these younger than my mom.
Speaker 1: actually he looks like a normal kind of guy But he sounds like a cranky old man who is totally out of touch with the world and doesn't understand things well.
Speaker 1: apparently He doesn't understand security.
Speaker 1: He doesn't understand culture.
Speaker 1: He doesn't understand information He doesn't understand technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well.
Speaker 0: He's the vice president of the European Commission for justice freedom and security and apparently he's against.
Speaker 0: wait He's against freedom.
Speaker 1: He thinks that something that will provide security that won't and He doesn't know the meaning of justice.
Speaker 0: now the even funnier.
Speaker 0: I just I looked up the Wikipedia to find out more about this dude and Apparently he's also a Freemason.
Speaker 0: Alright, that doesn't mean anything because he was outed as a Freemason by the guy who he replaced.
Speaker 0: It doesn't mean who himself was controversial for some reason.
Speaker 1: uh-huh well this guy.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking is pretty control.
Speaker 1: It's not really controversial.
Speaker 1: There is no controversy.
Speaker 1: Well, no the guy is wrong.
Speaker 1: end of story.
Speaker 0: the previous guy was controversial because he was a Roman Catholic.
Speaker 0: So then to get this guy's not Catholic.
Speaker 1: He's he's Italian For some obviously not every Italian is Catholic, but a lot most of them are.
Speaker 1: so that's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: well
Speaker 0: Actually the more I read about all these people and there's like this cluster of just weird stupid crazy Politics in the EU and that all kind of like there's the circle jerk of all this and this guy is kind of a spoke Sticking right out of the center of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Even if a bunch even if the EU is entirely comprised of kooky old men and they all decide this is a good idea It's unenforceable, and maybe they'll give them a fucking wake-up call.
Speaker 0: well You know how they could do it.
Speaker 1: they could simply be like China Yeah, and then everyone will just say hey, you're like China, and maybe they'd feel bad.
Speaker 0: I don't think they'd even realize what that meant.
Speaker 0: yeah, but I just like to point out that way back in the day.
Speaker 0: I mean I was online long before I was on the internet And there was a time in my life where I'd log into prodigy or a friend's AOL And I think man I always hear about the internet, but I want to be on it.
Speaker 0: How do I get on it like?
Speaker 0: I wasn't sure how that works me either.
Speaker 0: and one day?
Speaker 0: I got a service and I paid and I was on the internet and my whole family and like all of our friends my grandparents ever were in the house and we're sitting around the computer and I dialed in and I Connected for the first time of anyone in our family to the internet
Speaker 1: mm-hmm
Speaker 0: and the first thing I did was type into the search bar bomb making instructions Because I'd heard that stuff like that was on the internet And I was really curious.
Speaker 0: and you know what.
Speaker 0: the first four links were 404s, but the fifth one was a bomb Mm-hmm, and you know what.
Speaker 0: I didn't make a bomb and I didn't blow anything up.
Speaker 1: You know at the library you can get the anarchist cookbook.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, the anarchist cookbook recipes mostly are flawed and will kill you.
Speaker 1: I know it's a 10-0.
Speaker 0: Actually a lot of libraries don't carry it either.
Speaker 1: yeah, it was in the library as I was at once.
Speaker 0: It's a really shitty book.
Speaker 1: It is really shitty, but you know it's infamous, and it's bomb making instructions.
Speaker 0: Oh snap panic everybody.
Speaker 0: save the kids the children Things of the day now.
Speaker 1: I said my news and my thing.
Speaker 1: they were both sports related And they are.
Speaker 0: you know I it's very rare for me to hear the term sports related without hearing the word injury right after that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know isn't it like I expected you to say it like today is sports related injury?
Speaker 1: sadly well Or happily depending on your point of view this does not Involve a sports related injury.
Speaker 0: not like back when we had hockey fight week.
Speaker 1: No, so if you've been paying attention at all.
Speaker 1: I'm a fan of the Formula One racing.
Speaker 1: There's actually been some crazy stuff going on in the Formula One racing this season.
Speaker 1: You know some Disqualification from the Constructors Cup by McLaren and such and such for craziness.
Speaker 1: But not gonna get into that you may know that the greatest driver of cars To ever live as a human being is a man named Michael Schumacher And he still lives.
Speaker 1: and this is like the first season in a long time Where he has not been an f1 driver, and he won more championships than an f1 that anyone has ever won and More than likely anyone ever will win.
Speaker 0: I mean not only does he live, but he hungers.
Speaker 1: yes I mean sure.
Speaker 1: he often drove a car that was faster than everyone else's car.
Speaker 1: But when you look at it You know there was at least one other person each year driving the same car as him And he was always faster than they were and not just like always faster like by a tiny.
Speaker 0: He was always consistently a lot faster.
Speaker 1: right now You might think you know you see someone like Tiger Woods play golf and you see someone like Roger Federer play tennis And they're just so much better than everyone else, but it'd be really interesting, but in some ways also Demystifying and disappointing to use like you know scientific data to figure out exactly Why or how they are so much better than everyone
Speaker 0: else.
Speaker 0: I mean this is like say you figured out that I'm making this up Obviously, but Lance Armstrong the only reason he was better at bicycling was because by a genetic Whatever one of his ligaments was one centimeter longer than normal or something.
Speaker 1: because his.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, technically he had humongous lungs.
Speaker 0: Yeah humongous lungs, and he was has humongous lungs.
Speaker 0: He's not dead Yeah, well also there was the fact that I believe he lost one or both testicles.
Speaker 0: I think one to cancer.
Speaker 0: so he takes testosterone supplements, but because it was for a medical thing it was legal.
Speaker 1: I think he only took him for some time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a lot.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm not I can't say for sure cuz I don't follow bicycle racing at all.
Speaker 1: it was mostly his huge lungs.
Speaker 1: He was good at bicycling before he yes.
Speaker 0: He was an amazing bicyclist long before all that.
Speaker 1: but anyway You know you always see these people and you wonder what makes them better.
Speaker 1: And you look at someone like Michael Schumacher where a lot of it is the car.
Speaker 1: You know not all of it, but a lot of it's the car.
Speaker 1: I mean I could beat him in a race if he had a Ford Pinto, and I had a Ferrari He's not that good.
Speaker 0: well Depends cuz in a race like that you might crash.
Speaker 0: I might I might but regardless He's gonna take that Pinto as fast as it can go.
Speaker 1: he was and probably still is the greatest driver of cars ever and he was faster than everyone else.
Speaker 1: and here's a video that explains in Somewhat.
Speaker 1: I guess it's sort of demystifying in a way Because it shows you why he was faster than everyone else.
Speaker 1: And it's kind of sad because now like sort of like the mystique goes away.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's how he did it, and it's not even like a commentary of oh well because of blah and blah and blah Subjective subjective.
Speaker 0: it was like here are the absolute graphs of this and that and that and here yet They use they have something called telemetry which is on all the f1 cars.
Speaker 1: They have all sorts of sensors like monitoring everything in the car like every piece of data.
Speaker 1: They can get about the car the temperatures in different parts of the car the vibrations Exactly how far you're pressing the gas pedal at any time Exactly how much braking you're putting on the temperature of the brakes the temperature of the tires the pressure in the tires.
Speaker 1: You know how much you're steering?
Speaker 1: Everything is measured and sent to a computer.
Speaker 1: so they looked at the Throttle control the brake control and the steering and also the gear shifting of Michael Schumacher driving through the same part of the same racetrack as someone else and Basically he steps on the gas you know more gradually and more controlledly than the other people.
Speaker 1: But at the same time this sort of you know puts the car on edge And he has to make a lot more corrections in his steering.
Speaker 1: so basically he's like steering like a madman and the other guys You know braking a lot more so that he can steer nicely through the turn.
Speaker 1: But as a result Schumacher goes through faster and doesn't lose as much speed and gains the speed right back.
Speaker 0: I mean basically the theory of driving a car around a corner fast is simply that There is a there is for any given car in situation an absolute Perfect most optimal way to get a car around a corner.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean if you go too fast the car will fly off the road and crash and you'll die.
Speaker 0: and if you go too slow You could have gone faster.
Speaker 0: There is an absolute physical limit and theoretically if you had enough information you could calculate that limit exactly For every as long as you accounted for every possible.
Speaker 1: You know factor Some fact theoretically you can't you know account for like a gust of wind or something like that you know.
Speaker 0: and the primary difference between Like say me going around the corner and a guy who's actually race cars going around the corner if we're both trying to go Around as fast as we can is that the closer you get to that optimal line the less margin for error you have.
Speaker 0: I mean Say, I'm I don't know 20 food units away from the
Speaker 1: absolute
Speaker 0: point where my car will spin out And there's no way I can prevent that where I will lose traction no matter what And I can't get closer than that because I don't know how like I'll crash I won't be able to control the car.
Speaker 0: I won't be able to make the fine correction.
Speaker 1: Or you don't have the balls to step on the gas.
Speaker 0: a lot of it.
Speaker 1: You don't have the balls to you know step on the brake half a second later, or it's also.
Speaker 0: I'm not as experienced.
Speaker 0: So if the car goes out of control it takes me longer to react to it And I don't react as well.
Speaker 1: so I need more of especially when the cars go in 200 plus kilometers an hour.
Speaker 0: As a result someone like me needs a much higher Margin of safety where I'll have time to correct and fix my problem and not die.
Speaker 0: Michael Schumacher it drives so close to that edge that you look It's great when you look at the graph of his steering versus the other people.
Speaker 0: the slower people Steer much less like they've got it under control, and they're just going.
Speaker 0: he's so close to crashing at any second.
Speaker 0: He's constantly going left right left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's basically wrestling the car to go when he's pushed it to the absolute limit perhaps over the limit of the car.
Speaker 0: I mean the deal is if if the other driver like say had it like sneezed or something They'd have a much better chance of surviving the Michael Schumacher Just because the fact that he's so close to the edge that any disturbance of his car will immediately make him crash.
Speaker 1: Possibly, but he didn't crash so much.
Speaker 1: He didn't crash zero times.
Speaker 1: He drove fast.
Speaker 1: I mean they show you him going around this turn right.
Speaker 1: he goes around the turn 0.1 seconds faster than the other guy.
Speaker 1: all right 60 laps times.
Speaker 1: how many turns depending on what track they're racing at?
Speaker 1: time is 0.1 seconds He'll finish the race minutes before the other guy.
Speaker 0: the only thing that prevents that is that it's not that easy to pass an f1.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well it depends on what year what cars what track.
Speaker 0: modern f1 in general?
Speaker 0: There's not a whole lot of passing except at the very beginning of the race and then but no matter critical What f1 you're talking about it's not easy to pass Michael Schumacher.
Speaker 0: Well, it's pretty much once he passes someone.
Speaker 0: He's immediately on the next guy's ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that's just it.
Speaker 0: as soon as he passes you you're done, and he ignores you.
Speaker 0: yep Unless there's a pit issue.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 1: one other thing I like about this video is at the very beginning they show they have a way They have like a sky cam like you know filming a car driving around the track.
Speaker 0: That was really cool.
Speaker 1: Really, it's very hard when watching a car race on TV to really get the sensation of speed And how fast the cars are going like you watch NASCAR on TV, and it's just like They don't look like they're going that fast.
Speaker 1: I went to see NASCAR in person a long time ago like and I was in middle school or so and It's really fast and f1 is like 50% faster than that.
Speaker 1: it's crazy, but you really can't tell.
Speaker 1: but this video at the very beginning It's it's the best video I've ever seen that really gives you a sensation of how fast they're going because they're going hella fast goddamn.
Speaker 0: So for once I don't have a YouTube video.
Speaker 0: hooray Apparently there's a kind of lion called an Asiatic lion.
Speaker 1: I thought you were gonna say a Liger.
Speaker 0: no though there is a store an Asiatic liger.
Speaker 0: When I was living in Michigan in sterling heights a liger actually escapes In the area and for like two weeks They like they had police Watching kids coming home from school and generally patrolling and kids were supposed to stay out of the woods because there was a liger somewhere in sterling heights.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but anyway, so Asiatic lions are super endangered.
Speaker 0: There's like three hundred three hundred and fifty of them left in the world and all of them are in one forest in India mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: and The long story short is that they're still not doing so well.
Speaker 0: and you know poachers are getting them and stuff.
Speaker 1: What do they want them for?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I didn't I didn't I didn't really focus on like I can understand poachers going after Elephants because you can make stuff out of ivory and what I stand poachers going after whales because you can make anything out of Medicine.
Speaker 1: oh right right right yeah, I forgot about that.
Speaker 0: see it's one thing.
Speaker 0: no I mean I generally really don't like poaching anyway.
Speaker 0: But it's one thing if you kill an animal to make a piano out of its teeth If you kill an animal to make fake medicine out of it.
Speaker 0: That's like it bothers me on multiple levels.
Speaker 0: It's like not only you're doing something stupid, but you're doing it in order to do something stupider.
Speaker 1: It's weird because I really like that aesthetic of like Teddy Roosevelt hunting in Africa safari kind of action.
Speaker 1: But I don't actually like hunting in Africa safari action.
Speaker 0: see at least with the old Livingston.
Speaker 0: I could respect it more when there's a chance that the animal is gonna win and kill you.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah, definitely Yeah, like I if bullfighting were a 50/50 shot I'd probably be a lot less against bullfighting.
Speaker 0: Great bullfighting is actually kind of dumb to watch and despite I like Hemingway.
Speaker 0: But bullfighting is not cool.
Speaker 0: the way Hemingway tries to make it the aesthetic of bullfighting again is cool.
Speaker 1: Actual bullfighting is lame.
Speaker 1: It should be a fight you versus the bull.
Speaker 1: who wins?
Speaker 1: we don't know I would root for the bull, but anyway, so yeah, you're watching guys get gored is definitely more entertaining.
Speaker 1: Well because they totally deserve it they do.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so uh I I didn't wear those clothes on all that part of the.
Speaker 0: basically the Heart of this issue is that there is little baby tejas And he is a hand-reared Asiatic lion baby that they are raising in order to breed and repopulate the species.
Speaker 0: and There are two pictures of little tejas.
Speaker 0: one is his handler feeding him milk from a bottle and it's adorable and two is him Looking a little bit like our friend Conrad when he wakes up in the morning sitting next to a stuffed tiger.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, this is so cute.
Speaker 0: I would I would give almost anything in the world to be able to pet and play with this little baby line.
Speaker 1: I think it might bite you.
Speaker 0: no it wouldn't because it's really cute and it obviously Actually.
Speaker 0: no, I mean while it wouldn't be domesticated like or domestic atable the way domesticated animals are a Hand-reared lion like that would be generally friendly toward people especially a baby.
Speaker 1: But then how that's the?
Speaker 1: that's the thing I don't understand I guess maybe because I'm not a zoologist, but if your hair if you raise it domestic You know like domesticated like how are you gonna eventually put them back in the wild?
Speaker 1: they won't you know?
Speaker 1: They won't be the same.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure I believe in this case.
Speaker 0: They're not going to put tejas back in the wild.
Speaker 0: They're gonna breed tejas.
Speaker 1: So there's gonna have him make a bunch of babies and put them all out in the.
Speaker 1: what put the babies out in the wild?
Speaker 0: Something like that.
Speaker 1: No one to take care of them.
Speaker 0: Well, they probably breed them with wild.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not sure exactly what they're gonna do.
Speaker 0: All I know is this sort of thing is often successful.
Speaker 1: what they should do is they should train them while they're in domestic.
Speaker 1: You know domesticated to like, you know eat poachers and then now have like a little.
Speaker 1: you know Like a little stuff Teddy Roosevelt there with the safari hat plus honestly it's a bite him.
Speaker 0: and then what I've read a lot Of the things are actually instinctual and they'll take to the wild much better than you'd expect.
Speaker 0: uh-huh, it's kind of like because they're not bred for domestication like domesticated dogs Actually are that you really can't let them be feral easily because they're so Modified through you know centuries and centuries and centuries of breeding by humans.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's it.
Speaker 0: These pictures are really cute.
Speaker 0: I expect to see more pictures of baby tejas.
Speaker 1: All right today we're gonna talk about something that a lot of people seem to be confused about.
Speaker 0: Well one person in our forum.
Speaker 1: Well, no No No, cuz see I thought about doing a show on it a while ago and then someone reminded us and I get emails like pretty much Like clockwork every few weeks or so asking about it and people just don't seem to understand.
Speaker 1: or you know They totally don't get what's going on here And I think it requires an episode of explanation.
Speaker 1: and this is what we're gonna do.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about the Creative Commons that you know.
Speaker 1: We know that at the end of our show if you've ever listened all the way to the end We did not just released under Creative Commons 2.5 attribution non-commercial share alike license.
Speaker 1: Yes So what the hell is the Creative Commons?
Speaker 0: Alright, basically, maybe we should start with copyright.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm doing Alright, so in the United States and most of the rest of the world also you have copyright Which is a law that prevents creative works from being copied.
Speaker 1: So if you make a song someone else takes that song and copies it and sells that copy.
Speaker 1: They can't do that and the way the copyright law is written right now.
Speaker 0: Is that in the United States?
Speaker 1: We're not gonna talk in the United States, but it's also most of the the.
Speaker 1: you know, modern world has very similar laws.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time look up your own laws.
Speaker 0: We can only really speak with any authority about what the way things are in the US.
Speaker 1: Yeah but you know the vast majority of Europe is sort of the same way and there's only very small differences usually like in terms of The number of years.
Speaker 0: let's go to China and see how you feel.
Speaker 1: very chatty.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, but the way it works is let's say rim makes a song rims.
Speaker 1: You made a song Right now without doing anything.
Speaker 1: he did nothing.
Speaker 1: that song he just made is Automatically copyrighted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't have to register your copyright.
Speaker 0: You don't have to write a letter you don't have to any.
Speaker 0: all you have to do.
Speaker 0: if you write something down on a piece of paper a short story on a It's copyrighted technically and legally but you might have a harder time defending it in court.
Speaker 1: If you write, you know If you register it That means it'll be easier to defend in court if you ever get sued or want to sue somebody.
Speaker 1: But it's technically by the law copyrighted.
Speaker 1: as soon as you make a creative work If you write a page of a book copyright it automatically make a web page copyright it automatically?
Speaker 1: No, what?
Speaker 1: as long as you're?
Speaker 1: as long as you didn't infringe on someone else's copy right when you made it.
Speaker 0: now What does this mean?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's actually very simple once you make a work and it is covered and protected by copyright That means that by default No one else in the world has the right to use your work in any way except in a narrow band of exceptions known colloquially as fair use.
Speaker 1: so if I make a song and People want to remix it and I don't do anything.
Speaker 1: I just put my song on an mp3 on the internet, right?
Speaker 1: I don't do anything.
Speaker 1: They're not allowed to even like download the song technically there, you know, they're not allowed to Frickin play the song, you know at a concert.
Speaker 0: They're not allowed to know by putting it in a public place as as best I know.
Speaker 0: There is an implied right to consume it but no right to redistribute it.
Speaker 1: Yes So they can't give a copy of their friends.
Speaker 1: They can't make a remix.
Speaker 1: They can't do anything unless I have to give permission in some way, you know I have to do something to give to allow people to do something by default.
Speaker 1: They could do nothing.
Speaker 1: so I have to Explicitly say okay, you can use it.
Speaker 1: They have to ask me for permission.
Speaker 1: I have to say something in order for them to be allowed to do something with my art or else It's illegal for them to do anything.
Speaker 0: and I mean there's more complicated bits and pieces.
Speaker 0: But that's the gist of it and that's all that matters for our discussion tonight.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So what is the Creative Commons?
Speaker 1: Well right now because the copyright law is the way it is and we don't like it There's still a solution to the problem.
Speaker 1: We want copyright, right?
Speaker 1: I guess ideally to be by default less restrictive than it is.
Speaker 1: However, there's no reason why people who make works of art can't go out and just get rid of these restrictions.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm allowed if I make a work of art, I can just say all the restrictions are gone.
Speaker 0: I can do that Yeah, or I mean just by default you give people nothing and you keep all the rights.
Speaker 0: You might see people say things sometimes like blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: all rights reserved, right?
Speaker 1: Well, the point of Creative Commons is that some rights are reserved.
Speaker 1: when you make a work of art You go to the Creative Commons website and you pick out under what terms you want to give away that work.
Speaker 1: I mean, let's say I'm willing to have my artwork.
Speaker 1: I made a painting and I'm willing to have people share that painting with the whole world share it with all their friends.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: they can remix it.
Speaker 1: They can do whatever they want as long as they say that it was by me.
Speaker 1: They can't be like, oh, yeah, I'm Joe.
Speaker 1: I made this painting that Scott actually made, you know They have to give me credit.
Speaker 1: and if that's all I want I can use a Creative Commons Attribution license and that that basically says I give up all my copyright restrictions except for attribution.
Speaker 0: now I believe they've recently or somewhat recently remade is that there's no non attribution license available on the side.
Speaker 1: Well, you can use the public domain.
Speaker 1: You can choose public domain, which means anything goes.
Speaker 0: Yeah Then a non attribution Creative Commons Yes But not really not really.
Speaker 1: the point of this is that until now and without Creative Commons if you wanted to do something like this You needed a lawyer.
Speaker 1: if you wanted to use someone else's artwork.
Speaker 0: You needed a lawyer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you might think common sense.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll put my thing up and I'll just say on the website Hey anyone can use this however they want But you can't use it in.
Speaker 0: I don't know Nazi propaganda because I don't like Nazis Because you're not a lawyer and you didn't write that whatever you wrote on your website But perfectly if someone really wanted to break your license They probably could if they had a lawyer.
Speaker 1: at the same time if someone put some you know Someone was using some artwork and let's say they put it on their website and they didn't say anything or they said pretty vague Talking and you know and they didn't have legal text and you went and remixed it thinking that that was okay.
Speaker 1: based on what?
Speaker 1: They said if they had a lawyer they could probably sue you and get you because it's a copyright infringer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the issue the deal with Creative Commons is very simply.
Speaker 0: it's a standard way to relinquish or modify many of your inherent Rights to copyright without having to get a lawyer.
Speaker 0: It's a standard boilerplate license.
Speaker 0: You basically say I want to use Creative Commons.
Speaker 0: you pick a bunch of options.
Speaker 0: they're kind of like modules of the Creative Commons and that's it and they give you the shortened version like this is what it means in layman's talk but actually linked from that is the Legal legal legal written by lawyers tested in courts.
Speaker 0: This is the actual license where you're using.
Speaker 1: Yep, and So usually, you know when someone on the internet made something Let's say they make a webcomic and you want to remix the webcomic.
Speaker 1: Usually you're nice and you go and you ask them permission.
Speaker 1: you say hey Can I remix your webcomic?
Speaker 1: I get a lot of emails that I'm talking about here.
Speaker 1: Oh, can we put your podcast in our show?
Speaker 1: You know I want to take a piece of geek nights and put it in my pocket.
Speaker 0: at one point Scott had someone asked if they could Use content he made from I think his audio blog way back in the day in a techno song or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that someone does right.
Speaker 1: I forgot about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just remember that because you told me that I was like wow That was a techno song.
Speaker 0: is that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I forgot about it, but I'll have to go look for it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically the Creative Commons is you know by default with the default laws where all rights are automatically reserved Even if you don't want them to be reserved.
Speaker 1: people have to ask permission.
Speaker 1: The point of Creative Commons is that we come out and we say look don't ask permission.
Speaker 1: if you follow these rules You don't have to ask you do not have to ask don't ask me.
Speaker 1: Just read the license and follow the rules.
Speaker 1: Now if you don't want to follow all the rules of the license because you know We have picked an attribution non-commercial derivatives license.
Speaker 1: So let's say you wanted to you remix geek nights in a commercial way.
Speaker 1: I actually share alike not know derivatives.
Speaker 1: But if you wanted to remix geek nights in a non-commercial way You'd have to ask because in a commercial way not in a non-commercial.
Speaker 1: right right God, okay.
Speaker 1: So let's talk about what all the different licenses you have to choose.
Speaker 1: So I've already talked about attribution.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's rim made this.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: You can't go around saying yeah this this song It's not by Led Zeppelin.
Speaker 1: It's by Scott Rubin, right?
Speaker 1: Sure You have to give credit where credit is due and other than that you can do whatever you want.
Speaker 1: You can remix tweak, you know.
Speaker 1: add-on take away Share with all your friends do whatever the hell you want with it As long as you give credit where credit is due you have to say, you know That part of the music was by Scott or that panel in my comic is drawn by rim or whatever.
Speaker 0: now Non-commercial is another option you can add and it basically says what you might think you can't use this work in a commercial capacity Which actually is not entirely clear-cut.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's hard to say exactly what the line is.
Speaker 0: They're in commercial and non-commercial.
Speaker 1: There is some debate as to exactly what would be commercial and what would not be commercial.
Speaker 1: I mean if I made a song right obviously if you take that song burn it to a CD and sell the CD That's obviously commercial.
Speaker 1: if I make a movie and you sell tickets to see the movie.
Speaker 0: That's obviously commercial All right, but let's say all right.
Speaker 0: I make a song and you put it on your website for free.
Speaker 0: All right, that's non-commercial.
Speaker 0: you put it on your website for free But your website happens to include ads unrelated.
Speaker 0: There's a little gray.
Speaker 0: Let's say you put it on your website and you have to watch an ad to download it.
Speaker 0: That's real close to being over the line.
Speaker 1: over the line now his he is a really sketchy one.
Speaker 1: All right, you make a podcast your podcast.
Speaker 1: you make money from it because you have a sponsor who you know.
Speaker 1: every episode you have A sponsor and it costs like 20 bucks to sponsor an episode.
Speaker 1: Now you want to take like 10 minutes of geek nights and put it in your podcast.
Speaker 1: Ooh That's kind of.
Speaker 1: hmm, is that commercial or not?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: See, I actually I wouldn't worry about that one because that sort of situation is covered by the share alike and no derivatives.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: But that's it.
Speaker 0: And the thing is this is one of the biggest myths about Creative Commons that I hear repeated constantly to annoys me.
Speaker 0: People always argue don't use the non-commercial because it'll fuck you because no one can use it in their Google Adsense blah blah blah and no one will use your thing.
Speaker 0: and People always seem to be under this misapprehension that if you use a Creative Commons restriction That there's no way anyone can use your work in that capacity.
Speaker 1: and the truth is you can just ask the content creator Yeah, Creative Commons is basically saying don't ask me if you follow these rules.
Speaker 1: if you want to break the rules you can ask That's the default.
Speaker 1: That's the way would be without Creative Commons.
Speaker 1: if there were no Creative Commons You'd have to ask for everything.
Speaker 1: So Creative Commons just says you don't have to ask for these things, but you do have to ask for these things.
Speaker 0: So I think the next one that actually I find this one interesting because it's viral is the share alike clause.
Speaker 1: Right now the share alike thing is tricky.
Speaker 1: the read that I'm gonna explain it.
Speaker 1: The share alike is basically sort of taken from the GPL.
Speaker 1: because you know, let's see you a new public license Yes, the canoe public license.
Speaker 1: if you make software with a GPL like Linux or Emacs or whatever And you say give that software out right if someone modifies that software then the software the Modifications they make also have to be GPL.
Speaker 1: So for example, if we did not have the share alike, right?
Speaker 1: somebody could Take geek nights.
Speaker 1: They're allowed to share it with their friends.
Speaker 1: They give us credit.
Speaker 1: They don't sell it, but they give it to their friends, right.
Speaker 1: but they could say give it to their friends with a BSD license or something.
Speaker 1: or they could say make a remix of geek nights, right?
Speaker 1: But the remix of geek nights they could distribute under Some other kind of an Apache like.
Speaker 0: think of this if we didn't have non-commercial then theoretically they could take geek nights Remix it put it on a CD and sell it and we would not have the right to take the remix back and use it.
Speaker 1: Because basically share alike says if you want to make a remix of this right or a derivative work Then your derivative work also has to be creative commons or similar, you know similar enough to our lice.
Speaker 0: it pretty much means the license you distributed under has to at least be as Set up like as good as free as the one I distributed under.
Speaker 0: so you can go more free but you can't go less free.
Speaker 1: Yep, and Basically prevents, you know the non-commercial from being kind of silly.
Speaker 1: because if you say okay You can't you know, take this and set.
Speaker 1: if you say attribution non-commercial, right?
Speaker 1: Someone can't just take your podcast and sell it but or your book and just sell it but they could take your book Remix it and sell the remix.
Speaker 1: So share alike says alright if you want to remix this or some Well, I don't know.
Speaker 0: it'd be tricky if they could.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know exactly if they could sell it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of sketchy but share alike basically what they could do is make a really weird thing about your with your music And then you wouldn't have the right to take it back and use it for something else.
Speaker 0: Yep, and People tend to use the two in tandem the two options, so it doesn't really matter It doesn't?
Speaker 1: the other point of share alike is that it sort of spreads the Creative Commons love Because people are all remixing cool Creative Commons stuff and then it sort of forces them to also Creative Commons their stuff Which.
Speaker 1: and then people use that and Creative Commons that and it spreads the love all around.
Speaker 1: you know, hope.
Speaker 0: hence I said it was viral.
Speaker 1: Yep And all the all the art in the whole world if it keeps being remixes of one another will eventually all be Creative Commons and cool No matter what the copyright laws.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: Another one that some people use particularly commercial works is the no derivatives option.
Speaker 1: The thing with the no derivatives option is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: Don't remix this Yeah, don't alter it.
Speaker 0: Like if we use the no derivatives you could spread geek nights around give it to friends do whatever you wanted in terms of giving It to people but you couldn't modify it in any way.
Speaker 0: You'd have to give the exact file that we gave out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you couldn't like add like a little bumper to the beginning of it.
Speaker 1: You couldn't add audio to the end of it.
Speaker 1: You couldn't cut out like a single second of geek nights and distribute like, you know, the shortened version.
Speaker 1: You couldn't re-encode geek nights into a smaller mp3 and give that out because you've modified the work tech.
Speaker 0: I guess technically yeah I want podcast that.
Speaker 0: or put two podcasts that use this or escape pod and pseudopod because they tell stories From a commercial market, but they release their podcast which has these stories in them under a no derivatives license.
Speaker 0: So you can share the stories in their completeness, but you can't use bits and pieces from the stories or these readings and other projects.
Speaker 1: Yep, I think that's definitely a good license for them.
Speaker 1: Yes, now the hard part is choosing which license is right for you And you know what?
Speaker 1: It totally depends on what you're doing and the website.
Speaker 1: the creative commons website really helps you out in picking which one.
Speaker 1: And you can use almost any combination of the four things we have talked about, you know You can have a an attribution share alike.
Speaker 1: You can have an attribution no derivatives.
Speaker 1: You can have a Attribution non-commercial no derivatives, you know, you can do all sorts of different crazy stuff and it's totally up to you Whatever works best for what you're doing.
Speaker 1: Now they have some other licenses that are special that you're probably not going to use because they're mostly for special case.
Speaker 0: I like the developing nations the developing nations.
Speaker 1: one is very interesting Now the way the world works right is that if you are already a developed nation like the United States, right?
Speaker 1: Intellectual property law helps you because you are generating a lot of copyrighted works and you want to make a lot of money off of them.
Speaker 1: So you don't want people pirating them.
Speaker 1: But if you're a poor country, right and you don't you're not generating a lot.
Speaker 1: You don't have like research scientists or lots of you know, musicians and things and you're mostly you know getting your you know Copyrighted works from other places in the world, you know, you're not.
Speaker 1: you're getting importing books and importing movies and such Copyright law sort of sucks for your country because it makes it.
Speaker 1: you know You can't afford to get all these works of art and you're not producing that many and your country really can't get ahead in the world Because the copyright law is holding you down.
Speaker 1: and You can see a lot of countries like look at China Pirating like crazy pirating like crazy pirating like crazy and that helped them get way up there, you know, China's moving along.
Speaker 1: It's not great, but it's moving along.
Speaker 0: Well in largely due to piracy Yeah, especially of software in the race between India and China to join the like super industrialized world I think China's gonna like up.
Speaker 0: they do.
Speaker 1: But notice as China gets closer and closer to having their leg all the way up They start putting on the intellectual property.
Speaker 1: because they start, you know realizing Hey, you know, we've pirated so many copies of Windows to get where we are.
Speaker 1: But now it would be better off for us because we're you know, we have money now to actually not let people pirate windows.
Speaker 1: so maybe Microsoft China can make some money.
Speaker 1: and the developing nations license is sort of like a recognition of this problem.
Speaker 1: and one thing I know that was licensed this way was Cory Doctorow's like books at least one or two of them.
Speaker 1: and the way it works is you make a book say and You put the developing nations license on there.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna get into all the details But basically the book is not free in some place like the United States But the book is totally free and like the Congo.
Speaker 1: so that way Developing nations who need more works of art and you know can't really afford they need to get ahead in the world Can freely access and distribute your art.
Speaker 1: but places where people aren't poor And they have plenty of money to buy books have to buy your book and they can't just be sharing it.
Speaker 1: And it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I don't think it apply, you know, it doesn't apply to too many works of art But it does.
Speaker 1: it applies to quite a few and I think it's really interesting.
Speaker 1: You want you want to go over the other ones?
Speaker 0: Not too much.
Speaker 0: I don't want to bore anyone plus remember and we should probably say this and stress it very much We know jack and shit about laws.
Speaker 0: We are not lawyers.
Speaker 1: Yep There's I think there's one that that basically says I'm going to follow the copyright law.
Speaker 1: the founders copyright one Which says I'm going to follow the original copyright law of the United States.
Speaker 1: the founders got.
Speaker 0: I like that one just for.
Speaker 1: so it Basically, it says yeah, I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: you know, this is copyrighted in full but 14 or 28 years from now It's gonna be public domain Instead of you know, what 90 years after you die something like that 75 years after you die.
Speaker 0: I don't even know anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so basically says this is copyrighted and for real the whole thing You can't do anything with it without permission, but 14 years from now You'll be able to do whatever you want with no restrictions at all.
Speaker 1: That's the way it was back in the 1800s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean anyway to sum up we're not lawyers.
Speaker 0: That was just.
Speaker 0: we were trying to explain this mostly because a lot of people ask us to use geek nights all the time And the answer is it's all Creative Commons.
Speaker 0: Just look at our license and follow those rules.
Speaker 1: Yes, you only have to follow three rules.
Speaker 1: You have to say it was geek nights and give us credit.
Speaker 1: You can't make any money by using it.
Speaker 1: You know, you don't want someone else getting rich off geek nights before we do.
Speaker 1: and if you're gonna you know Share it with people.
Speaker 1: You got to share it with the coolness.
Speaker 1: You can't be sharing it with the assholiness.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Don't know?
Speaker 1: one should ask me permission unless they want to break one of these rules.
Speaker 0: granted.
Speaker 0: We're pretty open to that.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, if you ask permission, I'll probably say yes depending on what you're doing.
Speaker 1: There's very little.
Speaker 0: someone could say they want to do with our show that we would say no to.
Speaker 1: it's just we.
Speaker 1: you know If you're doing something that breaks these rules, I just want to know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't want it.
Speaker 1: I don't want you doing it without asking.
Speaker 1: So yeah, anyone who has failed to understand the Creative Commons.
Speaker 1: Thanks to our very terse You know, I guess possibly inaccurate possibly inaccurate Discussion that we have at the end of every episode.
Speaker 1: if that's not enough for you You should understand now and if you don't understand now You go to the creative commons org website and then you will fully understand.
Speaker 0: if you still don't understand I guess just email Lawrence Lessig.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's not doing that anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he could probably still give you an earful.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't think he would though you got other things to do.
Speaker 1: Well, he's working on fighting corruption instead of copy right now.
Speaker 1: And I guess joy Ito isn't is in sort of in charge of the Creative Commons now Which is all he's also a good guy.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you can watch plenty of videos of Lawrence Lessig on YouTube that are Creative Commons licensed Explaining the Creative Commons like they're.
Speaker 0: actually he's a pretty fascinating guy.
Speaker 0: I'd recommend you learn about him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Lawrence Lessig is a really awesome like lawyer guy.
Speaker 1: He's like a lawyer hero.
Speaker 0: All right, and one final note.
Speaker 0: I think we're done for tonight But I just like to warn everyone that the beta of Team Fortress 2 comes out next week.
Speaker 0: I hope geek nights will still be around.
Speaker 1: it is in your best interest to petition valve to have this game like destroyed because Otherwise it is likely this game will destroy geek night.
Speaker 1: You have to decide between Team Fortress 2 and geek nights that that that might be the.
Speaker 0: tell you what Scott.
Speaker 0: I'll quit my job and you can support me while I play this game.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: if you like what you hear you Can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.