Speaker 0: It's Wednesday June 20th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we have the audacity to review neon Genesis Evangelion.
Speaker 0: Let's do this This weekend and this weekend only for at least another about 365 days in other words on July.
Speaker 0: no, it's June June.
Speaker 0: I think 23 and 24 possibly also the 22 I don't remember is The museum of comic and cartoon art arts festival.
Speaker 0: and no that is not redundant saying arts twice Because art is in the name of the museum, and it's also the museum's art festival.
Speaker 1: Don't worry about it Just call it mocha and be done with it.
Speaker 0: Yes, even though mocha is the name of the museum, but regardless.
Speaker 0: This is the perhaps only Only Comic convention.
Speaker 0: that doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean we went last year and not only was I pleasantly surprised and somewhat overwhelmed, but it was downright awesome.
Speaker 0: basically what the mocha arts festival is is Imagine an artist's alley.
Speaker 0: But the artist's alley is all comic creators and everyone sits at their own little table And they sell their comic wares whatever sort of comic related business.
Speaker 0: They've got you know some podcasters artists writers.
Speaker 0: Whoever some retailers publishers.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: and It's in this many ballrooms in the puck building in New York City And you just walk around and you go to a table and you see a comic there and the person sitting behind the table Is the person who makes the comic and they're like hi?
Speaker 0: How you doing.
Speaker 0: and the best part about mocha?
Speaker 0: I think what really sets it apart from all the other comic conventions is that?
Speaker 0: You go there, and you see like this big-name guy like the guy who makes DMZ right he's gonna be there Yep, or the only guy the only guy he's pretty big or he eyes no award-winning alley guy.
Speaker 0: And they're standing there, and you could talk to them and sitting next to them at the next table is some kid who printed out his comic at Kinko's this morning, and it's still stapling it together.
Speaker 0: and When you have like these top of the like these professional people sitting next to these complete amateurs on an equal playing field It's super awesome because it's all about the arts and not about the business or the collecting or any other bullshit.
Speaker 1: That's the best part about mocha aside from the fact that everyone there was really friendly and there really weren't any scary fanboys around.
Speaker 1: But yeah Everyone's cool Indie comic type most of all was the fact that when I walked up to a table and just like started looking at a comic.
Speaker 1: They didn't immediately try the hard sell or try to force me to buy their comic.
Speaker 1: They just kind of sat there and let me browse and didn't pester me every comic con.
Speaker 1: I've gone to the comic artists practically demand that I buy a comic and they're really pushy.
Speaker 1: I really hate that.
Speaker 0: yeah when you go to comic cons like a wizard world or you know any other type of place I walked away from tables at wizard world.
Speaker 1: Yes I'd pick something up and they'd be like hey you're gonna buy that.
Speaker 0: you can buy all these - a lot of those places Are very business II.
Speaker 0: they have dealers rooms.
Speaker 0: They have you know all these other things Whereas mocha is just artists who want to hang out.
Speaker 0: mostly They're more there to see each other than they are to see you.
Speaker 0: a lot of them and There's like a whole bunch of awesome Like after parties, but I don't know if we can go to any cuz then we won't be able to get home.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, granted we could just sleep on the streets of New York City.
Speaker 1: It's not like we haven't done that or not sleep?
Speaker 0: stay at the after party till 5 a.m.
Speaker 0: Then take the train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think we'll wait one more year.
Speaker 1: We've got enough crap to deal with regarding cons this year.
Speaker 1: I know I mean Oh - con I'm not gonna say much.
Speaker 1: It's still not all set in stone and it's getting down to the wire, yep, so this Saturday pretty much all day.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll send I'll put a link to the to the website about the arts festivals.
Speaker 0: not even a convention It's an arts festival in the the front with the website and the show note whatever thing where we usually put the news and things of the day.
Speaker 0: and If you are anywhere new in New York City, and you like comic books even a little bit It's worth your time to go especially because it's really cheap really cheap.
Speaker 1: also I would like to know cuz I'm holding in my hand that I think the highlight of the con was.
Speaker 1: there was one table with these Artists and they made a bunch of pac-man s ghosts and each one was entirely unique from all the others and they were just free.
Speaker 0: So we both picked one up dutifully and I suppose people better be there so I could find out who the hell that is.
Speaker 1: It was brilliant cuz.
Speaker 1: I remembered them very clearly.
Speaker 1: I was very excited about.
Speaker 0: they was like the best business card ever except that I forgot who they were Their name or their website on the back or something and the ghost isn't saying or at least like a word That I could search on Google and find them.
Speaker 1: the ghost just stares at me with his kind of vacant ghost eyes.
Speaker 0: My ghost does the same thing.
Speaker 0: He's just as useless.
Speaker 1: I love him, but I wish I knew who it was so I could give them some props on the show.
Speaker 0: little necrophilia for him.
Speaker 0: They hey ghosts can be hot.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, news time.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if I talked about this last week or not.
Speaker 0: I felt like I talked about on the show and if I did talk about it on the show That's just tough shit.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about the show twice, but Because I've talked about this is like everyone here like ten times and I didn't see it linked to on our website So I assume I did not talk.
Speaker 1: we have this problem more and more where we'll talk about something independent of the show and then we'll do the show and we won't remember if we talked about that on the show or not because as Much as you might not believe it
Speaker 0: The way
Speaker 1: we talk on the show is almost exactly the same as the way we talk to each other in person.
Speaker 0: Yes, so this is show.
Speaker 0: it's a new anime that's on TV called bokurano and it's hot it's.
Speaker 0: it's like our favorite show.
Speaker 0: now I think we talked about the show in a previous episode.
Speaker 0: In fact, I know we talked about the show to to use the Dave and Joel is the business.
Speaker 0: So if you want to know about the show, we did a previous episode and you can go look it up or whatever.
Speaker 0: But the story is the original Manga ka mohiro Akito who also made shadow star narutaru and vendor mayor no Tsubasa.
Speaker 0: By the way shadow stars pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really like shadow star, but we'll talk a little bit about that in a minute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this is a manga car who makes manga We like made the manga for bokurano, which I don't think is in English yet But when it is I'm gonna buy it now until bokurano and until this news.
Speaker 1: and when I took our friend Alex is really into shadow star and I didn't know much about.
Speaker 1: I didn't realize but I kind of guessed that Shadowstar was the same guy as this and now that I've seen three independent things that this person has done Little bit of a dark streak.
Speaker 1: Yeah little bit that these things really all start out not so dark Relative to how dark they guys.
Speaker 0: the guys formula seems to be that you have sort of normal characters.
Speaker 0: They're not like super super cute, but they're also not super super dark.
Speaker 0: They're you know typical anime very human realistic characters But anime style with some bright colors and not stupidly bright colors like moe but just regular bright.
Speaker 1: I really like the style.
Speaker 0: Yep, then he throws in like one cute thing like some like star.
Speaker 0: or what's the guys?
Speaker 0: dung beetle?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah dung beetle, right some weird creature.
Speaker 0: That's pretty cute and strange.
Speaker 0: and then he throws in some incredibly dark actual plot.
Speaker 0: That's like a big dark evil robot.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's actually freaking scary and it's a little worse.
Speaker 1: I mean Sailor Moon starts out light and gets kind of dark as it goes on and darker and darker.
Speaker 1: This starts darker than Sailor Moon ends.
Speaker 1: and you think all right, I'm comfortable with this level of darkness and Much like now and then here and there it's just a rocket straight down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the reason that his his darkness works really well is because other shows in manga They're just dark likes from the bat off the bat and it's just like black all the way across.
Speaker 0: This guy maintains this contrast between the cute creature the normal looking characters Who you can relate to and this dark backdrop and the contrast is very unsettling.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Plus it's just.
Speaker 1: It's so.
Speaker 1: the characters are generally so realistic and normal with normal problems and they have normal emotions and they react to things Kind of the way you would expect people to react and it's just.
Speaker 1: really you don't feel like it should be as dark as it Is and it even though even if you know, it's coming it takes you off guard a little bit Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So this got the mangaka, right?
Speaker 0: He wrote this manga and a guy named Horiyuki Morita who is the director of the cat returns, so he's not a bad director.
Speaker 0: He is directing the bokurano anime which we were enjoying as we were watching it And I guess we're still watching it which is coming from Gonzo which you know.
Speaker 1: So we know that at least the first half is gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, it's been awesome so far.
Speaker 0: But this news story is that the director of the anime Does not like the direction the manga went into and he asked permission from the manga Creator if he could change it and if you know the plot of bokurano You could pretty much guess what's being changed and whatnot and it's
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: Apparently the guy making the anime has somewhat of a problem with just killing children indiscriminately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who would have guessed who would've guessed?
Speaker 0: so while this doesn't necessarily like a bunch I know a bunch of people are gonna be screaming like blah blah blah now that my anime sucks not gonna watch it.
Speaker 0: Actually, I got two things two feelings on it.
Speaker 0: one feeling is that this is kind of good because now You know when the anime and the manga are exactly the same.
Speaker 0: There's no point in doing both.
Speaker 0: That's why I didn't really watch the Death Note anime, even though I really like the Death Note anime.
Speaker 1: It's just I know the story unless it deviates all I'm gonna watch.
Speaker 1: you're like the fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna watch the scene where someone shoots at someone with the sniper rifle from the helicopter Yep, and it's like, you know in in the Death Note anime.
Speaker 0: It's I know I've heard it's exactly the manga.
Speaker 0: So what am I missing if I read the manga?
Speaker 0: nothing.
Speaker 0: I have better things to do with my time.
Speaker 1: It would have been kind of cool if I hadn't.
Speaker 1: you know If I hadn't read the manga Death Note would probably my favorite anime right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time I know the story of the manga at least the general premise and if that premise is sort of what drives the show and if That premise is gone.
Speaker 0: I really wonder what they're gonna do and I wonder if it's gonna be good or not.
Speaker 1: I really like the condition that the mangaka put on the anime person in terms of if they're allowed to do What they want to do and he says you can do it as long as you don't use magic.
Speaker 1: So he can't just kind of deus ex machina.
Speaker 1: Oh and everything's great.
Speaker 1: He has to kind of figure a way out and if anything we've talked a lot about how oftentimes the most creativity comes out of constraints and limitations and I have a hope that the director of the anime might go in a really interesting direction and That now I'll be able to read the manga and enjoy it.
Speaker 1: and I actually really want to read it now that I know Looking for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as soon as it comes out.
Speaker 0: I'll be on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Sadly the narutaru anime or manga at least kind of got cut off when everyone realized just how dark it gets If we had enough money, and if you got if anyone would don't ask enough money, we'd probably buy it and then translate it.
Speaker 0: Oh Probably.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: anyway It's gonna be interesting to see if the anime Starts to suck as a result of the director not liking what the story is yeah, or if The anime is actually good but different from the manga.
Speaker 1: All I know is what I've seen to the anime so far.
Speaker 0: I really like yep, me too.
Speaker 1: I mean that and claymore are the only things I'm watching and even claymore is starting to fall off Even though I love it.
Speaker 1: I just don't have time.
Speaker 0: I'm watching the two terrors on the train.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm gonna have to catch up on that later.
Speaker 0: It's actually good because it doesn't really deviate.
Speaker 0: it does but it's it's sort of just.
Speaker 0: they add a whole bunch and they really flesh out because they only had three volumes of manga to work with.
Speaker 0: so they make up a whole bunch of stuff to fill in the Gaps, but it's not meaningless stuff, but it's not.
Speaker 0: it doesn't change like the main happenings of the plot really Yeah, plus I'm spending all my time.
Speaker 1: Finally watching the rest of gunkutsu.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, which I mean I'm a big fan of.
Speaker 0: tell me when you get to like the last two DVDs.
Speaker 0: All right, I just watched like 23 episodes.
Speaker 1: Here's how sad it is.
Speaker 1: I just got up to the point at which I stopped watching the fan subs when they were coming out Which is when Haiti almost falls off the ledge in the balcony.
Speaker 1: Like that was the last episode I'd seen and I just watched it again.
Speaker 1: So now I'm really pumped to watch the rest.
Speaker 0: Alright, yeah, tell me when you get to the robots.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So anyway now there has been some talk about this golden ticket going on at Anime Expo and Frankly, I want to wait until there's a lot more information.
Speaker 1: I might even wait until after Anime Expo to talk about that Because I'd like to be able to say how it went in addition to how I feel about it.
Speaker 1: But I did notice this interesting story.
Speaker 1: I just want to bring it up because it's kind of related to us a little bit.
Speaker 1: but here on anime news network, it turns out that Lionsgate is reanimating speed racer, which a lot of people knew and apparently they're doing it with Animation collective a New York animation studio and it just so happens that Emily worked there for a while.
Speaker 0: I think that's it Yeah, and they're pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Also, I was reading this news and I find it interesting that they very pointedly say I'm just gonna quote this here this 2008 Reincarnation features the original speed racers son.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: Here's the part that bothers me who drives a non gas-guzzling Mach 6?
Speaker 1: Now why would you bring that up in a news article for one that has nothing to do with the story at all?
Speaker 1: Because the story here is the animation studio and everyone that's doing it not.
Speaker 1: Hey, it's a hybrid car or whatever.
Speaker 1: and - is This really just like water world where the bad guys happen to be smokers and they smoked cigarettes?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, is?
Speaker 1: they smoke cigarettes.
Speaker 1: They're bad guys.
Speaker 1: Is this some sort of heavy-handed?
Speaker 1: Unsubtle environmental message as opposed to the much more subtle and awesome way that say Miyazaki would do that?
Speaker 0: It's?
Speaker 0: I just don't.
Speaker 0: it's stupid.
Speaker 1: yeah regardless I'm kind of interested in this because I kind of like speed racer But I like the idea of speed racer more than I actually like watching speed race.
Speaker 0: Yes, actually reading this news story reminded me.
Speaker 0: So when I got home, I watched the English speed racer opener and I watched the original Japanese speed racer opener, which I had never realized I had never seen.
Speaker 0: and first of all The the Japanese speed racer opener is much longer and includes a lot more stuff like this big scene of driving through the wilderness.
Speaker 0: So these animals and elephants how much longer?
Speaker 1: what it's like 20 minutes like a whole minute longer.
Speaker 0: Ah, it's crazy.
Speaker 0: and The song you can tell how they derive the English song from the Japanese one.
Speaker 0: but the Japanese lyrics and singing is.
Speaker 0: I Enjoy that more because it's you know, got those Japanese guys singing in there.
Speaker 0: You know the way they sing for old giant robot shows and stuff.
Speaker 1: I I really like that kind of me too.
Speaker 1: But even though I know in my heart that it's kind of lame, but that almost intensifies my like for it.
Speaker 0: Yep But the thing is the American opener starts out with that And I really like that noise.
Speaker 0: that's good noise.
Speaker 0: But the Japanese opener starts with like this cool jazz riff action and it's hard to pick one.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess the Japanese version is better overall.
Speaker 0: But the American opener is not without merit, but the court the singing in the American opener while that song, you know Here he comes Right while that song is, you know a classic.
Speaker 0: It's really corny.
Speaker 1: I just remember.
Speaker 1: listen to that just reminded me.
Speaker 1: remember that speed racer initial D music video.
Speaker 1: Yeah to that song.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I was suddenly reminded to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Alright sure Things of the day.
Speaker 1: All I got to say is balls of steel balls balls Steel.
Speaker 1: it's time to kick ass and chew bubble gum and I'm all out of gum.
Speaker 0: I will tear off your head and fuck down your.
Speaker 1: I believe it was shit.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, whatever.
Speaker 1: That's just kind of creepy where you went with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, but there's one.
Speaker 1: It's one thing to degrade your opponent after you know beating them much like the classic stand over your opponent and repeatedly hit crouch.
Speaker 1: yeah, I Remember thinking I was so clever when I did that once way back in the day and like action quake I was like man, I'm totally humiliating him.
Speaker 1: No one else ever thought to do this before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one ever thought to shoot the guy after he's dead.
Speaker 1: That was a big deal in action quake.
Speaker 1: He's only had like four bullets anyway.
Speaker 1: but now Basically the point of my thing of the day is that there are some people Who might otherwise be good.
Speaker 1: people might be intelligent might lead normal lives but when confronted with the Internet a world in which people can be anonymous and we all know from John Gabriel's greater internet fuckwad theory that anonymity on The internet is a dangerous quantity.
Speaker 0: It usually just turns the internet into a shitcock generator Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: I remember our old CS server shit cock list and That was the best CS server ever.
Speaker 1: I was I mean we could only have like six people on it or it was too slow.
Speaker 1: So we'd start getting packet loss and the only map we could run without it crashing was icy world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was full 24/7 all the time.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: We'd kick because the ping was so low.
Speaker 1: Yep, we'd kick people off every time we wanted to play.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, and for some reason we never set the limit to six.
Speaker 1: the limit was always like ten.
Speaker 1: So we had to keep kicking people to keep the ping down.
Speaker 0: No, I set the limit lower eventually not right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember constantly kicking people to keep the packet loss from coming.
Speaker 1: But anyway, there are some people You know normally normal people but when confronted with a shit cocker on the internet Aren't quite aware of the fact that the the reach of their power does not extend through the wires Into that other person's physical space.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's kind of like I don't know Star Wars and Someone's making trouble way out in the Outer Rim and the Empire is like yeah We'll get you but it's gonna take the Empire like months to get a fleet out there.
Speaker 0: They can't do anything to the guy making trouble in the Outer Rim Especially if that guy has the Millennium Falcon, which is so fast that they'll be gone by the time the Empire gets course.
Speaker 1: That was probably a bad example because we all know that Vice Admiral Thrawn was out there kicking ass left and right.
Speaker 0: We that we do.
Speaker 0: I gotta read those books someday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most of what I know about Admiral Thrawn I learned from Wikipedia and TIE fighter.
Speaker 1: Yep, but there are people out there who just when confronted with someone who is Are you saying it for the third time?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm going more specific.
Speaker 1: when someone's griefing them on the internet They just can't take it and it breaks down their AT field and they just lose it.
Speaker 1: Yeah now this video.
Speaker 1: Basically, someone makes a soundboard of Duke Nukem.
Speaker 1: And if you might remember Duke Nukem doesn't have many things to say.
Speaker 1: Balls of steel And in ventrilo at least this ventrilo server, which is obviously being run by some mother for like her son's clan somewhere You can't seem to really tell who's saying what.
Speaker 1: so someone is logged in and basically Being Duke Nukem.
Speaker 1: and he only says Duke Nukem things when this mother says anything and it starts out kind of lame.
Speaker 1: But just bear with it because once you realize how insane this woman is getting it's quite entertaining.
Speaker 0: Why first of all, what kind of piece of shit is ventrilo that you can't tell who's saying what?
Speaker 0: TeamSpeak You can tell who's saying what.
Speaker 1: so ventrilo- Counter-strike I can tell who's saying what.
Speaker 1: not that it matters because they're all saying the same thing as shut the fuck up you faggot noob.
Speaker 0: But you can't tell who's saying what in ventrilo or I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've never used ventrilo.
Speaker 0: So maybe you can tell who's saying what.
Speaker 0: and this lady is just so stupid that she can't tell who's saying what.
Speaker 1: this lady Exemplifies the Set of steps that a person on the internet who doesn't realize that they are impotent against a griefer goes through.
Speaker 1: Because at one point right away, she basically says yeah, I know who you are You're banned and the guy keeps talking.
Speaker 1: so obviously she was lying.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the best part is I am reasonably certain that the person doing this was either her son himself I think it was the son or someone closely involved to all of this and I think it was a staged Attempt to drive his mother over the edge.
Speaker 0: I think it was indeed and actually it's pretty funny when the mother leaves for a minute and the other guy is like yeah That was pretty hilarious until she freaked out.
Speaker 1: So balls of steel.
Speaker 0: yes, just just I guess listen to this.
Speaker 1: and no you got to watch it because every time Duke Nukem speaks It cuts to this smarmy looking picture of Duke Nukem.
Speaker 0: This is why I've been waiting for Duke Nukem forever.
Speaker 0: if you haven't if you've never experienced Duke Nukem before this will be your first.
Speaker 1: Duke Nukem is quiet.
Speaker 1: I mean Duke Nukem 3d was a really good game.
Speaker 0: I gotta say it was if the big news if people don't remember when quake one and Duke Nukem 3d They both came out and it was a hotly contested debate as to which one was the game.
Speaker 1: Duke Nukem was hot shit, and I played it.
Speaker 0: all the many video game magazines are like quake is crap.
Speaker 0: sure It looks a little better, but it's a crap game compared to the awesomeness that is Duke 3d.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Duke 3d was a lot more in the doom line in terms of how gameplay progressed And there was a lot of really sick humor in it.
Speaker 0: It was a good game.
Speaker 1: granted the humor was all aimed at people between the ages of 12 and 12.5.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, maybe 13.
Speaker 1: Maybe 13
Speaker 0: all right, so if you're an a nine or manga readers watcher Yeah, if you're an experiencer and enjoyer of Japanese Culture and artistic works that are delivered over here to the United States or to whatever country you may live in
Speaker 1: You
Speaker 0: might notice that Japanese people they like to apologize.
Speaker 0: They apologize just about everything.
Speaker 0: They're like oh my god.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry got in a car accident.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: I did better than you on the test.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: You're stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sorry I bought the last DS in the store here.
Speaker 1: You can have I guess except for the rape of Nanking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except for that everything else everything else they apologize profusely and often with varying levels of apology.
Speaker 0: This video here is quite awesome because it's dual purpose.
Speaker 0: on the one hand It shows you all the different styles of Japanese apology all the different degrees of apology from the simple You know who I bumped into you to the ooh.
Speaker 0: I failed the the hit and now you please don't cut off my finger.
Speaker 0: And it shows you how to correctly bow and apologize in the different ways.
Speaker 0: But it is also humorous if you zoom in on it cuz in YouTube It's kind of zoomed out.
Speaker 0: you need to zoom in on it somehow go full screen or something.
Speaker 0: they explain the situations in which you would use the different types of bow and how to execute them correctly and It's pretty funny, especially the the ninja apology.
Speaker 0: And So this is worth watching.
Speaker 0: whether you are confused about Japanese apologizing or whether you are familiar with it and want to laugh.
Speaker 0: They also give the correct Japanese names for all the different types of apologies so you can learn them.
Speaker 0: Maybe if you're trying to learn Japanese might be really useful.
Speaker 0: I've ever go to Japan because or if you're watching an anime and someone does one of the Apologies and then you just yell out the name of it and see who laughs I don't know.
Speaker 1: just somehow I get the impression that when I do finally visit Japan while I'm going to have a great time And while I'm going to try to be very culturally aware I am pretty much a hundred percent sure that I'm going to offend a fair number of people at some point depending on how long I am there.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm gonna offend people.
Speaker 0: Just see me.
Speaker 0: They're gonna come say you and be like that guy.
Speaker 1: that guy's not a team player.
Speaker 1: Not at all.
Speaker 1: Look at him Look at him go.
Speaker 0: Yeah Apparently, I heard that there was.
Speaker 0: I was reading actually a story today about how Akihabara is getting all this tourists going on from other Countries, right?
Speaker 1: They're probably all anime fans from America.
Speaker 0: They showed like a picture of a French guy who visited there and he was looking at some perverted statues.
Speaker 0: But basically they set up some sort of like cultural center there or something that was designed by the Pokemon guy you know to sort of have tourists go to and Apparently like 7% of its traffic is from tourists, which is a big deal.
Speaker 0: apparently like that's a lot.
Speaker 1: Alright, I think we've delayed long enough.
Speaker 1: every now and then on a show like this There's an episode that you'd expect us to do a thing You'd expect us to talk about and yet much like the other podcasts or reviewers or whatever We know you can't we kind of hold out and wait to do these things Because you don't want to screw it up and there's a lot to say and a lot of people are waiting Waiting, I know of you personally to jump all over us about anything.
Speaker 1: We may or may not say over the course of it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and if you haven't noticed, I mean, there's probably some podcasts out there and that have you know, God and done Certain shows, you know that or manga that are super important and super popular.
Speaker 1: Yeah I remember Daryl Surratt's gushing love fest before we talked about.
Speaker 1: do you remember love?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah And not a good movie.
Speaker 0: I'm not a fan.
Speaker 0: I mean, I would like macross almost more than anything but I'd like the TV show and I'm not a fan of compilation movies.
Speaker 0: No, which is what do you remember?
Speaker 0: love is but if you like macross just watch the TV show.
Speaker 0: What's the point of that move?
Speaker 0: You don't have time I guess but it's worth your time.
Speaker 1: I skipped most of the middle of the TV show.
Speaker 0: you suck.
Speaker 1: Well, mostly because you watch it when I wasn't home and I gave up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna watch it again soon someday, but no tonight and I can't wait for the argument.
Speaker 1: I think our friend Conrad in particular is gonna jump down our throats in a second.
Speaker 1: He's been waiting for this forever because we have different.
Speaker 0: is he really?
Speaker 1: I didn't think he was Has the exact opposite opinion of the show that we do pretty much step for step.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh tonight We are going to talk about Shin Seiki Evangelion aka Neon Genesis Evangelion one of the most popular anime one of the iconic anime in America.
Speaker 0: This thing's like 12 or 13 years old One of the most important anime ever in terms of anime histories and modern animes.
Speaker 1: now before we continue no spoilers Don't worry.
Speaker 1: We're reviewing this like we review anything else.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna spoil anything.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna talk about what happens.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna you know Talk about what this show is why we like it what we didn't like about it all those normal things and maybe a lot of information about the show because It's kind of hard to set the record straight on things granted not related things.
Speaker 0: But like what episodes do you watch?
Speaker 0: kind of things?
Speaker 1: Yes, particularly in the end.
Speaker 0: Yes, we have a confusing end.
Speaker 1: We have to mention something about the movies and the other movies and the re-releases of the movies and the manga and the potential Live-action video game the potential live-action.
Speaker 1: There's been potential for like a decade.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, and two part of the reason we're reviewing this now is that way back way back.
Speaker 1: Well after we did our final thoughts episode on Big O to a lot of people were clamoring for us to do more final thoughts episodes and Our thinking was we really don't want to spoil the show That a lot of people haven't seen because then they either can't listen to our episode or they have to just let the show Be ruined.
Speaker 1: So as a result, we're reviewing Ava partly so that in a month or so when everyone who wants to see it has had a chance We can do our final thoughts
Speaker 0: and also because I haven't seen the show in like I don't know four years And I have to watch it again to do a final.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes but actually it's good because we know a lot of people who haven't seen Ava and Also by not having seen it just now It's not gonna be easy to go off on specific plot tangents that we really don't
Speaker 0: Worry about me spoiling anything because I haven't seen this show since college in college.
Speaker 0: I think freshman year I watched it all the way through on VHS and then we marathoned it again later.
Speaker 0: And that's all.
Speaker 0: that's the.
Speaker 0: I've only ever seen the whole thing twice on VHS and that's it.
Speaker 1: Well, you can spoil Ava but in the same way that you can spoil any show that has Something so unbelievable happened at the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah It'd be difficult for me to spoil it, you know, if I wasn't trying to it's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like I could slip up and be like, oops.
Speaker 0: I forgot that that was a secret.
Speaker 0: Yep But anyway, I probably just forgot it.
Speaker 1: period Ava Whether or not you like it or you hate it.
Speaker 1: You think it's brilliant.
Speaker 1: You think it's crap.
Speaker 1: I just want to keep in mind while we talk about it that one This came out a long time ago and it set a lot of precedent.
Speaker 0: Yeah a long time ago as in less than 20 years.
Speaker 1: Oh, you mean ancient times like the 90s.
Speaker 1: I mean back then there were dragons as far as we knew in most of the world.
Speaker 1: But back, I mean a lot of the things that people say Oh Ava's so cliche.
Speaker 1: It really set a lot of precedents.
Speaker 1: and well Even if you don't like Ava you at least have to admit that Ava is a very important anime in terms of how anime has Evolved now.
Speaker 1: Ava was directed by an interesting fellow named Hideaki Anno.
Speaker 1: We're not going to talk about the story behind him.
Speaker 1: If you want to know more about that check out anime world order.
Speaker 1: They'll go into great detail about that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: suffice to say the man is either brilliant or insane or both probably both.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of those evil mad genius kind of guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and despite his nuttiness I think I think that he is one of the main reasons that Ava is what it is Regardless of how you take that like any others evil genius, you know They invent some crazy evil robot or something and the robot is really cool.
Speaker 0: But the actual evil genius is someone you never want to talk to.
Speaker 1: So very briefly because I think a lot of people have seen Ava.
Speaker 1: But just in case you haven't the story is actually fairly simple in terms of what's going on on the face value.
Speaker 1: What is the plot the seed of the plot?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Here's the story already.
Speaker 0: You have this earth and you have this city and On earth, there's some people living in this city.
Speaker 1: I think you can start a little bit less broad.
Speaker 1: Okay, okay I think I. basically I think you're gonna explain this really badly So I'm gonna stand by to re-explain it.
Speaker 0: these people have some robots And the reason they have robots is because they're under attack by these angels.
Speaker 0: But they're not angels with wing-a-lings and you know cupid bows and arrows.
Speaker 0: they're just giant horrible monsters that come from the sky sort of randomly and In each episode or in most of the episodes.
Speaker 0: And my angel comes down So they get in their robots and they have to fight it off or else it's gonna destroy their city and it's not gonna be good,
Speaker 1: okay, so basically normal earth fast forward a little bit, you know technology is advancing about modern times is when it's really set and the Dead Sea Scrolls have Prophesized that God will send the angels down to destroy mankind and all sorts of other things and a semi shadow Organization of governments has gotten together Basically believing this to be somewhat true
Speaker 0: trying
Speaker 1: to deal with it prepare for it and prevent it.
Speaker 1: One thing leads to another and at some point there is a catastrophe on the earth known as the second impact.
Speaker 1: No I forgot about the first impact being when God created mankind Adam and Eve.
Speaker 1: all that as far as you know, the second impact is basically God Giving forth the harbinger of the end of the world saying now it begins you best be prepared now humanity having the prophecies and the Dead Sea Scrolls had been preparing and under the auspices of the United Nations and other international organizations had created an organization that with scientists and these prophecies had been preparing from that day forward for the day when the angels came and The anime picks up pretty much when that day comes and they're no longer crazy an Angel has come the military tries to deal with it.
Speaker 1: The military cannot.
Speaker 1: they finally relent agree that these people were not crazy and they hand over control of basically the combined economic output of the world to this organization to Basically try to fight off God and prevent the apocalypse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you don't find that out until well you kind of do it.
Speaker 1: they pretty much you know That's what the plot is and you know what's going on.
Speaker 1: It's actually a lot more complicated than that.
Speaker 1: There's actually like ten different organizations and there's all sorts of politics and it turns out that the Jews were behind it.
Speaker 0: Not really, but kinda the thing in the show is that they hardly ever say anything right out, you know things are always alluded to and implied and Symbolized and Sometimes you think something's alluded to but it's not.
Speaker 0: they lied and it's that's why a lot of people are like whoa.
Speaker 0: It's a total mind-fucking show because you can't tell what's going on But
Speaker 1: at the same time you can especially when you've watched it and you kind of know like the seed of the plot You really know what's going on and then you watch it again and you pick up a lot more.
Speaker 1: There seem to be a lot of shows like that.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: think part of the reason that is is I remember there's a couple scenes in the show where they'll show you something visually without any words for like two seconds and that's if you see that in whatever place in time that it appears that Tells you a whole bunch of stuff that you didn't know otherwise And like you miss that you miss out on a whole bunch of information.
Speaker 0: that shines a lot of light.
Speaker 1: So like that one scene, this isn't a spoiler or anything on the aircraft carrier.
Speaker 0: Yeah with the suitcase Yeah, and they show you what's in the suitcase for like two seconds.
Speaker 0: And if you see it you go But if you don't see those two seconds if you blink You just missed out on like a whole thing and now you're not gonna understand stuff that happens later.
Speaker 1: I mean basically the way the show seems to work in terms in in terms of that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Is that all the information is there?
Speaker 1: nothing actually comes out of nowhere?
Speaker 1: It's not like there's deus ex machina or just suddenly.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, it turns out that blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: It's all there, but they show it to you kind of in the sense that the characters involved wouldn't have noticed.
Speaker 1: These are things that wouldn't have been easy to spot in the heat of the moment but they're just.
Speaker 1: they're kind of setting you up so that these things don't come out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: and Also, it's not like you see it and you think oh, I know what's going on It's more you see it and you think why would he have that?
Speaker 1: What what's going on?
Speaker 1: I don't like this one bit or like that scene when Ray's got the spear of long a noose and then stabs that thing that Was crucified somewhere?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you don't find out what that was about for a long time.
Speaker 1: But once you do cuz that's the thing later on in the show something big will happen and you'll think back.
Speaker 1: You'll be like wait a minute, but I saw her stab that thing with the spear of law.
Speaker 1: Oh That's what that was.
Speaker 1: Whoa And there's a lot of that.
Speaker 1: now we've given you the backdrop of the show the way the show actually progresses.
Speaker 1: the story within this plot is that there is a young boy named Shinji Ikari and He is a loser.
Speaker 1: He's I mean he's not a loser.
Speaker 0: no one likes him you don't even like him.
Speaker 1: I don't like.
Speaker 1: I like him a lot more in the manga.
Speaker 1: I'll be honest I was I really don't like it.
Speaker 1: But the thing is you're not supposed to like him.
Speaker 1: because the thing about Ava is that all the characters are very human and they?
Speaker 1: All have very real psychological issues that they really can't deal with.
Speaker 0: It's kind of hard to not have psychological issues when giant monsters are coming out of the sky true.
Speaker 1: But even then the fact is that all these people have fairly simple Psychological issues, but they're very difficult to deal with and they're all very isolated from each other.
Speaker 1: And I think part of what makes Ava great is that there's all these characters and if at any point Anyone had talked to anyone else about their problems or opened up at all almost every problem that happened in the show could have been averted.
Speaker 1: but no Someone walks in on someone to see some crying and just kind of freaks out doesn't know what to do runs away and cries on Their own and then no one vents anything and everyone keeps everything bottled up and no one really trusts anyone.
Speaker 1: It's really a fairly No, I don't want to say accurate but a fairly poignant and kind of biting commentary on what's wrong with humanity on a very Fundamental level.
Speaker 0: if you think that people have that kind of problem then yeah, I a lot of people do.
Speaker 1: I mean I part of it.
Speaker 1: I mean there are people in the show who don't have problems.
Speaker 1: It's just that many of the main characters you mean the cool people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah the cool people Yeah, well actually there's some cool people who have problems But they're better at like keeping their problems hidden away.
Speaker 0: Yeah They don't let their problems get in the way of getting shit done.
Speaker 1: like my man my favorite character in the show That guy is probably one of my favorite characters in anime ever.
Speaker 0: He's alright.
Speaker 1: Akaji is just the man.
Speaker 0: He's got some nice watermelons.
Speaker 0: He does.
Speaker 1: I was once mistaken as a kaji cosplayer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they even took a picture of me.
Speaker 1: I'm in fans view somewhere cuz I just happened to have not shaved at some Otakon.
Speaker 1: So I was all scruffy and I had my hair tied back in a ponytail And I was dressed in like a collared shirt and a tie and pants.
Speaker 1: and I was hot because it was summer.
Speaker 1: So I had my tie kind of losing the top button on button and some guy walk.
Speaker 1: Somebody's like hey nice kaji cosplay and he takes a picture and I'm like what?
Speaker 1: But yeah, but the story is Shinji kari.
Speaker 1: this kid is the son of one of the men who is running this organization and For reasons I don't really want to get into the nitty-gritty of it but basically he gets embroiled in all this along with a lot of other children because it just so happens that the children the people who are able to Pilot these devices these Ava's these robots Have to have been born Pretty much like at a certain time like there's this window where kids were born and these people are the only people who have the capacity To pilot the robots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they can't just like put soldiers in them and they can't put babies in them.
Speaker 0: They can't put nothing in them.
Speaker 0: They gotta put these kids in there.
Speaker 1: I mean another nice thing about the show is that at least as far as you can see It's not like they don't try.
Speaker 1: you think why don't they just have a military guy do it?
Speaker 0: Oh, that's the characters are like military scientist people who are trying to figure out as much as they possibly can.
Speaker 0: of course Everything always goes wrong.
Speaker 0: Oh God goes more and more wrong every episode.
Speaker 0: My
Speaker 1: favorite thing is that the one thing that always bothered me about the show a little bit was that they have the kind of like Emergency cut the ties between the pilot and the robot in case something bad happens and eject the pilot and I guess it worked in training or whatever.
Speaker 1: But in the course of the show it never works.
Speaker 1: once and every time they try to do it It just doesn't work and there's some sort of catastrophe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like every single time.
Speaker 0: There's a robot fight with robot and an angel Right, they'll be sitting in the bridge.
Speaker 0: I guess it's not really a bridge because not a ship but it's like the war room where all the you know displays and controls Are forever know what it's the baby war room ever.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good war.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've been to NASA.
Speaker 0: NASA looks really small anyway But they've got all these freaking lights and things.
Speaker 0: and every time there's a fight right always the worst possible thing happens.
Speaker 0: It's like warning warning warning.
Speaker 0: Oh my god extreme system failure system failure over there.
Speaker 0: Oh, everything's exploding It's overheating.
Speaker 0: God knows what's going on.
Speaker 0: We're running out of power.
Speaker 0: Well, God does know what's going on.
Speaker 0: I know he's kind of behind it all but it's everything goes as wrong as it can every single time and Whatever they try to do to fix it never works.
Speaker 0: And it's why I didn't even bother with these computers.
Speaker 0: They just don't do anything.
Speaker 1: however while you might think that I do want to point out that Part of the reason that seems so strange through part of much of the show is that you don't know what's really going on Too much and you kind of take a lot of things at face value And you find out later in the show that you can't really trust what characters in the show have been telling you because either they're misinformed or they're lying or Something.
Speaker 1: and you start to find out that all the things that happen throughout the show happen for a reason.
Speaker 1: it's one of those shows where kind of like big O and big O - where Everything that happens happens for a reason there aren't really many loose pot plot threads and it all does come together in the end And I think a fairy fairly elegant way.
Speaker 1: In fact, I'm gonna come back straight out.
Speaker 1: I don't think we said it Despite what a lot of you might say.
Speaker 1: I really like and I really respect Evangelion and I think it has a lot to say and I think a lot of the people who are naysayers are just jaded By modern anime or I don't want to sound pretentious But I don't think a lot of people got it or they at most and I will respect this opinion and we'll get to this.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of people feel a little bit insulted at how Ava presented the message Because you know the story is this kid gets embroiled in all this and politics and one thing leads to another.
Speaker 1: What the show really is is the first four or five episodes are check it out.
Speaker 1: We got a robot show.
Speaker 1: God send angels to kill the world giant robots robot fights action show.
Speaker 1: Check it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not only that but a lot of these episodes they like.
Speaker 0: for half the episode They won't even have any God or robots or anything going on.
Speaker 1: It's Misato with her pet penguin.
Speaker 0: It's like people getting drunk hanging out with pet penguins and having all kinds of fun playing DDR.
Speaker 0: And who knows what else man Misato with.
Speaker 1: she has two fridges in her house one for food and one for beer.
Speaker 0: It is definitely still plenty of that classic anime
Speaker 1: comedy going on and there's actually at least in the first half of the show a More fan service than you would expect mostly about Misato who is probably iconic as one of the most idolized and I guess sexy anime characters at least in a first American except
Speaker 0: it seems like everyone likes the Younger characters because they're all perverted Hot if it hit him on the head
Speaker 1: in Scott and mine's old man generation Misato was hot because Misato was an adult.
Speaker 0: But I got.
Speaker 0: yes.
Speaker 1: In fact, my first wall screw ever was a slightly.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit edgy.
Speaker 1: I don't really hang it up anymore because I was given to me by the anime club as a gift.
Speaker 0: But I have this what you want it at a rap.
Speaker 1: No Remember I?
Speaker 1: I won the raffle and then they gave that to me and they gave me all of Ava to rent because it happened To be my birthday.
Speaker 0: I thought they didn't know.
Speaker 0: we asked for it.
Speaker 1: Like well, we asked for all of Ava and they said well It's your birthday.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and it was.
Speaker 1: they even made me show my driver's license.
Speaker 1: They didn't believe it was my birthday.
Speaker 0: whatever.
Speaker 1: yeah, the things falling apart and filthy but The problem with a. well not the problem, but the first five episodes and all this stuff It's like a typical anime.
Speaker 1: So the show was designed and I think it was very purposeful to trick the average anime fan or just the robot fighting fan Whatever to watch this show.
Speaker 0: It goes in the shell does a lot of the same thing where they try to trick you into watching the show with their Violences and their boobies, but really then they bait and switch and they show you something else that they wanted you to see.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: but with Ava, it's so calculated It's it's just enough robot show to get people going and actually all the people I know who like Ava a lot Are actually kind of turned off by the first few episodes and you got to kind of get them to watch until the point when the Switches.
Speaker 0: not only that but it's also so little robot show the people who are like super anti robot Will still be able to watch it because they like oh, it's not really a robot show.
Speaker 0: They don't really talk about the robot so much and they're barely even there.
Speaker 0: and you know Well fighting is just sort of like actual punching and kicking and not so much like, you know mechanical robot fighting.
Speaker 1: well plus I mean not to spoil but there is there's a point at which you find out just what these robots really are and I will admit that when I first saw Ava and you find out more about what's going on I had a chill.
Speaker 1: It was a very well executed scene and basically the show does the bait-and-switch and The show is not about the robot fighting at all.
Speaker 1: In fact at the end of the show and this is probably one of the biggest controversies ever in anime is that the show kind of stops right at the climax of everything that's going on and Doesn't really show you what happened.
Speaker 1: He doesn't show you the resolution to the plot.
Speaker 1: He basically says all right kids.
Speaker 1: I tricked you into watching my robot show.
Speaker 1: I slowly turned it into my commentary on the human condition.
Speaker 1: now I'm going to because I've already got you watching this far Tell you what I think and I'm going to do it in a very surreal very heavy-handed very straight-up way and People didn't like that so much.
Speaker 0: now people wanted to see their giant robot climax.
Speaker 0: Yes, so of course what I know did is stop taking his antidepressants.
Speaker 0: Yes Well, basically, it's a 26 episode TV series and the final two episodes 25 and 26 are I knows message to you and there's not so much robotic going on now.
Speaker 1: I really want to avoid talking about the message.
Speaker 1: that's for our other show on a device to say and I'm very open about this I cried at the final scene of Ava in the original TV show and I still think it is one of the best endings to An anime ever made.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's fantastic as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: Well, basically people Unlike rim really didn't go for that.
Speaker 0: They wanted to see their robots.
Speaker 0: So he said he said no fuck you.
Speaker 0: and then he said no fuck you.
Speaker 0: But then one day someone said what about money?
Speaker 0: money exists and he says fuck I need that.
Speaker 0: How can I eat if I don't have that yen over there?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because Ava did so poorly before the move.
Speaker 1: I know right got every money.
Speaker 0: So what he did?
Speaker 0: he said fine I need some yen's.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go and I'm gonna make the end that you fuckers wanted to see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he went and he made episode 25 and 26 Again, he made replacement episodes and he passed them off as the event end to Evangelion the Evangelion movie You know and the episode the remake of episode 25 is called air and the remake of episode 26 is called a pure heart for you And that's why we refer to it as air and a pure heart for you Because it's the two episode titles with the word and in the middle.
Speaker 1: now funny little story.
Speaker 1: way back before there were internet fan subs.
Speaker 1: I there's a fan server called V kill.
Speaker 1: I really like that but VK ll yes, not VK I ll.
Speaker 1: yeah, I guess there might be.
Speaker 0: I failed that searching for him on the internet many times.
Speaker 1: I did not realize he lacked the eye and I got all the Sailor Moon and a bunch of other stuff from these people and They were really good.
Speaker 1: But I didn't know about Ava and he had this thing called end of Evangelion and I. it looked like a standalone movie.
Speaker 1: So I got it and I watched it and I didn't know what it was and it was really weird and it disturbed me.
Speaker 1: So I showed it to all my friends.
Speaker 1: they were like wow what's with all the religious?
Speaker 1: this is just really creepy.
Speaker 1: and Then we all found out that there was a show and that basically ruined the whole show for us and to this day None of them will forgive me for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah I also have to say it's watching that first.
Speaker 1: really put the rest of the show in this totally different perspective.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the the air and a pure heart for you is is kind of fucked up.
Speaker 0: It's all.
Speaker 0: in some ways it's even more fucked up than the crazy ending he made in the first place I think but in other ways is less fucked up because it has it shows you quite literally what's going on.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, there it is.
Speaker 0: I mean here except for the part where he shows the empty real-life movie theater.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that gets weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then that's that swing that just keeps swinging back and forth for like 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: It's actually like a minute, but it feels like forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean the difference between the original ending in the movies in terms of plot is that you know the show stops at episode 24 and then 25 and 26 basically are Like what's going on in the final care like in one of the main characters heads at the end of the show and even shows you Flashes of stills from what happened in the real world.
Speaker 1: and the message is basically, you know, what?
Speaker 1: Yes Look, here's what happened.
Speaker 1: It shows shots of you know, certain people dead or things happening and the message is basically by now You should realize that you shouldn't care what happened.
Speaker 1: what actually physically happens Doesn't matter if you care about seeing what actually happened in the real world and what the end of this plot was.
Speaker 1: Then you miss the point of my anime.
Speaker 1: granted I can't fault many people for missing the point of the anime because it's a little bit obtuse But
Speaker 0: a little bit up to a little bit little bit quite
Speaker 1: obtuse, but and it's really I like it the movies Show physically while this character is in his head, you know kind of exploring.
Speaker 1: Well, what am I?
Speaker 1: and what does it mean to be a human?
Speaker 1: and why is there this pain of separation from other humans?
Speaker 1: But is it better to be all that stuff?
Speaker 1: The movie is here's what happened when the giant robots fought the other giant robot yeah, and all the physical stuff and whether or not the Armageddon happens and what happens as a result of that.
Speaker 1: but the real Answers to what the movies were was Anno basically standing there with his two middle fingers in the air saying Alright assholes you wanted to see what happened.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to show you but you asked for it.
Speaker 0: So here it is fuck you and not only fuck you but uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I got your yen.
Speaker 1: Yes It's like you like those characters.
Speaker 1: Well, wait till you see what I do to them all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's other.
Speaker 0: there's uh the movie.
Speaker 0: when we say the movie we mean the replacement episodes.
Speaker 0: Aaron a pure heart for you.
Speaker 0: there are other things like Evangelion death in her birth and revival of Evangelion and all this other Movies different that remakes with added scenes and stuff like that and I really can't tell them apart.
Speaker 0: and Honestly, you don't really need to watch any of those.
Speaker 0: All you need to watch is the 26 episode TV series and then the two replacement episodes for 25 and 26.
Speaker 0: Don't watch anything else.
Speaker 0: It's probably just a waste of your time now my recommendation.
Speaker 1: But this is entirely just my recommendation and you don't have to follow it at all.
Speaker 1: But if you have never seen Evangelion before I would recommend that you watch the first 24 episodes and then stop.
Speaker 1: Watch the movies now see what happens in the like in the end of the show and watch that ending and then Watch the last two episodes from the TV series because they kind of both say similar things But they kind of take two different tacks on it And I think that the real ending well not the real ending the first ending the original show Will leave a much better taste in your mouth and it'll
Speaker 0: also make more sense.
Speaker 1: Yes It's kind of tears of joy at understanding what the show is all about versus just sitting there with your mouth open going.
Speaker 1: What the fuck was that?
Speaker 1: Yeah now in terms of the show itself It's animated pretty well Especially considering when it came out and there are some extremely beautiful scenes in this.
Speaker 1: the soundtrack is fantastic.
Speaker 1: The voice acting is really good.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of big names in this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually I've heard that the dub is actually not so bad but I still wouldn't watch it.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's about as good as all the dubs back then were which means kind of better than the dubs now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess it was done by the.
Speaker 0: you know is day 80 V in the 90s.
Speaker 0: So whatever a TV was like in the 90s, that's what this was like.
Speaker 1: yep, and I gotta say they're the sit like the symbolism and the scenes and the way a lot of the.
Speaker 1: There's so much symbolism in the show.
Speaker 1: It's kind of love Gutena where it just hits you over the head constantly, but I guess unlike Gutena It doesn't get crazy to the point of there's a flashing hand with the finger Pointing at the symbolic thing on the screen to make sure you don't miss it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's sort of weird cuz it's not like, you know, they tell a completely normal story but there is a hidden meaning that is hidden but doesn't interfere because the symbolism does sort of interfere and they do a lot of scenes which are just Symbolic and not literal and you know, they are and sometimes you can decipher them and sometimes you can't.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of allegories Evangelion and a lot of the symbolism I think is very like.
Speaker 1: it doesn't say it doesn't hit you over the head so much It's more that it it kind of enhances the scene or adds a little something to your perception like there's a scene.
Speaker 1: I think this is the best example where Gen Dao kind of the leader of all this business is sitting at his desk and It pans out to him at his desk and the way he's sitting at it with the shadow behind him His desk and him cast a shadow on the floor that is pretty much straight-up a Star of David and Simultaneously, there is this shadow from the cross beams of the window and as the camera moves the cross beams form across over his shoulder And coupled with what he is saying and kind of his Force or what he is doing or his what he does in the plot and why he is important.
Speaker 1: It actually adds a lot especially if you know anything about Judeo-Christian mythology.
Speaker 1: In fact, I would recommend that you read up a little bit on Judeo-Christian mythology and the Dead Sea Scrolls.
Speaker 1: The show will make a lot more sense if you do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll show you a lot of things and you might say Oh, it's the tree of life.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's the Star of David.
Speaker 0: But what that means, I mean you'll be like God.
Speaker 0: It's the Jew symbol.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but you don't know any more than that.
Speaker 0: Then a lot of things will be completely lost on you that they're trying to say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean if you read about especially the Kabbalah which while it's obviously not true It's really interesting stuff and it's it's kind of neat and you'll get Ava a lot more if you've read about that at all Yeah, I guess that's you know.
Speaker 0: another reason why a lot of people are sort of you know say they don't like Ava so much because even if they're the kind of people who like symbolic meaningful existential kind of stuff this sort of requires like this base knowledge and You're a lot of attention.
Speaker 0: You had to pay attention to everything and every second and every single thing on the screen In order to get all the pieces and it's hard work, it's not like easy to watch and get it.
Speaker 1: It's very difficult, but unlike some shows like utenna no matter how hard you try You're not gonna figure out what's going on until the very end.
Speaker 1: with Ava you can get a very good idea if you just pay attention and if you watch the show with the mission of I Want to know what's actually going on You'll have a pretty good sense of what's going on near the like as it goes on.
Speaker 0: Because even even though everyone talks about how crazy it is most of the show is pretty straightforward like There's an angel coming.
Speaker 0: Hey, we're in school.
Speaker 0: Hey, there's a robot.
Speaker 0: Hey, should I go in the robot?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: you go in the robot instead this time.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm not doing so well in this robot fight.
Speaker 0: Oh, she's hot.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: most of it is straightforward.
Speaker 0: during the you know First half of the TV series for like 16 episodes everything will make sense complete sense like oh he's doing that now All right.
Speaker 1: Now I'd like to talk more about the show But honestly, I really don't want to spoil anything and I don't want to any more so than we already have kind of poison the well of how you're going to take Ava because much like all the shows like this there are a lot of ways to take it a lot of ways to interpret it and I really don't want anyone to watch this show having some sort of preconceived notion as to what the show is trying to say Because I'd like you to at least come to your own conclusion before you hear what we have to say about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think what it comes down to is whether you like this show or if you hate the show and you think it's the worst Show ever.
Speaker 0: It's such a significant show at least in its influence on current animes and animes.
Speaker 0: You know since you know in the later half of the 90s to today That if you are in any sort of anime fan whatsoever Even if you're only like shoujo and you hate robots and you hate all this kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: You should watch it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's it's sort of like a must watch Like if you watch movies you have to see citizen Kane, even if you don't like it you have to see it.
Speaker 1: It's like a law somewhere and luckily Ava is really easy to come by.
Speaker 1: There's a platinum thin pack and you want that you can get it for like 20 to 40 dollars.
Speaker 1: There's the whole show.
Speaker 0: back in the day You had to buy a pile of VHS's or a pile of DVDs and ATV keeps re-releasing Ava in different formats.
Speaker 1: forget all of those.
Speaker 1: buy the platinum complete thin pack because one the platinum complete has it's totally Remastered and with this show it really matters.
Speaker 1: It's like night and day.
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: and two and this is one thing that bothers me about Ava in the platinum thin pack there are the directors cuts or the original cuts of like five or six episodes from the show and I watched all of those and I discovered something really it seems like all the things they cut out of the show Were the things that explained exactly what was going on in excruciating detail.
Speaker 1: I watched this one episode and there's this organization called Garen that you kind of get the sense that they're important But they don't really explain exactly what that is And when they do it's really roundabout.
Speaker 1: in the director's cut version of that episode.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much.
Speaker 1: Garen was founded by this government to do this and this and this by these people.
Speaker 1: on this date I was like, oh great.
Speaker 1: I really could have used that when I watched the real show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you get the platinum thin pack, it's cheap.
Speaker 0: It's the whole show in a one tiny little box and it's really cheap and that's what you should buy.
Speaker 0: Don't bother buying any other DVD box sets.
Speaker 0: this probably, you know, you'll go to the store.
Speaker 0: There'll be some crazy expensive one for like three hundred dollars that comes with probably robots and things in there.
Speaker 0: You don't want that.
Speaker 0: you could buy the real.
Speaker 0: I guess if you could find the old DVDs on eBay that might be cheap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but make sure you don't get a bootleg if it's at a TV.
Speaker 0: It's not a bootleg if it's not from a TV.
Speaker 0: It is a bootleg.
Speaker 1: and don't get VHS tapes for the love of God Yeah Yeah.
Speaker 0: VHS tapes kind of useless.
Speaker 0: plus if you get the probably main problem with getting this on VHS is you want the subtitles and it's probably harder to find the Subtitled VHS.
Speaker 0: is?
Speaker 0: I mean we had them all at RIT, but that's probably the only place Yeah, but I mean we really like the show.
Speaker 1: it's in our top ten possibly our top five easily.
Speaker 1: Uh, I think the show has a lot to say and I think everyone out there Who is it all a fan of anime should at least give it a chance in?
Speaker 1: The future probably in a month or two.
Speaker 1: We want to give everyone time.
Speaker 1: We're gonna review the show for people who have already seen the show meaning spoilers and commentary Which means we have to watch it.
Speaker 0: So which I imagine we'll probably watch it in like August some point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because well part of it we are ting this weekend.
Speaker 0: it's cons.
Speaker 0: cons.
Speaker 1: We actually have several friends who have never seen Ava and one thing that one of my favorite things to do And I haven't been able to do this much since our IT is I love to watch one of those amazing shows With people who have never seen it because it's more fun to watch their reactions to certain scenes than to watch the show again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's cuz I've seen the show.
Speaker 0: Well, I haven't seen this in a while.
Speaker 0: So I'm actually gonna be paying more attention.
Speaker 1: I've seen Ava about four times.
Speaker 0: I've only seen it twice.
Speaker 0: But yeah it when guys if there's something I've seen 100 times like attack the gas station God, I can.
Speaker 0: I can't attack the gas station.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: But if I just watch it, it doesn't do it for me because I've seen it like 20 times.
Speaker 0: but if there's even one person who hasn't seen it before.
Speaker 0: I Want to show it to them so badly and I'll sit there through the whole movie with them just to see if you know They attack only one seat.
Speaker 1: now at least for us that seems to be the mark of a good show like some shows are just So important to us or transcendent or whatever.
Speaker 1: that I mean.
Speaker 1: You know our the way we talk about Netflix and fan subs and whatever most things we watch.
Speaker 1: we watch him once we throw them Away, we never want to see him again.
Speaker 1: We already got what we're getting out of it.
Speaker 1: But there's a few shows and a few things and movies that we end up just periodically watching like every now and then.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It's been about that time.
Speaker 1: We've got to watch eska flown a again.
Speaker 1: It's the matrix Yeah, and Ava's one of those things.
Speaker 1: we perennially watch Ava again and again And I imagine that I'm going to watch Ava every few years off and on for much of my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm an old man.
Speaker 0: I'll be sitting there I've read everything and seen every anime and whatever and I'll be like up seeing everything.
Speaker 0: Watch that Ava again.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Sure Yeah, plus I mean Ava.
Speaker 1: really it stands up to the test of time.
Speaker 1: if Ava came out today I think it would do well.
Speaker 0: Oh, it'd do crazy.
Speaker 1: Well, especially considering a lot of what's out there now.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, the thing is it's definitely from you know, that older school of anime.
Speaker 0: They don't make anime in this genre anymore.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Well, they've tried and a lot of people say that Raza fon does what Ava tried to do better.
Speaker 0: I watch Raza fon.
Speaker 0: it is definitely in the same genre, but it's also definitely different even though at times They're directly poking fun at Ava.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess we could actually do a whole episode in Raza fon slash Ava.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, you know we could do a whole episode on just all the shows that pay homage to or otherwise make fun of Ava.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, if you if you like Raza Ava Ava, you should probably watch Raza fon Yeah and also if you like both of those shows watch big-o solely so that you can watch big-o - and You might think what are you crazy?
Speaker 1: because big-o is about a giant robot who punches other giant robots in the face.
Speaker 0: That's why big-o is awesome.
Speaker 1: Big-o is one of my favorite anime But seriously big-o much like Ava takes a turn and goes the direction you wouldn't expect Ava with Batman.
Speaker 1: Yes All Right, I think we're done.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share a like 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.