Speaker 1: It's Tuesday September 4th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight death.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Alright, so I've been trying to find a video game podcast other than Dave and Joel which doesn't really count as a video game podcast.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess they review video games, but they don't tell me what games are coming out or anything like that.
Speaker 0: So I guess the one that I tried most recently was the one that goes along with that Magazine.
Speaker 0: we got for free the EGM whatever, but that's a terrible magazine.
Speaker 0: It was a terrible magazine in the podcast also kind of terrible and probably not gonna listen any more of it great.
Speaker 0: But the one episode that I just happened to listen to is my trying out episode the most recent one.
Speaker 0: they talked to this guy who made this new ps3 game called lair
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: Basically the reviewer who did the review I guess in the magazine Chatted with the guy who made the game and was like yeah This is why your game sucks, and the guy was like nah You're just seeing it that way cuz you're hardcore and my game is not for the hardcore Blah-blah-blah.
Speaker 0: and they argued about how I guess the game forces you to use the six axis business, but it's the control is fucked up and The game is you know nonlinear, but at the same time It's hard to actually figure out what the hell's going on.
Speaker 0: sometimes the game just fucks you and and whatever I never played the game.
Speaker 0: I'm probably never going to play the game.
Speaker 0: The point is I got two things.
Speaker 0: number one most of this guy's argument was that you're so hardcore.
Speaker 0: That's why the game doesn't work for you.
Speaker 0: the game works for the non hardcore, and I'm like dude It's a ps3 only game.
Speaker 0: What the fuck were you thinking?
Speaker 0: yeah?
Speaker 0: You made a game supposedly for the non hardcore on the ps3 only are you.
Speaker 0: what are you thinking?
Speaker 0: That's just not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: There's no one who has a ps3 who is an ultra hardcore.
Speaker 0: So if you put a game out for the ps3 that's for the non hardcore.
Speaker 0: everyone's either gonna buy and hate it or Not buy it.
Speaker 1: I'm with you there.
Speaker 0: What's number two number two is that people freaking with these review scores.
Speaker 1: I gotta say it again You know back in the day PC gamer had the only good review system ever because they gave bad ratings to a lot of games.
Speaker 0: I mean supposedly this is a bad game and the guy gave it like a four and a half or a five or something which He said is average.
Speaker 0: I'm like sounds to me like you're saying this game was bad, but yet you gave it an average.
Speaker 1: He's going on an absolute scale where a two or a three would be like Custer's revenge And maybe a one would be that one with the witch.
Speaker 0: all right, but the way he describes this game It's at least three not five.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: you know
Speaker 0: and also people who make games and people I guess who care about video game magazines and people who work at video game magazines take these scores away, too Seriously, well,
Speaker 1: I think part of it it's just that in the video game industry the video game press is almost complete bullshit and I Don't really have a lot of respect for people who pay those ratings a lot of credence because they're usually super inflated And they're really not that useful.
Speaker 0: Yeah And I guess like they it seems like there's some false belief that the ratings have something to like.
Speaker 0: if you get a good Ratings on your game that somehow translates into like big sales.
Speaker 0: You know what people.
Speaker 0: that's bullshit.
Speaker 0: if Halo 1 got say I don't know Fives instead of tens it would have sold just as many if Halo 3 gets all ones from every magazine.
Speaker 0: guess what a bajillion People are still gonna buy.
Speaker 1: I mean among gamers.
Speaker 1: I think the actual primary factor in selling a game is word-of-mouth, but not any other factor.
Speaker 1: I think that is the primary thing that sells games to gamers.
Speaker 0: Yeah but Websites are chatting up a game for good or bad.
Speaker 1: you can't forget that a lot of the people who buy games are not gamers They're mommies buying games for in which case they're not looking at a video game magazine at all.
Speaker 0: They go to the store and look at the shelf.
Speaker 1: Oh, so I guess the video game press is just complete crap.
Speaker 0: Well, at least the reviewing in the scoring and such Part of its non-crab The letting.
Speaker 1: you know what games are coming out, but I can find that out from press releases and blogs.
Speaker 1: That's all.
Speaker 0: that's press.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but people write articles about it and the articles don't.
Speaker 1: they just say more things like the games going to come out on next day.
Speaker 1: Blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can cut out those blahs.
Speaker 0: I just need game is coming out a next day.
Speaker 1: It is kind of interesting that to me the only people I trust at all when it comes to camera views are Penny arcade and to a much lesser extent Dave and Joel.
Speaker 0: I think what it what it is is you need reviews.
Speaker 0: Reviews are a lot more useful with something like like movies because there's a lot fewer of them, right?
Speaker 0: And you know, you're gonna go to the movie theater and you gotta like sort of pick which one.
Speaker 1: even that I ignore reviews and I go on word-of-mouth if all my friends say movies terrible.
Speaker 1: I wait for Netflix.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know but it is slightly more useful.
Speaker 0: but with video games, I think it's not useful because you have like a bajillion games out there and You're only.
Speaker 0: you know, it's not like you're gonna buy a video game.
Speaker 0: which one it's like I'm gonna buy Metroid.
Speaker 0: It's like once you know about the game you buy it.
Speaker 0: You don't need like this reviews to tell you which ones are what you know Which ones are what.
Speaker 0: if you're in it and if you're not in it You're going to the store and looking at the covers and picking one out.
Speaker 0: So the reviews not so useful I don't know.
Speaker 1: I could see reviews having been useful back in the day when well, maybe just like more mainstream money You know like a magazine review or a big company doing a review because back then The internet wasn't quite what it is now and that was the only way to find out about a new game.
Speaker 1: But now it's just.
Speaker 0: it's not necessary Especially the score.
Speaker 1: I think it'd be a lot better if reviews were just you know.
Speaker 1: But whoever's writing the review saying here are my thoughts on this game.
Speaker 1: I like this.
Speaker 1: I didn't like this.
Speaker 1: I think this part won't appeal to you people.
Speaker 1: I think this part will appeal to you kind of people and not bother with the score at the end.
Speaker 0: I mean, what if we did that in anime like yeah, I give cowboy bebop a nine point seven out of ten point one Whatever Right, yeah Mostly I just want to say the guys doofus cuz he's like yeah the games for the non hardcore on the ps3.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think that's the part that really needs to be brought out into the open.
Speaker 0: I think also and I think it was a funny coincidence that I listened to one episode of a bad podcast.
Speaker 0: Well, it wasn't the worst podcast, but I'm not listening.
Speaker 0: We know what the worst The penny arcade happened to be about the same thing as the the episode.
Speaker 1: Well, it helped that they could make a pretty good joke based on the title of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it did help.
Speaker 1: indeed I'll admit I loathe.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right.
Speaker 1: So basically all I've been doing for the last week is playing natural selection as much as I can.
Speaker 0: way to go.
Speaker 1: I just now that I got a gaming PC again I think like oh I should play all these like you're playing this game that your old PC could have played.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I didn't.
Speaker 1: my old PC had other problems.
Speaker 1: Remember the video card was dead.
Speaker 0: I know your old busted TNT - yeah But that doesn't matter left TNC - could play now just like barely it could play half-life one.
Speaker 0: just fine.
Speaker 1: barely The thing was.
Speaker 1: I just like I got new games now, I got Bioshock I got a play that you didn't.
Speaker 0: you didn't buy the whole game.
Speaker 1: Did you I bought it?
Speaker 0: Oh you the whole game It was.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna play it.
Speaker 1: I really like it.
Speaker 0: All right, the thing is I might buy it then.
Speaker 1: I haven't played it yet because I just keep playing every time.
Speaker 1: It's like I have this process a cue where my brain will cycle through when I sit down from the gear and I think all Right.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna play a video game on my computer and my brain goes Alright, you're gonna play tribes - when I say brain tribes - is not playable anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry and it goes shit.
Speaker 1: I gotta ask.
Speaker 1: All right, fine.
Speaker 1: You're gonna play natural selection, right and I go Yeah, and I never get to any other games.
Speaker 0: So I forced myself to put the games in a queue.
Speaker 0: I mean I just beat paper Mario and now I'm playing the Metroid Prime the new one on the Wii and then I'm probably when that's done I'll either do the Bioshock or the system shock - and I don't know what order and then but the thing is When the orange box comes out everything else is getting pushed aside.
Speaker 1: I'm taking the day off work.
Speaker 1: when Team Fortress 2 comes out I'm just.
Speaker 0: it goes like.
Speaker 0: I also got to play half-life 2 episode 2.
Speaker 1: You know what I get enough vacation days.
Speaker 1: I'll take the week off.
Speaker 1: I'll just as soon as the game comes out I'll spend the next seven days becoming the god of it.
Speaker 0: Maybe but yeah, but you know.
Speaker 0: So I got my games all lined up in a row, you know And there's like a space for you know Hourglass and the DS games can go in an edition because I play them on the train.
Speaker 1: See I had that and I was cool with that.
Speaker 1: But now I have a problem one.
Speaker 1: it's really more related to Monday nights, but Kind of to prove that they're worthless and also kind of because my company doesn't seem to understand that they're not Terribly useful.
Speaker 1: I'm getting all the Cisco search like I'm just gonna get them all and I'm signed up for all the tests and everything, but I got a look over Cisco iOS on the train and I bought a portable DVD player.
Speaker 1: So I spent today watching mutiny on the bounty from 1935 instead of reading anything.
Speaker 0: All right way to go for you.
Speaker 1: I haven't even beaten Pokemon and I don't think I will for another year now.
Speaker 0: Oh, you still didn't beat that?
Speaker 1: No, I just stopped trying.
Speaker 1: I've been doing other stuff.
Speaker 1: I feel bad.
Speaker 1: I never even beat the second Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: I just stopped.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah, oh well.
Speaker 0: So what's in the video game news here?
Speaker 1: Well, it turns out that on the 12th anniversary of one of the more revolutionary games in PC gaming We can now get that game for free in its original form.
Speaker 1: That game is in fact command and conquer.
Speaker 0: Well, it's command and conquer gold, which is the slightly improved version of the original command whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah one Walleye, I'm not good at that game and I'm not good at any RTS.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't really like RTS is to be honest I like.
Speaker 0: the thing is I like them.
Speaker 0: I just suck so badly at them and also Some of them.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: I like some parts But I don't like others.
Speaker 0: like I like the idea of build a bunch of stuff get a bunch of upgrades Select units send them out to do stuff.
Speaker 0: But I don't like is the fact that it boils down to more Fast clicking and knowing the order to build stuff.
Speaker 0: then it boils down to strategy.
Speaker 1: for me it's just that I was never good at the games partly because it did just boil down to the fast clicking and knowing exactly what to do.
Speaker 1: and I wanted to do complex.
Speaker 1: I remember when I first played the game multiplayer with other people over my Nullmodem cable and then with my modem dialing into their phone.
Speaker 1: We'd set it up and we'd play and I'd be like, alright So I'd make a group of tanks and infantry and I'd put them in one group like to the side.
Speaker 1: Then I make another group like grenadiers and something else and I try to like set an ambush and have like a pincher attack.
Speaker 1: And while I'm setting all this up, my friend just made a bunch of tanks and clicked on my base.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that wasn't fun.
Speaker 1: And also why won't the infantry just kind of sidestep my harvester?
Speaker 1: Why do they just sit there and get crushed?
Speaker 1: Pissed me off so much It did.
Speaker 0: it was pretty sucky except when you did it on purpose for funniness.
Speaker 0: or use your harvester to squish enemy inventory.
Speaker 1: so Back in the day.
Speaker 1: I was playing this game with a friend of mine named Ken He and we had with two computers in my house the Pentium Pro 200 and the 486 SX - they were connected via a serial null modem cable and We had command and conquer installed on both.
Speaker 1: Now the 486 had a problem with the mouse driver where About once a week the mouse would suddenly go bad shit and just fly around the four corners of the screen and freak out And you couldn't do anything.
Speaker 1: and if you hit any keys on the keyboard nothing happened and just chaos.
Speaker 1: But it only happened like once a week once a month.
Speaker 1: So I kind of ignored it.
Speaker 1: So we're playing and the game's going on pretty well, you know command and conquer and suddenly commanding and the conquering.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Ken says what the fuck the mouse stopped working I can't play the fucking game.
Speaker 1: What the fuck's wrong with your computer rim.
Speaker 1: and without missing a beat I turn to him and say well, uh, I guess it's just conquer for you.
Speaker 1: Anyway, no, I like this game even though I'm terrible at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the single player is actually kind of fun, which is weird for a game.
Speaker 0: That should be an RTS.
Speaker 1: Well, it had that thing where you could play as the good guys or the bad guy.
Speaker 0: Well, I came with two CDs the good guys CD in the bad guys and they were kind of really different and it was super Fun.
Speaker 0: I like it was like two games in one.
Speaker 1: I was better at the good guys, but I always wanted to be the bad guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I guys had cooler stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think tie fighter did that to me because tie fighter was a much better game than x-wing.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: but the other thing about this version of command and conquerors They're basically giving you the original Iso's for the windows 95 version and then they give you this patch file and then they give you this Instructions document of how to make it work in Windows XP and it's not trivial, but you can do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah and also the download is really slow and we don't think the online play will work because if you Recall you had to do the Westwood whatever to make it work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know What kind of.
Speaker 0: there's no internet play that's for sure, but there might be LAN play.
Speaker 0: Who knows.
Speaker 1: Well, regardless if anything I have a 50-foot and all modem cable and Scott and I both have serial ports.
Speaker 0: We'll see about that.
Speaker 1: That would be kind of awesome not?
Speaker 0: So?
Speaker 0: in other news, there are other free games available for the PC now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well not really free but Ubisoft or Ubisoft or her whatever you want to pronounce Ubisoft Ubisoft Ubisoft, whatever They they are putting some of their old crappy PC games.
Speaker 0: Well, not so much crappy but old PC older not so old.
Speaker 0: They get the Rayman Raving Ravids the Far Cry the original.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute didn't that game just come out on the Wii or something?
Speaker 1: I think so, but How are they releasing it for free?
Speaker 0: It's on the PC.
Speaker 0: Oh the PC versions a different I guess different game with the same name.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay I just ignore that the original Far Cry which is like three or four years old and that first the first 3d Prince of Persia For the PC.
Speaker 0: They're also giving that away for free.
Speaker 0: You know, I'll admit I never played any of those games Yeah, but I played the first Prince of Persia 3d.
Speaker 0: I played like two levels of it, but none none of the others.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you can get these games for free on file planet Which is sort of not free because using file planet is like Even if you wait in the line to get the gate to download for free.
Speaker 0: It's so painful that it's like spend.
Speaker 0: it's as painful as like spending $50.
Speaker 1: There was only one game in the history of gaming that ever got me to use file planet and that was tribes - yep but Also in addition to these games being PC games being free to download and free to play they're loaded up with ads.
Speaker 0: Aha, so, uh, yeah, it's not such a bad business decision to say Hey, we've got these old games.
Speaker 0: We're not making any money off of them, right?
Speaker 0: We could just let people pirate them and give them away for free to be nice
Speaker 1: or thing and sell them
Speaker 0: or we can load them up with ads for free and then continue to make money off them even though They're old and we're not making any money off them anymore.
Speaker 1: I'd rather they sell them for five bucks.
Speaker 0: I would rather sell them for five bucks and it did for the plus.
Speaker 0: These games are old and in the bargain bin.
Speaker 0: You can just get them for five or ten bucks and If these games are worth playing, you know back in the day Then I would have spent 50 bucks on him.
Speaker 0: if they were worth playing now I would have spent five or ten bucks on him.
Speaker 0: The game is either worth my time or it's not.
Speaker 1: you're forgetting one important thing.
Speaker 1: There was a time in my life When I had more free time than things with which to fill it.
Speaker 1: Yeah and I remember I would think I would like I would play a lot of games that nowadays I wouldn't even consider.
Speaker 1: but back then I wanted to play a game and I already got sick of sieve 2 and tie fighter and x-wing and quest for glory and all my SNES games and all my SNES games and I already run around outside.
Speaker 1: So I just go to the store buy whatever $5 game was there and just play it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'd rather spend $5 then wait in line at file planet and then look at ads while I'm playing.
Speaker 1: actually You know, that's the word even the ads in the game while I wouldn't play it because of that file plan.
Speaker 1: It's really the only thing that's bad about this file.
Speaker 1: planet is like the worst website in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah it is a good business idea to continue making money off of your old games that you spent all this money making and now they're Not making any more money for you.
Speaker 0: But I don't think it's something I would ever go and get.
Speaker 1: gotta do it in a more clever way.
Speaker 1: either sell the game Straight up and like a super giant package.
Speaker 0: That's what you got to do.
Speaker 0: You got to do it Like ID did.
Speaker 0: that's the better way to go.
Speaker 0: or get so every quake ever and every doom ever and every game you've ever made For like a 60 or
Speaker 1: give them away as a bundle bonus pack that comes with I don't know two or three new games You're selling
Speaker 0: no
Speaker 1: or anything like that
Speaker 0: Wouldn't be a bad idea if like when you came out with new game like what you could do is you could just Like every even
Speaker 1: better make it like the first five thousand people who buy this game.
Speaker 1: get the bonus pack like Nintendo did.
Speaker 1: That's a really good idea.
Speaker 1: I don't I didn't like.
Speaker 0: that's an idea if I was a video game company, right making big games.
Speaker 0: You only come out with a game like every few years, right?
Speaker 0: So I'd sell the first game 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: Then a few years later when I finally come out with another game I will give you the first game for free with the new game and then in a cup I give you the first two games are free.
Speaker 0: You gotta watch out.
Speaker 1: What if Kenny gamers think fine?
Speaker 1: I'll just play your game I'll wait and that's fine.
Speaker 0: They eventually have to buy and When new games come out they eventually have to buy.
Speaker 0: So, you know, they might buy every other.
Speaker 0: you you know Every other game to try to.
Speaker 0: you know, get get big discounts on half the games But they're gonna have to buy eventually.
Speaker 0: Plus I could always be like every time I come out with a new game.
Speaker 0: I could be like buy just my new game for 50 bucks buy my new game and all my old games I've developed before for 70 bucks, you know something like that.
Speaker 1: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm sure everyone knows about my thing of the day already mostly because it was so awesome I had to post it in places.
Speaker 1: Yes, in fact, I actually have already used it to make a bunch of things for geek nights that you'll be seeing shortly.
Speaker 0: Basically it's a generator as there are many generators on the internet such as the I don't know lolcat generators and Haha guy, haha guys my favorite.
Speaker 1: I spent like a week just making an infinite number of those things.
Speaker 0: so some someone made a Atari game cartridge label generator.
Speaker 0: it makes labels in the style of the labels that go on Atari game cartridges.
Speaker 1: Well Atari 2600 game cartridges.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes, and I'm wondering why aren't there like, you know NES label-makers rest NES label-makers?
Speaker 1: I think part of it is that the Atari I mean Nintendo.
Speaker 1: while the shape was always the same All the actual labels were so different that there's really nothing to.
Speaker 0: I'll know but you could go with the old style You know, well there were some Atari games that had different style labels on very few but all Nintendo games.
Speaker 1: Just the graphics were totally the only thing that was the same was the shape.
Speaker 1: but the Atari one Hell.
Speaker 1: and the Nintendo seal of quality which we can't legally put on.
Speaker 0: no No, but the Atari games they always let you put the Atari trademark on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I took you.
Speaker 1: take it off if you're gonna do something big or real.
Speaker 1: and also Atari Not quite the same as Nintendo when it comes to lawyering.
Speaker 0: No, you know, they're owned by someone.
Speaker 0: these days It keeps changing.
Speaker 0: but the point is if you want to make Atari cartridge labels This is pretty damn cool because there's a there's a lot of uses of them and you can make some funny ones like you know.
Speaker 0: What would be funny if it was an Atari cartridge?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Bioshock.
Speaker 0: Yeah Sorry, it's a good one.
Speaker 1: or maybe if we made some sort of geek nights logo that kind of looked like an Atari cartridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe All right, right.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day I'm not really gonna talk about it because it's quite germane to the topic at hand But it is essentially a speedrun of the game.
Speaker 1: We are about to review.
Speaker 1: so and if you haven't played this game or you want to hear the music from the game a little Watch a little bit of this but don't watch too much.
Speaker 1: if you ever plan to play the game because you're gonna ruin it for Yourself.
Speaker 1: you're gonna ruin the delightful trial and error discovery of how to win.
Speaker 0: the game known as The game has some gates and I guess it has some shadows, but the name shadow gay.
Speaker 0: I guess it's just the name of the castle right?
Speaker 0: It's castle shadow gay.
Speaker 1: Well, as far as I know this was a port of a PC game.
Speaker 0: was it I'd ever heard of that?
Speaker 1: These games were originally and I say these games because for those of you who played NES games You know that there were other games a lot like shadow gate like deja vu a personal favorite the uninvited.
Speaker 0: Was the uninvited for the NES?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right shadow gate 64.
Speaker 0: Yeah shadow gate 64.
Speaker 0: My brother rented that for the 64 once and that's game.
Speaker 0: It's so bad.
Speaker 0: It's like MD guys bad.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute your brother.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think you needed to say your shadow gauge 64 that my brother rented for the 64.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I don't think shadow get 64 came out in the Atari 2600.
Speaker 0: There were games that that were 64. that weren't?
Speaker 0: you know, I could have been for that.
Speaker 0: It could have been a Jaguar.
Speaker 0: It could have been.
Speaker 0: it could have been for some other system.
Speaker 1: Like what the Jaguar I'd say.
Speaker 1: Anyway, these games are part of something called the Mac venture series on the Mac.
Speaker 0: Oh news to me.
Speaker 1: and It's pretty easy to port a game like this to the NES because there's really no control.
Speaker 1: you just hover around a little skeleton finger Or gauntlet finger and click on menus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: play these games in the NES because they're designed to be run You know with a mouse and the clicking but instead use the gamepad actually to move a finger around.
Speaker 1: this from what I'm told But I can't.
Speaker 1: I mean I didn't play it on the Mac.
Speaker 1: People said that you actually use the keyboard to move the thing around on the Mac.
Speaker 0: It's terrible.
Speaker 0: a lot of games used to be like yeah But it is kind of handy though because the it'll just when you move the hand it like around the the main part of the Screen.
Speaker 0: it moves around slowly But once you get it into the menus on the bottom and the right hand side of the screen It just snaps to all the options and it's pretty easy to scroll through.
Speaker 1: Yeah now before now, I mean before we review this game or talk about it in any depth I'm sure many of you have played it and if you have that I think you know what we're about to Bring up, but this was a game that some might have called.
Speaker 1: some words could be difficult arbitrary insane stupid painful.
Speaker 1: Right, I guess we could mime Scott.
Speaker 1: I'll pretend that I am shadow gate and you try to do various actions in the game on me.
Speaker 0: Are you shadow gate?
Speaker 1: I'm shadow gate.
Speaker 1: Just you stand you see a door.
Speaker 0: I look death.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's quite that bad.
Speaker 1: I think Shadow gate is a game where every door every torch every Pixel just is seething with death and not just like oh you die, but really bizarre Elaborately described deaths it ranging from oh, no You're sucked out into the vacuum of space where you explode horribly or you melt into the green slime You tried to walk across or the dragon burns you or you fall into the fire or you punch yourself in the face.
Speaker 1: into that You know, I think there I could do a whole show just describing or reading all the deaths in that game.
Speaker 0: Basically, you know when you play an adventure game like say, I don't know quest for glory grim fandango King's Quest Because like police quest in particular you just fucking died all the time There were there.
Speaker 0: it was possible to die in many of those games.
Speaker 0: However, there you basically most of the game was spent running around collecting items talking to people and Trying to figure out where to go to use your items to access a new area.
Speaker 0: so you could you know get further in the game.
Speaker 1: I'll break it down even further.
Speaker 1: in those games You would click like five or six times before you were presented with the situation that could possibly cause your death.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'd you'd be like.
Speaker 0: You know trialing and erroring all over the place.
Speaker 0: and while you would have error error didn't mean game over.
Speaker 0: error meant Sorry, this isn't how to get further in the game.
Speaker 1: Try something else except in police quest where if you open the door and walk around the wrong side of the police car a car Just hits you and kills you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the games weren't free of death, but shadow gate has a lot more death than any of the others.
Speaker 0: I mean like just picking up a torch off the wall death opening a door death.
Speaker 0: you go into a room There's the you know, there's four doors and there's no clues.
Speaker 0: You just open one die.
Speaker 0: You know the grim reaper just shows up all sorts of randomly.
Speaker 1: It's a lot like that that scene in the silver surfer that screen of him crying on a surfboard.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: I mean there are some things you can do in the game where you won't progress further, but you also won't die but there aren't many of them and basically you have to figure out exactly what to do in the game to get ahead and Don't do anything else or deviate from that path whatsoever And that's the only way to win.
Speaker 1: really all these games are one-shot plays because once you have played through shadow gate once or Uninvited or any of these and you've beaten it There's no reason to ever play again because you know the exact sequence of steps necessary to beat the game.
Speaker 0: I mean you watch this speed run how the speed runs really short, isn't it?
Speaker 1: Actually it is.
Speaker 1: it's like 10 minutes long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I played shadow gate once in college.
Speaker 0: I had a fact on game facts open on one screen and the the ROM open on the other screen and I scrolled through the fact and did it and it took me like 20 minutes and it was just straight through Completely boring and bleh.
Speaker 0: The only fun you're gonna get from this game is from Trialing and erring and trying to figure it out.
Speaker 0: But that's gonna be mad frustrating because you'll die all over the place.
Speaker 1: It's not that.
Speaker 1: well, let's fast-forward back in time.
Speaker 1: I guess reverse would be better or rewind.
Speaker 1: Back to the future?
Speaker 1: Back to the past?
Speaker 1: Well ahead to the past if we fast-forward back to the future there anyway.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I'm like nine or however old I was when I owned this game and it was frustrating.
Speaker 1: But I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe I'm alone in this but I think a lot of you who played NES games would agree that There was this certain level of frustration where you wouldn't stop playing the game.
Speaker 1: It wasn't so frustrating that you'd say fuck it I'm just gonna beat break the game or sell it to my friend or not play it.
Speaker 1: But it wasn't so easy that you just beat it.
Speaker 1: it was just frustrating enough to where you'd think all right now I have to beat this game.
Speaker 1: I got to prove that I can beat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if you I played deja vu a lot more than I played shadow gate, but it was a better game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was but I actually have deja vu.
Speaker 0: one and two for the Game Boy Color.
Speaker 0: But I haven't played that.
Speaker 1: but I never played to me either.
Speaker 0: but I bought it at GameStop for like five bucks random.
Speaker 1: I think I wanted three dollars.
Speaker 1: I wanted it, but you bought it.
Speaker 1: Whatever lend it to me.
Speaker 1: I'll play him.
Speaker 0: It's Game Boy Color.
Speaker 0: you need a SP or something.
Speaker 0: anyway We got a bunch of SP when I played that game.
Speaker 0: the way I played it is.
Speaker 0: I would sit down and I would get Like maybe three or four screens into the game or five screens into the game and every time I played I already knew everything I had to do up to a certain point and then I would try different things and basically I just kept playing the game over and over and over and each time I Played I knew everything I had to do up to a certain point of the game.
Speaker 0: So it was sort of like it was.
Speaker 0: it was almost as if I had the game saved But I had to replay from the beginning every time because it was a Nintendo game.
Speaker 1: Well, at least I mean we said, you know death.
Speaker 1: all the time when you die You don't actually have to start over.
Speaker 1: All it does is weak like one of your torches burns out or something and your torch it whatever.
Speaker 1: you lose some torch power.
Speaker 0: That is one thing interesting in shadow gate is that you have these torches, right?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get to that.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So you have to keep a torch lit pretty much Always almost or else it gets dark and you can't see in bad things that.
Speaker 1: well if it's ever dark if there's ever a moment Where you were anywhere in the game and there's not a lit torch in the room or in your possession you immediately die.
Speaker 0: Yep, because the dark horrible nasties come out and get you but they're scared away by a small fire.
Speaker 0: So you have these supply of torches and every almost every room in the game has some torches lying around that you can take.
Speaker 0: But sometimes you'll take a torch and it'll actually be a lever that opens up something.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you take a torch and you'll die.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you'll take a torch and it won't be a normal torch It'll be a special center.
Speaker 1: That's my favorite part in the game.
Speaker 1: early on right you grab torches.
Speaker 1: So you feel like torch torch one.
Speaker 1: So it's like torches torches torch.
Speaker 1: I got eight torches and then I pick up this one torch and it just says torch on a separate line item.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: Why do I have ten torches but this one torch that look just like all the others?
Speaker 1: Torches and one torch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like what.
Speaker 0: why is that?
Speaker 1: Well, if you like that torch death.
Speaker 1: Oh, gee Yes, but uh if I'm gonna spoil something if you just decide to throw that torch at a wraith It kills the wraith but throwing another torch does death.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so arbitrary thing is part of the fun is to me the game was fun in an exploration way Because especially if you didn't cheat.
Speaker 1: and it was really fun in this kind of when I when I read choose your own adventure books As a kid right nominally I was trying to win but more importantly I was trying to get as many interesting gruesome deaths as I could and I basically sought out all the interesting deaths.
Speaker 0: It is a lot like a very advanced choose your own adventure game.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a part where like you run into his Sphinx and he's got some riddles for you.
Speaker 0: You know and like that's the kind of thing you'd see in a. choose your own adventure book is like maybe a riddle.
Speaker 0: Raise my right hand and then at your left at the bottom It would give you like three different potential riddle answers and say if you answer Go to page 10.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, if you answer riddle number two go to page.
Speaker 0: if your answer is, you know this answer go to page 20.
Speaker 1: Shadowgate was different though.
Speaker 1: You actually had to have an item and give it to the Sphinx.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why it was a very.
Speaker 0: It's a much more complex.
Speaker 0: choose your own adventure where instead of just having a few choices and you go to those pages It's.
Speaker 0: you have a lot of choices and most of them are death and you have to and you can actually use some sort of Twisted Nintendo logic to maybe figure it out.
Speaker 1: See Oh God, you know, I just realized.
Speaker 1: I don't think we've ever properly explained the phrase Nintendo logic Nintendo logic, let's see.
Speaker 0: Let's think of some real-world examples instead of some made-up example.
Speaker 1: Well, Nintendo logic is the.
Speaker 1: if the in video games Especially for NES gamers like a kid who's nine years old has been playing NES games There are solutions to problems that to a kid like that makes perfect sense but to any other human being are just ludicrous and Crazy Shadowgate is probably the most perfect example of that.
Speaker 1: I mean, all right There's a lake and there's a skeleton in it holding a key and there's an island on the other end and you can't go in The water the skeleton shark whatever gets you.
Speaker 1: Well, obviously I throw this glass sphere I found into the lake thereby freezing it Obviously or I make so much sense.
Speaker 1: I'm a plumber right mushrooms make me big, duh Or Maniac Mansion was really good about that, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so anytime there's you know a puzzle or of some sort and it's solved by something that makes no sense whatsoever.
Speaker 0: That's what we call Nintendo logic Like yeah throwing the banana over the top of the house is totally the only way to open the unlock the front door.
Speaker 0: You know something crazy like that where it makes sense within the context of this wacky video game usually an adventure game But in the real world, it makes no sense.
Speaker 1: I think partly it was just a suspension of disbelief.
Speaker 1: as a kid I wouldn't even think that doesn't make sense.
Speaker 0: I think yeah, I got it Like hey, I need to hear his example and uh, I need to get across this water.
Speaker 0: I know I'll give the monkey a banana and it'll build a bridge for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, right but this game is probably the core of all Nintendo logic because the game is mostly trial and error and For a lot of it if you're clever you can figure it out.
Speaker 0: For example, there's a part where you go into a room and it says the rooms getting hot And there's a bunch of treasure in the room and you want all of it and there's a dragon staring.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't see it.
Speaker 0: You don't know it's a drag.
Speaker 0: You see eyes.
Speaker 1: All right, you see a very scary looking thing.
Speaker 1: It's
Speaker 0: obviously a dragon because it's hot and it smells like brimstone and you see eyes looking at you through the wall And you know, there's a dragon gonna breathe fire on you and you know that there's a bunch of treasure in here that you want but you don't want to die as is gonna happen in This game and one of the treasures is shield.
Speaker 0: if you pick up the shield first The dragon will breathe fire and then you'll have a bit of time After the shield melts to get some treasure before running away.
Speaker 1: Or like an early part of the game you learn spells and the spells are all words.
Speaker 1: The first spell you learn is from a sign on the wall and if you look at the sign a few times you learn the spell and the spell is a poor and There's a coil or rope laying there and sure lo and behold if you cast that spell in that room that rope does something.
Speaker 0: It's like that stupid DC superhero chick who says things magic spells backwards and they happen.
Speaker 1: Oh, what the hell's her name?
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is a stupid underwear Stupid superhero and a stupid power and a stupid set of comics, but I digress but in Shadowgate not so stupid But seriously the other than that a lot of the stuff is just fucking random Some of its common sense.
Speaker 1: like for the longest time I never thought of this.
Speaker 1: but there's a point where you come into a room like in a field a courtyard and There's a Cyclops and if you try to get past him He kills you.
Speaker 1: and if you try to like stab him or something with the sword You've got he kills you because he's a better Cyclops and you're just a punk.
Speaker 1: But if you use the sling and you have a rock in the sling you knock him out All right, and I have like five rocks.
Speaker 1: So I go past him later.
Speaker 1: I gotta come back through that area.
Speaker 1: He's awake shit.
Speaker 1: I use my sling again.
Speaker 1: I come back later.
Speaker 1: He's awake shit.
Speaker 1: I'm running out of rocks and there's a limited number of rocks in the game.
Speaker 1: One day I realized wait a minute after he's knocked out.
Speaker 1: What if I stab him then?
Speaker 1: and sure enough It says you stabbed the Cyclops it dies bleeding into the ground blah blah blah and then it never bothers you again.
Speaker 0: Yep, but if you don't figure that out, you can only go through there five times.
Speaker 0: You don't need to go through there five times to beat the game, by the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless you really suck at the Sphinx riddles.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the thing is the game has a plot I guess technically.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know the plot because remember I read the novelization of that game.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: The plot is like you're the prince I think or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah You're going to castle castle shadow gate to stop the evil wizard who's going to summon the blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: It's going to destroy the world or something and the king is fucked.
Speaker 0: or something King.
Speaker 0: so you go around getting like the king's treasure and then you find the dead king and you take his ring and his staff or you and then you or like you use the king's stuff to open the final door in the game and then you go Through and is the evil wizard and then if he summons the big monster that looks like Godzilla and you have to kill it
Speaker 1: most of the I'd say about a third of the puzzles can be solved by being smart a third of them can be solved by bizarro fucking Nintendo logic and A third of them are missed puzzles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like God the worst one the only part of the game I actually looked up how to beat.
Speaker 1: there's a part where you find there's this room with three levers Okay and you can kind of manipulate them just randomly.
Speaker 1: if You think back to way way back in the game in the room where the Sphinx is sitting there's a stairway that goes up and Behind the Sphinx on the stairway is a bunch of lines kind of etched into it and it looks like background Whatever you wouldn't even think.
Speaker 1: to look there It turns out that's the pattern in which you have to move all the levers in order to make the thing happen completely unrelated Completely far away.
Speaker 0: Not not in any way.
Speaker 0: Would you make a connection between that and the levers now?
Speaker 1: That's why I hated mist because almost all of mist was bullshit like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like hey, what do I do here?
Speaker 0: well, if you had bothered to look at you know, the the Way, the chlorophyll was shaped on a leaf on the other side of the board No way connected to this.
Speaker 0: you would know that the correct pattern to place those things is, you know, CD QB RXV something.
Speaker 1: and I mean, I honestly despite the fact that the game is bad in a lot of gameplay regards.
Speaker 1: It is really fun to play.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing about this game is that what it lacks in I guess good adventuring it makes up for in charm.
Speaker 0: I mean the music is cool.
Speaker 1: The music is awesome.
Speaker 1: This game has some of the better Nintendo music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the music rocks.
Speaker 0: You walk around while all this stuff the game itself is kind of silly.
Speaker 0: a lot of the stuff is kind of cute Like you see a nice skeleton or there's like a shark in the water.
Speaker 0: And you know this stuff is just.
Speaker 0: it's got a good like feeling to it of like sort of like a happy Cool crazy kooky dungeon full of kooky stuff.
Speaker 1: Of course at the same time you start I mean nearly in the game anytime you see something like oh you start poking and fraud and using stuff and using stuff and The game trains you the same way.
Speaker 1: people who don't understand puppies train puppies by hitting you in the face with the newspaper.
Speaker 1: all the top death death death.
Speaker 1: So once you get like there's a point where you get to like the second part.
Speaker 0: even the most benign Actions will result in death.
Speaker 0: Hey, why don't I try using this on that?
Speaker 0: Okay, it does nothing.
Speaker 0: Why don't I try using this on that?
Speaker 0: it does nothing.
Speaker 0: I'll try using this on that death for no reason.
Speaker 1: when you get like to the second part of the game where now you're in Like this mansion and you like go get a lightning rod and put it up and get lightning to strike it by casting a spell To get the book to get the glasses to read the other book to clear the spell.
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah, that part of the game is really hard and difficult to do.
Speaker 1: But you start to get really paranoid and anytime you enter a new room you sit there thinking don't touch anything Don't touch anything.
Speaker 1: Don't look at anything.
Speaker 1: Don't do anything.
Speaker 0: Oh shit looking usually won't get you killed Yeah, but doing anything dead moving can get you killed.
Speaker 0: like there's some.
Speaker 0: there's some doors that if you just go in the door You die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are some doors.
Speaker 0: if you open them you die.
Speaker 0: There is some.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: sometimes the game will give you a choice of like two or three ways to go.
Speaker 0: If you choose the wrong way you die.
Speaker 0: You just have to figure it out.
Speaker 0: It sucks.
Speaker 1: It helps that the flavor text is really funny.
Speaker 0: The game rewards depending on when every different death sort of has different flavor text.
Speaker 1: Mostly yeah, almost all of it does.
Speaker 1: very few of them don't?
Speaker 1: you can also kill yourself.
Speaker 1: set yourself on fire.
Speaker 0: You can be like use torch on self.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 1: Oh And there's like a bunch of different potions potion one potion two potion three potion four.
Speaker 1: I think with one exception.
Speaker 0: They're all poison Way to go.
Speaker 1: a lot of items in that game are just fucking nothing.
Speaker 1: They'll just kill you if you use them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is what I look.
Speaker 0: I do like that when games give you stuff in your inventory.
Speaker 0: That's just not necessary.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like when someone's trying to solve a riddle and you give them a bunch of extra information.
Speaker 0: That doesn't actually mean anything and it throws them way off course.
Speaker 0: It's like hey Sort of like petals around the roads.
Speaker 0: The reason that's so hard is all the extra information.
Speaker 0: That's not necessary.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, I taught that game to Emily's dad and it's really bugging him and he wants to solve it.
Speaker 0: I just did what.
Speaker 0: there's a bunch of extra information there that you don't need to look at.
Speaker 1: I don't think he listens to our show regularly.
Speaker 1: Oh, well,
Speaker 0: I guess that's his loss And he'll say my shadow gate, I don't know I just
Speaker 1: it kind of gives me this feeling of exploring like While the game is weird and fucked up it's every screen is really interesting and the way you interact with a lot of things is really interesting and If nothing else I think of it as an exploration game and I'm exploring this screwed up world And I don't care if I beat the game because that's really hard Like getting some weird item and using it on something and making something happen and seeing a new screen with a weird graphic is kind Of cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean just looking at pictures of all the screens would be enough plus the flavor text also.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I didn't find a video of a bunch of deaths from the game But I found that speedrun.
Speaker 1: if you want to play the game though Don't watch much of the speedrun or you're not gonna be able to play the game and enjoy it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Just get the ROM or whatever because I think that's the only way to get this game nowadays and don't play any other versions of it.
Speaker 0: don't play like sequels or 64 versions or anything though.
Speaker 1: do play deja vu because it is overall a much better game.
Speaker 0: a Deja vu is the same kind of game only better and it's sort of like one.
Speaker 1: It's right up our alley.
Speaker 1: It's like 2030s gangsters something mafia something film noir something really cool theme.
Speaker 1: the characters are cool and Most of the puzzles you can figure out by being smart and by reading text and not just random death Most of them anyway, and there is a plot the only.
Speaker 0: there's only a couple fit arbitrary things in deja vu But like exactly how you end the game is not immediately obvious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you figure that out.
Speaker 1: if you're not an idiot Yeah, I figured it out.
Speaker 1: eventually if you don't figure it out.
Speaker 1: That means you didn't understand the plot.
Speaker 1: yet Why don't you figure out the plot?
Speaker 0: You're like, ah It's not so easy to understand.
Speaker 0: the plot like gives you everything you need But it doesn't fill in all the blanks.
Speaker 0: you sort of to fill in some on your own.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I kind of like that.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not the best either but it's better than shadow.
Speaker 1: The only real problem with deja vu is that you can totally fuck yourself.
Speaker 1: the first time I got to the end of the game I went to the bungalow.
Speaker 1: I had every day.
Speaker 1: I got all the shit.
Speaker 0: You didn't have enough money to get back in the cab.
Speaker 1: I didn't have any more quarters, so I couldn't take the cab back, but I had a $20 bill.
Speaker 1: But the cabbie wouldn't give me change and it wouldn't.
Speaker 1: just let me give him the 20 and not take change.
Speaker 1: And if I tried to leave the cab, he called the cops and if I tried to shoot him he called the cops.
Speaker 1: Yep, yeah Granted I was very satisfied when I found the people who did this to me Instead of you know getting the evidence and calling the cops.
Speaker 1: I just shot him both in their beds And then the cops came and took me away, but whatever I got revenge.
Speaker 0: That's not how you end the game.
Speaker 1: You can in the game that way.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: There's a losing end.
Speaker 1: I see there's a bunch of different ends and I feel like that's a victory in a way.
Speaker 0: It's a losing end.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like the week ending and Simon's quest.
Speaker 0: No, it's also a losing end.
Speaker 0: There's only one good ending in deja vu the correct at the one that lets you see the credits.
Speaker 0: That's the real ending.
Speaker 1: All right, right.
Speaker 1: I think we're done.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.