Speaker 1: It's Monday June 11th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we talk a bit about raid.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well for anyone who thinks that we are wizards of all technology I submit that I am only a wizard of digital technology.
Speaker 0: when it comes to analog technology I am the fail.
Speaker 1: how?
Speaker 1: so what did you do?
Speaker 0: well?
Speaker 0: I want to get a parking permit for the the beacon train station right and I hate Sending mail.
Speaker 0: just cuz I have to get a stamp and go to the post office and go out of my way And it kind of sucks, so I don't even open my mail anymore really.
Speaker 1: I just kind of let it pile up and then after a month.
Speaker 1: I kind of go through it.
Speaker 0: I only know I know what like think certain mail looks like and I know what other mail looks like.
Speaker 0: so only certain mail gets Opened right away and certain mail just gets thrown out without even being open all my bills.
Speaker 1: Everything is electronic.
Speaker 1: the only things I get in the mail are wedding invitations.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Get more packages than letters anyway.
Speaker 0: So I don't want to mail them the application and they couldn't.
Speaker 0: I couldn't do it by internet or by phone or anything like that But I could do it by fax.
Speaker 0: So I filled out the form and faxed it to them on my own volition according to what their website said.
Speaker 1: All right, did you use a cover sheet?
Speaker 0: No?
Speaker 0: Such a thing existed.
Speaker 0: But anyway, they never ever responded to me, and I was lazy and the parking is relatively cheap here.
Speaker 0: So I didn't care that much.
Speaker 0: and today.
Speaker 0: I said all right.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try this again.
Speaker 0: So first I called them, and I was cuz.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say hey I'm about to fax you this.
Speaker 0: tell me if you get it right, so I'm like all right are there parking permits?
Speaker 0: Yes, we have permits, so I just my fax to the application.
Speaker 0: You'll send me the permit.
Speaker 0: Yes That's what we'll do all right, and I realized when I when I did the faxing I went over to the fax machine with the filled out form.
Speaker 0: I put it in.
Speaker 1: did you put the paper in upside down and Fax them a blank sheet of paper.
Speaker 0: I punched in the phone number, and it just didn't work.
Speaker 0: It was like dee dee dee dee dee dee something.
Speaker 0: it made a shit ton of noise And it sucked.
Speaker 0: so someone next door who you know someone in the next cube or whatever who knew?
Speaker 0: How to use.
Speaker 0: the machine came over and he's like you got a good nine and then one?
Speaker 0: That's pretty obvious, and then the number.
Speaker 0: yeah, and also you're correct this fax machine.
Speaker 0: You have to put the piece of paper with the text facing away from you.
Speaker 1: You do realize that every fax machine or anything like that There's a little icon right there with the paper and that tells you which way the text.
Speaker 0: I think there was no such like it's there.
Speaker 1: I practically guarantee it.
Speaker 0: well anyway I had apparently previously faxed them a white sheet of paper.
Speaker 0: This time.
Speaker 1: well you know I realized that in that case the cover sheet wouldn't help you because it just would have been two Blank sheets of paper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't believe the fax machine can even fax a blank piece of paper wouldn't it say hey That's a blank piece of paper there you realize how old and dumb fax technology is.
Speaker 0: it's such shit They really need to.
Speaker 0: people just need to like not PDFs attached to email at least come on.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah I really and that's if you suck you really what you should have is some sort of Like document sharing sort of thing going on.
Speaker 1: well I actually I have to use fax machines pretty often, so I'm just used to them But I don't like them, and I can't really blame you for having trouble.
Speaker 0: It's not just fax machines that I can't use it's pretty much all analog devices.
Speaker 0: I just have a problem.
Speaker 1: Well your phone is digital.
Speaker 0: No my telephone.
Speaker 0: Yes, but like landline phones.
Speaker 0: I'm no good like voicemails not so good.
Speaker 1: What trouble?
Speaker 1: can you have a voicemail leave a message beep message?
Speaker 0: I always like leave.
Speaker 0: I always like fail to delete the voicemail or accidentally save it.
Speaker 1: Ah, I thought you meant you have trouble using other people's voicemail.
Speaker 1: like you get the voicemail You just don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: Oh and when it cut that's the other thing.
Speaker 0: It's like my cell phone.
Speaker 0: I'm alright because it has like menus and things like that the phones at work even though they're voip.
Speaker 0: It's like I can't do.
Speaker 0: I can barely make a call.
Speaker 0: Actually my current company unlike IBM transferring a phone call give up.
Speaker 0: I can't do it.
Speaker 1: There was everything was out like there were documents on the website.
Speaker 1: So if I need to know how to dial internally in the PBX is and all that I could just go to this website.
Speaker 1: It would say you know dial six seven to call this facility and blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: then the extension and my current work?
Speaker 1: No, there's really no documentation for it at all.
Speaker 1: so I realized one day that I had no idea how to call anyone Anywhere other than with the full phone number.
Speaker 1: So I ended up always going nine one area code phone number to call someone in the cubicle down from me.
Speaker 0: yeah, I Think that's the one thing I do know.
Speaker 0: if it's you know someone's extension You can pretty much just type the extension.
Speaker 1: It'll work only if you work in a really small place because usually there'll be a bunch of different sites or different Categories different areas.
Speaker 1: like an IBM.
Speaker 1: you had to dial for to get some people's extensions.
Speaker 1: You had to dial three four to get other people's extensions.
Speaker 1: Ah Yeah, I've never worked at a small company.
Speaker 0: But in that case right the extension would be like.
Speaker 0: if your extension was like 100 right and they were I would just on my Business card.
Speaker 0: I would make my extension three four X 100 or something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah But that doesn't help because you never give your business card to the internal people.
Speaker 1: as for the external people we give the real phone Number that connects you to the outside world I'm talking about if I have to call Bob and receiving to find out if my package came.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I know his big phone number, and I know his extension But I don't know which number I have to append or prepend or whatever to get to that extension short of dialing the whole Thing at work.
Speaker 0: They actually do have a pretty cool system where I am now where like my extension until before the phone broke was 666 right because it was the phone from the conference room.
Speaker 0: and If you want to call that phone It's like phone number phone numbers 666 and it's like they actually just got real phone numbers that end with the Extension for each and every phone.
Speaker 0: so everyone sort of has their own phone number.
Speaker 0: as opposed You can also call the main phone number and then dial the extension or you within the office just the extension.
Speaker 0: But it's pretty cool because you have a real full phone number where the last four digits happen to be your extension And that's neat.
Speaker 1: so the very least you think you got the faxes under control now.
Speaker 1: You think you could send a fax.
Speaker 0: I think I can send a fax.
Speaker 0: We'll see if I get a parking permit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just sent a bunch of faxes a little while ago.
Speaker 1: actually yeah earlier today.
Speaker 0: fax machines need to die.
Speaker 0: There's a reason that like cool people like when they get faxes they automatically go into email.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is one day people get up like an email with a PDF.
Speaker 0: They're gonna push the fax button It's gonna go over the telephone line to someone else's end where it gets turned into an email with a PDF.
Speaker 1: the reason faxes still exist seems to be that people For some reason trust signatures.
Speaker 1: still so if you want to send an official document to someone they always want you to fax it.
Speaker 1: That way they've got a copy of your signature Which is just a scribble that anyone could duplicate and handwriting analysis is pretty much made up.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile they don't trust electronic signatures.
Speaker 1: You know like a PGP signing or a GPG that which is perfect it.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: It's not perfect.
Speaker 0: It's effectively perfect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's effectively perfect.
Speaker 1: It's so much more provable that I did or did not sign something with that than it is with a blurry scribble on a piece of paper that I Sent over an analog phone line.
Speaker 1: well technically most phone lines convert to digital anyway, but you get the point yep.
Speaker 1: anyway in the news There's a story about a blogger getting kicked out of an NCAA game for blogging.
Speaker 1: live at the event.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's actually whether you know it or not.
Speaker 0: It's sort of illegal to cover sporting events if you are like licensed to do it like if you go to a football game.
Speaker 0: It's technically illegal to like call someone on the phone and tell them what's happening at the game while it happens.
Speaker 0: like there was a problem With that where people would watch a game on TV in an area where there was a blackout and then they would set up a pirate radio station and Like call the game as they watched it on TV.
Speaker 0: So people in the blackout area could listen to it on the radio and a lot of people got busted for that.
Speaker 1: Yep, now the story itself is kind of sensationalistic.
Speaker 1: It wasn't just oh he's blogging.
Speaker 1: they actually were specifically prohibited from blogging live Ahead of time and decided to try and do it anyway.
Speaker 1: I pretty much just ignore the headlines and digger slash data.
Speaker 1: I just read the comments and find out There's always the one comment right away that says what actually happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just noticed this trend lately where it's like people Seem to think that you know if they think that something should be free like yes You should be free to blog whatever you want, but you know, it's not illegal I agree.
Speaker 0: But when there's things that are specifically prohibited like you cannot bring a camera into this concert People are starting to like take a little too far.
Speaker 0: and it's like no that it really is prohibited.
Speaker 0: and yes They do have a right to prohibit that.
Speaker 0: and no you don't have a right to go in there.
Speaker 0: And yes, they can just take away your ticket.
Speaker 0: You better listen to them or the?
Speaker 0: I have no sympathy for you.
Speaker 1: but yet at the same time all of this that they do is Obviously nothing more than trying to control and protect their revenue stream, which is based solely on Selling the information that is being generated at these events.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: I agree that if I was them I would not have the same policy the same way.
Speaker 0: you know people like the Grateful Dead don't have the same policy and it works out really well because you're not stupid.
Speaker 0: but the It's not wrong for them to have it.
Speaker 0: It's not evil.
Speaker 0: It's not unconstitutional It's perfectly legal and right in every way.
Speaker 0: They're allowed to do that.
Speaker 1: Well, I think you should be allowed more down to the issue that Originally back in the day when they made all these rules and decided like oh we're going to not let people see you.
Speaker 1: Well, make sure they don't sneak recording equipment in.
Speaker 1: Recording equipment was big and expensive and heavy and easy to see and not many people had it.
Speaker 1: It was hard to get away with that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: now everyone's phone is Connected to the internet and as a camera and as a video camera and as a recorder and things are getting smaller.
Speaker 1: and again I mean even I remember I used to go to Red Wings games a lot as a kid and my mom Had that.
Speaker 1: the rule was kind of complicated where you couldn't have Bigger than a certain size lens if you came to a hockey game Because they wanted to sell you the official pictures of the game Instead of letting you take high-quality ones on your own.
Speaker 0: and also the only people allowed to take high-quality photos like press Photographers and things like.
Speaker 1: well, my mom had a very very small looking camera, but when you turned it on it went and Was an ad.
Speaker 1: I mean it wasn't an SLR crazy camera But it was super super high quality and way beyond the rule.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and every time we go to a hockey game They'd look at it and it said how big the lens wasn't all that stuff on the front But she just put some tape over that and they'd look at it and they didn't know anything about cameras.
Speaker 1: They just let her in.
Speaker 1: but one day they said hey, wait a minute turn that camera on.
Speaker 1: it went.
Speaker 1: They said alright, you can't bring that camera in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go put it in your car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, uh, she just walks right over to a line like two doors down and just walks in there.
Speaker 1: nice Like there's just.
Speaker 1: there's no way to prevent this sort of thing from happening No matter how many rules you make no matter how many people you arrest.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's cliche to say that information wants to be free But at the same time people want to make information free and will take great risks and go to great lengths to do so.
Speaker 0: But at the same time While I agree with everything you just said I have no sympathy for the guy sitting in the movie theater with the video camera.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 0: And he says this is this is oppression.
Speaker 0: They kicked me out of the movie theater for videotaping the movie and I'll say yeah, cuz you can't do that dumbass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time if someone was at a baseball game and they were typing up blog posts about the baseball game or covering The baseball game on their own.
Speaker 1: it does bother me that you could have a monopoly on the factual Press coverage of an event, but at the same time it's technically a private event But yet then you're broadcasting the event public.
Speaker 1: I mean technically.
Speaker 0: well, they don't.
Speaker 0: they don't have a monopoly on the press coverage but it's that you are prohibited from Like because the you have to do it with a press pass.
Speaker 1: Here's my.
Speaker 1: alright, so they they don't want not like non approved press from coming in and doing this.
Speaker 0: No, it's not that they don't want not approved press.
Speaker 0: They don't care.
Speaker 0: what you say about the baseball game of the basketball game is that they don't care.
Speaker 0: they care about you Telling people what's happening while the game is going on.
Speaker 0: Don't want you to confess with the TV and the radio.
Speaker 1: No, that's not where I was going with this.
Speaker 1: All right, so all right.
Speaker 1: so to prevent this they have all these rules about how you can't broadcast stuff out of the stadium or whatever.
Speaker 1: what if Happen to have a geosynchronous satellite over the stadium and I just have a real-time camera pointed at it.
Speaker 1: I'm not in the stadium I'm just filming something from public property and I happen to be distributing it on the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah now could they go after me?
Speaker 0: Where are you space?
Speaker 0: Are you in space?
Speaker 1: I'm not in space.
Speaker 1: Where's your company?
Speaker 1: No, no company.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that you were filming something that is publicly viewable from a public space.
Speaker 0: See, there's nothing wrong with the filming it.
Speaker 0: it's that they wouldn't care about that.
Speaker 0: the thing that they would get you for is the Distribution of it without expressed written consent.
Speaker 1: but yet photography.
Speaker 1: if you take a picture of something from public space and There was no reasonable expectation of privacy.
Speaker 1: Then you can distribute that picture all you want.
Speaker 1: Yes, you could You know, you know depending somewhat on the country and our state you live in.
Speaker 0: but yeah, the other thing is that Watching a baseball game from space not too exciting.
Speaker 1: Hey, I'm zoomed in enough.
Speaker 1: I mean there's gonna be some bit of delay until we get some sort of quantum transport device.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically, they're just.
Speaker 0: they're gonna use every legal means necessary to just because they make an agreement with like a TV company saying you Will be the only people broadcasting this in these areas and they make an agreement with the radio station saying you will be the only people to you know.
Speaker 0: Share this information live as it happens in these areas and you'll be the only website to do, you know.
Speaker 0: So if they don't want you to be able to compete with those exclusive agreements Without paying up That's all they're trying to prevent so that people don't not watch TV and not listen to the radio and instead go to your pirate Website.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time f1 in the very least has shown us why this fails.
Speaker 0: because f1 is a prime example.
Speaker 1: There are people who want to cover it and people who want to see it but it's not easy to see and it's not easy to get and All the coverage is really exclusive and hard to find and you really have to pirate it or pay a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Yep, the way because the way f1 is done is there's a company.
Speaker 0: the guy who sort of runs the business side of the FIA is Bernie Ecclestone Ecclestone everyone to say it and he owns this a lot of companies but this broadcasting company and every f1 race has this same people filming it and So in every single country in the world like the US Germany France Italy It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: if you're watching the f1 race You're all seeing the exact same cameras the people who are calling the race.
Speaker 0: the announcers are different for each country Of course because different languages and everything and they're watching the same video feed that you're watching.
Speaker 0: They're not like looking around They're not at the track.
Speaker 0: usually unless the you know They happen the the race happens to be in your country and they're watching this.
Speaker 0: everyone's watching the same video feed.
Speaker 0: you're watching and just talking and It kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: because the people announcing, you know Usually they like to have some coordination with the people who control the cameras like hey, we'd really like to see that.
Speaker 0: Hey, we'd really like to see that.
Speaker 0: Why don't we look over there?
Speaker 0: when I look over there, you know If you're in Spain, you want to see what the Spanish drivers are doing if you're in France You want to see the French driver is doing not Show everyone in the entire world the same exact thing and it doesn't really work out and it's not HD.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I just think that is actually hurting the sport.
Speaker 1: It's hurting it tremendously, but they don't seem to realize Helping their wallets tremendously.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is I mean, maybe they don't realize that it could be more popular But I think they do realize that what they're doing now makes them a lot of money So they probably don't care they.
Speaker 0: I don't think they care about f1 being popular.
Speaker 0: They're sort of like with the pomp and the.
Speaker 0: you know The prestige and all that highfalutin business and they're really big, you know, they don't really want a bajillion fans.
Speaker 0: They want few very rich and snooty fans Because that's what they are the few rich and the snooty.
Speaker 1: of course.
Speaker 1: I guess the moral here is uh Do everything you can to pirate sporting events then broadcast them to the world, but don't complain if you get busted because yeah You're not.
Speaker 1: well complain about the policy, but don't complain about the fact that you got caught.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's not a policy I would implement but it is a fair and you gotta be like I'm a bootlegger, baby.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh I have a news also So I'm just gonna say this really quick.
Speaker 0: Is that Apple announced that they're putting out Safari for Windows?
Speaker 0: and There's not much I got to say about that.
Speaker 1: Nah, I don't see the market because there aren't many people I get.
Speaker 1: I. the only people I could see caring about this are people who have either a Windows laptop or Work in a company that doesn't have Macs which means work at a company.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you're a web developer and you want to see how your website works.
Speaker 1: I was just saying they use Macs at home and it bothers them that they can't get their Safari anywhere else.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing Safari runs in this the same web browsing rendering engine that Conqueror does.
Speaker 0: it's very fast and it's got some niceness to it like the custom widgets that match your you know OS widget set and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But and it's it's fairly standards compliant very standards compliant in many cases But a lot of things don't work in it and it's not really all that useful.
Speaker 0: and like the tabs in Safari are all not Even half as good as the Firefox tabs and it just is it does not any extensions for it really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I honestly I ranked Safari third after well, obviously Firefox Number one and then after opera.
Speaker 0: Yeah, an opera is really The only reason I don't use opera because it is faster and has a little better set than Firefox.
Speaker 0: extensions Extensions and the keyboard shortcuts are off.
Speaker 1: I honestly opera had a use when we use the Mac before we realized that we can just zoom in straight up because it has.
Speaker 0: the Opera has the better zooming function where it actually resizes the images as well as the text.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you might as well just go one step further if you're zooming in anyway And just use actual zoom in on your desktop technology.
Speaker 0: Yep, but yeah Safaris not that great a browser.
Speaker 0: It's gonna have a real hard time competing with because on the Mac It doesn't really have to compete because Mac users either use that or Firefox.
Speaker 0: There's no IE.
Speaker 0: No one uses opera on the Mac.
Speaker 0: that that's just stupid.
Speaker 0: and on Windows.
Speaker 0: You've got Firefox IE7 which isn't that bad?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used it a little bit since I'm still having troubles with Linux So I keep ending up in Windows and I tried it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like the advantage ie has.
Speaker 0: in Windows It's pre-installed.
Speaker 0: the advantage Safari has in Mac is pre-installed.
Speaker 0: if Safari is not pre-installed You're gonna have a hard time beating Firefox which is also not pre-installed.
Speaker 0: Yeah and better.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, but yet the actual news I want to talk about is this drobo thing.
Speaker 0: Drobo drobo.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if it stands for disk robot or drive robot, but there's nothing robotic about it.
Speaker 1: I think it's pretty obvious.
Speaker 1: stands for dr.
Speaker 1: Abbot.
Speaker 0: Oh obviously that bastard Him and his doctor about.
Speaker 0: okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the basically this is a box.
Speaker 0: It's pretty fancy if you've ever wanted to set up like a raid or some sort of storage array or like.
Speaker 0: you have a whole lot of hard drives mainly for because that's all it can hold and You want to turn them into one big hard drive?
Speaker 0: This thing does it from a user interface perspective better than anything else has ever done it?
Speaker 1: Yeah from the way Scott described it to me Thusly plug four drives into it and then plug the USB in.
Speaker 0: that's pretty much all you have to do.
Speaker 0: It's got four holes for force here.
Speaker 0: any serial ATA drive will work.
Speaker 0: any serial ATA drive any any and you plug them in you just slide them right in there and it has lights for each one.
Speaker 0: and When the drive is sort of like doing its business the light will be sort of yellow like hey This drive isn't ready.
Speaker 0: yet when the drive is ready.
Speaker 0: It's green and when the drive is broken It's red.
Speaker 0: and if the light is red you just take the drive out and put a new drive in the spot.
Speaker 1: so what kind of striping a raid or whatever does it do?
Speaker 1: because doesn't?
Speaker 1: obviously it has some sort of parity because otherwise a Broken drive you wouldn't just swap it out.
Speaker 1: You'd be fucked.
Speaker 0: It doesn't use any of the like the raids that we know it like.
Speaker 0: it's not just a raid 5.
Speaker 0: It's not just a raid 6.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like great six.
Speaker 0: It's something else that is not known to us but it can be that way because it's like it's a special box that does things its own special way and It doesn't have to be something that we know about because it's sort of like this.
Speaker 0: It just works what you know.
Speaker 0: and while I like things to be open source and well-known if it just works What the hell do I care as long as it works?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not like unless they had secret firmware that would look for credit card numbers on your hard drive.
Speaker 0: But you plug this thing into your computer.
Speaker 0: It just sees it as a normal external USB hard drive.
Speaker 1: I guess all I want I would wait for is I want what I want is that thing that little four-way spider With a serial ATA hole or a SCSI hole on the end instead of USB.
Speaker 0: Yes, they're going to make ones supposedly with with ES ATAs or Fire wires or something else and better USB is probably what I really want.
Speaker 0: The only problem I have with this device is that it's an external hard drive as opposed to a network attached hard drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah If only it had like an RJ45 and a little web server.
Speaker 0: What you have to do with this is you have to plug this into a computer that on that computer You have to make a file server of some sort.
Speaker 0: It should have the file server in it.
Speaker 0: So I just plug it into my router put it next to my router and now every computer on my network can read and write To it like it's some sort of network drive.
Speaker 1: See sadly Scott and I for the longest time were Planning like.
Speaker 1: we kept like periodically looking at the prices of hard drives and sans and nazis and all those things.
Speaker 1: We wanted a gigantic file server.
Speaker 1: We could put all our music all our everything other than our personal files on it back everything up to it put geek nights on It and be our permanent storage in the house forever.
Speaker 1: But every time it always cost a little bit too much.
Speaker 1: We didn't worry about it.
Speaker 1: And now I realize that with my new computer once I get the motherboard working fully I think I'm just gonna build a big raid 5 in my computer and use that Because it's so much cheaper than any other solution out there.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus I got these 10 saders.
Speaker 1: I gotta use them for something.
Speaker 0: You don't have to use it I have to.
Speaker 1: it bothers me that I have all these saders and I'm not using any of them.
Speaker 1: I'm using you.
Speaker 0: It's a big thing on in gadget here that compares all the the features of raid 5 with the features of the Drobo and the Drobo is sort of slightly better in some ways and Equal and others and I'll have to read that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty cool And it the coolest thing about it I like is the lights on it because you know as the lights that tell you if a drive is working or not It has these blue lights at the bottom where as you're filling up your storage space more blue lights will turn on and as you You know, if you take a drive out put a bigger one in.
Speaker 0: they'll try it.
Speaker 0: the lights kind of turn off.
Speaker 0: So you have a visual thing looking at it how much space is left to put data on?
Speaker 0: It also has some other things that tell you like how hot the box is in case it's overheating and stuff like that All with just colored and nicely shaped and positioned LEDs Which is more than a lot of those expensive NASA's have huh?
Speaker 0: And the thing is only five hundred dollars Which is not bad at all.
Speaker 1: five hundred dollars without drives without drives.
Speaker 0: But a lot of those NASA's that are not as good as this except for the fact that they have file sir Oh except for the fact that they have the one thing we need.
Speaker 0: but they're also normal raid and not the superior Drobo thing and they also don't have the Helpful LEDs and they also are a pain in the ass to get to work.
Speaker 1: Oh Superior is it?
Speaker 1: I mean are there bad?
Speaker 1: they have benchmarks showing performance differences.
Speaker 0: Oh, they've got all this.
Speaker 1: What about?
Speaker 1: how does it affect the MTBF?
Speaker 1: because different kinds of raid are?
Speaker 1: varying have varying levels of Stress.
Speaker 1: they put on drives and raid tends to kill drives and better raid tends to kill drives more quickly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well is the whole thing about it on engage it that you can read?
Speaker 1: I got it Because I really would wonder how reliable it is and it seems pretty good to me.
Speaker 0: I think some of the best features are like it works with only one drive but you need at least two drives for redundancy and the Whereas if you unarrayed five like the redundancy overhead if you have like four two hundred and fifty gig drives you get a seven hundred and fifty gig array, but with a Drobo to 250 gig drives and to 500 gig drives is a one terabyte array.
Speaker 0: you see That's interesting.
Speaker 1: yeah, but I wonder because that means that there's some sort of the distributing parity in a different way or it's not symmetrical and I wonder if that wouldn't put a lot more stress on the drives.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: but or either that or what hurt the performance It could hurt the performance but that you know what the problem is It's impossible to tell because you as limited by USB I'll bet I'll bet that it because it's on USB 2 is the only reason it's better.
Speaker 1: and if you weren't limited by that I think you'd see a serious performance deficit compared to standard raid.
Speaker 0: Yeah But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: if you are The kind of person who's gonna buy this is a home user who wants to store their photos or the videos of the music.
Speaker 0: You don't need fucking performance on that.
Speaker 0: It's not like some giant database hosting god-knows-what.
Speaker 0: for that you get like a sad or something.
Speaker 0: if you're just storing your photos It's gonna take less than a second to store the photo over the USB to no matter what.
Speaker 1: so But at the same time performance at the same time Those people are the people who are much less likely to buy this strange contraption.
Speaker 0: and then well That's the thing is that this is a nice friendly box.
Speaker 0: I mean look at that.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not some strange contraption.
Speaker 0: It's targeted trying to get people who you know have a whole bunch of photos or whatever and just want to you know A nice only kind of thing, but then those people have to buy four of these big ugly metal boxy things.
Speaker 0: You just buy two plus.
Speaker 0: a lot of people are like selling it in packages with drives and things like that.
Speaker 1: So now that's a good idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah I just think that the target audience of this wouldn't really be willing to buy hard drives might have difficulty.
Speaker 0: I think the target audience is sort of those middle people like You know people who don't know as much about like as much about technology as we do.
Speaker 0: But they're you know, the kind of people who down have like a hundred DVDs of burned fan subs.
Speaker 0: But they don't know shit about computers.
Speaker 0: but they know how to do.
Speaker 0: they know how to do this and they're always Complaining about how their raids don't work and they want they keep asking us how they should partition their drives.
Speaker 0: Those people are gonna buy this thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah I thought those people just burned everything to DVD and then made gigantic Spindles that they never opened again.
Speaker 0: Well now they're gonna buy like three drobos instead.
Speaker 1: god I remember there's this one kid at RIT always came to the club and he had You know those like 200 CD spindles you can buy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: He had two of those full of CDs With burned anime.
Speaker 1: I never understood those people and they were in his dorm room covered in dust.
Speaker 0: Why do you save?
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 1: Well, even the fact that he saved him on a medium where it was almost impossible to get any given episode you wanted out Of that mess, you know It's like.
Speaker 0: I don't even understand the people who collect Physical things like just collect them like collect comic books to have not to read but to have.
Speaker 0: So I really don't understand someone who collects digital non-physical things.
Speaker 1: I can understand people who collect just to have if they're historians.
Speaker 0: Well, yes Because then you're actually getting a purpose out of it not just to have as in just to have not for any other purpose.
Speaker 1: But I thought when I bought a hundred copies of Cyclops and Jean Grey getting married that I was making an investment?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure Things of the day.
Speaker 1: So, uh, we really don't like American Idol and all of the sort of effluvia surrounding that business.
Speaker 0: I don't even watch TV.
Speaker 0: So there's definitely no way I'm gonna be in on this reality TV Which is really just a fancy way of saying New Age game show.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is I didn't.
Speaker 1: what really bothered me about American Idol because it was off and on when I went to go get My laundry or whatever would be that the singing was usually really bad and it was kind of this Warbly modern can't hold a note for any given amount of time.
Speaker 1: They were all singing the same kind of music.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: the show just was really painful and it bothered me.
Speaker 1: I didn't like it.
Speaker 0: I'm much more a fan of what was that show?
Speaker 0: star search that old one.
Speaker 1: Yeah any any kind of old variety show?
Speaker 1: I like.
Speaker 0: yeah, I like those.
Speaker 1: In fact, I wish there were variety shows.
Speaker 0: I think there are but just they're not so much in the US anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not so much in the US.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we caught this clip on YouTube.
Speaker 1: wasn't from American Idol or something else I think it was.
Speaker 0: they said it was from like Something Britain.
Speaker 1: see that would make sense because they're a little bit more cultured on the other side.
Speaker 1: Yep So at least as far as the accents would lead us to believe I think we've talked about that before God, I should.
Speaker 1: I'll have to tell that anecdote about that pocket watch and what it did to us at the wedding.
Speaker 0: All right, but anyway do anything to me?
Speaker 1: Well, I did.
Speaker 1: you didn't have it.
Speaker 1: You were not forced to speak in a terrible British accent while holding a pocket watch up Constantly.
Speaker 0: if I had a pocket watch I would not speak in a terrible British accent.
Speaker 1: You have to it's part of having a pocket watch.
Speaker 1: It's one step away from a monocle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I had a monocle, I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be all British though.
Speaker 0: I would be all railroad tycoon Ah equally good equally good.
Speaker 1: I do say the railroad blub anyway.
Speaker 1: So this guy comes out and says I'm going to sing some opera for you and everyone goes, huh?
Speaker 1: And he sings opera pretty damn well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I. the thing was is like I was going backwards through the dig videos.
Speaker 0: So there was a video of Pavarotti singing the same song and then I go back two pages and then there's this guy and I'm like, oh They posted the Pavarotti because they saw this one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see what you did there So it wasn't so impressive.
Speaker 0: after watch it's like watching Michael Schumacher drive and then watching some guy drive the same course.
Speaker 1: Granted it was still very impressive.
Speaker 0: It was it was you look at the guy and you're like, alright, you're gonna sing opera Let's see this.
Speaker 0: and then you're like, oh, hey He was no Pavarotti, but it was pretty damn good.
Speaker 1: And I got to say I was happy that the audience reacted positively very positively Which was somewhat surprising because most people I talked to express in the least a mild dislike of opera.
Speaker 1: Not many people I know are fans of opera.
Speaker 0: I think what it is is a lot of people You'd say they don't like opera don't know about it.
Speaker 1: Never seen.
Speaker 0: actually Really listen to it.
Speaker 1: or or there are people who liked opera and then went to see fucking God.
Speaker 1: or Dammer on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that thing is.
Speaker 0: I thought it was Dammer on.
Speaker 1: it's the the you know, the the the last of the Ring cycle.
Speaker 1: Yeah and everybody dies and it's just freaking long and the overture takes forever and it just it won't end and it just keeps going.
Speaker 1: and I fell asleep twice.
Speaker 1: Ah,
Speaker 0: I saw the Romeo and Juliet opera once like the afternoon at Lincoln Center And the only problem I had with it is that okay, you know, everyone sings really well, that's cool You know and it's Romeo and Juliet, which is also cool and it's in Italian Which normally I'd have no problem with but it's in Italian and I kind of want to know what they're saying Even though I could kind of guess I'd like to know.
Speaker 1: well, you know good opera house They either give you a libretto with translations or they have the little screen.
Speaker 0: they have the little LED readout on the chair in front of you and you you can't see anyone else's because the angle the Viewing angle of them is exactly straight on.
Speaker 0: so you only see your own and if you look over the shoulder of the person In front of you, you can see theirs and you just like one row of them all the way down to the front.
Speaker 0: But and I'm looking at that.
Speaker 0: I'm not looking at the stage.
Speaker 0: It's not like subtitles on an anime where I can see both.
Speaker 0: Well, you're usually not missing too much I know I know but they had really fancy costumes and I only barely remember them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think my favorite is still Don Giovanni.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever I like opera you should like opera too.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about the.
Speaker 0: we talked about the browser and now we're talking about the.
Speaker 1: yeah, I didn't realize that We could have made a joke, but we didn't we?
Speaker 0: just I just made the joke.
Speaker 1: No, you didn't.
Speaker 1: You didn't make the joke.
Speaker 1: You just made a reference to it.
Speaker 1: That's you pointed out that you at least you were a step above the person the people.
Speaker 1: we used to know a guy.
Speaker 0: This is a C programming joke.
Speaker 1: Just put like a little asterisk on there and you got the joke, uh But We used to know a guy who would always and sadly it's a very easy thing to pick up and start doing subconsciously.
Speaker 1: You know, sometimes someone says something and you know that you could make a joke about it or there's a joke there But you're don't come up with the joke.
Speaker 1: What do you do is he'd always whenever that situation come up say something like well, I could make a joke about that but I think I'll leave it to your imagination.
Speaker 1: or ah I could make a joke, but I'll just let it slide.
Speaker 0: and what that really means is I'm good at recognizing opportunities for jokes, but not coming up with jokes you know very quickly and Improvisationally.
Speaker 0: therefore I will attempt to make myself Seem like I could be cool and come up with jokes by saying I could but I can't.
Speaker 1: it works pretty well.
Speaker 1: It's like getting you like you get a half point in a game when you do that as opposed to the whole point for actually Making the joke.
Speaker 1: However, if someone actually makes the joke that you couldn't come up with that's bad news.
Speaker 0: You are the lose.
Speaker 1: Anyway, my the last thing I want to say is that they kept cutting to the audience and showing everyone.
Speaker 1: You know acting like this is really cool and like getting really into it.
Speaker 1: But looking at their faces and this might just be me being very cynical, but I get the impression I would wager that several of the people who are like nodding along like oh, this is good Oh, yes.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes and looking at each other and looking around and smile like yes we're.
Speaker 1: Or acting like they liked it or acting like this was a big deal in order to appear more educated or erudite or cultured to the people around them much like how Psychologists have recently discovered that the dynamics of laughter and humans have a lot to do With how you feel about your social standing compared to the people around you much more so than with the actual humor involved in the jokes Being told.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That is my guess.
Speaker 0: also, you know how the people it's like You present them with the highfalutin waters that are actually all just hose water and they're like, oh, yes I can taste the salt and the minerals in this one.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh It's quite that.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that even if it even if there might be some people in the audience I have a feeling that that Psychological phenomena is quite prevalent among the persons Listening to this man saying
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like the reverse smile and nod or the group smile and nod or whatever.
Speaker 1: What do you got for me?
Speaker 0: So I'm going through and I see something.
Speaker 0: that's you.
Speaker 0: normally I'm not a big fan of the animals But this is a case of animals fighting which is.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter what it could be anything fighting and fighting is always good.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of tired of the human fighting.
Speaker 1: you're saying you're not a fan of the animals.
Speaker 1: You're the one who posted that big long thread about funny cute animal.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna reveal why that was done.
Speaker 1: Oh, so you had some sort of ulterior motive.
Speaker 0: Perhaps we did.
Speaker 0: I also had an ulterior motive Ulterior motive in what I didn't posting another thread.
Speaker 0: I didn't even post in that thread I know but you you will see why.
Speaker 0: the the the.
Speaker 0: in the future I'll discuss the ulterior motive of that thread and another thread which rim started quite quite quite.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes Anyway, anyway in this video it starts off with some people.
Speaker 0: They're probably in Africa and like the Savannah or the Serengeti or whatever you want to call it.
Speaker 0: I don't know I'm not a wildlife discovery channel person and See some Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo and There's a lot.
Speaker 0: there's quite a few.
Speaker 1: Buffalo perhaps a herd of them and there's not the word I mean, I mean, it's like a big herd of buff like it's a murder of crows.
Speaker 0: heard a gaggle of geese and One of them is really big like a huge Buffalo and it's walking and it's walking.
Speaker 0: And then they look over to the right with their video camera.
Speaker 0: And what do they see?
Speaker 0: Lions and you go, oh man, this is gonna be good.
Speaker 0: We're gonna see lions eat buffaloes All right, or possibly buffaloes fight off lions.
Speaker 0: Yeah This Buffalo is pretty big.
Speaker 0: like if it was brave enough to like rush the lion and ram it with the horns It could have done some serious damage like probably just gored the whole damn line, but there are quite a few lines.
Speaker 0: So not the greatest move.
Speaker 0: they would have to like work as a team to get rid of the line plus the Buffalo.
Speaker 1: They were obviously unawares.
Speaker 0: They were much like me walking toward the bomb site and dust - I mean The Lions are pretty much the same color as the grass.
Speaker 0: like, you know They were the light brown and it was all this light brown grass everywhere, huh?
Speaker 0: It's almost like there was some pretty sure buffaloes done at the greatest eyesight.
Speaker 1: It's almost like there's some sort of evolutionary advantage and being the same colors or surroundings if you're a predator, huh, huh?
Speaker 0: So there's some few lions crouching down and the buffaloes come closer And eventually the Lions go run run run run run run run run run run run and the Buffalo goes doo doo doo doo And the buffaloes turn around and run away.
Speaker 0: Enemy spotted yep, and I think these lines are gonna go and jump on this Buffalo, right?
Speaker 0: But they don't.
Speaker 0: they pass by it and like why are you passing that Buffalo?
Speaker 0: Where are you going to bite him?
Speaker 0: They pass by another Buffalo and then they jump on the baby Buffalo Lava girl cuz I mean while it was a baby Buffalo and that's kind of cheap.
Speaker 0: It's like picking off like the worst player on the other Counter-Strike team just to get a kill.
Speaker 0: But that but it had plenty of meat on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, baby Buffalo is no shame Leaving your team to die Defending the bombsight while you sneak around back through the sewer to knife slowly to death the one afk guy.
Speaker 0: So they get this tiny Buffalo and it's like a little pond or a lake or something there and they kind of get it.
Speaker 0: But it you know and all the other big Buffalo kind of back off and they're they're going away a little bit not too far away But they're going away and all these Lions are jumping on this baby Buffalo They sort of fight with it and wrestle it like onto the edge of this water and they kind of into the edge of the Water a little bit and they're fighting with it and they're fighting with it and they're biting it.
Speaker 0: it looks like they've you know, pretty much killed it.
Speaker 0: as far as I could tell and You know, there's people in the who are taking the video or commenting.
Speaker 0: They're on some kind of Safari and after a few minutes It's a hubbub Crocodile.
Speaker 1: come oh shit.
Speaker 1: You sure it's not an alligator.
Speaker 0: It was a crowd.
Speaker 0: They said crocodile And it lives in the water, you know, okay, you know the difference.
Speaker 0: one lives in the water one scuttles on the land.
Speaker 1: Well the easy way to tell crocodiles have the pointy nose and alligators have the wide noses.
Speaker 0: I couldn't really tell.
Speaker 0: it's kind of far away.
Speaker 0: and they go snap snap snap snap snap try to steal the Buffalo And the Lions are like.
Speaker 0: So eventually the Lions do manage to pull the Buffalo out of the water and more onto the land and the alligators are.
Speaker 0: the Crocodiles are like, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm not getting out of the water's too hot.
Speaker 0: And then the big buffaloes come back.
Speaker 0: Oh shit They're probably mad now and I won't give away the ending but it's it's quite hilarious.
Speaker 1: You know what it is.
Speaker 1: It's the circle of life lol.
Speaker 0: All right, so by recent request and by Going along with the news item.
Speaker 0: We got to talk about the raid.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: now very briefly raid RAID.
Speaker 1: now there is some debate as to what raid actually stands for but I'm going to pretty much go out into the open and say that if you think it stands for anything other than redundant array of Independent discs then you're pretty much an idiot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really expensive discs.
Speaker 0: Okay Yes, so I could get floppy disks.
Speaker 0: Does that count?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna make a raid with floppies.
Speaker 1: They're real Alright.
Speaker 1: so before we talk about what raid is What I mean raid solves a problem that a lot of people don't realize they have.
Speaker 0: you see well It solves a problem that also was a great bigger problem in the olden days.
Speaker 1: Yes, you see in terms of your computer into the most unreliable as per how unit valuable it is in a computer is Always the hard drive because that is where the data is and the data is often not as Replaceable as the components of the computer itself.
Speaker 0: I mean even if RAM let's say RAM was super unreliable RAM broke all the time Right.
Speaker 0: Well if RAM breaks That's not really that big a deal.
Speaker 0: if you have money because you replace the RAM you didn't lose anything.
Speaker 1: Yes, money can always solve normal computer problems, right?
Speaker 0: But your hard drive has some data on it, which cannot be replaced if it is lost.
Speaker 0: So that's why you do backups and all these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: also hard drives have moving parts Which makes them extremely prone to failure Extremely.
Speaker 1: Yes hard drives crash fairly often and I've actually got two Completely full completely crashed hard drives sitting around my room that I wish I could get the data off of.
Speaker 1: but there's just no way.
Speaker 1: Even if I had a lot of money, there's a good chance.
Speaker 1: I just couldn't do it.
Speaker 0: So raid is one.
Speaker 0: one thing raid does is technology which solves the problem that Hard drives are prone to failure and you don't want that to fuck you and you don't want to lose data.
Speaker 1: now There's another problem.
Speaker 1: There is another problem hard drives because like Scott said they have moving parts.
Speaker 1: You know, there's a physical thing moving around in there getting the data.
Speaker 1: hard drives are Incredibly slow.
Speaker 1: They're the slowest part of your computer by far.
Speaker 0: This is why we have RAM and why we have cash and why we have all these other place registers and other places for to store data in your computer because Sometimes you need to access read and write data really quickly.
Speaker 0: So that's why we have RAM and things.
Speaker 0: if hard drives are as fast as RAM We just wouldn't have hard drives.
Speaker 0: We would have just so much RAM You wouldn't believe.
Speaker 0: but when you want to store all it's hard to have a lot of data.
Speaker 0: That is also rapidly accessible.
Speaker 0: That's why we have these different levels, you know, a register is stupidly fast but it's also stupidly small.
Speaker 0: a RAM is Bigger.
Speaker 0: you can have like two gigs of RAM many gigs of RAM and it's fast not as fast as registers.
Speaker 1: Well, more importantly it's not persistent.
Speaker 0: Yep hard drives Not only can you have a whole shit ton of data stored permanently even after the computer turns off but you can have a whole shit ton of data stored permanently when the computer turns off and It's kind of slow.
Speaker 1: It sucks.
Speaker 1: So raid Solves both of these problems in various different ways.
Speaker 1: You see they realize problem - oh you have a third problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a third problem right?
Speaker 0: So sometimes, you know, imagine if you did, okay Let's say you just wanted to have a whole bunch of hard drives, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you wanted to have I don't know three terabytes of data, right?
Speaker 0: So you went there's.
Speaker 0: no it's very hard to get terabyte drives.
Speaker 0: Let's say you in the olden days was even harder to care terabyte drives.
Speaker 0: You would need 31 gigabyte hard drives or as some people say gigabyte hard drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those people however.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but let's say today you go out you buy three one terabyte hard drives, right?
Speaker 0: Now, let's say you have a database and that database is two and a half terabytes large.
Speaker 0: You need to now Have.
Speaker 0: you're like you'll see using Windows.
Speaker 0: You've got the C Drive the D Drive in the eDrive.
Speaker 0: How do you get one file on three drives?
Speaker 0: a 30 terabyte hard drive does not exist.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do about that?
Speaker 1: Yes, so think about the name raid redundant array of Independent disks.
Speaker 1: It's pretty self-explanatory as to what it is.
Speaker 1: Basically One hard drive is unreliable.
Speaker 1: However, the odds of that hard drive failing are X. say you have two hard drives.
Speaker 1: the odds of both of them failing at the same Time are much less.
Speaker 0: unless you buy two of the exact same hard drive on the exact same day from the exact same And even then use them the exact same amount.
Speaker 1: even then it's still somewhat less.
Speaker 1: Yep But not as much less.
Speaker 1: but still now.
Speaker 1: three drives four drives.
Speaker 1: if you only needed one drive to stay up and your data would Be okay, then for every drive you add your data is that much safer and that much more secure.
Speaker 0: Yeah If I have a hundred gigs of data And I have three 100 gigabyte hard drives and I have the exact same data on all three drives at all times and one of them crashes Big deal.
Speaker 1: now to Speed.
Speaker 1: All right I've got a hundred megabytes worth of data on a hundred megabyte hard drive and when I'm gonna read that data I basically because it's a physically moving part in there I have to read it from beginning to end if I'm reading it at one big piece of data in one go.
Speaker 1: So I'm limited by the speed of the hard drives.
Speaker 0: data access Yes The slowest part of the hard drive is the moving discs inside and the read head that goes back and forth on them.
Speaker 0: Actually that when once the data is read off of the platter the rest is stupidly fast.
Speaker 0: So anytime you can make those things go faster is better.
Speaker 0: Your computer can handle all the hard drives are sending out because it's just so much faster than the hard drive is.
Speaker 1: So now let's say I've got two 100 megabyte drives.
Speaker 1: Both of them have the exact same data on them.
Speaker 1: I could have one hard drive start reading from the beginning of the file forward and Simultaneously start reading the data from the middle of the hard drive to the end on the other drive.
Speaker 1: So now I can get the data off the hard drive pretty much twice as fast.
Speaker 0: That's pretty high quality right now.
Speaker 1: say I have three.
Speaker 1: now I can read in third save for every drive.
Speaker 1: I add it gets that much faster to read data off because I can read the data in parallel Obviously diminishing returns if you're randomly reading data from all over the hard drive.
Speaker 1: But it's still a significant performance increase and that's why rate is awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, problem three.
Speaker 1: I want to have I say I got ten one gigabyte drives.
Speaker 1: I want to combine them all to make one ten gigabyte drive.
Speaker 1: Well ray just does that.
Speaker 0: it just does that.
Speaker 1: not gonna make an Analogy, I think you can figure it out at this point.
Speaker 0: You take rats up pretty much to sum up raid the simplest way possible to someone who doesn't want to know any of the details.
Speaker 0: You take a bunch of drives a bunch of hard drives and you combine them into one hard drive.
Speaker 0: That's what it is.
Speaker 1: So you might have heard then that there's all these different kinds of raid raid zero number one raid zero plus one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you might have five Jbod raid ten.
Speaker 1: raid six is my favorite.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well the first one let's talk about that one first.
Speaker 1: Jbod Jbod Jbod just a bunch of discs.
Speaker 1: That's a Jbod is it's all it lets you Do is take a bunch of drives and either plug them all in or mash them all together into one big drive.
Speaker 1: So it's not really a raid.
Speaker 1: It's an aid.
Speaker 1: It's just an array of independent disks.
Speaker 1: There's no redundancy.
Speaker 1: if one drive goes you lose everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz it's just one big hard drive.
Speaker 0: If it's part of your hard drive crashes Well now it can't figure out what data is on any part of the drive because the way file systems work That's using that fancy new ZFS thing.
Speaker 1: But even that might save.
Speaker 1: like theoretically if part of a hard drive died you could get the data from the rest of it.
Speaker 1: But that data would be mostly useless due to fragmentation and other issues.
Speaker 1: You'd be lucky to get anything and to be very expensive and difficult.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 0: basically if you have just a bunch of discs and a one drive crashes You're done also with just a bunch of discs.
Speaker 0: You're not speeding anything up at all.
Speaker 0: It's it's going just as fast as it would be if you had one disc.
Speaker 1: You basically get almost none of the benefits and all of the problems.
Speaker 1: because think of this.
Speaker 1: Here's the biggest problem.
Speaker 1: All right, J Bob say I combine one.
Speaker 1: I combine two discs into one.
Speaker 1: now I've doubled the chances of losing all the data because if either one of those drives fails at any point I lose all the data.
Speaker 1: say I've got ten discs.
Speaker 1: now There are ten hard drives.
Speaker 0: if any one of them fails, I'm fucked Alright, so the next one you got is raid zero.
Speaker 0: raid zero does something called striping.
Speaker 1: raid Zero is the way to get speed and performance and you sacrifice for liability.
Speaker 0: Yes, basically raid zero is also not gonna save you if any of the drives crashes.
Speaker 0: You still have the same problems of oh my god one drive crash.
Speaker 0: now It's all gone.
Speaker 0: You solve the problem of turning a bunch of drives into one drive and you solve the problem of hey Let's make this go faster what it does.
Speaker 0: instead of writing Let's say you have a hundred megabyte file, right.
Speaker 0: instead of writing a hundred megabytes onto drive number one It'll write 50 megabytes into drive number one and 50 megabytes into drive number two.
Speaker 0: And that way when you want to read the debt that file It will read it off of both drives at the same time.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like slicing through a cake if you imagine both drives being on top of each other and the data is written by right directly on top and then through into the next drive and You basically can get almost twice as much data on and off your drives.
Speaker 0: Yes, you could with just one drive.
Speaker 1: in practice due to the way it works It ends up being somewhat less than that, but it's still a fairly significant and measurable performance increase.
Speaker 0: If you're having it keep in mind that's not gonna be a performance increase for most normal people.
Speaker 0: It's only gonna help you if you're reading and writing a lot of data Like I don't know loading a gigabyte of textures from a drive So you're loading times and fancy games will increase.
Speaker 0: or say Encoding HD videos that take up ginormous amounts of space something like that.
Speaker 1: a lot of people will put like their scratch space or their temp files on a rust right trade like that.
Speaker 1: or They'll install their operating system there on a stripe like that and then they put all their actual data files and config files Somewhere else where it's secure and backed up.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now again, this is not really a raid.
Speaker 1: It's an a raid.
Speaker 1: There's no redundancy.
Speaker 0: It's not but it is called raids.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is called raid, but technically there's no redundancy.
Speaker 0: that is No data, I guess I guess the name of it is actually quite good because it's raid zero raid nothing.
Speaker 1: Ah Yeah, now raid one is the exact opposite of that.
Speaker 1: instead of striping It's mirroring all it does say I've got two identical drives two drives of the same size.
Speaker 1: It writes the exact same data to both.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: now
Speaker 1: you often will take depending on how it's set up a slight performance hit because you have to write data to both Drives and keep them in sync, but you get a substantial performance increase on reading because you can still read the data Independently from the two different drives as long as the setup properly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this is really good.
Speaker 0: because now, you know If you have important data you want to save and you don't really care about reading or writing it very quickly and it's you Know you can fit it on one drive.
Speaker 0: You just buy one more drive and now you don't have to keep tape backups You need to run backup applications.
Speaker 0: You do need to take you do if you're in a serious environment But for your home a raid one is enough.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess we we're not gonna get into this but there are two very different kinds of backing up data.
Speaker 1: raid is one of them.
Speaker 1: there's another kind of backup and a lot of people are under the Misassumption that if you have a raid one or some sort of raid that protects your data from being lost in a physical hard drive failure That that is all the backing up you need to do because there are a lot of things that does not protect you.
Speaker 0: You know if you're in a business environment and you want to make sure you have the best practices then the raid is not enough.
Speaker 0: But if you're a guy at home and you want to make sure your mp3 collection is around forever a raid one will do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just don't accidentally type RM - RF star and you're fine.
Speaker 0: Yes, and if one of the drives crashes replace it so that you know, you can keep your mirror.
Speaker 1: But anyway raid one I mean obviously the benefits.
Speaker 1: you have your failure chances because you have two drives in this.
Speaker 1: if one of them fails You're just fine.
Speaker 1: You just replace it and it'll rebuild itself.
Speaker 1: You don't lose any data at all.
Speaker 1: the only way you can lose your data short of a problem with you know, Deleting your data on your own a user error is if both drives fail Simultaneously.
Speaker 1: the odds of that are pretty low.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now the thing to know about raid zero and one is that they require at least two drives each.
Speaker 0: You know, you could do a raid zero with two drives.
Speaker 0: You could do with more than two drives also But you need at least two.
Speaker 0: raid one also needs at least two drives.
Speaker 0: The thing with raid one also is that let's say you have a 500 gigabyte drive and a 200 gigabyte drive.
Speaker 0: Well, you're only gonna have 200 gigabytes of space total because it's gonna have 200 gigs and that it's gonna mirror it.
Speaker 0: and that's you're Done.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So the benefits of raid zero super fast super easy big performance increase and there's effectively zero overhead.
Speaker 1: You don't have any space.
Speaker 0: Yep, but you are going to Double your chances.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah you Significantly increases your chance of losing data.
Speaker 1: raid one has your chances of failure and you still get a performance increase from reading.
Speaker 1: you take usually a performance hit of some kind in writing but The overhead is 50%.
Speaker 1: you lose fully half of the hard drive capacity you have.
Speaker 0: Yep, to 500 gig drives only gives you 500 gigs of space Whereas with a raid zero that gives you a terabyte of space.
Speaker 1: so you might think alright.
Speaker 1: Well, uh, there is there a more efficient way to do this.
Speaker 1: Well, I ought to be some sort of math.
Speaker 1: I could do this one.
Speaker 0: There's one other thing you can do.
Speaker 0: You could do a raid zero plus one.
Speaker 1: Ah the raid zero plus one the realm of people with infinite money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see a raid zero plus one.
Speaker 0: the way this works is you have two raid zeros, right?
Speaker 0: So I got drive one and two drive one and two are striped in a raid zero.
Speaker 0: Drives three and four are striped in a raid zero But drives three and four are a mirror of the stripe.
Speaker 0: that is raid zero and one.
Speaker 0: you basically Mirror two raid zeros.
Speaker 1: It's a little more complicated than that.
Speaker 1: But all of these kinds of raids are a little more complicated than that.
Speaker 1: Yes, you don't care good god You don't care.
Speaker 1: Yes, so nice to say you get crazy performance benefits and the only thing it costs you is money.
Speaker 0: yeah, raid zero plus one obviously requires at least four drives and Use the size of the smallest drive and it's expensive and it needs a lot of overhead.
Speaker 0: and But you basically get a striped raid zero, which is stupidly fast.
Speaker 0: so you get all the speed benefits of raid zero and If one of the two if one of the stripes goes down you can replace it with another stripe and you're still good With the the raid oneness, it's not widely reused not terribly well supported.
Speaker 1: You probably want to avoid it because Raid five exists.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about raid three and five.
Speaker 0: you want to talk about three first?
Speaker 0: Well be able.
Speaker 0: first I think we should just talk about why we don't talk about two three and four and why no one uses two three and four.
Speaker 1: well the Raid standards each level of raid is a specific way of going about this and they all have their pros and cons and for various reasons They have all become effectively obsolete except for raid Zero one five six and then a lot of the proprietary or special corporate ones that we don't need to talk about.
Speaker 1: Yep, raid four and raid five are the same Effectively.
Speaker 1: It's just a matter of how they go about what they do.
Speaker 1: raid three is Similar to four and five.
Speaker 1: it just goes about it again in a different way But it's not as similar as far as to five.
Speaker 1: Yep raid two.
Speaker 1: Don't even worry about it.
Speaker 0: Good God Don't don't worry about raid two.
Speaker 0: in fact I wouldn't even recommend reading the Wikipedia is or anything on the other is actually a website if you just search that has pictures And diagrams that show you how all the raids work specifically.
Speaker 1: It's kind of interesting if you're into that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yes, but basically what all these things come down to is something called parity.
Speaker 0: It's a magical math that I'm going to teach you.
Speaker 0: that allows you to have say I don't know five hard drives and Be able to actually use four of them but without mirroring and You can still have all the benefits of raid zero and one at the same time by using magic math.
Speaker 1: now Parity is not just used in raid and harder.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it's used all over the place.
Speaker 1: Parity is used in a lot of things.
Speaker 1: It's basically a way of knowing well, there's different ways to use it.
Speaker 1: it's a way of knowing if data has been corrupted or changed in transit or in storage and Depending on how it's set up knowing how to fix that data by adding metadata the meta the sum of the metadata Being less than the sum of the actual data.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm because I mean theoretically you could always just send your data twice.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I'm not gonna actually talk about the actual math used because it's kind of complicated.
Speaker 0: I love I'm going to use the simplified version of it.
Speaker 0: That is easier to understand.
Speaker 1: What I will do is I'll link to a very simple and easy to understand method that is used in some old networking equipment.
Speaker 1: Yep, I'll link to it.
Speaker 1: There's a nice animated tutorial somewhere out there.
Speaker 0: I'm sure but here's an example, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say I have four bits.
Speaker 0: So four zeros and ones right and I want to remember all four of them.
Speaker 0: now I all I need here first is I need one more zero and one.
Speaker 0: Alright, if I only have four zeros and ones and one of them breaks There's no way for me to figure out what that missing one is.
Speaker 0: it broke and I only have three of the zeros and ones.
Speaker 0: Let's say it's one one zero zero just for example, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say the second one dies.
Speaker 0: now I have one blank zero zero.
Speaker 0: How the hell do I know what if that broken one is a one or a zero?
Speaker 0: I have a 50% chance of guessing that sucks.
Speaker 0: I'm basically gonna be screwed if I pick wrong and that that imagine.
Speaker 0: now you're dealing with a hard drive.
Speaker 0: That's millions and millions and billions of ones and zeros.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna work out.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So first I need an additional one or zero.
Speaker 0: so Normally with a mirror, right?
Speaker 0: I would need to remember all four of these ones and zeros.
Speaker 0: I would need four more ones and zeros to mirror four drives.
Speaker 0: I need four drives.
Speaker 0: that kind of sucks with this magic parody math.
Speaker 0: I can do it with just one more drive.
Speaker 0: So four drives add just one more drive And now I can remember it just as well as if I had four more drives.
Speaker 0: That's pretty hot.
Speaker 1: now to get back to raid We'll use the example of raid three because that makes it's the easiest to understand.
Speaker 1: Let's say we'll do we you.
Speaker 1: it doesn't really give by you anything with two drives because you need one drive to be the parody Drive, so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: So we'll start with three drives and we'll compare this to mirror.
Speaker 1: So I want to make a raid three with three drives.
Speaker 1: Basically drive one and drive two contain data and I spread data across these two.
Speaker 1: But drive three doesn't contain any data at all.
Speaker 1: drive three contains parody information of the data on the other two drives.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's the extra bit that you need as opposed to copying everything.
Speaker 0: You just have the extra bit on the end.
Speaker 1: so if drive one fails Between the information on drive to the data there and the parody information on drive three I can recreate the data that should have been on drive one when drive one got destroyed.
Speaker 0: and this is how it's done.
Speaker 0: You ready?
Speaker 0: Let's say drive zero is has a one on it and drive two has a one on it.
Speaker 0: right drive three.
Speaker 0: What do we put there?
Speaker 0: Well, let's say let's pick even right.
Speaker 0: Well, there's two ones That's an even number of ones.
Speaker 0: So on drive three we put a zero.
Speaker 0: now, let's say drive one dies.
Speaker 0: Well, we know that the drive three says zero.
Speaker 0: So there should be an even number of ones.
Speaker 0: and we know that on drive two, which still works.
Speaker 0: There's a one.
Speaker 0: Therefore drive one must be one dun-dun-dun.
Speaker 1: Luckily for the world Ray does not work on the bit level like that.
Speaker 1: No I doesn't precise.
Speaker 1: and in fact the only difference between raid four and raid five is how it goes about that specific.
Speaker 0: Yes, they don't use that exact math because that exact math would take for god damn ever.
Speaker 0: They do it.
Speaker 0: It would be a nightmare.
Speaker 1: They do it in much larger chunks.
Speaker 0: Yes, they do it in huge chunks of ones and zeros.
Speaker 0: But and they use very fancier and more efficient math.
Speaker 0: But that's basically the kind of thing that's going on here is you have You know some ones and zeros and then some other ones and zeros.
Speaker 0: that are your actual data.
Speaker 0: and then you sort of line them up in rows and columns and Make a new line of ones and zeros and that way if any one line Column or row gets knocked out you can look at the columns and rows around it add them up and then By looking at all them and doing some math you can redraw all the missing ones and zeros.
Speaker 0: sort of like if someone array Yeah to sudoku that was working and I erased the middle of it you would be very easy for you to just figure out the Answer in the middle.
Speaker 0: That's what it's like.
Speaker 1: That's a really good analogy actually Yeah.
Speaker 1: So thus very briefly because I'm sure now you're all wondering what the differences are between raid three four and five Because you always hear about raid five, you know here about three so much.
Speaker 1: Yep, three Alright, so I've got what I have a parody drive and two normal drives.
Speaker 1: Basically with mirroring I lose 50%.
Speaker 1: I lose one drives worth of space to put stuff because the whole drive is taken up by that extra information.
Speaker 1: With raid three I lose one disc total.
Speaker 1: So I get the space of n minus one discs and being the number of discs that I've bought The problem with raid three is that while you get a performance increase from being able to Hit all these drives and read data from them parallel Whatever no matter what you do whenever you write data to the drives There's always the bottleneck of that third drive.
Speaker 1: No If you're just reading from drive one or drive two You always have to read from drive three drive three.
Speaker 1: the parody drive is always in use.
Speaker 1: It's always the bottleneck.
Speaker 1: It actually becomes much more likely to fail because it's getting hammered all the time.
Speaker 1: Yep, and thus raid four and five.
Speaker 1: We'll just talk about raid five.
Speaker 1: The only difference is that instead of having one parody drive It distributes the parody among all of the drives.
Speaker 1: So every drive contains parody and data.
Speaker 1: Thus there's no one drive that's singled out and all the drives are treated equally and as a result you get much more of a Performance increase lesser performance hit and it's generally much safer.
Speaker 0: Yep So instead of having let's say you got five drives Normally, you would have let's see drives one two, three and four would have the data and drive five would be the parody.
Speaker 0: Well, what if we made each drive?
Speaker 0: Four fifths of each drive was data and one fifth of each drive was parody.
Speaker 0: So the first fifth of drive one is parody the second fifth of the second drive was parody the third fifth of the first drive Was parody etc.
Speaker 0: and all the other fifths of each drive was the actual data.
Speaker 0: Now each drive has a little parody and a lot of data and you're only losing what one fifth of the space.
Speaker 0: So with five 100 gig drives you have 400 gigs of space.
Speaker 0: if a drive crashes you can replace it and you won't lose any data.
Speaker 0: More the benefits of the striping going on because you're reading from all these drives at once instead of just one drive.
Speaker 0: It's just awesome all around.
Speaker 1: and the primary benefit is that now you can raid three.
Speaker 1: I guess I don't know afraid you could actually do it because I've never actually run into raid three in the real world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not going to.
Speaker 1: in all my I mean, it's always raid five or some proprietary thing.
Speaker 1: But with raid five say a drive fails.
Speaker 1: The raid will continue to function in a degraded state where when you're reading data It'll on the fly figure out what the data should have been based on the parody.
Speaker 1: and because the parody is distributed It's not as much of a performance hit as it otherwise would be It's still a performance hit though.
Speaker 1: So usually what you do is you end up having an n minus 2 hit to the amount of space you get.
Speaker 1: so say you've got You want four drives you want to raid five of them.
Speaker 1: what's generally done in the corporate world is two drives end up equivalent of being data and then the third drive equivalent is the parody and It's distributed.
Speaker 1: but that's how it works logically.
Speaker 1: The fourth drive is not even active.
Speaker 1: It just sits there spun up ready And if a drive fails the raid starts running in a degraded state so you can still use it.
Speaker 1: But there's a performance hit.
Speaker 1: meanwhile it starts Recreating the data that should have been on the dead drive on that spare drive Because they're only really failing of raid five and raid three.
Speaker 1: and all this is that let's say a drive dies.
Speaker 0: All right It'll still work.
Speaker 1: But now I'm in a dangerous position because now all the drives are being hit harder Because they have to do more work to figure out all the data on the missing drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah So now I'm pushing them more than I would have been already - if another drive fails before I have on that old drive that broke replaced I lose everything.
Speaker 1: it's over because I can't recover from drives.
Speaker 0: failing you get to figure out the number of even ones and zeros and Stuff like that.
Speaker 0: You need to have pretty much all of them But one.
Speaker 0: if you're losing just one of the you know The set you can figure it out.
Speaker 0: if you miss two from the set you can't figure out - it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: The math doesn't work that way.
Speaker 1: That is where all those other raids that we're not going to talk about come in.
Speaker 1: Where they'll do something like the parody is actually a grid instead of just stripes so you can lose Certain combinations of drives and still be okay.
Speaker 0: You have two different parity schemes working at the same time.
Speaker 0: So if you lose certain data Then you can.
Speaker 0: you might one parity scheme might work or like one parity scheme might be able to save the other Parity scheme which can then save the data and all sorts of it's like redundancy of the parity But not of the actual data and it's crazy stuff like that.
Speaker 1: All right, we've gone on a while.
Speaker 1: So very briefly There there are a couple different ways to do raid.
Speaker 1: Generally, it comes down to doing it in hardware and doing it in software.
Speaker 0: Hardware is the best way if you do it in hardware.
Speaker 0: basically what that means is you buy a machine and you plug a bunch of drives into the machine and the Machine does the raid on its own and it does it with chips and things like that and it's very fast and it's very reliable.
Speaker 0: And your computer your actual computer doesn't know this raid going on.
Speaker 0: It doesn't need to know shit.
Speaker 0: your CPU doesn't do anything your RAM doesn't.
Speaker 0: it doesn't know that there's a raid Computer a disk.
Speaker 0: your computer thinks that it's just one hard drive and it's a really big hard drive.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like a net like net is for having a bunch of computers behind.
Speaker 1: then there's one interface to the outside.
Speaker 1: It's like that for hard drives.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's super good super awesome super expensive very expensive Difficult to manage and it's all scuzzy which means the drive all scuzzy.
Speaker 1: This is plenty much.
Speaker 0: Nah, there are hardware acla t-rays.
Speaker 0: It's expensive.
Speaker 1: There aren't many that they're out there There aren't many and very few people use them and a lot of things that Say they'll do raid with a card or something with serial ATA are actually software raid And they're not really like good hardware real raid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are some boxes you can buy that you can actually not just cards that you would put in your computer But actual boxes that drives go in that do a hardware raid like some NAS and SAN type things.
Speaker 0: But don't worry about that.
Speaker 1: every raid you run into is software raid.
Speaker 1: pretty much now Here's the kicker.
Speaker 1: a lot of people see a motherboard or whatever and it says oh Supports raid zero one zero plus one and five and jbud.
Speaker 1: and you might think hey, it's a hardware raid isn't the hardware?
Speaker 1: Actually, it doesn't do it in the hardware at all.
Speaker 1: It just makes it easy for your processor and your stuff and your operating system to do it, but it's still basically Software raid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it might be a little bit of hardware raid like.
Speaker 0: it has some raid functions built into it But you still need some sort of driver and your operating system has to know it's a raid and your operating system has to deal With it in some way or another.
Speaker 0: and that's why a lot of those raids Will work only with certain operating systems and under certain conditions, and they're really not all that fast or that reliable.
Speaker 0: But if you make them work, it is a raid five.
Speaker 0: It's just not as good a raid five now.
Speaker 1: Here is the primary problem with people out there using raids Outside of corporate server environments even though I personally like raid a lot.
Speaker 1: I plan to build a fairly extensive raid system in my new computer.
Speaker 1: but raid at its fundamental core the way it accesses discs puts a lot more stress on them than normal access would and Especially if you're doing raid with consumer level hard drives, you know, you buy a serial ATA Car drive at Best Buy.
Speaker 1: Yeah a max tour a Seagate or something.
Speaker 1: These drives are not really ready to handle that amount of stress and they're going to fail on you at a much higher rate than They otherwise would have.
Speaker 1: so you will end up buying Replacement drives more often than you would otherwise.
Speaker 0: I mean if you just buy a hard drive and just keep using it sure one day it'll fail and you lose all your data If you didn't back it up.
Speaker 0: But it'll probably fail Many years from now unless you're crazy using it too much.
Speaker 0: if you put that drive in a raid like a raid One with one other drive.
Speaker 0: It'll probably fail like in two years.
Speaker 1: Well, luckily It's the.
Speaker 1: the lower lumber raids don't do it so much.
Speaker 1: It's mostly raid five or eight.
Speaker 1: zero is pretty nasty though raid five is the worst because you're constantly Fiddling with the parity data.
Speaker 1: So all the drives are being accessed all the time You're.
Speaker 1: as a result you're gonna wear those drives out and Professional SCSI drives and servers are much more apt to deal with this.
Speaker 1: your consumer level hard drives We're not designed with raid in mind.
Speaker 1: They're not built at the same tolerances.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not as reliable.
Speaker 1: They can't handle the heat as well.
Speaker 0: Yep, they still might last for a year or two, but they're not gonna last in super long term.
Speaker 1: So I guess what my warning here is that you might think oh, I'll just build a raid five.
Speaker 1: My data's safe forever.
Speaker 1: Be aware that you're gonna have to have an extra hard drive on hand to be ready to replace one when they die because they're Going to die.
Speaker 0: Here's the other thing that you got to know about.
Speaker 0: in a fancy server like a data center if a hard drive crashes You can just without doing anything.
Speaker 0: Just pull the hard drive right out of there and slide another one in.
Speaker 0: just whoop whoop.
Speaker 1: Yes, you realize in fancy servers.
Speaker 1: I have hot swapped PCI cards.
Speaker 1: I have hot swapped hard drives.
Speaker 1: I hot swapped RAM.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hot swap means that you can take it out and plug it in while the computer's on.
Speaker 0: It's a USB.
Speaker 0: You can just plug USB things in while the computer's on.
Speaker 1: Yeah fancy computers You can do that with hard drives and cards and everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could just take the CPU out put one in while the computers on but you can't take all the CPUs Not all of them.
Speaker 0: But there's some where you could take a CPU out.
Speaker 0: You could put sticks of RAM in the computer while it's on and then it will add that RAM to the computer.
Speaker 0: There are computers like that.
Speaker 0: Your computer your computer is not like that.
Speaker 0: pretty much the only thing you can hot swap on your computer is like a CD ROM Or a USB or a firewire.
Speaker 0: that's about it.
Speaker 0: so if your raid has a problem you pretty much have to shut it down immediately and take the drive out and put a new drive in and Figure out which drive you have to replace.
Speaker 0: because if you don't have the fancy box with the lights on it telling you which one Crashed you got to figure out which one crashed.
Speaker 0: you might replace the wrong one and now you're in trouble.
Speaker 0: So it's not that easy to have a consumer raid and raid isn't really meant for consumers And that's why things like the Drobo I talked about in the news are pretty hot because it brings something like raid.
Speaker 0: You know that sort of redundancy and data safety to the consumer with ease and not a lot of effort or all these troubles that You can have.
Speaker 1: and on that note.
Speaker 0: There's there's one more thing one more thing.
Speaker 1: We've gone long already.
Speaker 0: You can do a software raid even if you don't have a motherboard that has anything for it.
Speaker 0: Oh,
Speaker 1: yeah, in fact in Windows you can pretty much just click in the disk manager and say make a raid go Yeah
Speaker 0: in Linux you can just be like if you just had three drives Plugged into your computer and your motherboard is like stupidly old, but it can plug in three drives.
Speaker 0: You can just say alright Combine those three partitions on the three drives into one drive and yeah do a raid one and it'll do it.
Speaker 0: You have to configure it and stuff, but you can do it entirely in software with no help from the hardware whatsoever.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.