Speaker 0: It's Tuesday August 14th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight natural selection and not the science kind.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Man, I think it's FPS season again.
Speaker 0: I think it just might be well.
Speaker 1: the show started.
Speaker 1: Well, we started recording a little bit late because Scott was playing counter-strike, and he wouldn't stop.
Speaker 0: well You know it was an icy world and I basically would spawn with the para Hold the button down die spawn with the para hold the button down die And it was pretty much.
Speaker 0: I was living for the rounds where I actually killed the whole other team.
Speaker 0: It's like you know.
Speaker 0: you got the para So you go around the corner you die.
Speaker 0: you go around the corner you die.
Speaker 0: you go around the corner You die you take a tricky path you die.
Speaker 0: you take a different tricky path.
Speaker 0: you get to the behind the enemy lines And you just hose them down, and then you die.
Speaker 1: See pretty much whenever I like you know there's all those delay.
Speaker 1: I don't play a counter-strike for a while.
Speaker 1: It's time to get back into it.
Speaker 1: I always play icy world for a couple weeks just to get my click on the guy's head skills back.
Speaker 0: I I was.
Speaker 0: I think I was getting more headshots than any other sort of kill But that might have been a result of the weapons of choice.
Speaker 1: well remember the trick with the para.
Speaker 1: if you really want to be good with it is aim for the head and Nintendo wrist a little bit with a mouse.
Speaker 0: that's what I did.
Speaker 0: is I was just going to be behind the enemy lines.
Speaker 0: I would aim at the general mass of enemies aim high and just shake it back and forth And it would be like headshot headshot headshot rampage And I'm like yes, and then I would die.
Speaker 1: actually in any icy world my favorite weapon is always the Mac 10.
Speaker 1: It's a headshot machine.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I was actually also kicking it up with the aug and the m4 plus over the weekend something We used to do back when we had I don't know free time.
Speaker 1: We actually played some games with some of you people out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah Ever since I bought all those ID software games on Steam, and I've been using my laptop a lot more my piece my desktop Which I don't use so much has been sitting in windows with steam action going on.
Speaker 1: so playing some Defcon Playing some CS source that water is poison handed our asses to us.
Speaker 0: He did.
Speaker 0: we're not so good at Defcon a game I've played maybe four times But
Speaker 1: we were playing some awesome two-on-two counter-strike with him and bees knees and Right before Scott and I were talking in the tea in the chat, and he says Rim I'm worried you think we're not as good as we used to be.
Speaker 1: what if we get hosed by these two kids that's not gonna represent well, and then we come around the corner, and they're right there laid in perfect ambush and Two seconds later.
Speaker 1: I had headshotted both of them and was raping one of their corpses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my p90 had bullets left in it, and he was like ah There was one particular set of kills.
Speaker 1: They ambushed Scott and got him and I had almost no health And I just ran around the corner with the pair and killed him both, and I think bees knees typed And I quote holy shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott had some magnificent kills.
Speaker 0: They had me pinned down at one and I'd been around and I jumped off the.
Speaker 0: he was.
Speaker 0: he was coming up the stairs And rim was at the top of the stairs.
Speaker 1: I was behind the wall like to get to get to get out with almost no health left running out of bullets And they were coming toward me about to kill and they came up the stairs.
Speaker 0: So I just walked to the side of the stairs Jumped off and came up the stairs behind him.
Speaker 0: and not that they're dead.
Speaker 1: It was absolutely beautiful.
Speaker 1: I called for assistance and the next thing I know is Scott is standing there over the bodies of the fallen.
Speaker 1: yep God, I love counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're good at that game.
Speaker 1: alright Well, I got us.
Speaker 1: I just want to say that playing counter-strike I'm used to playing.
Speaker 1: you know 10 on 10 20 on 20 whatever playing just a two verse two in a good map I forgot how absolutely intense that is.
Speaker 0: you want to is not so bad It's just one-on-one kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and like two on one sucks.
Speaker 0: Also, yep three on two still kind of sucks like four on four I think is pretty good.
Speaker 0: ten on ten is of course perfect, but you know as long as you get
Speaker 1: in a different way I mean when you got like the two on two or the three on three the strategies get very specific like I'm gonna hide behind This and give you cover fire while you run forward with that flash ten on ten.
Speaker 1: It's bomb a Bambi camp mommy.
Speaker 1: Those are good strategies, or if you're a CT in certain maps.
Speaker 1: hosties camp one of the two.
Speaker 0: oh Good times good times.
Speaker 1: I love that game anyway.
Speaker 0: anyway I guess news action.
Speaker 1: I don't know we don't have anything else.
Speaker 1: What are we gonna talk about?
Speaker 0: I've been playing some paper Mario on the virtual console.
Speaker 1: We've been playing a lot of Mario strikers.
Speaker 1: I'm currently up in way in games, but not by much.
Speaker 1: I think I'm one.
Speaker 1: every game was always close Like a domination, I think I'm like 1% better than Scott And I think as we play more that's gonna even out like it does in most games.
Speaker 0: I think I'm better than you now, but you know it sort of depends like you just played about you.
Speaker 0: Well, no It's like you played me after you had just played a whole bunch and gotten a bunch of practice.
Speaker 0: and since we're both nubs Like if someone has played like a few more games against the computer especially if they just played them And they're already in the groove You know it's like you were in the groove from playing the computer a bunch and then me who hadn't played since the day before Came in.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna win see it's hard to say because sometimes I get in the groove by doing that and sometimes I just Get fatigued by doing that.
Speaker 0: yeah, it depends But I think we need a lot more playing before we can just pick it up and be on the you know on the ball.
Speaker 1: The only thing I do want to say is playing it single-player.
Speaker 1: You know it's a game, and it's really good.
Speaker 1: It's the same as the other Mario strikers.
Speaker 1: Just you know better in every way, but playing it multiplayer While it's really fun in terms of tactics or strategy or how you actually have to play It's a completely different game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna have to learn a completely different style of play.
Speaker 0: Well talk about it next week or something not now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 0: So this is I don't know if you've ever heard of this thing.
Speaker 0: It's called camp Hyrule.
Speaker 0: obviously It's a Nintendo thing.
Speaker 1: I've heard of it from you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically what Nintendo has been doing for the past few summers.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure how many years they've been doing it, but basically on the internet they make a summer camp with a Zelda theme and they give away prizes and they have chat rooms and they Organize the users into cabins and you have cabin activity things and this flash games and all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like a summer camp for people who can't go to summer camp And it's got Zelda action and Nintendo marketing and such.
Speaker 0: and back in the day when I first heard this thing existed I was like ooh.
Speaker 0: There's a super secret camp that only for cool people about Zelda.
Speaker 0: This is something I got to get in on oh shits.
Speaker 0: So I tried to get in on it and I failed.
Speaker 0: and the next year I remembered it when it summer came around and I actually got in on it and I was like, oh man Oh man, I'm in the super secret thing.
Speaker 0: No one's in.
Speaker 1: he was so excited.
Speaker 0: So I log in and It was totally lame.
Speaker 0: I mean There was some cheesy flash games that weren't even as good as the kind on congregate that had some Zelda themes.
Speaker 0: There were chat rooms full of punk Pokemon kids talking about how they leach mudkips.
Speaker 0: only They weren't even talking about how they leach mudkips.
Speaker 0: They're talking about a BS six geodudes that can't lose.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's like that.
Speaker 0: the chat rooms were like, you know, man Zelda is the best oot for the win.
Speaker 0: not even that cuz it was so more primitive than that cuz it was so many years ago, they didn't have the new internet speak.
Speaker 1: it was just AOL kids see I think the issue here is that Nintendo of America when they do anything They really only market and cater with these online things toward 12 to 12 point five-year-olds.
Speaker 1: Great team much and I think the reason is they have to get those kids excited and get him on cuz you know when you Were 12 your attention span was like point two seconds pretty much.
Speaker 1: So Nintendo just has to keep grabbing him and grabbing him and saying Pokemon Zelda Pokemon Zelda and they just yell right back Pokemon Zelda.
Speaker 1: But for us they've already got us they don't need to market the next Zelda game.
Speaker 0: to me It's like everything Nintendo does is targeted to a specific You know demographic and they don't.
Speaker 0: and it's sort of annoying because even when something has a potential wide appeal It's sort of like they they narrow it down, you know They have all these very.
Speaker 0: it's like they're shooting with a sniper rifle when they should be using a shotgun sometimes.
Speaker 1: Why do you say should?
Speaker 1: because their strategy in terms of making money for Nintendo is brilliant and flawless.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's some times where you know, they they aim something at one particular spot and they hit it perfectly.
Speaker 0: But there's some people out there who would have also could have been hit perfectly.
Speaker 0: But they don't.
Speaker 0: they only use one bullet per thing and it's like come on you could is you still could have done better?
Speaker 1: Nintendo seems to always go after the low-hanging fruit first and go after it until they've got all of it And then after that they really don't care because they're already making so much money and we'll buy the games anyway And there's there's no reason for them to cater to us in any way other than making games that are good enough For us to play while at the same time grabbing infinite hordes of 12 year olds.
Speaker 0: Well, it's basically you do one thing that's stupidly easy and you get a zillion dollars.
Speaker 0: There's another thing you could do that is also easy But not stupidly easy.
Speaker 0: that could get you another zillion dollars and they just don't bother with the second thing.
Speaker 1: I mean.
Speaker 1: look at this in terms of this camp.
Speaker 1: I rule what is this?
Speaker 1: boil it down?
Speaker 1: It is just marketing.
Speaker 0: pretty much They don't need to market to anyone.
Speaker 0: here's the thing this marketing right.
Speaker 0: apparently.
Speaker 0: check this out.
Speaker 0: there's no mention on this thing at all of the Phantom Hour glass Zelda game that's coming out not a one and It seems like the only thing going on there as a contest to win a full-size link statue.
Speaker 1: I think what they're doing is they're just trying to imprint upon these 12 year olds the word Zelda because remember the kids don't grow up with that the way we did so in To get them into this Nintendo flock and make money off of them well into their 30s.
Speaker 1: They have to just brad it into their brains that Zelda is amazing and awesome.
Speaker 0: My thinking actually is if you look at the talk on the internet it's that people were saying Oh camp Hyrule isn't gonna happen this year and I think that Nintendo wasn't planning on making it happen this year that they sort of pulled it out at the last second.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm thinking, huh?
Speaker 0: Usually there's like a big build-up to camp Hyrule like this emails and this stuff on websites and stuff and You know suddenly you know this sort of people on the internet We're talking like a couple weeks ago like hey Where's camp I rule at?
Speaker 1: maybe Nintendo realized they could have the same effect with much less effort.
Speaker 0: perhaps.
Speaker 1: See now the thing is in terms of I mean marketing.
Speaker 1: I don't care about but when it comes to games I just would like to point out that lately the style of Nintendo games that I like the most on terms of gameplay but in terms of the style around the game is Mario strikers just the attitude of the characters and the character designs and the way they do it.
Speaker 0: because instead of just taking You know the Nintendo characters and putting them forth in their usual idiom.
Speaker 1: It's a me a Mario.
Speaker 0: They sort of Waluigi They sort of applied You know another thing on top of that.
Speaker 0: It's like now everyone is sort of badass and really wants to kick your ass at soccer and it's like oh, yeah You know.
Speaker 0: so I think if they started taking their characters that are in every goddamn game like look at Mario Kart and Mario Kart Mario is just Mario.
Speaker 0: What if in Mario Kart they made all the characters sort of like NASCAR and like yeah I'm good.
Speaker 0: I'm uh you know riding around the track in a circle?
Speaker 0: I Don't know, but you know they give them some attitude of some sort.
Speaker 0: they could really flash it up some.
Speaker 1: but yeah at any rate I don't really care about Nintendo's marketing campaign.
Speaker 0: my main point of doing this news is to let anyone know who's thinking that Oh Camp Hyrule this cool secret Awesome thing that's sort of exclusive.
Speaker 0: Don't even bother with it.
Speaker 0: It's a waste of your time.
Speaker 1: It's a secret to everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just don't don't care about it.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about it.
Speaker 0: You're not missing out if you're not in Camp Hyrule.
Speaker 0: Go to real summer camp.
Speaker 0: It's a thousand times better.
Speaker 1: You know I've never been to summer camp.
Speaker 1: Yeah, really pretty much no one where I lived went to summer camp.
Speaker 1: Just it wasn't.
Speaker 1: it was the thing where people were here like summer camp in a movie or on TV And literally none of the kids.
Speaker 1: I knew knew what it was.
Speaker 0: no one.
Speaker 0: salute your shorts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what it was.
Speaker 1: see I had band camp instead.
Speaker 0: Imagine if it was salute your shorts last eight weeks.
Speaker 0: How long did band camp last?
Speaker 1: band camp was two intense weeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so eight weeks.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I wanted to be at home with my video games and all my friends and my bike and my stuff.
Speaker 0: yeah Well, it's the thing about summer camp is like you have your school friends And then you have your summer camp friends.
Speaker 0: you get twice as much action plus You can have a lot more awesome action at summer camp.
Speaker 0: That's not action.
Speaker 0: You can have at home like what it's.
Speaker 0: It's only for summer camp people to know.
Speaker 1: uh-huh well considering the ages of summer campers.
Speaker 1: I doubt it's the things that I'm particularly interested in.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: summer camp like ages go up to like 15 16 year olds.
Speaker 1: uh Even so that's yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway We've always been interested in packs, and we want to go to it.
Speaker 1: I think it would probably be the perfect convention for me and Scott to go enjoy ourselves instead of you know Doing the things we do at conventions, and we just never get around to it.
Speaker 1: We're always busy, or it's always the wrong time on the other side of the goddamn country.
Speaker 1: Yes, stupid other side of the country.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean maybe you in Europe who listen to our show to realize it.
Speaker 1: But to get from where we live in New York to California is Washington State not California.
Speaker 1: California's where the other stuff we want to go to is yes But why we have to get from New York to Washington?
Speaker 0: Seattle Washington not Washington DC Which is easy to get to by train in like a couple hours, but Seattle Washington State on the other side of the country It's touching the other ocean.
Speaker 0: We're touching the Atlantic Ocean.
Speaker 0: They're touching the Pacific Ocean.
Speaker 0: They're far away.
Speaker 0: They're about as far away as we are from London.
Speaker 0: ish kind of almost so.
Speaker 1: Every time there's a PAX announcement it always something that says oh wow rim You really should have been there, and you really should go there.
Speaker 0: How many paxes have we missed?
Speaker 0: like three?
Speaker 0: We've missed all of them obviously obviously, but there's been a lot more than just one and they were all awesome.
Speaker 0: We've missed all of them.
Speaker 1: I mean everyone I mean like the anime con out west you know built itself up And then when it actually happened it failed to deliver Pax.
Speaker 1: every year it builds up and builds up and then we don't go and then it happens and the news Afterward is always bad.
Speaker 1: It was more awesome than you could have ever imagined.
Speaker 0: I mean they got that omega-thon action.
Speaker 0: They've got that awesome concert action.
Speaker 0: They've got the Freaking video games and tabletop gaming galore.
Speaker 0: I could buy just stay in the tabletop gaming all day.
Speaker 0: They got more DS's than any con.
Speaker 0: I've ever been to supposedly and I know all this and I totally believe it There's no doubt in my mind plus.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like the new e3 for Consumer facing you know video game industry sort of dealer room action, so you got all that together and We don't get to go because it's too far away.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling we're gonna go next year.
Speaker 1: I think we're just gonna bite the bullet and force ourselves to no matter what.
Speaker 0: I think we'll just get a hotel in frickin Seattle whatever and take an airplane and maybe stay over there and do some other stuff That's to do in Seattle and go to the packs and then come back.
Speaker 1: But anyway, they have added yet another event there's and not only that but this event is attempting to break a world record Really world record for most DS's on at once.
Speaker 1: Well, apparently they're going to have a all-con long con wide LARP.
Speaker 0: Aha now if I don't want to play in the LARP and I want to go to the con you don't have to all right.
Speaker 1: Apparently it's it's Terradrive live and there's a bunch of details here.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna read them because you probably don't care.
Speaker 1: But basically they're gonna try to teach everyone the rules and apparently it's pretty simple and there's gonna be zones and stuff and a modified version of rock-paper-scissors with cards that give people power ups and things and You can get into clans and fight with people and take over territory and whatever.
Speaker 1: they haven't really said a lot yet But yeah, they're gonna try to teach everyone in line Thursday and Friday how to play and just kind of wing it from there.
Speaker 0: Aha so, how will they verify if they have broken a world record for largest learn I imagine because they say they're actually gonna try to do the Guinness Book thing.
Speaker 1: So they're probably gonna have someone there counting the number of people participating.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean, how do you know everyone's participating if you just go down the line of 20,000 people and say hi I've taught them all the LARP and then you know The people start out like a in line a plan a little bit and then they all kind of go
Speaker 1: in.
Speaker 1: Well, the way the Guinness Book works is that when they set a list of requirements and then they send judges And if those requirements are met then they award the award and that's it Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So obviously the judges are going to set some sort of threshold for parties.
Speaker 0: I just wonder how what kind of requirements they'll be and how they'll verify that because it sounds pretty difficult to in a mask.
Speaker 0: I got 20,000.
Speaker 1: Scott will determine it is the Guinness Book is completely stupid bullshit.
Speaker 1: I've always hated it.
Speaker 0: Thank you for finally bringing up the point I was trying to make.
Speaker 1: the Guinness Book is crap.
Speaker 1: the world records in it are almost always crap except for the sports ones and I don't care about it at all.
Speaker 0: And there's some verifiable ones like fattest guy as of this year Actually, they just weigh it and find unless they've changed They stopped doing anything that was an oddity of humanity because they thought that that encouraged.
Speaker 0: but that was the only interesting part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, so yeah, I just remember when I was a kid in elementary school We'd have the book club whatever.
Speaker 1: you could order a bunch of books and I always ordered like Calvin and Hobbes books.
Speaker 1: Everyone in my classes always every time only got the mad libs and the Guinness Book for that month or year or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and no one ever bought any other books and I always thought they were all stupid.
Speaker 0: I got real books and once I got a mad lib and other people got the Guinness Book and I would look and look at the picture of the fattest Guy and then I wouldn't actually buy it now.
Speaker 0: and that was it plus the library.
Speaker 0: the school library had some Guinness Books And I would look at the picture of the fattest guy in there or the tallest guy.
Speaker 1: The thing is things like this can be cool.
Speaker 1: I mean we malign LARPing a lot but most of that is just due to the fact that we went to school in Rochester New York.
Speaker 1: the LARPing community in Rochester, New York around the Rochester Institute of Technology is by and large full of well Let me put it delicately Scary.
Speaker 1: no scary ass motherfuckers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's about as delicately as I can put it.
Speaker 0: these people they do fuck mothers work.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know the fact that that is actually true.
Speaker 1: anyway Scary people we avoided them at all costs once we realized what these people were.
Speaker 1: and I say what's with a lot of venom?
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: but there is a lot of good LARPing and back when I lived in Michigan I used to go to a lot of local gaming cons and I participated in a number of D&D based LARPs And while some of them sucked a lot of them were really really awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean LARPing isn't inherently bad like, you know, it's not like all LARP suck.
Speaker 0: the problem is the vast majority of LARPs out there suck and it's actually Pretty difficult to make a LARP good, but it's not impossible and good LARPs do exist in many places.
Speaker 1: well the other thing gaming LARPs like LARPs at a gaming con tend to be awesome because they tend to be the weird ones like a Paranoia LARP or they tend to be something like this where it's a really light con-wide kind of ongoing.
Speaker 0: Hey, I'm totally gonna say it's almost not even a LARP.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of like a silly kind of game in a way, but yeah, I guess it counts.
Speaker 1: It is a LARP.
Speaker 1: I mean people are gonna have roles and there's gonna be territories and clans and whatever and you walk around your thing.
Speaker 1: But I mean so you're in line and you see an enemy and you just happen to attack and have a little fight and then Keep going.
Speaker 0: but a LARP at an anime con is not good.
Speaker 0: It's very bad.
Speaker 0: Do not do it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much just scary fan people living out their anime fantasies and trying to bring you into their anime fantasies or maybe Taking turns fulfilling each other's anime fantasies.
Speaker 0: It's I don't know why cons have them fight an anime con.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have a LARP.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, hey, well the thing is one they're popular - They can be run really well and the people are into that.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't like cosplay is terribly much even though I like cosplayers and I don't like masquerades very much Just because I've seen all the good ones.
Speaker 1: I think in the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah total ever.
Speaker 1: I don't think any anything will ever beat the ones I've seen maybe but You still gotta have met a con because a lot of the people there like them and they're big event.
Speaker 0: I guess they do serve the purpose of keeping those scary people out of anything else while LARP is going on.
Speaker 1: I wasn't going to say that outright but I was gonna spend a few minutes and eventually make that point a really roundabout way.
Speaker 0: Well good now we can just get on with the show can't we?
Speaker 1: Things of the day?
Speaker 1: so I stumbled upon this kind of randomly but back in the day on the NES Maniac Mansion was one of my favorite games.
Speaker 0: Maniac Mansion is a game I had heard the name of and I never really played it even though somehow I knew all about it.
Speaker 0: But well never really played it or owned it.
Speaker 1: that might have been due to the Nintendo power where they described many of the secrets.
Speaker 0: I didn't have Nintendo power.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you're one of those heathens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so at any game pro until like sixth grade so and that was when there was already Sega Genesis action.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I don't know how I know about Maniac Mansion.
Speaker 0: I just do.
Speaker 1: well Maniac Mansion is the microwave one of the most one of the more famous video games ever made.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of people have heard about it it.
Speaker 1: it's a cult classic among numerous generations and sadly I never played it on a computer ever.
Speaker 1: the first time I ever saw it was on the Nintendo Entertainment System
Speaker 0: Basically for those you don't know I'm not gonna go in depth about this but Lucas ours the people who make you know Obviously Star Wars games and such they made back in the day a bunch of point-and-click adventure games such as day of the tentacle Indiana Jones and the Atlantis.
Speaker 0: something you didn't realize.
Speaker 1: the day of the tentacle was Maniac Mansion 2 basically Sam & Max Full throttle etc.
Speaker 0: And they were just these point-and-click adventure games where you know You'd sort of click on the screen.
Speaker 1: Oh the pirate one Monkey Island anyway, yes the games especially Maniac Mansion.
Speaker 1: We're really kind of off-beaten Gooney and Maniac Mansion was really kind of dark and weird especially as a kid.
Speaker 1: I mean walking into the house and you go into the kitchen, you know you're breaking into this mansion basically and suddenly when you get to the end of the kitchen this crazy old woman in a nurse's outfit sees you and starts screaming and chasing you and you freak out and I remember just looking at things.
Speaker 1: There's weird stuff everywhere.
Speaker 1: you can pick it all up and mess with it and The game wasn't really meant to be beaten on the first try because you could very easily make it impossible to win.
Speaker 1: the game was more one of those.
Speaker 1: you explore the world you start to figure things out and Eventually you figure out how to beat the game.
Speaker 1: and there were many many different ways to quote-unquote beat the game.
Speaker 0: yeah, but basically it's all about exploring this wacky mansion and looking at all this weird stuff and trying to do weird stuff.
Speaker 0: and There's a lot of weird things you could do and weird things you could encounter and it was just a lot of fun to Sort of poke all the bits and see what they all did.
Speaker 1: So that's my things of the day.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about these games in some show someday.
Speaker 1: our two speed runs of Maniac Mansion one on the computer and one On the NES and they do it in just under 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: both of them Wow Yeah the thing is they look very different and granted part of that is the fact that of course Nintendo of America being fruitish as They were back then censored and replaced a lot of things in Maniac Mansion.
Speaker 0: I mean Maniac Mansion was the only one of these games to ever come out on the NES.
Speaker 0: all the rest of them just sort Of came out for like DOS and the PC and the max and not really anything else.
Speaker 0: I guess that's because they had a mouse.
Speaker 1: It was I mean, it was actually really hard to play Maniac Mansion on the NES.
Speaker 1: I'll admit that it pretty much sucks.
Speaker 0: If you want to play Maniac Mansion, seriously, you should get the PC version.
Speaker 0: There's a thing called scum VM that you can get for free and then you can get the data files for all these different games By buying them, which is the only legal way and then you can play them on modern computer.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm pretty sure that in day the tentacle if I recall correctly There is a place where you could end up booting up a computer and playing Maniac Mansion 1 in its entirety.
Speaker 0: Wow, I did not know that.
Speaker 0: I'll have to go check that out.
Speaker 1: The one thing I want to point out I wouldn't recommend you watch the entire speedruns unless you're a masochist.
Speaker 1: they're interesting in that they show you the quickest path to beat the game as far as I can see and They show you the differences in the graphics and the aesthetics and the music.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna point out the music.
Speaker 1: you can Say what you will about the music or lack thereof and one or other of these versions.
Speaker 1: The music did get really annoying though.
Speaker 1: I remember as a kid.
Speaker 1: I usually turned it off after about five minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah Granted it was.
Speaker 1: I forget the term for it But the music wasn't just like theme music playing out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: Every kid had a CD player or a tape player or something on him that you could turn on or off.
Speaker 1: that played the music.
Speaker 0: But they have CDs.
Speaker 0: in those days, I don't remember I probably must have been a Walkman.
Speaker 1: CDs were pretty old.
Speaker 1: I had a CD player relatively early.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean this was like way early.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this game didn't come on CD-ROM.
Speaker 0: It came on floppy disk Wasn't until the later ones they came on CD-ROM.
Speaker 1: remember CDs were out long before.
Speaker 1: there were CD-ROMs with computer games on.
Speaker 0: I know I know but you get my point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do get your point.
Speaker 1: But the other thing I'd like to point out is that these games are really fun.
Speaker 1: If you're just playing through them and you're exploring it's all.
Speaker 0: just try to play one of these games.
Speaker 0: They're all great.
Speaker 0: There's a reason that someone made the scum VM thing to allow us to play them in modern machines because they still get good games Worth playing.
Speaker 1: but the thing is a speedrun of a game like this Almost makes the game look like shit because it skips all the interesting stuff and it's just run run run object Run run run object run object run object.
Speaker 1: meteor in the edge of the launch into space game over.
Speaker 0: Yep I guess if you all if you like playing these games after you play them all they're putting out new Sam and Max games in Sort of episodic fashion, but you can like buy at the store or on Steam like packs of all the episodes.
Speaker 0: So if you're liking the Sam and Max Especially the old, you know the old one they got new ones that people are pretty pleased with.
Speaker 0: apparently you can go for those.
Speaker 0: Alright, so my thing of the day rim you love the television, don't you?
Speaker 1: Well the Intellivision - alright.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this is a video for 1983 or 84 if I may.
Speaker 0: Yes, when we were one or two years old.
Speaker 0: if it were yes, and this video is Spa of and by some people at Mattel electronics home of the Intellivision, uh-huh, and Basically, it's a bunch of them just fooling around in the office making a silly video.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like they knew YouTube was going to exist in the year 2007. so 23 years in advance there's 25 24 years in advance.
Speaker 0: They decided to make this video knowing that one day it would be on YouTube for us to watch.
Speaker 0: Where of a bunch of silly old-school video game programmers fooling around in the office making jokes Hating each other with water balloons being naked.
Speaker 1: What was that?
Speaker 0: making fun of video games?
Speaker 1: Well, what was that?
Speaker 0: One of the guys is naked actually naked I'm not sure but you don't see any of his bits, but he could be naked under there.
Speaker 1: See that that's very misleading because there are many pictures of me particularly in the ocean at the shore or back in high school In band where it looks like I'm naked.
Speaker 0: basically, he's he's sitting in a chair at an at a table in a conference room and You can see his torso above the table and he's got his legs up on the table But his bottom and his bits are below the table in the seat.
Speaker 1: I will wager I would got some shorts on that.
Speaker 1: He's wearing some sort of speedo.
Speaker 1: Maybe a one-piece bikini down there
Speaker 0: Possibly but that the point is it's a funny video made in the olden times and it's got a lot of that old styling kind of early 80s computer nerd kind of humor, which is almost identical to YouTube current current day humor, so you should watch it.
Speaker 1: man I suddenly have this urge to get my grandpa to send me the old and television too so I can play those games in a Format that works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but my favorite part actually is the guy when he starts talking about all that.
Speaker 0: there's a video game for everything.
Speaker 0: What video game could we possibly make next?
Speaker 0: and he's got just this pile of all these video game boxes And he's throwing them all around.
Speaker 1: They made a lot of games for the in television.
Speaker 0: It's like every sport imaginable.
Speaker 0: curling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I played a curling game.
Speaker 0: I know it's not good.
Speaker 0: It's not real curling.
Speaker 0: It's not good.
Speaker 0: How can fake curling be?
Speaker 1: curling is not curling so pretty fun smart.
Speaker 1: It's interesting.
Speaker 0: No, not really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is now.
Speaker 0: If you ever played it once when a time when back in the day what day I don't remember.
Speaker 1: How do you curl Scott?
Speaker 0: Yeah for one person takes the the rock and you try to throw the rock down the ice and some other people with the brooms go Broom, broom, broom, broom, broom, and they want the rock to stop in the in the bullseye area.
Speaker 0: But then another person throws a rock and they might bump you out.
Speaker 0: So it's like shuffleboard with ice.
Speaker 1: What is the up rooming?
Speaker 0: do it makes it the the the rock either go faster or slower?
Speaker 0: It sort of makes the ice, you know You can broom the ice in a certain way to sort of guide The rock to where you want it to be.
Speaker 1: most of what you've said could be derived from common knowledge of the sport.
Speaker 1: I don't believe for a second you've ever curled.
Speaker 0: All righty.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna call you out.
Speaker 0: I curled one time.
Speaker 1: when One time give me a year.
Speaker 1: Give me a range of years Late 90s late 9 between 95 and 98.
Speaker 1: In what circumstances?
Speaker 0: My friend's dad was like all about the curling.
Speaker 0: So one time I just happened to be there and I curled.
Speaker 1: one time happened to be there.
Speaker 1: where did he have a curling rink?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a. there was a the wonderland of ice place.
Speaker 0: They they curl on the the ice that they usually play hockey on the curling time.
Speaker 1: So you went there with the family and then you curled with the dead?
Speaker 0: No, I rolled I threw the rock one time Exactly, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: That was it.
Speaker 0: And I said, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: It's shuffleboard might as well be shuffleboard, which is better.
Speaker 0: So seeing as we're all back into the FPS actions.
Speaker 0: We remembered.
Speaker 0: Hey, there are some FPS.
Speaker 0: as we played back in the day I wonder if we can play those.
Speaker 0: FPS is again in addition to you know counter-strike.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think part of it with at least terms of the show was that like Alex was over and you two were in the living room talking about FPS and whatever and I was in the other room and natural selection came up and then Suddenly I ran into the room and said we never did a show on this did we?
Speaker 0: I guess not.
Speaker 0: Let me search again to make sure.
Speaker 0: Sure, we never done a show a natural selection and not the Darwin kind and sure enough we hadn't.
Speaker 1: scarily enough I mean, this is one of my favorite games ever.
Speaker 0: actually, I just searched and apparently we have mentioned the game in the show before because once I did a news about how there Might be dynamic infestation in the sequel remember that video.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I remember that video.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: But who knows if we'll ever see that.
Speaker 1: I don't know why you searched for that.
Speaker 1: We already did that, you know weeks ago when we decided to do this show.
Speaker 0: I just so I didn't search I wasn't there I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah natural selection is a mod to the FPS half-life.
Speaker 0: Yes, and you know calling it a mod is sort of crazy.
Speaker 0: I mean technically speaking it is a mod.
Speaker 0: It uses the half-life one engine and creates a different game on top of that engine.
Speaker 0: But more strictly speaking, this is more like a total conversion of half-life.
Speaker 0: I mean only the most expert of FPS players if you gave them this game would recognize that it was actually Half-life 1 not half-life 2.
Speaker 1: half-life 1 the game from like the 90s now It was made by a guy named Charlie Cleveland, but most people in the world know him as Flaira Flayra, yep.
Speaker 1: I think he eventually went on to found the company that's now unknown worlds, which is Theoretically working on natural selection 2 and natural selection for the source engine.
Speaker 1: the odds of natural selection 2 coming out are Pretty low.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say yeah I mean They're supposedly working on it and once in a while there's drips and drabs of news and they say stuff.
Speaker 0: But I've never seen anything substantial other than that dynamic infestation video.
Speaker 0: That was a news back in 2005.
Speaker 0: Oh No December 5th 2006. but yeah, I'm not getting my hopes up for any more natural selection.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna be happy with the natural selection We've already got.
Speaker 1: now the thing is I mean I say this is one of my favorite games ever and I think Scott will agree On that point, but it's a pretty good FPS.
Speaker 0: I gotta tell you that I mean, it's one of those games You know.
Speaker 1: periodically like we talk about anime and certain shows like Ava bebop eska flown a lay They just try gun they come up again and again and again and they're just they're timeless They never die.
Speaker 1: They're said such an influence on us and in video games the same way and in FPS is particularly.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much counter-strike natural selection tribes - pretty much the thing about natural selection is.
Speaker 0: it's one of those things where someone comes up with a Genius idea and it's maybe it's an idea that a lot of people have come up with before.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you this is an idea that a lot of people have come up with before But no one is able to execute the idea.
Speaker 0: No one does it like.
Speaker 0: for example the idea of dig was an idea that slash dot.
Speaker 0: people had for years and years and years And years, but no one actually did it, you know, or did it successfully for the longest time?
Speaker 0: Natural selection is pretty much the only successful implementation as far as I'm concerned of an RTS plus FPS ever and it's a really good Implementation of that.
Speaker 0: somewhat obvious, but everyone recognizes the awesomeness idea.
Speaker 1: So let's describe the game a little bit Basically, it's an FPS straight up, but it's asymmetric and there are two teams the aliens the Cara the infestation Whatever you want to call them and the Marines the humans the quote-unquote good guys You
Speaker 0: can tell this is based on the the movies You know with the aliens and the spitting and that and the stomach exploding in the such.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now it's that kind of theme in the game.
Speaker 1: I mean, you're pretty much gonna be sure that that is definitely an influence when you see the century turret.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know some of the guns.
Speaker 1: now a lot of games that are FPS is of two or three sides and they're asymmetric like pirates Vikings Knights for each side as Different but equal powers and as a result, they have different advantages and disadvantages even counter-strike terrorists counter-terrorists.
Speaker 0: They have different weapons You know, they're not exactly the same but they're.
Speaker 0: you know One team is not better than the other team.
Speaker 1: Natural selection takes it one step further and that not only are the teams themselves in terms of their capabilities Completely different and asymmetric but the way you play the game the way you see the game and the way you interact with the game on a Fundamental level are completely different.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean it's really not like any other FPS you're gonna play.
Speaker 0: I mean basically what it comes down to is The aliens when they play in a game of natural selection are trying to kill all the Marines.
Speaker 0: They want to spread their alien infestation around the entire map and eat all the Marines and eat all the marine equipment.
Speaker 0: And if they can destroy all of the Marines important machines and eat all the Marines The Marines can't teleport in and the aliens have conquered that place and they can infest it with aliens all they want with no interference Yep.
Speaker 1: So basically if the last marine dies and there's no way for anyone to respond The game is over and the Marines the Marines don't respawn.
Speaker 0: They have these teleporters and new Marines are teleported in from marine base.
Speaker 0: Also, the Marines are trying to clean out the alien infestation.
Speaker 0: They will not be satisfied until all of the aliens and all the alien hives are destroyed so that they can use this You know marine, you know human facility for its original intended purpose.
Speaker 1: again Obviously, it's some sort of space base that was taken over by the aliens and you're coming to save everybody.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of different bases and things.
Speaker 1: You find out that oh everybody's dead.
Speaker 1: now We just got a flamethrower over the place and then put more scientists here and hope this never happens again.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now which one should we talk about?
Speaker 1: first because I think the Marines and the aliens are equally interesting.
Speaker 0: They are equally interested.
Speaker 0: That's part of what makes this game Awesome is usually when you have an asymmetric game where you have two or more teams that are so drastically different you find people Really want to stick with just sort of one side like people playing World of Warcraft, you know I mean everyone likes the different teams in World of Warcraft or Starcraft But any particular person likes to stick with just one.
Speaker 0: usually I mean you find a Zerg guy He's all Zerg or it's really like Warhammer.
Speaker 0: people pick one and they stick with it But that's probably because of money mostly but in natural selection people who play They most of them play both sides and they don't really mind.
Speaker 0: It's not like ah shit.
Speaker 0: I'm on aliens crap.
Speaker 0: It's like alright aliens.
Speaker 0: Alright Marines, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's all good.
Speaker 0: Even though the two teams are so different.
Speaker 1: They're basically different games though.
Speaker 1: I will say there is one big exception to that and that is the commanders.
Speaker 1: Yes, but they're reading of their self.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about the Marines first because that you mentioned the RTS FPS and yes, I think that alone.
Speaker 1: So, I mean that's what sold me on the game before I even knew anything else.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So the way the Marines work is.
Speaker 0: They spawn into the map and their Marines and they walk around and they have guns and it's like playing a normal FPS.
Speaker 0: You have a machine gun a light machine gun.
Speaker 0: It's not very powerful, but it is.
Speaker 0: it is pretty good.
Speaker 0: You got a pistol and a knife and you can sort of you have a. you can use your use button to sort of work Different machines and that's you walk around the map.
Speaker 0: You're trying to kill aliens and such.
Speaker 1: now There's one chair this big machine.
Speaker 1: that's sitting there in the room.
Speaker 0: you start in and that's the command chair and whoever goes and sits In that chair is playing a different game from everybody else what they sit in that chair.
Speaker 0: Suddenly they're playing an RTS.
Speaker 0: They look at the map that the FPS map the same map that you everyone else is playing an FPS on and they see it with an overhead view and they have.
Speaker 0: it looks a lot like Starcraft and you could build things on the map and you have resources that you can spend and earn on different things.
Speaker 1: You can group up Marines and give them a waypoint and then the game will tell you when they get there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, humans you're playing with are no longer FPS and humans as far as you you're concerned They're just units that you have at your disposal.
Speaker 0: But unlike a game like command and conquer where the units do exactly what you say The units are real people.
Speaker 0: each single one is a real person playing an FPS and you know they might suck.
Speaker 0: their individual skill determines whether they'll win or lose a lot of the time and They might not follow your orders.
Speaker 0: They might be incompetent.
Speaker 0: They might follow your orders too You know, so it's imagine if when you're playing command and conquer every guy that you gave an order to was a real person playing an FPS.
Speaker 1: The nice thing is though while they might not listen to you sometimes and sometimes just there's problems.
Speaker 1: at least Every individual marine will get out of the way of something dangerous if it's right there and coming to kill him.
Speaker 1: Yes, they will do that and conquer not so much and I lost a lot of men to my own harvesters.
Speaker 0: Okay, so the commander basically what he tries to do is first the goal unless they have a crazy strategy and not going to talk about crazy strategies in this game because there are many is To get more resources.
Speaker 0: and the way you do this is there are certain points on the map which everyone knows where they are.
Speaker 0: once you know the maps where there are resource nodes and The the commander can say alright I'm gonna spend X resources to build a resource node there and a resource node appears, you know a resource harvesting thing appears on the node and That isn't enough.
Speaker 0: because if that if it was that easy, what would be the point of the game?
Speaker 0: You know the guy would just build resource nodes all over the map right at the beginning.
Speaker 0: get all the resources win.
Speaker 1: Well, remember what Scott's saying applies to any structure that the commander can build ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when he builds the resource node or any other structure Marines have to go over to it and make it work.
Speaker 0: They have to go stand next to it and push a button on it in order to fix it and turn it on and it Takes a while.
Speaker 0: So you build a resource node.
Speaker 0: you're gonna need Marines Standing next to it to make it work to defend it from being eaten by aliens before it starts working etc, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: Now this really really creates an interesting game first.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about from the players perspective.
Speaker 1: So you spawn and you're in this really dark world with weird music and there's noises all around.
Speaker 1: the atmospheric effects in these games are Absolutely amazing.
Speaker 0: for half-life 1.
Speaker 1: they're double amazing maps are so well made and so perfect.
Speaker 0: I think they're the best maps in all of FPS is period pretty much and So you get up and someone's elected the commander and they start building stuff.
Speaker 1: They secure the base.
Speaker 1: They build some stuff.
Speaker 1: maybe they build a shotgun and they give it to the player that they knew from the previous game is really good.
Speaker 1: and then You go out and it'll get divided into teams like you three.
Speaker 1: go to this waypoint.
Speaker 1: Wait for me to build a resource tower build it and defend it until I tell you.
Speaker 1: otherwise You three go build this resource tower then go to this other point and wait for further orders defending that point at all costs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you stand and watch that hallway if anyone comes yelling scream granted That's how it's supposed to work on paper.
Speaker 0: And if you practice with like a team for a long time, it will work like that.
Speaker 0: But in general pickup games, it doesn't work like that.
Speaker 1: actually now that I've been playing again It works like that almost all the time really everyone listens to the commander.
Speaker 1: The commander is God, uh-huh granted I think it's just that the game's been out so long that it's mostly Hardcore players and newbies who really want to get into the game.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But anyway You go out and you stand next to this resource point and it sort of appears out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: and now you're holding on To it.
Speaker 0: and while you're holding on to it trying to turn it on and make it work to get your team more resources You can win.
Speaker 0: Aliens might be coming.
Speaker 1: so usually you got like two guys building it and one guy standing off to the side with a shitty machine gun kind of nervous looking around.
Speaker 1: because Basically, whenever you're walking around anywhere as a marine if you are alone You're probably Already dead.
Speaker 1: You just don't realize it yet because The aliens just come out of nowhere and they wait for you in ambush.
Speaker 1: You go around a corner.
Speaker 1: You're being real careful.
Speaker 1: You're swinging your machine gun around.
Speaker 1: Suddenly you hear tick tick tick tick tick and before you can finish trying Buddy, buddy, buddy, buddy, buddy, buddy.
Speaker 1: You're done.
Speaker 1: You're dead.
Speaker 1: You tell the commander.
Speaker 1: There's some skulks over in data processing.
Speaker 0: Yeah I like how it on the maps.
Speaker 0: Every part of the map has a name and that name shows up on your screen.
Speaker 0: So you always know where you are.
Speaker 0: so you can learn the maps and easily communicate about different parts of the map to your team.
Speaker 0: Like, you know up guys in data guys and sensory bad guys in.
Speaker 1: you know dark hallway and Parts of the map are worth more than other parts.
Speaker 1: and there's choke points and there's vents.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this place there's like some of the maps have double res where there's a spot that has two resource nodes.
Speaker 0: You know some of the place that the alien hives can only be built in three different locations.
Speaker 0: So, you know where those those are pretty important spots.
Speaker 0: and the place where the marine base starts is also pretty important.
Speaker 1: So it's really scary walking around.
Speaker 1: But the fun part is it's not like counter-strike or FPS and most people are used to.
Speaker 1: you move Really slow and you make a lot of noise.
Speaker 1: if you don't want to make a lot of noise You hold down shift or whatever and you walk really slow.
Speaker 1: you go so slow It's almost painful and furthermore.
Speaker 1: I wish more games did this counter-strike would be a lot better if they did this.
Speaker 1: In natural selection you move at your normal speed when you're walking forward or turn it or whatever.
Speaker 1: But if you were trying to walk backwards while looking behind you you move slow.
Speaker 1: Yep, so that means instead of you know in any counter-strike game You're backing away from an enemy shooting and that's just what you do in this game.
Speaker 1: You have a choice.
Speaker 1: the moment aliens come either stand your ground and shoot Retreat slowly shooting behind you or shooting in front of you you're walking back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're walking backwards, but you're still shooting back in the direction.
Speaker 0: Yes, if you try to walk backwards and shoot forwards You will walk insanely slow Even if you're not trying to shoot.
Speaker 0: walking backwards is twice as more than twice as slow as walking.
Speaker 1: So as a result when something horrible suddenly happens, like you think you're good.
Speaker 1: You almost built the phase gate.
Speaker 1: You've got four Marines with you and suddenly three fades run into the room and everyone's going fade fade Fuck.
Speaker 1: they got an early fade.
Speaker 1: Fuck.
Speaker 1: They got a second eye.
Speaker 1: But at that moment a lot of Marines you'll see him they know they can't win.
Speaker 1: They're not even gonna try to retreat.
Speaker 1: retreat in an orderly fashion because they don't want to die.
Speaker 1: they turn around and run.
Speaker 0: Usually that's not enough But it's it's a lot faster than trying to back up while shooting your piddly pop gun at this giant nasty alien.
Speaker 1: It makes the game a lot more realistic and a lot more immersive and a lot more frightening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically as the Marines you're trying to build a lot of structures Which means you need Marines to go to where the structures are build them defend them from aliens.
Speaker 0: Get a lot of resource see that you can build most of the structures in your base where they'll be relatively well defended and you can build defensive things like Automatic turrets Allah aliens the movie and such.
Speaker 0: that will defend your structures when when Marines aren't there to do it You know themselves.
Speaker 0: But the resource nodes are all around the map and you need to go and get them in order to have enough resource points For the commander to pay for all those important things and you need to pay for all those important things or else Marines won't be able to get better guns and they won't be able to get better armor and they won't be able to get better Anything and aliens will own you.
Speaker 0: and basically you're just trying to get enough resources To get enough upgrades to your weapons and armor to be able to go out and destroy the aliens without worrying about it.
Speaker 0: You know because if you just go out there with the stuff you start the game with they're gonna bite you Unless you're really really good, which is unlikely.
Speaker 1: now the commander has I mean, there's all this stuff He has to deal with it.
Speaker 1: You don't really see but he has a tech tree.
Speaker 0: He spends resources on different things and eventually basically playing an RTS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean he builds up Research and eventually get shotguns and the super machine guns and grenade launchers and jetpacks and the super awesome heavy armor.
Speaker 0: Yeah and there's also other stuff he can buy like That you might not realize like the sensors that will tell you where aliens are or the beacon Which will.
Speaker 0: which if all the humans get when you die as a human They're these teleporters that you teleport in.
Speaker 0: I talked about them already.
Speaker 0: They're basically the spawn points and if you have no spawn points left, no one can spawn into the map.
Speaker 0: So what sometimes will happen is they'll be maybe two or three spawn points and all the humans will die because they rushed an alien Hive and they all got killed.
Speaker 0: and they'll spawn in kind of slowly You know because they can only spawn in at a certain number of Marines per second.
Speaker 0: There's per minute per spawn point and the beacon is one of the things the commander can use to say everyone spawns Who's dead immediately and it's good for the like the last ditch when the aliens are in the base and everyone died Suddenly everyone spawns in the base and maybe you'll have enough to push the aliens.
Speaker 1: That's one thing about natural selection that makes this game So great.
Speaker 1: is that in a lot of like once you've lost a game, you know You've lost and now crap.
Speaker 1: now I got a way for this to play out whatever and people to stop caring in this game Even though you'll know you've lost a good five or six minutes before it finally happens.
Speaker 1: You lost the double res you try to retake it and you failed.
Speaker 1: You know the aliens have the whole eastern half of the map.
Speaker 1: You're basically being defensive.
Speaker 1: all your expeditions out fail all the scouts you send out get killed.
Speaker 1: Eventually, the Marines kind of realize they're all gonna die and the commander realizes this and you move into this.
Speaker 1: It's weird because you don't feel bad about it.
Speaker 1: You just realize that now it's time for the last.
Speaker 1: stand Yeah and you start just Barricading yourselves in and trying to live as long as possible and it's just as fun as when you're winning.
Speaker 0: I think part of it.
Speaker 0: what it is is that the game makes you feel as if you've always got a chance like I Could sneak out all alone get into a place if there's no aliens there and totally owned with my little knife I could cut up their whole hive and I've done it before it happens.
Speaker 0: It's not common But there's always this crazy chance that with some covert mission of like two Marines with knives Going out there maybe a little help from the commander Maybe a shotgun they can totally turn the game around or at least make a setback for the aliens.
Speaker 1: Yep or maybe you defend it so well and you Defend it early enough when you realize the tide was against you and you held out long enough to build out the resources To suddenly make a heavy train and March your asses out.
Speaker 0: I think what it is is that even if you've already lost you are still able to sort of hold the enemy back.
Speaker 0: It's not like you've lost and then you're crushed.
Speaker 0: and because you still have the ability to hold them back You really feel like you can make a difference.
Speaker 0: if you can hold them back Why can't you push them back, you know, and if they decide to suck then you kind of can.
Speaker 0: sometimes
Speaker 1: You really start to develop a camaraderie with the people on your team because everyone's voice chatting pretty much Almost everyone who plays this game voice chats and you hear people talking and it's
Speaker 0: necessary
Speaker 1: commander given orders and you really start to feel like you're a part of something.
Speaker 1: and it's really scary.
Speaker 1: when you're out with a team and the team gets taken out by a sudden fade and It's just you and you survive because you hit around the corner or the team got taken out around the corner and you were guarding the rear.
Speaker 0: then or when you decide on your own that you're gonna you just gonna take.
Speaker 0: you're gonna take your welder and open up This vent with your welder and you're gonna sneak through these vents where you know Nobody's there and it's all dark and there's no one in there not even aliens because it was a vent that was welded shut You know.
Speaker 0: and then you're sneaking through the secret way all alone and it's gonna come out who knows where on the map and there's Stuff there.
Speaker 0: Who knows what?
Speaker 0: and you're gonna open up the other end with your welder and But a single marine.
Speaker 1: and if you if an alien comes you're dead and there's almost nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 0: It's right, but if no aliens come you can fuck shit up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, so let's talk about the aliens.
Speaker 1: Well, I got one more thing to say about the Marines.
Speaker 1: I the way the guns work.
Speaker 1: not gonna go into details But unlike counter-strike where you know, you got to hit the head pick pick pick and double tap.
Speaker 1: This is a game much like certain scenes in certain movies involving chain guns where the light machine gun your primary weapon Shoots a fucking lot of bullets really fast in a general direction, but they're kind of weak.
Speaker 1: No But the thing is the big gun shoots a bunch more bullets in a general directions.
Speaker 0: It's big bullets like freaking imagine like Desert Eagle bullets like on a chain.
Speaker 1: just damn the guns are ludicrous.
Speaker 1: The point is that when you fire it's not like I got to walk slowly and like pick the guy off.
Speaker 1: all realistically It is aliens the movie guns where you run down the hall with your minigun Blowing shit up and hoping you don't die.
Speaker 0: There's a grenade launcher that shoots for.
Speaker 0: it's basically a revolver that holds four grenades and it's like doom doom doom doom And then you reload it kind of slowly and carefully, but when you fire those four grenades God damn Do you fire four fucking grenades.
Speaker 1: the visceral feeling you get when you fire any weapon in this game is?
Speaker 1: Amazing because it's basically point and shoot and empty your clip.
Speaker 1: You pretty much empty your clip every time you shoot the other.
Speaker 0: the other things the commander can buy.
Speaker 0: if you're the heavy armor in The jetpack, let's just talk about this for a second the heavy armor, but you can't have them both at the same time.
Speaker 0: It's one or the other.
Speaker 0: the heavy armor basically makes you really hard to kill.
Speaker 0: aliens will have a seriously difficult Time killing you because you have so much armor on and plus they usually give you a welder with a heavy armor Which lets you repair someone else's armor, and they repair your armor, so you're basically when you have a train It's called a heavy train a whole bunch of guys in heavy armor lined up with welders and guns Which
Speaker 1: is generally the goal of any commander?
Speaker 0: It's really hard for any aliens to fuck with that and they just march around the map in a group destroying Everything like.
Speaker 0: it's just a big alien cleanup.
Speaker 0: But then
Speaker 1: again the aliens can win because if the chain like say they realize the chains coming and they have one onos and they Send him in the middle of the chain and the chain splits in two and then they start picking off the stragglers one by one Which is actually kind of easy to do.
Speaker 1: yeah a heavy by himself is just as dead as an unarmored guy by himself Depending on how strong the aliens are.
Speaker 0: but anyway yet the heavy armor you walk really slow But you're a freaking.
Speaker 0: it's like freaking robot armor.
Speaker 0: You're dangerous as all hell.
Speaker 0: Then the jetpack is slightly different because you don't have the heavy armor.
Speaker 0: when you have the jetpack You're pretty easy to kill just as easy to kill as anything else.
Speaker 0: But you can fly around and move really fast all over the place like crazy And it's kind of difficult to control the jetpack.
Speaker 0: it takes a lot of practice with the jump button and such But once you've got the hang of it You can fly around with your mad skills and basically zoom past aliens and go straight for the hive and start fucking it up.
Speaker 0: Or you know flying aliens can't escape you by hiding in vents and places and you can fly around getting otherwise Difficult to reach things and just rape it them apart.
Speaker 1: now the aliens.
Speaker 1: playing as an alien Like I said is basically a completely different game.
Speaker 0: It's really silly and awesome.
Speaker 1: first off There's no commander.
Speaker 1: instead There's a hive mind and the way that works is you get a bunch of information constantly Visually and audibly About the state of your fellow aliens and the state of the state of the game.
Speaker 1: So you can see in the distance all these kind of glowing waypoints all your alien friends all your alien structures where your hives are all this stuff and you hear noises and sounds that tell you things like an alien is under attack.
Speaker 1: and then you see that alien blinking red and you know where they are.
Speaker 1: or Structures under attack and you know that the Marines are attacking some alien structure somewhere.
Speaker 0: or there is no commander on the alien team.
Speaker 0: Everyone is the same.
Speaker 0: You're all.
Speaker 0: basically it does.
Speaker 0: there's no difference between one alien player and another alien.
Speaker 1: Everyone gets all the same information and the players just by talking come to a general consensus as to how to act based on that Information.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now you might be saying well your team gets resources, right?
Speaker 0: Yes, you do.
Speaker 0: you are competing for the same resource nodes.
Speaker 0: The Marines are competing for.
Speaker 0: however What happens is instead of the resource is going to one alien who decides so they will be spent.
Speaker 0: they are divided up semi-evenly according to some algorithm amongst all the players and everyone can spend their share of the resources and the way they see fit.
Speaker 1: Now the aliens.
Speaker 1: you start as everyone starts to the same little alien and you get one of three hive locations.
Speaker 1: You all start there and then this voice says cleanse the intruders and then you run off your little skulk and skulks.
Speaker 1: Basically, I have one thing they can do but I just go bitey bitey bitey bitey bitey bitey bitey bitey bitey Big mouth, that's all it is.
Speaker 0: And you're pretty small and you're really fast and you're hard for Marines to kill and you can go on the walls Without doing it.
Speaker 0: You just walk on the walls or the ceilings.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: so generally what you do is the game starts and the aliens either all rush the Marines start and there's this sudden immediate melee at the start of the game where and then it kind of evens out into battle lines or The aliens kind of scatter and they set up ambushes.
Speaker 1: That's what I usually do.
Speaker 1: they'll be like three skulks you
Speaker 0: hide you go to like two doors away from the Marine base near one of the resource points and You wait for a marine to come by and you're hiding up in the ceiling in like a dark crevice And he's that marine is gonna walk right under you.
Speaker 0: So you just wait for him to walk through the doorway and he keeps walking.
Speaker 0: He doesn't hear you He doesn't see you.
Speaker 0: you're hiding in the dark.
Speaker 0: You're a little tiny alien in the ceiling and after he walks by you you fall down off the ceiling Go up behind him and bite his butt right off.
Speaker 1: just Yeah, it takes like one or two bites to kill.
Speaker 0: and it's kind of weird because playing as the Marines aliens are scary and dangerous Like whoa shits like in the movie aliens.
Speaker 0: playing as the aliens They're kind of silly and happy like buddy buddy buddy buddy buddy buddy buddy.
Speaker 1: I feel really sympathetic toward the aliens.
Speaker 1: when I'm like when I'm playing an alien.
Speaker 1: I like him.
Speaker 1: I like him a lot.
Speaker 1: those fucking Marines should leave him alone.
Speaker 1: But when I'm a marine aliens are scary and they kill me immediately.
Speaker 0: aliens Just want to have fun.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you now think of this when you're a marine Aliens just kill you if you're alone.
Speaker 1: when you're an alien if a marine sees you you're pretty much dead.
Speaker 0: Yes the reason the aliens just kill Marines when they're alone by default is because Marines usually don't see the aliens coming.
Speaker 0: the aliens are small and fast and they're on the walls and the ceilings and they come and They bite him before the Marines have a chance.
Speaker 0: and but if you're an alien and there's a marine down the hallway And he sees you sitting there he has a gun you're far away.
Speaker 0: you're gonna bite him from down the hallway?
Speaker 0: I think not.
Speaker 0: his machine gun will kill you.
Speaker 1: You have to sneak up on him somehow.
Speaker 0: He had to move really fast and really cleverly and even then like running up if you think Rushing at the marine by running up the wall while rushing at him.
Speaker 0: He sees you.
Speaker 0: he has a machine gun.
Speaker 0: It shoots a lot of bullets.
Speaker 0: They're pretty weak individually, but there's a lot of them now this they will kill you.
Speaker 1: This is the sign of an excellently designed asymmetric game.
Speaker 1: the doom game I hear is the same way where if you play as one side or the other side Both sides are equally afraid of the other side.
Speaker 1: or you think wow how could I ever win against that?
Speaker 1: But you think that for every side you hear about yep That that's the sign of a perfect game or at least a really good game a really good asymmetric game.
Speaker 1: and in this game I mean the worst thing in the world is you're an alien and you go like you're walking out of your way to a resource tower.
Speaker 1: you're gonna cap it do whatever and you come around the corner and suddenly you see like four Marines Working on stuff and they're all talking and you don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: But you see him and you hear him and they haven't seen you yet and you don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: and then suddenly while you're thinking like you're trying to back into the shadows one of them looks Up and suddenly they're all pointing guns at you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: It's like Marines will walk down the hallway and a bunch of aliens are hiding there.
Speaker 0: Oh, no But they'll be the same situation where a bunch of aliens walk down the hallway and there's a bunch of Marines with a bunch of Equipment they're setting up and it's like oh shit.
Speaker 0: We can't go over there.
Speaker 0: God damn.
Speaker 1: now I said the Marines are all talking and I was serious.
Speaker 1: one thing about this game.
Speaker 1: I talked a lot about the environmental stuff and a lot of that's in the maps.
Speaker 1: But it's also in the game itself.
Speaker 1: when you're a marine or an alien your guy depending on how Exerted you are and what you're doing will say things into his calm and just say things and make noises.
Speaker 1: And the aliens kind of burgled in belch and groan and just creak and make noises all the time and the Marines just keep saying Stuff.
Speaker 1: so you'll be like sneaking along and then around the corner you hear two Marines say something to each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of cool It feels it really does feel real despite the lack of modern graphics or sound technologies.
Speaker 1: Now there are other kinds of aliens.
Speaker 1: you can be.
Speaker 1: The way it works.
Speaker 1: Well, the resources like Scott said get distributed around evenly and you can either turn into this one kind of alien The best kind called a gorge and they're the only ones who can build
Speaker 0: as a default Alien, if you die as an alien and come back to life, you're a skunk you can spend what 10 resource points?
Speaker 0: I think yep to become a gorge.
Speaker 0: basically, you your alien will go pop and turn into an egg and you have to wait while you're sitting in the egg and Sometimes the Marines will come and kill you while you're an egg.
Speaker 0: and that's not pleasant because there's nothing you could do.
Speaker 1: But only if you're stupid.
Speaker 0: only if you're stupid and you turn into an egg in the middle of like the hallway Where this Marines walking around and then after a little while when you're done Gestating in your egg you pop out and you're a different kind of alien.
Speaker 0: You're a gorge, which is nothing like a skulk at all.
Speaker 1: Now that's the only one that can spend resources real quick.
Speaker 1: There's also the lurk and the fade and the onos and the onos stands for onos.
Speaker 0: That is exactly because Both
Speaker 1: sides have this moment where you realize that you're fucked and when you're the Marines It's when you're doing your stuff and you think you're doing okay, you're not doing great But you're doing okay, and you're gonna win and then suddenly some guy somewhere out there yells.
Speaker 0: Fuck.
Speaker 1: Oh, no Oh, no, so does that means that some alien had so much excess resource like a hundred resource points Ludicrous they decided I'm going to spend that all on being an onos.
Speaker 1: now Remember if you die as an onos you go back to being a skulk.
Speaker 0: and all those resources all those resource points.
Speaker 1: So that guy is sure of himself and an onos will take out almost any number of Marines.
Speaker 0: and onos is basically this giant rhinoceros.
Speaker 0: you turn you.
Speaker 0: basically you go from being this little tiny bitey guy to a giant Rhinoceros and you can hit people with your horn.
Speaker 0: you can charge into people and ram them with your horn.
Speaker 0: You can devour Marines with full health and the most expensive equipment whole with a single click and then they will basically sit there unable to do anything as they watch goat see for a few seconds and then you eventually shit them out when they die from the Horrible acid in your giant rhinoceros stomach.
Speaker 1: now theoretically if they can hack the onos to pieces they can pull you out of the stomach If
Speaker 0: you if there are other Marines with them Let's say there's three Marines with heavy armor and heavy machine guns and you eat one of them and they're in your stomach dying If the other two kill you before the one inside of you dies.
Speaker 0: Basically you die around him and he just stands up and goes ah, oh god.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was disgusting.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna talk much about the other aliens But the lurk is a flying alien that can spit and spit gas at people and he's pretty stealthy and annoying.
Speaker 0: He's basically the pestering alien.
Speaker 1: if what I run pestering them when I was much better at the game I used to always do the early lurk, but I'm not good at it.
Speaker 0: The lurk can fly which is pretty good Especially if the other people have jetpacks and the fade is just the dangerous.
Speaker 1: it runs into the room and kills like four Marines suddenly And that is aid is sort of like controlling.
Speaker 0: the fade is the only one.
Speaker 0: that's anything like controlling a human because it's a bipedal Alien and it has two really dangerous claws.
Speaker 0: It can go really fast.
Speaker 0: It can shoot acid rockets.
Speaker 0: It's basically Frickin dangerous, but not an onos.
Speaker 0: and then the gorge is the alien that builds things, you know We've already gone pretty long.
Speaker 1: We might have to break this up into two shows.
Speaker 0: Let's just talk about what the gorge builds and we'll be done with it.
Speaker 1: All right, though.
Speaker 1: I have a lot more to say about NS.
Speaker 1: We're gonna have to do another show.
Speaker 0: No, I don't have that much more to say.
Speaker 0: I have a lot to say.
Speaker 1: all that all the remember all the stories all the interesting stories.
Speaker 0: I just want to talk about the game to get people to play it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: We pressure to spend more time talking about the fun parts of the game and less describing the individual guy.
Speaker 0: The thing is the game is so amazing that and it's so different that you sort of have to describe it So the people can understand what's.
Speaker 1: I think you could have described it in more general terms, perhaps But anyway the gorge.
Speaker 0: he builds things.
Speaker 1: I tend to play as the gorge almost exclusively.
Speaker 1: Most people don't like being the gorge But I like to be the workhorse of the team and when Scott and I play on a server together We're usually the gorge.
Speaker 1: now one.
Speaker 1: the gorge builds structures and you can build like offensive structures that hurt Marines and you can build defensive structures that give powers to the aliens and Gorges also are the ones who will build additional hives, which is kind of how you win the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so when you're a gorge, all you can really do is spit this weak-ass acid spit.
Speaker 0: That doesn't do much.
Speaker 0: You can use this healing spray that heals aliens and alien structures and also kind of hurts Marines if the team's winning really like super.
Speaker 1: Well, you got multiple hives.
Speaker 1: You have this thing called a bile bomb where you can take out marine structures.
Speaker 1: really well But aside from that you're really web.
Speaker 1: You're pretty much defenseless.
Speaker 0: Yes You're just as little.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like a pig and it walks around and it doesn't do much in terms of combat.
Speaker 0: but you can spend resources to build things and Building things is really awesome.
Speaker 1: Now the other important thing about the gorge is that there would be for whatever reason never made a jumping animation.
Speaker 1: So when the gorge jumps it just kind of floats up and floats back down.
Speaker 0: It doesn't like wiggle its legs or move its legs in any way.
Speaker 0: when it jumps It just goes straight up and straight down.
Speaker 1: and a while ago they said all right We're gonna fix this and the community went nuts and said no because the people who play gorges are kind of weird and they want the Gorge to stay exactly the way it is.
Speaker 1: I agree with them.
Speaker 0: I also agree Basically the gorge.
Speaker 1: if I talked about the aliens building silly the gorge is the silliest of the silly partly because while you're gorging You know, I've built the hive and I built defenses for the hive.
Speaker 1: now I'm just waiting for resources and otherwise, I'm just defending whatever point I'm at.
Speaker 0: I mean if I start walking around the map I'm just gonna be killed.
Speaker 0: if I spend resources to become something other than a gorge Then I have to spend more resources to become a gorge again.
Speaker 0: So a lot of time when you're a gorge you spend a good minute or two sitting around and waiting Usually with other gorges who are also waiting.
Speaker 0: So you sit there waiting next to a resource point in a defense tower or whatever and you just sort of look at each other Spit at each other jump up and down Be silly.
Speaker 1: Yep, a lot of gorges start dancing playing the spit game playing spit tag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, another thing about this game is that when you're not playing when you enter a server You're not actually put directly into the game.
Speaker 0: You're putting the ready room and the ready room is this room that you can walk around and do whatever you want in and it Doors and some of the doors say become an alien and some of the doors say become a marine and some of the doors Say join a random team.
Speaker 0: But people like to fool around in the ready room and the ready rooms usually have things in them to fool around with like one Ready room has a picnic table with some cheese on it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: One of them has a wet bar Yep, and people will fool around in this ready room.
Speaker 0: I remember one time I was in a ready room and there was a guy who was a gorge in the ready room and He was playing music through the voice chat.
Speaker 0: It was like And he was dancing his little gorge and he did that and I entered the game and then I left.
Speaker 1: I went back to the ready room and there he was dancing Still and Scott tells me this and I'm like, alright, so I left the game because we were losing anyway.
Speaker 1: at this point I was like whatever.
Speaker 0: one funny thing about NS is that there's a. you could push the f4 button in the f4 button.
Speaker 0: What it does is it sends you to the ready room if you're in the game and you don't want to play anymore Or you just kind of tired.
Speaker 0: take a break you push f4 and it sends you to the ready room and then you can enter The game again later.
Speaker 0: So usually when a team is losing or something happens everyone will say Everyone f4 f4 f4 and everyone will push f4 and go to the ready room and the game will sort of reset.
Speaker 0: That's sort of like the signal like everyone f4.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of times people will fight to the end and they'll joke like everybody f4.
Speaker 1: But sometimes if it's totally over everyone f4 is just to play another game.
Speaker 1: But that one time I have Ford and then I saw this dancing and Scott wasn't lying so I started dancing with him and More and more people.
Speaker 0: yes for people to sit around in a room jumping up and down while music plays.
Speaker 1: one time I remember why joined a game and we're and Scott was there later and we're all in the ready room and a few people have joined the game but not enough to let the game start yet and Everyone just stayed in the ready room making a pile of Marines trying to see how high they could get it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and after a while someone comes out of the game and says what the fuck are you guys doing?
Speaker 1: We're trying to start the game because there's like three people in the game and like I think you're piling up on top of That cheese.
Speaker 1: I think we were.
Speaker 1: yes, but there were like 15 people in the ready room piling up on this cheese.
Speaker 1: We're making a little marine pyramid on top of the cheese and the guys like what the fuck is wrong with you people.
Speaker 1: Ah But he didn't go back into the game.
Speaker 1: He watched for a while and eventually jumped on top of the pile.
Speaker 0: Yep That's that's.
Speaker 0: that's the way NS is it's.
Speaker 0: it's a serious really?
Speaker 0: Atmospheric RTS FPS.
Speaker 0: that is like no other game and it is is unlike many other gaming experiences but at the same time It's just a lot of silliness going on and a really great community of laughing and having a good time.
Speaker 1: The community is fantastic.
Speaker 1: Most of the people who play are awesome.
Speaker 1: There's almost no shit cocking.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I guess we could actually talk about that combat game that was added later But let's not.
Speaker 1: maybe we could do a separate special on that if we needed to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah special I think would be good.
Speaker 0: talk about combat and then we're done.
Speaker 0: basically they got.
Speaker 1: We were out of time.
Speaker 0: There's another game.
Speaker 0: We're out of time.
Speaker 0: You can play.
Speaker 1: there's a bunch of mods of NS now And they're mostly crap except for combat.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: But the game is I mean we say It's free.
Speaker 1: If you have half-life 1 it is one of the best multiplayer FPS is ever made.
Speaker 1: I might go play some right now and when I say that I mean I'm dead serious.
Speaker 1: I will defend that statement to the death.
Speaker 0: I will also.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share a like 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.