Speaker 0: It's Monday April 23rd.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights Tonight we attempt to teach you quite hastily about Linux package management.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well in the course of the last several hours.
Speaker 1: We've generated a great number of noteworthy events in our lives.
Speaker 0: Yes, not only that but over the weekend we generated quite a few noteworthy bits But we can't even talk about them because well the things that just happened are far more exciting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we could have talked about the Mets game or gaming for hope But no or we could even talk about the fire that happened near our house.
Speaker 1: Yep, a fire happened near our house, but then a fire almost happened inside our house.
Speaker 0: Well Not quite the same variety of fire.
Speaker 1: Well you see a way way back at our IT This computer that I'm using now for the show the terrible computer that is.
Speaker 0: Listen to any old episode and you'll hear about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've had issues with this computer Just because I built this computer before I went to college.
Speaker 0: I built well you replaced the most important bits.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I replaced the motherboard with almost the same motherboard in like 2001.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what the processor.
Speaker 1: I got was Oh 200 megahertz faster and otherwise mostly identical.
Speaker 0: yes the computer is Regardless old and terrible.
Speaker 1: Back at our IT It is starting to have some problems with cooling because it's a gigantic case.
Speaker 1: and I no longer need a gigantic case because gigantic cases Are no longer necessary.
Speaker 0: No one gets the gigantic cases anymore No one unless you're making it even the giant servers.
Speaker 0: everyone uses rackmount.
Speaker 0: No one uses full tower cases anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, it used to be.
Speaker 1: you'd have like seven external drives if you were a geek, but now I have one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe yeah, I mean you have the DVD CD burner.
Speaker 0: well cuz way back You need used to need to have like four or five and a quarter floppy drives.
Speaker 0: You could load all those.
Speaker 1: well You'd always have like your CD ROM or your DVD ROM and then you'd have your burner Which was separate and you'd always use both of them especially when games that needed two CDs.
Speaker 1: A lot of people had the zip drive.
Speaker 1: you had the live drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah You had that annoying hard drive cooler kit that just made a bunch of noise.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah I don't know why I forgot that.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's right because back in the day people used to tell you that if you had a 7200 rpm drive you needed to cool it or it would crash.
Speaker 0: and Well, I don't know if that's true because I have a lot of 7200 rpm drives and a lot of people have them and they aren't Cooling them.
Speaker 0: They don't seem to be crashing.
Speaker 0: However that drive that was in that cooler.
Speaker 0: It's not in that cooler anymore, but it's working pretty well.
Speaker 0: Still that 20 gig old drive is going.
Speaker 1: so in colony where we used to live at our IT Every year we didn't have air conditioning.
Speaker 1: So once it became summer and it started getting warm There would be a periodic event where Scott and I would be playing counter-strike or tribes 2 or whatever We were playing at the time
Speaker 0: was the counter-strike in those days and
Speaker 1: in the middle of the game suddenly you would start hearing That was the sound of my motherboard warning me through the PC speaker that my processor or Something on my computer was dangerously hot and was overheating.
Speaker 1: and my computer was now reaching a critical and dangerous state.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well that CPU in there is an Athlon Thunderbird.
Speaker 0: Yes, they might as well call it the Athlon Firebird.
Speaker 1: back then it was an 800 megahertz Athlon Which wasn't much better?
Speaker 1: no, no, no, but the worst part was it would happen and I'd be in the middle of a game of counter-strike and I'm not gonna quit cuz I'm doing great.
Speaker 1: I'm up in his base killing his dudes.
Speaker 0: I actually blame the pre XP Athlons for the fad of cooling CPUs Ludicrously because those actually needed it not until the XP.
Speaker 0: could you get away with normal cooling on an Athlon?
Speaker 1: I'd imagine the scenario.
Speaker 1: I'm playing a game.
Speaker 1: I'm doing well.
Speaker 1: The alarm is going off.
Speaker 1: Scott is laughing because the alarm is going off.
Speaker 1: I am playing the game.
Speaker 1: I don't want to stop playing the game, but every second I continue to play There's the chance that my computer will either burn itself out catch fire or break.
Speaker 0: Yep, because remember we talked about how Athlons will just set on fire while Intel's, you know, though they might overheat but they won't break from overheating.
Speaker 1: now Luckily after about after one summer the next summer it happened again even earlier because the computer was in further disrepair.
Speaker 1: Remember the whole time that this computer I still used to do geek nights.
Speaker 1: But anyway So I solved the problem and very simply all I did was go into the BIOS and set the danger threshold Seven degrees centigrade higher and the alarm stopped going off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's real smart, I know.
Speaker 0: let's turn off all the safety mechanisms that way if something bad happens We just won't know about it.
Speaker 0: You know, what could possibly go wrong?
Speaker 0: out of sight out of mind?
Speaker 0: Chernobyl.
Speaker 1: Possibly that was perhaps the first thing that's ever gone wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well that actually worked pretty well.
Speaker 1: The computer is fairly robust and it didn't destroy itself though.
Speaker 1: There were a few close calls.
Speaker 0: It's working right now, but I'm not betting on how long that's gonna remain true.
Speaker 1: I cleaned the computer a year and a half ago and also the video card.
Speaker 1: it died due to overheating, huh?
Speaker 1: So I replaced the video card sadly with a GeForce 4 which is like a thousand times faster than that video card was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is the GeForce 4 for like $30.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah that things made the rounds of the computers in our house.
Speaker 1: It's like the backup video card.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like oh crap.
Speaker 0: We need video cards to put in computers, but we don't actually care How you know if the computers can do 3d or not?
Speaker 0: I know let's get GeForce 4. is there 30 bucks?
Speaker 0: They work with the Nvidia driver legs that ATI card.
Speaker 1: that was dick and worth.
Speaker 0: Oh that thing was such ass.
Speaker 0: That's why we bought the GeForce.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz we after spending three days trying to make that stupid ATI work in Linux.
Speaker 0: Well, we try it worked.
Speaker 0: We couldn't get the TV out to work.
Speaker 1: We also couldn't get acceleration to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't try to get accelerate.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz that FGLRX.
Speaker 0: meanwhile We put that in video card in without doing anything.
Speaker 0: it just worked.
Speaker 0: just dang immediately There was output on the TV screen.
Speaker 0: That was correct.
Speaker 0: So yeah ATI you suck.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the computer is working pretty well.
Speaker 1: And once I replaced the burnt-out video card It didn't overheat nearly so much anymore Because the video card was actually the significant factor which as I discovered the fan on the video card Once I took it out had probably not spun in at least three years.
Speaker 1: It was you.
Speaker 1: you couldn't even spin it with your finger.
Speaker 0: You should have just used the TNT to which only can get away with passive cooling.
Speaker 1: I did for a little while and then I put this thing and I forget why.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe the TNT to you complained.
Speaker 0: It didn't work with the Nvidia driver.
Speaker 0: So well might have been.
Speaker 1: I'm I don't even remember It does.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: So now the first hot day.
Speaker 1: it was actually surprising.
Speaker 1: look 80 degrees.
Speaker 0: It was super warm today.
Speaker 0: I wore shorts and a t-shirt to work.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: Everything's awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm like super happy.
Speaker 0: The cold is finally over.
Speaker 0: knock on wood.
Speaker 1: Yep, hot damn I mean even I didn't get to take the train home Even though I'm gonna start taking the train to work.
Speaker 1: so I had to drive home, but I drove past the mountain.
Speaker 1: So I stopped and I climbed the mountain and then I learned something this mountain I go this hill for the one person who likes to argue or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's all a rock without many trees.
Speaker 0: the rocks heated up.
Speaker 0: the rocks heated up and they were hot.
Speaker 1: and on the top of the Where there wasn't any wind because there's another Ridge kind of block you burn you're like burning your feet on the rock.
Speaker 1: It was like a hundred degrees and it was like an oven cooking me.
Speaker 1: It was awesome and a little bit horrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I have this actually logitech like V. I think it's 550.
Speaker 0: It's like a little mouse that comes with a really fancy Numpad, right and I bought one a long time ago to go with my laptop.
Speaker 0: But I lost the mouse and I also lost the wireless trans EV bit and I paid like $60 for it way back in the day.
Speaker 0: now, it's only $30.
Speaker 0: So when I lost the mouse, I just said whatever and I bought a new one.
Speaker 0: So now I have two numpads.
Speaker 0: so I just leave one numpad at home one at work and I carry the mouse back and forth and The numpad is actually really cool and that it's also a calculator.
Speaker 0: It's also, you know a multimedia controller with play pause mute volume, whatever.
Speaker 0: But it's also has a thermometer in it and a clock.
Speaker 0: the thermometer work was like 82.
Speaker 1: I was like god damn God damn, so I finally get home today And my computer had been off all weekend because despite the fact that the cooling doesn't work.
Speaker 1: It's really really loud.
Speaker 1: So I had it off all weekend, which is always dangerous.
Speaker 1: whenever I turn this thing off There's like a 40% chance.
Speaker 1: It doesn't come back up when I turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you have a junky old car.
Speaker 0: if it's running it'll keep running it won't you know, unless it's weirdly junky It'll stall maybe but it's not gonna just break down while it's going.
Speaker 1: Hell a lot of old junky cars.
Speaker 1: when you turn them off they keep going for a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so but if it's off good luck getting it started again, yeah and computers are the same.
Speaker 1: That's why if you have an old server.
Speaker 1: little hint.
Speaker 1: if anyone ever gets in the IT industry you have an old server That's important and hasn't been touched in a long time.
Speaker 1: Don't even fucking think about turning that thing off until you have a backup up and running.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good.
Speaker 1: God has that bitten me in the ass enough for me to learn my lesson.
Speaker 1: Then I come home and I turn the computer on and I'm using it.
Speaker 1: Everything's fine, and I watch some dig videos and the dig videos start skipping a little bit and skip it a little bit more.
Speaker 0: and then As soon as that went off that was so priceless I was like ah shit What are we gonna do?
Speaker 0: the show we gotta go at the Mac for downstairs?
Speaker 1: Yeah, or we could use Jameson who has probably the worst sound card ever made.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a pretty bad sound card on that computer.
Speaker 0: I blame it mostly on the $20 motherboard.
Speaker 1: the first thing Scott says is why don't you just turn off the PC speaker?
Speaker 1: Which I did and then the computer crashed about 45 seconds later.
Speaker 1: Awesome, and I stick my hand under there.
Speaker 1: and of all things with the geforce 4 overheating.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe that's just where the heat pooled up because of the air channels.
Speaker 1: in the case I think so cuz it burned me it hurt.
Speaker 1: I have a little red mark on my finger.
Speaker 0: I've burned myself on quite a few CPUs, but more often.
Speaker 0: I've hurt myself on course fan.
Speaker 1: I also noticed that the CPU is a solid mass of dust.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So right
Speaker 1: now I don't think we'll be able to hear it after the post-production in the show But I currently have the fan that is normally in my window Which I use when it's warm enough for a fan But not so warm or humid that I need the AC on.
Speaker 0: so I like to keep my way.
Speaker 1: I didn't put the AC in the window yet now me either, but I'm gonna cuz when the humidity comes There's gonna be rain at some point.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, God.
Speaker 1: I gotta get a new computer before the humidity god damn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you do so.
Speaker 1: now that fan is sitting next to my case Which I open both sides up, and I don't have an air channel going through it.
Speaker 0: That's good
Speaker 1: however unlike a certain unnamed friend of mine And a little another little hint for all you kids out there if your computer is overheating It is not that bad of an idea to get a box fan or something and stick it next to your case and open up Both sides and just get air blasting through.
Speaker 1: it's a good temporary fix.
Speaker 0: It is a good temporary fix But do not make it your permanent fix.
Speaker 1: more importantly do not make it so that it is touching your case Or is close to your case because one thing that plastic spinning fans are good at generating is static electricity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that could ruin it pretty quickly right really quick.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: God.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna name names, but someone got fucked by that.
Speaker 0: Yeah You want to keep the box fan because the box fan blows so much volume of air That it doesn't need to be right up against the computer.
Speaker 0: You could put it like a foot back two feet back.
Speaker 0: It won't be close enough to shock anything And it'll still blow more air than all the fans in your computer could ever hope to blow.
Speaker 1: now luckily might remembered way back.
Speaker 1: I'm segueing here into the news that I kept saying that April 22nd is the day April 22nd.
Speaker 1: according to various leaked sources and according well according to the calendar April 22nd was yesterday Exactly, which we didn't do a show yesterday.
Speaker 1: But they kept saying oh Intel's gonna have price drops Intel's gonna have price drops.
Speaker 1: And I kept saying it and I was excited and I said if it happens.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy a computer.
Speaker 1: Well sure enough yesterday Intel announced gigantic price cuts across the core two and quad-core lines and they introduced a bunch of new chips and sure enough immediately on Newegg the E6600 which I'm convinced is the absolute sweet spot with one possible exception that Scott pointed out in terms of price for power
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: so I thought hot damn gonna buy my computer within an hour.
Speaker 1: It sold out on Newegg Looks to be in stock right now, but I just checked and I got the auto notify email saying it's back in stock.
Speaker 0: Well who knows how long that's gonna remain true?
Speaker 1: yep, so in the next three days I say three days because I still have to pick a motherboard Which is not as easy as I thought and I still have to pick all this other stuff.
Speaker 1: But I'm getting a new computer.
Speaker 1: so the timing was perfect.
Speaker 1: And I think I'm going with the core two because even though the XP's are still cheaper, and they still perform almost as well I really feel better going with Intel this time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think AMD.
Speaker 0: They just need to do something I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well the thing is the AMD chips for a similar performance draw more than twice as much power Require a lot more cooling and just feel like they're not gonna scale very well in the future.
Speaker 0: I think what it is is you know the AMD does still seem to win on the price performance ratio But it the Intel is just so fast and so it doesn't feel like there's anything wrong with it at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it feels like it's worth the price.
Speaker 0: You're paying for the all the other stuff that goes along with it.
Speaker 1: It's not like the late Pentium 3 early Pentium 4 days where a Pentium chip cost four times as much and wasn't even as fast Or like the late Pentium 4 days where a Pentium 4 cost four times as much and wasn't that much faster at all.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the other I mean while AMD based motherboards are still a lot cheaper They're not that much cheaper and actually the Intel motherboards are starting to look a lot more impressive to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it's.
Speaker 0: you know I really not even get an enforce.
Speaker 0: I know that's the thing is like I always For all for the past how many years I felt like enforce is the chipset to get and in many cases Enforce is still the chipset to get.
Speaker 0: when you start looking at the motherboards the enforce chipset really rocks with the AMD processors But it's kind of normal with the Intel processors.
Speaker 0: It's also overpriced with the Intel process.
Speaker 1: Yes, I mean the the newest series of enforces.
Speaker 1: the motherboards that supported fully are in the 200 $300 range And I've never paid that much for a motherboard, and I never will.
Speaker 0: yep, and the thing is I look I realized hey in my life I've owned two motherboard chipsets in primary desktops You know and that was an Intel which is the best one ever and an enforce 2 which was really great But not quite as good as the Intel.
Speaker 0: so I kind of don't have a problem getting an Intel chipset.
Speaker 0: now I'm like hey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll get an Intel chipset until my previous one was the best ever sure yeah.
Speaker 1: And Linux now is more pretty much just supporting 99% of what's out there.
Speaker 1: I don't have to worry about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you only really have to worry about your sound cards and your wireless cards and that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you can always buy a sound blaster.
Speaker 0: Yes, you can but yet the quad core is now what?
Speaker 0: $560 on Newegg, which is less than some of the core two extremes which freaks me the hell out now.
Speaker 1: Also, I point out that if you really want to build a relatively fast computer.
Speaker 1: Oh my god That's what John C. Dvorak looks like.
Speaker 0: you'd ever saw him before.
Speaker 1: I've never seen him before.
Speaker 0: That's what he looks like.
Speaker 1: that's not what I expected.
Speaker 0: Okay, all right anyway.
Speaker 1: I just got distracted.
Speaker 1: ed block isn't on this computer right here, right?
Speaker 1: So I saw a picture of John C. Dvorak.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: so You can get Computers with chips.
Speaker 1: the chips are faster than the computer that I'm using right now to record geek nights and to process geek nights for 30 to 40 dollars.
Speaker 1: Yep, 30.
Speaker 0: well 40 dollars rim.
Speaker 0: That's been true for like four years, but yeah Oh, even you can get faster.
Speaker 1: once it says here the 3.2 gigahertz penny MD is $84.
Speaker 0: yeah, I wouldn't get that though.
Speaker 0: right now It's pretty much if you're buying a computer, and you you know you're not trying to get like one of those $300 machines.
Speaker 0: That's like super cheap.
Speaker 0: if you're trying to get a reasonable desktop machine.
Speaker 0: They're pretty much two chips.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the one that rim was looking at.
Speaker 0: the 6600 core to duo is the three-time winner of the customer choice award at Newegg, which is like whoa.
Speaker 1: yeah it seems like most people who are buying PCs were either holding out for this chip or Decided that this chip is the perfect plateau or point of most bang for your buck and most forward compatibility.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well here's the thing right.
Speaker 0: the e6600 is a core to duo with the con row and it's 2.4 Gigahertz and right now it costs two hundred thirty five dollars, right?
Speaker 0: There's also the core to duo e6400 Which is the next step down.
Speaker 0: that is exactly the same in every way except it has two megabytes less L2 cash.
Speaker 0: so is half as much L2 cash, and it's only two.
Speaker 0: point one three gigahertz, and it's one hundred and ninety six dollars.
Speaker 0: It's like forty dollars less right?
Speaker 0: yep There's a new chip right.
Speaker 0: that just came out part of this whole thing that Intel did the 6420.
Speaker 0: It's identical to the 6400 in every way Except it has the four megs of L2 cash that the 6600 has.
Speaker 0: so it's basically the same as the 6600 Except it's like point three gigahertz slower about and $40 cheaper.
Speaker 1: now as we were just talking about it's been ourselves before the show.
Speaker 1: It used to not be that big a deal.
Speaker 1: But with the core twos every gigahertz or every megahertz faster is a lot more than a megahertz faster was with older chips.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well see here's the thing that's weird that can freak you out right.
Speaker 0: megahertz isn't an Absolute indicator of how good the CPU is compared to other CPUs.
Speaker 0: for example the CPU in my computer right now Is an AMD Athlon 1.8.
Speaker 0: Gigahertz XP Athlon XP.
Speaker 0: right my CPU at work is a core to duo.
Speaker 0: each one of the cores is 1.8.
Speaker 0: Gigahertz.
Speaker 0: even using only one core and not using the other core because I could do that It's a zillion times faster than my 1.8 Gigahertz Athlon XP.
Speaker 0: the chip is just so much more efficient that with the same clock speed it can be like five times faster.
Speaker 0: It's ludicrous now that which means that adding one more megahertz to that chip is Gonna add a lot more performance than adding one more megahertz to my Athlon XP.
Speaker 0: yep So when you're adding 0.3.
Speaker 0: Gigahertz Which is like what 300 megahertz to that super awesome efficient chip how much of a deal is that?
Speaker 0: is it a?
Speaker 0: $40 deal?
Speaker 0: that's a tough call.
Speaker 1: yep the thing is Generally like I watch and it depends on you know how much money is worth and everything.
Speaker 1: But I look at the list of chips in the series of chips I want to buy and I look at how much it costs to upgrade from one chip to the next chip Mm-hmm and the progression is usually something like
Speaker 0: one dollar like five
Speaker 1: dollars twenty dollars thirty dollars forty dollars.
Speaker 1: And there's always a point where there's a big leap like the leap between the e6600 and the next Intel chip.
Speaker 1: up is a hundred dollars is a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: But the leap between that and the chip before it is only $40.
Speaker 0: yep to go from the 6420 to the 6600 Which is just 0.3.
Speaker 0: Gigahertz for $40 to go from the 6600 to the 6700 is You're getting 0.3.
Speaker 0: Gigahertz abouts again for a hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: I'd say if you bought the 6700.
Speaker 0: You're an idiot.
Speaker 0: Yep, at least as far as I'm coming if I had a lot of money Oh, if you're just loaded out the ass with money You're still an idiot to buy the 6700 because if you're Bill Gates you can buy the core to extreme for eight hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: So there's no reason to buy the 6700.
Speaker 1: yep But there's always that point and the e6600 really feels like it's the hot hot hot point.
Speaker 1: however Don't you fuckers go out and buy them until I get mine?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I might order the chip now just to get it and pick the rest of my computer tomorrow.
Speaker 0: What if like the 6620 comes out tomorrow with eight megs of l2 cash or something?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: see I know it won't because that's the other thing.
Speaker 1: yeah You're thinking of buying a computer.
Speaker 1: You always want to buy right after the next big set of releases like as soon as they say Price drops or that's why
Speaker 0: if it's like if it's been more than a month since something came out people always say wait for the something Wait for the something and
Speaker 1: if I buy it now I get that it'll be the same price.
Speaker 1: now That'll be just before they announce the next.
Speaker 1: yeah, however I'll have that chip with that speed for that much longer, so it's a better deal.
Speaker 0: See here's the problem is.
Speaker 0: you sort of get this paradox of people saying wait wait wait.
Speaker 0: And then when something just comes out people like no it just came out don't get it.
Speaker 0: It's still.
Speaker 0: it just came out.
Speaker 0: You can't trust it.
Speaker 0: yet It's like what do you want me to do?
Speaker 0: never buy anything by the time?
Speaker 0: I can trust this.
Speaker 0: they'll tell me to wait for the next thing.
Speaker 0: yep So you've got to wait for the second generation to just come out because you can trust the second generation.
Speaker 0: You know I mean the core 2 duo didn't just come out.
Speaker 0: It's old.
Speaker 0: It's been around for a while Is the core solo?
Speaker 0: yep, this is just a better core 2 duo that just came out.
Speaker 0: So now it's safe because you can trust it, but it just came out.
Speaker 0: so it's time to buy Suppires.
Speaker 0: market people all right, so if you're paying attention at all Direct x10 is the new hotness for PC gaming.
Speaker 0: direct x10 is basically the same as direct x9 But as a bunch of extra stuff, and it's only on Vista.
Speaker 0: so when new games start using all sorts of direct x10 stuff And you want to have those games work as best they can with all the fancy graphics and the full speed and the whatnot You need Vista you need a direct x10 supporting video card and need a direct x10 game.
Speaker 0: Some people are pissed because they might have direct x10 video cards.
Speaker 0: They have no problem buying video cards.
Speaker 1: see that's.
Speaker 0: they also have no problem buying direct x10 games.
Speaker 0: They don't care.
Speaker 0: They'll buy a direct x10 game.
Speaker 0: They want to buy a direct x10 game.
Speaker 0: They don't want to buy Vista because they don't like Vista for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: they like their XP.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with it.
Speaker 0: They're sticking with it.
Speaker 1: Well my reasons very simply I don't want to buy a Dell computer because they really don't have exactly what I want for the price.
Speaker 1: I want to pay yep, but I If I pay for Vista on my own it cost a lot.
Speaker 1: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: It's like $300, but I have a legitimate XP license.
Speaker 0: I have two legitimate XP lies.
Speaker 1: well I'm using one of your licenses.
Speaker 0: well that might be the third one that I forgot.
Speaker 0: I'll have to see what the key you're using with the the program that tells you what key.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm gonna use very soon when I start planning my computer.
Speaker 0: even beep boots the windows.
Speaker 0: it does it does.
Speaker 1: I booted it two days ago to play xcom for like an hour.
Speaker 0: all right cool, but yeah, so there's these guys.
Speaker 0: This is guy Cody bro.
Speaker 0: She's.
Speaker 0: I don't know if this is real name, but that's the name on the blog.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty good name.
Speaker 1: If it's a real name.
Speaker 0: He's a 19 year old.
Speaker 0: It says 19 year old software reverse engineer living in San Diego.
Speaker 0: something something.
Speaker 0: But he says he's working on project Alki Alki project And he's gonna.
Speaker 0: well He's basically says he's got a working one right here a set of DirectX libraries that will let you do DirectX 10 in XP and he basically runs the DirectX 10 demo programs on XP.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: I haven't downloaded this and tried it.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: a lot of people are arguing like it's impossible.
Speaker 0: No this works.
Speaker 0: I downloaded it works.
Speaker 0: I downloaded it didn't work.
Speaker 0: You know it's really tough call.
Speaker 0: and whether this is all bullshit whether it's all talk whether it's the real deal No one's quite sure, but if it is the real deal That's gonna be hurtin Vista pretty bad.
Speaker 0: cuz gamers are not shy about Downloading some weird program and running it to make their games.
Speaker 1: God in the early Nvidia days how many people made just weird utilities that would set a bunch of stuff and make your video car Leet optimal even though half those things were Trojans.
Speaker 0: yep The gamers are not ashamed or afraid to just download some utility that will help them run games in some way.
Speaker 1: part of that Because a lot of PC gamers aren't afraid to just wipe out their computer.
Speaker 1: They'll reinstall windows once a year or every few months just because they know I might have something slowing me down.
Speaker 0: Gotta have a clean windows yep, so if you think I'm kidding if this works gamers everywhere are gonna Be using it and people are gonna start working on it.
Speaker 0: and Vista is not gonna sell with the gamers at least not the hardcore Gamers because they're gonna be running their direct tens on XP's if it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: It's all BS, and I predict that within five years the gamers will go to Vista because they're gamers.
Speaker 0: That's what they do.
Speaker 1: I think I'm probably going to stick with XP get a DirectX 9 video card that isn't that expensive.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm but good enough to play the games I want and then Eventually I'll probably jump to the direct sec direct extend later whenever I don't know I somehow get Vista.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've got Vista for this laptop But I'm not using it or placed it with the Ubuntu, and I probably wouldn't use Vista on a laptop You know.
Speaker 0: but if I was gaming if I'm PC gaming a lot a whole lot And I keep PC gaming a lot it might eventually be worth it, but not right away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm probably gonna replace my computer at the end of the summer Which will be a whole different scenario than buying one now.
Speaker 1: if I was you or if I were you I would hold out until Penryn.
Speaker 0: I'm holding out a long time.
Speaker 1: if you can cuz Penryn probably won't be available until next year.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll see how long I can hold out because my computer now could probably Play the team fortress twos and all those games that we're gonna want to play at the end of the year.
Speaker 0: But it's not gonna do it that way.
Speaker 1: Yeah granted you have a lot higher tolerance for low FPS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can play with like 40 FPS.
Speaker 1: I'm.
Speaker 1: I'll admit that I'm just a stupid nut but you are stupid Really bothers me if I don't get at least 60 frames per second continuously and uninterruptedly.
Speaker 0: Monitors are 75 FPS.
Speaker 0: so that's all I really need.
Speaker 1: see that's the other thing and I got a deal with this.
Speaker 1: So I'm sure I'll be able to deal with just fine because I'll have an awesome flat LCD.
Speaker 1: But I always ran my CRT.
Speaker 1: in fact right now It's running at a hundred megahertz, and I always played.
Speaker 1: all my FPS is locked at a hundred megahertz FPS.
Speaker 0: well, well, yeah hundred FPS a hundred Hertz not a hundred megahertz.
Speaker 0: Hundred million yes a hundred hurt.
Speaker 0: Are you playing there some dead heck at a hundred million FPS?
Speaker 1: I I will say right now that I misspoke.
Speaker 0: Yes, okay It's done things of the day.
Speaker 1: They're real quick here because we kind of went long in the first half.
Speaker 1: But and again, I hate to use something on dig even though there's a lot of cool stuff on dig.
Speaker 1: I assume that everyone sees everything on dig But in case you didn't and also because there's nothing interesting on the internet That wasn't already on dig in the last several days.
Speaker 0: man half of what's on dig right now is stuff I've seen before.
Speaker 0: it's like oh come on people.
Speaker 0: We have a new business.
Speaker 1: in fact I just saw again on dig on the front page of the videos that Christopher Christopher Walken fat boy slim video.
Speaker 0: I saw that in high school people high school.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: We know it's awesome.
Speaker 1: We've all seen it.
Speaker 1: Christopher Walken is one of the cute coolest human beings ever But he went to dance school.
Speaker 0: He can fucking dance.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what if the Nazis had mechs?
Speaker 1: What if the Americans also had mechs?
Speaker 1: and it was World War two?
Speaker 0: obviously sounds like every board game and video game ever.
Speaker 1: Well this CG Feels like it's a video game like I kept almost expecting Control to turn to me at several points.
Speaker 0: yeah, especially when like you saw the guys in the airplanes show up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like expected the camera to just float on into the cockpit, and then you know it would go blue, and you'd have joysticks.
Speaker 0: It'd be good stuff, but regardless.
Speaker 1: This is really cool.
Speaker 1: I gotta say the CG people are Not so much realistic in terms of how they look with their faces, but in terms of how they move are spot-on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's one thing that really kind of gets me in this in this particular Animation is that all the people moving like they've run naturally they move.
Speaker 0: naturally they move their heads.
Speaker 0: naturally They don't look real because their faces still aren't quite.
Speaker 0: You know they're obviously CG rendering faces and everything But the way that people run around looks just right.
Speaker 0: you could have fooled me from far away.
Speaker 1: Granted Emily speculated that they might have used a lot of motion capture for that which is awesome.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: yeah, it works You do it do.
Speaker 0: It's good all right.
Speaker 0: Here's an old thing of the day.
Speaker 0: cuz rim is right.
Speaker 0: There is nothing new on the internet lately.
Speaker 0: Lorem ipsum generator, it's at lip sum calm.
Speaker 0: basically when you want to you know Practice some typography.
Speaker 0: you're like you want to set some type or format a page But you don't have any text to actually format.
Speaker 0: Or you don't want to be distracted by the text.
Speaker 0: like if I do put an article about fire And I want to typeset it I might be distracted by the article itself And I won't be able to objectively typeset it in the best way possible
Speaker 1: and at the same time you can't just use a stream of gibberish because that doesn't actually look like typing and Not only would also be distracting, but it doesn't fit.
Speaker 1: It doesn't give you a sense of what the document will.
Speaker 0: any lots of things that are like any tall letters short letters Any wide letters narrow letters.
Speaker 0: you need you know short words long words lots of spaces.
Speaker 0: You know you need a lot of mixed up kind of stuff, so the solution to this problem is lorem ipsum.
Speaker 0: if you go to this website, they'll tell you all about the history of lorem ipsum and People especially web developers.
Speaker 0: and you know printers and all sorts of people Get lorem ipsum that they use in order to you know get things typeset Just right when they don't have actual content, and I want everyone to actually read the paragraph on the bottom.
Speaker 0: It's really cool what the pair the last paragraph on the page is And this page will generate lorem ipsum for you if you need some if you're making web page man.
Speaker 1: way back in the day I had a little program on windows that would generate however much lorem ipsum I needed and put it in the clipboard and I could paste it into stuff.
Speaker 1: I was working on.
Speaker 0: yep Yeah, this is a pretty good lorem ipsum generator.
Speaker 1: You know I wonder I should make a lorem ipsum device that I can just cat out of.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, no, but this lorem ipsum generator is actually the best.
Speaker 1: Why shouldn't I do that?
Speaker 1: That's really gosh.
Speaker 0: I'll just see if anyone else has done that and I'll bet they have Because it will not put any random humor, and it won't put any other random.
Speaker 0: You know garbage in there.
Speaker 0: That's not doesn't work right.
Speaker 0: It's it's pretty much the best lorem ipsum generator there is All right.
Speaker 0: today We're gonna talk to you about something very relevant Because a lot of people are switching to feisty fawn or at least trying it out like I told them to.
Speaker 0: yeah Oh, if you haven't tried it out.
Speaker 0: You should try it out.
Speaker 1: I convinced some of the old curmudgeons at my job to try it out.
Speaker 1: They're really curious about this Ubuntu thing because the last time most people in the tech industry used Linux was Red Hat 7 when it was ass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Red Hat 7 sucks.
Speaker 1: It really it was so bad and not not Power Glove bad.
Speaker 0: No, so a Lot of people are having a hard time understanding Just how you install software in Linux?
Speaker 0: because well in pretty much all Linux Distributions well each one does it differently as some of them do it the same as others, but not many.
Speaker 0: It's a totally different concept from installing software on Windows in Windows.
Speaker 0: Let's say you want to install.
Speaker 0: I don't know Skype.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 0: you go to Skype calm.
Speaker 0: you download Skype setup that exe you double click on it?
Speaker 0: You're good on a Mac.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 0: you download some program you double click on it?
Speaker 0: You drag an icon somewhere into your applications folder.
Speaker 0: It's installed.
Speaker 0: You're all good in Linux.
Speaker 0: That's not how it works.
Speaker 1: Yep, totally different.
Speaker 1: back in RIT when I was taking you know various classes on sys administration and Linux and all that One of the most common questions that other people asked in class and they asked it with such frequency Was after they installed something they got an RPM or whatever and they installed it.
Speaker 1: they'd ask so where did it install to?
Speaker 1: How do I run it?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: Where is it?
Speaker 0: Yep?
Speaker 0: That's the thing is because when you installed software on Windows and DOS and all those olden times You would always install it to somewhere.
Speaker 0: I mean in DOS days Installing software was just copying a folder from a disk onto your hard drive somewhere and you would choose where it went.
Speaker 0: And it was your decision.
Speaker 0: and nowadays everything goes into C colon program files or whatever.
Speaker 0: But it's all about where it goes in Linux.
Speaker 0: It's not about where it goes because this it's it's not one piece of software.
Speaker 0: That's all in one folder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not gonna get into it.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get into it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we did a show on this, but if we didn't we should we should.
Speaker 0: it's all little bits.
Speaker 0: Everything is a little bit and all the little bits work together.
Speaker 0: So the little bits are all over the place where the they belong and your program is actually just one thing.
Speaker 0: that then grabs a bunch of separate bits and then uses them all together to make the whole big thing go.
Speaker 0: so when you want to install software and Linux and the year is You only have one way to do it pretty much you get the source code the actual source code because remember this is open source.
Speaker 0: You know you have the source code available to you.
Speaker 0: It's not like in Windows with a closed source program where someone else takes the source code Compiles it and gives you the result to run.
Speaker 0: you get the source code yourself You compile it yourself, and then you run it yourself.
Speaker 1: Yep, now of course there were a number of problems with this.
Speaker 1: in one a lot of people didn't really know how to compile things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well anyone who's using Linux in those days that true pile things, but even that most people still don't say alright I'm gonna compile foo, but what if foo needs all this other stuff that it doesn't come with?
Speaker 1: well I gotta go get all that and compile it too.
Speaker 0: You got to go out.
Speaker 0: you got to get all these different little bits compile them each individually.
Speaker 0: the other part is You know when you have a compute a program And you always the first thing you do when you have a new program is you go to the settings and you check all the?
Speaker 0: Settings that you want your preferences.
Speaker 0: because what you like when you compile a program their Preferences that you can set at compile time before you install the program before it's running you can decide things like hey Do I want this?
Speaker 0: Program to support mp3?
Speaker 0: I should compile it with mp3 support.
Speaker 0: if I don't it won't be able to support mp3 stuff like that and You had to give a whole bunch of configuration options when you compiled something And it's not easy.
Speaker 0: it is still this way where everyone had to compile all their software by hand.
Speaker 0: it would be a nightmare.
Speaker 0: No one could do it.
Speaker 0: only nerdy people who knew how to use compilers could use Linux.
Speaker 1: so enter binaries.
Speaker 0: yes Basically people said hey, this is too damn hard.
Speaker 0: Let's compile the software and give the people that compiled stuff.
Speaker 1: so what they do is that on you go to any website for someone who has an open source project they give you the source code and nicely they would make various binaries of Various versions that you could just download and install without having to compile them.
Speaker 0: yep And they had a lot of different systems for how these binaries would work.
Speaker 0: like some systems someone would give you a special thing They made and you would run it And it would put the binary somewhere like acrobat reader still does it that way.
Speaker 0: if you want to install that on Linux you know And Skype does it that way I think.
Speaker 0: but they invented these systems of having binary app Software installation and the two major systems that you have to care about our RPM and DEB Deb.
Speaker 0: RPM is the Red Hat package management and Deb is obviously what Debian uses and since Ubuntu is based on Debian it uses Deb's also.
Speaker 0: Basically the way it works is you download an RPM or a Deb and you have a little program already Installed that came with your distribution.
Speaker 0: if you're you know using an RPM distribution it probably comes with the RPM program.
Speaker 0: Using Ubuntu or Debian.
Speaker 0: it comes with the Deb program, and you say hey install that RPM Hey install that Deb and your computer tries if it can it can.
Speaker 0: if it can't it can't.
Speaker 1: Now again we could talk about how they work and how like what's actually in one of these things and how it knows where to Put things.
Speaker 1: and it's actually a little bit more complex than you'd expect.
Speaker 1: but again It's not something the average user needs to know or care about.
Speaker 0: yeah Basically what it does is you know you download like the Deb for Firefox And it says oh I need this and this and this all other things and it tries to get them.
Speaker 0: and yeah It's that's how all the little bits come together is because these programs know by looking at one package whatever packages They need and they can get all the dependencies and things.
Speaker 0: and it's sometimes causes problems when distributions suck.
Speaker 0: But when distributions work right it's awesome.
Speaker 1: now back then there was still the problem of all right I want to install foo.
Speaker 1: I go get the binary for foo.
Speaker 1: I run it.
Speaker 1: Oh, it says you need a bar vaz and bat in an addition in order to install foo.
Speaker 0: So you go and try to find the RPMs or the deb's for Bar baz and bat and maybe you can find them.
Speaker 1: Maybe you can't and it usually involved going to semi shady websites looking for RPM, and then you get like the wrong version.
Speaker 0: It's like 0.01.
Speaker 0: You needed 0.02 And it doesn't work with that version and then that in turn needs other things that are different versions And the whole thing falls apart.
Speaker 0: It's terrible.
Speaker 1: enter Package management.
Speaker 0: yes, what eventually happened is the distributions of Linux.
Speaker 0: You know people who take because Linux is just a kernel.
Speaker 0: That's all it is, but people would take all we're gonna.
Speaker 1: We're gonna.
Speaker 1: we should talk about the whole.
Speaker 0: how technically there's the GNU now We're not talking about that, but people who make a Linux distribution is basically some.
Speaker 0: It's someone who goes out and they get a whole bunch of bits because you can choose different bits.
Speaker 0: You know it's like Legos.
Speaker 0: you can choose to use these Legos of those ones the black or the gray or the red.
Speaker 1: so I take like the Linux Kernel and then I grab I don't know this package manager and this this and this thing.
Speaker 0: it's like I take Linux kernel Then I'll take Firefox, and I'll take the X terminal and I'll take the barrel thing.
Speaker 0: You know you take the pieces that are necessary And you put them together and you make decisions about which pieces you're gonna use and which ones you're not gonna use.
Speaker 1: if you build Linux from scratch you just do that for yourself.
Speaker 1: You've basically you made your own distribution just for you.
Speaker 0: Yep You choose which pieces you want in which places you know and in The end you come up with enough pieces to make a whole system that has a GUI or maybe your distribution doesn't even have A GUI who knows?
Speaker 0: you come up with enough pieces to make a computer that someone can use and that's what a distribution is.
Speaker 0: The distributions like Red Hat and Ubuntu and Debian and all those people Gentoo.
Speaker 0: They decided hey this really sucks.
Speaker 0: No one can install software.
Speaker 0: Let's make Repositories.
Speaker 0: what the repositories are is there's a server somewhere or a bunch of servers where they store?
Speaker 0: all the debs or all the RPMs or all the whatever and your computer Connects to the repository and knows what software is in there.
Speaker 0: so when you want to install say Firefox you say hey Ubuntu apt-get install Firefox and Ubuntu goes to the repository.
Speaker 0: That's managed by the Ubuntu people.
Speaker 0: It's all set up.
Speaker 0: everything you need is in there because they're constantly.
Speaker 1: Yep a lot of big distributions will have a team of people who work with them or for
Speaker 0: a lot of people and
Speaker 1: all those people will do is Pick applications or work together to decide which applications they care about and whenever there are new versions They'll go get the source make a binary that they know works on a standard Version of their distribution and put it in the repository Guaranteeing that it will work.
Speaker 0: And they don't put it in the Depository that you can get to until it's fully tested and they know it's gonna work no matter what at least most of the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah and granted like you can get like on Gentoo even though it's source based is still the same kind of thing where There are different kind.
Speaker 1: like you can get the normal stuff that's tested But you can change some bits and then you get access to the repositories that have things that are Mostly tested and should work but might not.
Speaker 0: yeah, basically It's a big server full of software and the software there because it's managed by these people who are constantly You know checking for new versions and patching security fixes and everything like that.
Speaker 0: It's like your one-stop shop You know, you need something new.
Speaker 0: they got it.
Speaker 0: You need an update for something you already got.
Speaker 0: it'll tell you because it checks the repository for when those updates.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this stuff you've got now and it's really cool.
Speaker 1: You can also usually there's various managers You can use with the repositories actually search through them and find programs.
Speaker 1: say I need I don't know a text editor.
Speaker 1: I can search through for text editors find a list of 15 of them that are available through my Distribution.
Speaker 1: download the ones I like delete the ones I don't like.
Speaker 0: yeah It's it's.
Speaker 0: instead of hunting around the web looking for stuff possibly getting something shade possibly getting something shady the Disney Repositories offer a place to get something that's not shady guaranteed.
Speaker 0: as long as you don't use some weird repository as long as you only use the ones they tell you to you're guaranteed to Get something that'll work and you can.
Speaker 0: it's really easy to find software without roaming around wondering what's available And all that garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the whole Windows paradigm of download a program install it to a directory is Really completely obsolete unless you're still using Windows.
Speaker 0: and this this is why Linux doesn't have spyware.
Speaker 0: I mean like there's.
Speaker 0: no it's not difficult to make spyware for Linux.
Speaker 0: I can make a spyware program But no one's gonna go to your website and download your exe file and run it just because you fooled them with a tricky website.
Speaker 0: People only get their software from one place, you know, if they're using Ubuntu they get it from the Ubuntu repositories.
Speaker 1: I think it also helps that security in Linux is just generally more that helps.
Speaker 1: Yes, but and there's no Internet Explorer.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's true.
Speaker 0: However, that this is really like.
Speaker 0: one of the big reasons that you don't get shady software on Linux is no one will put shady software in their repository.
Speaker 0: and The thing is if you want software sometimes you want software that's not in your repository.
Speaker 0: Like you'll be using Red Hat and you'll want say I don't know the new version of Firefox.
Speaker 1: And you say the new version of Firefox only comes out in a deb for some reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or maybe the new version of Firefox?
Speaker 0: the people who manage that repository.
Speaker 0: They didn't put the new version of Firefox in there yet They're not gonna put it in there for another month or like.
Speaker 1: here's something I ran into with Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: There was a program I used to set some logitech mouse parameters and it was old and barely maintained.
Speaker 1: Yep, it was not in any Ubuntu repository.
Speaker 1: In fact, all I have is one old busted rpm and the website's gone and everything.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, you can choose to go out and try to find it yourself.
Speaker 0: You can go get the deb or the rpm on your own on the web and do it that the old way.
Speaker 1: Yep, I can try and find the source and compile it.
Speaker 0: Yep, but those are difficult.
Speaker 0: What you can do is you can find a third-party repository for a lot of things out there.
Speaker 0: There's someone who is making packages and they make their own repository of stuff.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's a guy out there who has a special Ubuntu Firefox repository and you can add his repository To your Ubuntu install and now when your Ubuntu is looking for Firefox It'll get it there if he has the most up-to-date version.
Speaker 0: and that's how you can get all their stuff is not by going out Onto the internet and finding some package of a newer version because that'll only work once.
Speaker 0: You want to go out and find someone who's managing a repository and you add their repository to your computer And now you can get all the software that they're offering in addition to the software that you already had being offered to you.
Speaker 1: now Handy-dandy little Ubuntu tip.
Speaker 1: you want to go into your repository stuff and add universe and multiverse.
Speaker 0: Yes, you see in Ubuntu by default.
Speaker 0: They only give you the standard Ubuntu repositories.
Speaker 0: there are other semi-official mostly official Ubuntu repositories called multiverse and universe that offer you all the software you really want.
Speaker 0: if you add those Because they're they're run by Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: They're just not as official as the real ones.
Speaker 0: That's how you're gonna get all the cool software.
Speaker 0: once you've got those You're basically never gonna need to go and get software anywhere else.
Speaker 0: almost never like 99% of the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the only time I've had to is when I needed a specific version of something like Wesnoth for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Wesnoth is pretty easy to install.
Speaker 0: I mean, yes Plus if you can find a deb nine times out of ten you just double click on the deb and it will install and work.
Speaker 0: But you know that only installs once.
Speaker 0: like I install bit torrent from a deb I go to bit torrent comm to get the official bit torrent client.
Speaker 0: I get the deb.
Speaker 0: I double-click it works.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not a big deal, you know one package.
Speaker 0: I install the old-fashioned way.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna kill me Yep, but for Ubuntu generally just go to system Administration and then there should be something that says software sources.
Speaker 0: That is where you can change this Yep, you can also get to there through the synaptic package manager Which is your graphical user interface to interact with the repositories and the software installation methods.
Speaker 1: Yes, in general you should use synaptic instead of ad remove programs, which is also there.
Speaker 0: add remove programs is actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: I recommend that when you first install Ubuntu for the first time go to add remove programs and go through the whole thing once.
Speaker 0: Andrew never use it again because that's pretty much it shows you this.
Speaker 0: it gives you a different interface on the software installation.
Speaker 0: It's much better for newbies, but isn't really helpful in the long run.
Speaker 1: But it also it has most of the things that normal users will need right away.
Speaker 0: yep, so your first time through you can go in there and it's real easy to understand and you'll be able to install all the Software that you need to get going.
Speaker 0: but from then on out just use the synaptic package manager for when you need.
Speaker 0: You know real software beyond that.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I hope that was a good explanation.
Speaker 0: We had to hurry it because we're running out of time.
Speaker 1: Yep Also, I've been watching my computer to make sure it doesn't overheat and I think the sound cards having some troubles.
Speaker 1: So we'll see how this sounds.
Speaker 0: Oh great.
Speaker 0: Fantastic.
Speaker 1: Not bad trouble, but I think it's slowly.
Speaker 1: slowly.
Speaker 0: We're gonna use the Mac tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'm gonna have a computer by next week.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna try to hold out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, we'll see.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I hope you understand Linux package management.
Speaker 0: We barely went into detail on it.
Speaker 0: But if you have any questions, the forums are awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah granted half the time you ask a question and Scott just says Google it.
Speaker 0: But that's true as Google.
Speaker 0: before you ask me cuz nine times out of ten Google has the answer first.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.