Speaker 1: It's Thursday November 15th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm really tired.
Speaker 1: Me too, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, Telogical Fallacies Teh?
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well this weekend ought to be interesting.
Speaker 0: We're uh for the first time in a long time We're going to some other geek house instead of having people at our geek house.
Speaker 1: I try to avoid doing that as much as possible because it usually means I'm gonna have to sleep on the floor and The days of sleeping on the floor are done for me.
Speaker 1: It's bad or nothing.
Speaker 0: See, but the thing is in return for sleeping on The floor what we get is a weekend full of geekery with all our friends and all the Visigoths.
Speaker 0: No mess to clean up.
Speaker 0: No responsibilities.
Speaker 0: No nothing.
Speaker 1: But I have to drive for hours.
Speaker 0: No you don't.
Speaker 0: You have to sit in a car playing worms with me while Alex drives Maybe.
Speaker 0: Or you can drive and me and Alex can play worms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, either way It's I got to sit in a car and then like all my all the stuff I want to do in this house.
Speaker 1: I can't do.
Speaker 0: I can't even sit in my chair.
Speaker 0: See, that's the point.
Speaker 0: We get away.
Speaker 0: So bring the chair with you.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Let someone vomit on it.
Speaker 0: That's kind of the point though.
Speaker 0: by getting out of the house like that like when I'm here I always think well, I could work on all that geek night stuff I've been shit talking about for the last two years.
Speaker 0: or I could do this or I could do that.
Speaker 0: if I had someone else's House.
Speaker 0: I wake up and not only do I have zero responsibility to anyone in the world Not only can I do make whatever mess I want do whatever I want There's no chance.
Speaker 0: I'll get worked on so I don't even think about it.
Speaker 1: See my problem is I take it a step further.
Speaker 1: when I wake up in someone else's house I go.
Speaker 1: why the fuck did I come here?
Speaker 1: I could have stayed home and worked on my stuff.
Speaker 0: But this will be fun also because uh Let's just say the place where you're going and the event that is happening is one of those Kind of not what you'd expect us to go to.
Speaker 0: it's a. I think Bach and Elle might be the word I would use.
Speaker 1: I don't know how much of a bucket L will be.
Speaker 0: well if tails from the previous event That was much like this are not exactly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz neither Scott I have also.
Speaker 1: I have heard tale though that the the worst offenders are not are not gonna be there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'll be tough to say it's a tough call.
Speaker 1: You'll hear more next week.
Speaker 0: Yes, but I can guarantee that if anyone's gonna be dry heaving it's not gonna be us.
Speaker 1: No, I will definitely not be the any heaving.
Speaker 1: So speaking of dry heaves This is nothing to do with dry heaves.
Speaker 0: Yes, it does.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right, you think I'd all right.
Speaker 1: So you work dry heaves into whatever.
Speaker 1: your news is absinthe.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's kind of worries that I'm not gonna get into all the details here because you probably don't care.
Speaker 0: absinthe is a very alcoholic liquor that Tastes pretty good.
Speaker 0: If you like anis Anis you mean anus?
Speaker 0: No, I mean anis You know licorice.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna taste like ass I'm sure you would know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you can't tell guys we're tired tonight and we had a lot of stuff to do I was falling asleep on the train and while reading manga so that tells you something.
Speaker 0: That's the worst.
Speaker 1: when you're reading a book or something and then you suddenly realize because I was reading frickin massive Mooney Shiro's crazy nutjob footnotes in the bottom of ghost in the shell one and a half in the tiny text and I Was falling.
Speaker 1: I just got trapped.
Speaker 1: I'm like, I'm gonna read this one footnote and then go and then doze off.
Speaker 1: I couldn't finish the footnote like my eyes would not stay.
Speaker 0: it was worse.
Speaker 0: I had that thing where you read and read and read and then you realize like I don't remember what I just read.
Speaker 0: Yeah Start backtracking back and realize that I flipped like 15 pages and didn't remember our goddamn thing.
Speaker 1: I hate that when you're reading read and read but your brain like sort of doesn't actually process the words.
Speaker 1: You just sort of process them only with the eyeballs.
Speaker 0: I think it tricks you.
Speaker 0: I think the brain is like, you know what?
Speaker 0: He's too tired to notice.
Speaker 1: It's like you know I'm totally gonna just have.
Speaker 1: it's like you need two parts of your brain to read.
Speaker 1: you need the part that Processes the words and you need the part that actually turns the words like imagination and imagery.
Speaker 1: and it's like you can use.
Speaker 1: you can do one without the other and when you do that you end up Flipping a lot of pages in the book without actually getting.
Speaker 0: I think it's simpler to go back.
Speaker 0: brain says he won't know He's not paying attention.
Speaker 1: I ain't doing work and then it figures itself out.
Speaker 1: Well, I caught you brain.
Speaker 0: Oh brain I got you.
Speaker 1: the brain catches itself.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it looks like absinthe is now less illegal in the United States Which is good news for one really important reason All the reasons that the government has given over the years to make absinthe illegal are completely made up bullshit.
Speaker 0: Absinthe is just a really alcoholic beverage that tastes pretty good.
Speaker 0: If you like that licorice.
Speaker 0: I mean, I like Sambuca a lot.
Speaker 0: of course a lot of people make the mistake of drinking absinthe as it is without diluting it in water, but people drink laudanum also, I Hear laudanum tastes terrible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well people drink it.
Speaker 0: Also who drinks laudanum.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of people.
Speaker 0: Oh You know one person who's not even real aka captain laudanum.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: But now captain laudanum it drinks enough laudanum for ten men.
Speaker 0: This is a step in the right direction because the government always said yeah Absinthe we're banning it because it makes people crazy and it's hallucinogen and it's a drug and it's got through Joan in it Causes through Joan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was totally made up.
Speaker 0: absinthe has no effects other than just being alcoholic.
Speaker 1: Really is worth alcoholic.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it's not even close to Everclear.
Speaker 1: Is it more than Vodak?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: It's like double Vodak.
Speaker 0: It's usually about 120 proof so it's double Vodak.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Alright, so if you just well not quite double.
Speaker 1: So if you just use half as much absinthe as you normally use Vodak, you'll be alright.
Speaker 0: Well, you're supposed to drink absinthe diluted in water possibly with sugar.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I like this.
Speaker 0: it's a step in the right direction.
Speaker 0: It means that someone has convinced the government a little bit to go back on an absolutely stupid and meaningless decision They made to arbitrarily ban something.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to ban it or maybe there was a time limit on the old thing And it ran out.
Speaker 0: I know it had more to do with the fact that Manufacturers and foreign countries that wanted to really start selling it out here and people who realize they can make money selling absinthe on the mystique that it gained when Moulin Rouge came out and a bunch of kids went.
Speaker 0: oh, I want to get me some of that.
Speaker 0: Great cuz absinthe.
Speaker 0: there's all this mystique around it and it's just a really alcoholic licorice drink my prediction vomiting.
Speaker 0: I imagine.
Speaker 0: all the people who are actually gonna drink it are gonna drink it because they want to like they want to be one of those people who drinks absinthe and I think they'll be disavowed of that obsession rather quickly when they taste it.
Speaker 1: It is shall we say it takes a special kind of person to drink.
Speaker 0: it is an acquired taste acquired.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is how I would put it.
Speaker 0: It is it is not for one with a delicate palate.
Speaker 1: All right, so There's a if you know the website in gadget and gadget comm.
Speaker 1: it's the pretty much the tech blog period.
Speaker 1: They have every story about tech that you care about and well There's run by two people mostly with this guy named Ryan block But also this other guy named Peter Rojas, right and these guys they're both pretty Outspoken against DRM and stuff.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much on the side of the consumers in all things.
Speaker 1: They're sort of like think of them as the gave in taiko of the technology world You know gave in taiko or the video games.
Speaker 1: Ryan block and Peter Rojas are the gadgets, right?
Speaker 1: The Peter Rojas guy he.
Speaker 1: today they announced that he is starting a record label.
Speaker 1: the record label will be called record blue RCRD space LBL all caps and That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and this record label will distribute all digital all free Streaming or download no DRM music Aha, and they already have artists such as most F block party and the stills.
Speaker 0: I'll admit that I've never heard of any of them.
Speaker 1: I Think I've heard of most F but I don't think I've ever heard any of most devs.
Speaker 1: music.
Speaker 1: I've never heard of block party or the stills.
Speaker 0: It's a start.
Speaker 1: They've also partnered with some other labels like warp and dimmock, which is a pretty dumb name for record.
Speaker 1: So I guess whatever music whatever artists they have they're gonna partner up with.
Speaker 1: and I like I don't know how well this is Gonna go cuz I don't know how he's gonna make money But I I hope it works out.
Speaker 1: Well, and I think if they play the cards, right this could be like the record label.
Speaker 1: you know as the name implies and If they get some, you know good music on there.
Speaker 1: Well, I will be listening because I couldn't hurt.
Speaker 1: right free music That's how it's supposed to be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh Maybe this I mean I'd say oh this might be the start of the revolution and everything is gonna change when it comes to audio distribution.
Speaker 0: for real.
Speaker 0: but people have tried Similar things not not quite to this extent but there have been a lot of little labels that were like Yeah, we're gonna buck the trend and go with what the people want.
Speaker 1: Yeah to me This is this is sort of like the first.
Speaker 1: well, it's not the first but it's it's the first real Try like someone's actually gonna give it a full-on go and we're gonna see what happens.
Speaker 1: So whether it succeeds or fails is not as important as whether we learn what we learn from this.
Speaker 1: plus You know, it's someone awesome doing it.
Speaker 1: So so best of luck to them I say and free music for me Even if it's cracking, huh?
Speaker 0: At any rate if you can't tell we're kind of tired.
Speaker 0: So I think I'll just jump right into things of the day.
Speaker 1: I'm already sleeping.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day should be sleep.
Speaker 1: It is fun and nice and everybody should take extra sleep.
Speaker 0: So you remember the 90s?
Speaker 0: remember back in the 90s?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were no cell phones.
Speaker 1: They were just expensive and large.
Speaker 1: well, yeah, usually they were car phones and not cell phone.
Speaker 0: Well, there weren't cell phones like we have now.
Speaker 0: No, not even close.
Speaker 0: I mean I had one.
Speaker 0: it was a big break.
Speaker 0: It was totally useless.
Speaker 0: You could talk for 45 minutes before the battery died I know or you could put it in standby for four hours.
Speaker 1: I know some people had car phones that were as big as regular phone.
Speaker 0: car phones were the late 80s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were by 1993 or four.
Speaker 0: there were some cell phones But not the Verizon.
Speaker 0: I remember Scott and I didn't have cell phones until we were already in college.
Speaker 1: I had a cell phone In the year 2000.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was when we went to college.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I remember it.
Speaker 0: didn't?
Speaker 0: you got it while we were in college.
Speaker 1: Did I?
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz I remember.
Speaker 0: we went to get one and then you found out that you had to put a big deposit down Because your credit history wasn't long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right, you were like well screw this and he had your mom do it.
Speaker 1: That's right Cuz.
Speaker 1: my dad got rid of his Motorola StarTech Which is still one of the best cell phones ever and then I had to go try to get it activated at the Verizon At the mall.
Speaker 0: In fact, we went to some of our first anime cons Without cell phones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 1: We had to get those walkie-talkies from Best Buy which suck but which became awesome because only in one instance because you see Somewhere like Otacon whenever.
Speaker 0: well back then which whenever amount?
Speaker 0: is it twice?
Speaker 1: I think we should get around to the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I Guess I'll save the.
Speaker 0: it's a me a Mario story for another day before.
Speaker 0: a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I'll bet half our listeners never heard it.
Speaker 1: Well, they can hear it again later.
Speaker 1: We'll keep them enticed by something at least It's a me a Mario Right.
Speaker 0: So anyway Whatever my thing of the day is a video College Humor.
Speaker 0: What if that show 24 which I think is kind of stupid was set in 1994?
Speaker 1: I I don't know much about the show 24 other than it's pretty popular and I've never seen it.
Speaker 1: I guess it's a lot like this video.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: That's a guess.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 1: I've seen two episodes one of them assumption to make.
Speaker 0: I think one of them was just really Stupid and the other one really kind of glorified Overreaching anti-terrorism measures.
Speaker 0: and what was it?
Speaker 1: well Anyway, the the video we just watch is really funny because it's like you see these people back with like, you know The early AOL dial-up modem technology like running into all these problems because of it.
Speaker 1: and it's sort of like wow That was just like not even 10 years ago.
Speaker 0: Think about this nowadays.
Speaker 0: say I'm gonna meet you and Emily in the city.
Speaker 0: We're gonna get dinner.
Speaker 0: All right Say I don't show up at the restaurant.
Speaker 0: You call my cell phone rim.
Speaker 0: Where are you?
Speaker 0: Hey, the six train didn't come.
Speaker 0: I'm walking or yeah I'm in book off because I forgot to go to the restaurant.
Speaker 0: now back then it was Shit, where's rim?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: What do we do?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: How do we find him?
Speaker 0: There's no way to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was no way.
Speaker 0: I guess I could find a payphone.
Speaker 0: Call the restaurant.
Speaker 0: if I knew the number which of course I don't I could try to look it up in the phone book.
Speaker 0: But where am I gonna find a phone book?
Speaker 0: Even back then when people needed them any phone book tied to a phone booth was broken and full of penises
Speaker 1: Missing pages because punk high school kids tore them out for their scavenger hunts like I did
Speaker 0: or they tore them out when they needed a number to remember or
Speaker 1: toilet paper For the gas station.
Speaker 0: gas station has always had toilet paper as far as I was But yet self Station and on the roll of toilet paper would be the phone book.
Speaker 0: I'm sure some old fogies are gonna think us punk kids don't know how hard it was But you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm glad I don't know how hard it was.
Speaker 0: without my cell phone My life would be largely miserable and difficult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you're old fogies complaining about how punk kids got it easy and you had it hard in your day Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: You have only yourself to blame Easy what?
Speaker 0: wait, but you know, you could take that another way.
Speaker 0: You have yourself to blame for not inventing cell phones and then making them widely distributed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, take that grandpa.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like they have themselves to blame for not inventing the good stuff sooner And they also have themselves to blame for inventing the stuff and then letting us have it without having to invent it.
Speaker 0: But what about the old the people who didn't invent it and didn't want it and now it's just here tough.
Speaker 0: Okay Right.
Speaker 1: So what are you there fall for not preventing the invention of it?
Speaker 1: Alright, so, you know those people.
Speaker 1: they play the miniatures games with the rulers, you know Like I like those games that people talk that someone asked us about I guess.
Speaker 1: But anyway, like Warhammer and stuff like that, you know people always make terrains for those games like they make hills and there's a whole hobby of just making like maps and like trees and Stuff like that and buildings.
Speaker 0: It's very much related to that same thing about railroads.
Speaker 0: make a little model railroad with the terrain all around.
Speaker 0: They use a lot of the same techniques, right?
Speaker 1: Well, here are some pictures of some guys who made a sort of post apocalyptic city thing for their miniatures game.
Speaker 1: and well I'm not gonna say anything else.
Speaker 1: You're probably like whatever from my description, but if you look at this I think you will change your mind and go what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Oh my god, those guys.
Speaker 1: They're the crazy.
Speaker 1: You should look at this.
Speaker 1: That's what else can I say?
Speaker 1: Especially if you have an interest in those kind of games you this.
Speaker 1: well This is like probably the best terrain maybe in the whole world that I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Someone else are probably like now here's the best terrain and post some images, but this is the best I've seen right, so Since as you can tell we're dragging we're just getting right into it.
Speaker 0: We've brought them up a lot.
Speaker 0: We've talked about them on the show obliquely many times, but we've never really gone through the logical fallacies.
Speaker 0: I mean we did our Somewhat epic show on the burden of proof and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: We talked about how to speak in public.
Speaker 0: We've talked briefly about how to argue but we're still gonna do a whole show on How to argue for truth and then a separate show on how to argue to win because they are very different Techniques very different.
Speaker 1: mostly I am concerned with the arguing for truth and Graham is concerned with the arguing for winning.
Speaker 1: see Scott here thinks he's a comedian but a Good example of the arguing to win versus my arguing for truth.
Speaker 0: It all comes down to the eternal battle between Calicles and Sophocles where Sophocles said There is truth and we must find it and Calicles said truth is whatever.
Speaker 0: I convinced all the stupid people around me And it's like Calicles is the bad guy and that D1.
Speaker 1: yeah bad guys win the car old.
Speaker 1: shitty world bad guys win.
Speaker 1: You know what shitty world bad guys win me is the truth.
Speaker 1: That's how.
Speaker 1: that's the truth.
Speaker 0: That might be the mean world fallacy.
Speaker 1: It could be mean world fallacy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, right now first We got to talk about I think arguments in general.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna say one thing we're going to talk about a lot of this very generally because there's actually a whole field of study in terms of Argumentation and it involves a lot of Latin words.
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 0: Well more than that it involves a lot of very precise Terminology and it would take a whole show just to explain the bounds before we can even get into the good stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and most of that terminology we don't know even though we know the the thinking behind it.
Speaker 0: but in the end all Argumentation which is the fancy way of saying yelling at each other.
Speaker 0: Yep comes down.
Speaker 1: Oh, by the way This is a show you should pay attention to because it will help you on the Internet's where argumentation is common.
Speaker 0: And also once again You should go back and listen to our episode on the burden of proof because that is also critical very critical.
Speaker 0: But all argumentation comes down to either arguing to convince or Arguing for collective truth.
Speaker 0: and aside from that.
Speaker 0: Are you inductively argue me?
Speaker 0: argumenting arguing or are you deductively argumenting argumenting Dating.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Are you deducting or inducting?
Speaker 1: deducting is like Sherlock Holmes?
Speaker 0: Well, it's more like very simply All snakes are green.
Speaker 0: Let's say that that is my premise.
Speaker 0: I am assuming that all snakes are green.
Speaker 0: I see a snake.
Speaker 0: The snake therefore is green or there's a. I know that all snakes are green.
Speaker 0: There's a snake in that box.
Speaker 0: I know that that snake is green.
Speaker 0: now in deductive arguments If you accept the premise and the logic follows true, then you must accept the conclusion.
Speaker 0: Case closed end of that it is.
Speaker 0: it is a very precise and exact logic.
Speaker 0: this therefore this it's if this and This then that that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: All A's are blue.
Speaker 1: Here's an A that A is blue.
Speaker 1: Because if you believe that all A's are blue the first thing then you have to accept the second thing.
Speaker 1: You can't get around it.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, the first thing was wrong.
Speaker 1: Go back to square one.
Speaker 0: Now this kind of argumentation is Difficult in one way because you have to be extremely precise in what you say and very careful about what you accept.
Speaker 0: But at the same time it's very easy because the conclusions are obvious absolutely obvious and undeniable.
Speaker 0: and furthermore a logical fallacy in regards to a deductive argument is Perfect.
Speaker 0: a logical fallacy in that case means that your argument is patently wrong Logically untrue.
Speaker 0: it is stupid.
Speaker 0: You're an idiot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're making a deductive argument and you may you know submit a statement that is logically fallacious It is wrong.
Speaker 1: automatically just period up your girl up wrong and sorry go back to start wrong answer.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter what you said it was wrong.
Speaker 1: It was logical fallacy.
Speaker 1: game over.
Speaker 0: For example if I said all males are Human which is obviously not true, but let's say we accept that all male beings that could ever exist are human.
Speaker 1: Oh, here's a male dolphin.
Speaker 0: Ah All right, forget that you get the idea.
Speaker 0: yeah All right But that's not what we're gonna talk about so much because that is no one ever argues deductively in the real world.
Speaker 0: They do in debate class debate class in high school debate club and that they kind of yeah like quiz ball is not debate.
Speaker 0: It's literally.
Speaker 0: how fast can you talk and how fast can you flip through index cards and read things?
Speaker 0: Someone else already wrote on.
Speaker 1: and how much did you research in advance?
Speaker 0: You don't do any research.
Speaker 0: It's already done for you.
Speaker 0: If you're in the not I don't want to say professional but in like the people who go in like the national tournaments It's all already done.
Speaker 0: You literally just flip through note cards Like they'll make an argument and you boil it down to.
Speaker 0: did they say Clinton good or Clinton bad?
Speaker 0: And if they said Clinton good you flip through to your Clinton folder until you find the Clinton good argument And you don't care what it is.
Speaker 0: You just read what's on that note card.
Speaker 0: No ignore what you're actually saying.
Speaker 0: you just read the note card and assume that that refuted whatever they said.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's so stupid, but I digress.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure some debate club fans out there.
Speaker 1: good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bring it You know what?
Speaker 0: I was debate.
Speaker 0: I was varsity debate for like three years.
Speaker 0: All right, it is exactly like that All right.
Speaker 1: Well rim you'll be defending that then I'm sure I can.
Speaker 0: I think I can handle that.
Speaker 1: You'll be arguing about arguing.
Speaker 0: I always argued the affirmative.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So do you want to talk about the inductive arguments?
Speaker 0: inductive reasoning is pretty much what you do in your daily life.
Speaker 0: It's not so much.
Speaker 0: There's a lot more kind of language involved or more reference.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to be very generic here.
Speaker 0: I don't want to bog you down with terms that you probably won't understand or they just won't be Interesting or that will be wrong about.
Speaker 1: I get yelled at.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if you really want to know the details Just go find an article that describes the differences between deductive and inductive scientific method.
Speaker 0: That'll probably explain it pretty succinctly.
Speaker 0: Yep, but even in an inductive argument, you can still make a logical fallacy.
Speaker 0: The only difference is that a logical fallacy in those cases does not necessarily Always not follow.
Speaker 0: you might make a logical fallacy, but the truth at the end of the fallacy might be true.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the difference is if your argument consists of nothing but logical fallacies, then you don't actually have an argument.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the best you could try to hope for is some sort of preponderance of evidence argument Mm-hmm in practical use of everydayness, which is what you care about the most, you know on the internet or with friends.
Speaker 1: Logical fallacies are basically a way to help you win arguments against people.
Speaker 1: if you know the logical fallacies You know, which there there are a set number of them.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean there are a lot that people mention but there's a lot of classical ones that are clearly fallacy.
Speaker 1: Yes If you know them and you study them and you know what they are Then when you argue with someone you can just be like that was the logical fallacy of blah and you can just erase Everything they said.
Speaker 1: so in practical everyday use knowing logical fallacies helps you smack people down Because you because most people when they argue just you know Normally without you know thinking really hard about or studying make logical fallacies left and riding up and down.
Speaker 1: So if you know how to point them out You can just own people in arguments without even having to give one point of evidence in favor of your position.
Speaker 0: In fact, there's an entire branch of rhetorical debate that effectively is dedicated to using logical fallacies like that to basically Confound idiots and then convince them that you're right.
Speaker 1: Yep But on the other hand if you're so smart that you recognize this you have the ultimate defense where no logically fallacious Argument can stand in your way.
Speaker 1: But at the same time many correct arguments will fall before you because the people presenting them are so inept at arguing.
Speaker 0: now you can also take it one step further and You could if you're really clever and evil.
Speaker 0: you could use false Logical fallacies to confound your opponents and then win an argument.
Speaker 0: All right, especially if you just make up Latin words.
Speaker 0: Making up Latin words is great You know, I I think this is the direction we should go in because we're definitely not awake enough to talk about the you know Nitty-gritty.
Speaker 0: Well this therefore there's blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: This is called this kind of.
Speaker 0: let's just go straight into the logical fallacies That matter the most.
Speaker 1: All right, the one that matters the most as far as I am concerned is my favorite one Which is postdoc ergo proctor hoc.
Speaker 0: I think that actually means that that does not follow or that that does follow or I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think it means Just because it comes after Doesn't mean it's basically Correlation does not equal causality, right?
Speaker 1: For example, let's say I have a statistic and the statistic says that People walking out of I'm trying to think of an example.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 1: Can you think of anything?
Speaker 0: I think we just go with a straight-up exam go at the straight-up exam.
Speaker 0: All right, so let's say I Can't come up with anything either guy.
Speaker 0: No, hold on You know, I guess we're just so good at arguing that we have trouble actually making a logical value.
Speaker 0: So let's say I have a statistic that says that in the past ten years The globe the average temperature of the earth has increased steadily and we can chart it clearly.
Speaker 0: It's increased Yep, and in that same span of ten years the number of pirates in international waters has decreased.
Speaker 0: now I could make the conclusion from this data that Pirates decreasing causes an increase in global temperature and this is obviously not true.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: there are many things in the world.
Speaker 1: They're coincidences all the time.
Speaker 1: They're you know, they're.
Speaker 1: you know, Google is making more and more money every day and I'm getting a little bit more money every day and Google's getting a lot Here's that mean that Google.
Speaker 1: getting more money causes me getting more money or vice versa.
Speaker 1: No They just be two things in the world Happen to both be going up or two things happen to both be going down or one happens to go up when another goes down.
Speaker 0: I mean, here's a real-world example.
Speaker 0: There's there is a perceived correlation between immunizations and autism which as Smart people know is caused mostly by the fact that children get their immunizations right about the time when autism symptoms kick in.
Speaker 0: and There's all this other evidence too that basically that correlation is completely fallacious.
Speaker 0: But yet people still make the argument which is a logical fallacy That they cause autism when in fact they do not and there's evidence that they do not.
Speaker 1: There are many things that they seem to go together.
Speaker 1: You know one thing happens and another thing happens at the same time or one thing seems to happen a lot after Something else happens and it looks like it causes it.
Speaker 1: But unless you can actually show evidence that yes this caused it For example, you could show in like, you know a test tube, you know some DNA and then some vaccine and then the vaccine Modifying the DNA before and after to actually change it in a way That is to make that would make a person autistic.
Speaker 1: that would be a demonstration of causation.
Speaker 1: Other than that just because two things happen to coincide or you know Anything like that does not mean one thing caused the other and to say so without enough evidence is logically fallacious.
Speaker 0: So I think right along those lines perhaps my favorite because I'll admit that I use this as a rhetorical technique often ad hominins.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: the false dilemma.
Speaker 0: Now the false dilemma is very simple.
Speaker 0: all I do.
Speaker 0: you do use the false dilemma quite a bit And you know what it works because as a rhetorical strategy, it is brilliance brilliant I say even though I shoot it down all the time.
Speaker 0: All you do is present what two or more options in an argument and Make the kind of beg to question assertion that those are in fact the only two options.
Speaker 1: for example You know rim will make a statement and I'll say oh that statement, huh?
Speaker 1: So either a or B, which is it?
Speaker 1: which is it?
Speaker 1: and I'm totally ignoring the fact that there could be CDE and F. I'm acting as if a and B are the only possibilities in the whole world if you assume that what rim just said is true and it sort of traps rim because a is bad and B is bad also, but he can't get his mind out in out of that box and start thinking about CDE and F
Speaker 0: Certain.
Speaker 0: well one government in particular in the world in recent years has used this fallacy extensively.
Speaker 0: I believe you may know it as you're either with us or you're against us.
Speaker 0: That is very much the false dichotomy.
Speaker 1: Yep False dichotomies are great.
Speaker 0: So you want to since you mentioned it you want to bring up the ad hominem?
Speaker 1: All right ad hominem is is perhaps the the worst of all logical fallacies and the most used on the internet.
Speaker 1: For example, let's say rim set rims make up make a true statement.
Speaker 0: I am Incredibly intelligent and good-looking.
Speaker 1: No, that's not a true statement.
Speaker 1: You have to come up with something bad, but anyway, let's pretend the rim said that Scott was incredibly intelligent and good-looking.
Speaker 1: So that's a true statement.
Speaker 1: But now let's say I go and I say well rim you're wrong because you're ugly.
Speaker 1: That's basically what ad hominem is.
Speaker 1: you attack the person making the argument and you basically say well you're stupid.
Speaker 1: Therefore the thing you said is wrong.
Speaker 1: Listen You know, there are people in this world who are more educated than others.
Speaker 1: that that's just the truth.
Speaker 1: You know, there are some people in the world who are smarter than others.
Speaker 1: That's the way it is, but Just because someone is dumb doesn't mean everything they say is automatically wrong.
Speaker 1: I mean you could find the dumbest person in the world and they might say 1 plus 1 is 2. you can't say Well, you're dumb.
Speaker 1: that so 1 plus 1 isn't - no 1 plus 1 is - it's how it is.
Speaker 1: The person making the argument has nothing to do with the validity of the argument itself.
Speaker 1: like a lot of people You know, someone will be making a bunch of arguments and then someone will say well You're an ex-convict who killed a bunch of people and you know, that's a lot of the news channels will do that a lot, you know with some crazy person is making an argument, you know of some kind and you know Crazy people are usually wrong because they're crazy.
Speaker 1: It's they say a lot of crazy things.
Speaker 1: But sometimes a crazy person says something right and people use ad hoc the logical fallacy of the ad hominem attack To sort of make it so that anyone if they're crazy or if they're evil or if they can they can make the person seem like a bad person.
Speaker 1: then it may give the impression that everything they say is wrong because they're a bad person.
Speaker 1: and that's just not true.
Speaker 0: right along those lines is the argument from fallacy which is the false conclusion that just because an Argument was itself technically a logical fallacy that therefore the conclusion is false.
Speaker 0: The example I'm just poking around Wikipedia to remind myself of which ones I want to talk about.
Speaker 0: but there's a good example here All cats are animals.
Speaker 0: Ginger is an animal.
Speaker 0: therefore ginger is a cat.
Speaker 0: now that does affirm the consequent.
Speaker 0: It is a logical fallacy.
Speaker 0: But so the argument technically is an illogical argument.
Speaker 0: But at the same time that does not prove that ginger is not a cat, right?
Speaker 0: It just proves that the person arguing doesn't know what they're talking about exactly.
Speaker 1: So the person makes that argument.
Speaker 1: you don't have to believe that ginger is a cat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, here's a good example.
Speaker 0: The sky is blue because I am God and I made it that way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly It's like the sky might still be blue Just be.
Speaker 1: but the argument that they use to support the fact that the sky was blue was a bad argument.
Speaker 1: That doesn't mean the sky is suddenly not blue.
Speaker 1: I mean there are people around the world who argue for all sorts of different things and they use different evidence to support all those Arguments.
Speaker 1: but just because someone who's really bad at arguing is arguing for the right thing with bad evidence or falsehoods Doesn't mean that their conclusion is wrong.
Speaker 1: They might have.
Speaker 1: you know I might be trying to argue that one plus one is two and I might say well one is a half and one is a half and yeah, then you know, I might say something completely batshit and My argument might be bad.
Speaker 1: But one plus one is still two either even though I just I'm not able to argue in favor of it because I suck.
Speaker 0: So, I know you've been waiting to bring it up so I figure I'll let you broke the no true Scotsman.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, no true Scotsman the game of goof Yes, the no true Scotsman argument is something you will find quite often and it's actually something related to.
Speaker 1: another pet peeve of mine is basically, someone will say some it really has to do a lot with semantics.
Speaker 1: the no true Scotsman argument is where someone will say Well, like I'll use Emily's mom was like, oh, well, they're not athletes and it's like well It's like people have these personal definitions of words or they assign their own value systems to the definition of a word in some way and it's like they don't want to apply a Certain label to something for whatever reason but it has nothing to do with with reality or truth.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, that's not a bagel because it's not at every if it's not an everything bagel.
Speaker 1: It's not a bagel.
Speaker 1: Well, no a bagel by definition is a circular bread baked in a certain way with a certain dough.
Speaker 0: but at the same time if you're arguing the no true Scotsman is a Very easy way to get yourself out of a tricky situation If you can introduce it in such a way to where it's not clear right away that you're making the no true Scotsman.
Speaker 0: Yes because if it's someone proves like if someone proves that I'm an Englishman and I don't want to be Portrayed as an Englishman for whatever reason then I could say ah But I do blah and no true Englishman would do blah therefore.
Speaker 0: I am NOT really an Englishman.
Speaker 0: Yes, despite the fact that you have just proven me to be an Englishman, but that is the unstated part.
Speaker 0: That's the part you say quietly to yourself.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: on another podcast I listen to some guy was like science fiction means Spaceships and planets and that stuff and he I'm like, well, what about like, I don't know the Twilight Zone He's like in my personal definition.
Speaker 1: That's not science fiction.
Speaker 1: First if you think you have a personal definition of a word I gotta say this it's bullshit.
Speaker 0: Well, no No, it isn't what you do.
Speaker 0: in that case it's just that that it's that fallacy often comes about unwittingly on both sides because The fallacy can arise if people are using different lexicons to argue.
Speaker 0: That's true, which happens often.
Speaker 0: That's why probably the most important thing you can do when you're actually debating with someone and we'll talk about this whenever we do the argument show is to together Agree on the terms any time a word comes up and there's any disagreement.
Speaker 0: that would result in a no true Scotsman you kind of have a Subdebate where you both agree that the word means X and then you finish the debate as though that word means what you agreed upon.
Speaker 0: Yep Otherwise, you can't actually have a true argument because you're coming from two different positions.
Speaker 0: if I think that all Scotsman or Willie and I argue as though any person who is Scottish is exactly like Willie from the Simpsons and Scott Argues from the perspective that Scottish people are Scottish we have a problem woman.
Speaker 1: Have you got any grease?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes, I do.
Speaker 1: Then grease me up woman.
Speaker 0: Okie dokie.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: I got to do this one.
Speaker 0: All right, partly because people use this phrase wrong.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna beg your question?
Speaker 0: I might.
Speaker 1: I know you love begging the question.
Speaker 0: if you ever want to infuriate me There is nothing you can do more perfectly more elegantly more Immediately than to use the phrase to beg the question to mean to raise the question.
Speaker 0: That is not what that means and you're doing it wrong.
Speaker 0: Begging the question is a brilliant and subtle fallacy where you basically make an argument That assumes something But you just go right past proving the thing you're assuming and act as though it's already a postulate mmm-hmm.
Speaker 0: and Basically what you've done is you've begged the question For example, I say the world is flat because God made it that way.
Speaker 0: Well now I've begged a whole bunch of questions.
Speaker 0: So there's a God.
Speaker 0: so we made the world so we made it flat.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's you make a statement and you act like the statement has already been proven like and you didn't you know back it up at all.
Speaker 1: and Now the people are gonna ask a whole bunch of questions like well How wait a minute go back a minute that thing you you just said something to support another argument.
Speaker 1: But that's something you said isn't quite right.
Speaker 1: I got a bunch of questions to ask about it's kind of it's circular logic.
Speaker 0: It's like you use your can.
Speaker 0: your conclusion implicitly proves the precedent.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep Alright, you want me to do one?
Speaker 0: I think you should do one.
Speaker 1: Alright, this is the fallacy of many questions Of the loaded question.
Speaker 1: in Latin the Plurium interrogate.
Speaker 0: you're looking at Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Yes, I am.
Speaker 1: Okay, but you know, you know kids will often pick on each other and they'll say something like hey Have you?
Speaker 1: uh, have you told your parents that you're stupid?
Speaker 0: When did you stop beating your wife?
Speaker 1: Yeah, when'd you stop beating your wife did?
Speaker 0: how long have you been a communist?
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: It's how long have you been a communist?
Speaker 1: you you in your statement?
Speaker 1: You you basically ask a question where no answer to the question directly Will be true.
Speaker 1: because like if you ask someone how long have you been a communist you're making the assumption that they're a communist.
Speaker 1: And if they're not a communist How do you can't say wait your question is wrong.
Speaker 1: this is basically asking a question in which the question carries a false assumption and It's a really good trick because people are like what the fuck and it's you know, what do you say to that?
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it's like even if someone comes up to you and says hey Have you have you told your parents that you know?
Speaker 1: You stole a million dollars from the bank and it'd be like I didn't steal a million dollars in the bank.
Speaker 1: That's sort of a weak comeback to that.
Speaker 1: Are you know convincingly to other people?
Speaker 1: So it's it.
Speaker 1: it's very false.
Speaker 1: But if you're arguing with people and you use this technique It's very difficult for them to say something that makes them look powerful, you know It really puts you on top of the game.
Speaker 0: now one particular branch of five fallacies.
Speaker 0: I'll just call them the appeals in general and This is an argument that you don't make really to the person you're arguing with ever.
Speaker 0: Wow, it seems like every time I bring up a fallacy I end up describing it as here's how to use this fallacy in an argument.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this is a the kind of thing where you're not even you don't even care who you're arguing with.
Speaker 0: this is a fallacy where you appeal to the audience and Furthermore you appeal to something that has nothing to do with the argument with the audience like an appeal to fear.
Speaker 0: You appeal to the fear of the audience like if we listen to him then Nazis are gonna come and kill you all That.
Speaker 0: if not, unless you're in World War two era Germany is a logical fallacy.
Speaker 0: you were appealing to the fear of the audience.
Speaker 0: their fear of Nazis Have nothing to do with the argument at hand.
Speaker 1: You're basically scaring people into Agreeing with what you say no matter what your bait you're saying at all, you know, like I could say All right I say X and rim says why and if you believe why you're all gonna die tomorrow.
Speaker 1: if you believe X will all live in paradise, which one do you believe?
Speaker 1: and The the ifs the if statements that I just presented were both had absolutely no evidence to support them whatsoever.
Speaker 1: But by making them I was able to basically Convince weak-minded people into believing my thing no matter what a is and no matter what X is.
Speaker 1: That that's what he's talking about.
Speaker 0: Yeah and I also got to bring this one up because it's also a very useful one and it's one that we've actually brought up a lot because I I've been known to use it occasionally in a rhetorical debate, but the straw man
Speaker 1: Oh the strong of the famous straw man.
Speaker 1: many people they talk about the straw man But they don't really know what the straw man is.
Speaker 0: They think Wizard of Oz nothing burns like an effigy.
Speaker 0: Nothing quite burns like the effigy basically, so Scott's arguing some point.
Speaker 0: now What I'm doing.
Speaker 1: Zelda 1 is the greatest.
Speaker 0: the analogy that I'll do that I'll make here is that Scott is standing there arguing.
Speaker 0: I distract the audience by making a straw man a scarecrow that looks like Scott and Then I set it on fire and the audience says wow.
Speaker 0: He just burned that scarecrow.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, the real Scott is standing there.
Speaker 0: No one's listening to him.
Speaker 0: The straw man is when you take the other person's argument and Reframe it or rephrase it in such a way that it sounds so much worse than it was or even better if you change it entirely and you make it disappear as though your enemy is arguing something that they're not really arguing and Furthermore you make that thing that you have made it sound like they're arguing be patently false and easily disproven.
Speaker 1: For example rim might say so pick rim pick a video game.
Speaker 0: Alright Silver Surfer is the best video game ever right?
Speaker 1: So I say so.
Speaker 1: you're saying that Zelda 1 is a terrible god-awful game.
Speaker 1: Well, you must be a terrible person.
Speaker 1: But I said right he didn't say anything about Zelda But I basically put words in his mouth to make it, you know.
Speaker 1: And I basically, you know made this scarecrow that looks like rim and I put my hand in the back of it Like a little puppeteer, you know or a wedding marionette.
Speaker 1: and I made that scarecrow say Zelda is terrible And then I set it on fire like it.
Speaker 1: Look rim said Zelda's terrible and everyone agrees with me.
Speaker 1: Yeah Get him Zelda's great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though rim didn't say Zelda was terrible I just make it look like rim said something really bad that everyone will disagree with when he didn't say anything of the sort.
Speaker 0: It's basically a way to make your opponent look bad And as a result, you can then use the leverage you've gained from making them look bad to make everything else They say look just as bad.
Speaker 0: Yep, and also if they make a real solid argument by reframing the argument carefully You can introduce a way of defeating the argument that wasn't there in what they originally said.
Speaker 1: Now there's a problem with the straw man.
Speaker 1: that I run into quite often is if you're making an argument.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you can straw man yourself by accident because you'll have an idea in your mind.
Speaker 1: It usually happens more the less eloquent you are and you have an idea in your mind of what you arguing But you're unable to express that idea or maybe you're just unable to communicate that idea to ever.
Speaker 1: you trying to communicate it to you And the idea they get in their head from your words is Different from the idea that you're actually trying to get across.
Speaker 1: and thus the argue.
Speaker 1: You'll basically build a straw man by accident and then they'll the person you're trying to convince starts beating up the straw man.
Speaker 1: You're like I'm over here guys.
Speaker 1: It's not what I was trying to say.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should call that man by accident.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should call that the funeral pyre.
Speaker 0: I build a funeral pyre around myself and then I just wait for my opponent to light it.
Speaker 0: Yes, I'm like that, you know, I know even better.
Speaker 0: We'll call it the gas can on the head fallacy.
Speaker 0: All right, let's argue but I'm gonna stand here with this gas can and I know you've got a match.
Speaker 1: I got one that people use quite often and is really pissing me off every day and people don't seem to stop using it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So hey rim a is true.
Speaker 1: You know why is true?
Speaker 1: because all my friends say so and because everyone else says so you know what?
Speaker 1: if everyone in the whole world Except for me says that one plus one is three and I say that one plus one is two I'm right and everyone else in the world is wrong.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: This is a tricky one because Conspiracy theory type people will often be like yeah, the whole world is wrong.
Speaker 1: It's a huge concern.
Speaker 1: It's not common for the whole world to be wrong.
Speaker 0: When anytime, you know, you see some crazy guy I was gonna remember, you know, how do you know that?
Speaker 0: You're not that guy.
Speaker 0: anytime you think that everyone else is crazy, but you the odds are against you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean crazy people generally seem to think that you know They're right and everyone else in the whole world has got it wrong about achievements whatever.
Speaker 1: But it's not just because many crazy people are like that and they are crazy.
Speaker 1: Don't get yourself wrong Doesn't mean it's necessarily true.
Speaker 1: I mean like Albert Einstein came up with the theory of relativity It was like him and a few people in the whole rest of the world had it wrong.
Speaker 1: And now the whole rest of the world realized and now we have it right err than we did before.
Speaker 1: you know, right?
Speaker 1: Right err more correct.
Speaker 1: So just because a large number of P It's the argument ad populum populace many people, you know a population of people It just because a lot of people agree on something doesn't make it true.
Speaker 1: a lot of people agree on a lot of things and They're very wrong.
Speaker 1: a lot of people, you know, a lot of people in this world believe all sorts of crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean people are believing in like fake medicine and all sorts of bad shit, you know psychic powers and it's all false.
Speaker 1: just because a lot just because more people agree on something doesn't make it more true.
Speaker 1: if everyone in the whole world said that you know Nintendo is spelled QX JBF It's still fell.
Speaker 1: it's still spelled nint endo.
Speaker 0: the real point here is pretty simple Just any time someone is trying to argue with you don't you don't need to memorize the stupid names of fallacies.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know like well, that's the fallacy of this and that's an informal fallacy And that's a formal fallacy and that it out of that.
Speaker 0: All you need to do is In your head whenever someone's speaking boil down what they're saying to what logical argument They're actually making if they're making a logical argument at all.
Speaker 0: And at that point if you can do that Very often if they're making a bad argument, it will become readily apparent.
Speaker 0: And if you can point that out, you've pretty much won the day.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Oh and you know That's pretty much what it comes down to.
Speaker 1: you're arguing with people and the way people argue on the internet these days is just logical.
Speaker 1: Fallacies left and right.
Speaker 1: so if you just learn to notice them You could just win any are you?
Speaker 1: just shut people down left and right shut down shut down shut down.
Speaker 1: The thing is it takes quite a bit of thinking and quite a bit of learning and quite a bit of practice.
Speaker 0: That's where the so-called name fallacies kind of come anyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if anyone comes along and is like hey Scott, you don't argue that way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I you know not trying to do it all the time.
Speaker 1: What do you want from me?
Speaker 0: and I often use the opposite and I use logical fallacies to my own ends.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes you do All right.
Speaker 1: We have anything else to say about this now.
Speaker 0: I'm going to bed.
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 0: Yeah, good God This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.