Speaker 0: It's Tuesday February 27th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We review an old classic Super Mario world.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know sometimes when I do my job I start to think about how weird is the world where I get paid more money than most humans on this planet to Get up drive to a building somewhere Unplug one cable plug in another cable and then stand there to make sure that new cable is working.
Speaker 1: and You had to go through how many years of training to reach.
Speaker 0: oh yes Learning how to unplug this cable consume much of my college life.
Speaker 1: Could you have done it say I don't know six years ago.
Speaker 1: Could you have accomplished this feat?
Speaker 0: I could have accomplished this feat when I was nine.
Speaker 1: How come nine-year-olds aren't paid the amount of money you are paid to do the same thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean you could pay a nine-year-old with candy to do the same thing.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess part of it is that I mean it Realistically.
Speaker 0: the only reason it was easy is because nothing went wrong.
Speaker 0: But if that optical circuit had in fact not come back up I would have had a world of trouble to deal with that.
Speaker 1: the nine-year-old would probably have just cried Yeah, I'm going to work the day after tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Oh, man's new job.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna fall into that rut of Work really really really hard to try to impress everyone for a month before?
Speaker 0: the decay of the reality that this job is not temporary eats at your soul and eventually you slip into that show up late leave early don't do half the work you're supposed to because it Doesn't matter it all depends on how this work goes.
Speaker 1: There is a chance I'll be it a less than 50% chance that this work is actually a good work.
Speaker 1: And if it's a good work Then everything's cool, or it could be just like every other work in which case yes, I'll do exactly what you just said Right?
Speaker 0: so in the news you know it's gaming day I was gonna talk about how Sony has now said that rumble.
Speaker 0: who needs rumble?
Speaker 0: That's a last-generation feature anyway, but I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: That's not my news cuz what can I say?
Speaker 0: Sony is just done?
Speaker 0: Alrighty, so I'm gonna go way off topic here cuz a lot of people on the internet have lost their shit over this.
Speaker 0: Coca-cola for those of you who are unaware is one of the most popular brands of carbonated sugar water in the world It's true.
Speaker 0: It's perhaps the number one and coca-cola is doing something crazy.
Speaker 0: They're changing the design of their cans.
Speaker 1: What are they making it blue or white?
Speaker 0: no no no actually It's a really subtle change.
Speaker 0: They're making them kind of this matte instead of the glossy shiny that they are currently.
Speaker 0: They look a lot more like old old old cans of coke.
Speaker 1: I like that cuz.
Speaker 1: I like the way the old cans look better than the new ones.
Speaker 0: I had to admit.
Speaker 0: I was well one.
Speaker 0: I don't care about this at all.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't make a difference in my life.
Speaker 1: I mean I don't even drink soda I don't drink anything that fizzes, and I don't drink any sodas.
Speaker 0: Why don't you drink anything that fizzes?
Speaker 1: cuz I don't like fizz.
Speaker 0: now I'm just curious here in the sake of knowledge and such.
Speaker 0: What is it about fizz that you don't like?
Speaker 1: it feels unpleasant in my mouth now unpleasant?
Speaker 0: How is it in?
Speaker 0: somehow painful?
Speaker 1: or it is the?
Speaker 1: it is not a pleasant tingling?
Speaker 1: It is slightly more pain.
Speaker 1: It is not painful as an ow like if I cut my finger But it is more pain than is pleasant.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh like a scratching only tingly, but tingly more so than necessary.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm not sure what I could say about this.
Speaker 0: I'm just I'm amused at how seriously people around the world are taking this like it's actually somehow a big deal.
Speaker 0: Yet I remember when dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper changed their 20-ounce thing to be this kind of cone-shaped business and no one even batted an eye.
Speaker 0: And people keep changing the designs of cans and bottles and no one cares.
Speaker 0: Suddenly cokes touching on that you know deep-rooted American coca-cola and mom's apple pie and baseball and suddenly everyone loses their shit.
Speaker 1: It's only cuz someone said something.
Speaker 1: if no one said anything if they just changed it without saying anything No one would have noticed or cared except for maybe a few of those nutty people who collect you know coca-cola Memorabilia or something like that.
Speaker 0: you know I knew one of those people in high school who had some crystal Pepsi Wow a quite a bit of it in fact scary all sealed and he actually they do really really likes crystal Pepsi.
Speaker 0: It's a serious problem.
Speaker 0: It's like those people who have you know the wine cellar full of 20 bottles of hundred-year-old wine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like you can ever make more of that.
Speaker 0: if you really like that and you drink the last bottle What kind of life are you gonna?
Speaker 1: I actually understand those people's pain because I drank from like the ages of 10 to 23 or 24 dull 100% pineapple orange juice every morning, and then Just recently perhaps less than a year ago.
Speaker 1: They changed it completely.
Speaker 1: It's still.
Speaker 1: you can go and still to the store to buy dull a hundred percent pineapple orange juice.
Speaker 1: But they changed the flavor.
Speaker 1: It's now actually more apple juice than either orange or pineapple.
Speaker 1: it used to be just orange Pineapple and like a squirt of lemon and maybe some vitamin C or something.
Speaker 0: see that's actually a trend That's been going on in the US for a long time now where?
Speaker 0: Apple juice is kind of like how they make chocolate ice cream where the chocolate overpowers everything else.
Speaker 0: They don't worry about it.
Speaker 0: Apple juice is so neutral that in a lot of fruit drinks They sweeten it mostly with apple juice.
Speaker 0: then they add a little bit of whatever flavoring to it in the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the pineapple orange juice did not.
Speaker 1: I drank it because it was so acidic But it didn't have that you know.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like the pineapple canceled out the part of the orange flavor that I wasn't super fond of You know But it was acidic enough to clean out my whole throat in the morning When they added mostly apple juice to it, and it's now like more than 50% apple juice.
Speaker 1: It didn't do the same thing anymore.
Speaker 1: I might as well.
Speaker 1: Just drank an apple juice cuz it wasn't acidic at all.
Speaker 1: So I went back and I now I just drink God he.
Speaker 1: I tried to mix orange and pineapple juice together and like squirt lemon juice into it, and it totally didn't work.
Speaker 0: So now I just got wasn't doing well for about three weeks every morning.
Speaker 0: He'd get up, and I'd hear him downstairs just This
Speaker 1: imagine if you drank this
Speaker 0: I'd come home like I'd get up like he get up before me And I'd wake up to get ready for work or whatever and I'd see like three glasses dirty with various Concoctions and like the pineapple juice in that laying on the floor Scott on the ground naked crying
Speaker 1: wasn't that bad.
Speaker 1: But imagine if you drank the same thing for like over ten years every day And then it changed and you could never get any ever again.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm over it now mostly, but if I saw some for sale.
Speaker 1: I totally buy it.
Speaker 0: oh Well in the end.
Speaker 0: I do will I agree with Scott though.
Speaker 0: I kind of like the new aesthetic of the coke hands.
Speaker 0: It's really?
Speaker 0: it really is kind of old-school.
Speaker 1: Yeah, old-school is definitely cool because uh people have nostalgia for times from before they were born.
Speaker 0: actually People have nostalgia for times that never existed.
Speaker 0: really there was a really cool Scott.
Speaker 0: I'll if I find it I'll make it a thing of the day whenever I find it again.
Speaker 0: But I read an article a while ago about a brand of root beer.
Speaker 0: I don't remember what brand of root beer it was, but they did a bunch of studies about Nostalgia and memory and they made fake commercials and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: And they basically give people different kinds of root beer and ask them questions about their childhood like do you remember drinking?
Speaker 0: This is a kid you remember.
Speaker 0: What do you remember about it?
Speaker 0: and a lot of people when the brand presented to them was some sort of old-timey?
Speaker 0: Styling or nostalgic styling drink would remember drinking it as a child when in fact it did not exist when they were children.
Speaker 0: Wow It's very easy to alter non-critical memories in humans.
Speaker 0: There's actually a lot of cool research about that.
Speaker 1: It's like de Bellas is actually called what nostalgia incorporated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I guess a lot of it is like I wasn't alive until the 80s early 80s.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm like.
Speaker 1: I sort of believe that a lot of these things existed before I was born Despite you know not really making sure of it even recently.
Speaker 0: a lot of people our age remember Pokemon from way before Pokemon came to the US.
Speaker 1: that's true Pokemon.
Speaker 1: was it with the late 90s something like the Pokemons?
Speaker 0: a relative Oh God, I was about to say it's over like 10 years old.
Speaker 0: I was about to say relatively recent.
Speaker 0: cuz think about it the mid 90s.
Speaker 1: No, the first Pokemon game was for the original game boy.
Speaker 0: No, but think of this.
Speaker 0: the mid 90s doesn't sound like it was that long ago.
Speaker 1: No, it's over a decade.
Speaker 1: I know Pokemon's real old.
Speaker 0: All right Now they're on Pokemon meaning I've very nicely brought this conversation right back around to video games.
Speaker 0: What's your video game news?
Speaker 1: All right, so Metal Gear Solid 3. that's a game that I knew existed.
Speaker 1: It's it's a. it's a ps2 game.
Speaker 1: I Think it's called like substance or subsistence or whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't know the word that comes after the colon.
Speaker 0: We're the best game journalists ever.
Speaker 0: We play what DS is and that's it something like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's a game and actually I think I saw someone Greg playing it once.
Speaker 1: it's one with the camouflages and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah Apparently I did not know this game had an online component.
Speaker 1: Now as you might imagine it's a ps2 game with an online component Like who the hell has the ps2 modem?
Speaker 1: barely anybody.
Speaker 1: and you know who the hell has Metal Gear Solid 3 and the ps2 modem?
Speaker 1: Not too many people and in the US not too many people.
Speaker 1: But apparently it does exist and you can play Metal Gear Solid 3 online with the ps2 in the US.
Speaker 1: I didn't know this.
Speaker 0: Wow good job for keeping those servers up for the few people left.
Speaker 0: That's a really nice thing to do.
Speaker 1: Oh, no an April 2nd They're gonna take them servers down because barely anyone plays this thing.
Speaker 0: Ah This illustrates a lot of things that are wrong with the world today.
Speaker 0: one, it's tribes 2. all over again I feel for anyone who still plays this game.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean first of all, um, why the hell you playing Metal Gear Solid 3 Multiplayer?
Speaker 1: shouldn't you like get a 360 and maybe some Gears of War or something?
Speaker 0: Hey some you have nostalgia for games.
Speaker 0: or if you find a game that's Metal Gear Solid 3 You never know.
Speaker 0: that might have been.
Speaker 0: I mean that might have been some kids.
Speaker 0: quake 2.
Speaker 0: You can't really take that away from people.
Speaker 1: It's a sad kid.
Speaker 0: Hey, I'm trying to be nice here.
Speaker 0: All right, wait - is still perhaps one of the best FPS has ever created.
Speaker 1: But I don't know about that name.
Speaker 0: a better one other than tribes - he's half-life - Half-life - right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there aren't many half-life 1.
Speaker 0: Half-life 1. multiplayer was pretty man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Okay, so that's it.
Speaker 0: They're shutting it down.
Speaker 1: Yep it's like They're taking servers down that I didn't even realize existed Which you know.
Speaker 1: while we're always sort of worried that when you have an online game with some sort of corporate controlled centralized servers That you could be totally screwed if they decide to take those servers down Especially for MMO people who might have paid like for a year of service or something like that and then it goes down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now a lot of people yell at us nerds.
Speaker 0: Hey, that's not something you should care about.
Speaker 0: that won't happen.
Speaker 1: Well, it does happen But it is good to see that usually it happens when the game is really really dead And not when the game is sort of thriving at least not usually.
Speaker 1: I mean this game Metal Gear Solid 3 online is pretty dead.
Speaker 0: You got any numbers for all you know, that's like the hot shit on the internet.
Speaker 1: I guess it is possible.
Speaker 1: There could be a lot of people playing this but just my guess as to how many people with ps2s that are online Playing this game.
Speaker 1: It can't be that many.
Speaker 1: It really can't be.
Speaker 1: this now is not possible.
Speaker 1: so the fact that they'll keep these servers on that long is Kind of good, but the fact that it's even possible for games to stop existing is kind of sad things of the day.
Speaker 0: Scott's running with it with his little theme here and I got to say the one he's got tonight is Probably the best one.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's a tough call in terms of accuracy.
Speaker 1: Uh perhaps Perhaps there were some ones that are really close like the Disney ones are spot fucking on.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: Well, this is a non Disney one, which means you.
Speaker 0: so I'm surprised at the level of care put into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's pretty surprising when you really think about it outside of the major studios like Disney and Warner Brothers.
Speaker 1: a lot of the cartoons don't have opening theme songs with lots of vocal complexity and lots of lyrics and words and The ones that do they sound really bad.
Speaker 1: It's like only Disney and Warner Brothers can come up with theme songs that have lots of words in them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there's the occasional good rare one.
Speaker 0: Like I will admit the sonic underground opener for what it is.
Speaker 0: I kind of like it.
Speaker 0: Okay, the lyrics aren't that bad the only art that's really cheesy it.
Speaker 0: well nevermind I'll get into that when we actually talk about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Disney and Warner Brothers also seem to be the only people who can Internationalize their theme songs.
Speaker 1: very well, you know when the songs are song in different languages.
Speaker 1: They don't change the songs They just translate the lyrics to a different language and it seems to somehow work out whereas other people just don't even have lyrical openers to avoid the problem entirely.
Speaker 1: or They don't change the words and translate them when they bring them to another country and such and such.
Speaker 1: well Today is I have for you a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: That is a rarity.
Speaker 1: It is not Warner Brothers nor is it Disney but it does have a lyrically complex opening song That is translated to German Almost perfectly now.
Speaker 0: Not only that I think what really gets it here Is that they found a German guy who can sound exactly like captain Lou Albano?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess you could say that it's so perfect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's actually kind of surprising a lot of the voice acting too.
Speaker 1: when you hear it is like wow There's someone who sounds exactly like that guy.
Speaker 1: only he's a different guy and he speaks a different language.
Speaker 1: Look at that.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the Super Mario Brothers Super Show opener in German enjoy.
Speaker 0: so speaking of Sonic Underground.
Speaker 0: Sonic Underground was also released in France and the French opener to Sonic Underground is the exact same song just translated pretty much straight up into French though the guys singing it has a more stereotypically French sounding accent than one would expect.
Speaker 0: Oh But the thing is I will admit that I do from.
Speaker 0: ah, not only do I really like Manowar but I also like listening to Manowar singing in French and This kind of rock in French is actually music that I kind of enjoy.
Speaker 0: That's all you Plus Sonic Underground for all of its faults.
Speaker 0: that show tried.
Speaker 0: It tried to do more than you would have expected from children's television of the era.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess maybe it's closer to a bad anime than it is to a bad American cartoon.
Speaker 0: I'll put it that way maybe in terms of what the way the plot goes and in France, it's called Sonic Laravel Laravel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you don't have it I guess because they won't not sing Sonic Resistance.
Speaker 1: Well, there you have it two openers to video game related cartoons and Languages other than English, of course you get.
Speaker 0: if you really want to get ahead of yourself You can go to Scott's blog and look at ya.
Speaker 1: I basically went around YouTube for a couple hours today listing these things.
Speaker 0: So if you go, you know to the forums, I made a post about it and yeah, that's you're probably better off Just going to the ones we pick his things of the day just because we're kind of filtering them.
Speaker 0: They're not all amazing.
Speaker 0: Some of them are just oh, wow.
Speaker 0: It's the Transformers in Spanish.
Speaker 1: Yep Wow Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got some good ones tomorrow too.
Speaker 1: So I might bring out the heavy hitters tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I got a heavy hitter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll say I don't know if you're gonna try to steal what I want.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: the one I'm gonna use is also awesome.
Speaker 0: It's not the one you're thinking of.
Speaker 0: but anyway, okay get off of that.
Speaker 0: It is video game day and we've been talking a lot about what have we been doing on video game days the last few.
Speaker 1: I've been talking about board games and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I don't even remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, whenever we don't have a better topic We usually think all right what games have we played before that?
Speaker 0: We don't need to prepare it all to talk about.
Speaker 1: Well, there is one game that came out the the most recent game.
Speaker 1: well not the most recent game on the virtual console but a Recent virtual console release that I purchased because I never owned it before in my life, which I couldn't believe.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that until Scott told me just a few days ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and But I played it many times before in my life a whole lot actually.
Speaker 1: So I decided you know what?
Speaker 1: I've never bought this game yet.
Speaker 1: I've played the hell out of it.
Speaker 1: I should pay eight bucks for it or whatever.
Speaker 1: Where the five bucks.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they were charging.
Speaker 1: Haha Nintendo you I think it was eight bucks.
Speaker 0: Nintendo is once again getting us Pirates born and bred for most of our lives who have access to superior emulation.
Speaker 0: We had Nintendo's.
Speaker 0: I owned this game.
Speaker 0: I still own it.
Speaker 0: I have the cartridge and a Super Nintendo and yet we'll spend money to play it on the Wii.
Speaker 1: Yep So I got Super Mario World the one with Yoshi the first Super Nintendo Mario game.
Speaker 1: Are you believe Mario were all Super Mario Brothers for you?
Speaker 0: Are you believe the best or one of the best Mario games ever?
Speaker 0: I mean pretty much it and Mario 3 are at a dead heat in my book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you ask me, I'll give Mario 3 the slight edge, but that's not to say Mario World is not to awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there's no way for you to know if that might be partly due to nostalgia for having played one of them a lot more.
Speaker 1: You know I think the reason I kind of like Mario 3 a little bit more is.
Speaker 1: it seems like Mario 3 has more that old-school hiddenness that like, you know The Metroids would have and you know stuff like that, you know Whereas Mario World the hiddenness is a little more open and out there.
Speaker 1: so it's not as exciting.
Speaker 0: It's more Zelda II like in Mario 3. you'd never know that you can go behind the scenery on white pillars.
Speaker 1: Yeah You would never know that you could get that coin Crazy coin ship by getting enough coins in this level that scrolls really fast.
Speaker 1: You never know that you could
Speaker 0: fly
Speaker 1: off the screen in a particular place Carrying a turtle shell to bust a brick to get inside a pipe that takes you to fuck who knows where
Speaker 0: Or going to the far right of the desert using two hammers on blocks that have
Speaker 1: one hammer.
Speaker 0: I guess you need one.
Speaker 1: You only needed one hammer.
Speaker 0: if you don't waste your hammer on something else I've never actually bothered to go get that warp whistle.
Speaker 0: I just knew it was there.
Speaker 0: cuz you only need two warp whistles.
Speaker 0: You don't need a third one.
Speaker 1: I would go get it just because I would get all three and then cuz see my strategy to beat Mario 3. well, I was talking about Mario 3. now is I would get all three of the warp whistles, right and Because I. what I would do is as soon as I got to world 3 I would beat the boss of world to the desert.
Speaker 1: then I would warp to world 8 because only then you wing Extra p-wings and clouds because beat level 2 you get a cloud.
Speaker 1: that way I would have exactly the number of p-wings and clouds I needed to get to the end of world 8.
Speaker 0: man clouds are dangerous though Cuz if there's a level that's hard and you skip over it with the cloud and then you die in the next level It's not good.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, we're not gonna talk about Mario 3 but I'm Mario world.
Speaker 0: I mean the secrets are there but they're Zelda II where you'll be up and you'll see like hey There's a key and a keyhole over behind that pipe and I can't get over there.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: I wonder how I get that?
Speaker 1: Yep, or you'll go over to a level and on the map The level will be like a red dot.
Speaker 1: and if the level is a red dot, you know That level has multiple exits.
Speaker 1: or you'll go into a boo house and a boo house Obviously has mad boo secrets in it.
Speaker 1: so you'll explore the hell out of that boo house and you'll use your p-blocks all over the place and It's pretty obvious where a lot of the things are like.
Speaker 1: hey, there's some coins outlining the shape of a door.
Speaker 0: I wonder Yeah, there's also now that I think about it.
Speaker 0: Mario 3 was one of the last of those old-school.
Speaker 0: Winning is not a foregone conclusion.
Speaker 0: in Mario 3 and even as a kid when I was badass at that game Sometimes I would sit down and say I'm going to beat Mario 3 and fail.
Speaker 0: Yeah and one out of lives.
Speaker 0: There's no continue.
Speaker 0: There's no saving.
Speaker 0: you got to go and beat it before mom calls for dinner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also Mario World you basically have infinite lives effectively unless you suck and the game saves So you're gonna beat it eventually and once you beat it, you're done.
Speaker 0: That's not a big trend in games over the last many years that it went from this Beat the game.
Speaker 0: beating the game is the end.
Speaker 0: the means are entertaining but the end is beating it - You're going to beat the game.
Speaker 0: No matter what the game is more about going around and actually getting everything over time.
Speaker 0: It's like progress as opposed to one straight shot.
Speaker 0: Yep Great.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not a big deal, but super mario world I actually did own as a kid and I beat all the way through and I think it's my favorite Mario game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's a damn good Mario game.
Speaker 1: I remember when I first heard about it.
Speaker 1: I was like a cape a Yoshi.
Speaker 1: What's that crap?
Speaker 1: What happened to the raccoon tail?
Speaker 1: because I like the Mario 3 action, you know.
Speaker 1: But the thing was as much as I didn't like Yoshi before I got to you know to use Yoshi.
Speaker 1: When you got Yoshi, he was awesome You know and it's pretty.
Speaker 1: it was like before Yoshi.
Speaker 1: you looked at him and you said I don't like why they throw in His green dinosaur into my Mario world.
Speaker 1: I don't want him in here.
Speaker 1: get him out.
Speaker 0: See now.
Speaker 0: the reason I didn't worry about that was think Mario 1 came out.
Speaker 0: great game.
Speaker 0: Yep, Mario 2 u.s.
Speaker 0: Style came out.
Speaker 0: Uh now that's also but it's my number 3 Mario game.
Speaker 0: I mean, I can't save Mario world or Mario 3 is better overall, but Mario 2 is the number 2 as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: I really like Mario.
Speaker 1: I like Mario 2 Doki-doki panic also, but I'm not gonna give it incredible praise or anything.
Speaker 1: It's a good game.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe I mean my like if it is a lot like my like for Zelda 2.
Speaker 0: Maybe for some reason it just grabbed me.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: it's definitely not sequels cuz I hate most sequels Yeah, but no, I don't quake - damn it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alrighty, but Mario - as far as the Americans saw it was this totally different game where they threw in all these new weird Monsters and weird mechanics and all these things that never bet they weren't in the other Mario game.
Speaker 0: It was like this, you know what?
Speaker 0: like you see a shy guy you're like, wow, that's weird.
Speaker 0: But then you play Mario World or Mario 3 and you think back and you feel like those shy guys and those ninjies had Always been in Mario and you can't imagine them having not been in the Mario universe.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know what is now that I think back on it.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid I never felt like Mario 2 was really a sequel to Mario.
Speaker 1: I you know it because I also had the Zelda 2 which didn't feel like a sequel to Zelda.
Speaker 1: It felt like some other game with the same character Felt like some other game with the same character even though in both cases the instruction books very clearly made the Lineage known.
Speaker 1: Yep, but Mario 3 really felt like a sequel and Mario World definitely felt like a sequel to Mario 3.
Speaker 0: Hmm, but you were talking about you know, Yoshi like why are they adding this weird thing?
Speaker 0: but every Mario game added weird stuff and it felt uneasy or strange or Like just tacked on like.
Speaker 0: ah, they're just trying to add something.
Speaker 1: Actually before playing Mario 3 and I knew about the tail it was like, ah, yeah But before playing Mario World Yoshi was like what?
Speaker 1: Yeah, why I had the different feeling?
Speaker 0: but well, that's just Yoshi, but all the stuff in Mario World.
Speaker 1: I don't know some of the stuff in Mario World.
Speaker 0: I kind of accepted the football Koopa Troopa guys.
Speaker 1: I love those guys.
Speaker 0: I like him too, but they were definitely a strange addition.
Speaker 1: I guess you could say so.
Speaker 1: but yeah once Like the some of this stuff definitely flowed naturally like the boo houses.
Speaker 1: It's like a Mario 3. there were boos and in Mario World who houses it was just a natural progression.
Speaker 0: I guess the thing I'm talking I'm thinking about more is the idea that it's the nostalgia factor.
Speaker 0: You forget that there weren't boos until Mario 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of that people there weren't boos until Mario 3.
Speaker 1: You know where else there were boos though, I think in Yoshi the game just Yoshi.
Speaker 1: I think that had boos in it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think it did anyway.
Speaker 0: But the other thing music.
Speaker 0: to think about some of the songs that are so iconic to Mario and then realize that They were didn't exist until Super Mario World and yet now they're just they're part of the Mario universe And you can't imagine that they were never there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's actually kind of true.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I forget like which songs.
Speaker 1: I mean It's obvious which songs started in Mario 1 and it's obvious which songs came from Mario 2.
Speaker 1: But sometimes like I forget which songs started in Mario 3 and which ones started in Mario World and when they you play a game.
Speaker 1: Now like you pick up say new Mario Brothers for the DS, and they play a Mario song you go That's a Mario song and someone goes up to you and goes yeah, which Mario song?
Speaker 1: and you go uh?
Speaker 1: And some of them are easy like oh, that's the castle music from Mario 3 or oh That's the boo house music from Mario World, but sometimes you're like uh And it feels like that music has always been Mario music.
Speaker 1: you want to say Mario 1 But you know that's not true.
Speaker 1: It wasn't in there until Mario 4.
Speaker 1: Holy crap
Speaker 0: I think that is the sign of an extremely well done franchise that Nintendo has had such foresight and that when they or maybe it was random chance I don't know who knows but the fact that the continuity is so smooth even when there are jarring Transitions from game to game that the feeling that the universe is unified and when you see a thing from a Mario game you feel Like it's always been there without question.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you can change something and then as much as you have compared Mario 1 to Mario Sunshine Yeah, hey, it's like if you change the can of coke and then later if you change it again people are upset.
Speaker 1: You know you've done a good change because what you changed it to is just as beloved as what you had before.
Speaker 1: So let's talk about Mario World more specifically.
Speaker 0: well The plot is that the princess has been kidnapped by Koopa and your here's Koopa kids.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not the Koopa kid that you know.
Speaker 1: nowadays It's the same Koopa kids that were in Mario 3. see if you played Mario 3 in Mario World King Koopa had what like seven kids I think bunch of kids.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like Iggy Koopa Wendy was the worst one.
Speaker 1: Wendy was the bitch God when with those candy rings that she threw around and and Ludwig von Koopa and All sorts of other what were the other camera?
Speaker 1: if you can name all the Koopa kids you win a prize.
Speaker 1: Yeah Nothing.
Speaker 0: I've got this great piece of art that I still have to hang on the wall of the real awesome new Koopa kid Who's one of my favorite characters in any video game ever?
Speaker 0: Being beat up and trying to get away from all of his I guess stepbrothers and his stepsister.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the old Koopa kids that were from Mario 3 in Mario World.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's by that Brandon Kramer guy who we keep talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the awesome art, dude.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so basically you're Mario.
Speaker 1: you go from level to level world to world.
Speaker 1: Each world has one Koopa kid as the boss and in the final world Bowser is the boss and he's a motherfucker.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it follows the same kind of idea of Mario 3 where there's this overworld and you travel along lines from dot to dot Going into worlds and fighting and sometimes there are multiple paths or secrets or different ways to go.
Speaker 0: But there's a big wide world to explore.
Speaker 0: Unlike Mario 3 you can go between worlds easily.
Speaker 1: You can also Revisit worlds which is a huge difference from Mario 3. in Mario 3 you would beat a world.
Speaker 1: The world is beaten.
Speaker 1: you can't go back into it.
Speaker 1: in Mario world you go back into a level.
Speaker 1: You can like pick up a mushroom at the beginning of it and then quit or you can go into a level Pick up the one secret you missed and then quit the level.
Speaker 1: as soon as you get the secret, you know It's allows you to just keep Experiencing any part of the game you want to experience at any time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not many games really use that mechanic until after Mario 3.
Speaker 1: Well games had a mechanic where you could see.
Speaker 1: this is kind of weird because Mario world is one of the first games to Let you revisit levels, but you never had to revisit a level.
Speaker 1: There was no reason to other than to get you know, say pick up a mushroom You know easily in an easy level or to reopen a secret that you didn't open.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you don't need any of the secrets to win the game.
Speaker 1: Oh need them.
Speaker 1: You know there was.
Speaker 1: there's no reason to or necessarily miss of backtracking.
Speaker 0: Well, it can be necessary in the in the mystic forest if there's that one level where if you beat it by one exit It actually makes a loop that doesn't take you anywhere.
Speaker 0: Then you have to go back in.
Speaker 1: I guess it could be necessary.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it's not in general now.
Speaker 1: It's just general.
Speaker 1: it is possible to beat the game without repeating any levels, you know.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it wasn't until much after Mario world where they actually made games where backtracking was Important and useful and you needed to do it a lot more.
Speaker 1: in Mario world You only could do it to get some extra secrets.
Speaker 0: now We don't really need to talk much more about how Super Mario World worked if you if you've played the game before you know how it worked if You've never played it and you have a Wii and you don't feel like dealing with emulation.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend it.
Speaker 0: It is one of the best Mario games ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're pretty much it's.
Speaker 1: you're not a gamer if you haven't played beaten Mario world.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's.
Speaker 0: it's so classic it it's like having not seen Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I'm going to try to beat the game a hundred percent every single level and every single secret.
Speaker 1: But you don't have to do that.
Speaker 1: You just have to beat the game straight through and that's good enough.
Speaker 1: But if you haven't played it at all Wow, that's scary.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about all the interesting fun things in this game because one thing houses boo houses.
Speaker 0: I don't think you all understand Scott's fetish for boo.
Speaker 0: Banish Scott has this unhealthy obsession with boo though.
Speaker 0: I'll admit boo is pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: So who is the awesome?
Speaker 0: I understand it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's got a stuffed boo that he has in his room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically in Mario 3 there was boo But all boo was was the ghost and if you looked at him He would cover his eyes and if he turns your back to him, he would sneak up on you.
Speaker 0: now This is really cute in and of itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well Mario World had the same boo that you had in Mario 3. it also had a whole bunch more boos.
Speaker 0: There were silly boos and shy boos and gigantic boos and boos came in different formations.
Speaker 1: Like some boos would turn into rocks that you could stand on when you looked at him.
Speaker 1: But if you looked away, they turn into a boo and try to get you.
Speaker 1: There would be gigantic boos that you had to jump over without touching them.
Speaker 1: there would be Rings of boos that would spin around and only live you what like one point of entry if you wanted to jump through them.
Speaker 1: There would be like millions of boos flying in the ceiling and then they would swoop down on you trying to get you like the Sun in Mario 3 did.
Speaker 0: those are actually my favorite kinds of boos.
Speaker 0: They were kind.
Speaker 0: they were like this mass of Semi-translucent boos that would materialize whenever you got near him and swoop in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there were lots of crazy different boos and it definitely it always felt cool Cuz you'd be these haunted houses that you had to go into and Yoshi wouldn't go inside.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yoshi How useless are you?
Speaker 0: whenever I really need you you abandon me?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you had Yoshi in a boo house Holy shit, you could wreck that place up.
Speaker 1: cuz you get hit by a boo You just land on Yoshi again.
Speaker 1: hit by a boo land on Yoshi again.
Speaker 1: It'd be all great.
Speaker 1: But no, he doesn't come with you in the boo house makes it all hard.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the boo houses were always cool because they were less about the platforming jumping from thing to thing you know tricky timing and maneuvering and reflexes that the other levels had and it was more about finding the secret way to go to different paths while these ghosts were pestering you.
Speaker 1: and Basically the ghosts work to limit your time in the level I mean.
Speaker 1: if the ghosts weren't there it would be stupid.
Speaker 1: easy because you could just walk around and do whatever you want.
Speaker 1: But because the ghosts are there you pretty much not only get to find these secrets and figure them out with tricky thinking.
Speaker 1: You have to do it really fast because if you don't work fast enough the booze will descend on you and kill you.
Speaker 0: Now the boo house has also had numerous secrets some of which were actually very fucking difficult to get a hold of You mostly cuz booze harassed you while you tried to get them.
Speaker 0: Yeah See one of the great things about this game was the secrets.
Speaker 0: and while Scott says he's going to try to beat the game 100% I did so when I was a kid and it took me months months and months most of which was spent
Speaker 1: trying
Speaker 0: to beat the star world and the Super secret star world of which Scott was existed was dubious of the existence thereof.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, cuz I didn't own a Super Nintendo Sega Genesis kid But I played Super Mario World a lot and my friends houses and my cousin's house and I had seen and played The majority of the game, but I had never seen like this double plus star world ever.
Speaker 1: So I didn't you know believe it existed.
Speaker 0: Yeah So Scott's going around to the star world and I said hey Are you gonna go to tubular and awesome and all those places?
Speaker 0: and he's like what what are you talking about?
Speaker 0: So I said you see that big pillar in the middle of the star world.
Speaker 0: if you beat all the star worlds around You can go up there There's another star and it takes you to this magical world where you can't win and it's fucking impossible.
Speaker 0: and I threw the controller at my TV like 12 times as a kid.
Speaker 0: and They get.
Speaker 0: each one is harder than the last and they're not like normal Mario levels.
Speaker 0: They're like a normal level from these games this game just a little bit bigger Except that you have to get the secret exit to advance and it's just impossible.
Speaker 1: We'll see how I'll do that last.
Speaker 0: probably they were really hard But if you beat them all and get to the end you can go in this final star And it changes the rest of the game.
Speaker 0: It changes the color palette.
Speaker 0: all the coopers are now wearing Mario mask.
Speaker 0: It changes a whole bunch of stuff all over the game permanently.
Speaker 1: That's pretty crazy stuff right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, another thing I like about the star worlds is that it's sort of like the whole game.
Speaker 1: You have this green Yoshi who does what he does and if he eats certain shells he can do other things.
Speaker 1: If you go to the star world you can get these other colored Yoshi's and it's like whoa.
Speaker 1: You know remember I was talking about that sort of wonder.
Speaker 1: Yeah That sense of wonder and sort of holy crap.
Speaker 1: look at that secret that Mario 3 definitely had more of that than Mario.
Speaker 1: world.
Speaker 0: God when I got a blue Yoshi I was so excited about that.
Speaker 1: cuz but Mario world definitely still had it and where it had it was in the star world Where all this crazy shit was happening.
Speaker 0: yep like you'd see you know yellow shells and red shells and blue shells And they did stuff.
Speaker 0: and then one day I stumbled upon a flashing shell and I thought to myself I wonder what would happen if Yoshi ate that and it turned out had the powers of all three shells at the same time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was crazy.
Speaker 1: It was super crazy.
Speaker 0: The game also honestly has one of the best learning curves of any Mario game out there.
Speaker 0: it starts out Really really easy, but not stupidly easy.
Speaker 1: That's very true.
Speaker 1: I mean most Mario games like the first level of say Mario Brothers 1 is so Easy.
Speaker 1: I mean if you figure out the controls you can beat that level.
Speaker 1: you might not beat it well But you can beat it, but then again at least that was the first Mario game.
Speaker 0: So it's not like anyone had any experience and all of us died on their first goomba at least once yep.
Speaker 1: But it's you know it's so easy that someone who's good at the game Won't really find it interesting at all in Mario world.
Speaker 1: even the earliest levels Which are a lot easier than the later levels are complex enough to still be interesting to play when you have a high skill level.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like they have this perfect balance of introducing new elements at a rate to where you will understand them and see their uses Introducing novel uses of things you already knew about Introducing new kinds of enemies new mechanics whatever.
Speaker 0: and they do it so that the game never gets old the moment You think you've got the game under control.
Speaker 0: it steps the difficulty up this tiny little bit and adds one more little Complication.
Speaker 0: and by the end of the game when you're in the mystic forest or by the the ghost ship You'll look back And you'll look at what you're doing in the game and be amazed at how good you are at this game compared to when you started.
Speaker 0: Like the game trains you to be good at Mario games Yeah, and like where is a Mario 3?
Speaker 1: you know there were different kinds of levels even a Mario 1. there were different kinds of.
Speaker 1: There's a normal level an underground level a bridge flying fish level a mushroom.
Speaker 0: are the pillars level those long Level?
Speaker 1: and underwater level?
Speaker 1: and a castle level you know and Mario world They keep throwing all sorts of new kinds of levels at you, and that's what really keeps your interest going.
Speaker 1: I mean you know there'll be one level where dolphins are coming out of the water, and it's crazy.
Speaker 1: It's like whoa.
Speaker 1: This is a new kind of level.
Speaker 1: That's a dolphin level.
Speaker 1: what the hell's up with that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the thing is the game has enough novel stuff in it that throughout the entire game You were constantly running into new things Until the very end where it takes all the things you've learned and throws them at you as hard as possible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you're never gonna.
Speaker 1: You know you if you keep beating levels You're gonna keep running into new stuff And you're gonna get being excited to keep playing like even as late in the game is the mystic forest Which is pretty late.
Speaker 0: you've gone through a lot of the game at that point.
Speaker 0: now Bubbles and there's wigglers, and there's bob-omb suddenly.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, I mean even mario 3 didn't do such a good a job at that You know because mario 3 basically each world had a type of level.
Speaker 1: you know all of the levels in world 7 were Mostly sort of kind of the same.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean in general you could like something.
Speaker 0: there were definitely some water levels and underground levels and platforms moving through the air levels and Standard platformer levels levels that scroll on their own and levels that you scroll.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mario games are all about the kinds of levels at least 2d mario games are.
Speaker 1: a lot of people don't realize that.
Speaker 0: One thing I do remember from mario 3 though was that the worlds were so different and exotic.
Speaker 0: Maybe it was partly because you couldn't save the game so certain levels like level 5 and 6 and 7 you didn't see Often in your life.
Speaker 0: ah like if you wanted very true if you wanted to see these levels You either had to have a game genie Or you just had to start and play through the game enough to get to him.
Speaker 1: so when you got to him you only got To play him once.
Speaker 1: as soon as you walked past a pipe that pipe was gone.
Speaker 1: You weren't gonna see that pipe unless you died or unless you played the whole game again up to that point And it was definitely the sense of like the cloud world.
Speaker 0: and then that's like the tower to the top And you just you know the tower was so hot.
Speaker 0: I love that so much.
Speaker 0: of course I was kind of pissed when I got to the top and found out there was a whole nother level that was twice as hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that see the thing is world 5 on the ground is One of the best worlds and that tower is one of the best because they it's like they have a difference.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know who designed all the different levels like who did what level in Mario 3.
Speaker 0: But I would guess that a different team did world 5.
Speaker 1: Maybe because it's just so different from the whole ride about how they snuck that caribou shoe in there.
Speaker 1: But I don't know why the caribou shoe is not in Mario or curry beau shoe is the dog.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's why I think that's what makes Mario 3 better than Mario world.
Speaker 1: definitely It's that sort of thing, but the end the same time.
Speaker 0: Mario world is such a precise polished game with like no flaws.
Speaker 0: Well, no flaws other than flaws that are inherent in 2d platformers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't really see anything wrong with Mario world at all.
Speaker 0: a lot of people don't like the mystic mystic forest world.
Speaker 1: I don't like the mystic forest, but just cuz I don't like it.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with it.
Speaker 1: I just don't like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I personally really don't like vanilla dome.
Speaker 1: I love the vanilla dome.
Speaker 1: That's the best now.
Speaker 1: butter bridge.
Speaker 0: butter bridge is pretty good.
Speaker 1: I like the butter bridge.
Speaker 0: man getting the butter bridge was always like whenever I started a new game like when I got to butter Bridge is when I felt like I had the game under control.
Speaker 0: like I've crossed the bridge I am now ready to kick some ass.
Speaker 1: Oh see for me It was like as soon as I got into the vanilla dome like that's when the game started before.
Speaker 1: the vanilla dome was sort of Like this pregame wussy crap.
Speaker 0: I don't know for me the vanilla dome was not really wussy But the vanilla dome was like this like the calm before the storm.
Speaker 0: like this is the last easy leveler This is the last male level and then everything gets crazy.
Speaker 1: Whatever, it's Mario world.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah Really if you haven't played Super Mario world you have to buy this game on the virtual console or at least emulate it and play it.
Speaker 1: it is or get a Super Nintendo and a copy of Mario world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever find a way to play the game and play it.
Speaker 1: if you haven't if you have Maybe it's time to go back and play it again.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm probably going to once I finish finish Phoenix Wright 2 which I'm working on and then we could talk about that shit That game as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course if you are looking for our New York Comic Con convention coverage You'll get that tomorrow since tomorrow is anime manga and comics day.
Speaker 0: Holy crap and tomorrow we're going to start a contest and CPM gave us a bunch of free goodies at the con that I Really have no desire to own so I'm gonna give them away to you nice people.
Speaker 0: Yeah All Right, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.