Speaker 0: It's Wednesday June 6th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is the geek nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we reviewed the amazing awesome comic just released a trade paperback Elks run.
Speaker 1: You know if it weren't for the fact that the one thing I need from Linux isn't on Windows I think I would have given up on Linux pretty much right now at least for my primary computer because Audio just doesn't work for shit in Linux.
Speaker 1: I gotta say I gotta say I got to admit well I mean, it's not that audio doesn't work in Linux.
Speaker 0: It audio is shitty in Linux.
Speaker 0: There is no doubt.
Speaker 0: It's just that Linux works pretty much perfectly well for absolutely normal everyday computer.
Speaker 1: Apparently it's not normal to record.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it works perfectly normal on Nor you know run-of-the-mill Older hardware.
Speaker 0: when you have a new fancy computer, it's not gonna work for shit.
Speaker 1: It's not that new.
Speaker 0: I'm not a great deal of effort.
Speaker 1: It's not really that new and fancy.
Speaker 1: this chip sets Relatively old and see but it's.
Speaker 0: it's relatively new and fancy compared to Linux.
Speaker 0: I'm talking like you know two-year-old stuff here.
Speaker 0: well I think that's some 64 bits or two cores.
Speaker 1: Or I think the problem is more that most people use Linux don't do anything like podcasting So no one really cares about if the audio actually works for anything intense.
Speaker 1: well See that's.
Speaker 0: the thing is that there are a lot of podcasters on Linux.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's like three.
Speaker 0: There's actually a whole like at least 20 or 30 I can name like five.
Speaker 0: I think all right But it's you know it.
Speaker 0: It's mostly the fact that if you want Linux to be easy you pretty much Ubuntu feisty is the way to go And that's also the best way to get the newest hardware working with the least effort.
Speaker 0: But also because the way Ubuntu works You're not gonna be able to upgrade the kernel like there's a better kernel that might work really well on your computer.
Speaker 0: But you can't get that in feisty great really easily.
Speaker 0: You know gentoo you could but that's a huge pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: So it all comes down to like your distributions and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: and right now There does not exist a Linux distribution that without a great deal of effort It doesn't have problems doing exactly what we want to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's always the special cases that it totally fucks on and all the general cases Linux has it covered.
Speaker 0: when it comes down to a special case like I want to do this specific thing that is slightly out of Line of the norm you're gonna run into at least one bump in the road.
Speaker 0: It's guaranteed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I want to play games on my computer.
Speaker 1: Oh Linux.
Speaker 1: Can't do that?
Speaker 0: No again, it's because the games haven't been written for Linux.
Speaker 0: Just fine.
Speaker 1: Oh great.
Speaker 1: Yeah doom 3 was such a wonderful game.
Speaker 0: At least the audio is actually a complaint like there's something wrong with Linux.
Speaker 0: the games complaint is not really anything wrong with Linux It's in fact.
Speaker 0: I say it's a miracle that you can wine so many games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's more games.
Speaker 0: You can't wine That is true.
Speaker 0: Honestly.
Speaker 1: I would just boot into Windows, but ReSound doesn't work.
Speaker 1: ReSound barely works in Linux So it certainly doesn't work in Windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just.
Speaker 0: I think more of our problem Also is that there just don't exist that many quality single-track wave editing programs.
Speaker 0: They just aren't any of them that they did.
Speaker 0: where are they?
Speaker 0: this ReSound which has a bunch of problems there was cool It was cool at it, and I guess audition, and that's what else is there?
Speaker 0: is that Sony thing?
Speaker 0: fuck that?
Speaker 0: What there's a whole frickin type of application and there are so few choices and no one's working on this Problem.
Speaker 1: because no one cares except me and I have time.
Speaker 0: I know like imagine.
Speaker 0: It was like only one spreadsheet.
Speaker 1: You know what there effectively is because most people don't know about open office And they don't care.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying is like there are a whole bunch of spreadsheets, and they all work.
Speaker 0: And if you need one you can get one.
Speaker 0: yeah, and it's not a problem.
Speaker 0: We need a specific application.
Speaker 1: It doesn't exist because not many people do what we do.
Speaker 0: I think it's a lot of people do would do that.
Speaker 0: It's just they don't know any better.
Speaker 1: well I mean they'd like I said they don't do what we do.
Speaker 1: they do things differently.
Speaker 1: They do things.
Speaker 1: they use that garage band or all those other programs.
Speaker 1: the way the multi-track editors work like audacity is a pretty Good multi-track editor But it's actually really crap.
Speaker 1: if you want to edit or actually filter audio all the filters are garbage.
Speaker 1: the compressor is garbage.
Speaker 1: Lots of support barely works.
Speaker 1: most of the lots of plugins are crap, but that's it's Wednesday So we're going to talk about this anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm just miffed that my new computer is awesome except for podcasting.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep, yep, yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, well.
Speaker 0: What's she gonna do?
Speaker 0: So I got some news, but the site that has the news article currently has an internal server error.
Speaker 0: But that doesn't matter because I remember the news enough.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's bad news really bad news Like possibly some of the worst news if you've ever seen I don't know Macross.
Speaker 0: you know the original one the amazing amazing TV show that is the amazing of all amazingness.
Speaker 0: or if you've seen I don't know a whole bunch of other anime.
Speaker 0: I can't really remember the names of it all because I probably haven't watched any of them.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't matter you watch.
Speaker 0: Macross has this amazing soundtrack.
Speaker 0: It's like fully composed with an orchestra and the whole deal, and it's.
Speaker 0: it's really Sort of weird, but it fits so well, and it's so wonderful in every way.
Speaker 0: And it was composed by a man named Kentaro Haneda and Kentaro Haneda I regret has recently passed away.
Speaker 1: Now if I had it available, which I don't just because I haven't migrated all of my data yet I would probably have played the Macross national anthem just now.
Speaker 0: I've got every Macross mp3 There is on my computer over there, so if we want we can go get it.
Speaker 1: no now with all the problems I'm having with audio right now in Linux.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: yeah, but regardless This is kind of sad because he was this amazing composer, and if you've never watched Macross you should at least like Watch some episodes and just listen to the music in that show even if you don't like the show because it's not a show for Everyone even though it's a show for everyone.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you not liking it.
Speaker 1: I'll admit.
Speaker 1: I it's okay I don't I don't like it that much.
Speaker 1: you suck, and I've watched almost all of it.
Speaker 0: you suck, but The music in it is really something to behold.
Speaker 0: and they're gonna have a big concert.
Speaker 0: They were planning this already having a big concert for you know the I guess 25th anniversary of Macross.
Speaker 0: I think I'm not sure but When they had they're gonna of course now dedicate that concert to this guy.
Speaker 0: So I'm definitely gonna like be looking for a DVD of that or so let's go to the concert.
Speaker 0: I think it's a little far away.
Speaker 1: Where is it?
Speaker 0: Japan on the side of the world?
Speaker 1: Let's head over there.
Speaker 1: That's all you know biggie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: so in news more close to home Con season is upon us.
Speaker 1: This is more of a personal news.
Speaker 1: It's not a news that's out there on the internet anywhere.
Speaker 1: It's just my observation.
Speaker 0: We're making news.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Is that the wow?
Speaker 0: is that the next step for you guys to make news?
Speaker 0: We're gonna be journalists read news from a website.
Speaker 1: Well, it's kind of annoying news, and I haven't really.
Speaker 1: I have one or two Last-ditch leads I could use to figure out what's going on But I got to say that I'm getting the impression that Otacon is really not That together.
Speaker 1: this year compared to any other year of Otacon It's really.
Speaker 0: it's more upsetting because I'm looking at what other cons are doing.
Speaker 0: Look at the go to anime Expos website and look at the news.
Speaker 0: remember we talked about anime So was last week or two weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: They're doing some crazy amazing shit over there.
Speaker 0: Like I usually like.
Speaker 0: I never been to anime expo.
Speaker 0: so but I had suspicions about it for a long time that it was a very Industry centric con and I got the feeling that it wasn't my kind of deal.
Speaker 0: But based on the news and the press releases they have put out this year It's looking really hot just in terms of what they're having there.
Speaker 0: You know regardless of anything else.
Speaker 0: I may be suspicious about Meanwhile Otacon is what a month or two away, and they haven't announced a musical guest or anything and They just recently had like the panels and the artist alley submissions.
Speaker 0: They haven't gotten back to anybody about it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they've gotten back to anyone or not for the artist alley But they definitely did not respond in any way to my request for a table at all.
Speaker 0: I mean usually cons get all this stuff out of the way Way before the con.
Speaker 0: like you'll get your artist alley table like six months in advance.
Speaker 0: You'll get your pet.
Speaker 0: You'll know know it if you're doing a panel or not way in advance.
Speaker 0: I mean, how are people who are like preparing fancy panels supposed to know like prepare the panel in such a short period of time?
Speaker 1: I'll put it in very specific because it's not just my perception.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you exactly about my interactions with all the conventions.
Speaker 1: We've been working with this year and for next year all right and basically Long time ago, and I started talking to Kinetic con.
Speaker 1: We've already hammered the whole thing out.
Speaker 1: Kinetic con is already set and we're done.
Speaker 1: We've already got all of our programming ready.
Speaker 1: all that's left to do is to specifically schedule When they'll all be.
Speaker 1: but I already have a vague idea.
Speaker 0: yep So Kinetic con is like a couple weeks before Otacon.
Speaker 0: you got this hammered out when oh god over a month ago.
Speaker 0: It's over a month ago.
Speaker 1: in fact they responded to me within 12 hours Every single time I've emailed them and in fact they out of the blue send me status updates on what's going on.
Speaker 0: All right, and didn't we just hear something from katsu-kun?
Speaker 1: Oh all right, so katsu-kun next year?
Speaker 1: Well one.
Speaker 1: we're subscribed to the state like the video game katsu staff email list because we're kind of staff for them And it was really fun.
Speaker 0: We're half members of game katsu.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and those guys are all awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Basically unlike.
Speaker 1: I don't know how other conventions work, but I do know that watching that mailing list They started planning next katsu-kun pretty much two weeks after katsu-kun ended And they've been continuously talking about it.
Speaker 1: and now well.
Speaker 1: They're already putting together the programming for katsu-kun.
Speaker 1: We're already working with them to get the programming done for katsu-kun Which is months and months and months away a long time from now.
Speaker 0: meanwhile?
Speaker 0: Otakon Perhaps our favorite card.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna name any names because I don't know how many of you work with these people, but I've emailed Otakon.
Speaker 1: I've sent dozens of emails to Otakon and various people in the past several years.
Speaker 1: Maybe
Speaker 0: that's oh in the several years
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's why
Speaker 0: they're not replying because you're emailing them to death,
Speaker 1: but this year I Anyone I've ever emailed within Otakon has not responded to me at all or if they did They responded with basically nothing or they said in fact at one point.
Speaker 1: I got an email saying oh well We'll get back with you shortly.
Speaker 1: We're almost done with whatever and then they just never follow up.
Speaker 0: It's like okay your con is the biggest and the baddest on the East Coast But if you don't get on the ball I think it's already on its way.
Speaker 0: it feels like it's.
Speaker 0: it's on the way down.
Speaker 0: now like I honestly all the other cons have bigger Badder events and they're on the ball and Otakon.
Speaker 1: I mean I hate to say it, but we're getting to the point where if they don't respond soon Even if they want us to do panels.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna prepare anything.
Speaker 1: We're not we can't.
Speaker 1: We've got too much else to do with other cons.
Speaker 0: now I know it's it's it's I might like and if they drop the ball too hard this year I could see in the future like it could be the doom of Otakon in a few years or Could be at least with me what might not even go.
Speaker 1: yeah meanwhile the New York anime festival Which a lot of people have maligned a little bit about being very corporate yeah
Speaker 0: Very skeptical about the New York anime festival to say because it was run by the same people's New York comic-con And it's gonna be for-profit It's gonna be the Javits Center.
Speaker 0: and those three things when added to Anime convention send off all the alarm bells and the brain of Scott saying warning warning major catastrophe coming to you soon.
Speaker 1: Well, we can't talk about it yet.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know if we can but I don't want to reveal anything.
Speaker 0: well Let me go see what they have said on their website.
Speaker 1: Yes suffice to say they.
Speaker 1: it seems like they've got their act together Really well and a lot better than anyone would have expected and I actually have high hopes for this convention now.
Speaker 1: plus When I talk talk to them about panels.
Speaker 1: we already the contracts done.
Speaker 1: We're doing panels there It's already all set up and this thing is until December.
Speaker 0: it December people.
Speaker 0: We actually have time to prepare things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know it's it's I don't want.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: cuz see I don't have access to the internal Otakon communications because it's a much more I guess closed Information can compared to other cons.
Speaker 0: so I could just be you know, making up stuff or it could be totally wrong.
Speaker 0: But my first this is my perception.
Speaker 0: I'm soft talking here and I don't speak for the truth of anything.
Speaker 0: But from going on Otakon message boards and proposing many suggestions for the con over the years Many times suggestions that were I think quite good suggestions.
Speaker 0: not all the time But sometimes we're always shot down as saying that will require too much F, you know physical manual labor.
Speaker 0: We don't have the people or the time or the manpower and I accepted that answer, you know as okay.
Speaker 0: You can't possibly do this unless you have a whole bunch of money to hire people to do it because it takes forever and whatever.
Speaker 0: But I really I get the feeling personally that the people who run Otakon at least some of them Someone who's doing something is not working as hard or as many hours for the con Outside of the actual hours of the con compared to other conventions, that's the feeling that I get.
Speaker 0: granted.
Speaker 1: I mean one don't forget Otakon is still our favorite con.
Speaker 0: It might not be but right now it still is.
Speaker 1: as of cons I've been to and two I mean, it's like all these cons.
Speaker 1: That's all volunteer work.
Speaker 1: So while you can't fault someone for not putting in.
Speaker 1: I don't know that like the super effort that we would put into something like That.
Speaker 1: yeah at the same time I have offered every year for the past three years to just handle panels for Otakon and join the staff and No one is.
Speaker 1: at once someone said yeah We'll get back with you and they never got back with me.
Speaker 1: and then in person at the con someone said yeah We'll email you and they never emailed me and I just gave up and I got to say of all the cons I've we've ever done panels with even in previous years.
Speaker 1: Otakon really doesn't Respond.
Speaker 1: well these panels that Otakon has never responded to emails in a timely manner and It's really hard to work with them to get a panel going.
Speaker 0: These people they need to remember if you're.
Speaker 0: I mean if I emailed.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I picked a random convention Akon, I guess that's I know that's a convention called Akon right if I emailed them today I would imagine that they would email me back tomorrow or within the week.
Speaker 1: at least that would be like and that would be actually Kind of bad in the very least if it was to a specific department.
Speaker 1: I mean if you just send an email to the con chair of Otakon.
Speaker 1: I don't expect the conjure of Otakon to respond to me.
Speaker 0: Like if I had a specific thing like, you know asking for some information or something that wasn't on their website I'm pretty sure they'd get back to me.
Speaker 0: Otakon just doesn't get back to people and that's a big problem.
Speaker 1: And uh, I just want that not to again not to name any names.
Speaker 1: But there's a couple other people who are staff or should be staff for Otakon who have expressed to me Independently that they have had a lot of hard time getting answers out of anyone else in the Otakon staff.
Speaker 1: and Even like the big panels that we do every year No one knows what's going on with them.
Speaker 1: and I'm at the point where I'm assuming that I'm not doing anything at Otakon this year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess all I can say left is we need to work on our communication.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: it just bothers me because Otakon is my favorite con and Yeah, I want it.
Speaker 1: I guess I feel like I I mean I'm not.
Speaker 1: I want to put my money where my mouth is because we kind of We panned Kineticon a little bit last year and Kineticon immediately got back with us and said all right hotshots.
Speaker 1: Well, uh, if that's how you feel then are you gonna help out?
Speaker 1: and we said damn straight.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's exactly right.
Speaker 0: And so now I you know Kineticon respect plus plus, you know You might my experience going to your convention as a guest last year might not have you know I meant everything I said and whatever podcast we reviewed it, but now you come up and you're like, all right You know, we're actually cool people, you know, we didn't.
Speaker 0: we can't do everything.
Speaker 0: Not everyone's perfect Not every conventions gonna be perfect and it's not gonna be perfect for everyone.
Speaker 0: But you know you you're talking shit All right, come on and so respect for them.
Speaker 0: But Otakon, you know, they put on this great convention that I enjoy a lot every year.
Speaker 1: But trying to interact with them not making me happy I mean, I just think I'll end it on this and I don't think this is negatistical thing to say.
Speaker 1: But I think that despite doing geek nights and my job and all the other things in my life I could probably handle the panels part of Otakon and respond to every email I got within 24 hours And I probably have all the panels set and done at least five months before the convention.
Speaker 1: In fact, I would require them to be well at least all the fan panels because I know it's hard.
Speaker 1: You got to coordinate with the industry people.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have the schedule of what time and what rooms but I would know You know exactly how many hours worth of panel programming I needed and I would have the people and their and what panels they were doing lined up well in advance
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: I would not allow that to change.
Speaker 0: unless you know, someone quit on me and I'd have backups too.
Speaker 0: I'd have like okay prepare your panel, but I can't guarantee it'll go on just in case someone else quits.
Speaker 1: yeah, well, I have a lot.
Speaker 1: I know exactly how we would run panels for Otakon or any convention and If Otakon would let us we do it.
Speaker 1: But until then we'll see what happens at Otakon because I don't know what we're doing.
Speaker 0: It's not be hilarious.
Speaker 0: He went to Otakon.
Speaker 0: There is no panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would be just I don't know.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I hate to say this and this is really mean to say but it'd be a lot like the previous Otakon.
Speaker 1: I mean not.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying that every panel at well every fan panel at Otakon last year was bad But everyone I attended was really really terrible like below what I would expect from even a mediocre Panel.
Speaker 1: at a con like this Otakon is too big to accept the bad panel.
Speaker 0: There might have been good ones that we you know, didn't attend.
Speaker 0: I guess that's possible.
Speaker 1: There were a few.
Speaker 1: I forget the names offhand, but our listeners did tell us about the one or two panels that were good.
Speaker 1: Yes,
Speaker 0: but if your convention is so big as Otakon the biggest anime convention on the East Coast you should have so many panel applications from so many people that you should be able to sift the wheat from the chaff and There's not that much hour, there's not that many hours of panels to actually fill in.
Speaker 0: It should be trivial to fill them in with the highest quality panel so that any panel room at any time is awesome.
Speaker 0: It just might not, you know fit someone's taste.
Speaker 0: I mean, I might not want to go to a super doll fee super doll fee panel But yeah, but you can have the best damn super doll fee panel in the country right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah team.
Speaker 0: So yeah, whatever Email us Otakon.
Speaker 1: What the hell's your problem?
Speaker 0: Email new invention.
Speaker 0: use it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I'm I don't want to get one.
Speaker 0: You click the reply button you get one.
Speaker 0: you click the reply button every time.
Speaker 1: in the very least.
Speaker 0: what I what you do is If you can't respond to the email like if I ask you like hey who's gonna be the musical guest, right?
Speaker 0: You don't just.
Speaker 0: you don't tell me because you can't tell me yet.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends.
Speaker 1: if you ask.
Speaker 1: if I was the con chair, I would ignore an email like that.
Speaker 0: I know I know but like if it was like a well-written professional email right not just like hey some punk kid going Who's the musical guest?
Speaker 0: OMG, right?
Speaker 0: But if a professional email comes in you don't just ignore it Even if it's asking for something you don't know or you can't tell you.
Speaker 0: say I regret to inform you blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: at this Time I cannot reveal that information.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: that way at least we know.
Speaker 0: fucking someone read it.
Speaker 1: That's all we want to know is that someone's reading it.
Speaker 0: Someone's paying attention Someone's is doing something, you know, I want to feel like my email didn't just go into the void.
Speaker 0: How do I know a spam filter didn't eat it?
Speaker 0: That's all we need.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess I put up with this for the last many years because I never really.
Speaker 1: I didn't work with many other conventions Until now and now that I've worked with a lot of other conventions I'm starting to see that every other convention is really easy to work with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just like hey, how you doing?
Speaker 1: You want to thank God?
Speaker 1: Toricon scheduled a panel for us without even asking us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the easiest to work with ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I think we're done with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no malice was meant of course But it is.
Speaker 0: it bridges state.
Speaker 1: our personal experience, yeah deep nights full of truthiness great But that aside it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: total cop-out, but the fact that it was on dig is kind of lucky because this is one moment in The Simpsons that for some reason is Oftquoted and very often just brought up in casual conversation in the front row crew.
Speaker 1: This exact scene just happened to be on dig today, so it's got to be my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I even want to explain what it is other than must crush.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: basically whenever Communism comes up in our group someone inevitably says must crush Capitalism or possibly.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: That's what we wanted you to think Yep, and here is where that came from.
Speaker 0: So now you are part of the inside joke as well and you can lift ten inside jokes.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day rim doesn't know about this at least.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure he doesn't know about this.
Speaker 0: I don't know you didn't but I think you'll be very interested in it.
Speaker 0: It is a recipe and it is a. it's not an Asian recipe.
Speaker 0: So the only way I could but I can relate it to anime day very loosely Because it is involving a rice cooker.
Speaker 0: Aha Here is a recipe on how to make something in a rice cooker.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: He's gonna.
Speaker 0: you know what this recipe tells you how to make it.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 0: I'll give you a hint.
Speaker 0: It's not rice.
Speaker 1: Uh, I'm gonna take make a few guesses.
Speaker 1: Uh sponge cake nope, um Stew nope, chili.
Speaker 0: No, uh Flan nope jello.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I'm out.
Speaker 0: bread just bread bread.
Speaker 0: You say here's a way to make bread in a rice cooker.
Speaker 0: You don't have a bread maker.
Speaker 0: You're afraid to use the oven.
Speaker 0: you want to use a nice safe rice cooker.
Speaker 0: Follow these easy steps at this, you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's actually a recipe.
Speaker 0: wiki place wiki how the how-to manual.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: We've got two rice cookers.
Speaker 1: We should take the old rice cooker and try to make bread in it because it certainly doesn't make.
Speaker 0: this guy made like this nice sort of Circular loaf of bread in his rice cooker.
Speaker 1: Was it the size and shape of the inside of a rice cooker?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not.
Speaker 0: it doesn't go up to the full height of the rice cooker.
Speaker 0: Ah, like.
Speaker 0: it's only like a couple inches high and it's circular like here.
Speaker 0: Look, it looks sort of like a like a cheese disc, huh?
Speaker 1: Only you cut out a wedge of it and eat it whenever we have a free weekend Which will be August at this point.
Speaker 1: I might try that.
Speaker 0: Yeah flour yeast sugar salt butter milk water rice cooker.
Speaker 0: So this is pretty cool for anyone out there with rice cooker.
Speaker 1: So we've done a lot of anime and everything lately and every now every time it's like every day that goes by where we don't Talk about comics the comic fans you listen to us Email us bit by bit asking us when we're gonna talk about comics again.
Speaker 1: So I think today's that day.
Speaker 0: Actually this comic we're gonna talk about is kind of funny it because I get lots of comics.
Speaker 0: I mean today how many comics came in the mail?
Speaker 1: Oh my god I came home and there was a box that was somewhat difficult to lift in the front porch.
Speaker 0: Yeah Basically, I pre-order comics two months in advance to get a huge discount.
Speaker 0: Like I get 75% off some things and I get mostly trades.
Speaker 0: It's like I'll get like a $20 comic like trade paperback for like $12.
Speaker 0: so pre-ordering two months in advance is totally worth it.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm planning to sell everything I'm never going to read again mostly to shave save shelf space and save money again because I do end up pre-ordering.
Speaker 0: I don't get to see what I'm buying before I buy it and sometimes I buy a bad comic most of the times I don't.
Speaker 0: yeah, sometimes I do.
Speaker 1: I mostly use it through Scott to get all of a given manga series that I really like Manga.
Speaker 0: I pre-order manga two months in advance.
Speaker 0: $10 manga for me is like seven dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah and change.
Speaker 1: So I got chromartie so I plan to get Emma.
Speaker 0: Yep So it's one comic I ordered because I had a whole bunch of hype and I read it and it was pretty good.
Speaker 0: So I usually if I think a comic is pretty good and not underwear pervert Which means rim will read it.
Speaker 0: then I'll like give it to him say hey read this sometime We'll do it on the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically Scott comes into my room You know while we're doing the show and then afterward He'll usually just plop a comic book on my desk or something or just leave it in my room.
Speaker 0: and Usually rim doesn't read it or he takes forever and he doesn't read the whole thing.
Speaker 1: It used to be that way because I didn't train to commute.
Speaker 1: So I really had no time to read manga.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but now that I take the train I grab a manga or a comic pretty much every day.
Speaker 0: So this was kind of amazing because I gave it to rim and like a day later.
Speaker 0: He had read the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I was kind of surprised too.
Speaker 1: I mean usually I pick him up flip him through him and then say alright I'll get to this.
Speaker 1: I'll put it at the end of the queue Which means it's never getting read.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my cue basically my cue not just my Netflix cue But my life cue has a few things in the front and a few things at the back and I just keep adding things to The middle but I never get to the middle because the middle keeps growing.
Speaker 1: Yep, but no I for some reason read it partly because it was one shot I knew that it would end and there wouldn't be more volumes of it.
Speaker 1: So if I liked it, I wouldn't be sucked into this trap of having to read it all like I was with Ex Machina.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Ex Machina is gonna end though.
Speaker 0: I think after like 50 issues.
Speaker 0: So there's only like a few more trades before it's over.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 1: But even so this I knew there's no commitment.
Speaker 1: I could pick it up put it down and also I'll admit the art was kind of bad.
Speaker 1: So I didn't have my usual problem where I tend to read some comics and some manga But not all manga at all comics Really slowly and generally the better the art is the slower I read it because I spent a lot of time admiring the art.
Speaker 0: Yeah, generally what I do is like I will admire art also in reading comics But like I don't admire the art in every panel like I'll admire just like the amazing panels like if I read Akira like there's certain panels like I know where they are because I've read the whole thing like seven times and Every time I get to them, I'll stop and look at them for like a minute But then as soon as I finish admiring it I'm like burning through the panels and pages and pages pages pages pages.
Speaker 0: But I will go back and admire the art when I'm not reading it like.
Speaker 0: I'll admire the art separately like I'll just open the book.
Speaker 1: Oh, I do that with sanctuary all the time.
Speaker 1: I'll just walk over there open a random sanctuary and flip to one of those two page spreads.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or death note.
Speaker 0: I do that sometimes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually like a lot of the like I have some DC books where actually I don't like them But this is really nice arts in them, and I'll just look at him.
Speaker 0: But yeah this book the art.
Speaker 0: You know it's not bad art.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: It doesn't detract.
Speaker 1: Don't get me wrong It doesn't detract at all from the story.
Speaker 0: It didn't say what the book is yet, and we're already oh We're doing a Dave and Joel here.
Speaker 1: I know did we talk about it yet, or did we say what it was?
Speaker 0: I think we did.
Speaker 0: I think it's time to do it now.
Speaker 0: alright.
Speaker 0: This book is called elks run.
Speaker 0: It is by Joshua Hale Fialkov and He I think he's the writer You know.
Speaker 1: I'll just say I had this horrible urge to in in the end after we're done with the show.
Speaker 1: Put the kill bill sound effect over you saying the name of it.
Speaker 0: yep, and the art is by Noel twas on and I'm pronouncing these names wrong probably.
Speaker 0: and Colors by Scott Keating lettered by Jason Hanley.
Speaker 0: chapter title art by Datsun Tran edited by Jason Rodriguez.
Speaker 1: Did you say dr.
Speaker 1: Tran?
Speaker 0: no, but that was close.
Speaker 0: It was Datsun Tran.
Speaker 1: That's is a good name.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 0: It is published by Villard books.
Speaker 0: Which is actually.
Speaker 0: I looked up Villard books.
Speaker 0: It's Villard books is basically Random House.
Speaker 0: That's what it is.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's just a thing.
Speaker 0: They're putting on like a lot of like.
Speaker 0: they're actually buying up a lot of cool hip graphic novels like this and Publishing them which is pretty awesome Right.
Speaker 1: so it's a story Basically about an insular community that is created by what Vietnam War veterans I think they're war veterans of some sort.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 1: It's the Michigan militia.
Speaker 1: It's that idea.
Speaker 1: the people who the super survivalists the people who say this country is corrupt or going down the tubes are dangerous or whatever.
Speaker 1: We're true patriots.
Speaker 1: so we're going
Speaker 0: to live in
Speaker 1: the mountains in our own closed community entirely self-reliant with the real Constitution and When the commies eventually come we'll be the ones to hold out or you know That sort of thing the not really a cult so much as just a very very Introverted Introspective closed-off community.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I choice and not by any other reason.
Speaker 0: Yep So you have this this group of people maybe some hundred people or so Maybe a few hundred it's hard to tell and they decide to set up a town in Elks Ridge in the middle of fuck nowhere Where no one was an elks run?
Speaker 0: No, I think I think it's Elks Ridge the town of Elks Ridge In West Virginia.
Speaker 0: All right, elks run is the name of the book.
Speaker 0: Ah yes, and It's basically impossible to get in or out of the town except through this tunnel.
Speaker 0: So and the town sort of takes care of itself Except as a guy who drives into the town with a truck full of supplies every week or so Yep, and even does that under the table in cash.
Speaker 1: So there's no record in the government anywhere that this town exists.
Speaker 0: Yep, and these people live in seclusion very happily on their own with their crazy ways.
Speaker 0: They're not really that crazy in their ways You know at least as far as you can tell at the beginning of the book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it definitely starts in this really kind of idyllic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is kind of working.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know, it's mostly the story starts to focus on the kids who live in this town.
Speaker 1: See now think of this.
Speaker 1: these people decide that they want this community.
Speaker 1: All right, they bring their wives.
Speaker 1: All right, the wives are now in on it, but no one's allowed to leave like that's.
Speaker 1: one of the big rules They have is like no one come no one goes out.
Speaker 1: No one comes in.
Speaker 1: It's completely cut off.
Speaker 1: They don't want any contact with the outside world because it'll corrupt the kids or whatever.
Speaker 1: But even so it's still a choice.
Speaker 1: now you've got kids being born here who realize that there's an outside world and Realize that something weird is kind of like.
Speaker 1: this is kind of a weird place to be living.
Speaker 1: But yet what are they gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: their kids?
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly, you know You've got the way they make it really frustrating is that like the main characters is teenage boy And there's no girls in town like this.
Speaker 0: one girl in town Maybe and she's like way older than he is like to wear it out in.
Speaker 0: like normal world.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't even like consider each other but because they're the only she's the only girl.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like a and that That that talk about frustrating, you know being forced to live in a closed community.
Speaker 0: There are no girls here.
Speaker 0: that there just aren't any.
Speaker 0: it's not that you can't get one.
Speaker 0: You're some nerd It's there aren't any and you can't leave to go find some and none will come in.
Speaker 1: now I don't want to ruin any because it's a one-shot, you know one story.
Speaker 1: I don't want to ruin any of the story in this.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: think it was originally eight comic book issues and this trade paperback for 1995 manufacturers to just retail price is all eight of those issues in a row with a little bit of fun stuff at the beginning like a little introduction page and a little Is there a prologue page in the back?
Speaker 0: There's an afterword in the back.
Speaker 1: Basically the story without revealing much is that I mean?
Speaker 1: the community is kind of weird and there is tension.
Speaker 1: I mean despite the fact that it seems very ideal and very happy there is tension among many of the people in this community, but it's all kind of below the surface and a small thing happens and the small thing sets into motion a chain of events that Basically inexorably drives the town toward getting into this out-of-control Situation where everything starts to break down and all the things that were under the surface start exploding out.
Speaker 1: and it's just an escalation from beginning to end.
Speaker 1: but the pace of the book is such that Everything is constantly at every moment getting more and more intense more and more out of control more and more difficult to deal with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it definitely.
Speaker 0: it feels pretty awesome just to read it because you you know You keep turning the pages at the same rate and things are just getting Exponentially worse and crazier and worse and crazier and worse.
Speaker 0: and it it's.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like you're on this ride and you can't stop it.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like really this is really off the wall.
Speaker 1: But it's kind of like watching the movie strange days Because strange days starts out very slow kind of a mystery detectives police whatever and the.
Speaker 1: it's the pace of the story Just accelerates and accelerates and accelerates and the plot just gets more and more and more out of control.
Speaker 1: Until you gave you get to the end of the movie you you kind of lose track of just how far you've come.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the books the same way.
Speaker 1: by the end of this you're in a place that you never would have expected this book to Go, I've never seen strange days.
Speaker 0: I don't even know what it is.
Speaker 0: But I really ace is also similar to that of Falling down.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: This is a lot like falling down only without.
Speaker 1: well You know what.
Speaker 1: the guy and falling down is a little bit like the dead in hooks run Actually just a tiny bit.
Speaker 0: dad and elks run.
Speaker 0: obviously I do not like.
Speaker 0: no the guy in falling down You can kind of go along with like where he's coming from.
Speaker 0: the dad and elks run is just wow your bad.
Speaker 1: well, I think the main difference is at the end of falling down the guy realizes when he says I'm the bad guy and In this the dead basically says I'm still right.
Speaker 0: I'm still right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically.
Speaker 0: Oh, we're not spoiling too much I don't think we really are.
Speaker 0: I don't think cuz I think even if we told you everything that happened And we're not gonna say specifically things that happen So you won't be really spoiled.
Speaker 0: But even if we told you the point of reading this I think is is the ride along the way and not so much Figure.
Speaker 0: it's not like a figuring it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz the one thing that really draws me.
Speaker 0: It's like being on a roller coaster.
Speaker 0: It's not a mystery that you're gonna get to the bottom of the hill scream a lot and then go up the next hill.
Speaker 0: It's all about.
Speaker 0: we're going down the hill real fast Ain't going whoo?
Speaker 1: but what really grabbed me is that you know, it's a roller coaster ride and all that but it draws you in and It gets to a point where if you're used to reading comics or manga or books or anything you feel like alright I know where this is gonna go I know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: like an event happens and after that event you think alright, they're gonna react to it in this way but then no one's gonna do anything and then this is gonna be remembered later.
Speaker 1: and then something, you know, and Basically the characters aren't stupid and the situation progresses very rapidly and every character just immediately does If not what I would do at least something that makes sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the situation progresses.
Speaker 0: there were a few times where they had that symptom of you know, like, oh, why don't you just do this?
Speaker 0: Ah, and it doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: and I'm a little upset even though it might happen later earlier.
Speaker 0: It just doesn't happen in like the exact way I wanted to.
Speaker 1: yeah But at least part of that is that they are kids and they really don't know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't happen in a way that just makes me put the book down and say fuck this shit that's just stupid but it's just.
Speaker 1: I expected a few tedious parts of the story to appear because they set themselves up like every other piece of media does where if this kind of thing happens then there's this kind of scene or this series of scenes before it's resolved and they basically Skip right over that and cut to the chase.
Speaker 0: I think what it is also is that whenever a thing happens instead of having the typical Expected series of scenes to resolve it.
Speaker 0: It's just the worst possible consequence immediately pops out Yeah, and then something out and then then you have to resolve that with the worst possible consequence.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's one answer the other.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like how Rome fell in that there was no one factor that made Rome fall.
Speaker 1: There's no one factor that made what happens in this comic happen.
Speaker 1: It's that all these little things and all these stupid accidents just kind of all happened at the wrong time And as a result the whole thing just gets out of control.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's mostly a combination of you know certain people have certain feelings and then certain opportunities arise and everyone sort of acts in their own interest and People are trying to control other people and they can't.
Speaker 1: and you know people get pissed off and then ah shit Yep, because if and if you look at it the whole thing stems back from like one of the first scenes.
Speaker 1: I mean all this starts when the kids.
Speaker 1: they aren't even trying they're not like they're trying to escape or anything.
Speaker 1: They just kind of go into the tunnel to hang out at night And then things just go out of control from that.
Speaker 1: keep saying out of control sort of like an Archduke Ferdinand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except the Prussians don't come and save the day in this one.
Speaker 1: No, no, I don't think save the day is the operative word for the Prussians did either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah the art in the book I mean, it's not like it's not something you're gonna sit in awe and look at like whoa.
Speaker 0: Look at that art.
Speaker 1: No, it's very functional art.
Speaker 1: It serves the purpose you get what's going on.
Speaker 1: It doesn't stand out, but it doesn't detract either.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean, it's not like, you know, it's it's not bad.
Speaker 0: Like I'm looking at it and I'm like, oh, that's terrible I can't even look at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like that, but the characters get really off model a lot all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah I do notice a few things though that like there's really good Like coloring going on like they're out in the woods like you have all these bright colors and actually they'll draw the characters like with cleaner lines a lot more like a Newspaper comic strip and then like when things are all darkened in the tunnel they'll like sort of paint everyone with this really dark like washes and things and It definitely they do things with the art to go with the mood and enhance the storytelling.
Speaker 0: but it's not art that is so Amazing and attractive to the eye that you want to put a poster on your wall because it's some amazing thing.
Speaker 1: Also, they do something interesting where there's a few there's a section in the middle where there's a bunch of flashbacks to the kids When they were younger kids before before they kind of realized what was going on and it's basically Archie at that point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, it startled me for a second because when I first whenever I read a comic especially a one-off I always kind of flip through it just to get a sense of it before I read it.
Speaker 1: So I flipped through this and I opened to a random page and I see all this Archie and that really threw off my Expectations for what this was about.
Speaker 0: that'll super throw you off.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 1: It is not about that.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess it could be about that if Archie was actually a serial killer at the whole time and he never realized it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean yeah, that would make Archie awesome.
Speaker 1: It would think about that.
Speaker 0: Okay, it does show you how they change the style of art to serve the story as opposed to Serving awesome amazing art or anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus the wind is fire.
Speaker 0: the way they get the fire in there.
Speaker 0: The fire looks really cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah I must say the way it's painted in there and I gotta say the art does do work very well at the end because there Is a scene like near the end.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like the end of Lord of the Flies.
Speaker 1: Well, remember you actually know anything about Lord of the Flies did the same thing Where the story starts out very slow and methodical and the pace of the bad things that are happening are Just increasing and increasing and increasing and brings you to this feverish pace.
Speaker 1: And then the end of Lord of the Flies is suddenly all the I'm gonna ruin Lord of the Flies.
Speaker 1: Oh shit statute of limitations.
Speaker 1: I think all the kids spill
Speaker 0: out
Speaker 1: and there's an adult standing there because he's on the island and suddenly like the cameras just zoomed in and everything's going so fast and suddenly the camera zooms out and you're back in the real world and You're back in normal time and there's this moment of Wow, I came this far this story came this far and you finally get a moment of relief when things finally get resolved and It's a very palpable moment of relief.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah Another thing is I think the story has the way it's painted and stuff.
Speaker 0: The lighting is actually really cool.
Speaker 0: It is it is it's you know, the characters are drawn kind of like not the greatest designs in the universe.
Speaker 0: I mean you can recognize which character is which but there's not like super facial expressions going on or anything.
Speaker 0: But when there's lights and things it's always like the contrast is like, ooh, look at that You know You can tell like light shining through in caves and shining through windows and all different colors of light.
Speaker 0: It works pretty well All right.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also, I'll just point out that I guess the moral or the lesson learned from this is Pretty much right along my thinking.
Speaker 1: it was definitely a validation of things that I believe.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Definitely whatever this comic is trying to say whatever you think whatever you think is trying to say after you read it I mean I can tell you what I think is trying to say Well, as long as you don't think yeah those fucking kids.
Speaker 1: It's all their fault.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as long as you don't think that but Yeah, it is definitely Agreeable, you know and it's also because it's so agreeable.
Speaker 0: It's like the guy riding it knows what I think and he thinks the same thing.
Speaker 0: So he purposely puts things in that like especially in the earlier parts that like piss him off and he knows they'll piss me off.
Speaker 1: Yep There's a lot of little bits little knits where a Character does or says something and it just goes.
Speaker 1: so against everything that I believe in everything that I am and it's obvious that he's very Deliberately vilifying the characters that he wants you to not like.
Speaker 1: He
Speaker 0: basically makes the people so He vilifies them so perfectly that it's like an instant bad guy Like you'll read like a superhero comic and they'll be like this evil looking dark guy who's fighting the superhero And you won't hate that guy even 1,000th as much as you hate some of the people in this thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like Magneto.
Speaker 0: Hey, you can be kind of cool Magneto I feel sorry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like The man yeah, but like the normal guy on the street.
Speaker 0: and this is like fuck you asshole God damn that guy.
Speaker 0: I hope he dies right now.
Speaker 0: I hope he dies before he was even in the book at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah I gotta say there are some characters that when they get if and when certain characters get what's coming to them I actually stopped and in a moment, I thought it's about time damn straight.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, and it's only eight issues.
Speaker 0: So, you know, even though you might be suffering for like maybe 20 minutes You'll read this whole thing in one shot and you'll you at the end.
Speaker 0: you won't be a roller coaster.
Speaker 1: It pulls you to the top it throws you down and then it's over and you're walking back to the car.
Speaker 0: Yep So yeah elks run by Joshua Hale.
Speaker 0: the alcohol from Villard books $20 about.
Speaker 1: it is well worth purchasing.
Speaker 0: I probably get it on Amazon.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend it Yep, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.