Speaker 1:
Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, May 30th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek night Tonight.
Speaker 0: we continue getting into it week with getting into anime.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So at long last.
Speaker 0: the saga of rims computer is nearing its conclusion.
Speaker 0: not gonna talk about it.
Speaker 0: suffice to say Ahead Scott not had the good grace to decide to drive me up to buy another power supply just now.
Speaker 0: I Would probably not be doing the show because I'd just be stewing in my own anger and Instead we're here really late starting the show at like 10.
Speaker 1: So it's gonna be a quick show cuz best of all.
Speaker 0: we thought Oh, we'll just eat on the way home.
Speaker 0: But all the quick food places that weren't fast food were closed because it was late, and we're not in New York City We're upstate where everything closes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so yeah, I really got to keep shit open.
Speaker 1: if they want to make money
Speaker 0: I really miss the days when I was in college And if it was 2 45 in the morning And I wanted some falafel or a chicken pita I could go to the pita pit and get it and then get a fresh doughnut right next door at the Krispy Kreme.
Speaker 1: Yep, those are the days.
Speaker 0: those were good days.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: Let's get right into it here cuz I can go to bed.
Speaker 1: news.
Speaker 1: Anime Expo a convention.
Speaker 1: We've never been to that.
Speaker 1: we often say not the greatest things about even though We've never been there.
Speaker 0: granted We've said not the greatest things about a great many conventions in the past.
Speaker 0: So it's no really big skin off of anime Expos back Yeah But it is the biggest anime convention in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Even though the actual size of it may be up for debate it is the biggest and they have announced Possibly the biggest event ever.
Speaker 0: I mean before this.
Speaker 0: I think that the lark concert at Otakon was probably one of the biggest just in terms of the the sheer Excitement.
Speaker 0: and how many people came to Otakon just to see them and how many people flew from Japan to Baltimore?
Speaker 0: Just to see them in Baltimore.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, there is a new band I'm pretty sure it's new that is going to perform at anime Expo on June 29th 2007. the band is called skin the four members of the band.
Speaker 1: I only know two of them, but the fact that I know two of them is kind of crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott doesn't listen to so much of the j-pop or the well most of the j-rock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the two band members.
Speaker 1: I do not know are Sugi's oh and Miyabi.
Speaker 0: so I know Miyabi.
Speaker 1: Who is that?
Speaker 1: Popular, okay, the other two members of the band that I do know are gagged, you know, who's gagged?
Speaker 0: Yeah No No I'll point out that gagged by like just the gagged alone Would have been a big deal and a lot of people would have been really excited about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a crazy awesome guy.
Speaker 1: and Yoshiki who was at Otakon right but didn't actually perform there.
Speaker 0: if I didn't actually see him I'm pretty sure it was there.
Speaker 1: You've got.
Speaker 1: those four people have combined to make one band.
Speaker 1: It's like Man, it's sort of like imagine if I don't know like John John bottom and John and May be Hendrix and it's bad.
Speaker 1: It's like an all-star band in a way and I'm pretty sure this is their first performance ever at anime Expo in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Which is Stupidly crazy.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine how we should have a betting pool And how many people at anime Expo are going to be Japanese?
Speaker 0: Citizens who have flown to America for this concert and this concert alone.
Speaker 1: I bet at least a thousand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least and that's a pretty conservative estimate here.
Speaker 1: They're any conservative probably 2000.
Speaker 1: But yeah, this is crazy.
Speaker 1: There's not much else I can say about it, except it's absolutely insane.
Speaker 1: I think you should be aware of it, especially for on the west coast.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be surprised if the Generally extremely warm reception that Japanese bands get when they come to the u.s.
Speaker 0: And perform at conventions is not pushing more of the bigger names to want to come to the u.s.
Speaker 0: To do concerts.
Speaker 1: It could be could be and better for us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though they still don't quite get that Americans aren't willing to pay, you know, $35 for a CD But you know what?
Speaker 1: Otakon still has not announced his musical acts if I am correct, and it just might be the same They might come across.
Speaker 0: who know is that that your speculation?
Speaker 1: That's it's a slight speculation.
Speaker 0: I don't stand by that speculation.
Speaker 1: However, were that the case I give it a 20% chance.
Speaker 1: I don't know what I do because Otakon is already pretty bad as even though they never answer my goddamn emails Yeah, Otakon the biggest best convention on the East Coast doesn't answer email But the tiny-ass conventions they answer the email right away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, honestly though, it's not.
Speaker 0: I mean I can't say like oh, it's just this year.
Speaker 0: Otakon has never really gotten back with me.
Speaker 1: That's Otakon's number one problem.
Speaker 1: It's like they seem to do everything else.
Speaker 1: Well, except answer people's email.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean God the New York anime festival Which isn't gonna be until December and hasn't really got anything together yet at all and is super corporate.
Speaker 0: They got back with me immediately.
Speaker 0: Like Every time I email them they respond immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Connecticut's the same way.
Speaker 0: Anime next.
Speaker 1: so it's not just because Otakon's fan run they can't respond to email their fan run conventions that respond to the email.
Speaker 1: It's just Otakon.
Speaker 0: granted anime next didn't respond either, but I only tried once through a web form.
Speaker 1: and yeah You can't go through a web form But if you actually email an actual person and that person is the person and they don't reply that's a problem.
Speaker 0: Well, honestly the reason I didn't follow up with anime next was that after the sheer amount of crap we're doing at Kineticon and the New York anime festival and Theoretically Otakon.
Speaker 0: I'm not actually sure anymore But I don't know if I'm really prepared vocally physically to do Kineticon and Otakon and anime Next all in the same stint.
Speaker 1: Yeah, besides I was only planning even if we were doing stuff at anime next.
Speaker 1: I was only planning to go for like, you know The day on Saturday or look at the schedule see what's happening and pick the day with the best event to go to Or something like that, you know, maybe it'll be Sunday.
Speaker 0: Who knows but yeah We're probably to talk about anime Expo a little bit more in another episode in the news because looking at their website They've definitely kicked it up a notch this year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and while I don't know if previous things you've said about the convention are true or false because we've never been there However, most of those are based on firsthand accounts from people we know.
Speaker 1: Yes, but looking at the list of things that they're doing at the next anime next anime Expo at the end of this month It's looking like something I would definitely want to be at the based on the events alone.
Speaker 0: The only problem with going to the anime Expo.
Speaker 1: It's on the other side of the country.
Speaker 0: No, no that's not.
Speaker 0: that's not really the big issue because I love the East Coast and there's only really three things on the West Coast that Really pull me out that way and they're momentary things transient things like the San Diego Comic Con.
Speaker 0: But If I'm going to go to the West Coast for a convention It's not going to be for anything but packs, which is probably in terms of desire to go Versus I don't know.
Speaker 0: pain felt by not going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to go to penny arcade Expo more than I want to go to any convention and yet it's just so inconvenient to Go, it's always at the worst time.
Speaker 0: It's so far away.
Speaker 1: I was going to go to anime Expo, right?
Speaker 1: That would mean that I'm already going to packs and I'm still willing to go to the West Coast again.
Speaker 1: And then if I was gonna go to the San Diego Comic Con it would be because I'm willing to go to the West Coast three times in one summer.
Speaker 1: You know and it's like, you know, sure you might say why don't you go to one one summer?
Speaker 1: One the next summer and one the next summer.
Speaker 1: Well if I was going to do that I would go to packs packs and packs.
Speaker 0: Yes, because When the first packs happen, I thought oh, I wish I could go to that But I didn't really think anything of it because I would con is frickin amazing Like Otakon is my still my Becca when it comes to geekery.
Speaker 1: But then we saw what happened at the first packs.
Speaker 1: We saw the aftermath.
Speaker 0: Yeah because packs is just.
Speaker 0: I think it's the best geek convention out there because It's up.
Speaker 0: It's not really
Speaker 1: and I can tell just from looking at what happens there based on Report because packs
Speaker 0: is doing for video game cons and webcomic cons what Otakon and all the big anime Video
Speaker 1: game kind
Speaker 0: but wallets a video game con, you know with It's effectively a geek con.
Speaker 0: a lot of people go who aren't super into video games.
Speaker 0: I mean how many people read penny arcade who don't actually play a lot of video games penny arcade.
Speaker 0: Just that funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of people but they at least know about video games.
Speaker 0: Yeah Or at least you're there in that geeky kind of culture.
Speaker 1: Let's hurry up.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway I'm really not gonna bother doing the news because I want to get to the main bit and the motherboard that for the first time since The May 7th when I ordered it It
Speaker 1: wouldn't boot with the fancy and tech power supply, but it boots with a piece of shit overpriced Best Buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I went and bought like one of those off-brand Crappy power supplies and it works.
Speaker 1: just the best thing Best Buy had.
Speaker 0: yes Well sadly Best Buy advertise better things that apparently they don't actually carry.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we'll get right to the chase here things of the day Since we're moving along right quick here.
Speaker 0: I'm sure many of you are aware of this But it's possible that you aren't and even if you aren't it's doubtful.
Speaker 0: Well even if you are it's doubtful that you probably Spent the amount of time watching these things that we did in college Particularly late at night.
Speaker 0: when there was we were bored.
Speaker 0: the night was winding down.
Speaker 1: well in the days before YouTube Right you had actual little video clips that you would download and store on your computer Yeah, and had a folder full of funny clips every person had like their personal collection.
Speaker 0: It was like everyone had their own Equivalent of anime hell on their person and whenever you're at someone's house and obviously it's college So you know 3 a.m.. Rolls around you've run out of stuff to talk about.
Speaker 0: you Don't feel like playing games anymore.
Speaker 1: some guy opens up his miscellaneous video folder and plays everything.
Speaker 0: so you watch puddle jumper And you watch.
Speaker 0: but hot dog and you watch chaos 9000 or death cast 9000. all those things.
Speaker 0: yep, and one of the things that I was in my collection were all of the Celebrity Jeopardy skits from Saturday Night Live which is still in my opinion the best of Saturday Night Live ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well except for the Blues Brothers.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's it, but that's indirectly out of Saturday Night Live.
Speaker 0: Yes anyway of Those I think Sean Connery or Sean Connery the character was perhaps the funniest bit and someone's made.
Speaker 0: and as an SNL compilation of all the Sean Connery bits from all of the SNL Celebrity Jeopardy bits, I'll take the rapist for 900 It'll rue the day truck back yeah.
Speaker 1: So that sounds pretty good to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: We will do a show on that or something I don't know on that.
Speaker 1: one thing.
Speaker 0: well show on I don't know comedy we like.
Speaker 1: oh It could be a good show on that.
Speaker 0: cuz we talk of Monty Python I talk about SNL talk about stand-up comedians the whole thing alright.
Speaker 1: It's just like a good Thursday alright, but watch this video.
Speaker 0: It's funny especially Especially if you've never seen these before.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm all right.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Here's something that's pretty funny.
Speaker 1: I was gonna save this until we did a Pokemon show, but I'll just use it now cuz I'm lazy.
Speaker 1: You might know that Pokemon is a game and it is an RPG and it does have leveling Special take and it does have the grind which I am not a fan of.
Speaker 1: if you have heard me rant about World of Warcraft And is grind I do not like the grind never mind the spelling error.
Speaker 0: Yeah That I'm not gonna talk about it yet on the show.
Speaker 0: If anyone out there will point out the spelling error in the new Pokemon or the old Pokemons I'll be thankful, but it pisses me off to the point that I feel dirty playing the game.
Speaker 1: wow That's pretty rough.
Speaker 0: It really bothers me when I run into something like that in a video game especially a Nintendo game Except for old Nintendo games with bad localizations, but that's different right now.
Speaker 1: The only reason I say Pokemon is playable is because it is the grind with a little bit on the side that makes it actually Not a grind, but there's also the fact that unlike a lot of MMOs Pokemon does have Extensive endgame combat.
Speaker 0: well combat content that content being the cockfighting on the internet or the cockfighting with friends at conventions Which is the only reason not entirely a battle of who has higher level stuff.
Speaker 0: also There's nothing more fun and social than what I expect will be happening at Otacon this year when I whip out my Pokemons Ronder it around and fight with 12 year old kids with their Pokemons.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that's what makes Pokemon acceptable despite its grinding which is not pleasant, but yeah I mean if World of Warcraft is below the line Pokemon is so barely above the line.
Speaker 1: It's just barely above the line.
Speaker 1: But here's a guy who has found a way to solve at least some of the grinding problem in Pokemon.
Speaker 1: You might know that in Pokemon there are certain Pokemons which will evolve only when they are very happy.
Speaker 1: So you have like a Golbat, and it won't turn into a Crobat until it really loves you.
Speaker 0: I had no idea about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah And one way to make Pokemon love you is to carry them around and keep walking.
Speaker 1: well the other way is illegal in most states Yes, but if you keep spending time with Pokemon they will fall in love with you, and they will like you very much.
Speaker 1: So what this guy did is there's a gym leader in the game and in this gym leaders gymnasium There are these arrows on the ground which will force you to move in certain directions.
Speaker 1: So he went to this gym and he found a good position and he took two wrenches and he held down the down arrow and the B button on his DS light and plug the DS into the wall.
Speaker 1: and Basically by doing this he was able to force his character to walk infinitely and thus Over the course of a few hours while he went away and actually you know spent time doing real things lived his real life Lived his real life.
Speaker 1: He was able to evolve six Pokemon, huh?
Speaker 0: That I guess that epitomizes everything that's wrong about games like Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is why grinding is bad.
Speaker 1: if it's just a matter of spending time holding down buttons What the fuck is the point in making a person do that?
Speaker 1: I don't understand, but the people who design such a mechanic into a game or thinking it's fine more and more.
Speaker 1: I wish I even understand less people who actually do this sort of thing Manually.
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: what kind of lives are they living where they have nothing better to do than hold down two buttons and wait?
Speaker 0: Granted at least Pokemon sets it up so that it's very easy to play Pokemon while living your normal life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I'll just sit there while I'm doing just about anything to level these stupid things up.
Speaker 1: I think that is.
Speaker 1: the main difference with Pokemon is that it's such like a side.
Speaker 1: It's like you could do it out of the corner of your eye.
Speaker 1: You just carry it around with you with like one hand on it.
Speaker 0: Just pushing buttons without looking I mean and look at us playing Wesnoth.
Speaker 0: It's me Alex and Scott.
Speaker 0: We're playing Wesnoth.
Speaker 0: We're all also playing Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Yep, whereas World of Warcraft seems to be a thing that demands your entire attention or at least more attention than Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess the people are really really play a lot of Wow.
Speaker 0: I know for a fact that they tend to watch movies and stuff in the corner while they're playing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but a movie is something I like to get full attention to also, so I don't know.
Speaker 0: yeah, well, maybe a crap movie or something I've seen before or Like a Simpsons.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah something like that a day killer even so worked.
Speaker 1: We're older.
Speaker 1: Warcraft demands more attention to Pokemon and Pokemon is barely over the line and World of Warcraft is under the line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, barely under the line because it's better than all those other MMOs.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: It is above all the other MMOs, but still not enough.
Speaker 1: Pokemon is almost so bad It's unplayable, but it makes it over.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that more in our poke.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we will because the fact that I'm playing Pokemon says a lot because I hate games like that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and Pokemon infuriates me slightly less than it entertains me.
Speaker 1: Yep Sums it up right there.
Speaker 1: All right, so the meat of the show gonna do this quick All right It's still getting into it week the week in which we tell you how to get into various geekeries or get your friends into Various geek.
Speaker 0: you might remember last Wednesday when we talked about how to get into a throat infection.
Speaker 0: Oh, right Yes, right Scott is just starting to recover from it.
Speaker 0: I'm fine.
Speaker 1: I didn't have a throat.
Speaker 0: Well, no you had the nose infection.
Speaker 0: Yep, I had.
Speaker 1: basically I'm at the stage where my head is full of mucus and I can't get it out.
Speaker 0: I think you should take one more Nyquil and then you'll be fine.
Speaker 1: There's no more Nyquil left.
Speaker 1: drank it One dose left cuz I drank most of that bottle when I was sick, yeah Well today we're gonna tell you what we didn't tell you to get into last week.
Speaker 1: It's how to get into the a-nives.
Speaker 1: I've noticed a lot of people who became geek nights listeners because they like the video games or the board games or you know They like the the technology and then they crossed over into the anime from listening to the anime nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually in general a lot of people email us constantly saying hey Listen for the one day, but then you got me into something else and I guess that's great because that's what we're really a proponent of.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean we're geeks and Geekery is a really broad thing.
Speaker 0: I mean there's sports geeks and there are athletics geeks and there's everything geek you star geek Yeah, and the fact it's not just video games and anime.
Speaker 0: However for all of you out there who are not anime geeks It's very easy to get into anime.
Speaker 1: I think that's why a lot of people have got like a lot of people weren't able to get into Like role-playing or German board game easily.
Speaker 1: So we they really need an episode from us to help out.
Speaker 1: they need to really need it a Linux episode to help out.
Speaker 1: But anime is kind of easy to get into.
Speaker 1: thus we can do this episode quickly and thus Many people who listen to the show have already gotten into it without our specific help.
Speaker 0: now what I wanted to say first And this is before we go into anything else This is kind of important and it's a distinction that really needs to be noted.
Speaker 0: A lot of people make the mistake of thinking that anime is somehow a genre.
Speaker 0: Anime is nothing more than a medium So a lot of people who don't know anything about anime Will hear about it and have some sort of opinion based on what they've heard before.
Speaker 1: Oh anime is all that crazy violent Super gory stuff that kids should be watching.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all anime is that Japanese cartoon porn?
Speaker 1: or all anime is that cutesy wootsie big eyes small mouth?
Speaker 1: Bullshitty crap.
Speaker 0: Yep, or it's all the seizure robots of the pokemons or whatever.
Speaker 1: Ah, guess what?
Speaker 1: It's all those things and more.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean I actually got a fair number of people back when I worked at IBM into anime and Once I mean, all you have to do is explain to people and as we're explaining to you Don't think of it.
Speaker 0: Like anime is different from any other movie.
Speaker 0: It's the same as any movie you've ever seen or any TV show you've ever seen.
Speaker 0: It just happens to have been made in a foreign country and it just happens to be animated Instead of filmed with people and it happens to be originally cast in a foreign language.
Speaker 0: Well, I said it was foreign.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, I mean you this anime that are about science fiction.
Speaker 1: They're anime that are about crazy stupid fighting.
Speaker 0: There's horror anime.
Speaker 1: There's This comedy there's everything and whatever your taste is there is you know, you might not like one anime or another.
Speaker 1: But there's probably for every person who enjoys watching video.
Speaker 1: There's probably an anime out there for them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there are a lot of people who would like to say something like oh, I hate anime I hate all this anime crap.
Speaker 1: That's like saying I hate movies or I hate books.
Speaker 0: I hate.
Speaker 1: yeah There's a book out there you like.
Speaker 1: you might really not like complicated books But I'm sure there's like some Star Wars.
Speaker 0: now You'll enjoy and it's nothing and it's not like if you.
Speaker 0: and by the same token if I like anime It doesn't mean like all anime.
Speaker 1: I hate most anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 0: So did Dave and Joel.
Speaker 0: So anime world order much.
Speaker 1: any anime fan hates most anime.
Speaker 0: In fact, if anything anime fans probably hate most anime more than non anime fans.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, probably but say or at least their hate is targeted or known as opposed to a generic, you know, not accurate Hate.
Speaker 1: it's a very real hate.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So bear that in mind if you have ever thought that you wouldn't like anime for any reason at all.
Speaker 0: That reasons probably BS because there's no unifying characteristic of anime other than that.
Speaker 0: It happens to be animated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you might say oh, I hate that cutesy crap.
Speaker 1: Well, I also hate most of the cutesy animes.
Speaker 1: not all of them But most of them and you might not like cutesy animes if you don't.
Speaker 1: there's plenty of non cutesy anime You just don't know about and haven't experienced and you're just being you know closed-minded and avoiding it.
Speaker 0: now to the other Excuse.
Speaker 0: a lot of people like to bring up is they'll say something like well I don't like the culture around anime or I don't like anime fans or I don't like anime conventions.
Speaker 0: I don't like all and something about anime.
Speaker 0: that isn't it.
Speaker 1: Well who says you have to do any of those things?
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean most people who watch anime don't go to anime cons don't post in anime forums don't have anime merchandise.
Speaker 0: They watch anime in the same way that people out there watch 24 or American Idol or boondock Saints.
Speaker 1: They just watch Adult Swim and they like it.
Speaker 1: and that's that they don't you know.
Speaker 1: Maybe they'll buy a DVD now and then or Netflix a series if they miss some episodes on TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who knows?
Speaker 0: so don't Decide you're not gonna get into anime Just because you don't like the people who are into anime because those people have nothing to do with you.
Speaker 0: Just watch your movie and don't worry about that.
Speaker 0: Yep So all that aside the biggest problem with getting into anime is that if you ask an anime fan the average man on the street As was evidenced in our forum.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm new to anime.
Speaker 0: I'm game.
Speaker 0: What should I watch?
Speaker 1: Well, depending on who you ask you might get a sarcastic answer.
Speaker 1: They might say oh go watch Orochika Doji, which is not something anyone needs to watch or they'll say oh go watch my favorite show.
Speaker 1: My favorite show is Excel Saga and there's some crazy anime fans.
Speaker 1: You don't you're not gonna like their favorite show.
Speaker 1: Their favorite show is gonna seem like crazy stupid to you.
Speaker 0: Most of the suggestions people give are really kind of bad because while anime is not a genre It's like with movies or anything else.
Speaker 0: There are some movies that can't really be appreciated unless you have a wealth of knowledge of other movies.
Speaker 0: There are some TV shows that really aren't interesting.
Speaker 0: unless you know something about the basis of the TV show You have some investment in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like Genshiken is a great anime, but you will not understand it unless you are an anime fan.
Speaker 0: Yes, watching Genshiken and not being an anime fan already is like watching a 26 episode Documentary on baseball if you hate baseball or you don't know how the game of baseball is played.
Speaker 1: Yes It just won't work.
Speaker 1: So if you're gonna start get into anime sort of the first thing you have to do is figure out Which anime is for you?
Speaker 1: Luckily, there are some anime that are for everybody.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't get into that even.
Speaker 0: Oh, what kind of movies do you like?
Speaker 0: What kind of TV shows do you like?
Speaker 0: find anime there to like that.
Speaker 0: if you like action movies get an action anime.
Speaker 1: If you like horror find a horror anime, yeah Yeah but anyway There are few and far between anime fans out there like us who will correctly tell you which anime is to watch.
Speaker 1: Basically, you can start out there.
Speaker 1: There are three places to go for an anime that just about everyone will enjoy.
Speaker 1: The number three place to go is the man we talked about quite often Satoshi.
Speaker 0: Can Satoshi khan is a genius.
Speaker 0: Satoshi khan is one of my heroes.
Speaker 1: Yes, Toshi khan is an artistic genius beyond most people currently alive on this planet.
Speaker 1: He is like almost a da Vinci of anime perhaps on the level of Michelangelo.
Speaker 0: granted He hasn't done a lot yet But everything he's done is amazing and I really want to see you know Ten years from now when this body of work is more filled out exactly what he's capable of.
Speaker 0: I'm also really looking forward to paprika.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna see it this weekend.
Speaker 1: So there's basically, you know, he's made like four movies I think and one TV series.
Speaker 1: But if you're new to anime you want to get into it.
Speaker 1: I recommend you watch his movie Tokyo Godfathers before you watch his other movies now.
Speaker 0: granted Tokyo Godfathers is a light-hearted But yet sometimes serious and poignant Comedy slice a lot kind of really slice of life more like adventure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it kind of crosses genre boundaries, but it's generally light-hearted and just enjoyable Yeah, and it's definitely able to be enjoyed, you know, depending no matter which country you're from or what language you speak or anything.
Speaker 1: There's not too much.
Speaker 1: There's Japanese in it.
Speaker 1: Yes now by this could be any city on the whole planet.
Speaker 0: Yep Now by the same token another thing that he has done is called perfect blue.
Speaker 0: now if you were into horror if you were into Psychological thrillers if you like Hitchcock movies or Vincent anything scary like that or frightening or disturbing like that Perfect blue.
Speaker 0: It's my favorite Satoshi khan work hands down I don't know.
Speaker 1: I might be able to say that even and though I like Tokyo Godfathers the most.
Speaker 1: but here we go again.
Speaker 1: We just said anime fans.
Speaker 1: Just tell you what they like the most.
Speaker 1: and here we are saying what we like the most.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't want to try to say that what we like is good.
Speaker 0: cuz I'll say I like a lot of things that I'm not Going to bring up in this show.
Speaker 1: Oh, I definitely like a lot of things I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: you don't want to be watching initial D is your first and oh you do that Not going to be an enjoyable Experience unless you're.
Speaker 1: if you're a guy who really likes all trace cars and car racing and upbeat high-energy music Initial D might be a good anime for you.
Speaker 0: actually if you're not making fun of you if you're a ricer And you're into you know riced up cars and souped up cars and drifting and all like a Honda Civic with a big wing on The back really turns you on.
Speaker 1: go watch initial D.
Speaker 0: You'll become an anime fan in two seconds if you watch initial D.
Speaker 1: in that case I know lots of people like I've run into them all over the place who they're fans of initial D But they're not anime fans.
Speaker 1: They just really like initial D and race cars and all that stuff all right, so yeah, Satoshi khan He makes a lot of great movies and two of his movies perfect blue and Tokyo Godfathers are really good entry points into anime.
Speaker 1: But after Satoshi khan there's another better entry point into anime and specifically TV anime.
Speaker 1: It's the only TV anime We're gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: you see because anime you know this anime movies Which are much easier for people to get into because people already used to movies.
Speaker 1: People are not used to watching a TV series.
Speaker 1: that is 26 half-hour episodes that all have to be watched in order.
Speaker 0: now granted This is starting to change very recently in the United States where?
Speaker 0: Serial television is coming back and now there's shows like Battlestar Galactica and lost and fire 26 episode beginning middle-end deals.
Speaker 1: they go on after season after season after season you know yeah.
Speaker 0: But at the same time there's cereal which is a big step Because there weren't so many serious cereals back in the.
Speaker 1: well there were and they went away and now they're coming back.
Speaker 0: exactly.
Speaker 0: I'm saying there was this time kind of like co-op gaming where they kind of fell by the wayside And I remember in high school How hard it was to convince any of my friends to ever watch a TV show or an anime because they just they couldn't understand.
Speaker 0: Why would why watch it all at what?
Speaker 0: what they just didn't get it yep?
Speaker 1: So because watching a serial TV show like this is sort of alien to Americans and people and most other countries other than Japan And because it's kind of hard to ask someone to start off by watching a show that Really requires you to watch 26 episodes in order.
Speaker 1: There's only one TV show that we recommend that is good as a starting place for an anime viewer and the show is obviously Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 0: now the best thing about Cowboy Bebop aside from the fact that pretty much everyone likes it Cowboy Bebop is Again, it's a fairly.
Speaker 1: there are people who don't like it, but they are so few and far between it is.
Speaker 1: it is quite crazy.
Speaker 1: It's fair to say that everyone likes Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 0: I showed my dad Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 0: He liked it.
Speaker 0: I showed a co-worker at IBM Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 0: He ended up watching all of the rest of it and not only did he and this is you know a guy with a family Like a normal not really a geeky guy He loved it to the point that he actually very specifically pointed out to me a lot of scenes that Particularly struck him and they happen to be a lot of the same scenes that particularly struck us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Cowboy Bebop strikes a chord in just about anyone who sees it.
Speaker 1: The thing about Cowboy Bebop is that it's sort of the everything show.
Speaker 1: It's got your sci-fi.
Speaker 1: It's got your westerns.
Speaker 1: It's got your action.
Speaker 1: It's got your mysteries your intrigue your drama.
Speaker 1: It's got cuteness.
Speaker 1: It's got everything everything that you could possibly want in a show.
Speaker 1: They somehow put it all in one show, but it works together Correctly and it's not some mixy matchy like patchwork piece of crap.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: it's so beautifully executed and you'll get to the end and the end of Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 0: it's probably sticks out in the minds of all the people who have seen it as An amazing event.
Speaker 0: I remember feel I didn't know how to feel when I'd seen all of Cowboy Bebop the first time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I saw it coming, but I didn't see it coming.
Speaker 1: and whoa the thing about Cowboy Bebop that makes it also great for entry into anime is that While it is 26 episodes that you should probably watch in order many of the episodes Do not contain the main plot.
Speaker 1: you can just watch them on their own and they're standalone stories.
Speaker 1: You know like Batman the animated series a standalone story.
Speaker 1: They're only episodes like five I think 13 14 and 20 and like the last three or four are Actually plot.
Speaker 1: every other episode while there's little tidbits of continuity in them are mostly standalone.
Speaker 1: So if you watch episodes one through four, you know?
Speaker 1: Or just episode one you'll get a whole story in just that episode and it feels right and you won't be stuck Having to see more of it to figure out if you like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Instead thing like it's kind of this idea where each individual part is in and of itself Very enjoyable and you'll feel satisfied seeing just it.
Speaker 0: But the work as a whole is greater than the sum of its parts.
Speaker 0: Yep, also Cowboy Bebop because it moves pretty quickly and it's a lot of action in it.
Speaker 0: It's very accessible to just pick up and watch because the first DVD has five episodes on it.
Speaker 0: those five episodes I practically guarantee Anyone who watches those five episodes will like Cowboy Bebop Before by the time they have watched the fifth episode and will want to see the rest of it.
Speaker 1: and the fifth episode is something special.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the first episode is actually one of the best episodes in the show But not yeah It's not the best episode in terms of being an enjoyable episode as the best action scene at my favorite action scene.
Speaker 0: Actually, there's a couple of really good action scenes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll talk about Cowboy Bebop someday Yep.
Speaker 1: But the other thing about kaviva the final thing that makes it good as an entry point is that the dub is actually good.
Speaker 1: You see if you're not anime fan, you got to realize these things were originally had Japanese voice acting.
Speaker 1: So if you try to watch them, you could watch them with the original Japanese voice acting and subtitles Which nerds prefer.
Speaker 1: and in many cases, it's actually probably a good idea.
Speaker 1: And if you're one of those people who says I don't want to read my show you get used to it.
Speaker 1: Just get over it.
Speaker 0: All right, the voice acting in Cowboy Bebop is perfect.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's great in the first five or six episodes like it's already up well and above the best dub ever then and it gets better and better and better and by the end It's there's better voice acting in Cowboy Bebop than I've seen in a lot of actual American live-action movies.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So even though I say that if you want to get into anime You should probably get used to subtitles.
Speaker 1: if you start off with Cowboy Bebop You don't have to get used to subtitles quite yet.
Speaker 1: You can decide if you're into this whole anime thing before you start getting used to subtitles because Cowboy Bebop the English and the Japanese Languages are both awesome.
Speaker 1: And in fact, if you speak English is your primary language.
Speaker 1: I recommend watching the English language version and not having the subtitles because there are certain episodes where it is superior.
Speaker 0: and if you really like action or Gun drama or gunplay or anything like that or you're trying to get someone else into anime who doesn't really like it Or but they like violent movies or action movies or whatever.
Speaker 0: Or if you don't have time to watch all five episodes of the first DVD of time to watch a movie just watch Episode 5 of Cowboy Bebop Or just episode 1.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd recommend episode 5 because I remember my first experience with Cowboy Bebop was at the RIT anime club Yeah at their first meeting and they did something brilliant.
Speaker 0: they showed four different episodes from four different anime to get people into anime and The big one they showed is kind of the climax was episode 5 of Cowboy Bebop And that was the moment when I went from an anime fan to an anime geek that exact moment.
Speaker 1: I think I think what you really have to do is if you're showing Cowboy Bebop to someone to try to get them into anime you have to decide if they're an episode 1 person or an episode 5 Person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz something like if someone's already a geek They're probably an episode 5 person.
Speaker 1: if there's someone who likes, you know, like they're intellectual or they like sort of deep meaningful stuff You know, they're.
Speaker 1: they're an episode 5 person.
Speaker 1: if they're sort of a Schwarzenegger movie person.
Speaker 1: They're an episode 1 I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'd say the other way because episode 1 has an almost utenna-esque level of depth to it But I think that it works on the lower level better than episode 5.
Speaker 1: does?
Speaker 0: I don't know?
Speaker 0: because episode 5 makes up for the lack of action early on with the action scene at the end.
Speaker 1: Well, it's up to you.
Speaker 1: I mean that if you're at the point where you're showing Cowboy Bebop to people to you know Them into anime, you know, you've seen one and five and you know, which one is probably gonna work better on that person.
Speaker 0: Yes, all right I think I know where you're going with this But I'll let you continue the last thing you if you want to get into anime number one number one above all I'm just gonna come out with it.
Speaker 1: any movie at all that is directed by how Miyazaki any single one pick one It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Well, it matters a little.
Speaker 1: you probably don't want to start with pom poco.
Speaker 0: These are very Direct.
Speaker 0: that one great to get into especially if you were trying to get Families or younger children in.
Speaker 0: because on one hand I don't want to say these movies are Disney ask But they are definitely all ages.
Speaker 0: and when I say all ages, I don't mean actually for little kids I mean all ages.
Speaker 1: Yes As in if you are two years old or two hundred years old you will enjoy a how Miyazaki movie Possibly on a different level in fact most likely on a different level But you will enjoy it that you'd have to be inhuman or some evil prick not to enjoy.
Speaker 0: I mean particularly just for someone who's never seen anime at all before.
Speaker 0: I'd probably recommend Spirited away.
Speaker 1: spirit is my favorite one or Mononoke Hime.
Speaker 1: I don't okay.
Speaker 1: He may is also good I I really like.
Speaker 1: moto Rosso is an excellent choice Is an excellent choice.
Speaker 0: Lobbit is a little long, but it is a little long.
Speaker 1: It's a little but the content is good.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh lobs is great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah castle not so much, but you know not as much as the other ones, but still great.
Speaker 0: Yes I really enjoyed how I was moving pat castle But it wasn't as solid of a screen story as the others that we mentioned are.
Speaker 1: the thing that's great about how?
Speaker 1: Miyazaki's movies is not only do they have some sort of universal appeal and not only you know Are they all awesome and can be enjoyed by all ages, but the dubs on them by which Disney has done actually are actually pretty good and tend to have famous people like Billy Crystal is Calcifer and how's moving castle.
Speaker 1: and What's that guy Billy Bob?
Speaker 1: Whatever?
Speaker 1: yeah, he's in Monodoke Hime I think and the voice acting is really good on them, and you can watch the dub yep, and Even people who like don't aren't get.
Speaker 1: you can actually show these two people and not get them into anime like you could just show Them these movies as they would watch a Disney movie like Aladdin or something in fact.
Speaker 1: It won't become an anime fan.
Speaker 1: They'll just a joy a wonderful And you know animated full-length motion picture with universal appeal
Speaker 0: if you know someone who first whatever reason hates anime But hasn't really seen a lot and you could probably get away with showing them a Miyazaki movie dubbed
Speaker 1: Without letting you know it's anime.
Speaker 0: Don't tell them.
Speaker 0: It's anime until after they've said they liked it.
Speaker 1: Just say hey, this is movie Disney put out or something like that yeah, and then at the end You know that was anime right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, all right They're also really easy to get like though your best.
Speaker 1: any store that has DVDs will have Miyazaki movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm pretty sure you can even get him at Walmart probably Alright, so we're not gonna linger long on this because we could do shows and shows and shows about anime as we tend to do.
Speaker 0: But we've already told you how to wet your teeth on anime.
Speaker 0: Where do you go from there?
Speaker 0: aside from the fact that you know pick genres you like in terms of you know action comedy Whatever and then find anime in those genres and just watch them.
Speaker 0: I think like we do with board games I'd like to give you a general just list of in a vague order the big-name shows that That in my mind really stuck out as further cementing my love of anime or in some cases actually Affecting my worldview much like great movies.
Speaker 0: do yeah in general as much as people malign it.
Speaker 0: Neon Genesis Evangelion is a huge anime.
Speaker 0: It's a great anime and just take turns Yeah, all right, so definitely Neon Genesis Evangelion again.
Speaker 0: This is the list of anime.
Speaker 0: once you've cut your teeth You've decided you like some anime you want to see more.
Speaker 0: Here's some directions to go in.
Speaker 1: yeah It's plus.
Speaker 1: watching all these different kinds of shows you'll be able to say oh that was a show I didn't like like.
Speaker 1: these are like big ones in specific genres.
Speaker 1: Yes, if you like one then you can go deeper into that genre.
Speaker 0: now a lot of shows.
Speaker 0: I just will warn you.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of shows that do things very similar to what Ava did Because Ava to not really spoil things went in a very philosophical Direction and a lot of people say very heavy-handed.
Speaker 0: a lot of people say that was shallow And I don't think it was necessarily shallow.
Speaker 0: It's just that it's so heavy-handed.
Speaker 1: lays it on so thick?
Speaker 0: yes Yeah, but suffice to say while some shows may have done what this show did better I think that Ava is a better show overall because a lot of those shows go more heavy-handed or Less heavy-handed and in the end they lose the message
Speaker 1: yep, all right the next show.
Speaker 1: I think that people should at least give a try.
Speaker 1: if you watch Gundam seed the original Gundam seed now It's a good one that Gundam see destiny, which is garbage.
Speaker 0: Yeah garbage all right.
Speaker 1: if you watch Gundam seed all right Just like watch the first few episodes, and if you're liking where it's going you're probably someone who's gonna like Gundam And you know what.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of Gundam out there for you to enjoy.
Speaker 1: yep And it's not hard to go and figure out which other Gundams are really great.
Speaker 0: now even better Say you think the first four episodes of Gundam seed are kind of lame.
Speaker 0: keep watching because it's not like that.
Speaker 0: for the rest Yeah, it's a totally different show.
Speaker 0: It's much more about character relationships and drama that it is the stupid robot.
Speaker 1: I notice a lot of people who are our anime fans.
Speaker 1: They just go blah robots.
Speaker 1: I don't do robots.
Speaker 1: well If you're one of those people who says bye you don't do robots.
Speaker 1: well Gundam seed if you're gonna like if you're gonna like a robot show then that's the one you're gonna like because it's Definitely the least robot II.
Speaker 0: you know I realize most of the anime We're about to bring up involve robots But yet here's the thing.
Speaker 0: there are shows that are about the robots and there are shows that have robots.
Speaker 0: don't confuse the two.
Speaker 0: Yes, giant robo is a show about robots.
Speaker 1: Yes, Evangelion really isn't a robot show.
Speaker 0: I would say if anything This is there's a little hit.
Speaker 0: Evangelion pretends to be a robot show and then after it's tricked the robot show people into watching it it stops being a robot show.
Speaker 1: Yep, yeah So Gundam seed that'll let you know if you might like robot shows.
Speaker 0: and most even if you don't like the robot show part You'll still like Gundam seed because Gundam seed is an emotional roller coaster that will leave you feeling mentally exhausted by the end.
Speaker 1: It's also sort of soap opera II yes, but it's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would definitely recommend Trigon.
Speaker 1: yeah, try try.
Speaker 0: gun is probably one of my favorite anime ever.
Speaker 0: now try guns.
Speaker 0: a little silly.
Speaker 0: it starts out as a comedy.
Speaker 0: It's really kind of wacky and off the wall But it's not wacky and off the wall in the way that a lot of modern anime are.
Speaker 1: yeah It's definitely a post-apocalyptic Liptick sci-fi Western.
Speaker 0: and the thing is it takes a turn for the serious and it gets Really dark and really philosophical and really good and it has great action and great characters and great comedy.
Speaker 0: It it's an anime where I will admit that I be rim and pretty much everyone else in the front row crew Openly cried during yeah, let's see you should probably at some point if you've decided you like anime you should probably watch Akira.
Speaker 1: Akira is like the anime movie period and While if you've read the manga the movie loses a lot for you Which is kind of sad because I do think the movie is great.
Speaker 1: But like whenever I watch it, I've read the manga.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of a on me.
Speaker 1: So I always say if you haven't read the manga or watch the movie watch the movie first.
Speaker 1: That way you can actually get the enjoyment from the awesome movie without having it being ruined by the awesomer manga.
Speaker 1: But yep, Akira is sort of like this.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: that's what booted off, you know anime in the US and basically the current, you know That was like the start our generation of anime fan.
Speaker 1: That was the Archduke Ferdinand of the current anime.
Speaker 0: Yep, because and not just the current anime but the current anime fans as in people our age Yeah our wave because now there's other waves of anime fans.
Speaker 0: There were ways before us but we grew up on the sci-fi network anime and the Akira movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's definitely something everyone should see and whether you like it or not, you know is up to you But it's it's super important and you should.
Speaker 1: it's sort of like Citizen Kane.
Speaker 1: You should watch it whether you like it or not.
Speaker 0: Now one a lot of people like fantasy especially geeks But there's not a lot of great fantasy out there other than in book form.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of great fantasy movies.
Speaker 0: You could count them on your hands and there's actually.
Speaker 0: well, there's a lot of fantasy anime.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of good fantasy anime.
Speaker 0: now here 12 Kingdom is good, but I haven't seen enough to really say anything.
Speaker 1: it's also kind of hard because well, we define as fantasy is kind of different.
Speaker 1: like there's a lot of Anime that you could call fantasy, you know, because they like you could call bleach fantasy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could call antenna fantasy Yeah, but we're talking about high fantasy like wizards and dragons and Knights and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: now I would say slayers.
Speaker 0: slayers is funny fantasy.
Speaker 0: slayers is you know blowing up the in beer and pretzels D&D.
Speaker 0: But it's an anime and it's a great show.
Speaker 0: I love it.
Speaker 0: I absolutely love it but if you're looking for, you know straight up semi hardcore fantasy a fairly overlooked show now even though it was Absolutely huge when it was out and it endures to this day and I think it stands up well against a lot of anime that comes out.
Speaker 0: now is Vision of eska flown a mmm.
Speaker 0: That is an amazing fantasy anime.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It came out back in the Ava days.
Speaker 0: It's been around for a long time.
Speaker 0: It's old.
Speaker 0: you can get the whole thing in a thin pack super cheap at Best Buy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like 30 bucks.
Speaker 1: You can have the whole show or something like that.
Speaker 0: I can't recommend this show enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's definitely has a lot of things in it that are now cliche and anime like oh transported to another world Obvious romance people with wings, you know transforming robots that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: But it's sort of started a lot of those things and it doesn't execute anything in a way that seems cliche Even if it was at the time.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Do you want to keep you think any cuz beyond this if you watch everything that we have just mentioned?
Speaker 1: Probably already anime fan.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah by then you'll have figured out.
Speaker 0: My only real recommendations from this point on is don't bother about this aspect of it.
Speaker 0: Well, if you watch the things we mentioned early in the show But if you start watching everything we talked about just now and you start getting into it That is the point where you want to start and this is important pay attention To who did the character designs and who directed?
Speaker 0: The shows you liked versus the shows you didn't like and that'll give you a lot of direction in terms of what to watch next.
Speaker 1: Yep, also you can go online and talk to people and listen to podcasts and things and find out you know People who liked X also liked why.
Speaker 1: I guess I probably like why.
Speaker 1: also, you know, what's similar to this?
Speaker 1: What's similar to that and it's not hard once you're into it to figure out which things you will also like.
Speaker 0: And I'm sure a lot of you out there are saying but they didn't say X show or they didn't say such-and-such or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna say every show in the whole world.
Speaker 0: No, we're just giving you a starting point if you need more than what we've given you.
Speaker 1: You're already an anime fan Yeah, and if you're not sure like, you know, if you're not an anime fan You're not sure which kind of or maybe you like watched one that you watch cowboy bebop and you like it.
Speaker 1: But now you don't know where to go.
Speaker 1: come into like our forum or email us or something and say, uh These are the kind of movies I like.
Speaker 1: You know real move like actual live-action movies that you like because everyone has some live-action movies They like and we'll recommend some anime.
Speaker 1: They'll probably like yep.
Speaker 0: And while a lot of our forum members will probably give advice I do note that we because a lot of people seem to be surprised that we do this But we actually post in our own forums.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: A lot of people don't.
Speaker 0: we're there actively Yeah, so if you ask this sort of question to us in the forums, we will personally answer.
Speaker 0: probably if we notice Yeah, we'll eventually get to it.
Speaker 0: We answer the forums a lot more readily than we answer emails.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm All right.
Speaker 1: I don't think I want to talk anymore about this because it's getting late Yeah, and I haven't eaten yet.
Speaker 1: So you have to eat something go to bed.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: But yeah getting into animes not hard.
Speaker 1: Oh and oh, I forgot one two things.
Speaker 1: if you're into anime and you've got you finally you decided you like it You're either gonna want to do one or two things or both get Netflix.
Speaker 1: That way you don't have to buy a whole bunch of DVDs just to watch a show.
Speaker 1: You know you buy the shows that you love.
Speaker 1: that, you know, you like that you want to watch again and again.
Speaker 1: But if you want to watch it a 26 episode show just once get Netflix.
Speaker 1: Also What the new shows that are coming out in Japan right now won't be on DVD for many months.
Speaker 1: So you go on the internet and use bit torrent to get those episodes with fansubs on them to figure out which ones you like.
Speaker 1: That way when they do come out on DVD in the US, you know, which ones to Netflix and you know Which one's not to Netflix?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean as much as I love anime.
Speaker 0: It's a rare show that will be good enough to get me to watch all the fansubs because I can't wait for the DVDs.
Speaker 0: Currently it's just Claymore and Bocorano.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mostly Bocorano.
Speaker 1: I could probably wait for DVDs and Claymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a feeling We're gonna wait for DVDs on Claymore because we got a lot going on in the next couple.
Speaker 1: Also, I recognized when I went to Best Buy today I was quite surprised at you know, how quickly.
Speaker 1: they're getting the anime over this side of the ocean.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I realized a lot of ergo proxies already on a DVD Haru.
Speaker 1: He was on the shelf and that's a really new show.
Speaker 1: So hey pretty awesome right there.
Speaker 1: You don't got to wait long to get the stuff in English All right time to eat and go to bed.
Speaker 0: indeed This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.