Speaker 0: It's Tuesday July 17th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight beating the game.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Huh, it's gaming day, and we still haven't played any more video games.
Speaker 0: You think we're gonna have time until I don't know well.
Speaker 0: Maybe at the shore.
Speaker 0: We might play some video games.
Speaker 1: I think we might play some guitar hero type games.
Speaker 0: I think we're mostly gonna play guitar hero and possibly the old Wario ware and maybe some pac-man verse Yeah, and we'll also might gonna play DDR in the arcades.
Speaker 0: Oh, man I I gotta say I like video like console games I like PC games and all that.
Speaker 0: but I Love good arcades, and I'm so looking forward to this week at the shore because last year arcades are good again Because they've been going steadily downhill for a long time.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: because the one arcade it kind of shifted and last year We pretty much had the sea of the eight DDR machines.
Speaker 1: I know but it's just DDR and air hockey.
Speaker 1: I need my variety.
Speaker 1: I need a good shooting game variety.
Speaker 0: There's no new good games.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: I need like a racing game.
Speaker 1: I need any a pinball.
Speaker 1: You know you got to mix it up.
Speaker 1: the arcade of just DDR and air hockey isn't really an arcade.
Speaker 1: It's just like a DDR air hockey place.
Speaker 0: I guess my expectations are just so lowered by the fact that real arcades pretty much don't exist outside of Chinatown.
Speaker 0: Well in Japan yeah, yeah well in the u.s.. They don't exist so much anymore.
Speaker 0: I know I mean the best arcade I know that's actually an arcade is this shady seedy looking place on Mott Street in Chinatown, but you know what?
Speaker 0: They've got Giga wing.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, but kinetic on we the video game room We didn't play so much in there.
Speaker 0: know all kind of video game rooms except for katsu cons are identical pretty much.
Speaker 1: But we did have some fun in the board game room played some goa Which is a game you might remember.
Speaker 1: we failed to play in the past because the rule book sucks.
Speaker 0: What I wasn't so much that the rule book.
Speaker 1: it was partially that the rule book.
Speaker 0: I think it was primarily that one.
Speaker 0: the game is a lot seems a lot more complicated than it is.
Speaker 0: yeah Involves many disparate mechanics.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm three.
Speaker 0: there was a dog barking in the room for There were a bunch of people barking in the room.
Speaker 0: Five we only had an hour.
Speaker 1: none of us knew how to play.
Speaker 0: Yes having someone actually knowing how to play.
Speaker 0: teaching you how to play that game is probably the only way to really learn easily.
Speaker 1: Regardless it's an awesome game and expect to hear about it in the future not the near future, but the future for sir someday.
Speaker 1: yes So and the news this might not sound like gaming news at first, but on July 13th 14th and 15th in Union Park I think near Chicago right There was a pitchfork music festival, or I guess a music festival known as the pitchfork music festival.
Speaker 0: Do they make music with pitchforks?
Speaker 1: no, but it had a lot of high-profile bands such as Mastodon and the GZ a and a whole bunch of others that are listed on this website.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh De La Soul The William Parker quartet it seems like a real you know varying styles music festival something with you know something for everybody.
Speaker 0: It's kind of thing I like.
Speaker 1: yeah I would probably would have gone if I lived anywhere near Chicago and I knew about it And I wasn't doing anything this weekend, but apparently there were some kids at this music festival.
Speaker 1: They actually don't look like kids.
Speaker 1: They look like our age.
Speaker 1: Maybe a little younger.
Speaker 1: Maybe college kids.
Speaker 1: I can't tell I were they punks?
Speaker 0: uh No, they don't look Punk.
Speaker 1: They look normal all right, but They pretty much walked around the entire music festival with a sign Saying let's trade Pokemon, and they were holding their DS's up in the air, and they traded a lot of Pokemon.
Speaker 0: You know I just I got to point out while we were at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: you know every con season ever since the DS and the PSP came out we've always talked about like the ratio and Pretty much everyone had a DS, but I saw like six or seven PSPs.
Speaker 0: there was like one PSP for every 30 DS's so it wasn't that bad of a ratio.
Speaker 1: I see some PSPs on the subway.
Speaker 0: You know but thing is though.
Speaker 0: You never see like a crowd of PSP.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: They're always solitary like video watchers or solitary guys on the subway.
Speaker 1: You went to ever see the crew of PSP.
Speaker 0: if you went anywhere at Kineticon and opened your picto chat there were just penises left and right and up and down and Behind where you don't want them to be.
Speaker 0: and if you said my pokemons Let me show you them.
Speaker 1: there were like seven people Standing around you ready to talk in the underground to get a spirit oom and ready to show you them yes So I think it's pretty crazy if you know we go to an anime convention.
Speaker 1: of course you expect there to be pokemons all over The place.
Speaker 1: yeah, well not just pokemons, but like geekery, and I don't really see that Outside of geek magnets, but here you go to a sort of wide appeal mainstream music show and Pokemons and lots of pokemons going on.
Speaker 1: apparently you know I think it's good.
Speaker 0: in the end people may say oh pokemons and Naruto's and all those things are crap And that's not the cool real stuff that I care about.
Speaker 0: but most of you well I don't say most of you But many geeks who like you know like the good anime or the good video games started out playing halo and watching Dragon Ball.
Speaker 0: Yeah You can't say that just because someone likes something that you think is pulpy or crab or for little kids Doesn't mean that that thing can't be entertaining in and of itself and can't be a gateway drug.
Speaker 1: But you know it seems like you know we were in a world where anyone who liked anything geeky was in the minority and everyone Else didn't like anything geeky at all.
Speaker 1: and now we're moving into a world where Everyone is geeky or more and more people are geeky and then the these geeks that are even more Geeky who are secluded and split off and segregated in some way, so I don't know will it eventually?
Speaker 1: Will there always be some group that is like separate and minority from the other group?
Speaker 0: or well There are always the nerds.
Speaker 0: and second They're always the people who decide that they don't like something because now it's mainstream so they get more and more obscure.
Speaker 1: Those people need to get a life.
Speaker 1: That's all I gotta say.
Speaker 0: see the ultimate is you know like.
Speaker 0: there's the indie kids who are they?
Speaker 0: name-drop bands like oh well I was listening to Feebly fobbly last night.
Speaker 0: They're a. they're a transfusion hypnotic techno remix emo something.
Speaker 0: no They always make up like no matter what sub-genre you like.
Speaker 0: they always add like a sub sub-genre to it like you're like.
Speaker 0: I like new Neoprimativist music.
Speaker 0: there's a great.
Speaker 0: I like post neoprimativist music.
Speaker 1: There's a great shirt you can get on threadless and all it is is a t-shirt that says I Listen to bands that don't even exist.
Speaker 1: yet
Speaker 0: What I was about to say was I think at some point all those people are gonna have left to do is They'll make up something and pretend that they like it and the moment anyone else says that they also Like that thing that's made up and doesn't actually exist.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They'll just kill themselves.
Speaker 0: I have no idea, but regardless Pokemans let me show you them.
Speaker 1: So would you like this?
Speaker 0: there's been all this news about e3 and I don't want to get into the details of.
Speaker 0: oh E3 moved or oh, it's not Lloyd it used to be your.
Speaker 0: Oh news happened to d3.
Speaker 1: It's small It's insignificant.
Speaker 1: now blabbity blabbity blood.
Speaker 0: All I really want to say is I'll be perfectly honest and that as hardcore as I am into video games granted I'm not quite as hardcore as a lot of you know, modern hip hardcore gamers since I mostly like Platformers and older games and I played Nintendo games more than anything else Yep.
Speaker 0: But I never really cared about e3 in my entire life and I only wanted to go before I actually knew what e3 was.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, like once I found out that e3 was pretty much just.
Speaker 0: I don't think most people who go actually have fun.
Speaker 0: I think they do not the same kind of fun.
Speaker 0: I can't have fun at a con like that.
Speaker 0: most of what I like at a con is hanging out with people and Maybe putting on a show if I could do that or hanging out in my geekery and go into stuff But any three.
Speaker 0: it seems like most of it.
Speaker 0: especially what e3 turned into was stand in lines play short demos of games Be in a room.
Speaker 0: That's so loud.
Speaker 0: You cannot hold a conversation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seems like all the real fun action was all the after parties.
Speaker 1: But the real fun action to me seemed like it was in that You know famous other hall where all the indie game type the weird games would be that You know people always talked about.
Speaker 1: but those days are over.
Speaker 1: So now e3.
Speaker 1: whatever.
Speaker 0: Frankly, I'm glad e3 did what they did.
Speaker 0: because while I mean e3 originally was supposed to be like the video game event where all the News comes out and the press gets to see what's coming and they kept letting more and more people come I mean they used to claim that you had to be a journalist of some kind to go
Speaker 1: an EB employee to get
Speaker 0: in.
Speaker 0: That was such a joke.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and now it's actually you really do can't need to be someone important to get in.
Speaker 1: you can't just get into e3 now.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm glad now the press will just do their thing and we'll get our stuff.
Speaker 0: and if someone wants to have the crazy Hangout gaming convention.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the industry will care about it so much So it'll probably just end up being more like a gaming convention with people hanging out and not so much of the industry.
Speaker 0: Let me show you my pokemons.
Speaker 1: I think the one thing that's interesting about this though.
Speaker 1: Is that unlike other media, right People in the video game media are also the fans, you know, I mean sure in the sports media Some people are also sports fans, but that's not quite the same because it's not an interactive thing, you know.
Speaker 1: And people, you know some people in the tech media are also tech fans.
Speaker 1: But for the most part media people are not usually super fans of the things they media.
Speaker 1: So e3 and trying to appeal to the gaming media appealed to the gaming fan And it because it's video games those interactive experience and that's why actual fans tried to get in Now by changing the show in such a way that it is not fun for the fans.
Speaker 1: It is only good for the media.
Speaker 1: the media that is also fans Which is most of the video game media is now also like not having fun there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do agree with that.
Speaker 0: I just there's no real easy way around it because if there was ever an event like that that kept going.
Speaker 0: I mean like all the punk kids are always gonna want to go.
Speaker 1: I know look at look at Nintendo's press conference, right?
Speaker 1: They spent the the first poll part of it talking about sales numbers and things like that stuff that in any other Industry, the media would have cared a lot about.
Speaker 1: But most of the gaming media people the blogs and the magazines are like man.
Speaker 1: Nintendo's press conference is so boring.
Speaker 1: All they do was talk about numbers, you know Maybe that comes in.
Speaker 0: there was just an article on slash out about how bit by bit Blogs and all that sort of thing and you know kind of independent press are pretty much dominating tech news at this point because the real media just can't keep up at all and they don't know what's going on.
Speaker 0: and yeah I kind of agree with that because I listen to you know NPR or the BBC or I read Google News and anything that's on the mainstream media.
Speaker 0: It's like a week old like I already knew about it for a week.
Speaker 1: It's to the point where it doesn't help.
Speaker 0: it's usually wrong or it's just it's garbage.
Speaker 0: and I feel like the gaming more and more we're having these things where people who are fans of or knowledgeable about Something are being the press for it.
Speaker 0: So the generic normal Reporter guy who works for Reuters or the AP wire or whatever?
Speaker 0: He doesn't really have anything to add anymore unless it's a special interest local story or something that for whatever reason people don't care about.
Speaker 0: Yep, but at least there aren't people who are fans of it.
Speaker 1: I mean he does sometimes have the job of translating these stuff so that normal idiots can understand You know what's going on and something they don't know about.
Speaker 1: In the process, they usually make things also wrong and they misinform people.
Speaker 0: I mean really self-centered here.
Speaker 0: I'm just talking from the perspective of a knowledgeable person.
Speaker 0: Yeah I have almost no use for the mainstream media when it comes to anything I know about and I'm glad that the internet has made it so that the people reporting on the things I care about Care about the exact same things I care about.
Speaker 1: that is a good thing, but at the same time I feel like There's something missing like that.
Speaker 1: You know shouldn't be?
Speaker 1: it's like I wish that at while also being fans of the things I care about They were also the professional in the journalism way.
Speaker 0: See some people are.
Speaker 0: some of them are yes I mean outside of whenever Apple releases a new product.
Speaker 0: a lot of the tech people are pretty objective tech people are.
Speaker 1: it's mostly the Video game people I'm complaining about not being real journalists.
Speaker 0: It depends on the video game people.
Speaker 0: I mean, honestly, I'll say this straight up the only people outside of my circle of friends I look to for any guidance whatsoever in terms of what video games are good or what's going on the video game industry Penny arcade and to a lesser extent Dave and Joel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because we have similar taste in games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the other thing is like you read some of these gaming blogs like the Kotaku's and the Joysticks and they don't really tell you like which games are good and which ones are bad.
Speaker 1: They're just like hey these games are coming out.
Speaker 1: Hey, these companies made these announcements.
Speaker 1: It's like You're not really helping me out here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean so the stuff.
Speaker 1: I still read your stuff because I do care about that.
Speaker 1: But there's other stuff I care about.
Speaker 1: you're not telling me Honestly, though.
Speaker 0: I don't really have a strong opinion.
Speaker 0: I just needed to pick a crap news to get the show over with.
Speaker 0: cuz I agree I got a million things to do before, you know, tonight's pretty much the night We have to get everything done for the next two weeks of geek night.
Speaker 0: I'm doing laundry while doing the show Yeah, and I'm actually like working on two other geek nights kind of while we're recording and it really sucks Yep, so, uh, I'll be honest.
Speaker 0: I was just talking I wasn't really listening what was coming out of my mouth and I really truly don't have a strong opinion.
Speaker 0: I just I don't care that e3 changed.
Speaker 0: I think it'll be good in the end.
Speaker 1: and Beyond that that man Mom Things that but up.
Speaker 0: Yeah things of the day.
Speaker 0: So Emily showed this to us last night and it reminded me Enough of the you can't live 10 Pokemon that I just had to talk about it plus, uh, it's not on the top of dig Right now so you can't.
Speaker 1: it didn't really remind me of that.
Speaker 1: You can't find 10 Pokemon so much.
Speaker 0: mostly was the things that guy was saying before they let him in the car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that did remind me.
Speaker 0: cuz that part right there.
Speaker 0: He's like, I think this dog is staring at me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what he wants.
Speaker 1: Once the guy was in the car.
Speaker 1: I just wanted to hit him.
Speaker 1: I don't even know why the people let him in.
Speaker 1: They should have just driven off.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they were stupid.
Speaker 1: They got what they deserve.
Speaker 0: Apparently a friend of Emily's back at NYU was working on this so she saw him working on it.
Speaker 0: now It's done and it's online and it's uh, it's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: I got to say because I've been in a similar situation someone really needs to just make a website.
Speaker 1: That's you know, cuz there's a lot of colleges out there with animation programs And they just need to make a website that says all college students with making animation projects when you are done put them here and then we can watch all of them in one place.
Speaker 1: and Or maybe a special category on YouTube for college Animation film projects, you know that way because those are always, you know They're always better than just some high school kids with a camera But they're not always as high quality as a movie in the theater.
Speaker 1: I saw some pretty bad ones at RIT But they usually have something clever to them that makes them worth watching.
Speaker 1: Cuz that's what you need to stand out and get a better grade.
Speaker 0: I just think this was really funny and it reminds me of some people I've met in my life And that's all I'm gonna leave it at that.
Speaker 1: Oh, it does remind me of a few people that I don't talk to anymore.
Speaker 0: The guy's speech pattern reminds me a little bit of Dave from Dave and Joel's fast karate for the gentleman.
Speaker 0: The thing is I don't think Dave is even a thousandth that annoying.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think so either.
Speaker 1: So my thing is that I am watching right now But I turn the audio off To cuz.
Speaker 1: I know Rimmel yell at me.
Speaker 1: if I try to like play it out of my laptop speaker and into the microphone I will but I'll probably keep it in the show.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm too lazy to edit but I'd probably go.
Speaker 0: Ah, now I got to edit that out and then.
Speaker 0: but anyway, go ahead.
Speaker 1: It's not loud enough.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I just played it for a second.
Speaker 1: But anyway there's a Snoop Dogg is a hip-hop and rap guy who I don't really I mean I know.
Speaker 1: so I know of him which says a lot and I know Some stuff about him but only like the barest information.
Speaker 1: Apparently he has this song that called drop.
Speaker 1: it like it's hot cuz.
Speaker 1: I don't understand any other words cuz.
Speaker 1: I didn't really pay attention To what they were so much.
Speaker 1: I could probably figure them out and the song is like drop it like it's high.
Speaker 0: Drop it like it's hot Like it's hot something something something.
Speaker 1: apparently Somebody realized that this song is basically the same as the song in Kirby, you know Dude, dude, dude, dude, dude, dude, dude, dude, dude, dude, dude, man.
Speaker 0: We're not nearly as good as that.
Speaker 0: No, Dave and Joel are
Speaker 1: no, but Joel but the Some guy made a YTM ND and also a YouTube where he basically took up and a repeating animation of Kirby Dancing after beating wispy woods and
Speaker 0: I don't think you need to explain how you make a YTM
Speaker 1: And a repeating animation of Snoop Dogg dancing back and forth and he put
Speaker 0: Snoop
Speaker 1: Dogg's Rapping without any background music combined with Kirby's background music and it matches eerily exactly,
Speaker 0: I got to admit I actually like the end result more than either of the original songs and I Kinda need an mp3 of that.
Speaker 0: You just listen to.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's a good song man.
Speaker 1: You should check it out.
Speaker 0: No We were talking about it and I know actually last night showed us another Thing that's similar to that with the Phoenix Wright song.
Speaker 0: We realized something.
Speaker 0: hip-hop in particular.
Speaker 0: the chord structures tend to be repetitive and simple.
Speaker 0: I can think of one other kind of music that is generally chord wise repetitive and simple and that is Video game music.
Speaker 0: the odds are there are a lot of hip-hop songs that coincide with video game music.
Speaker 1: There are.
Speaker 1: what was the example?
Speaker 0: We saw it was well, there was the Phoenix right thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like Phoenix right plus some other rap guy, but they sort of had to slow down the Phoenix Right music and whatever.
Speaker 1: but this is just exact out of the box.
Speaker 1: It's almost as if Snoop was rapping to Kirby which he might have been for all we know.
Speaker 1: The odds are not zero.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it.
Speaker 1: this is scarily accurate and I'm sure there are many others that are close.
Speaker 1: But this is damn.
Speaker 1: you got to hear this shit.
Speaker 1: Damn.
Speaker 0: Now what we need to do is find some guy who's good at rapping You know Maybe a nerdcore guy and get him to do the hip-hop thing where you just have Beats from video games and just rap straight up over that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because they do have the chiptune action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we do have the nerdcore action But the nerdcore action is usually nerdy lyrics like about Boba Fett or something on top of normal hip-hop music.
Speaker 1: someone's got to do a Nerdcore hip-hop on top of just video chiptunes.
Speaker 1: You got to got to get emerging going on and that would be super us.
Speaker 0: So we of course it's the week between the con and the con So we didn't really have anything planned and I kind of expected to skip this week entirely.
Speaker 0: But we're plugging through and doing shows anyway for some reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we also still have to record some.
Speaker 1: well No, we've got to make some crap shows to fill in next week when we're not here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I pretty much have to do all of that tonight.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: So today we tried to think up something to talk about, you know, cuz you haven't been playing video games lately.
Speaker 1: So we didn't want to talk about the board games quite yet.
Speaker 1: So we we found a topic in video games to discuss.
Speaker 0: see I remember when I was a kid that this mattered a lot more to me than it does now.
Speaker 1: I think that's the point of this discussion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we might have talked about this before.
Speaker 0: I don't think we did even if we did it was only as part of another episode or something.
Speaker 0: So I don't really care.
Speaker 0: I can say it all again and I think I have enough relevant anecdotes.
Speaker 0: Yep, but beating the game was such a big deal to me when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Like I remember if I beat a game I would call my friends like immediately no matter what hour it was be like Dude, you got to get over here about to see the end of guerrilla war and they'd all come running.
Speaker 1: Yep Well originally when I was playing video games, you know, it was just score and even playing Mario 1 I felt like the game would go on forever like an end wasn't even something in my mind.
Speaker 1: Like it didn't even conceive that there would be an end to the games.
Speaker 1: I figured they just kind of went on and on.
Speaker 1: and you know is I Gotta keep going get far get farther and see more stuff.
Speaker 1: and a lot of the appeal of video games Especially as soon as we got to the NES games was you know, oh my god I got to a new level.
Speaker 1: I get to see some new stuff because playing Atari games You see the same thing over and over again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Atari games monsters didn't even change color as you went on.
Speaker 0: Yeah in berserk They did a little.
Speaker 1: so a lot of the fun for me as a kid playing video games was When I went to a new level there'd be a new bad guy like a hammer brother.
Speaker 1: Holy shit Oh my god a blooper.
Speaker 1: Holy shit flying fish.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: I almost peed myself the first time I saw hammer brother.
Speaker 0: That was not cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you play Zelda and he'd like oh man.
Speaker 1: There's the horsey guys.
Speaker 1: Holy crap.
Speaker 1: or the graveyard.
Speaker 0: Whoa, I really different.
Speaker 0: I remember getting to that graveyard like the first time and I walk in there and suddenly the screens all gray and there's that ghost.
Speaker 0: And then I bumped into a tombstone and a ghost came out and after a kid I mean, it wasn't like really scared But I felt like I was in this eerie like Twilight world and I I felt on edge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't get that anymore.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: when I discovered that video games actually had ends to them, you know, and I got to those ends It was pretty much like the same sensation is getting to a new level where you saw all this new stuff But multiplied by a zillion because it was like holy shit.
Speaker 1: It's the ending stuff stuff that you can never possibly see without going through insane amounts of effort.
Speaker 1: This is you can only see it once.
Speaker 0: this is back before.
Speaker 0: FMV is pretty much any good Nintendo game like we're talking.
Speaker 0: any s-days had like a little opening animation Which was usually really really piss-poor.
Speaker 0: But you're always amazed by it because while it was really bad compared to anything else you'd seen for a Nintendo game It was always awesome.
Speaker 0: Like two ninjas are running at each other like not even shaky and then like one dies.
Speaker 0: Yep, we all remember that game.
Speaker 0: But if you didn't see anything like that after you started the game Until you beat the game and then you got like the final payoff and you got to see some other thing as time went on I remember as a kid I used to remember like how long the end of a game was after you beat it and I always felt like the longer it Was the better it was.
Speaker 1: Yep, like Final Fantasy 4 because it was more stuff you haven't seen before that you were able to see, you know It's just one screen.
Speaker 1: It's like oh I saw one screen of stuff, you know It's all about seeing new stuff and it wasn't just seeing new stuff But it was the fact that there was no way to see this stuff without expending a great deal of effort again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if you wanted to see mr.
Speaker 0: Miyagi wink at the end of the karate kid You basically had to kill yourself in front of that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and to do it again.
Speaker 1: You had to spend a whole bunch more hours.
Speaker 1: That's why when you beat a game you called your friends Yeah, I mean some kids were really smart and they would like VCR the end of the games.
Speaker 1: They'd get him on tape, but that was very rare.
Speaker 1: And you know, there was no YouTube to just go watch whatever game ending you wanted It was.
Speaker 1: it was totally different in those days.
Speaker 0: I remember the most proof because a lot of times, you know If the friend couldn't come over or like say I beat a game really late at night I can't call my friend Joe and tell him to walk down the streets of Detroit to come to my house at 11 o'clock On a school night when we're in second grade.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so every Nintendo game like you'd beat it and well every good Nintendo game they'd be like the end stuff and then it would finally scroll up to like the the end and always be like the end.
Speaker 0: or you've won or congratulations or game over and you'd always Sit there Waiting to see if anything else came.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, because you're so afraid of missing something.
Speaker 0: You're
Speaker 1: so afraid of missing something So I would sit there watching that screen for a good many minutes and like I jam all the buttons on the gamepad to make But also I wouldn't touch the buttons no case they accidentally made something get skipped and I wouldn't ever turn it off the power unless I was absolutely sure there was nothing left to see.
Speaker 1: because imagine like You know You're all your whole.
Speaker 1: you spent hours and your only goal and your only reward was the ability to see this footage this pixelated pictures and animations and hear this music that you could not hear any other way.
Speaker 1: and If you missed any amount of that you had to do all of that again I remember.
Speaker 1: and if it was if there was any randomness or luck Involved or if it took a long amount of time or if there was no save game That was a nightmare.
Speaker 1: You might never do it again.
Speaker 0: I remember as a kid and I'm not kidding I would sit there when I beat a game and I've watched the end especially like Final Fantasy or 4 or 6. that is gigantic And maybe you could save those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but still the end itself was still like this big deal.
Speaker 1: It was it was a big deal.
Speaker 0: You know, I get a little mad every time I had to blink just a tiny bit.
Speaker 0: I'd be like, I know I didn't miss something but I could have the game could have tried to show me something just then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course I was a weird little kid but more to the point our parents must have all thought we were crazy.
Speaker 0: cuz you know Oh kid, there's always the thing of mom.
Speaker 0: I can't go to the doctor.
Speaker 0: I gotta get to a save point Exactly the end of the game.
Speaker 1: Oh, and we'll understand that when we have kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the end of the game was like that, but it was beyond like.
Speaker 0: it wasn't.
Speaker 0: it was sacred It was like the Holy Land.
Speaker 0: compared to a save point It was like once you cross the threshold you well, you know what?
Speaker 0: It's more like an orgasm.
Speaker 0: There's a threshold For little kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, once you cross it like a nerdgasm You can't go back once you hit that point.
Speaker 0: once you hit the last hit on the last boss you have beaten the game.
Speaker 0: There is nothing left but to watch the end and you cannot pull a kid away from the end of the game.
Speaker 1: No, you can't.
Speaker 0: I once at Cedar Point Which was like Mecca for me as a kid because I was also super into roller coasters.
Speaker 0: We got there right and we're gonna go into the amusement park.
Speaker 0: But I'm in the car plugged into the AC adapter with my game gear and I be I just must have misplanned.
Speaker 0: I beat crystal warriors Just as we pulled into the parking lot.
Speaker 0: All right, and that game has like a 10-minute ending.
Speaker 0: So I'm sitting there staring at this game gear with the music all the way up.
Speaker 0: So I don't miss anything cuz there's a new song at the end and my parents are trying to get me out of the car.
Speaker 0: So we can go to the amusement park and I won't leave I won't move I won't acknowledge them because I don't want to miss any of that music any of that anything.
Speaker 0: And I think my parents just thought I was a weird little kid.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't think they understood.
Speaker 1: No probably not.
Speaker 0: they'd always get mad if we had a game and I'd pause it to eat dinner and we keep running back into Unpause it and pause it again because we were afraid it would crash.
Speaker 1: Yep I had that same fear cuz I had a game crash once.
Speaker 0: I think it was Wizards and Warriors 3 that came sucked By the way, it did suck ass.
Speaker 1: That was all the elements.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think that was two.
Speaker 0: three was the one where you could like turn into a thief and you had to sneak past the ogre And you couldn't fucking save the game.
Speaker 1: Whatever Wizards warriors not so great.
Speaker 1: Um, yeah, there were basically two times.
Speaker 1: I beat the game.
Speaker 1: that were Lifelong memorable.
Speaker 1: one of them was when I beat right.
Speaker 1: I think it might have been the first game.
Speaker 1: I beat was Megaman 2.
Speaker 0: Ah, that's a good game man - you know, it's I never beat that on hard.
Speaker 1: I remember I think I beat it one morning really early before Saturday morning cartoons and it was like all Suspenseful there and like the alien came out.
Speaker 1: It was like oh shits.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: It's OMG.
Speaker 1: Oh shits And nowadays is just like yeah alien did did did you did?
Speaker 0: The one that really stuck out for me or stood out for me was Final Fantasy 1 Because I the first time I played that game I got to the end but I had a crap party because I didn't know much about the game and I totally wasn't ready to win and I would add a level forever and I ended up just giving up and starting over.
Speaker 0: So I get to the end again, and I'm leveled up and everything's going great.
Speaker 0: I'm like, okay I can do this and first I get to Tiamat and I'll skip that I'll get to the end.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I get to the end of the game and just before I get to the final boss chaos The game totally fucks me over and two of my characters die including the white mage.
Speaker 0: So I'm sitting there thinking son of a bitch Not to bring myself back to life.
Speaker 0: Son of a bitch, you know what?
Speaker 0: whatever I'm just gonna fight him and die and I'll come back here again.
Speaker 0: So I just fight him and I won.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I won not that hard I just.
Speaker 0: well partly because winning Final Fantasy 1 is pretty much random because chaos Might just cast X X X X on everyone or you might just cast fire one.
Speaker 0: You really don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah It also depends a lot on your levels.
Speaker 1: Yeah levels You can just win.
Speaker 1: the same thing happened to me when I fought Tiamat and he'll cast X X X X You'd be like whatever.
Speaker 0: I was just about to fight Tiamat and then I'm thinking come on.
Speaker 0: No war mech.
Speaker 0: No, that's right.
Speaker 0: All right
Speaker 1: Say something about war mech
Speaker 0: war that comes up in the last step
Speaker 1: for anyone who doesn't know in Final Fantasy 1 at the end Of the game there's a bridge and you go over this bridge and I think every step you take on the bridge There's a 1 in 255 chance of the war mech appearing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically lost civilization Technology from beyond time.
Speaker 0: and there's this nuclear machine and there's a tiny chance You'll run into it and basically it'll fuck you up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it was always this cool thing because most people didn't even know about it.
Speaker 1: And you know some kids would be like no, I thought that I had to fight the war mech.
Speaker 1: But what war make you talking about, you know, like a lot of people didn't believe you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like 1 in 255 people saw the war mech or so.
Speaker 0: Well, it was 1 in 255 times the number of steps.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it wasn't that many steps.
Speaker 1: It wasn't the longest bridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, war mech's main attack was called thermonuclear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and not too pleasant for the party He brought me down to one fighter who was practically dead.
Speaker 0: So I said fuck it fought Tiamat.
Speaker 0: and uh, I kicked Tiamat's ass in two hits because Tiamat decided to waste a whole round Basically cast in a spell that didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah the next game I beat after Mega Man 2 was of course Zelda 1 Which you know.
Speaker 1: nowadays I could beat Zelda 1 in like an hour if I don't even try that hard, you know Well, you know where everything is.
Speaker 0: there was a time when you didn't know.
Speaker 1: so this was a Zelda game that I had played from beginning to end as a kid who didn't know anything with no help and It spent hours and hours and hours and hours and hours Like I must have put like hundreds of hours into that game Just spending so long going back getting some coins going back buying something going back getting some bonds Bombing everything burning everything killing every bad guy a hundred times Beating bosses over and over
Speaker 0: spending forever fighting those blue nights
Speaker 1: figuring out freaking the last level map You know figuring out which way to go on but trial and error and not Knowing which stairs to take in which order to get.
Speaker 0: figuring out where the last dungeon even was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 1: and after all those hours I was finally at Ganon and I had some friends over who also hadn't beaten it and it was like Totally well, and I beat him with only the silver arrow.
Speaker 1: damn.
Speaker 1: Yep I ended the game because I knew that when he teleported he moved around the room and sort of a clockwise fashion You know.
Speaker 1: so I was just.
Speaker 1: I would shoot silver hours at the middle of the room up the right of the room up the middle of The room up the left of the room up the middle of the room up the right of the room and I brought in all These coins with me and eventually he appeared red and I shot him with.
Speaker 1: you know I got him and he was like, holy shit.
Speaker 0: You got actually speaking to Zelda I think the like the other really big with my red potions.
Speaker 0: I read potion.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just always wondered because they always offered you the blue potion Like you could buy it.
Speaker 1: a blue potion is if you were poor and you need to do so.
Speaker 0: No, if you're poor you got and get some freaking rupees.
Speaker 1: But what if you need some potion to get some rupees?
Speaker 0: you don't.
Speaker 1: you can get rupees anywhere just kill stuff But you can always go to the ferry which is the thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so pretty much you had to be stupid to buy the blue potion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and most of the time yeah, it was kind of like giving up the Heart instead of the money.
Speaker 1: Even on the first play of the game.
Speaker 1: I was not so dumb as to take the heart or the potion instead of the heart.
Speaker 0: Yep But the prime my most my most triumphant moment in beating a game because honestly as a kid as much as I love Zelda 2 I never beat it.
Speaker 0: I couldn't beat it.
Speaker 1: That game was really hard.
Speaker 1: I didn't beat it.
Speaker 0: well at our IT as a kid anyway, we had Zelda 2 on the GameCube and Scott and I had a friendly wager like let's just see who beats it first and Scott got kind of ahead.
Speaker 0: But then I really started catching up and one day I was home and I had like an hour to kill before I went to Anime Club and Scott was already over there or on his way at work or something.
Speaker 0: So I'm thinking alright I'm just gonna play Zelda 2 in practice because I got to beat this before him and I'm fighting through the last dungeon.
Speaker 0: I'm fighting and fighting and I make it to the Thunderbird and I got one life left.
Speaker 0: as in if I die It's over and I don't even have much magic.
Speaker 0: I had enough magic to cast like Thunder and then jump.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even cast shield.
Speaker 0: Wow, so I'm like, alright I'm just gonna fight it until I die and I'm fighting it.
Speaker 0: and I'm fighting it and I'm fighting it.
Speaker 0: and as I'm whittling it Down, I'm think like more and more.
Speaker 0: It's like I hope I just die because the closer I get the more it's gonna suck.
Speaker 0: when I finally do die Yep, and I ended up beating the game.
Speaker 0: So I go I. this seemed to be a trend with me.
Speaker 0: I always beat and Nintendo games when I think I'm not gonna beat him.
Speaker 0: I think it's almost like if I'm going in like I'm gonna beat this the pressures on.
Speaker 0: But if I've already resigned myself to losing the pressures off and now I move into this like Zen state of beating a Nintendo game Mmm doesn't work in real life at all.
Speaker 1: And when our Zelda competition I did get to the last level and then I just didn't care it we were both like at the end and it just sucked.
Speaker 0: but So I go to the RIT anime club
Speaker 1: and you
Speaker 0: know, I'm the president I get to talk in front of the club before the thing and Scott's in the audience and I stand up there and I'm like Before we begin I have a very important personal announcement to make and this is something really near and dear to me.
Speaker 0: it's something that took a lot of blood and sweat and tears and I Really got to get this off my chest.
Speaker 0: to all of you out there and the whole club's like, uh-oh What's going on?
Speaker 0: It's rim coming out.
Speaker 0: Does rim have cancer.
Speaker 0: Did he just kill a man?
Speaker 0: What's going on?
Speaker 0: both and then I turn to Scott and say just before club I Beat Zelda 2 for the first and Scott stands up and says no you didn't that's a lie.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, no I did.
Speaker 0: you can go look at the little triforce symbol over link.
Speaker 0: I beat the game and Maybe it's just because there were people in the audience.
Speaker 0: They were all geeks.
Speaker 0: But I got a standing ovation and I will probably never in my life again get a standing ovation for beating a vid you game.
Speaker 1: Let's not start doing that why not?
Speaker 1: that's no good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically after like those early days of NES game beating like game beating became not such a big deal Really?
Speaker 1: I think part of it was I mean like Beating half even beating amazing games like half-life 2 like.
Speaker 1: it's a lot more fun to play than to beat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I never beat half-life 1.
Speaker 0: I got all the way to the end.
Speaker 1: I got to the thought you beat it.
Speaker 0: No, I got to the very end.
Speaker 0: I got to the giant alien fetus thing Yep, and at that point I was like, wow, I pretty much beat it.
Speaker 0: This just isn't fun.
Speaker 0: this last part.
Speaker 1: Oh, you gotta beat it cuz the endings actually pretty.
Speaker 0: I watched the ending.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, I base because if my game came with a save game at the end.
Speaker 0: Oh Alrighty then so I just I skipped the final battle.
Speaker 0: just cuz the battle wasn't fun.
Speaker 0: I tried it for like five minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you've got to like bounce up and throw grenades in its head, but I beat the rest of that alien world And that was great.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the thing with the FPS is always more fun to play than they are to beat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well then again, it depends like the single-player quake one quake two wasn't even fun to play.
Speaker 1: It was somewhat fun to play.
Speaker 0: I didn't play either one at all.
Speaker 1: I think the problem is that they weren't quite half-life 2 with the fun like, you know other non shooting stuff.
Speaker 1: But they weren't quite serious Sam with the all-out shoot him up either
Speaker 0: Hey, but then doom 2 was fun to play but beating it was such an accomplishment
Speaker 1: Really like I beat all the different things to doom and all you got with those screens of text and it felt like shit.
Speaker 0: You beat doom - yeah, did you?
Speaker 0: yeah on ultra violence?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Ah, you go and you kill commander keen.
Speaker 0: No, that's in the bonus levels.
Speaker 1: Yes the bonus level.
Speaker 0: It's not the end of the game.
Speaker 1: That's the end?
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: it is that comes after the end.
Speaker 0: No those two levels are just at the end.
Speaker 0: if you cheat because that's the number indexes where they put them those levels actually take place in Last third of the game.
Speaker 0: if you take the secret exit you do those two levels and then you pick back up where you left Off.
Speaker 0: I'm 100% sure.
Speaker 0: are you going to risk your reputation as a geek on the internet by defying me?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying I don't know Internet, I will bet Scott a thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: that I'm right.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're wrong.
Speaker 1: That's all I said.
Speaker 0: We're gonna.
Speaker 0: you're gonna look it up and you're gonna feel real bad.
Speaker 0: Maybe Actually beating doom 2 on co-op was so much more satisfying than beating it by myself Even though it was easier.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: well I take that back.
Speaker 0: It was easier half the time and the other half of the time I'd get randomly Shotgunned and then I hear laughing on the other end of the phone something like that What are they like?
Speaker 1: I beat like all them.
Speaker 1: well actually Super Metroid is something to be pretty awesome, but Oh, actually, yeah Metroid games in general are pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: to beat mostly the 2d ones But the 3d ones again beating them not as good as playing like when you you're in the end You're just like ah shit.
Speaker 1: There's no more to play.
Speaker 1: I just want to keep playing.
Speaker 0: actually one game that my brother and I would beat when we were kids Semi regularly it was kind of like the hey you want to go beat such-and-such right now and two hours later We'd beat.
Speaker 0: such-and-such was a guerilla war for the NES a game where you have infinity lives.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have infinity lies and you kill infinity bad guys with a bunch of bullets and tanks And it's super fun.
Speaker 1: and you get killed infinity times.
Speaker 0: And when you get to the end the game gives you all these outtakes and the credits are really really funny after you kill Fidel Castro, how about beating bionic commando there?
Speaker 0: beating bionic commando is Special because on one I don't know if any of you have ever played Hitler no fukatsu aka bionic commando.
Speaker 0: But they Nintendo had this big thing where they didn't want anything that was untoward for children in games at all And they super freaked out.
Speaker 0: they were super censoring But they didn't always check the game so much.
Speaker 0: and bionic commando was about Nazis.
Speaker 0: But they took all the Nazis out in the US and replaced him with basically nothing like big iron eagles instead.
Speaker 0: But at the end of the game you wake up the evil guy who they're trying to resurrect and they call him Master D, but it's clearly Adolf Hitler and he's naked And he says the word damn and then he blows up in a pile of gore.
Speaker 0: Nice, and as a little kid.
Speaker 0: I just thought that was awesome.
Speaker 0: Plus beating that game.
Speaker 0: you're likened unto a god if you beat that game all the way through without dying without dying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the ice I guess you could practice it enough to do it.
Speaker 0: But even just beating the game is really freaking hard.
Speaker 0: at the end those last couple of levels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you gotta you gotta have a strategy for the game.
Speaker 1: You know you get fair which levels to go to in which order?
Speaker 1: to get the right items.
Speaker 1: But not do don't do anything unnecessary and at the really tricky parts.
Speaker 1: We have to swing over spikes and fire.
Speaker 1: you got to do it Just right.
Speaker 0: see when you really think about it though most of the endings to NES games were super lame like mr.
Speaker 0: Miyagi winks, or it says congratulations want to play the same game again He'd start or even Zelda like The Legend of Zelda.
Speaker 1: the only reason the ending is okay is because you get to see Zelda and you get to see Ganon and Just scrolls a bunch of text and then you're there holding the Triforce.
Speaker 0: now think of this.
Speaker 0: This is something I just realized just now.
Speaker 0: I knew it about Metroid But Metroid and The Legend of Zelda were two interesting games in that the title Characters or the things in the title are not ever seen in any capacity until the very end of the game.
Speaker 0: in Metroid You don't see a Metroid forever.
Speaker 0: Metroid.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: you forget that there's this Metroid in the game, and I'm right - yeah.
Speaker 0: And the Legend of Zelda you don't see Zelda at all until you win.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I think that's kind of neat.
Speaker 1: I do think that's kind of neat But and I think that was a reason why the endings to those games affected us as kids so much, but at the same time Those endings don't hold up so much anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, I think they do for a different reason.
Speaker 0: the reason the endings affected us wasn't so much that we saw something That was a big part of it.
Speaker 0: Don't get me wrong, but I think part of it was just that Nintendo games to put it in the vernacular.
Speaker 0: We're fucking hard.
Speaker 0: You couldn't beat them you would like.
Speaker 0: you couldn't beat all the Nintendo games no matter how hardcore you were back.
Speaker 0: You would pick like four games or ten games, and you'd be like I'm gonna beat this game.
Speaker 0: And it was like this Battle of will.
Speaker 1: that goes back to our episode about save games because you know when you could.
Speaker 1: when you can save a game you Can beat it more readily?
Speaker 1: It's actually.
Speaker 1: it basically makes your odds of beating the game one whereas without save games It's now really difficult to beat a game.
Speaker 1: because now not only can you do you have to repeat parts?
Speaker 1: You've already done But you have to repeat parts You've already done in order to practice the new part and if you fail at practicing the new part you have to do it all again whereas With a safe game you can just brute force each part of the game in order till it's done.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's sadly what happened to me with both of the Castlevania's for the DS.
Speaker 0: while I really liked them Especially the second one.
Speaker 0: I totally just brute forced it.
Speaker 0: I didn't even try.
Speaker 1: and the thing that gets me about a lot of those games They put all this cool stuff in the games that you don't need to use in order to win at all.
Speaker 0: It's why is it even there like in the first Castlevania for the DS?
Speaker 0: I leveled up a bunch of weapons But then I realized that Why don't I just level up the axe all the way and just use the axe?
Speaker 0: because it's clearly the best weapon in the game.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to ever use anything else.
Speaker 1: I wanted to use the guns.
Speaker 1: I wanted to use the knives I wanted to use the swords, but they all sucked compared to like the axe and the spear.
Speaker 1: so I just hear whatever.
Speaker 0: I always use the axe and the fist because the fist was the fastest thing in case I needed to disrupt an enemy's attack like That one boss and the axe was just to kill everything.
Speaker 1: I use the axes and the Spears because the Spears are longer that I like to keep bad guys away from me.
Speaker 0: The axe did so much more damage.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I use the axe actually the secondary weapon axe I used more than anything because that's that arc that makes it you know Perfect for hitting pretty much every bad guy in the game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I also use that bone vacuum a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Really liked it.
Speaker 1: Games like the end was just unsatisfying.
Speaker 1: It's like I like playing the games.
Speaker 1: the feeling I get playing the game is what I want And I guess the best ending I can hope for is more game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I think part of that contributes to there's no the carrot at like those games.
Speaker 0: beating was a foregone conclusion.
Speaker 0: It's just a matter of putting in the time and that's it and you'll just beat it.
Speaker 0: So I feel like my interest in the game can wane.
Speaker 0: Like there are a lot of games that I start playing I get near the end like the second DS.
Speaker 0: I got real close to the end of Castlevania DS the second one and then I just stopped and I just stopped caring and I Have.
Speaker 0: I've yet to beat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just didn't care.
Speaker 0: but a game like I don't know Gradius or Mario 1 I want to get to the end like beating.
Speaker 0: the game is like the thing and if I'd it's like a Boolean.
Speaker 0: It's not like I beat 80% of the game.
Speaker 0: It's I beat the game or I didn't yep Game beating a long lost art.
Speaker 1: I Guess there's some games though with plots like Final Fantasies where you want to get to the end to see the plot But that's because you don't want to play Final Fantasy.
Speaker 1: You just want to see the plot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was a time when I really wanted to play Final Fantasy though I got to admit I never actually bothered playing Final Fantasy Tactics just because I didn't have a PlayStation.
Speaker 0: and I'm Finally playing Tactics Advance and I'm really digging it and I worry that I might get into these types of games again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I might there's a lot of crap.
Speaker 0: I can make the little math and I can make the clan and I could build the Clan up and I can fight for territory and I can level up my dudes and I can trade the items in the classes and The jobs.
Speaker 1: and I've beaten golden Sun one once.
Speaker 1: but I might go.
Speaker 1: I got halfway through golden Sun 2 before I stopped and I think I might go back and do that because Like the only reason I stopped playing golden Sun 2 halfway through is because there's a point you reach in the game where you have To do a bunch of management that I don't want to do and it's just like I wanted to beat the game But I didn't want to do the management of items and stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah at any rate We should probably stop because I like I said, we have to do a lot of podcasting tonight.
Speaker 1: Yep I'm gonna go do my laundry.
Speaker 0: However, stay tuned tomorrow night because then we will be covering Kinetic on 2007, which was freaking awesome.
Speaker 0: And I would just like to say now but we'll talk about this a lot tomorrow that Steve Bennett is now my man.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm really.
Speaker 0: I like Steve Bennett.
Speaker 1: He's no longer scary.
Speaker 0: He was scary and kind of this Imposing way cuz I you know, we'd heard all I thought he was scary in some sort of a perverted way.
Speaker 0: Well, you see you hear all the rumors about people like all the people in the anime industry.
Speaker 0: But regardless of what may or may not be true Steve Bennett on the anime match game Was perhaps the best anime match game contestant the world has ever seen.
Speaker 1: He was a panelist a panelist.
Speaker 1: same difference, I guess in that respect.
Speaker 1: Yes, I would have to agree this Contestants is an excellent anime match game panelist.
Speaker 0: Perhaps the best the man has charisma.
Speaker 0: I guess This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.