Speaker 1: It's Tuesday August 28th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We review Mario's strikers charge our.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: ah Digi games, I've been really feeling it lately.
Speaker 1: I got to say Yeah, the thing is I got it sort of contained myself and forced myself to beat paper Mario before I play all these other judges that I have to force myself to go to goddamn bed.
Speaker 0: now I mean Sunday night we started playing on natural selection and then midnight rolls around and I my brain says Rim you got to go to work in the morning, and I said shut up you.
Speaker 1: yes I know what's wrong on this server.
Speaker 1: They're not going to bed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know you know what's funny.
Speaker 0: It's back in college rims on the server.
Speaker 1: He's not going to bed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I was like I see Scott there I see waters poison there Alex is there and I guess I can stay up to.
Speaker 1: yeah Why not?
Speaker 1: other people are different ones doing it.
Speaker 0: man now the funny thing was back in RIT.
Speaker 0: That was kind of a valid excuse.
Speaker 0: I mean I when I started playing NS or counter-strike or tribes or anything at night didn't matter what day of the week it was.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like oh, I have class in the morning.
Speaker 0: It was I played until the game wound down and everyone went to bed and sometimes that just didn't happen, and I just kept playing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's how The multiplayer games go.
Speaker 0: it really took a lot of effort to say to myself all right I am going to stop playing now that the round is ended and not play the next round Despite the fact that I'm the only one leaving the server right now, and I felt like a loser.
Speaker 0: I actually played one more round Because Scott comes in immediately was like man.
Speaker 0: the round you miss was like the best one.
Speaker 1: It was a pretty good around that last round.
Speaker 0: there I was because the teams were starting to.
Speaker 0: it was kind of bad because Like one team would get creamed every round and then as time went on it started kind of even and out as the good players And the bad players started to get to know each other and the team started working properly.
Speaker 0: like one round.
Speaker 0: We were aliens and some guy built sense first Which is okay if everyone on the team is down with that.
Speaker 1: I was on the Marines that time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was awesome.
Speaker 1: That was the one time that I would.
Speaker 0: yeah thing is I was like awesome.
Speaker 0: now I can ambush and focus and thing is how well I did.
Speaker 1: totally depended on the team.
Speaker 1: like that last round when you weren't there.
Speaker 1: I was doing real well, but the team lost anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we held out for a while.
Speaker 1: That was a little back and forth.
Speaker 0: We just couldn't get the heavy train rolling And I've been playing my DS on the train instead of reading my Cisco books.
Speaker 1: I Don't know why I ran out of stuff to do on the train today.
Speaker 1: I gotta lay more stuff and bring it.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine that happened.
Speaker 1: I mean think it didn't run out of stuff.
Speaker 1: I ran out of stuff on me.
Speaker 1: Oh bring more.
Speaker 0: That's the worst thing in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see I don't know why I bought a little portable DVD player for the train because I got a lot of DVDs I want to watch.
Speaker 1: I'd use a laptop.
Speaker 1: Why waste that?
Speaker 0: because I well one because that thing's really cheap and a really tiny and really portable.
Speaker 0: My laptop is tiny and it's a lot smaller than your laptop.
Speaker 1: It can't be that small.
Speaker 0: It's time.
Speaker 0: It's just a battery plus.
Speaker 1: If you compare size and screen and screen quality my my laptop has a better ratio.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: besides a lot even a cheap laptop that's worth a damn is like 700 bucks.
Speaker 0: This thing was like a Hundred and something.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I mean it was super cheap and I'm kind of holding out on a laptop for a while.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't know what you're holding out for because I don't have any particular need for one.
Speaker 0: all the work I do is online stuff.
Speaker 0: If a computer is not connected to the internet.
Speaker 0: There's almost nothing I can use it for right now.
Speaker 0: Google Gears Yeah, it doesn't let me do my Google Docs offline and my email offline yet I think it might and if not, you can do something about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm holding out Whatever, but I got this thing like alright.
Speaker 0: now I can watch that documentary.
Speaker 0: I bought about Rome.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute, but I'm still playing Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I'm still playing Final Fantasy Tactics Advance Oh, and I'm still reading all those books.
Speaker 0: Fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I think I should start going to work earlier and taking the longer train.
Speaker 1: Yeah I pre-ordered the Metroid Prime on the Amazon and I'm actually kind of glad that it's supposedly not gonna ship until like September 10th or something because I'm still playing paper Mario and stuff and I'm not gonna have time to play Metroid.
Speaker 1: so better it not be here.
Speaker 0: Plus I got to say I was reading around the press and what people are saying about that game.
Speaker 0: and It's rare that I care what reviewers say and it's rare that I care what people buzzing about a game say because I'll just kind Of wait until it all foments.
Speaker 0: I've yet to hear a human being utter anything bad about the game other than possibly that it might be a little easy.
Speaker 1: You should just play the freakin Metroid Prime meaning.
Speaker 0: I don't like controlling any sort of 3d first-person game.
Speaker 1: Metroid Prime isn't like an FBI.
Speaker 0: I didn't say FPS.
Speaker 0: I said first-person anything an FBA.
Speaker 1: It's not it's it's.
Speaker 1: you never played it.
Speaker 1: you have no idea.
Speaker 0: it's got started playing it.
Speaker 0: I just didn't really like it.
Speaker 1: You said you're not gonna.
Speaker 1: I don't know why you think you're gonna like this other one cuz.
Speaker 0: I just don't like using those sticks.
Speaker 0: I hate analog sticks.
Speaker 0: I want what you barely.
Speaker 1: you only have to use the stick to walk in Metroid Prime, and that's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Using a stick to walk you do that in any 3d game now.
Speaker 0: I gotta look around a little bit.
Speaker 0: I don't like that.
Speaker 1: You know you look around holding down the button.
Speaker 0: You don't look around with the other stick, but I still got to look around with the stick.
Speaker 1: You don't walk while looking around.
Speaker 0: I didn't say walk and look around.
Speaker 0: I said look around I don't like that.
Speaker 1: you you got a problem in your head.
Speaker 0: there I'm just.
Speaker 0: I like super super control of my five a game But it's a game where they're super.
Speaker 0: super control is not necessary I know and I'm just saying it bothers me in any any time.
Speaker 0: I think you're always a viewpoint every time I control a portal through which I view a world in the first person.
Speaker 1: If I don't have so you have.
Speaker 1: you have a psychological problem that prevents you from See.
Speaker 1: you have a. you have a mental disorder that prevents you from being able to enjoy one of the greatest games.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: even then I wasn't - I don't.
Speaker 0: the only Metroid game.
Speaker 0: I really liked was Super Metroid.
Speaker 0: I'll be honest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're stupid.
Speaker 0: I played Metroid 1 and I beat it But I didn't.
Speaker 0: I beat it because it was a Nintendo game, and you have to beat it.
Speaker 1: I think you just because you refused to play them in Refuse to play him what.
Speaker 0: I played Metroid a lot.
Speaker 1: I didn't say in Metroid the Metroid Prime I did play I play.
Speaker 1: I did for a while how waiting for a while like I never seen you play it ever.
Speaker 0: I played it for like four total hours.
Speaker 0: I just didn't get into it And then I stopped.
Speaker 0: and then I had better things to do like tribes and counter-strike and everything else in my life.
Speaker 1: tribes Wasn't working in those days.
Speaker 1: by the time Metroid Prime 1 came out traps was dead.
Speaker 0: I tried playing the game way after it came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, try means like turn it on once and then turn it off.
Speaker 0: I think four hours is enough to know if I like a game or not.
Speaker 1: I don't believe you played the game for four hours all right, whatever.
Speaker 1: What do you care?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that you got a problem, okay?
Speaker 1: Anyway, and I know what you think that somehow you seem to think like there are all these games to the Gamecube And they basically make the same game for the Wii and they change the controls slightly and somehow You think the game's gonna?
Speaker 1: You're gonna like the game any more than you liked it on the when it came to Twilight Princess.
Speaker 0: It was a hundred percent true.
Speaker 0: I love Twilight Princess.
Speaker 0: You didn't you barely even played it.
Speaker 0: I don't have time.
Speaker 1: I think you just lying is?
Speaker 0: I want to play it?
Speaker 1: you either don't like You know either don't like Twilight Princess, or you do like hot green of time.
Speaker 1: you didn't know.
Speaker 0: just Twilight Princess is more polished.
Speaker 1: So it's the same goddamn game.
Speaker 0: It's more polished.
Speaker 0: It went over the line.
Speaker 1: I don't know what your problem is.
Speaker 1: Anyway, maybe you should do some newses and things like that.
Speaker 0: I was waiting for you all right.
Speaker 1: So that Bioshock game everyone's talking about.
Speaker 0: yeah, I got to play the demo still.
Speaker 0: yeah I haven't had time.
Speaker 1: I got that new video card yesterday.
Speaker 1: So I played the demo and I can see what everyone's talking about with this game.
Speaker 1: It's it's real heavy like it weighs Heavily on you when you play it and the demos real shorts.
Speaker 1: and I think I actually kind of liked that the demo was short because as Amazing as the experience was and as the work of art the game obviously was It's sort of like was so heavy.
Speaker 1: It was like eating a really filling cheesecake where it tasted so good, but then my stomach was on not feeling so well I guess along by those tokens then doom 2 is just like a sprite something like that.
Speaker 1: just Yeah, so I was sort of glad that the demo was short because as amazing as it was it was sort of I Sort of didn't want to.
Speaker 1: I got this feeling I didn't want to keep playing because my you know like the same reason you don't want to eat any more cheesecake because your stomach Is full because it's so rich.
Speaker 1: So I think it's definitely Just from playing the short demo I can tell it's one of the best games ever top 50 top 100 something like that.
Speaker 1: But it's not like this amazing game of all time.
Speaker 1: Everyone's talking about it like it is but I definitely think that right now It's totally worth playing if you have money this weekend.
Speaker 0: I'm probably gonna play the demo and I might just buy it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it only takes like a few minutes to get the demo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the The one thing I'm gonna say the news is is that valve, you know the people who are making Team fortress 2 and half-life and all you know the business.
Speaker 0: Oh touch Sasha There.
Speaker 1: they have banned Bioshock in their office.
Speaker 1: not that not like you can't bring the game here or we don't like this game Keep it out.
Speaker 1: But like ok guys if we're playing this game, we're never gonna finish our games.
Speaker 1: So they're not gonna.
Speaker 1: no one there is gonna play Bioshock until They're done with Team Fortress 2 and all those games, you know.
Speaker 0: Judging from what people have said about the game and what I know about those people I would wager that because of that Team Fortress 2 is gonna be released in about 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: It's nothing like that Because as soon as they're done with the Team Fortress 2 I guess they're giving everyone in the company a copy of.
Speaker 1: I Imagine
Speaker 0: this imagine back when tribes 2 was that its prime and if suddenly RIT came down and said we are blocking access to the tribes 2 servers until rim and Scott take this terrible test and pass it
Speaker 1: That terrible test to be done
Speaker 0: So fast
Speaker 1: either that or
Speaker 0: everyone in the school who has control over the routers would be dead
Speaker 1: cares about Team Fortress.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: We just have a cable modem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, but yeah think about a game.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like that thing they have in Japan where you know It's like a Dragon Quest game comes out in a school day.
Speaker 1: No one goes to school.
Speaker 1: It's you know, like what are those?
Speaker 0: I gotta say though?
Speaker 1: I heard that that's just an urban legend that but I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 1: it's totally fine.
Speaker 0: I can say that when Team Fortress 2 comes out.
Speaker 0: I'm Almost certainly going to take the day after off work.
Speaker 1: I probably will as well.
Speaker 1: and you know what unlike Metroid Prime Team Fortress 2 comes out on Steam.
Speaker 1: So there's no chance of Amazon not getting it to me on time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's no way.
Speaker 1: a media pre-loaded before the game is out It's on my hard drive and then as soon as the game is released valve unlocks it.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a DRM but not really because they give you they.
Speaker 1: all they're really doing is just giving you most of the game And then they give you the last bit of the game at the last second.
Speaker 0: This is a new thing for me.
Speaker 0: I mean, I skipped something at RIT to drive Scott to get his GameCube the day it came out.
Speaker 0: But well skip something kind of because Scott picked it up way before the class, but I just didn't go to the class.
Speaker 0: But I've never taken a day off of work because of a video game and this might be that day.
Speaker 1: I think it might be that day just because this is one game where I think I'm gonna play it a lot and I want To make sure my skills are up.
Speaker 1: I don't have the low skills rim weighted.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So speaking of valve, huh?
Speaker 0: there's an article on slash out here and I'm just gonna get right to the point of it because I got a few things to Say and then there's a slightly tangential conversation that I'm pretty sure is just gonna happen.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna quote the slash dot right here valves.
Speaker 0: president Gabe Newell is calling new.
Speaker 1: well, I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: new Is Microsoft's choice to make DirectX 10 Vista only a quotes.
Speaker 0: I'm double quoting here.
Speaker 0: terrible mistake.
Speaker 0: That is harmed gaming.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what it is is that the developers want to make DirectX 10 games.
Speaker 1: They want to make fancier games or the fancier graphics But making it Vista only means that those sorts of new fancy games are only gonna work on the fancy Vista and a lot of people are resistant to buying Vista.
Speaker 1: thus game developers resist making their games DirectX 10 and The games are held back because Vista doesn't March forward.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean basically the argument is that people aren't switching to Vista for various reasons.
Speaker 0: So as a result game developers aren't using DirectX 10 so much because most people don't have an operating system And it's kind of this catch-22 where it'll never get used because no one's using it.
Speaker 0: but at the same time and actually now I saw it at work, but when I get home, they updated the article and Apparently people are pointing out that Windows XP's uptake numbers were somewhat similarly slow when it was first announced and a lot of people stuck with Windows 2000 for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it's sort of true.
Speaker 1: when XP came out I had the same feelings about it that I have towards Vista now like a new Windows.
Speaker 1: No, it sucks Blair, right and then just eventually it's like alright, I got a blank computer.
Speaker 1: I need a Windows and That's the only windows.
Speaker 1: There is the new one and you just use it and it's not really that much different from the old window.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'll end up using Vista whenever I build a new computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you just built one.
Speaker 0: so five years Yeah, so maybe I'll use this Vista 2020 or whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe Wista That comes after W. I don't know.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that seems to be.
Speaker 1: the Windows goes is Windows Windows?
Speaker 0: You know Windows
Speaker 1: is a thing that people have to put on computers and the way that they get an install base is by Removing the old version and putting out the new version and over time as people get new computers The old version goes away and the new version comes in even if people don't actively Adopt it.
Speaker 1: However, that's gonna take a couple years and game development and advancement goes a lot faster than that Yep, and it's it is holding back the game developers on the PC.
Speaker 1: Also, the Xbox killed PC gaming.
Speaker 1: I still while there are many good PC Yeah, really kind of hand-fisted that in there I just always have to say that whenever this issue comes up is despite the bio shocks and The orange boxes and all these things right thing.
Speaker 1: all these games are on the Xbox also.
Speaker 0: Okay, see now here's an interesting thing and I wonder about this because I no one.
Speaker 0: regardless of whatever people say You know, I don't like Microsoft or Microsoft is evil.
Speaker 0: You can't claim that Microsoft is stupid because Microsoft makes all its money and they know exactly what they're doing most of the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm still pretty sure.
Speaker 1: if you look at PC gaming when the Xbox appeared all the types of games that were big on the PC you know FPS is an RTS and all those things started coming out in the Xbox and they started diminishing from the PC.
Speaker 1: and It's still that way.
Speaker 1: and what you gonna do?
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is as we were talking about just before we did the show team forgers - which I've waited for For a long time.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I go off on a tangent.
Speaker 1: just cuz I want to and now you're gonna do the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the semi unrelated.
Speaker 0: You said the keyword now.
Speaker 0: I got to go in on this.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's actually kind of related to what you said.
Speaker 0: So Team Fortress 2 is coming out on the Xbox Of course and on the PC Now.
Speaker 0: this is one of those games with the online, you know There's not.
Speaker 0: like you play single-player Team Fortress 2 you fight with people.
Speaker 0: Now technically and they've admitted this it is possible and feasible for all Team Fortress 2 people to play against each other Meaning they're already doing it at the valve office.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean in the meaning that I could in the when the game comes out theoretically log on to a server and some Xbox kid could log on to a server and I could play with my widescreen monitor mouse keyboard scripts and whatnot against a kid with an Xbox controller and a TV.
Speaker 0: and I hope desperately that Microsoft allows this to come to pass
Speaker 1: Because they put a little icon next to everyone's name
Speaker 0: Because I want all of those kids out there to know and to quake in fear when they realize that if they see that Little PC icon that means I got a mouse and that means that I can shoot them in the head and they can't shoot me In the head, that's
Speaker 1: how it's done.
Speaker 0: but if I were Microsoft just no way in hell I would let that happen.
Speaker 0: because if They they let this happen and you could just play against people.
Speaker 0: It would become pretty apparent to the gaming media pretty quickly that and I I'll stand by the statement That on average people on PCs would be stupidly better at the game than people on the console just because the controls are better.
Speaker 1: So the thing is the argument that you could make in that case is hey People who are playing on PCs are more likely to be hardcore gamers with more skills anyway.
Speaker 0: Well that just makes the disparity even worse because even if you put someone I just think that the cap on how good you can Be at an FPS that I'm saying someone might say the controls not the difference.
Speaker 1: It's all the better players use the PC not that you know, they're better because the controls are better.
Speaker 0: Well, the way around that is to force people to play on the opposite consoles for a while and see what happened.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: But even then even if that were the case people just noticed that Wow PC gamers kick our asses and I wonder if that might make young punk kids think I gotta get me a PC mom Buy me a PC.
Speaker 0: I gotta play Team Fortune on TV.
Speaker 0: Fuck the Xbox.
Speaker 1: Oh Whatever.
Speaker 1: It doesn't.
Speaker 1: it doesn't really matter right now.
Speaker 0: It matters to me.
Speaker 0: I really care about this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know there's Darfur and there's a rack and no I care about showing these console kids.
Speaker 0: what for?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess the last thing to say just sort of mandatory is the packs was this weekend.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we didn't go.
Speaker 1: Many awesome things happen there.
Speaker 1: I watched some YouTube videos and I was as Moved by the videos as I imagined I would have been being there.
Speaker 0: Alright pack staff.
Speaker 0: I'll note lately that we don't go to cons though.
Speaker 0: I mean it's not on purpose.
Speaker 0: We just end up not going to cons unless we're doing some sort of entertainment.
Speaker 0: Get us to be guests at packs and I can guarantee we'll be.
Speaker 1: I think the problem is that all the guests at packs are 10,000 times better than we are.
Speaker 0: I think the only problem is not even that.
Speaker 0: packs is the only convention in them in the world Where I don't want to be a guest because I want to go to the con as a person and do all the con stuff.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: I don't want to sit at some table and do a show.
Speaker 0: I want to sit there and play video games.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: So I think next year we've decided we're gonna go to packs no matter what.
Speaker 1: I guess not.
Speaker 1: no matter what something crazy Could happen like plane crashes we die Terminally ill in the hospital, etc.
Speaker 1: But other barring that we're going to packs no matter what next year no matter what.
Speaker 1: I'm not committing to that yet, but come on you.
Speaker 1: so I'm going to matter.
Speaker 1: I'll go without you yo, no matter what I'll go in no matter what.
Speaker 0: ah Sure.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I'm down.
Speaker 1: It's recorded.
Speaker 0: It is what you gonna do.
Speaker 0: I will know how it is.
Speaker 0: You know, I never thought of that.
Speaker 0: I've never done a malicious edit before.
Speaker 0: yeah, well don't start Things of the day.
Speaker 0: ass Mmm balls.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, you know, I'm like ass and balls.
Speaker 0: you say actually I wanted to say a more poly syllabic one But I think it's poly syllabic.
Speaker 0: I said a Vic and I'm gonna go with that because it's a syllable.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I can't believe this hasn't been a thing of the day or anything.
Speaker 0: We might have mentioned it now and then but it's kind of like Zombocom just way.
Speaker 0: Whoa We never talked about this thing of the day classic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you've seen this before whatever everyone's seen it before We talking about.
Speaker 0: ah, a lot of people haven't seen it before I'm sure.
Speaker 1: okay I'm sure one person at least one person listen the show hasn't but I think the majority Have.
Speaker 1: because if you're hip enough to the net that you're listening to this podcast on Tuesday You're hip enough to the net to know about this thing.
Speaker 0: Well, I would hope so because I'd point out that in the front row crew where we practically worship Horatio hornblower I'm running a game based on that in burning wheel like starting in a month or two and Suddenly it came out of the woodwork that most of the crew has never seen a single episode of that show.
Speaker 1: I know it was so weird Like we watched it as a group in college and we've watched it as a group since then.
Speaker 1: But apparently a lot of people major people haven't seen it is kind of weird.
Speaker 0: I find that frightening.
Speaker 0: but no this is my thing of the day the angry video game nerd.
Speaker 0: Basically it is videos of this kid playing shitty old video game really kid.
Speaker 0: I think he's our age Kid guy, he's our age.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I can still say kid fine kid guy playing these video games Games such as I don't know Simon's Quest or die hard or Custer's revenge.
Speaker 0: And he reviews them and his style includes shall we say some profanity a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is is profanity is sort of like.
Speaker 1: is profanity?
Speaker 1: is profanity in the same way that Looney Tunes?
Speaker 0: is Violence like instead of saying man fuck shit this game.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: He'll say things like I'd rather let a buffalo Take a diarrhea dump in my ear.
Speaker 1: That's that's the theme song.
Speaker 1: it is Yeah, but he'll be like this is a pile of cockadookie something in you know, your mother's something I can't do it.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm not the angry video game nerd.
Speaker 0: and he is yeah, and the best part is it's half, you know It's funny the way he talks and he reviews the games really well.
Speaker 0: but the other half of it is pure nostalgia because the first one I ever saw was when he talked about the original Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles game for the NES and Everything he showed was just oh, man.
Speaker 0: I remember that.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: I remember that Basically what he goes for most of the time is those incredibly old NES games that were incredibly and frustratingly difficult But as a kid you didn't mind that.
Speaker 1: and now when you get to something like that in a video game You're just like fuck this game, but he goes and he brings you a kid.
Speaker 0: you had what like for video games.
Speaker 1: He brings these games up and he Brings you back to the feelings you had when you were a kid in that same incredibly frustratingly difficult spot in the game.
Speaker 1: And you remember and he gets he's like fuck this shit.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: This is Tara and you're like, yes It was.
Speaker 1: I remember I did the same thing.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's one scene where he's like that fuck done and he's biting his NES controller like that.
Speaker 0: And I did that more than once.
Speaker 1: I never bit the NES controller.
Speaker 1: Oh my god our friend Luke.
Speaker 0: I Got a story here.
Speaker 0: This is a nice aside But yeah, angry video game nerd.
Speaker 0: So a biting controllers, right?
Speaker 0: Remember when Advance Wars 1 came out for the GBA?
Speaker 0: Awesome, awesome game, but the advanced campaign, you know, like the I'm hardcore I'm gonna play the hard version was fucking hard and arbitrary like it was crazy Basically, it moved the Advance Wars 1 in the u.s.
Speaker 1: In on the hardest mode Stopped being a tactics turn-based strategy game into a puzzle game with a solution like move this guy here Move this guy there who this guy here, you know down to the spot.
Speaker 1: It had to be perfect and exact.
Speaker 0: so, uh, he was determined to beat this with an s-rank and he did or even just beat it and It was so frustrating.
Speaker 0: and he kind of had this habit where if he lost he'd either squeeze the game or really hard like.
Speaker 0: Or he'd kind of like drive in his mouth and kind of go like I have and bite it a bit.
Speaker 0: one day He loses a mission and he goes to his mouth and he goes And then he goes and then he throws the game boy across the room and holds his mouth.
Speaker 0: What had happened was he bit it but his tongue went against that little port and it gave him a little bit of a shock.
Speaker 1: Haha, oh and no exaggeration true story He'll admit it.
Speaker 1: he failed graduate school because of Advance Wars 1 for the GBA.
Speaker 0: It's not a joke.
Speaker 1: It's not a joke.
Speaker 1: I swear to God.
Speaker 1: It's a hundred percent true.
Speaker 1: Luckily in advance was too much and thus failed.
Speaker 0: luckily It didn't matter because he still got a badass job.
Speaker 0: But yeah, actually now he runs an awesome anime store You know, it shows you graduate school.
Speaker 1: not too necessary unless you really want to do something specific like be a doctor or a lawyer.
Speaker 0: I mean, it depends on the field or a dentist.
Speaker 0: He did.
Speaker 0: Okay I think his life was probably better off having not gotten that mask.
Speaker 1: I think so as well.
Speaker 1: Anyway, think of the day for me.
Speaker 1: Do you remember that thing of the day with the guy who said are you a girl?
Speaker 1: Is it Halloween?
Speaker 0: Sexy nun sexy banana sexy whatever.
Speaker 1: so I wondered who that guy was and I still haven't totally found out but apparently his name Is Nick.
Speaker 1: I. I guess that's his name of the character everybody.
Speaker 1: But anyway he's made two other videos of that are basically parodies of low-budget commercials and One of them is for a fireworks emporium where there's a crappy rap song and it's okay.
Speaker 1: the other one is for like his winter wonderland where he sells a bunch of Christmas shit and it's See the thing is like.
Speaker 1: I get the feeling it's as funny as the Halloween one But because I've seen the Halloween one it sort of doesn't feel as funny to me.
Speaker 1: But if you like that Halloween one from the Goyles costume warehouse You gotta watch these other two videos because even if they're not as funny They're still funny and worth the like five minutes it takes to watch him plus I'll admit whenever someone says Goyles.
Speaker 0: I just crack up and I don't know Goyles.
Speaker 0: You should watch Popeye.
Speaker 0: I used to watch Popeye, but you're the one who's never seen the live-action Popeye movie with Robin Williams.
Speaker 1: No, I've never seen a live-action Popeye.
Speaker 1: No, but you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about buying Robin Williams.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about buying this box set of incredibly old Popeye cartoons.
Speaker 0: I really like the Aladdin one.
Speaker 1: I remember that There's also an incredibly old Popeye like comic collection book.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about buying - I don't I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy one of the other I think probably the cartoon.
Speaker 0: Ah before we go on I just got to say the angry video game nerd.
Speaker 0: I think I might link to it specifically But if I don't if you haven't seen this before before you watch anything else that guy's done.
Speaker 0: Go watch the one about Bible games.
Speaker 1: No go watch the one about Silver Surfer.
Speaker 1: You know, we always talk about how incredibly difficult Silver Surfer is.
Speaker 1: I think he put it best in his Silver Surfer review.
Speaker 0: The difficulty of this game is legendary.
Speaker 1: Difficulty is legendary.
Speaker 0: This way if you're a gamer like straight-up video gamer watch the Silver Surfer one because it's mostly yeah, fuck that game.
Speaker 0: But if you're just looking for humor watch the Bible games one and watch it all the way through.
Speaker 1: trust me on this Because when he's throwing that rock at those animals And he is still making these because he just came out with the Atari porn one Oh my god, Atari porn and he's still he's still got he's still on the ball.
Speaker 1: All his videos are as good as they always were All right.
Speaker 1: today we're gonna talk about the new Wii game the Mario strikers charge.
Speaker 0: We kind of held off since we wanted to play it enough to get a full course.
Speaker 1: We didn't play it so much more.
Speaker 0: I played it a bunch.
Speaker 0: I played it online a little bit.
Speaker 0: I understand the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically this is a sequel a direct sequel to the other Mario strikers for the GameCube Which is the first one and it's pretty much the same game.
Speaker 1: But they have made you.
Speaker 1: we did a review on that original one, didn't we?
Speaker 0: So yeah, we did.
Speaker 1: you go listen to that and it's pretty much the same game.
Speaker 1: But it does have significant changes and I think those significant changes make the game Superior.
Speaker 1: sort.
Speaker 1: of the same way the GameCube Mario tennis was better than the N64 Mario or how Smash Brothers Melee was better than just the original Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: Yep So this is an incremental improvement on the other Mario strikers and there's pretty much no reason to play the old one now that we Have the new one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'll for one.
Speaker 0: if you like the old one just buy the new one.
Speaker 0: don't even question you have a way.
Speaker 1: I mean if you don't have a Wii this is not a game that is so good.
Speaker 1: You should buy a Wii to play it.
Speaker 0: No, those games are coming.
Speaker 1: You should wait until there are more games.
Speaker 1: You know wait until there's strikers Wii Sports.
Speaker 1: We got those two after Metroid and may and brawl come out.
Speaker 1: then you can buying a Wii will be worth the money.
Speaker 1: but right now this if you have a Wii get the game.
Speaker 1: if you don't have a Wii don't run out and buy one for This and two.
Speaker 0: if you didn't listen to our old review or you think you don't like sports games one This is Mario sports are not sports games.
Speaker 1: Don't tell yourself that they are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if you don't like those Madden whatever games, don't worry about it Yeah, if you don't like say FIFA, whatever.
Speaker 1: This is nothing like a sports game.
Speaker 1: This is Something else.
Speaker 0: So before we get into the game, it's a lot more like NBA Jam.
Speaker 0: We talked about this a lot when we reviewed the original and it's it's times 10. in this game.
Speaker 0: The style and the character design and all the little extras in the game that don't actually affect gameplay are So important and this is one of the reasons why Nintendo's first-party games tend to kick everyone's asses.
Speaker 0: They went the extra mile and there's so much in this game that doesn't directly affect gameplay.
Speaker 0: But just the way the characters move and the way they talk to you and the way they yell at each other and the way They react when they get a goal or when they miss a goal or when they miss a shot is Just.
Speaker 0: it adds so much to the experience that you'd be surprised.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: I mean the first one had all that going on full on and the new one has it going on even more Except I think that the way they've designed the character models wearing all that armor I like the old way better where they were just sort of sporty but with attitude.
Speaker 1: But other than that everything about the new one is better.
Speaker 1: in those respects.
Speaker 1: I mean every character sort of has like their own music and it's like each one has a different kind of music.
Speaker 1: like Mario has some rock and roll and Luigi has like like a hat dance kind of thing.
Speaker 0: and you know, Luigi is like Desperado coming down from the sky.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: And a kid Koopa is all.
Speaker 0: Quentin Tarantino You feel like he's just.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah freaking princess like peaches like a Deva.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah
Speaker 1: Daisy sort of techno and all the music no matter what genre it is or which character you've picked is Totally intense and builds up the energy sort of like the way music in a you know A sports stadium builds you up, which is what you should do in a sports game Sporting arena.
Speaker 0: while Luigi's all banjo II I really like his.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's banjo II but somehow it builds energy in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's get it on.
Speaker 0: and much like the other game The character is just.
Speaker 0: you know, every Nintendo sports or Mario Kart Mario Tennis, whatever.
Speaker 0: They're good games They're great games, but the characters are still just Mario.
Speaker 0: It's a me a Mario It's nothing.
Speaker 0: they don't go beyond that.
Speaker 0: these games these Mario strikers games Go one step past that and the characters have attitude.
Speaker 0: They're pissy Sometimes they're hardcore and they want to kick your ass.
Speaker 1: That's I think what's necessary for a soccer game.
Speaker 0: When Yoshi looks at you and he's like, I'm gonna kick your ass and you stink.
Speaker 0: Oh crap He's coming to kick my ass.
Speaker 0: You don't get that in any other Nintendo game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when you get like, you know kid Koopa giving you like the old slit throat like yeah bitches I think my favorite thing in the whole game and Wario farts at you.
Speaker 0: Oh my god My favorite thing is something like when someone makes a shot It shows whoever made the shot like celebrating and everyone celebrates in a bunch of different ways and they're really funny and they're really good.
Speaker 0: but Wario and kid Koopa have two of the greatest.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: We're losing the game animations.
Speaker 0: Wario just fucking commit suicide.
Speaker 0: He's like, I cannot go on and he pulls out a bomb and blows himself up.
Speaker 0: Kid Koopa just like it shows like a like a camera view of his face and then he punches the camera and then it cuts To another camera and he's just attacking all the press cameras around him and yelling It's just So great.
Speaker 1: It is pretty great.
Speaker 1: All right, let's talk about the actual gameplay going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the actual game All right.
Speaker 1: Now if you've played a soccer game before any sort of hockey's maybe even a basketball game before right?
Speaker 1: it's sort of like, you know, you're passing you're shooting you're moving right and You're also sort of defending the goal or the net in some way, you know Like if you play ice hockey for the NES, you sort of got to control your guys and control the goalie.
Speaker 1: Well, like the original strikers you don't control your goalie at all.
Speaker 1: Your goalie is automatic.
Speaker 0: now I really like that.
Speaker 1: I like that because controlling a goalie has always been annoying and It basically making me not have to do that is kind of okay.
Speaker 1: But you're always worrying like okay now the game I whether I win or lose depends on this.
Speaker 1: You know goalie that's controlled by an AI.
Speaker 1: I might suck.
Speaker 0: the game is so well crafted that one the goalies really good and stuff's not gonna just randomly get in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and two the D. how well your defense is depends a lot more on how your defenseman play and how you get them.
Speaker 1: I think I think this is where the game makes a serious improvement on the original Strikers and the original strikers.
Speaker 1: they were like you could set it up where you just score because you knew how to what you could.
Speaker 1: Oh, you could like pass and position your guys in a certain way to be like pass Lob pass kick in the out of the air and it would just go in most of the time Right.
Speaker 1: and the new one.
Speaker 1: They have this system of charging up the ball in addition to a bunch of other things like skill shots and charge up shots And items to where it's not so much a game of score right beat the goalie.
Speaker 1: It's a game of you know the ball.
Speaker 1: if you just shoot the ball It will never go in.
Speaker 1: if you just walk and shoot it you have to play.
Speaker 1: you have to make a play in the field which is not easy and takes a significant amount of time and Unless you make a play in the field Your chance of the ball going in the net when you eventually shoot is pretty much nil.
Speaker 1: So it's pretty much the game becomes.
Speaker 1: You are trying to make a play in the field when you have the ball and when you don't have the ball You're trying to prevent the other player from making a play in the field and it's all this Offensive and defensive maneuvering in the field.
Speaker 1: and then the actual shooting is pretty much like I've made the play.
Speaker 1: All I have to do is push shoot and it'll go in.
Speaker 1: you know eighty percent of the or ninety percent depending on how good your play was.
Speaker 1: and That's and I've never seen a game that handles it that way before and it's really great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because ice hockey is really fun But you know the original ice hockey for the NES.
Speaker 0: yeah but the game gets to the point where the only thing that matters is how good of a goaltender you are and There's not so much maneuvering on the field and granted that's a simple game But most sports games are like that.
Speaker 0: This game is just focused down to this.
Speaker 0: one aspect of play which I would argue in Football or soccer depending on what country you're in is the most fun part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean when you watch like a sporting event, right if someone just like scores and scores and scores, you know Normally, that's why I always got bored with a lot of sports games because eventually you figure out the trick to just score a lot And you just keep doing that trick over and over again in the games over.
Speaker 1: in this There is no trick to just score a lot.
Speaker 1: You have to make a play and you can't just make the same identical play.
Speaker 1: because like just a pass and a shot is not A play a play is like, you know pass pass pass charge up shoot rebound pass Lob in the air shoot, you know, and it's not like the same thing every time you have to.
Speaker 1: you know I mean keep the ball moving and do some tricks and things to sort of build it up and Pull something off without the ball getting stolen or without your guys getting hit.
Speaker 0: now That's also hit with an item the really fun part that you know.
Speaker 0: We said you charge up the ball anytime you take direct action on the ball.
Speaker 0: It adds energy to it and eventually turns white meaning it's fully charged.
Speaker 0: and the more charged It is the better chance it as of going in.
Speaker 0: if someone makes a shot But at the same time a white shot is not going to automatically go in because how close you are Where the goalie is.
Speaker 0: I mean if the goal is distracted for whatever reason like from a rebound shot Then even a low-powered shots gonna go in because the goal is in the wrong spot.
Speaker 0: He can't get there in time Yep, but to the charge keeps the energy going because once you're making an offensive play You can't just back off and then try again.
Speaker 0: You got to keep pushing.
Speaker 0: keep pushing because if they grab the ball from you It's still fully charged because you charged it up and now they're coming straight for that again Like let's say they grab the ball from you.
Speaker 1: Like if the goalie catches the ball, right it immediately starts losing charge.
Speaker 1: So the game encourages you to keep making lots of action and not just like sit around and bide your time And you know walk around in circles or anything.
Speaker 0: It's great for rebounds because it's like rebound rebound.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you shoot shooting charges the ball up.
Speaker 1: passing charges the ball up.
Speaker 1: charging charging shots charge the ball up.
Speaker 0: doing things Charges the ball up.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Another thing I had to talk about in this game of the skill shots which are new and awesome and they actually take skill.
Speaker 1: basically Your second you you.
Speaker 1: the way it worked in the original strikers is you would choose a team leader and teammates.
Speaker 1: So for example, you choose Luigi and and booze.
Speaker 1: you'd have one Luigi and three booze on your team and this one.
Speaker 1: There are a lot more teammates and a lot more team leaders and you can mix up your teammates.
Speaker 1: you can have like a boo a hammer brother and a Goon, not a goon.
Speaker 0: Not a goon.
Speaker 0: Goon would be useless in soccer.
Speaker 1: I know right all he has his feet There was the ball hit him.
Speaker 0: That's the end.
Speaker 1: You can headbutt it really well.
Speaker 1: I know that head butting Mario from the bottom Like your team could be a Birdo a mole man and a hammer brother or and Waluigi or two booze and A Koopa Troopa.
Speaker 1: and then Luigi and they all have different.
Speaker 0: I always play Luigi's.
Speaker 1: That's my exam.
Speaker 1: Yeah But each sidekick right the main player.
Speaker 1: when they charge the ball up when they do a charge shot They hold down the shoot button for the maximum amount of time and let go.
Speaker 1: they do the super strike Which we'll talk about in a minute.
Speaker 1: but if the secondary players charge up all the way and let go they do the skill shot and each Player each secondary teammate has a different skill shot.
Speaker 1: And the reason it's a skill shot is because you have to sort of use it at the right with the right Timing in the right position and if you do it just right.
Speaker 1: you can get a goal pretty easily, but it's not easy.
Speaker 1: It's a skill shot for a reason.
Speaker 1: It takes a lot of skill and the skill shots are awesome
Speaker 0: Yep, and also real quick because it's kind of related to that in the old game, you know You get items any time someone else Checks you or kicks you or something and you didn't have the ball if you did an illegal hit.
Speaker 0: in this game They still have that.
Speaker 0: but also just before you get a skill shot the ball like flashes for a second And if you sure to shoot during that span instead of doing a skill shot You take a shot on the goal and it charges the ball and you get an item.
Speaker 0: so you can build up items Just by taking shots on the other person's goal and make it play.
Speaker 1: So the other guy can't starve you of items.
Speaker 1: alright now let's talk about the The waggle whatnots?
Speaker 1: that is so people call it right.
Speaker 1: how does the Wii work into this game for the Wii one?
Speaker 0: You don't have to do any of that if you don't want.
Speaker 1: Yes, basically, it's actually you know, forget about the weakness, right?
Speaker 1: Think about it.
Speaker 1: the controls are pretty similar to the GameCube controls except now you're using the Wiimote in your right hand or you know your primary hand I guess and The nunchuck in the other hand.
Speaker 1: so it's sort of like if the GameCube controller was split in half So you could move your hands around more freely and there was just a wire connecting them.
Speaker 1: and it's wireless.
Speaker 1: so it's actually a lot more comfortable than just the GameCube and Most of the controls of the GameCube are very similar or the same.
Speaker 1: So it's not much different.
Speaker 1: It's just more comfortable.
Speaker 0: The only really waggling is when you want to tackle someone you can hit a button or you can shake the stick.
Speaker 1: And well the difference is if you hit a button Just to tackle you do a slide tackle.
Speaker 1: if you shake the Wiimote you do the hitting tackle Right, so that's sort of different.
Speaker 1: But I've actually I mostly use the slide tackle because the hitting tackle is only useful in other in specific situations.
Speaker 1: So I find myself using the slide tackle a lot more.
Speaker 1: You can also if you take the nunchuck and you shake it a little bit.
Speaker 1: That's how you change items when it sort of feels good to change items that way because it's sort of like, you know flipping through items like You know sort of like changing cartridges in a gun or whatever and that's pretty much it except For the mega strike.
Speaker 0: All right now in the previous game The mega strike was pretty much if you got it off It was automatic goal and it was worth two points.
Speaker 0: That was the point.
Speaker 0: It was either two points or no point and it was kind of bad because once you got good at the game The strategy was just get right over the center line super shot right over the center line.
Speaker 1: super shot I'm saying is if you're playing with good people they could stop you from doing the super shot.
Speaker 1: The problem is if you got it off two goals No one could do anything about it and you had to sit there and watch this animation.
Speaker 1: That was unskippable to get two goals.
Speaker 0: and yeah also real quick.
Speaker 0: in this game They got rid of that slow-mo all the time Which I'm pretty sure was only in the GameCube because the guy I think it was I think the slow-mo and the GameCube one Was for dramatic effect, but I think I think I think they over.
Speaker 1: it was definitely overused.
Speaker 1: I think it was partly also to deal with the processor not being I don't think it had a problem with that because you could Play a whole game without slow-mo as it was the.
Speaker 1: the reason slow-mo happened is if you did like a big pass and then You did you know like a like a one-timer shot?
Speaker 0: That's when it would do the slow-mo, but also every time I did the slow-mo there was like that effect around the character.
Speaker 1: What it was a special effect?
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe they couldn't do that.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they got rid of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this slow-mo now, but it happens much less.
Speaker 1: It's super rare and it's it's only for dramatic effect.
Speaker 1: But what they do?
Speaker 1: this the mega strike.
Speaker 1: in the new one the way it works is you charge up But with your main team guy your team leader And you charge up all the way and you charge up all the way in a meter appears and the meter is very similar to The meter in the old one, but when the meter goes to the left it go it counts up three four five six And you push the button when it's at the number you want.
Speaker 1: now the number that you stop it on is the number of balls You're going to shoot.
Speaker 1: So if you push it on the three, you're only gonna shoot three shots, but it doesn't take long.
Speaker 1: So if another guy's coming to hit you and make easy if he hits you you're gonna get no shots.
Speaker 1: So do you push the ball?
Speaker 1: quit.
Speaker 1: you push the button real soon?
Speaker 1: So, you know you get three shots off or do you hold out to try to get four five or six shots?
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: then after you push it to select how many shots you're gonna take it goes back to the right and you try to stop it when It's in the green or the yellow area and that determines how fast the shots are gonna be
Speaker 0: and in the way it works out.
Speaker 0: Well first we'll talk about how you fight him off if you're a player because you get the shot off.
Speaker 1: This is the other waggly bit.
Speaker 0: awesome animation happens and now and this might sound dumb But I'm bear with me cuz I'm gonna defend it.
Speaker 0: It works out really well.
Speaker 1: Oh you think it works.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it works out.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I think it works a lot better than a lot of other ways.
Speaker 1: They could have handled it does but I do feel like it is a tacked on waggle thing.
Speaker 0: Oh it is but what else could they have done?
Speaker 1: Not waggle then.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: No, you just make it strikers game for the Wii.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with that?
Speaker 0: Because I didn't like the fact that it was deterministic like it's just gonna go in automatically if you get the good thing.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: That's the only thing I didn't like.
Speaker 0: There's got to be some sort of like mini game or skill or something to block those super shots And they could have done it another way.
Speaker 0: I think this is a pretty good quick elegant way.
Speaker 1: It's an okay way.
Speaker 0: It works pretty well.
Speaker 0: The way it works is You've got it You've got a little hands on the screen that you control with the remote and it gives you a countdown and you have to click Before it'll start and the balls come at you and you have to block them and depending on where they got on the meter Is how fast they'll come at you and it's basically if they didn't hit the good part Like the green part of the orange part.
Speaker 0: You can block them all like just whatever unless you suck unless you're a moron.
Speaker 0: It's
Speaker 1: basically sort of like a mini game of duck hunt where the Ducks sort of appear in one spot for like part a fraction of a second and you sort of have to shoot them all really quick and it's actually not that hard because you can sort of see the where they're coming from and If you if you practice at it super shots won't really pass by you so much.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then the green area, you know It's pretty hard, but you'll usually get all of them if you're a good player most of them Most of them to where you're not just done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, six shots go in game over.
Speaker 0: But if you get it into the orange one, which is pretty hard to do But I've practiced the hell out of doing that It's you're lucky if you block half of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's The thing is it's good.
Speaker 1: It's hard to get it in the orange.
Speaker 1: And also if someone gets it in the orange you left them wide open on the field and we're not playing defense.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also if they get off more than three or four shots you again left them out there and it's your own goddamn fault.
Speaker 1: They get off any shots on this.
Speaker 1: on the mega thing Then you weren't playing defense properly.
Speaker 1: it when I noticed when we play with people who know what they're doing almost No one gets a mega strike off ever.
Speaker 1: It's it's like people try but then they always get hit every time.
Speaker 1: Yeah items at the very least.
Speaker 0: The only other thing I could really talk about is the fact that it has Wi-Fi play.
Speaker 1: Yeah I played the Wi-Fi play once and it was kind of fun because you are playing the full game against someone on the internet and It is a contest of skill and awesome.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: It just works, but it just works.
Speaker 1: The only thing I can complain about is that I played it and it didn't seem so bad when I was playing it and it Said you have a four star internet speed rating, but when I actually went back to playing the single-player game I realized that the internet play was mad laggy.
Speaker 1: I only did it once so it could have been just that time but it could also been who you were playing against.
Speaker 1: it could Have been but it was pretty laggy.
Speaker 1: So Laggyness in a game like this is not really the greatest but at the same time demands no lads.
Speaker 0: basing that on one play.
Speaker 1: Yes, I'll have to play more.
Speaker 1: Wi-Fi is to figure it out.
Speaker 0: cuz I played one Wi-Fi and I didn't notice any lag.
Speaker 0: I just played.
Speaker 0: it seemed pretty good.
Speaker 0: kid kicked my ass.
Speaker 1: But yeah, yeah I actually had a pretty close one, but I played it on the day the game came out in the u.s.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I've been practicing so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've been practicing either.
Speaker 1: been playing for Mario Good God.
Speaker 1: Anything else you wanna say about strikers?
Speaker 0: It's not so much I can say.
Speaker 0: I just I highly recommend this game.
Speaker 0: if you own a Wii It's a must-buy.
Speaker 0: if you don't own a Wii it's a must-buy.
Speaker 0: after you get a Wii It's not a reason to get a Wii.
Speaker 0: like Scott said, yep, and Yeah, good soccer game me.
Speaker 1: It might be the best soccer game.
Speaker 1: There is except maybe that one.
Speaker 1: That was all River City rants.
Speaker 0: I just wish Nintendo would use that kind of style or that kind of.
Speaker 0: you know Make the characters a little hardcore make them kind of competitive.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have to make them hardcore necessarily just make them different.
Speaker 1: make them not the standard.
Speaker 1: It's a medium audio.
Speaker 0: Stylize it a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when you make the next Mario tennis give the characters, you know an attitude.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have to be you know, a badass attitude.
Speaker 1: It could be any attitude.
Speaker 1: You know, I do like the attitude and strikers though It's cool and just the me not just.
Speaker 0: we talked about the characters theme music, you know They're light motifs if I may but the music in the game as a whole that like the loading music.
Speaker 0: I in fact the loading music specifically pumps you up Sort of like the way tribes to did.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.