Speaker 0: It's Monday July 9th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight hard-Drive failure.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, I gotta say it was a pretty relaxing and generally awesome weekend until the last minute until I went to the emergency room.
Speaker 1: Yeah That can never be good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: We had a good weekend.
Speaker 0: We didn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: We just finished challenger on fire.
Speaker 0: mostly Mostly we still have something to do and yeah, we're getting ready for con season.
Speaker 0: You know that was our last free weekend.
Speaker 0: So it's like nine o'clock, and I'm making lamb burgers, and I'm not paying attention.
Speaker 0: I'm chopping up some onions I'm chopping them up stupidly and I hit my finger with the knife.
Speaker 1: good job, Mr.. Cut yourself there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, quite deeply - yeah.
Speaker 1: So of course rim cut himself Huh, and we got to take him the emergency room because otherwise he'll just bleed to death all over the floor.
Speaker 0: well I'm standing there looking cuz it's the tip of my pinky finger, so I'm thinking I'm holding it back together And I'm thinking all right is this something I can deal with on my own?
Speaker 0: And then I pull it open and I pull off the whole front of my pinky finger.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, so uh great.
Speaker 0: Let's just go to the emergency room.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not something where you got to call 911 to get the ambulance.
Speaker 1: I mean he cut his finger.
Speaker 1: You don't call the ambulance for the cut finger especially since you have to pay the ambulance fee.
Speaker 1: well I wouldn't have but yeah, but anyway I'm sure many people would have but we being sane would not have called the ambulance for a cut finger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I mean my insurance would have covered it.
Speaker 0: It's more that I hate calling the ambulance unless I really need to exactly.
Speaker 1: so we're just gonna drive to the emergency room now.
Speaker 1: This is an ambulance that drives by our house crazy fast all the time.
Speaker 1: He's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've never actually seen his face no, but we hear him drive by and we see him drive But we can tell him apart from the other ambulances cuz he's going about 70 or 80 down our street.
Speaker 1: Yep, so We figured there's a hospital right next to our house And we figured that's where he was going to and coming from.
Speaker 1: so we go over there And it is a hospital, but it's only a rehab kind of hospital.
Speaker 0: It was like Dominion tank police.
Speaker 0: We only treat healthy people here right.
Speaker 1: so they didn't have an emergency room there.
Speaker 0: luckily We ran into some guy on rehab who told us where some other emergency.
Speaker 1: They were all like walking around in a circle around the hospital.
Speaker 1: So we just drove through the mass of people.
Speaker 0: it was kind of scary when Scott pulls up to these people and they kind of Swarm around the car when he opens his window, and they all start talking at once.
Speaker 1: yeah But they told me how to get to the emergency room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we went and One.
Speaker 0: the nearest emergency room to our house is quite a ways away.
Speaker 1: It's on the other side of the Hudson River.
Speaker 0: the only other option is to drive all the way up to Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking maybe they should set up places that are just emergency rooms and not a whole hospital.
Speaker 0: The only reason they don't I think is that emergency rooms are the least profitable and most pain-in-the-ass part of any hospital.
Speaker 0: as it Is no one would willingly run one in and of itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: It's the most necessary part.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I was a certain part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe that's the ticket is did not have socialized medicine, but just have socialized emergency rooms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe that's make them all over the place.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be opposed to that at all if it were a system where if they only treated Sudden illness I mean it's already sort of socialized and that they're forced to serve people right.
Speaker 1: so now we could have private hospitals for all the.
Speaker 1: you know the long term the cancer treatments and things you know that actually cost a lot of money and Those places can actually be profitable.
Speaker 1: and the unprofitable part that we really need badly the emergency room.
Speaker 1: We could just make it happen and all every city.
Speaker 1: Anyway anyway, so so we find out where the emergency room is and it wasn't so easy to get there.
Speaker 1: We made one wrong turn.
Speaker 1: we had to turn around on this road on that cursed road.
Speaker 0: Yep, see well before we often would try to drive over to Newburgh thinking All right, everyone says there's great restaurants over here and we're sick of eating at restaurants on this side of the river.
Speaker 0: let's go eat somewhere.
Speaker 0: and Every time we got over there we end up going down this one road Technically up this one road and as far as I can tell there is nothing on that road Anywhere.
Speaker 0: if you go down that road There is never going to be a single useful place of business Until you get to new Paul's like an hour away in which case you will just find many alcoholic places of businesses.
Speaker 1: Yes places of businesses.
Speaker 1: So we turned around the other direction on that road and we found the hospital because we followed an ambulance there And I was.
Speaker 1: you know of course I know that waiting in emergency rooms Especially if you're not dying takes a long time now.
Speaker 0: I also know this partly because I work in hospitals every day.
Speaker 1: Yep, so my plan was drop that rim off and go home and then rim would call me when he wanted to come back.
Speaker 1: So I drop him off and then I start leaving and then Emily calls me and she's like, oh they took rim right in And he's like really now they did.
Speaker 0: they took me right away because I was bleeding and they said all right go right in there We're gonna triage you the triage me.
Speaker 0: then she left.
Speaker 0: another person came in.
Speaker 0: They took all my insurance information.
Speaker 0: someone else came in.
Speaker 0: a third nurse came in asked me a bunch of questions that did a few more tests to make sure I Wasn't dying or anything asked me a couple questions about my wound and then they said and I quote a doctor will be right with you It won't be long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so because they took rim right in usually when you're waiting at the emergency room.
Speaker 1: You're waiting in the waiting room and it takes forever before they let you inside.
Speaker 1: But once you're inside usually within like unless you know a crazy dying person comes in You're only gonna be waiting inside for at most 15 20 minutes before someone does something to you.
Speaker 0: thus it Begins, so I'm sitting there reading my book thinking.
Speaker 0: All right any minute now any minute now any minute now any minute now.
Speaker 1: No one has walked by in the hallways dark With Emily and there was not so many other people there.
Speaker 1: and eventually like the receptionist went home and see I'm sitting there thinking I should just go back home.
Speaker 1: It's gonna take longer.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: you bought into the sunk cost Didn't buy into the sunk cost fallacy?
Speaker 1: I had another made possible fallacy that I was falling to.
Speaker 1: I knew the sunk cost fallacy.
Speaker 1: You know the sunk cost fallacy is.
Speaker 1: I already waited an hour.
Speaker 1: if I you know by going home I'm basically route losing that hour.
Speaker 1: That's wrong.
Speaker 1: That's that's bullshit because every minute.
Speaker 1: I stay is another middle I lose even though I already lost that hour.
Speaker 1: I can't get it back right.
Speaker 1: But the fallacy if may might have been a fallacy that I was falling to.
Speaker 1: was that okay?
Speaker 1: Every minute that goes by.
Speaker 1: the odds of rim appearing you know doctored up increase.
Speaker 1: I Really don't want to risk having to go home and then turn around while I'm on the way home.
Speaker 1: That's losing more time yep, so it was basically I was assessing the risk of losing even more time in the future by going home as Because the end that risk of losing even more time increased as time progressed.
Speaker 0: meanwhile I'm sitting there making my own calculations in a separate room and because I have a real injury and there is a time limit Where good treatment can be applied that they can just ignore me like they normally do to people in emergency rooms.
Speaker 0: I could go on and on about the techniques They use to ignore you in the emergency room.
Speaker 0: my primary advice to you is unless you are dying or suffered a severe injury Don't go to an emergency room wait till the next day and go to a clinic.
Speaker 1: yep, but basically Waited there for many many hours.
Speaker 0: so after the first hour They come and get me and they say all right we're gonna move you to this room and they wouldn't really say why is they move you to another place and another hour goes by and Emily comes in and She was the kind of snuck in through the locked door when someone else walked in and there's really no one around and she basically Says yeah, apparently they lost you.
Speaker 0: you see they didn't tell me But the reason I waited in that room for an hour was that they forgot I was there and they tried to not let me know that they had forgotten I was there.
Speaker 0: so they moved me somewhere else and made something up.
Speaker 0: So then they say all right someone will be with you shortly because you're bleeding all right we wait and wait wait and wait and wait and wait and wait.
Speaker 0: and eventually I Look at my finger And I'm talking Emily and she our sister knows a lot about this and we're pretty much starting to feel like it's gonna be too.
Speaker 0: Anyway at which point there's no reason to be at the doctor?
Speaker 0: they're not gonna help me.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: so eventually I get up and I kind of walk out into the main area outside of the Emergency rooms and the nurses are all kind of walking around.
Speaker 0: There's like 12 of them and they're all pointedly avoiding eye contact at all costs.
Speaker 0: So eventually I kind of stare at one.
Speaker 0: I just pick one this guy who's sitting there and I stare at him not moving and he knows I'm there because he glances up Once and eventually he realizes I'm not gonna stop staring at him.
Speaker 0: So he looks up and he asked very pleasantly.
Speaker 0: Can I help you?
Speaker 0: and I basically said If there's no chance of me getting treated anytime soon Can I just get like a butterfly bandage or something to put on myself and just leave and then all the other nurses come over?
Speaker 0: And they basically said no They basically were elated.
Speaker 0: Yeah You can leave if you want.
Speaker 0: But they balked at giving me the one thing I wanted a butterfly bandage to kind of suture the thing myself.
Speaker 0: uh Eventually, I convinced them to give me a band-aid.
Speaker 0: so I wouldn't believe we have band-aids.
Speaker 1: We don't need their band.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to bleed on your car.
Speaker 0: So they would be grudgingly give me this one band-aid and then they tell me to get out Huh?
Speaker 0: So I left and I come out and I explained to Scott that no I didn't get treated.
Speaker 0: fuck this hospital.
Speaker 1: See people complain about the health care system and they say oh, it should be private.
Speaker 1: Oh, it should be public.
Speaker 1: They say be this it should be that you know what is with socialized medicine.
Speaker 0: You have to wait in lines to get medical treatment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what the problem really is is the hospital is incompetent.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if we pay the hospital with money out of your wallet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't matter if we pay the hospital with tax money.
Speaker 1: The problem is the hospital sucks ass either way.
Speaker 0: that and not to sound conceited or anything.
Speaker 0: But the way the world is I have super good health insurance and I'm relatively wealthy.
Speaker 1: The insurance would have just paid it.
Speaker 1: there wasn't a problem with the insurance.
Speaker 1: Even if Rym was Bill Gates and he had a billion dollars going to this hospital it would have been treated like shit.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: if I was Bill Gates, I would have known better and I would have flown to my personal doctor.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: But you know no matter how rich Rym could have been like an executive from New York City or something who would like five million Dollars but is not famous or well-known and just walked into this hospital and he would have been treated exactly the same way.
Speaker 0: It's total ass but it's kind of fair in a sick way everybody treated in the same shitty level of service.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I can understand the fact that you know, okay if someone else comes in with something more serious.
Speaker 1: you treat them first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's possible.
Speaker 1: You have a run of bad luck.
Speaker 1: You just happen to cut your finger when ten people have heart attacks and that that's fine.
Speaker 0: You got it.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's that's that's acceptable the prod.
Speaker 1: the main problem I have here Right is that I was watching and only like three ambulances showed up.
Speaker 1: You're telling me there's less than three doctors.
Speaker 0: There was one doctor.
Speaker 0: you realize very one doctor.
Speaker 1: So three people came in in ambulances and only one of them got treated and two of them were suffering.
Speaker 0: There is insufficient number of doctors there but the problem is there's no money to pay for more doctors and you can't predict the odds of people coming into the Emergency room at night and all that business.
Speaker 0: what it really came down to was that they didn't care.
Speaker 0: They didn't really triage me properly because they no one actually looked at my wound.
Speaker 0: if they had looked at my wound They would have realized wow that just needs two stitches and maybe some antibiotics and a tetanus shot and he can go home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they waited so long and I didn't know much about this.
Speaker 0: but now I know that according to the real doctor I went to today if You wait too long to get stitches like more than a few hours.
Speaker 0: It's too late now You can't get stitches and now you're fucked.
Speaker 0: In fact the new the doc the real doctor I went to today told me that if I wanted to I could probably sue the Emergency room for failing to properly triage me and denying me the treatment that would have led to a better prognosis.
Speaker 1: You should at least ask one of your free lawyers about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't really want to sue because that I'll be okay.
Speaker 1: I need to make a stink at the very least.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm gonna make a little bit of a stink but my real gripe is with that specific hospital.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean they were not.
Speaker 1: it isn't anecdotal evidence here, but dad Anecdotal evidence you speak of.
Speaker 0: yes, so I skipped work today because I was still bleeding in the morning.
Speaker 0: Wow So just oozing it wasn't like super bleeding, but it was still bleeding.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I go to just a normal walk-in clinic.
Speaker 0: It's actually a clinic designed more for poor people.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's this place called.
Speaker 1: There's a couple of them around here.
Speaker 1: It's called medicus, and it's just a place that you walk into and they have normal physicians and nurses there.
Speaker 0: It's like a daytime emergency room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can go get.
Speaker 1: it's not like an emergency.
Speaker 1: if you have an emergency They can't really help you.
Speaker 1: But you know if you have a cold or you need a prescription for a cream I got a rash.
Speaker 1: you know anything normal, and you don't you know.
Speaker 1: you could just go there.
Speaker 0: I think that the thing is these serve the vital purpose.
Speaker 0: They're kind of the mid-range because what I had was not a life-threatening emergency Yeah, but it was a situation that the proper thing to do was to go to a doctor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and prompt treatment, but the problem is a much better kind of place is not open 24/7 the fraud.
Speaker 0: The fact is the only place open 24/7 was the shitty emergency room and by the time you waited until morning It was too late.
Speaker 0: I do want to point out that way back like a year and a half ago I had the long.
Speaker 0: story short is one of my teeth had this weird cavity underneath that no dentist had noticed and One day the whole front of the tooth just popped off while I was brushing my teeth.
Speaker 0: well in the middle of the night I was home alone to which I go.
Speaker 0: Oh fuck.
Speaker 0: What do I do ah?
Speaker 1: Call the dentist.
Speaker 0: so I called my dentist and that no one was there obviously But there was.
Speaker 0: they said in an emergency call this number And I called this other number and they told me to come and they paged the dentist and he came and fixed me that night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was an emergency.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that wasn't even as serious as the cut on your finger.
Speaker 1: I'm not at all Yeah, and they got a doctor or a dentist up in the middle of the night to come.
Speaker 0: granted It was a private practice.
Speaker 0: the dentist did it willingly because I guess he cares and because he made some money off of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean rims insurance was gonna pay this hospital money.
Speaker 1: if the hospital is losing money Don't you think they want to take rim in first?
Speaker 1: I mean sure it's kind of I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't say that they should treat someone with insurance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz they got a monster syndrome where you got to treat the famous politician exactly.
Speaker 1: You don't want it to be like monster.
Speaker 1: You do not want to do that because then you know the person who's seriously dying will die while Bill Gates gets his like scrape You know bandaged up.
Speaker 1: You don't want that to happen, but at the same time if the hospital would have had the one more doctor.
Speaker 1: You know, they're not proud.
Speaker 1: they're thinking they're losing money with the one doctor they have there.
Speaker 1: but with the two doctors They'd be able to treat some of these other people and maybe get some insurance money out of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem is the vast majority of people who come to any emergency room don't have insurance.
Speaker 1: I know that's.
Speaker 1: the other thing is they need to find That the law is if someone comes to emergency room, they kind of have to treat them.
Speaker 1: They really need to make it some way.
Speaker 1: where you can be triaged out the door, you know I mean rim should have been triaged to stitches.
Speaker 1: There is no doubt about all I need.
Speaker 1: It was two stitches, but the problem is people who come in with a cold They they eventually get in and people with a stomachache.
Speaker 1: That's not appendicitis Eventually get in.
Speaker 1: they need to be able and allowed to just send those people home and they'd be allowed to save a lot of Money, it's a complicated problem.
Speaker 0: We should probably do a show about this because I have some in sounds like you already did the show about this.
Speaker 0: Well having worked in hospitals for a while now.
Speaker 0: I've learned a lot about how this works.
Speaker 1: You should definitely like make a stink like to the local media or something I'm thinking about it.
Speaker 1: make the hospital have a bad name because I think that's the only way we can hurt them without.
Speaker 0: well So I'm at this doctor today and they say yeah It's too late to get stitches.
Speaker 0: and when I tell him the story of what happened They basically stop and say what hospital was it?
Speaker 0: and I tell him st.
Speaker 0: Luke's.
Speaker 0: I went to st.
Speaker 0: Luke's It's the only emergency room and the nurse says oh Well, let me tell you something about st Luke's.
Speaker 0: and she spewed forth the anecdotes of all the problems they have had with st Luke's and how she personally had had a problem at st Luke's once in the emergency room.
Speaker 0: and now someone basically like almost broke his pelvis and they wouldn't really do anything.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 1: Yeah How could a place like this be in operations like dr.
Speaker 1: Nix?
Speaker 0: Well, I've been to some emergency room like remember way back when I had Lyme disease Way back years and years ago I caught Lyme disease and I didn't know what it was right away.
Speaker 0: So I go to the hospital in the emergency room and I'm like.
Speaker 0: I got 103 fever and a headache and it's persisted for a Day, I think I'm sick and they ran some tests and they made me sit there for like four hours At least.
Speaker 1: they ran tests.
Speaker 0: Yeah useless tests.
Speaker 0: Oh the test didn't show anything.
Speaker 0: They showed me being in perfect health and then they sent me home with a bottle of aspirin.
Speaker 0: Wow, so the next day I went to a different doctor who said you have Lyme disease.
Speaker 0: Here's some antibiotics.
Speaker 0: go home.
Speaker 1: Yeah Maybe it's just that they shove the shitty doctors in the emergency room, but I went to another emergency room.
Speaker 0: It was just a different hospital.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh Maybe I was just lucky.
Speaker 0: I went into the other one and the nurse is like wait a minute Let me see your arms and she looks at one arm one time.
Speaker 0: So let me see your knees and I pull up one.
Speaker 0: She's like, aha There it is.
Speaker 0: You've got Lyme disease.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: What do I do?
Speaker 0: Take these pills?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, well So tech type news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the moral is my fingers hurt and I got to hold it up and it sucks, but I didn't die yet Yep, and I got a tetanus shot, which I was kind of due for.
Speaker 1: Yeah, too bad you didn't get tetanus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tetanus is double awesome.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: I remember back when I had tetanus.
Speaker 0: That was a riot.
Speaker 1: Yep All right, so everyone's probably seen this story and the headline is NASA buys 19 million dollar toilet.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute NASA or NASA NASA the regular NASA, okay Right and everyone's like OMG.
Speaker 1: Our government is crazy.
Speaker 1: They waste money on bullshit blabbity blabbity blah.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like that apocryphal story about You know NASA spent millions and millions developing a pen that would work in space and the Russians just used a pencil, right?
Speaker 1: So basically this is not stupid like you think it is.
Speaker 1: The space station needs a toilet.
Speaker 1: people need to go to the bath.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: People don't pee.
Speaker 1: Alright, no one guys.
Speaker 1: I forgot.
Speaker 1: And it has a toilet but the toilet has some problems.
Speaker 1: you see it doesn't really have a way to Like hold you down while you're pooping.
Speaker 0: well, you can kind of strap yourself down.
Speaker 1: Well, no there weren't.
Speaker 1: the current toilet doesn't have any straps or anything.
Speaker 1: Wow, you have to sort of push yourself towards the toilet with your arms or something.
Speaker 1: man The one imagine if like you just floated upwards and your poop kind of came out.
Speaker 1: Even worse the poop would act as a propulsive force Yes, and also what could you push against to squeeze the poop out of you?
Speaker 1: You need to push you against something.
Speaker 1: You can't just push against yourself to make the poop come out.
Speaker 0: Well, the poop will just come out.
Speaker 0: you realize it'll be like a jet though.
Speaker 0: It'll rocket you far I know and the poop?
Speaker 0: who knows what I'll happen to you.
Speaker 0: I do point out though that the space shuttle has straps Yes, but anyway, why didn't they just put some straps on on the Russian side of the space station?
Speaker 1: There's a toilet, right?
Speaker 1: That's all not.
Speaker 1: it's basically almost the same as the toilet The Americans have only it has straps and it has separate hoses for everyone to pee in.
Speaker 1: so everyone has their own.
Speaker 0: You know, that's kind of nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah But everyone shares the same pooper, right?
Speaker 1: Yes It's just and the US side had this toilet that was older and inferior.
Speaker 0: So what were the US astronauts sneaking over to the Russian side?
Speaker 1: Maybe I have no idea But basically NASA had two choices at this point.
Speaker 1: They're sending more people up to the space station.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be six people up there instead of three.
Speaker 1: So they need more privacy more pooping more peeing right and the current toilet wasn't gonna cut it.
Speaker 1: So what are they gonna do?
Speaker 1: They can either invent and develop their own toilet or they can just pay 19 million dollars to the Russians to get the Russian toilet on their side and that's what they did.
Speaker 0: It could hold it in and it's not stupid.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a waste of money.
Speaker 1: if you if you agree that the space station at all is a good idea Which is not something I want to discuss right now Then you must agree that buying this toilet was the good idea because it's either 19 million dollars to the toilet a lot more money for a new toilet that can invent one or The shitty old toilet which doesn't cut it.
Speaker 1: Well, it's your three choices.
Speaker 0: people always say Yeah, we went to the moon in the 60s and now we got this crap.
Speaker 0: What's going on?
Speaker 0: How come we're so much worse now?
Speaker 0: Why can't we go back to the moon?
Speaker 0: and people seem to forget the sheer amount of Economic and Mental power and and just the it took so much to get to the moon and to do the things we did back then That the nation really isn't prepared to put that some that amount of effort toward anything right now.
Speaker 1: Yep, especially when we've got plus think about it every guy going on every American right that they spend researching how to make a better Space toilet is not researching how to keep this rocket from exploding.
Speaker 1: Same guys, they're all NASA scientists researching.
Speaker 1: They all do the same shit.
Speaker 0: Not that NASA.
Speaker 0: I have mixed feelings about NASA.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna say they're the greatest organization in the world.
Speaker 1: They're very government bureaucratic inefficient, etc.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I'm not going to pretend that they're the worst organization of the world because they've accomplished a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not recently.
Speaker 0: think about the enormity of what they did.
Speaker 0: They sent human beings to the moon and back and it worked multiple times.
Speaker 1: Yes, so that's crazy.
Speaker 1: Anyone who reads this headline and is like a brabble rabble rabble You're an idiot unless you unless you want to argue about you know The space station being a stupid idea in which case I don't know if I agree with you.
Speaker 0: We'll see All right, one more thing 19 million, right?
Speaker 0: Yep So 19 million for a thing that's gonna make the space station much better and last a long time and generally make poopin nicer.
Speaker 0: I'm all for anything that makes poopin nicer.
Speaker 0: Yep I'm not.
Speaker 0: this is a rhetorical question.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna expect you to answer it, but I ask you all of you out there.
Speaker 0: How much does one cruise missile cost?
Speaker 1: They're like Ted.
Speaker 1: how much aren't they like?
Speaker 1: a million dollars each?
Speaker 0: How much are we spot us the United States spending in?
Speaker 0: Iraq, I don't know.
Speaker 1: see for the same people who would say this is dumb would also say Iraq is dumb.
Speaker 1: They say we shouldn't be spending money in either of those things.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we shouldn't be spending money on anything.
Speaker 0: That's their problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well I sort of agree.
Speaker 1: Emergency rooms in every city fuck yes.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I'm sure you were all familiar with captures completely automated public Turing test to tell computers and humans apart.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically, you know when you sign up for a website and it says type in the letters that you see in this picture The point of that is that only a person can look at the picture.
Speaker 1: point Is that yes beautiful a person only a human being can look at that picture and figure out what the letters are.
Speaker 1: well computer a Computer can technically do it, but it's very difficult and depending on the image.
Speaker 1: It's even more difficult.
Speaker 1: So, you know it even if someone was spamming and even if they had software they could figure out what the words in the picture Are and type them in.
Speaker 1: it would be so computationally intensive that they'd need a supercomputer to do it with any speed.
Speaker 1: Stop spam it slows it down significantly.
Speaker 0: See now while that's true.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of this theory.
Speaker 0: There's been a lot of arms race action going on here because on one Captures were developed but at the same time OCR got better Yeah, and you could make computers that could figure these things out pretty easy.
Speaker 1: So they got to make trickier captures.
Speaker 1: that then I hate it.
Speaker 1: when you see a capture that I can't even tell if it's like I see.
Speaker 1: or is it a you that got turned sideways because it got bent and then I typed it in wrong and then I Got to type it again even worse blind bag that the capture solving itself is not the real issue the spammers had to solve.
Speaker 0: because I'm not gonna get it all the theory or details about this, but there is something called side channel information.
Speaker 0: or basically, if you're trying to hide information from someone you have to be aware of the fact that Information gets out through other channels that you that you might not anticipate.
Speaker 0: Like say I'm trying to keep Scott from reading one of the books in my room.
Speaker 0: Alright, so I duct tape that book shut.
Speaker 0: now Scott sees that one of the books has duct tape on it and wonders Why I duct tape that book shot.
Speaker 0: Yeah or Say you're trying to hide the fact that you go to a certain website.
Speaker 0: So you encrypt all your traffic.
Speaker 0: Oh, but you can look at logs on routers and see that your IP address was talking to that IP address even if you can't know what the data was.
Speaker 0: things like that.
Speaker 0: and The deal is really that with captchas you could figure them out through means that had nothing to do with the capture itself like Maybe there's only a limited number of answers and you can brute-force it.
Speaker 1: You have some people actually have the full-on super captures which are random and they make images on the fly.
Speaker 1: But a lot of people just have like three or four.
Speaker 1: They have the same one over and over or something like that And even the ones that generate on the fly.
Speaker 0: a lot of people have done them stupidly like the alt text will be the thing That's supposed to be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good job.
Speaker 0: It just shows a picture and you can just correlate the file name to one of the known captchas.
Speaker 1: solved good Good job again.
Speaker 0: Also, you can very easily Just make a fake porn site and trick people who want to see your porn into solving captchas for you and then saving the responses Regardless of how they've done it.
Speaker 0: However, someone has broken apparently the captchas used for Yahoo and hotmail email and as a result Lots and lots of Yahoo and hotmail email accounts are suddenly being made and spamming the living fuck out of people.
Speaker 1: Well, I actually read this actually reminds me of something I saw recently.
Speaker 1: that is a really clever way of stopping spammers without captchas which also by the way inhibit blind people.
Speaker 1: What you do is you make a form right and when you make a form on a web page I don't want to get into this so deeply you make fields and there are different kinds of fields You can make.
Speaker 1: you can make text fields radio button fields checkbox fields, you know, pull down fields all that sort of stuff right.
Speaker 1: one kind of field you can make is a hidden field and a hidden field has some information in it and But the person filling out the form doesn't see it.
Speaker 1: But when you click the submit button that information gets submitted and it's very useful for programmers and people who fill out forms Don't really need to know about it.
Speaker 1: Well The thing is a lot of spammers.
Speaker 1: the way their software works is it looks at the form Not from the perspective of someone sitting and looking at the web browser.
Speaker 1: It just looks at all the fields in the HTML and fills them out.
Speaker 1: It also sees that when there's a hidden field, it doesn't fill it out.
Speaker 1: what if you took a non hidden field like a text field?
Speaker 1: right, but you Made it so the user can't see it with some CSS or even like.
Speaker 0: they make it so they can see it.
Speaker 0: But the text above it says don't write anything here Yep.
Speaker 1: And then a spam bot will automatically like if you call the field address the spam Bob will automatically fill that in Pretty much every time.
Speaker 1: and now whenever you get someone submitting the form with the address field filled in You know that a human being didn't fill it in, you know that a spammer filled it in.
Speaker 1: So you just ignore that.
Speaker 1: one or an idiot or an idiot, you know.
Speaker 1: But if you make the fee the form field disappear with CSS so that people can't see it.
Speaker 1: You know, the only way that was filled in was by a spammer.
Speaker 0: Of course They could just escalate the arms race and look at the CSS to figure out if something's visible or not.
Speaker 1: They could they could but there are tricky ways of hiding the CSS from them inside.
Speaker 1: True there are.
Speaker 1: With JavaScripts and things.
Speaker 0: The reason I brought this News up is that there is a fundamental problem here.
Speaker 0: That is well below this issue yet It is the real problem.
Speaker 0: I also want to point out that Google Gmail spam filtering works up almost a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I understand why people still have a problem with spammers.
Speaker 0: I mean we get a spam a second to the geek nights account.
Speaker 1: I mean if I was if I was someone like Google running email servers I would want to stop spam because that saves me money and bandwidth and such and storage.
Speaker 1: but as a user I have a spam filter.
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 1: It works 99% of the time.
Speaker 1: What's my problem?
Speaker 1: I don't really give a shit about spam.
Speaker 0: Well, the other thing is I tend to and I know some people disagree but when it comes to blocking undesirable content I've realized that there's so much content on the internet that I'm willing to miss something for the benefit of not having to deal with the crap.
Speaker 0: I'll block things with a wide brush if One out of a thousand emails that comes to me or even one out of a hundred that I might have wanted gets blocked accidentally.
Speaker 0: That's worth it.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to not get that email.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right,
Speaker 0: but the real issue here the real real problem the only reason this happens is because of the Windows machines that are compromised by Trojans and spyware and Because the only way this works is if you hit Yahoo or Hotmail or whoever from a million different IP addresses.
Speaker 0: That way sure they figure out someone's a spammer and they block the IP address, but there's a million more people spamming.
Speaker 0: you can't tell who's a spammer and who isn't because pretty much a good portion of the Windows machines on the internet are compromised.
Speaker 0: Do it based on IP address?
Speaker 0: if you knew at least 99% or even 90% That IP addresses could generally be trusted then it'd be really trivial to blacklist bad IP addresses.
Speaker 1: You know, what do we do when we go to IP v6 then?
Speaker 0: IP v6 is a whole different piece.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 1: I know it's what I'm saying though.
Speaker 1: if we want to go that way then IP address blocking doesn't work But I do agree I could compromise.
Speaker 1: Windows machines are the core of all the other problems and if we fix that one Everything will be good.
Speaker 1: Actually if everyone switched to Vista which so far is proved to be fairly secure even though annoying We a lot of this shit would go away.
Speaker 0: Yeah So think of this.
Speaker 0: spam is not caused by anything other than people Maybe like you who have a Windows computer and don't keep it secure.
Speaker 0: and if you think that this is a far-flung threat I dare you to install a program called wire shark.
Speaker 0: run it for an hour and See if anything interesting is in those logs.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many people you able to read those.
Speaker 0: well I installed a Windows before I wiped it out and install the new windows.
Speaker 0: when I built the new computer and I installed a bunch of Wares partly as a test and with one exception every single piece of wares I installed Had a horrible spyware and horrible spam bots built into it.
Speaker 0: awesome They didn't get past my firewall, but I saw him there.
Speaker 0: awesome things of the day.
Speaker 0: Fuck that's all I got.
Speaker 1: that's it.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: check it out.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you might have heard this before, but if you haven't it's rather amusing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of things that seem to cover this exact same topic.
Speaker 1: You know the many uses of the word fuck But this seemed this one seems to be like a pretty good one, so it's concise.
Speaker 0: It's funny.
Speaker 0: It's to the point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you seen this you seen them all so Fucking watch it all right.
Speaker 0: It was a really uncreative use of the word fuck.
Speaker 0: I must say fuck you.
Speaker 1: so I read this article today.
Speaker 1: That was actually pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: I don't agree with everything this guy says but I agree with him I guess in spirit.
Speaker 1: the main point of it you can read all the details for yourself Is that the computer mouse the mouse that you you know you move it around with your hand.
Speaker 1: two buttons right?
Speaker 1: Except for the two buttons and the scroll wheel if you have one is not an input device of discrete input.
Speaker 1: It is an input device of you know a sort of gradient continual input.
Speaker 1: You know now speed at which you movement and directions and vectors.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make a pedantic argument, but I'm not gonna follow through with it.
Speaker 0: But I point out that it actually is very discreet.
Speaker 1: Yes moving on the level pixels pixels picks on the underlying level.
Speaker 1: It is a discrete input on the user level as far as your hand and your brain.
Speaker 1: Yes, we're talking about user interface here.
Speaker 1: We're not talking about technology.
Speaker 1: It is not a discrete input device.
Speaker 1: It is a Gradual continuous input device whereas the keyboard is a discrete input device.
Speaker 1: you push s you push K. It does one thing.
Speaker 1: there's no more s or less s you're pushing.
Speaker 1: You know there's not hitting s harder or softer like there is on the ps2 gamepad where you can hit the circle harder or softer.
Speaker 0: You know it should be that way.
Speaker 0: see think of this.
Speaker 0: if we had keyboards that were analog sensitive to pressure We wouldn't have to worry about picking a font size anymore.
Speaker 1: I guess yeah, yeah, that'd be alright, but anyway No It wouldn't.
Speaker 1: the point he makes is that there are a lot of things the mouse is good for like drawing on the screen or Scrollbars Choosing colors or aiming in an FPS because all of those things require sort of these gradual Continual analog style inputs.
Speaker 1: you know it's not just aim It's where do you want to aim?
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: you can't do that with discrete inputs very well.
Speaker 1: It sucks to control an FPS entirely with the keyboard right.
Speaker 0: you know the first time I played doom I I tried to use the mouse, but I didn't get it.
Speaker 1: I used to play it with my.
Speaker 1: I played Wolfenstein 3d mouse.
Speaker 1: only then I did keyboard.
Speaker 1: only then I did gamepad.
Speaker 1: Then I went back to keyboard.
Speaker 1: only I remember playing only I didn't understand the mouse keyboard combination until I was playing.
Speaker 1: FPS is on my Pentium 3 on the 486.
Speaker 1: I never played them properly.
Speaker 0: I'm telling you playing doom without the mouse is a scary experience especially if you can't strafe because you didn't set that up Because I remember strafing Wolfenstein 3d.
Speaker 1: you would hold down the third button and move the mouse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'd let go of the third button to stop strafing.
Speaker 0: You can still do that even in counter-strike if you really want.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't do that if I were you.
Speaker 1: nah anyway The point is that he makes in in this thesis I guess is that there are a lot of things we do with the mouse nowadays that are better off That are actually discrete like saving.
Speaker 1: there isn't more or less saving.
Speaker 1: there isn't saving to the right or saving to the left.
Speaker 1: There's save.
Speaker 0: and what about save?
Speaker 1: as yeah, that's another time No input.
Speaker 1: But you know and he points out he makes a pretty decent argument that you it's you're better off using the keyboard for Discrete things because it's a discrete input for a discrete command and you can have muscle memory.
Speaker 1: You can.
Speaker 1: you can do it with your eyes closed.
Speaker 1: You can get you can make a habit of it You know, you can do it a lot faster.
Speaker 1: You don't need to clutter up the screen with extra buttons, etc.
Speaker 1: Etc, etc.
Speaker 1: And in spirit I agree with him and then he proposes a solution that I don't agree with that much.
Speaker 1: but this is very interesting to read and I always push people to Learn keyboard shortcuts and use the keyboard properly and I always yell at people when they use their computers inefficiently.
Speaker 1: So this is just more of that.
Speaker 1: You're gonna be using your computer a lot more efficiently and doing a lot more things in a lot less time and having a much Smoother experience if you learn to use the keyboard.
Speaker 0: What it really comes down to is some things are discreet but the mouse won't really hurt you like for example saving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just ctrl s or whatever.
Speaker 0: your keyboard shortcut is probably a better way.
Speaker 0: You don't need to think about it.
Speaker 0: But say you're in a program and you want to make a big edit change or you want to run a filter or something.
Speaker 0: Usually if you're doing something like that, there's a lot of thought before doing it and using the mouse Wallet slows you down at the same time.
Speaker 0: these aren't the kind of things you'll be doing just all the time willy-nilly without a thought.
Speaker 0: the kind of things you're thinking about and Opening up the filters or the effects menu with the mouse and then seeing it and moving the mouse to your option Gives you time to kind of process what you're doing.
Speaker 0: So you won't do things rashly.
Speaker 0: It's kind of the old thing of if your computer was controlled by your brain It would do nothing but delete documents and draw penises.
Speaker 1: Yep However, I will point out that saving is not something you should think about.
Speaker 1: you should save all the goddamn time constantly Unless you want to save incrementally.
Speaker 1: But then you have CVS or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, but sometimes you're using a word and you're writing an essay and you're worried the power is gonna go out.
Speaker 1: So you want to see versions of word.
Speaker 1: do that already?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But what if you're using your old Windows 95 box?
Speaker 1: upgrade your goddamn computer and you got five machine Microsoft works.
Speaker 1: Then you're spamming me Turn it off.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right All right We're not exactly sure a hundred percent exactly where we're gonna go with this topic But it was brought up recently and I listen to a podcast about it recently.
Speaker 0: So the smart one, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I figured we should talk about it in some context gonna talk about how hard drive sort of?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Damage to hard drives hard drive failure how they crash how they keep themselves from crashing what you should do about it.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a cop-out, but we went long in the first half.
Speaker 0: You can't complain.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: Well, basically you might know that when you use your hard drive Sometimes your computer might complain about it or it might say I'm repairing your hard drive It wants to run the scan disk or something like that And what it's doing is doing a few different things on a few different levels.
Speaker 1: but in general your hard drive has a lot of stuff in it to Help it keep all the data from getting fucked up which happens all the goddamn time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you put data on the hard drive and you don't really think about it.
Speaker 0: Your operating system windows is there or Linux and your mp3s and all that stuff and you think even if you listen to all Of our how computers work that all right, my files are a bunch of bits.
Speaker 0: Those bits are just written to the hard drive.
Speaker 0: There's a lot more to it and luckily your computer doesn't need to know a good goddamn thing about that.
Speaker 0: Well computer sends bits to the hard drive saying I want these bits to go on this hard drive in the olden days.
Speaker 1: Right, you would buy literally like this is before I even bought computers Like I was like 70s were talking here.
Speaker 1: you would buy a platter and you would get like a 10 megabyte platter megabyte people and You would basically wire the platter on.
Speaker 1: it's like the platter would have a motor and like a read/write thing on it And you would wire that into your computer and it'd be up to your computer To control the platter and like the logic of what to you know, all that stuff.
Speaker 1: nowadays your Hard drive has a circuit board and a microprocessor attached to it and the hard drive Handles itself.
Speaker 1: it handles the platters on its own and all your computer has to know is write this data read this data Find this data that sort of thing and it just tells the hard drive what to do.
Speaker 1: and the hard drive Handles the platters and that other level on its own.
Speaker 1: and that that's where I. that's what ID is.
Speaker 1: It's integrated drive electronics.
Speaker 1: That's where we integrated the electronics into the drive before IDE.
Speaker 1: It sucked big time.
Speaker 0: What it really means is that hard drives are interchangeable.
Speaker 0: Any hard drive will just work?
Speaker 0: Because all the logic any like some hard drives use completely different methods to put data in different places or to deal with all their Stuff internally.
Speaker 0: Yeah, your computer doesn't need to know anything about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I guess think of it this way your can.
Speaker 0: your hard drive is doing a lot more behind the scenes than you might be thinking and Your hard drive really doesn't tell you what it's doing.
Speaker 1: so much which is good and bad.
Speaker 1: It's good because well, you don't really need to know that much.
Speaker 1: but at the same time There are some things you really want to know because it is Technologically possible that the hard drive could be telling you that it's gonna die soon.
Speaker 1: It could be telling you that something an error just happened and it fixed it.
Speaker 1: It could be telling you all sorts of things and it doesn't.
Speaker 0: There have been attempts to make hard drives tell you these things that have met with mixed success.
Speaker 0: One particular example is a technology called smart.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna get into detail.
Speaker 1: Let me just say that smart doesn't work Basically.
Speaker 0: suffice to say I used to really like smart when I learned about it when I was young.
Speaker 1: the idea of smart is great.
Speaker 1: It's that your hard drive will tell you all the stuff that's going on and your computer can monitor it and know it's gonna crash Before it crashes and you can go get a hard drive and do all this preventative maintenance and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But in practice smart never really told you anything useful.
Speaker 1: half of drives that crash According to a very good Google study.
Speaker 1: because who better to do a study on then on hard drives than Google who has a million Hard drives?
Speaker 1: half of drives that crash.
Speaker 1: smart was just saying everything's a okay.
Speaker 1: That's how great smart is.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you can't trust it if you want to learn more about that.
Speaker 0: There's a good episode on security now about it.
Speaker 0: I just used to check it out.
Speaker 1: Yep But basically the hard drives even though they don't tell you what they're doing most of the time They are doing some pretty smart things behind the scenes to keep themselves from just fucking you over.
Speaker 1: one thing they do that's like.
Speaker 1: the most important thing you should know about is that they have sort of like a Most my hard drives now is they have a spare space on the hard drive.
Speaker 1: That's basically space they don't tell you about and a hard drive is divided into sectors and a sector is sort of like Think of it as the smallest unit a hard drive can deal with, you know.
Speaker 1: So if your hard drive has a thousand sectors, it's gonna have way more than that.
Speaker 1: Then it can write, you know If it's gonna write or read.
Speaker 1: it can write or read one sector at a time.
Speaker 1: It can read them really fast, but it can write or read a sector at a time.
Speaker 1: sometimes a sector Breaks it goes bad or something like that and in the olden days that was doomed.
Speaker 1: that basically meant you lost space on your drive.
Speaker 1: You've had a 10 megabyte hard drive with a thousand sectors and you lost a sector.
Speaker 1: You just lost space and the data that was there gone.
Speaker 1: bad news very bad news.
Speaker 1: Nowadays if a sector on your hard drive goes bad the hard drive knows about it.
Speaker 1: It can deal with it.
Speaker 1: It takes the data that was there and puts it on another sector somewhere else and you don't actually lose any space because it was Reserving space for just this problem.
Speaker 1: if you get to the point where your computer actually tells you that there's a bad sector They can't be repaired That means all the extra space to put the data from bad sectors in is filled up.
Speaker 1: That means your hard drive is going down.
Speaker 1: But of course the only way you're gonna find that out is a smart which might just not be telling you anything or might be Lying
Speaker 0: well like scan disk will tell you yep
Speaker 1: scan But scan disk is based is doing a lot of things basking smart and some things is not asking smart.
Speaker 1: So it's a tough call.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there are basically programs that you know force your hard drive to do certain things to test it out You know and some of them will ask smart things But they won't trust smart and you.
Speaker 1: there are tools you can use like scandis that'll that'll.
Speaker 1: let you know what's going on.
Speaker 0: So basically if your hard drive starts telling you for whatever thing you're using that has got bad sectors Consider it gone and buy a new one immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if your hard drives makes weird noises that it wasn't making before buy a new one immediately.
Speaker 0: Yep, the real the only way to really protect your data is to buy a new hard drive probably now before anything goes wrong And also a backup.
Speaker 1: nothing can help you more than a backup.
Speaker 1: this I mean there are ways that you can Tools you can use to like.
Speaker 1: if your hard drive goes bad to like, you know, sort of give it the old You know resuscitation a little CPR a little what are those defibrillator action?
Speaker 1: and get the data off of it.
Speaker 1: But you can't rely on that.
Speaker 1: You just use that in an emergency, you know, you should be only relying on a backup.
Speaker 1: That is your safest way to go, you know, and even a backup isn't a hundred percent safe.
Speaker 0: It's just like 99% safe, which is safe enough Yeah, but I mean, but bear in mind a backup is not just a raid.
Speaker 0: we talked about raid before.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright, what if I have a mirror?
Speaker 0: So anything I write to one drives on the other drive.
Speaker 0: So if one drive dies the other drives fine that's well and good unless something screws up the data that's being written to the drive or You accidentally type RM - RF star in a place.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't have with permissions.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't have had Yep, and the only way you can save that is if you had a backup in a hard drive that was unplugged Sitting on your shelf or data corruption or viruses or all sorts of problems.
Speaker 0: You could have.
Speaker 0: Backups are the only way to save you.
Speaker 1: Yep Alright, let's not keep repeating how backups the only way to save you.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now at the same time.
Speaker 0: I'd like to bring this up because this is something I've done at work and in my professional life for a long time.
Speaker 0: People always, you know, if you delete a file.
Speaker 0: I know you've probably heard this before deleting a file does not make it go away.
Speaker 0: Different file systems handle things different way.
Speaker 0: But basically when you delete a file most file systems in some way say Alright, all those places where the data for that file is are now free to be overwritten exactly because remember your file system.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna go into file system architecture But basically there's an area on your hard drive that says this file is over there This file is over there this files over there and then there's the other area where the files are.
Speaker 1: So when you want to open up I don't know read me dot text You go to the hard drive and it says read me dot text is over there and You go over there and that's where the text file is.
Speaker 1: when you delete read me dot text It doesn't actually remove all the ones and zeros because why is it gonna write zeros to that place?
Speaker 0: That just takes more performance, right?
Speaker 1: All it does is it goes to the place that says read me dot text is over there and erases that.
Speaker 1: So now when you say what files are there?
Speaker 1: It says well Geek nights that wave is over there and you know cool game that exes over there.
Speaker 1: and you say what about reading me dot text?
Speaker 1: It's like what read me that text are you talking about?
Speaker 1: But the files still their files still there the zeros and ones that made up read me dot text are still where they used to Be.
Speaker 1: the file system just doesn't know the file exists.
Speaker 1: It doesn't know where it is.
Speaker 1: But if you're smart and clever and you use various tools You can go and go to the place where reading me dot text still is.
Speaker 1: as long as it hasn't been overwritten yet It's still there and you can read it now, of course this depends a lot on the file system.
Speaker 0: It depends on a lot of things and generally the more you have used your computer since you deleted a file the less likely Yes, the data is still there because the greater the odds are that the data has been overwritten with a new file or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, uh, say you want to delete data securely.
Speaker 0: Well, all right What if I just have a program that writes all zeros to the drive and you know what that works pretty damn Well, that works really well.
Speaker 1: like it takes a lot of money and a lot of time to get the data back if someone just wrote zeros to the Entire drive because you now you lost where the files are where they begin and end you're in big trouble.
Speaker 0: But at the same time because you just wrote uniform data over the drive Alright, there is still the trace of the data because the actual data isn't real ones and zeros.
Speaker 0: It's magnets magnetic fields that are imprinted onto this magnetic medium.
Speaker 1: So you had all these magnetic fields and some of them are zero.
Speaker 0: There's a pattern there.
Speaker 0: you apply a uniform pattern to it to obliterate it.
Speaker 0: But traces of that pattern are still there.
Speaker 0: and because it's digital.
Speaker 0: It's either a one or zero.
Speaker 0: It's really not out of the realm at all to use fancy hardware or possibly even software in certain Circumstances to figure out what used to be on that drive.
Speaker 1: Yep, people have done it in labs and things and if you write all zeros to your hard drive They might not get everything back.
Speaker 1: But they if someone wants to really badly they can get your data off of that drive.
Speaker 0: now Of course the real answer.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm not getting into the details.
Speaker 0: I don't want to go long about this.
Speaker 0: is D Ban DB an just Google for that.
Speaker 0: You can put it on a flash drive put it on a floppy disk and Basically, it will write random or semi random data in multiple many passes over the data You want to get rid of and will fucking delete fucking drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I guess there might be a way to come back from that but it's not.
Speaker 1: no it's needs not realistic.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like yeah, you might be able to decrypt that 4096 bit key.
Speaker 0: maybe see that's another way.
Speaker 0: if you don't want it if you can't well I guess if you can't is stupid.
Speaker 0: but instead of deleting data One thing you could do is encrypt it with very strong encryption and then not keep the key.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing you're trying to prevent here is like let's say I buy a new hard drive and I throw out the old one.
Speaker 1: I don't want someone digging up that old hard drive.
Speaker 1: or if I sell a hard drive on eBay or if I Leave my company and I had stuff on the hard drive there, you know And I don't want anyone to see what it was ID ban any computer that I leave behind when I quit a company.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know I just you know I don't want people to get it data because I let a hard drive go out of my possession and the two ways to stop That are to D ban the drive After I let it out of my possession.
Speaker 1: by the way D band stands for Derek's boot and nuke because a guy named Derek wrote The software called boot and nuke.
Speaker 1: is you boot the software and then it nukes your drive.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool I like it.
Speaker 0: I like it a lot.
Speaker 0: I've used it in professional capacity for a long time.
Speaker 1: It's a very professional tool.
Speaker 1: The other thing you can do is just encrypt your drive.
Speaker 1: There are ways that you can have all the data on your hard drive be encrypted at all times And the only way to have to get the data off your drive would be to use your computer with your password and your software that decrypts it.
Speaker 1: and if anyone took the stole that hard drive from you and Plugged it into their own computer.
Speaker 1: They'd have basically an impossible time reading any of that data.
Speaker 0: Of course then we have to talk again about side channel information because by encrypting the data or Theoretically by using D band because the data it writes could be construed as encrypted data.
Speaker 0: Alright now it's kind of like when I duct tape that book together.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's on this drive, but I know whatever it is the dude encrypted it.
Speaker 0: Yep That's why you got to encrypt and then if you give it to someone boot a nuke or more importantly There are ways to encrypt that give you levels of deniability Where you can have nested levels of encryption or all sorts of fun stuff.
Speaker 0: that is really beyond the scope of tonight's show.
Speaker 1: Yes, the point is that hard drives.
Speaker 1: They're pretty fickle.
Speaker 1: They can get damaged pretty easily and The data on them.
Speaker 1: It's it's actually not trivial to make it go away for real.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess you could just ruin the drive like if you smashed it with a hammer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean theoretically you could get the data back, but that's kind of silly at that point.
Speaker 1: No, it takes a lot of money and a lot of time to do it.
Speaker 1: See if you make it more trouble than it's worth then you pretty much win.
Speaker 0: Suffice to say just remember that when you delete a file, it's probably still there in some form for quite some time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Now what are some ways that you can you know.
Speaker 1: besides, you know Keeping an eye on your hard drives and replacing them when they're about to crash if you find out they're gonna crash Or they have bad sectors.
Speaker 1: What are some ways you can make your hard drives last longer and not crash so much?
Speaker 0: Well, one thing is very simply you can use the power management of your computer to have the drive spin down when you're not using Them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a pretty big deal.
Speaker 1: I mean a hard drive is rated to only turn on and off so many times, you know.
Speaker 1: And if it goes if you turn it on and off more times than that, it's it's eventually that it's gonna near death.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time leaving it spinning all the time does theoretically introduce wear and tear.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean the thing that's gonna kill your hard drive most.
Speaker 1: the problem is is that it's a motor moving parts things moving back And forth stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So you want it to move as little as possible.
Speaker 1: So if you're doing something on your computer or let's say you're not doing anything on your computer You're just leaving it on while you go downstairs to get a drink Why should your computer sit there for hours with the hard drive motor spinning and spinning and spinning and spinning and spinning?
Speaker 1: You want to configure your computer to turn that motor off when it doesn't need to be spinning.
Speaker 0: But at the same time watch out because there's the problem of and this happened to me a bunch of times at IBM We have a server that hasn't been rebooted or anything in years.
Speaker 0: It's just been sitting there plugging along with OS 2. we turn it off to do some maintenance.
Speaker 0: The hard drive just doesn't spin back up.
Speaker 1: Yep Stuff like that happens.
Speaker 1: It's just the nature of motors and lubrication.
Speaker 1: and yeah I like that.
Speaker 0: the real answer there is simple if you've got a drive that you suspect is anything wrong with it There's even a chance.
Speaker 0: get the data off of it before you spin it down or turn it off because there's a there's a small Chance that it's not gonna come back.
Speaker 1: Another thing got to watch out for especially in laptops like to do this is what the laptop, you know Cuz they want to save power will turn off a hard drive pretty quickly like maybe every 10 minutes Maybe even every 5 minutes if you're not using it.
Speaker 1: But what happens is you might end up in a situation where you know Your computer turns the hard drive off or spins it down then it spins it back up and it spins it down.
Speaker 1: then it spins It back up and it spins down.
Speaker 1: spinning up and down constantly like that is not helping.
Speaker 1: It's hurting a lot and your hard drives life will be significantly diminished if you do that.
Speaker 0: Yep, so that's really a fine line and I guess in the end we can't give good advice about it.
Speaker 1: You need to sort of configure it based on your particular use case.
Speaker 1: You know to do this when the batteries for using your laptop battery and do something different when your laptops plugged in and stuff like That.
Speaker 0: here's a much bigger factor.
Speaker 0: This is probably the primary factor.
Speaker 0: It all comes down to heat the hotter your heart.
Speaker 1: actually according to the Google study.
Speaker 1: The heat didn't matter so much I forgot about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically cuz that that IBM heat was gospel and anytime the cooling went out in the data center Hard drives would die for the next.
Speaker 1: well, he does matter.
Speaker 1: right heat is important.
Speaker 1: But if your hard drive, you know It's gonna make heat if it goes cuz the hard drives had fast spinning motors and they're spinning magnetic discs There's gonna be heat.
Speaker 1: it happens if it gets over a certain temperature It's gonna fail cuz it's just too hot for the hard drive, you know, it gets too hot Stuff's gonna break down inside and it's game over.
Speaker 1: But as long as you're not going over the point of too hot for the hard drive it like, you know You put it in like a tiny case and it's very poorly You know.
Speaker 1: then as long as you don't go over like a hot, you know, the crazy temperature.
Speaker 1: It's probably okay.
Speaker 0: However, a lot of people do end up going over the crazy temperature because they never clean their computers They never dusted or they have like a little shuttle case and there isn't a fan blowing over the hard drive and there's all.
Speaker 0: Like you live in a house with cats and you're a smoker and you've never opened your computer.
Speaker 1: Yep Another thing is that actually if you keep hard drives too cold Google actually found out that that actually kind of makes them fail a little more often.
Speaker 1: But it's kind of hard to keep them too cold because hard drives heat up on their own.
Speaker 1: pretty nice Yep, you'd have to like literally put it in a freezer to make it, you know fail from being too cold.
Speaker 1: Another thing that makes heart the biggest thing that makes hard drives fail more often is just did you buy a hard drive?
Speaker 1: that's prone to failure.
Speaker 1: now hard drives are more prone to failure if they have more platters because he basically a hard drive is a bunch of magnetic disks and some hard drives have more magnetic disks than others.
Speaker 1: like a 20 gig drive has one disk and a 40 gig drive has two 20 gig disks and a 60 has three of them.
Speaker 1: But an 80 has maybe four.
Speaker 1: but you might be able to get an 80 that just has one 80 gig disk and then you can get a 160. that's 280 gig disks and so on.
Speaker 1: and it's you have to really look up on the internet and research how many platters are in your drive because a platter and a drive with one read/write head on it is has a rate of failure.
Speaker 1: if You have two of those in your drive You're basically doubling the rate of failure because if either one fails the whole hard drive is done.
Speaker 1: If there's three of them in there You've tripled the rate of failure because even though all of them are equally reliable Individually if any one fails even if the other two still work the drive is done for
Speaker 0: well notice how the same thing applied with Raid multiple hard drives that are rated in a way that isn't redundant, which I guess it's just an 8 at that point Yep, then if any one drive fails your data is fucked.
Speaker 1: Yep that's why you want to have you know hard drives with fewer platters in a raid that is Redundant and then you're pretty safe because your hard drives are not likely to crash and you got the redundancy going on.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I've read numerous articles pointing to the fact that if you take Hard drives that aren't designed to be used in a raid configuration and use them in a raid configuration Generally that puts a lot more stress on the drives than just typical normal use.
Speaker 0: if you make a raid five out of drives that Aren't quite prepared for that You're probably going to increase your data safety overall But at the same time decrease the total lifespan of all your drives.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically another huge factor and maybe the biggest I'm not sure is that expensive drives?
Speaker 1: You know, they're really expensive ones that people buy for servers and the ones that cost more money.
Speaker 1: They're generally just better than the cheap ones.
Speaker 1: The cheap ones are made cheaply.
Speaker 1: They care less about them.
Speaker 0: They basically don't buy that 40 gig Western Digital that you saw at someone's garage sale.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz that's that's gonna crash.
Speaker 0: don't buy used hard drives.
Speaker 1: don't buy the ultra discount hard drive on Newegg.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh the extra mile unless you don't care.
Speaker 1: but go the extra mile and pay the extra 20 bucks to get the higher quality Hard drive, it'll probably be faster be better in quality and last you a lot longer.
Speaker 0: You might wonder why?
Speaker 0: room and Scott if you not recommended a particular brand?
Speaker 0: and the problem is that there's no way to know which brand is Absolutely better because it's almost all anecdotal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and basically, you know I mean in general like I personally Western Digital and Seagate.
Speaker 1: awesome, right?
Speaker 0: I have often used Seagate and max tour.
Speaker 0: diamond maxes about.
Speaker 1: Seagate bought max tour So yeah, but back before and max door bought quantum.
Speaker 0: So if all the max stores that I owned only one failed and it was about time for that one to fail Yeah, I've never had a Seagate fail ever.
Speaker 1: So it's just anecdotal.
Speaker 1: It doesn't mean anything.
Speaker 1: Yes, I've always bought really expensive fancy Seagate's and I know a lot of people who bought really expensive.
Speaker 1: Western Digitals are really expensive.
Speaker 1: Itachi drives and like Hitachi invented that perpendicular whatever and they don't fail either.
Speaker 0: but yet like at IBM We'd buy the fanciest fanciest drives and sometimes they'd fail.
Speaker 1: Well, that's you know.
Speaker 1: It depends on how much stress you're putting them under.
Speaker 1: yeah that fancy drive and put it in a normal desktop computer.
Speaker 1: odds Are it's gonna last a long fucking time.
Speaker 0: The problem is there's no real good data on what brand is actually better.
Speaker 1: and even if you have the best data and it'll say Okay, if you buy this drive and use it for this purpose in this machine odds are it'll you know?
Speaker 1: It won't fail for five years, but those are just the odds.
Speaker 1: you could lose your gambling, you know The odds are in your favor.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's ten to one odds But you that could be the one in ten drive.
Speaker 1: the crashes you don't know.
Speaker 0: See now notice that all the advice we've given really wasn't advice because there were two sides of every coin so far.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's because the only actual answer is back your data up back it up back it up on something.
Speaker 1: There is one thing you should keep in mind though hard drives.
Speaker 1: if they have a problem Like let's say there are manufacture.
Speaker 1: You have a drive that was manufactured poorly.
Speaker 1: It's gonna die in about a year So it's gonna die pretty soon If you have a drive that's lasted you for at least a year or more.
Speaker 1: There probably weren't any manufacturing problems with that drive and you can bet on it Pretty surely that it's gonna last a few more years.
Speaker 0: and until it's you know until it wears out It's kind of this plateau of reliability and this applies to a lot of applies to cars do and a lot of anything Anything you buy.
Speaker 0: if it doesn't fail immediately.
Speaker 0: It's probably going to last relatively long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if you buy a washing machine and the washing machine works and it keeps working for months.
Speaker 1: Then it was made correctly and it's only gonna break from wear and tear from using it a whole lot over time.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna break from.
Speaker 1: you know, oh they didn't wire that thing properly or something like that.
Speaker 1: You know cars are the same way if your car doesn't explode off the lot.
Speaker 1: Then it was made manufactured properly in the factory and it's gonna last you until the.
Speaker 1: you know The pistons start to wear out and you know, the cables break and the car wears down.
Speaker 0: granted It's not quite as clear-cut cut with hard drives and the curve is not as clean as anyone would like it to be.
Speaker 1: Well, a hard drive is unique in that it is a mechanical device that moves a hell of a lot Stays on all the time a lot of the time has a fast spinning motor Generates a lot of heat that isn't dissipated super efficiently.
Speaker 1: It's just chumming or humming away all the time crazily.
Speaker 1: It's it's and it's magnetic.
Speaker 1: It's a very fickle device.
Speaker 0: I really look forward to the day when magnetic hard drives are only backups and all of my real live data is on some sort Of solid-state.
Speaker 0: non flash medium.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I said non flash because flash has problems of its own.
Speaker 0: flash is awesome Except for its numerous and manifold problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and flash is awesome But you can only read and write it so many times and then it's just done.
Speaker 1: and it's not like so many times till it Wears out.
Speaker 1: it's like so many times set in stone Like you can read and write one bit of the flash like five thousand times and then it's done.
Speaker 0: Flash memory actually does interesting things where it'll look at the data You're trying to write to it and try to fit it over data.
Speaker 0: You're overriding in such a way as to change as few bits as possible.
Speaker 1: But that has to be done in the software and not in the flash itself.
Speaker 0: Yes, because that has to be balanced by the speed of because anytime you do anything like that That's gonna take time and slow down your data rate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you're trying to write something quickly You know Like let's say you're trying to take pictures really fast on your camera.
Speaker 1: if your camera doesn't have a lot of RAM It's got a right to that flash real fast And it can't bother be bothered writing to the flash in such a way to prolong the luckily For all its drawbacks.
Speaker 1: flash is stupidly cheap and still it's not stupidly cheap, but it's pretty cheap and awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I was looking and cuz we need.
Speaker 0: we just bought actually for a compact flash isn't really flash?
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of them have hard drives in there.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but those are clearly set.
Speaker 0: they say they're micro drives instead.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I was thinking of getting one of those.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were.
Speaker 0: it's compact flash is an interface not an actual You know, yeah, but they're pretty much either flash or a micro drive.
Speaker 1: Yep, pretty much and go in the same slot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they both have frozen cons, but we just bought actually for geek nights a super fancy portable solid-state recorder.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be pretty awesome because now we can go to conventions and places and this thing records Like as good as our computer records.
Speaker 1: So when we're recording the show, we'll just simultaneously record to it And if something goes wrong We still have the show on there in perfect quality and if we go to a convention We want to record something.
Speaker 1: We just plug it into this thing and it records perfectly.
Speaker 0: So, I mean we've recorded a bunch of stuff at cons before but now we don't have to pull out the Mac Pull out the
Speaker 1: monitor
Speaker 0: hook it all up plug in the compressor You
Speaker 1: think one wire and put it in a little black battery-powered box and push a button.
Speaker 0: So we got to buy a gigantic pile of flash for this thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we do.
Speaker 1: It's a good thing though that you just record mp3 and then we can have a lot of audio in a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll play with it because we might use wave to flash is pretty cheap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the sad thing is this thing cost more than all of the other equipment we've ever bought for geek nights combined.
Speaker 1: It's a very professional piece of equipment and I you know, I think it's worth it to head.
Speaker 0: I almost wish I'd bought the more expensive one, but the extra 200 bucks was not gonna.
Speaker 1: Well, I do agree.
Speaker 1: The more expensive one definitely was clearly superior.
Speaker 1: It was clearly superior and so is the more expensive hard drive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and on that note, I think we're done.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go nurse my wound and possibly eat some food.
Speaker 1: I gotta eat some fucking food.
Speaker 1: God damn.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.