Speaker 1: It's Tuesday October 23rd.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: apples to apples.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So you know that new Zelda game that hourglass of phantoms whatnot?
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: I didn't even buy it or play it yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I bought it.
Speaker 1: I've been playing it have not beat it yet, and there's a reason for that.
Speaker 1: actually There's this one dungeon in the game it.
Speaker 1: overall there are many things about this Zelda game that make me go.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, this is the Zelda business, but there are other things about this game that make me go.
Speaker 1: This is just annoying and I wish I didn't have to do it And it's sort of tearing me two ways.
Speaker 1: and the one thing that's really bothering me Is this one dungeon sort of like the main big dungeon of the game and you have to keep returning to it.
Speaker 1: It's like you go out to other dungeons around the world or map and you get stuff.
Speaker 1: You know new items one per dungeon of course.
Speaker 1: you know you.
Speaker 1: you get them and you come back and Every time you get something new you come back to the original dungeon And you kind of.
Speaker 1: now that you have this new item you can go further in the main dungeon, but This main dungeon is really fucking annoying and not so fun compared to the other dungeons because it's sort of one of those hide from Bad guys dungeons, but it's also a time limit dungeon.
Speaker 0: So yeah have to keep doing the parts of the dungeon or like there's no way to just well like open two areas and then Come back and beat them both.
Speaker 1: Well sometimes right they they allow you to Basically like the first few times.
Speaker 1: It's like you can.
Speaker 1: the first time in the beginning of the game We just do one floor.
Speaker 1: then the second time you go through you can do like two or three floors And you never had to do the first floor.
Speaker 1: more than once You know and the floors get easier to do because you have more items available to you.
Speaker 1: So you can just sort of blow through them quick You know.
Speaker 1: it's like as soon as you get the bombs like the second and third floors get a lot easier You know.
Speaker 1: and when you get the bomb shoes another floor gets a lot easier And you can also unlock the more treasure chests on certain floors And you get more items.
Speaker 0: what I was saying is could just go around the game like opening like doing all the things to open Everything and then just come back and beat the whole.
Speaker 1: no because you need to like come back Get another piece of the sea chart.
Speaker 1: go out to that new part of the sea chart to where the new dungeon is.
Speaker 1: Come back get another sea chart.
Speaker 1: go out to where that plays.
Speaker 0: You know like that you know I don't know because on one hand the formula like the original formula of Zelda kind of in my opinion almost peaked at Snes link to the past because that was just a straight-up.
Speaker 0: There are areas you were denied to and as you get more items you were able to range ever Increasingly until eventually you were a master of the entire game, and there's a million dungeons, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess that formula kind of got overplayed, and they they're trying to make it more interesting.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: the games control surprisingly well with just the stylus.
Speaker 1: But there's one more thing to say about the crazy dungeon.
Speaker 1: is that you know after you go down like I say I guess five Floors or so or there's some floor I forget which floor it is you like.
Speaker 1: get to this yellow glowy bit right and you can use the yellow glowy bit to teleport Between there and the beginning of the dungeon.
Speaker 1: so now you don't have to do those in-between floors anymore You can just teleport past them.
Speaker 1: uh-huh, but I want to go and get all those treasure chests now that I've got new items On those in between.
Speaker 0: well if you want treasure chests you got to go do something right.
Speaker 0: go get them.
Speaker 0: otherwise.
Speaker 1: But it's like but it's not like treasure chests in someplace.
Speaker 1: new is treasure Annoying place that I've done already.
Speaker 0: well Then wait and then get all those treasure chests at once later, but getting those treasure chests earlier gives me new powers.
Speaker 0: Well, you gotta choose between the two.
Speaker 1: right, but not only that right.
Speaker 1: let's say I go down But you have this timer and as you get more sand for your hourglass you get more time in the timer.
Speaker 1: and when you're in The dungeons not standing in a safe spot the main only this main dungeon other dungeons are normal when you're in this main dungeon not Standing in a safe spot the timer counts down.
Speaker 1: So you try to stay in the safe spots as much as you can because that's also where the bad guys can't see you and You know you.
Speaker 1: you want to get there with as much time remaining as possible.
Speaker 1: Well when you get to the yellow spot, and you teleport back to the beginning of the dungeon it Remembers how much time it took you to get to that yellow spot.
Speaker 1: So if I teleport to the yellow spot for the beginning so I don't have to do those to repeat those floors And like cuts five minutes off my time, but now that I have new items I could actually make it there in like three minutes and save myself two minute You know.
Speaker 1: so it's like if I want to cut my time off I got to do it again.
Speaker 1: it at least the title of the game means something it does But it's it's tough because it's it's a lot better than a lot of recent Minish cats.
Speaker 1: yeah It's a zillion times well not as bad as Philip CDI, but that's not a Zelda game.
Speaker 0: That's one of those.
Speaker 1: I have no son Situations, but yeah, I guess we're not gonna fully review this until rim beats it, and I beat it and everything.
Speaker 1: But it's a really good Zelda game that I feel was worth the money.
Speaker 1: But I'm having a hard time beating it because this main part of the game is just so frustrating.
Speaker 0: I don't recall when Scott came into my room and said all right.
Speaker 0: Here's the puzzle From some part of the game kind of early on.
Speaker 0: how do you solve it?
Speaker 0: And I'm not gonna spoil it for you all, but the solution was kind of shitty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like really shitty one of those Exactly and I feel like I would probably have solved it by accident after getting frustrated, but Something like that.
Speaker 1: so yeah if you like Zelda's you like this game.
Speaker 1: the stylus controls are sort of amazingly good.
Speaker 1: You kind of forget you're playing with the stylus after a while But at the same time playing on a shaky shaky train at some part most of the time doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: like walking around killing Bad guys is fine, but at other parts is like ah fuck fuck fuck.
Speaker 1: you got to play it somewhere.
Speaker 1: You're not shaking which is I think one thing they didn't think about.
Speaker 1: what the DS.
Speaker 1: Is that a game with like?
Speaker 1: you cannot play Kirby's Whatever it is canvas curve canvas curse.
Speaker 1: I know it's been so long since I played it.
Speaker 1: you cannot play that in a car or a train or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You need to be like sitting in a chair not moving or else You're just not gonna be able to play unless you like.
Speaker 1: I guess if you have like the shaky hand disease And it sort of counteracts the shakiness of your surround.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that's how it works.
Speaker 1: You know what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: you get the at the point.
Speaker 1: It's yeah, right.
Speaker 0: so as you all may or may not be aware There are four times as many Americans living in urban cities than in rural areas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there there are four times more people living in New York City than farming.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm total like just more people live in New York City than farm.
Speaker 1: So you took all the farmers and you stood them up next to all the New York City people.
Speaker 1: New Yorkers outnumber them for everyone got in a fight and If anyone who you would all be one-on-one fights and anyone who actually fought But would die there would be New Yorkers left and there wouldn't be farmers left.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is New Yorkers would probably win anyway, just because they're generally tough.
Speaker 1: that yeah Yeah, some of the same time count them out.
Speaker 0: You know if we got this those many people think about it.
Speaker 0: at that point the farmers have one really really big advantage Threshers, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we got taxis.
Speaker 0: well Along those lines there are there are more people playing World of Warcraft right now as players in the game.
Speaker 0: Then there are farmers in the whole world at least in the US.
Speaker 1: you mean farmers actually farm not farmers.
Speaker 0: gold farming No, no.
Speaker 0: actual farmers digging up potatoes and I guess in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Is case corn.
Speaker 0: Yeah and corn derivatives Well, they're not digging them up.
Speaker 0: They're Harvest corn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess I could dig up corn and harvest potatoes.
Speaker 1: All right, so are you just counting the World of Warcraft us players or the worldwide world?
Speaker 0: I don't know this article sucks, but I'm not even gonna get into that.
Speaker 0: but it brings up a much more interesting point that Scott and I were talking about a little bit before the show that the popular conception of America still seems to be that.
Speaker 0: you know People are generally rural in Midwestern like the heart of America the heartland of America.
Speaker 0: that was.
Speaker 0: that's what matters.
Speaker 0: but Americans are Mostly city-dwelling World of Warcraft players and not so much farmers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean even you know, the other general conception of the core of America, which is the sort of you know, iconic Nuclear family with like, you know working dad and a soccer mom and kids in school playing sports and learning stuff.
Speaker 1: You know that sort of suburban ideal fantasy that doesn't really exist Even if you find the few of those that do exist the kids are playing World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: The moms are playing casual games online.
Speaker 1: The dads are doing all sorts of text.
Speaker 0: I just think that up their AV system within a generation the real heartland of America in terms of just people Culturally is going to be the mp3 Downloading game playing video punk kid kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I don't know I find that interesting.
Speaker 0: I just think the real issue under this is more that Society and culture kind of progressing faster than I guess ideas about society or government Relations with culture are able to keep up.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean you go look at the news and you're never gonna see that.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like how when we make a big story on dig is like oh my god There was a nerd on the news like oh my god Mentioned video games.
Speaker 1: like there's a one reference to video games like on something, right?
Speaker 1: It's not supposed to be news.
Speaker 1: That should be so super commonplace because that's like a huge part of the culture.
Speaker 1: instead We still you know, the the the mainstream cult, you know, it I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess the media have you know the media private vested interest in playing to their audience because the common mainstream media's audience is Not the World of Warcraft playing punk kid because that kid doesn't have time for TV and doesn't give a shit about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah but at the same time even the World of Warcraft punk kids conception is that the World of Warcraft punk kid is sort of in a Minority.
Speaker 1: and I think that the media, you know not catching up with the culture is also Causing the false ideas about the culture at the same time.
Speaker 1: It's like it's sort of like its own little loop there.
Speaker 1: It's like because they don't realize the world is not the way they think it is.
Speaker 1: They give everyone the idea the world isn't the way they think it is.
Speaker 1: So they continue to portray the world in a way that it not is see.
Speaker 0: but then at the same time I wonder if a lot of those because especially kids in school and like urban areas just They might not even notice that because they don't watch their traditional media.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and they're all their friends play World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: everyone they know plays World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'd like to see a survey where they ask them what they think about like.
Speaker 1: You know like the rest of the world's like, you know because I mean even if you're hanging out like with a whole group of nerds at Otakon there's 20,000 anime fans you think and the rest of the world doesn't even know what the fuck anime is.
Speaker 0: The thing is it's scary because it's kind of true.
Speaker 0: But not like it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we're at the turning point yet I think the no, it's like you sit there and you look at the the Circumstantial and anecdotal evidence you have right in front of your face.
Speaker 1: You're sitting around with 20,000.
Speaker 1: Here's here's a guy and you go out on the street and you send people say what the fuck is going on over there.
Speaker 0: Here's a good example you go to RIT the Rochester Institute of Technology, right?
Speaker 0: walk around the campus and you see mostly like frat boys sitting in hot tubs and People playing like football and hacky sack it might be and like normal stuff.
Speaker 0: or you see people going birds cold But you don't see it like geekery like just out there.
Speaker 0: But yet if you walk through the dorms outside of the public eye, it's nothing but kids Masturbating playing Counter-Strike sometimes both World of Warcraft World of Warcraft Playing D&D going to anime and all that.
Speaker 0: and I don't I feel like the next generation as that they grow up is going.
Speaker 0: we're gonna see a Kind of sudden and market shift in the conception of culture in the United States.
Speaker 1: Maybe that is part of it though and that the culture that we have reception the culture that we have is physically inside.
Speaker 1: it's a culture of individuality and Sort of privacy like everyone sits in their own room where no one can see Communicating with each other in a place.
Speaker 1: No one can see so since the culture is invisible It's not like.
Speaker 1: it's not like fashion where you walk around the street and you see all suddenly Everyone's wearing blue jeans.
Speaker 1: or it's not like you walk around the street and you see all these, you know, punk skater kids You know, it's like skater.
Speaker 1: culture is visible.
Speaker 1: You see it out there plus just locality.
Speaker 0: I mean if you take any culture and just average it out across the whole world Suddenly all the members of that culture no matter how big it is are pretty isolated from each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but geeks and just I guess the current generation in the Western industrialized internet world They're connected to each other no matter where they are and we've said this a lot.
Speaker 0: But I have more in common with some geeky kid in China or some geeky kid in South Africa.
Speaker 0: Then I do with the majority of the people who live in the city where I physically am.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Not only that, but I forgot what I was gonna say.
Speaker 1: Hold on.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel like our culture is gonna change a lot really quickly in our lifetimes And I think it's gonna be kind of an unprecedented pace of change because the new generations Have ways of communicating that the old generations just don't get and can't follow.
Speaker 1: Another thing I think what it is is that you know I there are like you see more geeks than you realize because geeks are sort of subtle, you know It's like unless they're wearing a geeky t-shirt, right?
Speaker 1: You see you might see geeks all the time.
Speaker 1: You see someone you might not realize that in their backpack is like ten pokemons, you know It's like you can't have ten pokemons.
Speaker 1: Like I walk around the street.
Speaker 1: What am I wearing?
Speaker 1: I'm wearing blue jeans.
Speaker 1: I'm wearing a blue t-shirt with a pic with a hot dog on it Right a picture of a hot dog on it, which I guess a super geek would recognize as a specific threadless shirt But most would just not even recognize it.
Speaker 1: and I was wearing like a Mets hoodie.
Speaker 1: So I don't even look like what I am, you know.
Speaker 1: So it's totally this invisible culture going on so people don't realize exactly how big it is.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's by the same token.
Speaker 0: That's why there is a lot mean you wrote that thing about this the social currency of the geek world.
Speaker 0: a lot of people now will they kind of.
Speaker 0: it's not like.
Speaker 0: I mean you see the people who wear like the black t-shirt with The square print of the red dragon, but a lot of people now that are more with it.
Speaker 0: Just kind of.
Speaker 0: it's like they keep small tokens of who they really are visible Just kind of as a like.
Speaker 0: it's almost like a Masonic ring Sort of yeah, like you see a little tan berry hanging from someone's cell phone.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like there's a few people I noticed on my commute Like there's a guy on the train who has a big old laptop and he's your typical, you know.
Speaker 1: Use a laptop business guy, but he's always playing some typical.
Speaker 0: use a laptop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, you know, I do I do but I still find that phrase funny yeah, but he's he's always playing a really crappy but He's always playing a different each time.
Speaker 1: I see him but crappy World War based FPS of some sort, you know.
Speaker 1: And there's like another guy is always playing like some crappy sports game on his PSP that no real gamer would buy.
Speaker 1: But that kind of person would buy.
Speaker 1: and there's another guy I see on the subway.
Speaker 1: Sometimes he's got this Helsing bag.
Speaker 1: He you know every other way he looks he's wearing, you know, the long-sleeve business shirt with a collar and you know pants for business But his bag says Helsing on it.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I guess the real moral is not to turn this into a whole episode but I mean I want I also have to say that another Confounding factor here is simply that farming is a lot more efficient than it used to be and it takes far fewer people to farm Which that's why I guess the Iowa caucuses Infuriate me because they shouldn't be as important as they are, but I digress.
Speaker 1: I just World of Warcraft caucus, you know, what's the?
Speaker 1: what's the place in World of Warcraft called Azeroth Azeroth caucus?
Speaker 0: You know, I more every now and then people like that.
Speaker 0: I would play World of Warcraft When I was in like high school, like I was a freshman sophomore in high school even in middle school I'm on the internet and I'm doing my internet shit.
Speaker 0: I always would think and I think a lot of geeks think the same thing.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute We're all over the place.
Speaker 0: What if we acted together?
Speaker 0: we could fuck things up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is we just haven't yet and there's a lot of reasons for that and we'll get into it.
Speaker 1: I really do think there should be some sort of internet caucus of sorts.
Speaker 1: I think what it's.
Speaker 1: even if I could do internet voting at least, you know Let the the people of that culture that are from the US that are you know living differently than everyone else.
Speaker 1: Let them have some sort of you know, say it's such a yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: Here's the thing I like the idea and I feel like like if we Were inclined if we were even if it doesn't actually count if it's just yeah.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: if we were well one if I was the lead like the head of the DNC or the head of the Republicans I Would push something like that just to make my party suddenly appear 10,000 times hipper than the other party and pretty much automatically get the vote of the internet generation.
Speaker 0: Ah, good call I like that.
Speaker 0: I think that because you wouldn't have to listen to it You don't give it any votes in the primaries or anything.
Speaker 0: But just do something like that and ignore whatever it says, but just say you're doing it and holy shit.
Speaker 0: But again, I digress.
Speaker 0: I think the point here if you sum it up, it's just that Gaming, I mean, you know, there's people like Jack Thompson.
Speaker 0: everyone worries like oh games are under attack.
Speaker 0: games are gonna be censored.
Speaker 0: gaming is becoming such a Silent ubiquitous part of American culture that I'm not worried.
Speaker 0: I think in a generation or two gaming is going to be as ubiquitous in the future as television is now.
Speaker 1: I mean Halo 3 made more monies than like most movies Yep and Nintendo.
Speaker 0: their market cap makes them one of the biggest companies in the world now almost entirely on the merits of selling the Wii to old Ladies and the DS mostly the DS to kids and old people.
Speaker 1: All right, speaking of Nintendo Oh Nintendo Well, we were not doing any news or things of the day all last week, which is questions week Which you haven't listened to.
Speaker 1: you should go back listen all four episodes from last week.
Speaker 1: There was big news mostly from the Nintendo camp mostly a press release.
Speaker 1: So they announced everything in the frickin known universe and a couple other things too One of those things being they're delaying the Smash Brothers, which you know on the one hand Everyone is waiting for that.
Speaker 1: Smash Brothers Like it's gonna be the thing that changes the world and it will have a significant impact on the gaming population An impact I foresee people losing jobs.
Speaker 1: however, I really don't see a problem with the delay because the delay can only mean a. the game will be hopefully better right because Spend more time.
Speaker 0: Ah, I'm Duke Nukem forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 1: Well, they did.
Speaker 1: they did announce a new date.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: yeah, we're delaying it indefinitely.
Speaker 1: It's yeah, it's delayed until February.
Speaker 0: I believe I recall some Team Fortress 2 dates.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, yeah, I think the delay will make the game better.
Speaker 1: Oh, I also there's so many games out like right now just cuz you know It's video game season and all these other games that they're talking about that.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of glad they pushed it back.
Speaker 1: So these other games actually, you know that I'm gonna buy no matter what get some time to get played.
Speaker 1: I mean if they put this out and Mario Galaxy out everyone will buy both and not play Mario Galaxy, you know It's well, I'll be honest.
Speaker 0: I would wager that most if not like most of the work is not like.
Speaker 0: they're not delaying it for any technical reason.
Speaker 0: I'm almost certain that they're delaying it just to put it into a better slot and like they probably looked at the Curve of what games are coming out when and they're like, all right winter game sales gonna slump Let's release it right then to have a continuous wave of sales
Speaker 1: exactly instead of people complaining about the Nintendo drought You know, oh they haven't come out with a game in like months.
Speaker 1: Well now they'll come out with a game and then a few months later they come out.
Speaker 1: You know, they come with a game instead of a bunch of games at once and then no games for a long time.
Speaker 0: Well the Nintendo news that Scott was gonna bring up and I'll just jump right in here that I'm most looking forward to It's just the fact that Okami is being released on the Wii and I really really wanted to play that game and I thought it looked really awesome.
Speaker 0: I heard great things about it, but I Still just couldn't bring myself to buy a ps2.
Speaker 0: There just weren't enough compelling games for me as a gamer.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of compelling game there are but not a lot of them are brought to your attention because they're just so many and most of them are so Old.
Speaker 0: what I'm saying is there aren't enough compelling games for the ps2 to me to warrant me one buying it and to taking The time out of my life to play all those games.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Take time to let to play all those games.
Speaker 1: I think if the ps2 gets like another price drop.
Speaker 1: and then you know If you were made aware of all the games for the ps2 like you actually sat down with a list of ps2 games It'd be incredibly long.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's all right.
Speaker 0: I can think of 10 or 15 that I want to play or have wanted.
Speaker 1: that's how many you can think of this probably like 40, you know, I think a better issues.
Speaker 0: if I were Nintendo I would approach Scott and I Scott had this idea to pretty much Everyone who made ps2 games and try to get the rights to just straight-up port those games to the Wii Yeah, and sell them for 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean why not?
Speaker 1: Frickin The problem is you know Sony's got their big thing like oh, we're gonna make all these PlayStation games go on the ps3.
Speaker 1: I think they got stuff for like.
Speaker 1: you can play ps1 games on the PSP Like you can download them or something and stuff like that going on.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if you know if companies I think it's mostly for a lot of the companies that released, you know Really innovative sort of out there games that were different from the herd, you know Like the psychonauts and stuff things that didn't sell back then, you know.
Speaker 1: But you know, they they put them out and they're there and now they're not making money off them anymore.
Speaker 1: But it's like they're not like, you know It's like PC games where you can just take the same exact code and just put you know Draw attention to it again to try to make some more money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like for example say you just took old scum.
Speaker 0: I'm putting all the ID software games on Steam take scum VM games Maybe update the graphics and then just release them in anthologies on the Wii for 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean there's.
Speaker 1: there's a big potential now for P. a lot of people have Wiis and DS's and a lot of people There aren't enough games for the Wiis and DS's to you know, and Nintendo's the only one who really makes like the big ones You know, so it's sort of difficult for people making new third-party games to compete with Nintendo.
Speaker 1: They just put a lot of crap out there and I think there's a big market for taking older games from other systems and just making Wii ports that are cheap or DS ports that are cheap and The game drought will go away because you fill it in with all these rereleases of awesome things.
Speaker 1: Of course a lot of people complain like oh the Wii is just full of rereleases.
Speaker 1: Well, most people didn't play a lot of those games, especially a lot of these, you know average grandmas and stuff buying Wiis.
Speaker 0: plus if there's a family that has a Wii and Grandma has to buy a game for their kid a lot of those games Really just will sell especially if they're 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah 50 bucks All right, but let's go down that it was big written in news's about all the releases that are gonna happen.
Speaker 1: So let's let's go over some of these.
Speaker 1: Today's the 23rd today.
Speaker 1: Actually the you remember the table tennis game from rockstar?
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's out on the we know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess if you're liking that, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I heard some good things.
Speaker 1: I heard some average things Price game.
Speaker 0: I don't think I could deal with the game like that.
Speaker 0: Just cuz.
Speaker 0: I played table tennis in the real world and I was really good at it.
Speaker 1: I think it'd be better than we.
Speaker 1: tennis probably but I don't know how if it's gonna be worth buying a whole game for it.
Speaker 0: Man, I'm just.
Speaker 0: I want Mario tennis to come out on the we so I know I know.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the Guitar Hero 3 comes out in like five days for everything.
Speaker 1: battalion wars - oh yeah, battalion wars supposed to be related to advance or somehow and Supposedly battalion wars.
Speaker 1: one was the suck, but I'm hearing some low rumblings about good stuff at the battalion wars - but I think it's worth paying for.
Speaker 0: It'll probably eventually be worth.
Speaker 1: It's the kind of game where I'd very much like to be able to like try it out maybe like rent it just well Don't worry Scott Johnson will buy it.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's for sure.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: Good call There's gonna be a Namco museum for the the Wii which I don't understand because the DS one is fine.
Speaker 1: Why do I need the Wii one for?
Speaker 1: The Fire Emblem game comes out November 5th for Wii.
Speaker 1: the DDR for the Wii comes out November 6th.
Speaker 1: Lego Star Wars complete saga comes out November 6.
Speaker 0: Those games are actually pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean at first I was like Lego Star Wars whatever and then I saw like some footage from it.
Speaker 1: And I'm all about Lego Star Wars.
Speaker 1: This is the complete saga.
Speaker 1: So this is like all the Lego.
Speaker 1: Star Wars is like all of them supposedly and I'm torn Should I get it for the Wii or the DS?
Speaker 1: I don't know which one do you think?
Speaker 0: You know just because we commute I think the DS is still gonna be our primary console.
Speaker 1: I know but this this feels like a game I should get for the Wii.
Speaker 1: maybe you know Cuz?
Speaker 1: it's sort of like the thing where everyone sits around watching and then laughing and stuff.
Speaker 1: Anyway that same November 6 apparently big release day the Mario Sonic Olympic Games is coming and while that looks okay I don't know if I want to buy that either.
Speaker 1: Yeah November 12th is the Mario Galaxy and that is why part of the reason why I'm glad they delayed the old Smash Brothers because now I can actually play Mario Galaxy without being rudely interrupted by a Smash Brothers release.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward to this.
Speaker 0: I mean, I didn't even really play the the previous Mario game Feeling this is gonna be a lot better.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, the thing is the best part of the last Mario game.
Speaker 0: Were all those like in the pipe stages where you run across just three-dimensional things and Jumping platform and all the puzzle II go around the world.
Speaker 0: I didn't care about that at all.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to do 3d Mario levels.
Speaker 0: that were really hard.
Speaker 1: Yep, we got some geometry wars coming on the 13th.
Speaker 1: for the Wii There's an.
Speaker 1: I think this geometry war is coming for the DS also.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the date on that is.
Speaker 1: We got the puzzle quest coming for the Wii.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna start with the dates anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, you know this made me realize that you could Redo and release something like DEFCON on the Wii pretty handily.
Speaker 0: Yep, right kind and it probably do really well.
Speaker 1: There's another trauma center coming for the Wii that allows like tag team surgery where you both surgery at the same time.
Speaker 0: That sounds awesomely stupid or stupidly awesome sad.
Speaker 1: I agree.
Speaker 1: Hey, there's some golden compass thing people are talking about But I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: the that Rygar which people have been talking about about that up the Knights game I'm getting Knights for people who don't understand.
Speaker 1: you might have noticed on certain video game blogs all this hubbub about like Knights into dreams.
Speaker 1: whatever I haven't.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, there's a game was a game for the Sega Saturn called Knights into dreams And it was like this huge game for the Sega Saturn went like it was on the cover of every video game magazine.
Speaker 1: I played demos in stores, and I think I played it at someone's house once.
Speaker 1: It was an awesome freaking game where you're like this jester thing flying around and it was sort of like a flying platforming kind of game.
Speaker 1: it was there really isn't much else like it and Everyone, you know, it's one of those things where people say hey whatever happened to that?
Speaker 1: You know cuz it's.
Speaker 1: it's like a game they made once and people liked it and then it's like where did it go?
Speaker 1: we don't know what happened to that and They're finally making another ones coming out for the Wii and I'm probably just gonna buy it Because I got to support that kind of action.
Speaker 1: Some Soul Calibur legends, I don't know what's up with that.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is Soul Calibur kind of disappointed me because I know a lot of people agree with me though There are exceptions that Soul Calibur 2 was a lot better than like Soul Calibur 3 wasn't really worse than Soul Calibur 2.
Speaker 0: It just it wasn't better enough for anyone to care.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I to this day Soul Calibur 2 is Probably one of my favorite, you know traditional fighting games out there.
Speaker 1: Soul Calibur 2 is one of the best fighting game.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's that and it could be Shido blade.
Speaker 1: No, but Shido blade is awesome.
Speaker 1: Soul Calibur 2 I think I will say is the best 3d fighting game.
Speaker 0: There is just a hot damn still.
Speaker 1: I want a new Soul Calibur to come out But it's got to be better than Soul Calibur 2 which is hard because the bar is really high.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean three just wasn't better enough.
Speaker 0: Like it had incremental improvements and incremental I guess On improvements.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like no link.
Speaker 1: No GameCube.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No GameCube is pretty much it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Smash Brothers in the spring.
Speaker 1: There's there's crystal chronicles coming for both systems, but they've been talking about those for so long.
Speaker 1: But I just keep changing the name Putting out new screenshots.
Speaker 1: Well, there's no conclusive anything.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: Those games are coming out someday and I gotta say The the thing the defining moment in gaming for me is going to be when I turn on my DS Connect it wirelessly to my Wii and play some sort of four-player multiplayer Semi-cooperative game.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's how it's gonna work.
Speaker 1: I think there's a Wii game and a DS game and I'd haven't heard about.
Speaker 1: Everyone's always talking.
Speaker 1: are they gonna link up link and link it.
Speaker 0: I know I didn't say this will be it.
Speaker 0: I just said once there is a game that uses the DS and the Wii in a competitive Cooperative way, I think that is going to be the greatest game of our generation.
Speaker 1: It's all we got now is the pokemons because so I mean soul caliber crystal chronicles for the GameCube was flawed.
Speaker 0: it was mostly just a tech demo, but at the same time it proved to me that Even a flawed game like that can be fucking awesome and four swords had a similar feeling Like Nintendo was so close to greatness.
Speaker 0: They just don't bother.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't have to.
Speaker 0: I know where they aim so much lower than they could.
Speaker 0: they had to learn from moonlight miles.
Speaker 0: They go into space and have sex with Sherpa.
Speaker 1: They're exactly the same as Apple.
Speaker 1: It's like you have this this potential, right?
Speaker 1: You have this but you're on like the top of a mountain with all this potential energy And you could roll all the way down the mountain and achieve terminal velocity.
Speaker 1: But instead if you only roll halfway down the mountain, you'll still get a bajillion dollars.
Speaker 1: So why wait why roll all the way halfway all the way down the mountain?
Speaker 1: You can just roll halfway down.
Speaker 1: It's so much more work to roll all the way down.
Speaker 1: why bother so they don't and they still make up a jillion dollars.
Speaker 1: They don't care.
Speaker 0: That's why to this day.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should in the future We should do a donation campaign to buy a we dev kit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Let's see, let's wrap this up.
Speaker 1: we've been going for like 30 minutes, okay DS People are talking about that front mission who like those tactical robot kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Dave and Joel were talking about front mission at some point.
Speaker 1: Yeah front mission DS.
Speaker 1: Actually, I played his worms new worms for the DS.
Speaker 1: that's already out.
Speaker 0: you guys said it was good.
Speaker 1: I played it and it was not bad like the first worms for the DS.
Speaker 1: So go buy worms - for the DS if you like worms But make sure you get the worms - for the DS and not the original worms the DS which God the original worms.
Speaker 0: luckily I didn't buy it, but I like I'd planned out I was like worms for the DS.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, and luckily someone else took that bullet.
Speaker 1: No Mario Party DS is.
Speaker 1: is it out or is it coming out?
Speaker 0: Okay, I don't know if I care.
Speaker 1: it's it's it's supposed.
Speaker 1: at least people say it's a little faster even though I still think it's Mario Party and Mostly it only has local wireless not the Wi-Fi action Which I guess.
Speaker 1: that's why good a lot of people are acting like.
Speaker 1: that's a bad thing.
Speaker 0: But I'm like, do you want to play a Mario Party with someone who isn't in the room with it?
Speaker 1: The only way they're gonna quit the game and you'll be stuck.
Speaker 0: Not only that the only point of playing Mario Party I mean the game is so slow that like playing it without three other people in the room and Some sort of championship belt is just not worth.
Speaker 1: to be honest with you The DS has Wi-Fi and I have a lot of Wi-Fi games.
Speaker 1: I just never used the Wi-Fi cuz it's kind of and I'm not interested in Wireless.
Speaker 1: I use crazily like.
Speaker 0: I think some games could do it better like You could probably do something with advance Wars.
Speaker 0: that will go really well on the Wi-Fi But most of the time I'd rather play with actual human beings.
Speaker 0: and I say that because people on the internet are not humans.
Speaker 1: Speaking of advance Wars new new advance Wars.
Speaker 1: But they change in all the look don't care and they're changing all the CEOs.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: She's still she's still the game.
Speaker 1: I want it's it's advance or so?
Speaker 0: I'm a man who beat advance Wars one Every mission in normal and hard with an s-rank and then everything in the war rooms.
Speaker 0: I did the same thing for advance Wars 2 and The only reason I didn't do it for advance Wars DS is because it was all the same man.
Speaker 1: It's looking like the game is just more advance Wars.
Speaker 0: Well plus that from what I've read they kind of dumped all the CEOs and it's like they're starting fresh with a lot of things Which is really a good idea because the CEO balance in advance Wars as it was Was getting kind of broken.
Speaker 0: like I just the there were only like two CEOs.
Speaker 0: They were actually good and everything else was just crap.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 0: It's true Plus the fact that I just kind of broken the game by playing it too much.
Speaker 0: I need something more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah in general it's like hey, you know There's there's a lot anyone who's still complaining like all the weeds got no games.
Speaker 1: all the DS got no games.
Speaker 0: The only legitimate complaint you can have is that the Wii does not have the full potential realized yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean in a in a month from now There's gonna be plenty of Wii games.
Speaker 1: You'll have nothing to complain about anyone who says oh there's no games for the Wii.
Speaker 1: That I think the people who are is gonna be saying.
Speaker 1: if you're still saying that a month or two from now Then all that means is you just don't like the video games that there are because there are plenty to like.
Speaker 1: You just only care about Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: not you know, I mean right now.
Speaker 1: I must agree There's not a lot of Wii games.
Speaker 1: a month from now There will be plenty of Wii games and if you just don't like those games, that's you.
Speaker 1: That's no longer Nintendo's fault.
Speaker 1: a month from now things of the day.
Speaker 1: Let's make it quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we probably should but I found this.
Speaker 0: I had another thing But I'm saving it and it's someone's list of the people who are ruining halo 3 now.
Speaker 0: when I started reading it I thought it was a joke.
Speaker 0: I thought it was one of those ironic like tongue-in-cheek Kind of like back in the day like in the quake two days.
Speaker 0: I read an article that was similar, but it was like what is ruining quake 2 lithium death match death match.
Speaker 0: It was like number one BFG whores.
Speaker 0: number two rocket launcher.
Speaker 1: There were eight people three everybody.
Speaker 0: Gaga you can't horten weapon huh?
Speaker 0: the last the last entry was blaster whores And then there was an addendum jumping whores and it was like if you don't get the joke by now You shouldn't be playing this game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well this article is the same article for Halo 3, but This guy's not kidding.
Speaker 0: He's actually complaining about all right.
Speaker 0: number one thing ruining the Halo 3 swordsmen.
Speaker 0: people who can't the sword and use the horn.
Speaker 0: number two Rocket whores.
Speaker 0: people who can't the rocket and use it.
Speaker 0: number three people who use the laser.
Speaker 0: number four children playing the game.
Speaker 0: Number five people who can't.
Speaker 0: number six people who snipe.
Speaker 0: number seven people who go for achievements.
Speaker 0: Number eight people who quit games in the middle.
Speaker 0: the only legitimate complaint here is people who go Into the microphone, but you know what that?
Speaker 0: that's a problem.
Speaker 1: I have a separate rant about the achievements.
Speaker 1: right but for every other complaint All I have to say is those were problems with FPS is way back in the day that have largely been solved well Except in Halo.
Speaker 1: not to say that more modern FPS is than Halo.
Speaker 1: You know not speaking time wise because Halo 3 very modern.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much brand new but modern PC FPS is.
Speaker 1: don't have these problems of camping weapons anymore and TF 2.
Speaker 1: It's a class being a natural selection.
Speaker 1: It's a game where just people you know you buy the weapons and counter-strike you buy weapons with money.
Speaker 1: These things don't happen in FPS.
Speaker 0: Solve these problems like lithium deathmatch.
Speaker 0: no no once you had a weapon if you were good you could beat anyone.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like.
Speaker 0: I remember once I was playing and I was accused of being a hyper blaster whore because I was using nothing But the hyper blaster.
Speaker 0: so I went got the chaingun And then I got accused of being a chaingun whore, and then I started using the fucking shotgun, and then I got kicked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah, but like counter-strike.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter what fucking weapon you choose encounter.
Speaker 1: You have to use the different weapons in different ways.
Speaker 1: But it's not like people use the AK a ruin in the game.
Speaker 1: people use the AWP ruin in the game.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's like the guns part of the game.
Speaker 1: It's part of the game.
Speaker 1: It's not like if a gun in the game and people using it to the best of its ability is ruining the game.
Speaker 0: So I say game is a bad game and so I saw you JW maker of this list on this website that I don't really care much about.
Speaker 0: Welcome to FPS is.
Speaker 0: I hope you have a good time, but I think you have a lot to learn.
Speaker 1: All right, I got it like 1990 called.
Speaker 0: They want their list back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, okay?
Speaker 1: Check this out.
Speaker 1: this guy all right went to a DMV, and he stole the thing that prints driver's licenses.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, and he was printed out IDs and doing all sorts of identity thefts.
Speaker 0: I guess technically oh I would have made really I would have made funny driver's licenses.
Speaker 1: I'm sure he might have done some of those two right.
Speaker 0: I would just want to put a subtle joke in my driver's license.
Speaker 1: Now get this already.
Speaker 1: here's where the hilarity comes.
Speaker 1: all right This is a non gaming thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Just because it was so great.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's some sort of digi mark printer or something and they only sell these obviously to.
Speaker 1: you know the DMV that you know.
Speaker 1: There's nowhere else to get.
Speaker 0: he called to get tech support.
Speaker 1: He called it did.
Speaker 1: he couldn't get the to work with his computer.
Speaker 1: He needed the drivers for it, so he called the tech support for the printer, and then the Secret Service game Win.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you steal something that that's all tech support.
Speaker 0: I think that goes.
Speaker 0: I think that pushes past black shade into epic fail.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right so we've talked every now and then about a lot of really hardcore games like Tigers and Euphrates And Puerto Rico and we're gonna talk about a different kind of game today.
Speaker 0: But we're not gonna talk about these games in general.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about a very specific one.
Speaker 0: the game is apples to apples And it is a card game that is public.
Speaker 0: I don't care who publishes.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter I'll look it up while you're talking.
Speaker 0: It's a game.
Speaker 0: That is so simple and yet so fun.
Speaker 0: I don't care if you've never played a border card game in your life Or if you were the kind of person who has beaten and solved pretty much every board game you've ever played.
Speaker 1: yeah, even someone like Who's the?
Speaker 1: Chess guy who's like a sprawl?
Speaker 1: No no the good the bad one.
Speaker 0: Oh Bobby Fisher.
Speaker 1: Yes, even Bobby Fisher would have fun one.
Speaker 1: even Bobby Fisher would have fun playing apple.
Speaker 0: You know what if you don't have fun playing apples to apples either one you're.
Speaker 1: Even Hitler would have fun.
Speaker 0: There are two of course.
Speaker 1: Hitler would have fun Seriously like even the worst person in the world.
Speaker 0: well know what I'm gonna say have fun.
Speaker 1: There are two possibilities.
Speaker 0: if you are not having fun playing apples apples.
Speaker 0: one you are a shitty person, too.
Speaker 1: You're doing it wrong.
Speaker 0: No two Everyone in the room playing the game is shitty except you.
Speaker 1: uh three you're doing it wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even it's hard to do.
Speaker 1: yeah, okay, so here's the way apples apples works.
Speaker 1: You buy this big box and there's these expansions with different cards.
Speaker 1: You want them all.
Speaker 1: you want as many cards as you can get pretty much.
Speaker 1: There's even a Jewish set and It is hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's green cards, and there's red cards.
Speaker 1: most of them are red cards, but this green cards?
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: everyone on the hand of red car everyone
Speaker 1: has like seven red car, and
Speaker 0: they're all nouns like alabaster or Mahatma Gandhi or global thermonuclear holocaust or fish Fishy-fishy or your mom grandma's house something
Speaker 1: like that right and they're all just nouns or Person places things stuff like that.
Speaker 0: you games Hillary Clinton.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the idea and every card also has a funny little like subtext on it.
Speaker 1: So it'll be like you know like Richard Nixon, and then in the subtext that'll be like I'm not a crook you know something like that, and then the green cards are all descriptive.
Speaker 1: They might not be adjectives per se most of them are but they're usually descriptive in some way like scary Diabolical frightening smelly awesome and instead of a subtext they have synonyms.
Speaker 1: so generally what you do is you draw a green card and The greet you'll say like you know odiferous Something something something smelly and the word is smelly see any bright.
Speaker 1: So the way the game goes is everyone.
Speaker 1: does you got as many people as you can?
Speaker 1: I think the game technically only supports like You have.
Speaker 0: we'll talk about this at the end, but if you have more than like five or six people the game Breaks down unless you play it a little bit differently, but anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think technically it's for four to ten players.
Speaker 1: ten players I think is the Mattie.
Speaker 1: you can play with a lot of people.
Speaker 1: you can get like 15 people to play if you have enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just you have to do a few changes to make it work.
Speaker 1: I think though there that for ten is the best number.
Speaker 1: you know four to ten is good like seven eight people.
Speaker 1: good anyway.
Speaker 1: So everyone has a handful of red cards the nouns.
Speaker 1: one person whose turn it is picks doesn't?
Speaker 1: they're not?
Speaker 1: they put their red cards Face down.
Speaker 1: They're not looking at them.
Speaker 1: They take one green card.
Speaker 1: They read the green card.
Speaker 1: They put it face up, so let's let's play room you ready all right my agree I'm the green card, and you're all the people with the red cards, which is everyone else playing.
Speaker 1: all right the green card says I Don't know Poisonous poisonous all right.
Speaker 0: so now I'll talk as the like collective people.
Speaker 0: we all sit there look at my hand and all right Which of my red cards best exemplifies poisonous?
Speaker 0: And maybe I have.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: the apple from Snow White is just one of my things like all right that fits.
Speaker 0: that was Poisonous.
Speaker 0: I put it down and someone else is looking through and they have arsenic and they're like yeah, that's poison They put it down, and then you go to the third person.
Speaker 0: They're looking and they they see Hillary Clinton, and they're like huh, and they put that down.
Speaker 1: someone else has snake.
Speaker 1: They put that oh snake.
Speaker 0: and the fifth person has Catamite and they're like I don't have whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm just throwing that down.
Speaker 0: and the last person has Puppies and they think I mean they have a bunch of cards.
Speaker 0: They think you know what I'm going for the ironic humor, and they put down puppy or the antonym humor.
Speaker 1: Yes, right.
Speaker 1: so now everyone who besides the person who put down the green card has put down one red Card from their hand right and then they each draw one replacement red card from the decks.
Speaker 1: And you have a lot of fucking cards like thousands of hundreds of cards right now.
Speaker 0: Here is where the game like this is the crux of the game.
Speaker 0: This is what makes it great.
Speaker 0: the game is not.
Speaker 0: there's no rule like the card that best fit wins or whatever.
Speaker 0: Whoever put up the green card draws all these red cards looks through them one by one Says what they are and puts them down, and then they decide which red card fits by whatever criteria They desire.
Speaker 1: oh yeah They don't know whose red card belongs to who because they did them all face down and whose red card belongs to whom right?
Speaker 1: So like right.
Speaker 1: so I can't help rim win by always picking the card.
Speaker 1: you know that.
Speaker 1: I know that rim put down.
Speaker 0: You know bill clinton song or play Bastard game theory and always pick the card of the whoever's losing just to make sure I win.
Speaker 1: yep You can't do that because you don't know which card belongs to which person.
Speaker 1: so You look through all these red cards, and I look at the word poisonous And I pick which one I think is Poisonous, and you know just playing the car first you show all the cards to everyone that everyone played and you laugh a lot.
Speaker 0: It's usually like poisonous.
Speaker 0: Let's see all right puppies.
Speaker 0: Huh, well there was that one puppy blah blah blah arsenic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yep, you got it Clinton.
Speaker 1: yeah, you know it's a lot of these sometimes.
Speaker 1: They're clever sometimes.
Speaker 1: It is so unrelated.
Speaker 1: They're not anything.
Speaker 0: you see what they did there.
Speaker 0: the game is not You know.
Speaker 0: pick the card that fits best or whatever the game is.
Speaker 0: Look at the person who drew this green card and think what could I play to get them to choose it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if you know that I'm playing the green card this turn.
Speaker 1: You know if you play the the puppy.
Speaker 1: if I put the cute card, and you put you know say trilobite.
Speaker 1: You know that's probably gonna win because you know it's me.
Speaker 1: But you put that when rims playing the green card you try to put cute trilobite.
Speaker 1: You might not win against like cute kitty or something you know.
Speaker 0: so it's The.
Speaker 0: this is what's the coolest thing about this game is over time.
Speaker 0: you know with you.
Speaker 0: if they pick your card You get the green card.
Speaker 0: you put it in front of you, and then the game ends.
Speaker 1: when I mean there about it Doesn't matter like you get four depending on the number of players You need like a certain number of green cards in front doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: you just play for a while.
Speaker 0: Then you see who amass the most cards, and it's interesting because whoever amass the most cards is Effectively the person who is most in tune with the zeitgeist of your group of friends or got all the good cards.
Speaker 0: Well see there are ways to mitigate that too.
Speaker 0: It's really just the person who is able on average and in aggregate to Best read all of their friends and play cards from their limited pool that would cause those cards to be chosen.
Speaker 1: yep and Let me tell you hilarity was guaranteed to ensue like it's hard to really Understand like just knowing the rules of the game Why it would be so awesome, but as soon as you play it I mean you might not figure it out right away.
Speaker 1: But I mean anyone like.
Speaker 1: I played this with my family.
Speaker 1: You know I bet I was.
Speaker 1: I went to my family's house in the Rosh Hashanah right and on the way I just bought apples to apples and brought it there right cuz someone had mentioned it and I'm like I'm gonna do it.
Speaker 1: So I got everyone to play it.
Speaker 1: the whole family like usually you know We want to play a game and like only me and my cousins will play.
Speaker 1: you know Everyone was playing like every single person all the aunts and uncles and grandma and my parents and everybody right the whole family.
Speaker 1: and you Know we were just kind of playing having a little fun right.
Speaker 1: and then you know we You know grandma with he was my aunt puts down a green card and the green card was scary.
Speaker 1: Alright, and everyone's trying to figure out which red card in their hand is scary, and I know someone plays Hitler someone plays Gandhi.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, yeah, I guess someone plays Hitler someone plays poison plays like my plays lightning rush limbaugh Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: You know my dad.
Speaker 1: He smiles.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: I got this one, and he puts it down right.
Speaker 1: and Okay, you know.
Speaker 1: and everyone's sitting around and now my aunt's going through the card the red cards one at a time And then she comes out and she's lights like it says grandma's house and my dad played this guy.
Speaker 1: No one knew he played it until you know.
Speaker 1: my aunt said you know grandma's house is the winner and my dad was like That's me tadpoles.
Speaker 1: tadpoles is the winner exactly you know.
Speaker 1: but like even grandma was left You know that that was the moment my family sort of figured out the game like oh, yeah, this game is the business.
Speaker 0: There's no reason for you to not buy this game and all the expansion.
Speaker 1: Everyone should at least have the basic set and whatever.
Speaker 1: you have.
Speaker 0: a whole bunch of people over Bust it out because I mean we're hardcore, and we want to play Tigers and Euphrates and la cheetah.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: pretty much any time someone suggests play apples apples And we actually have apples to apples handy, and we have enough people.
Speaker 1: We'll just have it.
Speaker 1: We have a good opportunity to do it.
Speaker 0: We'll just play it.
Speaker 0: It's such a great social game.
Speaker 0: It's just it's here.
Speaker 1: And you'd think that the game would be sort of boring like after you ran through all the cards.
Speaker 1: well first Of all there's so many expansions.
Speaker 1: You're never gonna run out of cards if you keep buying expansions.
Speaker 1: the second of all even the basic set has so many Freaking cards in it that it's like oh You're never gonna see another one twice and even if you do it'll be in a different context And it could be funny again, or you might have forgotten about it.
Speaker 1: It's like it's so much replay value pretty much forever And the game is like really all ages from like you know zero to a million.
Speaker 1: Everyone in the whole world will enjoy this game.
Speaker 1: You can play in any company with anybody.
Speaker 1: It's just the awesome now.
Speaker 0: I guess we'll fill out the rest of this episode because this is kind of important one.
Speaker 0: There are some variants to the game.
Speaker 0: We'll get into that last.
Speaker 0: but first there are some things you should probably do or encourage or some house rules that will Invariably make the game more fun or prevent the game from dragging right.
Speaker 1: well one problem Is that a lot of people will take.
Speaker 1: some people will take too long and putting out their red card right now usually?
Speaker 1: You know everyone puts one red card per green card.
Speaker 1: That's how it works and just don't worry about don't worry about it.
Speaker 1: But if some if people are taking a long time right then the game can be sort of unfun.
Speaker 1: cuz like.
Speaker 1: imagine It is ten people playing right one person plays the green card seven people play red cards right away, and three people are going in.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: They're having a hard time deciding and everyone's just sitting and waiting for them.
Speaker 1: That's not fun.
Speaker 0: So all you have to do is institute the rule of whoever puts the last red card Their card gets handed right the fuck back to them right?
Speaker 1: so whoever's the slowest at putting out the red card Just doesn't count you.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: How good your red card was you don't even show it to anyone.
Speaker 1: We don't say oh, sorry your last You don't get you don't even get to play a card.
Speaker 0: this turn the key here is don't be a jerk about it.
Speaker 0: if it's Real close like a bunch of people go hey don't try to figure out who was last.
Speaker 0: just take them all.
Speaker 1: yeah Because I mean the point is to prevent the game from slowing down from people dragging.
Speaker 1: if everyone rushes You know and put someone down real fast then the game isn't dragging.
Speaker 1: so there's no reason to enforce this rule.
Speaker 1: It's you don't need it, and you know.
Speaker 1: so just let it go.
Speaker 1: every card counts.
Speaker 0: Yep, now - if someone is the last person and they don't get to play a card It's usually a good idea to let them discard that card and draw a new one.
Speaker 0: anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think aren't you allowed to discard some cards and draw new ones or something like that.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I remember the rules don't matter.
Speaker 1: yeah The rules really don't matter because as long as you know everyone's generally you know being fair about the important things like you know You only award one point per turn and everyone only plays one red card.
Speaker 1: The rest doesn't you know.
Speaker 1: as long as no one's like sifting through the deck to find the perfect card You know it's a play.
Speaker 1: then the game's gonna work out
Speaker 0: now - if you try to play the game for more than an hour Or two it's really gonna start dragging partly because over time you're gonna use your better cards and eventually it's gonna get to the point where pretty much everyone has a handful of unfunny shit.
Speaker 0: yep, and Usually that's about the time.
Speaker 0: you want to stop playing if you want to play longer games Or you feel like that's happening.
Speaker 0: You should just do a alright.
Speaker 0: everyone give in your cards and we're reshuffling.
Speaker 0: or Everyone can discard X cards and draw X new cards and just do that all at once and then just continue Or you just stop playing.
Speaker 1: I think in the instruction manual it does suggest that whoever plays last rule to come into effect when the game's going too slow And it also says like how many cards you know points you need to win in a you know a typical game Depending on how many players there are and if you follow that you know you're generally not gonna play a game.
Speaker 1: That's so long it becomes unfun because if you just keep playing and playing and playing for a long time Which might be hard to resist you will start to the game will start to get sort of old as you play through.
Speaker 1: you know Similar cards, and you know you start to get tired.
Speaker 1: So I recommend playing the game often in Shorter bursts rather than less often and longer verse because that's a way to wear it out now.
Speaker 0: also playing it with strangers is fun But the game is extra fun If you play it with people that you are friends with or at least where many of the people playing know at least a few With the other people playing cuz like when we play The there are some trumps like if I play thermonuclear holocaust It's pretty much guaranteed that Katsu was gonna pick that no matter what the adjective is.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean it could be you know cute happy scary funny Because for him all of those are true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so maybe it could be any doesn't matter what the green card is.
Speaker 1: if rim plays that card You know it's gonna get picked.
Speaker 1: He's gonna get a point.
Speaker 1: It's like you got the card you got a point congratulations and You know a certain group of friends that happens, and it's sort of a good thing and that it's you know like.
Speaker 1: ah yes We all you know join together in our knowing of this thing and you know haha, but in other ways It's kind of like a okay.
Speaker 1: That was a waste of return.
Speaker 0: next yep I mean at the same time I wanted to discourage you because playing it with strangers still works because the game is so Fundamentally enjoyable yep, and the car.
Speaker 1: you'll lose a lot of that in stuff like if I was playing with strangers.
Speaker 1: Grandma's house being scary doesn't work so well, and it works when you got grandma sitting there and her son Who's the father of her grandchildren plays that guy now?
Speaker 0: probably the most important part.
Speaker 0: when you're the one with the green card and you have to read like do the red card thing a Lot of people just sit there and like flip through them all like yeah
Speaker 1: There are different techniques in sort of being the green card person And you know my technique is I read each one and I sit there and I ponder You know and then I'll pick one and you know something something.
Speaker 0: yes I will definitely read each one give some sort of commentary on it and then lay them out in some sort of arbitrary order.
Speaker 0: yep, and Usually my commentary is like Apples.
Speaker 0: what a shitty card.
Speaker 0: yep, whoever played.
Speaker 0: This is a pretty shitty person that that's not even funny.
Speaker 0: What were you thinking?
Speaker 1: and then someone will say I had a crowd, but I had nothing better in my hand.
Speaker 1: I'm just trying to get rid of that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah But you know you just.
Speaker 0: you got no matter what.
Speaker 0: you've got to play it up if you just sit there and read through them yourself.
Speaker 1: or just like apples water buffalo like yeah If you just like look look at all the red cards And then say okay this one wins.
Speaker 1: that sort of ruins the fun you kind of.
Speaker 1: you got a. you got to figure out a technique.
Speaker 1: I mean there are many techniques that are all acceptable But you have to sort of do something you know to sort of liven it up.
Speaker 1: You know in your presentation of the cards to to create the opportunity for their the humor to exist.
Speaker 1: You know I mean the cards do most of the work themselves.
Speaker 1: all you have to do is sort of show them and read them and the rest is done.
Speaker 1: as Long as you know you just have to do a little bit of effort in there And it sort of unlocks the potential of the card, but if you do nothing the card will just sit there like yeah I'm not funny because you didn't do anything with me
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: There's a variant that works very well.
Speaker 0: I mean it can add some meta But the meta only comes into play if your friends are stupid assholes And I don't.
Speaker 0: they had a name for it, but I forget the name.
Speaker 0: But I think our friend Idaho is the one who told us about it where instead of doing it anonymously Everyone picks a red card and Then what they do is the green person sits there like a judge and each person will go around robin and pitch their card.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, you'd be like I'm picking this and this is why I'm.
Speaker 0: this is my red card like scary and Mahatma Gandhi because a blah blah blah blah blah yep.
Speaker 1: And you know the problem with this is of course that I guess people who are better at you know Sort of takes away the game of it becomes more of a game of skill in the skill of you know convincing people.
Speaker 1: You know I could see in that opportunity.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't have people necessarily picking the same person over and over again wanting them to win And you wouldn't really have people picking.
Speaker 1: you know the people who are losing in order to keep the game even so that they could.
Speaker 1: themselves Can win you know.
Speaker 1: but what you'd have is the people are very good at selling.
Speaker 1: You know like if there's a salesman in your group was actually good salesman.
Speaker 1: They might win a lot even though they might not you know have the best cards and stuff.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a different game, but it's still a good game.
Speaker 0: It's very fun to play it that way.
Speaker 0: Just it doesn't work if you have shy people.
Speaker 1: no It doesn't work with shy people at all.
Speaker 1: shy people be like I pick Apple.
Speaker 0: I choose you Snorlax.
Speaker 1: Why did you pick Apple?
Speaker 1: I think it fits.
Speaker 1: oh?
Speaker 0: Stop talking to me.
Speaker 1: Well, they're never gonna get any points But that same person who's all shy right if they're playing apples to apples.
Speaker 1: this is great for shy people because All they have to do is play a card.
Speaker 1: It's not hard.
Speaker 1: even a shy person can play a card.
Speaker 1: so they play often The game.
Speaker 1: someone reads their card, and they laugh and then the person reading the card laughs, then they get a point like yeah the game is just Perfect it is Unflawed.
Speaker 0: it is a fantastic game.
Speaker 0: I cannot stress enough that you should all own it.
Speaker 1: Let's see how much the game costs and then get the hell out of here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I'm kind of hungry like powerful hungry.
Speaker 1: Yep, I'm gonna cook some good stuff.
Speaker 1: Let's see apples to apples on Amazon is currently the party box edition, which is the normal set is $21.99.
Speaker 1: that's So worth it.
Speaker 1: the same gate the same game in a wooden box is $30.
Speaker 1: the kids the kids edition is 13.
Speaker 1: The junior 9 plus.
Speaker 1: second edition is 22. the party box expansion 1 is 20.
Speaker 1: The Bible editions 24. the Jewish versions only 19.
Speaker 1: The customizable blank cards are $5.
Speaker 1: expansion 2 is $20.
Speaker 0: Oh customizable blank cards are great.
Speaker 1: It comes with a few blank cards in the regular set But then it comes with you.
Speaker 1: This is a whole set.
Speaker 0: a nice idea is if you have a like a group of friends that you would end up playing with regularly Or if there is say one or two people in your group of friends that is maligned or beloved or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Either make cards that are just them or make one card for every person in your group of friends or if you know think about The inside jokes you have with a group of friends and make a card for each inside joke.
Speaker 1: Like we could make a joke like one for mind flare or Cthulhu or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we can make another one.
Speaker 1: That's like lift ten blanks Snorlax borlax, you know.
Speaker 1: and if those cards show up It's like all the hands borlax.
Speaker 1: and you know in some ways those cards sort of tweak the game a bit and that if anyone Plays them they'll probably get a point.
Speaker 0: but at the same time you're not playing to win you're playing cuz the game is freaking hilarious Exactly exactly, but it's a game.
Speaker 1: It's a subjective game.
Speaker 1: You can't really brag if you win.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like I wanted a completely subjective game.
Speaker 0: You can in one sense and that if you win does normal rules game of apples to apples Consistently in a group of people.
Speaker 0: that means that you on average have a better Understanding of the thought processes of the of your friends in the group than everyone else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very important.
Speaker 0: That is an argument you could make to some extent but remember on average and in aggregate That is not.
Speaker 1: it's not like you have some sort of power It's not like it's gonna unless I guess if you won apples to apples with like straight sets just perfectly Many many times in a row playing with the same people You'd have to win me.
Speaker 1: if you won like 15 times in a row Reshuffling the cards every time new cards every time with the same people in straight sets Then I think you might have an argument that you just can read their mind.
Speaker 0: in that case I think your friends are not actually friends, but are merely thralls perhaps.
Speaker 0: Yes This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.