Speaker 0: Warning!
Speaker 0: What you are about to hear is not a normal episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: In fact, it is probably as far from a normal episode of Geek Nights as you'll ever hear.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess we could just go "pfft" and that would be it.
Speaker 1: And that would be as far from an episode of normal Geek Nights as you would hear.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess there was the last year on the Thursday before Otacon the show we put up.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, we have to make a show for that Thursday.
Speaker 0: No we don't, I'm thinking we shouldn't do anything.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: We're talking in the wrong tense because that already happened.
Speaker 1: It did already happen, yes.
Speaker 1: This is Tuesday, July... 24th today.
Speaker 0: Wow, it's a week from now.
Speaker 0: We're in the future podcasting back to you.
Speaker 0: That's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: Actually, no, we're in the past podcasting to you in the future.
Speaker 1: Even better.
Speaker 0: And then in the future, I guess we're... You know what?
Speaker 0: It's complicated.
Speaker 0: There's a paradox there.
Speaker 0: Suffice to say, if you are a new listener, and I know a lot of you are, from all the things we did at Otacon, all the things we did at Kineticon, this is not a normal episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: This is what's called the Geek Nights Special.
Speaker 0: Special is a code word for Raymond Scott or out of town, dead, or too lazy to do a real show.
Speaker 1: I guess we could be dead, but yeah.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about that on Thursday.
Speaker 0: You should...
Speaker 1: You should listen to a normal episode of Geek Nights before you judge whether you want to listen to our show or not.
Speaker 1: I don't care if you listen or not, but just don't judge us by this throwaway episode effectively.
Speaker 0: I care a little bit.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of Mega Love maniacal.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I like people to listen to my voice.
Speaker 1: I like people to listen, but you know, I just don't want them to judge based on the wrong thing.
Speaker 0: That is definitely true, because I'll tell the story, I think, also on Thursday about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, today we're just going to talk for a few minutes about a random video game.
Speaker 1: Rym picked the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Basically, we kept saying games until one of us picked a game that we both agreed on.
Speaker 0: And the idea was, it's not a game that we could review.
Speaker 0: We could do a whole show on it.
Speaker 0: And at the same time, it bears talking about, and we needed something.
Speaker 0: So, we're going to do a Geek Nights Flash.
Speaker 0: It's like under a special, even.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we're going to review Burger Time for the Intellivision and the Nintendo and a million other systems.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, Burger Time is about this cook.
Speaker 1: And the cook, I guess he wants to make burgers.
Speaker 0: This cook, the chef, lives in a world of giants.
Speaker 0: So, he has to make giant burgers for giants to eat, but he's tiny and wears a French chef hat.
Speaker 1: And he's being attacked by evil things, evil food ingredients.
Speaker 0: The pickles and the French fries and that egg.
Speaker 0: That fucking egg.
Speaker 0: I hate that egg so much.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And his only weapon is salt.
Speaker 0: Or pepper, depending on the version of the game.
Speaker 1: But salt pretty much ruins all the bad guys.
Speaker 1: He just shakes that salt on them and they dry right up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, for like 10 seconds and then they're fine again.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, there's water everywhere from the moist, steamy burgers.
Speaker 0: I just got to say, in terms of old games like that, this is one of the few games that really stood out as being awesome, even back then.
Speaker 1: It was, you know, I think what it was is back then, so many games were just unplayable.
Speaker 1: And this is a playable game that worked.
Speaker 1: So, it already was like way above everything else.
Speaker 1: And not only that, but in addition to being playable and working, it was fun.
Speaker 1: Until Donkey Kong, you know, this was pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Plus, I remember as a kid, and this got interesting, that I never owned an Intellivision or an Intellivision 2.
Speaker 0: But my grandma on my mom's side did.
Speaker 0: And I'd always be excited when I went to her house, because she had the Intellivision.
Speaker 0: I only had the Atari.
Speaker 0: And the Intellivision, whether you guys liked it or not, a lot of people haven't played it.
Speaker 0: Or they tried to play that GameCube crap version that just doesn't work at all, that I paid $1.99 for.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The actual Intellivision worked really well.
Speaker 1: It worked okay.
Speaker 0: It worked really well.
Speaker 0: Have you ever used one?
Speaker 1: Yeah, a couple times.
Speaker 0: What, an Intellivision or an Intellivision 2?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Alright, well, I'll review the Intellivision someday.
Speaker 0: But suffice to say, my grandma was real freakin' good at BurgerTime.
Speaker 0: She was better than me for as long as I played against her.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: And basically, you'd walk along the burgers, and you could track the guys in the burgers.
Speaker 0: And there was rudimentary AI as the things would try to chase you around.
Speaker 0: And it always felt like the egg was smarter than everyone else.
Speaker 0: The egg was always the one who headed me off at the pass.
Speaker 1: I think it just happened to be.
Speaker 1: the placement of the egg was always in the annoying spot.
Speaker 1: You know, the other guys were off to the side, or you could take some ladders and go around them and still get your burger together.
Speaker 1: But the egg was always right there, like on the burger, or right in your way.
Speaker 1: There was no other way to go, and that's why the egg sucked.
Speaker 0: The other thing I just really remember about it was there was this kind of this exploration aspect.
Speaker 0: Because as you got further into the game, different ingredients would start appearing.
Speaker 0: And I'd always be like, "Whoa!
Speaker 0: Check that thing out!
Speaker 0: I'd never seen that
Speaker 0: before.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, what the hell is that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, 'cause there's only so many things to put on a burger.
Speaker 1: You don't know, it might be a bad guy, it might be a new power-up.
Speaker 1: You know, of course there weren't any new power-ups.
Speaker 0: No, they were all just ingredients.
Speaker 0: It was pretty obvious what they were.
Speaker 1: I know, but you know, sometimes you never know.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I could- Especially in the- I mean, in some of the versions where the graphics are better, there was no question what they were.
Speaker 1: But in some of the worst graphic versions, if you hadn't played a better version, you know, so you see something new, you might not know what it is.
Speaker 0: Well, pretty much it was like, "Alright, that's obviously the bun, 'cause it's on the
Speaker 0: bottom.".
Speaker 1: The bun is always obvious.
Speaker 0: But there's the red thing and the green thing, and then the brown thing, and then there's the whitish thing, and you don't know what that is, maybe it's an onion, but they're all just squares.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Or rectangles.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you step on them and they fall down and they land on the burger, and eventually you put the top on that baby and you get some points.
Speaker 0: And I think that's the end of that, because frankly, at this moment, we are probably either watching a movie or playing a game in a beach house in Wildwood.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're a punk kid and you've never played BurgerTime, or if you're an old person who remembers BurgerTime, you haven't played it in a while, just go play some BurgerTime, 'cause it's still okay.
Speaker 1: And eat a burger.