Speaker 1: It's Thursday June 21st.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: spoilers Let's do this Man today.
Speaker 1: I was looking at the Dell website a new egg, and I'm getting real close to just buying a gigantic monitor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you kind of need one.
Speaker 0: you had that shitty 19-inch CRT is great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it sucks.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 0: And yeah many years.
Speaker 1: the only reason I'm really getting rid of it is that I can't have it and my microphone.
Speaker 0: It still sucks.
Speaker 0: It's fine, and oh if it's so fine Why aren't you using it right now?
Speaker 1: like I just said I can't have it and my microphone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it in your microphone for a long time before yeah And you know what it totally sucked.
Speaker 1: cuz I had to keep the microphone like several feet away from it or else I got that honey.
Speaker 0: Well that crappy crappy crappy LCD using right now.
Speaker 1: Oh god This thing is is not the business.
Speaker 0: It's still better than that 19-inch CRT that you not really.
Speaker 1: yeah I really I'd prefer the CRT right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, your eyes are broken.
Speaker 0: What do you know?
Speaker 1: well plus once?
Speaker 1: I realized that according to the stress test I can get a couple thousand frames per second in half-life 2 with everything turned up.
Speaker 1: so uh I Think I'm gonna go with the gigantic high-resolution widescreen monitor.
Speaker 0: the thing that I've noticed though Especially with my 22 inch at work is that most of the monitors that are over 20 inches It's kind of stupid to get them because what happens is you know you have a height.
Speaker 0: They do have a higher resolution.
Speaker 0: like the 20 inch can go to like 1600 by 1200 right and the 22 inch can go 1680 by 1050 80 pixels over 2 inches.
Speaker 0: I mean it's not it's 2 inches diagonally But that's the pixels on the 22 inch monitor or bigger.
Speaker 0: thus the image is lower quality Like if you look at the monitor on my laptop.
Speaker 0: It's a 10.6 inch screen, but it's 1280 by 768.
Speaker 1: It's not that it's lower quality It's that the viewing radius of how far away you can be and still see a good picture is increased I guess.
Speaker 0: but do I really that logic?
Speaker 1: Why do you ever have a TV?
Speaker 1: That's what if you had a one inch by one inch screen?
Speaker 1: There was like a million by a million pixels.
Speaker 1: That's not good.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: No, but the the point is how a monitor.
Speaker 0: you're sitting pretty close to it so bigger.
Speaker 0: close I'm pretty close.
Speaker 1: I'm probably gonna go with a 22 inch widescreen with the 1680 by whatever resolution And I have it at work and the pixels are too big.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I've used them at work too, and they don't doesn't bother me at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah I definitely have seen the 20 inches and with the same or slightly lower resolution the image quality is far sharper and far superior.
Speaker 1: To me the image quality is the same partly because I sit slightly further away from my monitor than you do.
Speaker 0: I Just put the monitor on the desk, and then I sit at depending on where the desk is not where the monitor is.
Speaker 0: hmm Yeah, I also don't really have a need to be that far away from my monitor.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm not going across the room to watch a video or something.
Speaker 0: That's.
Speaker 0: that's why TVs should be big because you sit across the room.
Speaker 0: But then again TVs also need some high resolution or else you get the syndrome like where we have the Mac plugged into our TV You can't read the text of them making it huge because there's not enough pixels to render the fonts properly.
Speaker 1: I'd argue more vehemently, but I'm eating some habanero cheddar cheese, and it's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway What kind of news actions going on?
Speaker 1: Oh?
Speaker 1: I thought you're gonna tell everyone we're going to mocha one last chance.
Speaker 0: Oh right right.
Speaker 0: so tomorrow this way.
Speaker 1: I could eat more cheese not tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Saturday Saturday June 23rd 2007 we are going to go to the Museum of comic and cartoon art arts Festival and that is not a redundant.
Speaker 0: art like I said yesterday is an arts festival at the Museum of comic and cartoon art And it's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: You know we always kind of rag on comic conventions because they're full of nerds buying you know super ultra old Crappy Silver Age books for like $50 like those two guys Interviewed at the Philly wizard world and they were.
Speaker 1: I was like what kind of comics you like?
Speaker 1: and the one guy said oh I only read Silver Age, whatever.
Speaker 1: and the other guys like yes, there's nothing else worth reading.
Speaker 0: Yeah So we don't like those kind of places because a lot of plus the the attitude of collecting as opposed to Enjoying art is not so About that.
Speaker 1: listen to last night's episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the mocha everything is totally turned upside down.
Speaker 0: first of all it is much more heavily populated with the indie comics than the superhero underwear perfect comics.
Speaker 0: and second of all It's it's like just like a big artists alley you go up to a table And if there's a comic there whoever makes that comic is sitting at that table like 99% of the time.
Speaker 0: you know you're not like going up to a Dealers room where someone some retailer you don't want to talk to is selling the comic that you want.
Speaker 0: it's just an artist alley pretty much and Everyone there is sort of on an even playing field.
Speaker 0: you've got big-name people or relatively big-name people You know who like what Eisner awards and have so published their comics widely around the world in many languages sold thousands and thousands of copies and right next to them is some punk kid who Xeroxed his frickin Comic at Kinko's this morning, and he's stapling it together as you're standing there, and he's like hey, how you doing?
Speaker 0: Read my comic.
Speaker 1: I'm sure our regular listeners wanted to hear you say exactly what you said yesterday.
Speaker 1: all over again.
Speaker 0: That's fine because there are some people who didn't listen today And there's not much else to say about the convention other than if you like comics And you are anywhere within striking distance of New York City you have no reason not to go on Saturday unless you're doing something Saturday, man
Speaker 1: I recently remembered when I picked up that prison comics last year And I just remembered how funny that thing was
Speaker 0: that that was a great comic And we will get many more like it and then talk about.
Speaker 1: you know what I like more than killing, but nothing stab.
Speaker 1: So in the news this is kind of big news partly because of the hilarity just provided us for up the Pirate Bay That upstanding bastion of freedom on the internet.
Speaker 1: They have decided that they're going to law well going to launch.
Speaker 1: They already did launch a new site called Bay IMG Bay image And what it is according to them is a censorship free image hosting website where anyone in the world can anonymously?
Speaker 1: Upload any image and tag it and it'll be there forever.
Speaker 0: See this is really awesome But it's also really bad.
Speaker 0: the reason it's awesome is because all those people who want to like put their avatar in a forum.
Speaker 0: Or they want to link to an image But they don't want a hot link to someone else's server or they do hot link to someone else's server, and they get some bad image or They use stupid image shack, and then they go over the bandwidth limit.
Speaker 0: all this stupid shit is now over with.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's really the intent of this.
Speaker 0: I know, but that it does solve that problem.
Speaker 1: Regardless I doubt it does.
Speaker 1: I'll bet there will be some sort of hot linking prevention in the future to keep the bandwidth from exploding.
Speaker 0: Then what's the point?
Speaker 1: the point is to upload things that aren't censored that whatever you put up There is gonna stay up there, so if you put up a picture of Muhammad and sure enough There's a tag Muhammad, and it is nothing but derogatory pictures of Muhammad
Speaker 0: Well, I think the problem with that is that of course it's all gonna be nasty nasty prong that no one wants to see Except the people putting it there.
Speaker 1: well the thing is I looked at it, and I decided all right I'm flipping through the slash comments and someone links to it and what they link to is the Digimon tag.
Speaker 1: now the Digimon tag.
Speaker 1: This is.
Speaker 1: these are the first images I saw on This Pirate Bay thing.
Speaker 1: it was nothing, but Digimon pornography.
Speaker 1: in fact It was all Digimon pornography of one specific animal from Digimon.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean one specific Digimon one specific Digimon.
Speaker 0: ah I went to the Pokemons, and there was like a Pidgeo doing something, and it wasn't pretty well.
Speaker 1: So of course I immediately noticed the lolcat tag, and I've realized that I I love lolcats And sometimes I forget how much I love lolcats.
Speaker 0: Lolcats are awesome with their Monorails.
Speaker 1: the thing is I like the idea of a repository in the world.
Speaker 1: you can anonymously put pictures or Information or anything out there for the whole world to see with no possible chance of anyone getting back to you anyone punishing you.
Speaker 1: This could be a great thing for oppressed people like people in China or Albion.
Speaker 0: People in China are gonna be able to get to this site.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you yeah, but still I like the idea of it.
Speaker 1: The problem is it's already full of spam and porn and I'll bet within a few more weeks The child porn that is going to be attempted to be uploaded by it will in and of itself bandwidth wise bring it down
Speaker 0: most likely, but I think that what they should have done is they as Being an uncensored image thing is kind of while I admire that and a sort of agree that it needs to exist It's gonna be really difficult to filter out bad images.
Speaker 0: It's not like filtering out bad text which you can actually do programmatically like someone in order to filter out bad images Like child porn and any other illegal images because I think what they say that anything illegal in Sweden would be taken off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not a free-for-all.
Speaker 1: I found this kind of funny.
Speaker 1: They said oh, this is gonna be an uncensored repository of images, but don't upload anything That's illegal in Sweden.
Speaker 1: are we gonna take it down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they gotta have some freaking army of people looking at stuff and taking it.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be easy but I think they should have just tried to solve the image shack problem because that's a problem that is still plaguing the internet and No one solved.
Speaker 0: I mean we they jump straight to the YouTube solving the problem for videos and Libs didn't solve the problem for audios, I guess but no one remembered to solve the problem for images.
Speaker 1: You realize that in terms of avatars linking to images.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of solutions.
Speaker 1: Most of them work really well and people who don't most of them kind of suck.
Speaker 1: people like oh Frickin bandwidth limits and they only suck because people try to use them for things They were not intended for.
Speaker 1: if you want to host I mean there are ways to host images that cost trivial amounts of money.
Speaker 0: See what it needs to be free.
Speaker 1: YouTube is free And if the way to host images is not free But Scott there's money in YouTube because there are ways to generate advertising revenue from something like YouTube.
Speaker 1: There's no way to generate advertising revenue from a site that serves nothing but hotlinked images.
Speaker 0: Does the bay image seem to be making money from advertising revenue?
Speaker 0: hell no So they don't.
Speaker 1: they're not gonna allow hot linking.
Speaker 1: if they do all right now I'm certain they're gonna stop that right quick.
Speaker 1: The reason YouTube works is that?
Speaker 1: Wally can show you the thing.
Speaker 1: it can also show you the related things or the ads and you want to go to YouTube.
Speaker 1: people Go to YouTube.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna go to a site that hosts a million twelve-year-old.
Speaker 1: to put the reason you.
Speaker 0: the reason YouTube got so big is Because people can embed the youtubes in their own page.
Speaker 1: yes But still with the link back to YouTube and people have a reason to go to YouTube.
Speaker 1: No one would ever go to a site that hosted people's avatars.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to.
Speaker 1: it's nothing but stupid avatars.
Speaker 1: There's no way to make money off of that ever.
Speaker 0: It's not about making money that the Pirate Bay.
Speaker 0: were they making money on the Pirate Bay?
Speaker 1: because if they don't allow hot linking this Thing will be okay.
Speaker 1: they could.
Speaker 0: they couldn't afford I don't think to see that without the Hot-linking and you know using it as an image host for images to post elsewhere on the internet.
Speaker 0: I have no use for this site.
Speaker 0: I can just go to Google Images to find an image if I want one.
Speaker 1: this is so you can go and browse around it.
Speaker 1: Besides I think this is in the end kind of a dumb idea, and it's gonna fail just for technical limitations.
Speaker 1: But there's no reason to give free good hot linkable image hosting on the internet because there's nobody needs that.
Speaker 1: But there's no way you can make money.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna do it.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: there's no good reason to make a Pirate Bay torrent tracker.
Speaker 0: There's no way to make money.
Speaker 1: Oh because the Pirate Bay torrent tracker Generates far less bandwidth than an image hosting site would in the end.
Speaker 0: well It's regardless.
Speaker 0: I think that while this is cool to look at maybe once if it's not useful as a place to host Images to use elsewhere on the internet which rim seems to say it isn't because it shouldn't be.
Speaker 1: that's not the purpose.
Speaker 1: They very clearly the purpose was to have an uncensored place where people can upload images.
Speaker 1: well Have them up there.
Speaker 0: I think that's interesting and I applaud them, but I have no use for it, and I really don't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I didn't say it had a use.
Speaker 1: it failed already.
Speaker 1: But your idea is completely contrary to what anyone cares about with this I think.
Speaker 0: but I think that's what would make it successful because if it was what I say it should be successful.
Speaker 1: How they couldn't afford that no one can.
Speaker 0: I don't see why they couldn't.
Speaker 0: they seem to be able to affording the Pirate Bay.
Speaker 1: the Pirate Bay is probably less bandwidth, and if you tried to host all the FARC images that get up there Or someone's forum avatar that gets seen a billion times Uh-huh, whatever.
Speaker 0: We'll see in the end.
Speaker 0: Meh, I'm not gonna go here really if the if it's not you.
Speaker 1: I went there once and I saw Pokemon porn and Digimon porn And it was somewhat inescapable.
Speaker 1: in seeing that I I'm not gonna go back because I can go to a site like FARC to see locads.
Speaker 0: Well, I just tested it and hot linking totally works, so now this site is useful.
Speaker 1: I doubt is gonna stay that way.
Speaker 1: That's just my guess.
Speaker 0: well I think that that is how it's gonna stay.
Speaker 0: because what's the point of image hosting if it says image?
Speaker 0: Hosting if it's just an image gallery on their site?
Speaker 0: That's not the same as image hosting.
Speaker 0: you see what I'm saying hosting is when you host my image And I use it elsewhere.
Speaker 0: So I have a feeling that it is gonna be hot linking and now image shack and all those people better run for cover because They're screwed.
Speaker 1: because they made a big point about saying that it's uncensored and it's all tagged Both because I don't see that.
Speaker 1: I just don't see it sticking around.
Speaker 1: I don't see it being Available or able to deal with the bandwidth over time.
Speaker 0: if they're able to deal with the Pirate Bay I think they can deal with some images.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: they was they wouldn't do it, and they there goes.
Speaker 0: those guys know technology.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't do it and allow the hot linking.
Speaker 1: Scott you realize they also allow image files up to a hundred megabytes.
Speaker 1: We'll see how long this lasts.
Speaker 0: I guess we will see how long it lasts that that a hundred megabyte image file that got Plus.
Speaker 0: it'll be popular and FARC would screw them over.
Speaker 1: plus the fact that you know they say it's uncensored.
Speaker 1: But that's absolutely not true according to the other things.
Speaker 1: They said I just really don't trust this to be useful at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah So basically my prediction if it doesn't work as a thing that beats out image shack and equivalents No one will care about it for very long And if it does then it will just replace all those things and but very few people actually go to the site.
Speaker 0: because What do you want?
Speaker 0: to just browse random images for this Google image search?
Speaker 1: I point out that 4chan is extremely popular, and it's nothing but variously pornographic images and people browsing them and comment.
Speaker 0: Yes, but it comes up in sort of like this time-based way as opposed to this just tag cloud.
Speaker 1: That's a big mess, but for those people the tag clouds even better.
Speaker 1: They click on lolcat.
Speaker 1: They see their lolcat.
Speaker 1: They click on Digimon.
Speaker 1: they see their Digimon form the Digimon form.
Speaker 1: they might they might have trouble hosting elsewhere, but they can't Comment on it, so I don't think anything that's ever been posted to.
Speaker 0: 4chan actually counts as a comment But it gets replied to with another image.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time.
Speaker 1: They're almost entirely unrelated.
Speaker 0: I think what's gonna happen is all the images that you see on 4chan will be hosted on the bay image and linked into the 4chan In which case it just becomes 4chan without the comments, which I don't know.
Speaker 1: what that is.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is either, but well I guess it also has a different community than 4chan.
Speaker 0: it has the entire Internets as opposed to the 4chan internets.
Speaker 1: one thing that got me I was surprised that I saw the wet like the link on slash down, and it wasn't.
Speaker 1: oh, they're gonna do this It's oh, it's already up.
Speaker 0: Yeah that really got me.
Speaker 0: It was like.
Speaker 0: Oh, they couldn't do it.
Speaker 0: Oh it exists there It is.
Speaker 1: yeah, I just I don't think it's gonna last.
Speaker 1: I think something bad is gonna happen to it.
Speaker 1: I do
Speaker 0: think Steve Jobs got it right though, and you know he decided to start announcing Apple products Like right before they came out and announcing the iPhone way before it came out was a bad move But I guess he had to because he needed the FCC approval and all that jazz
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: What could have been interesting is if they just put the FCC thing in and Just refuse to say anything at all about the iPhone.
Speaker 1: despite that That would be okay I guess cuz then basically without doing anything there would have been a Constant on not underground, but internet PR machine just working itself into a frenzy Waiting for him to acknowledge their their PR machine seems to be working just fine.
Speaker 1: anyway iPhone's gonna do just fine despite the fact that I think it's kind of silly.
Speaker 0: Regardless if I was a company of any sort I would announce things as They were ready and not before.
Speaker 0: cuz I've learned that mistake already.
Speaker 0: like a couple times the geek nights like yeah We're gonna have a DVD.
Speaker 0: Yeah From now on I'm only going to announce things if I'm holding if I'm ready to just push the button and make them go And that's the way it's gonna be right.
Speaker 1: so what do you got for me in the news on this lazy Thursday?
Speaker 1: Where I really want to continue playing Counter-Strike source.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well.
Speaker 0: I've always said you know stuff about.
Speaker 0: So you know the soldiers in Iraq.
Speaker 0: if they disagree with the Iraq war what should they do?
Speaker 0: bla bla bla right?
Speaker 0: Well one guy in the army somewhere Now they even get a fig.
Speaker 0: I can not even bother reading his name here.
Speaker 0: basically he said Yeah, he went to his superior officer, and he said yeah I'm against the war and I'm no longer gonna play a combat role, and I'm no longer gonna protect corporate representatives.
Speaker 0: Whatever he means by that all right.
Speaker 1: I hate to say it, but this guy already sounds a little bit nutty.
Speaker 0: That's not a little bit nutty.
Speaker 0: But while I'm sort of on his side like yeah, I don't want to fight in that war either.
Speaker 0: You know I can.
Speaker 0: I can see where you're coming from.
Speaker 0: you already Volunteered before.
Speaker 0: you can't be forced into the US Army, so You changed your mind Kind of can't do that.
Speaker 1: I want to join the army and go to college.
Speaker 1: You know if there's a war you got a fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever there won't be a war and then there is.
Speaker 0: I didn't agree to This.
Speaker 0: yes, you did Tough shit.
Speaker 1: I'm generally of the mind that outside of extreme cases like if Genocide is about to occur or you're ordered to do something that is clearly Immoral and illegal like a boo grieve type stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah in any other situation.
Speaker 1: I really don't think that members of the military of a sovereign nation should take it upon themselves to voice political or social opinion or Refuse officer are refused legal orders.
Speaker 0: Yes, they.
Speaker 0: so
Speaker 1: while at that point That's what happened to Rome when the military starts becoming politicized, and I think one of the Biggest things that has made America not collapse over the last several hundred years well two or three hundred years give or take is That the military is by and large just done whatever it's been ordered even if what it was ordered to do Maybe say in the case of Iraq was stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so as much as I'm against the Iraq war and I gotta feel bad for someone fighting it who doesn't want to be This guy's going to the military jail most likely and that's where he belongs and the court-martial Is in his future.
Speaker 1: I can't say that I have that much sympathy for him sadly.
Speaker 0: No, but at the same time People are basically saying, you know, he's taking an incredible risk blah blah blah, but other people get it already.
Speaker 1: He's not new.
Speaker 1: a lot of people have done this since the Iraq war started.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: they're like, oh no He's gonna be court-martialed.
Speaker 0: and then all they say is let's make sure that they don't do anything illegal against him.
Speaker 0: You know make sure they only give him what he deserves according to the military law and they don't you know secretly Kill him or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're gonna secretly kill him.
Speaker 1: They'd get away with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure.
Speaker 0: Well, they gotten away with a lot of other stuff, but they haven't.
Speaker 1: we all know what's going on in that prison.
Speaker 0: Oh See ya, I just thought it was interesting that you know people don't really notice when this happens so much.
Speaker 0: and well here it happens.
Speaker 0: some guy in the military said I don't want to fight me more and What happens to you?
Speaker 0: go to jail?
Speaker 0: You can't do that.
Speaker 1: things of the day.
Speaker 0: I got a thing of the day here and I don't before I tell you what it is.
Speaker 0: Let's let's do some drama acting here.
Speaker 1: All right This is a lot like Dave and Joel a little bit a little bit a little bit cuz.
Speaker 1: they haven't done that lately.
Speaker 0: All right, so you begin praise Jesus.
Speaker 1: you won't be saved without Jesus.
Speaker 1: you have to start believing in Jesus to be saved.
Speaker 0: Jesus will always be there for you.
Speaker 0: Would it would it be so awful if we pushed her out when the doors open?
Speaker 1: no, Jesus will save her The next one.
Speaker 0: I think so, all right Paper beats rock BAM.
Speaker 0: Your rock is blowed up.
Speaker 1: BAM doesn't blow up.
Speaker 1: BAM makes it spicy.
Speaker 1: now I got a spicy rock.
Speaker 1: You can't defeat that.
Speaker 0: So what this?
Speaker 0: where these are from is?
Speaker 0: there's a website called overheard in New York.
Speaker 0: calm and Basically what people do is they write there.
Speaker 0: they write down things that they supposedly overheard people saying in New York.
Speaker 0: So if you're sitting in a restaurant and someone near you has a funny conversation that you happen to overhear You type it into this website and there it is.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure not all of these are true But regardless of that, I'm sure some of them are.
Speaker 0: in fact, probably the majority are and this page I'm linking to you has the most popular ones.
Speaker 0: and If you like the two things we just acted out.
Speaker 0: that's the sort of stuff that's on this page.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like a real-life New York City bash.org.
Speaker 0: I was just gonna say it's like a bash.org IRL, dude I hit that so hard.
Speaker 1: Whoever could pull me out would become the king of England.
Speaker 0: That's my favorite line from the whole page.
Speaker 0: Man I would totally hit that dude.
Speaker 0: I would hit that so hard that you would be the king of England if you pulled me out.
Speaker 1: move nigga I'll cut you with my knife.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: He said the n-word knife *laughter* Supposedly on the Queen's Mount F train.
Speaker 0: The best one.
Speaker 0: Mother.
Speaker 0: The mother says Don't you ever do that again and then slaps the kid.
Speaker 0: and then the kid calmly says well, are you happy with yourself?
Speaker 0: That happened in Union Square Supposedly and oh the title is the Buddha was a tough kid to raise.
Speaker 0: *laughter*.
Speaker 1: That's the win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you want some I don't know good 10-20 minutes of humor depending on how fast you read and how long you laugh.
Speaker 0: Check this page out.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day is all over dig and it's in the forum and I think it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I just want to link to it because when I actually got around to watching it I really liked the little song and dance in the middle.
Speaker 0: I did also like the song and dance and it was like one part of me was like I like that song and I like that dance but damn that's horrible.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think the word we're looking for is macabre Perhaps perhaps.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it really counts as macabre.
Speaker 1: I think it's pretty macabre all things considered.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's definitely It's really a macabre.
Speaker 0: Let's go look up what macabre actually means while you describe this video.
Speaker 1: All right Well, I don't want to spoil it because you'll figure out what's going on pretty handily, but it's an awesome awesome Incredibly, okay.
Speaker 0: Um, okay just to show that how rim correct how correct you are The I'm gonna read the three definitions of macabre.
Speaker 0: Are you ready?
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 0: number one gruesome and horrifying Ghastly horrible.
Speaker 0: All right, it is those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah - of Pertaining to dealing with or representing death, especially is grimmer or uglier aspect.
Speaker 0: I know you ready for number three.
Speaker 0: I'm ready of or suggesting I can't of or suggestive of the allegorical dance of death.
Speaker 0: And that is exactly what this video is.
Speaker 0: it is macabre definition.
Speaker 0: number three Suggestive of the allegorical dance of death.
Speaker 1: now I defy you Despite I mean this doesn't say a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean the I guess the moral of this.
Speaker 1: Well defense of what kind of person you are because you might think the moral is damn dead.
Speaker 1: people dancing is awesome.
Speaker 0: No, that's not what the moral is.
Speaker 1: Or maybe the moral is you know what it's worth any sacrifice for art?
Speaker 0: No, that's not.
Speaker 0: what the more not just watch it.
Speaker 1: I really like it.
Speaker 1: The animation is amazing Yeah and I defy you to watch it and not at least You'll be bobbing your head and kind of dancing with a guy or at least half in your foot I guarantee it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: the message though.
Speaker 0: Is that You you know You don't these people they send people off to war as if they're trying to create a work of art with people's lives And that's that's probably not good.
Speaker 0: and that's not good something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So without further ado she was actually a man Rims gay.
Speaker 0: That's not a spoiler It's not the point Charlie wins the chocolate factory at the end of this episode.
Speaker 0: We played the same closer.
Speaker 0: We plan every episode.
Speaker 1: James Bond gets the girl in the end.
Speaker 0: Sometimes he doesn't.
Speaker 1: I think he almost always does.
Speaker 1: Oh depends.
Speaker 0: All right, not in the end.
Speaker 1: How about just James Bond gets the girl at some point at some point?
Speaker 1: He gets the girl like ten times private Ryan.
Speaker 1: He uh, he makes it to the end.
Speaker 0: Oh, does he?
Speaker 1: It wasn't worth saying okay.
Speaker 0: Well, I thought it was about saving private Ryan, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they win.
Speaker 0: Oh it but isn't like a guy they're going to find and then save.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they find him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay I thought he was one of those things that look for a guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, not really there.
Speaker 1: Jesus gets whipped the shit out of but then he comes back.
Speaker 0: We know that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah So a lot of people especially certainly greatest people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Rosebud was a slide.
Speaker 1: They find Nemo.
Speaker 0: they shoot old yeller All right, okay His father oh shit.
Speaker 0: So a lot of people.
Speaker 1: they especially in the model at O'Hare is a bitch.
Speaker 0: in the modern times of the Internet's Spoilers have become more and more of an issue and a lot of people have different opinions on to how Spoilers should be dealt with.
Speaker 0: a lot of people say, you know, ah, you know There's a satchel limitations on these things.
Speaker 0: if it's older than like a few years and you didn't see it already tough shit.
Speaker 0: and other People say oh, you should never spoil anything for everybody you ass.
Speaker 0: and other people say and who cares?
Speaker 0: It's your own damn fault.
Speaker 0: You should have been listening.
Speaker 1: Whatever I really have mixed feelings about it because on one hand it would Sudden me greatly if someone who had not seen cowboy bebop had the end ruin for them before they saw it.
Speaker 1: Like that would bother me and it really bothers me when people spoil.
Speaker 1: things like that are in my presence Not just anime, but anything like that.
Speaker 1: But at the same time when those people were running around all over the internet spoiling the Harry Potter book before it came out That was awesome.
Speaker 1: I couldn't help but laugh hysterically every time I ran into someone in counter-strike named OMG Snape or Dumbledore dies.
Speaker 0: Is that what is that?
Speaker 1: or Snape kills Dumbledore?
Speaker 0: That's what it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah I remember on that day someone was playing counter-strike with that name.
Speaker 1: Remember very specifically, you know what multiple people were playing with that name that day?
Speaker 1: I think there were servers.
Speaker 0: people are making user new accounts on sites like slash dot and Fark with that is the username It was.
Speaker 1: and while it might have been just as horrible as a spoiler for some reason.
Speaker 1: I found it hilarious Maybe because I don't care about Harry Potter maybe or maybe because people took it so seriously.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think generally the but my personal spoiler policy, right?
Speaker 0: Is that I'm not gonna go spoiling something on purpose?
Speaker 0: because what what's the point?
Speaker 0: Well, except for all the things we just spoiled Well, I mean, you know something You know that at like actively like.
Speaker 0: I know you haven't seen this and I'm gonna get you the odds.
Speaker 1: are we spoiled something for?
Speaker 1: Someone just now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean there's some stuff where it's like everyone knows like I Knew that Darth Vader was his father without even having seen Empire Strikes Back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even remember anyone, dude I don't even remember a point at which it was spoiled.
Speaker 0: It's just like I always knew like I always knew my name was Scott.
Speaker 1: Well, I do remember the wonderful story Greg told us back in the day about how they came out of the.
Speaker 1: it was that I think was the second episode of Star Wars like the new episodes yeah, and they're walking out and there's the line of people going in to see the second showing like the one right after the midnight showing and He just says kind of loudly man.
Speaker 1: I can't believe they killed Yoda.
Speaker 1: That was crap.
Speaker 0: This is this was Star Wars Episode 2.
Speaker 0: So if you're smart you realize Yoda dies in episode 6.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so how could he possibly die in episode?
Speaker 1: So he says this, you know, I can't believe they killed Yoda.
Speaker 1: That's crap.
Speaker 1: and some guy in the lines like way to go asshole.
Speaker 1: and then he stops and realizes what he's just said.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just got eggs his head while the crowd starts flat pointing and laughing pointing laughing Laughing.
Speaker 1: is the awesome that that is perhaps the best kind of spoiler in the world because you get all of the shock and the humor of a spoiler Plus the humiliation of an idiot plus you didn't actually spoil anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my feeling though more recently is that you know, okay a spoiler can potentially ruin someone's Potential experience of a work of art like six cents.
Speaker 0: six cents can the movie can provide like how long is it?
Speaker 0: Like a couple hours.
Speaker 0: Well, unless you're smart unless you're smart But it could potentially provide a couple hours of pretty awesome entertainment with a with a very enjoyable shock at the end.
Speaker 0: But if someone tells you right what the shock at the end is then you are.
Speaker 0: you basically lost all this potential Enjoyment you could have might have gained while watching this movie.
Speaker 0: and now basically like six cents I believe is a movie that you cannot watch more than once.
Speaker 0: it's basically not in no circumstance.
Speaker 0: watching it a second time Would be any even close to as enjoyable as the first time.
Speaker 1: see I could actually disagree there.
Speaker 1: Yeah because here's why when you watch through it the first time a lot of weird things happen and you might not remember them too clearly.
Speaker 1: like If you didn't figure it out you get to the end and suddenly you figure it out the way they handle.
Speaker 1: Thus the spoiler at the end of that throughout the movie to make sure that it makes sense is Actually pretty ingenious at a lot of times and if you watch the movie again Or if you just figured it out and knew what was going on the whole time It's almost a different movie just because you're watching How like you you can't imagine how you didn't pick it up before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, baby.
Speaker 0: It's a different movie.
Speaker 0: See, it's sort of like this this thing this sort of non-physical Like enjoy like specific enjoyment of a specific thing you could have attained has just been taken away from you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like an opportunity.
Speaker 0: cost has been snatched from your future and you can no law You know unless someone brainwashes you or you lose your memory You're pretty much never gonna get it.
Speaker 1: But at the same time too as I talked about last night.
Speaker 1: I Spoiled neon Genesis Evangelion one of my favorite anime ever Entirely on my own by myself because I was an idiot long before I watched the show.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So as a result, I watched the whole show Knowing how it ended and I saw it a lot differently as a result.
Speaker 1: But I can't say that the way I saw it in the end actually hindered my enjoyment of it.
Speaker 1: But then again that might just be because of the direction Ava goes.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what I. that's what the point I'm getting at Is that if your work of art, you know because any kind of work of art can have a spoiler, you know If your work of art Can it's possible for someone to not be able to enjoy it fully or in a certain way?
Speaker 0: Because they know a certain piece of information.
Speaker 0: What does that say about your work of art?
Speaker 0: It's only enjoyable for someone who doesn't know a certain piece of information.
Speaker 1: But at the same time I debate There's also the idea like you could spoil the end of cowboy bebop and all that takes away is the shock of all the things That go on but it still doesn't take away the journey or the experience.
Speaker 0: That's why I can't be.
Speaker 0: bop is still watchable like 10,000 times and it doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: But I can't.
Speaker 1: I can't think of too many things where the spoiler in and of itself entirely ruins it.
Speaker 0: There are some that ruin it.
Speaker 0: Maybe not entirely.
Speaker 1: the only war I can do one complete.
Speaker 1: I can think of one that would be the usual suspects.
Speaker 0: Yeah Kind of I really like watching the usual suspects like a hundred times.
Speaker 0: I didn't figure that one out even why that was kind of Weird.
Speaker 0: it was like the one movie rim had never seen and I was like, oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah, I can watch that like a hundred times.
Speaker 1: our group has this problem where if there's it's not really a problem but whenever there's certain movies that each one of us has kind of up our bot like a stick and they're just always they're Bothering us if there's anyone in the world who hasn't seen these movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's so you haven't seen that.
Speaker 0: sit down right now.
Speaker 1: So like I have my list and Scott has his list everyone We know as their list and pretty much if anyone in the room admits to have never not seen one of the movies on Anyone's list someone's on their way to blockbuster already, even though we hate blockbuster.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, but it's the only place to get a movie on short notice.
Speaker 0: Well pirates Bay?
Speaker 0: Well, I guess blockbuster can even be faster than pirates.
Speaker 1: I think the real problem here is that it's you can't make spoilers.
Speaker 1: go away because think about it They I think about all the things you a spoiler does.
Speaker 1: it's basically You can really color someone's perception of something and it takes zero effort on your part.
Speaker 1: and yet it has this huge effect on a Person especially depending on the person in the movie and on the internet.
Speaker 0: It's also not necessarily movies.
Speaker 0: It could be video games comics novels.
Speaker 1: She's an esper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott Johnson our friend Scott Johnson famously ruined Probably the.
Speaker 1: I just wrote fantasy say yeah, we just spoiled it too, but you know what?
Speaker 1: statute of limitations?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess.
Speaker 1: but this was a while ago and even then I still felt statute of limitations but at the same time I'd always kind of avoided talking about the end of that game because I knew people hadn't played it and I kind of wanted him to.
Speaker 1: and Scott Johnson just out of the blue is like well at the end blah blah blah when she's an esper and blah blah blah and She's an esper is like the middle of the game.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit past the middle Yeah, but it's not like the the end.
Speaker 0: and that's not the big thing at the end, you know It's.
Speaker 1: I think it's more of a spoiler than the.
Speaker 0: it is more of a spoiler than the end itself.
Speaker 1: It's just whatever Final Fantasy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: It's not like there wasn't enough foreshadowing for that But I just remember it turned out there was one person in the crew who had not played the game at that time and She turns around and flips ever living hell out on Scott.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was good times.
Speaker 0: Yes Yeah, but basically my policy on spoilers is that you know, I'm not gonna go out of my way to spoil something.
Speaker 0: But if I feel that, you know, this is something that everyone's seen I'm kind of come.
Speaker 0: It's like if I'm comfortable just saying it in public.
Speaker 0: good I'm comfortable just saying it like I'm comfortable walking around the street going Darth Vader's Luke's father or Rosebud was the sled.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not a problem.
Speaker 0: But saying other stuff is a problem.
Speaker 1: for a second I thought you were gonna spoil something big just to be funny.
Speaker 0: No, I wasn't because it's not.
Speaker 0: I'm not comfortable saying it.
Speaker 0: nah, and that's the point.
Speaker 0: and When I'm just in you know a new situation or just in general I'll follow my own personal guide and if that happens to conflict with yours as just the tough shit.
Speaker 1: But see the problem, but I was trying to allude to is that on the internet It takes no effort and yet you get all this result.
Speaker 1: It's a great way to grief people Especially people who might not take it so well and there's really absolutely no way to protect yourself from it Other than to watch as much media as you can as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: See so what I do on the internet is you know on the internet if you're commenting You're usually in a forum or on a blog or something and I tend to do the when in Rome.
Speaker 0: on the internet You know depending on where I am I do what people in that place do.
Speaker 0: so on FARC people spoil whatever they don't care.
Speaker 1: So I do the same thing and actually there was a big uproar about the Harry Potter things on FARC.
Speaker 1: Well, but total Farkers were mad that pretty much every single story submitted for a day and a half was just Dumbledore dies Dumbledore dies snake Dumbledore.
Speaker 0: That's good stuff.
Speaker 1: But the thing is they're also a lot of fake spoilers, which has made it even more hilarious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we'll talk about that in a second.
Speaker 0: But also like on a forum like people tend to do the put the word spoiler in your you know Topic.
Speaker 0: if you started the topic and you're making a comment use the hidden text and you know I do that, you know, cuz that's just whatever the people there do I'll do what they do and that way, you know No one can blame me for anything because that
Speaker 1: really seems following the rules.
Speaker 1: spoilers as far as I handle them it's any other.
Speaker 1: it's another matter of social etiquette and It seemed it generally.
Speaker 1: it's very crass to me or very Uncultured when especially at an anime club or an anime con.
Speaker 1: It's just a good example.
Speaker 0: That's a really bad.
Speaker 1: You can always tell the fanboys and the generally annoying people from the cool people Because the annoying people walk over and say like out of the blue.
Speaker 1: It's like they almost like they're not trying to spoil things.
Speaker 0: There's like they assume that you're because they're such nerds.
Speaker 0: They seem to assume that like you've seen what they've seen that you're watching like episodes as there are they come up like man.
Speaker 1: It was great when so-and-so died or God.
Speaker 1: I remember when I saw someone taking a picture of a cosplayer and then some other cosplayer walks up wearing another costume and both characters that they were cosplaying as Happened to have been killed in their respective animes and the guy says the other man, isn't it great?
Speaker 1: We're both playing characters who totally got killed in the middle of the anime and like ten people turned around and glared at them.
Speaker 0: It was great Good times, but yeah, one thing that there are things you can do when you accidentally spoil something for somebody to Recuperate.
Speaker 1: well depending on the crowd.
Speaker 0: It does depend on the crowd.
Speaker 0: My favorite method though that I have to share with you is the doubt Creation method.
Speaker 0: for example, I will tell rim a character X dies What or does character Y die as or does every character die?
Speaker 0: See I Probably in.
Speaker 0: rim knows now that in all likelihood character X dies because of the way it might you know The way I said it.
Speaker 0: it's kind of obvious.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's 99% obvious.
Speaker 0: But by saying those other things rim or someone who wanted to at least depending on rim wanted to or not He could in his mind Justify at least a small amount of doubt as to whether I actually just spoiled it for him or not.
Speaker 0: So while watching whatever it is I just spoiled or reading it He could keep in his mind the slight question of is it gonna be character X or Y?
Speaker 0: He'll probably be like I was probably X. Scott totally spoiled it for me.
Speaker 0: And then when he gets to it and it is X it like yup.
Speaker 0: Scott totally spoiled it for me.
Speaker 0: but that small amount of doubt leaves a small possibility of Getting the original experience.
Speaker 0: if you want it badly enough You can sort of you.
Speaker 0: you can grab on to that and create more doubt in your mind that it wasn't actually Spoiled for you.
Speaker 1: now, that's the immediate cover-up.
Speaker 1: Let's say that you just for whatever reason tend to spoil things.
Speaker 1: often You're just not careful about it or you're worried about doing it in the future.
Speaker 1: You can inoculate everyone, you know against it by just kind of randomly always making jokes and falsely spoiling things all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how many people like.
Speaker 1: they'll spoil anime randomly to kind of like yeah, everyone dies at the end of that.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, they kill everyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah main character dies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so like whenever you watch a new show be like I heard about this show and main character dies.
Speaker 0: Well, I heard about this show.
Speaker 0: No one dies at all.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the whole world explodes and they'll fly off into space.
Speaker 0: Yep, or yeah, I heard about this show.
Speaker 0: the second character gets syphilis.
Speaker 1: Now the funny thing is that the the everybody dies.
Speaker 1: cliche at least.
Speaker 1: anime came from the fact that there's a fairly killer.
Speaker 1: You know well-known.
Speaker 1: I anime a couple anime but one in particular.
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 0: Everyone actually does die and quite a few anime where everyone dies.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, at least almost everyone dies.
Speaker 1: But if you if you tell someone that especially someone who hasn't seen anime or just in general They just don't even assume that that's a possibility.
Speaker 1: How many movies are there where everyone dies?
Speaker 1: I mean even in Doctor Strangelove at least a few people survived.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it depends what you mean by everyone because this the everyone dies where the entire world and all humanity is gone Right, and then there's the everyone dies.
Speaker 0: We're like.
Speaker 0: all the named characters die.
Speaker 0: So like Romeo and Juliet It's actually kind of fair to say everyone dies in a way, you know, but Benvolio doesn't die though No, but he's not everyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah He's not everyone.
Speaker 1: he's a semi-major character.
Speaker 0: you get my point though.
Speaker 1: Yeah Mercutio dies though.
Speaker 1: Maybe he doesn't even.
Speaker 1: You see what I did there.
Speaker 0: I see what you did there Actually, it's funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah part of the reason we thought about this was on the way to work.
Speaker 1: I was listening to movies you should see and they spoiled something in seven when they were reviewing seven Which was a good review because seven is still a great movie and I really like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, seven is definitely a movie that's hard to spoil Not really.
Speaker 0: Ah, like you could tell what happens at the end, but it doesn't really ruin them experience.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, that's not what they spoiled.
Speaker 1: what they spoiled?
Speaker 1: Well, they kind of spoiled that but they spoiled one.
Speaker 1: There's a shock scene in during one of the murders Investigations, ah, I think you know which one I'm talking about I know what you talk about and they ruined it.
Speaker 1: and then they basically said oh, we'll bleep it out later Don't worry about it.
Speaker 1: And I guess they forgot to ha ha so it's still in there.
Speaker 0: Oh Fun time.
Speaker 1: yeah, luckily I've seen that movie twice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think.
Speaker 0: generally though what it all comes down to is if you're gonna Spoil things you need to like give a warning, you know That's all and then it's up to people whether they want to listen or not.
Speaker 0: And if they listen and they get it spoiled then it's their fault and you don't have to feel like you did anything bad.
Speaker 0: And that's what we do on the podcast and that's what I do in regular life Like oh is everyone I'll be like, hey has everyone here seen this?
Speaker 0: Okay, let's talk about it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you know what?
Speaker 1: That's just basic social etiquette.
Speaker 0: Yeah but yeah spoiling is becoming a big problem.
Speaker 0: because Well to see more people are seeing more media and they're communicating with more people at once in a more public and more difficult to avoid.
Speaker 0: fashion and Information travels faster and more widely and et gets home, you know, yeah, it Marty McFly gets back to 1985.
Speaker 0: It's really hard to see all forms of art and experience them before Information about those works of art gets to your brain and on the internet It's getting to the point where there's no way to be careful other than not going to any websites.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it even comes to things like not even works of art, but for example Like knowing the out.
Speaker 0: like I we don't have television here and it's not possible to watch sporting events live.
Speaker 0: very often Gandalf dies.
Speaker 0: yeah, so
Speaker 1: when I
Speaker 0: When a sports event happens, right and I want to watch that sports event perhaps, you know on a delayed video or something like that You know Like watch a Formula One race the next day on the train and I don't want to know who won.
Speaker 0: I basically can't read the news or else I'll find out who won and I have to sort of not Take in any information watch it and then read the news.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's kind of sucky.
Speaker 0: It's really prohibitive I guess.
Speaker 1: luckily this is kind of sad.
Speaker 1: But I think back and all the like all the media that I really would have cared about a spoiler.
Speaker 1: I mean there are some things a lot of anime in a few movies that if someone has spoiled them I would have been incredibly angry.
Speaker 1: But I haven't seen anything in recent memory where having a spoiler or not having a spoiler would have mattered to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I feel like I'm immune.
Speaker 0: also I can't remember a time where something was spoiled for me like.
Speaker 0: I don't remember a single one I can and but also at the same time a lot of things have been spoiled like by myself because like the foreshadowing just tells me what to expect.
Speaker 1: and then You know and I see it you were the one bitching at me when we were watching Gundam seed because I kept predicting what was gonna happen based on the opening animation and I was always right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know you were right, but I also knew you were right cuz I had seen it.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the fact that you know the opener to that anime spoils all the plot except for one thing.
Speaker 0: But I was trying to do is I was trying to create the doubt to sort of prevent you from spoiling for you.
Speaker 1: Ah, but see much like my arguments in a lot of philosophical realms I cannot abide in cognitive dissonance.
Speaker 1: So if I know something there is nothing in the world that can get me Even if I want to to pretend that I don't know it.
Speaker 0: Well, that's just your problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was actually I'm reading but I watch Gundam seed.
Speaker 0: I knew just as well as you did what all those openers alluding to but I purposefully said and it's just an opener They don't have to make the show the same as the ocean.
Speaker 1: I don't have that ability.
Speaker 1: It's funny cuz.
Speaker 0: actually it is true though that they could make the show different from the opener.
Speaker 1: that never happens It could I don't think it's ever happened.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: Oh Tana No, no, cuz you know horses.
Speaker 0: Um horses.
Speaker 1: I win All right, so in shoujo kakumei Utena, which is one of my favorite anime series ever.
Speaker 1: Don't don't The movie's crap.
Speaker 1: I just got to say that whenever I bring up this show But in the opener pretty much everything you see in the opener happens throughout the show and at the end of the opener there's the scene of the two main characters on armored horses wearing armor like flying up into the sky.
Speaker 1: and We had a friend whose name was dammit Dwayne.
Speaker 1: Dammit Dwayne dammit Dwayne Dwayne like to smoke the pot a little bit to the watch to the point that None of his pot dealer friends would sell him pot because they thought he should stop smoking it.
Speaker 0: He had some problems.
Speaker 0: for anyone who says, you know marijuana doesn't hurt you marijuana blah marijuana this right?
Speaker 0: You're probably right.
Speaker 0: You know marijuana is probably not as bad as that smoking anything else.
Speaker 1: I think the difference is benefits one joint per Week versus one joint per.
Speaker 1: yeah, I don't know if you mean oak marijuana in quantity.
Speaker 0: I don't care what you say.
Speaker 0: You will turn into a complete useless dumb.
Speaker 1: It'll turn into dammit Dwayne.
Speaker 1: Yeah who provide?
Speaker 1: he was the best dungeon master in the world for 20 minutes And then it all went downhill from there.
Speaker 1: But actually we heard he stopped smoking pot and he made something of himself.
Speaker 0: We'll see how true that is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how are we gonna find out?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: There's no way to find out.
Speaker 1: I've cut ties to all those people.
Speaker 0: I don't really care.
Speaker 1: But anyway This kid was convinced that that scene in the opener where they get on the horses and fly into the sky Was gonna be in the movie because he'd seen the whole show and it wasn't in the show.
Speaker 1: and he knew because he's so much Smarter than everyone else that that's what was gonna happen in the movie.
Speaker 1: and He was so devastated when he saw the movie and that wasn't there like he cried.
Speaker 1: He just lost it.
Speaker 0: That's not what I would cry over yeah, but that's what I figured the naked cars would have more of an effect But I don't know what kind of effect that was.
Speaker 1: Cuz at that point when the naked cars come on screen, you can't think what the hell you just kind of roll with it.
Speaker 1: At that point it was the weed crying.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, so that's what we got to say about spoilers.
Speaker 0: got anything else, uh, not particularly spoilers are on the internet.
Speaker 0: beware if a work of art can be spoiled so horribly that you know, there's no more enjoyment in it just because you know something then I Personally think that that work of art is inferior to say watchmen which can be spoiled but is enjoyable no matter how much you know About it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if watchmen were if what happens in watchmen had been spoiled for me.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it would suck I do not deny.
Speaker 0: but what I'm saying is that watchmen is superior.
Speaker 0: Let's say there was a work of art It was spoiled right and now you could not enjoy it period or you enjoyed it significantly less.
Speaker 0: Watchmen in even if you know the spoiler.
Speaker 0: sure that decreases the enjoyment of the first reading But it's still stupidly enjoyable every time and thus gets respect Whereas something else would get less respect.
Speaker 1: and for a final spoiler I'm about to go play a bunch of counter-strike source because I kind of like it.
Speaker 0: now that I've finally played it I'm gonna go read that giant like 600 page gunsmith cats omnibus volume 2.
Speaker 1: So I'm holding out on that.
Speaker 1: I got other things to read.
Speaker 0: Well, I also got gunsmith cats burst volume 1.
Speaker 0: It's kind of scary.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: So without further ado He was a man or no.
Speaker 1: She was a man.
Speaker 1: I already fucked it up.
Speaker 1: I'll just start over.
Speaker 1: Good job.