Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, October 10th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we review the first two hardcovers/first four trades of The Walking Dead.
Speaker 0: Let's do this!
Speaker 0: Next week on Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: It's questions week, amends.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of looking forward to it.
Speaker 1: A few of you, and maybe not that many, but a few actually have some good questions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and surprisingly, you know, while you might think that, you know, when something is fun for the listeners, it's not fun for us, it's not true!
Speaker 0: Questions week is sort of fun for all.
Speaker 0: I mean, I remember- I do questions week every week.
Speaker 1: if it wasn't gonna get bad and- Well, then it would turn into a Penn Jillette show.
Speaker 0: It's sort of the same reason that Penny Arcade doesn't do Cardboard Tube Samurai more than once a year, because they know if they do it too much, it'll get played out, even though they love it and we love it.
Speaker 1: 'Cause I will admit, when we first did this way back, we did like a Thursday "Ask Rubenscott" anything, and that was super fun.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, send in questions via forum or email, and we may or may not answer them.
Speaker 0: Make sure that, you know, we're doing this four days of the week.
Speaker 0: So, a Monday question should go to Monday, and a Tuesday question should go to Tuesday, and a Wednesday question for Wednesday, which is today.
Speaker 0: And Thursday, you can ask any question that isn't Monday, Tuesday, or Wednesday questions.
Speaker 1: And isn't already answered by Google, or perhaps a previous episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: And also, to try not to ask a question that has an incredibly long answer.
Speaker 0: But actually, a lot of people have asked questions that have incredibly long answers, but it's kind of okay, because we're just not gonna answer them next week, but they do make good episode topics.
Speaker 1: And I think you'll see a lot of those in the future, because a couple of them I looked and I was like, "What would I say about
Speaker 1: that?".
Speaker 1: "Oh, that's more than five minutes, doing a whole
Speaker 1: show.".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And they were actually good episode ideas.
Speaker 0: So I guess the next time we ask for episode ideas, just try to ask questions that have really long answers, and that's an episode idea.
Speaker 1: So, uh, nothing interesting happened in our lives in the last 24 to 28 hours or so, so I'll just get right into the news.
Speaker 0: I'm still, like, got this, like, phlegm coming out of me.
Speaker 1: Hey, you seem a lot better than you were on Monday.
Speaker 0: I feel better, but my nose is full of snot, and it's going down my throat, and it's not, it's, it's bleh.
Speaker 1: One more night of Sudafed, and you'll be fine.
Speaker 0: I don't know, I'm not even gonna do Sudafed, I'm just gonna- Why not?
Speaker 1: Take a Sudafed, can't hurt.
Speaker 0: Sudafed's great.
Speaker 1: Now I can't.
Speaker 0: I just blow my nose and cough.
Speaker 1: Or just take a Sudafed and feel great.
Speaker 0: No, or not.
Speaker 1: Right, so, this is kinda relevant, because *gasp* I read a comic, and, oh, I have news about a comic.
Speaker 1: Holy crap.
Speaker 1: Well, kind of.
Speaker 1: It's about a manga.
Speaker 1: But, you know, manga, comic.
Speaker 0: A manga is a subset of comic.
Speaker 1: But, uh, and I know, I'm curious, how many of you out there are gonna think this is good news, and how many of you are going to think it is bad news?
Speaker 1: And I wonder how many of you can guess what our opinion is.
Speaker 0: Well, that's easy.
Speaker 1: Dark Horse, who have been putting out, among other things, Blade of the Immortal, which is a very popular manga that's been running for quite some time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I am under the impression that it is very good, I just have yet to read it.
Speaker 1: I remember Greg was reading it, pretty much as it came out, and he had a whole mess of it, I just never- It's, it's a samurai manga, if you like samurai action, like, you know, the Kenshin OAV- Who doesn't like samurai?
Speaker 0: If you like, say, the Kenshin OAV- If you like the first Kenshin OAV- That's what I said.
Speaker 1: You said the Kenshin OAV, that could- There's another one?
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, there's, the first OAV, the Samurai X-.
Speaker 0: You missed my thing, I know about it, I'm saying is that there isn't another one.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're playing the "I have no son" card.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So, if you like the Kenshin OAV, or if you like, uh, Lone Wolf and Cub, or some Zatoichi or something like that, you're probably gonna like Blade of the Immortal, and you should buy it at the bookstore on Amazon or something like that.
Speaker 1: Dark Horse has, uh, finally seen the light, they've realized that something they were doing was kinda silly, and not many people cared about it- Or maybe
Speaker 0: they just weren't making money from it, so they-
Speaker 1: Well, you know, if they weren't making money from it, then it probably was kinda silly, and most people didn't want it.
Speaker 1: They're done with monthlies, they're no longer, as of, the last one that will be released on November 7th, going to release Blade of the Immortal in 32-page monthly comics.
Speaker 1: It is only going to come out in trades.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, you see, back in the day, like in the 90s- Well, I guess, graphic novel format, since trade doesn't actually mean the format, it means how it's sold, but anyway.
Speaker 1: Right, right.
Speaker 0: But whatever, in the back of the mid-90s, when they would bring manga to the US, you know, they started out with, you know, Sanctuary, Lone Wolf and Cub- Remember the mid-90s?
Speaker 1: Crying Freeman- People didn't have cell phones, and most people didn't have DVD players?
Speaker 1: Project Eiko, uh- Oh, that was a good show, we gotta talk about that.
Speaker 0: You know, Viz and Dark Horse are pretty much the only companies putting manga out, except for Marvel with their Akira, right?
Speaker 0: But even Marvel with its Akira, they put it out in the same format as comic books in the United States.
Speaker 0: They made- they chopped up the manga, and they would put one chapter at a time, in like a 24 or 32 or 36-page comic book.
Speaker 0: Just like the comic books of old, and the comic books that, you know, people who like underwear pervert comics still get every month.
Speaker 0: Little tiny, flimsy, floppy books that come out every month.
Speaker 1: That don't fit on a shelf, there's no way to store them easily, if you don't put them in baggies- Unless you buy bags and pieces of cardboard and cardboard boxes.
Speaker 0: Which cost more than the comics themselves sometimes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, all the mangas came out that way.
Speaker 0: But most of those mangas either ended, like Sanctuary, they eventually finished it, or they cancelled, or something happened, right?
Speaker 0: And the only one that's still going, that they're still putting out the monthly issues, is Blade of the Immortal.
Speaker 0: I think even, like, didn't they- they were doing, I think, the other one recently was like the canon god, Exaxian, but I think that one sort of stopped and got held up and had some censorship issues and whatever, so.
Speaker 0: Blade of the Immortal is the only real manga I know of that is still coming- that was still coming out in the United States in the classic monthly comic book format.
Speaker 1: And I guess this is just more proof that, by and large, other than fans of traditional comic books in the United States, no one wants that format.
Speaker 0: No one wants that format other than people who like it for nostalgic reasons and people who like to waste money.
Speaker 0: I mean, you could make the argument that they are- A lot of people buy that format because, like, they can't wait.
Speaker 0: It's like, they need to know what happens next.
Speaker 0: right away, as soon as it's possible to get, like, the next page of the thing, they'll get it.
Speaker 0: But if that just didn't exist, they would get, you know, the quickest way to get it would be the other format.
Speaker 1: Well, see, there's two things.
Speaker 1: In comics, what a lot of artists do now, maybe not a lot, but they'll release the monthlies, but they'll put little extras in those that won't be in the compilation.
Speaker 0: But also, some people release the monthlies and then put extras in the compilation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is what you should be doing.
Speaker 0: Other people are- they'll write their story, like, "for the trade" in quotes, you know?
Speaker 0: They'll write a story that's meant for a trade, but then it'll get chopped up into four, five, six pieces and put out monthly, and then a trade will come out.
Speaker 0: Or, they'll write for the issues, and then the trade will come, and the trade will be a little bit awkward.
Speaker 0: Because they didn't write- because it's not one, like, story beginning, middle, end.
Speaker 0: It's a bunch of small stories.
Speaker 1: That's actually something that I noticed when I read through the created version of Megatokio, and it just, in a non-webcomic form, it really didn't flow right, and it didn't feel like a comic.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: They'll also, like, the end of a plotline will come in the middle of a trade or something, because the number of issues they would've had to combine and stuff, because they didn't write for the trade.
Speaker 0: You know, and it's becoming, you know, it's gonna come to a head, I think, within a year or two.
Speaker 0: Either the monthly is gonna die- I hope, I hope, I hope.
Speaker 1: See, I don't think the monthly's gonna die, because that is one of the, like, the monthly mentality of "we've gotta sell these, and the fans have to buy 'em to be loyal to us,".
Speaker 1: and the nostalgia and everything in the underwear pervert industry is so strong.
Speaker 1: And no one seems to have the balls to say, "You know what?
Speaker 1: This business model is doomed to eventually extinct the entire idea of underwear
Speaker 1: perverts.".
Speaker 0: Uh, I've been saying that.
Speaker 0: And people seem to go,
Speaker 0: "Blah-blah-blah-blah-blah-blah.".
Speaker 1: Well, no, only comic people do.
Speaker 0: Other people either don't care- Well, other people don't care and don't read comics.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that's the problem.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, a lot of those other people read manga.
Speaker 0: They sure do.
Speaker 0: And, I mean, a lot- It's like, sure, barely anyone reads underwear perverts, and a lot of people are reading manga, but still, not enough.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on the mon- I mean, every now and then, there's the super hit.
Speaker 1: Like, "Fruits Basket" sold some stupid amount of comics.
Speaker 0: It did sell some stupid amount, but even that stupid amount was not even, like, a drop in the bucket compared to, like, an average video game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even then, it depends on what kind of video game.
Speaker 0: Or a run-of-the-mill movie.
Speaker 1: Because most video games sell for crap, and then there's the few that actually sell.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, we're talking, like, a crap video game that sells, like, hundreds of thousands versus, uh, you know, a crap manga which sells a thousand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it also- The markets matter, because manga, even if they don't sell in the US so much, still sold in Japan, and made all the money there.
Speaker 1: But, uh, underwear pervert comics don't sell anywhere but here.
Speaker 0: They actually do sell them in pretty much, like, all around the world.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but what volumes do they sell in?
Speaker 0: In many different languages.
Speaker 0: I mean, how many do they sell in Europe as opposed to- I mean, I guess they don't sell every single title in every single country, but, you know, they have, like, you can get Spider-Man pretty much anywhere.
Speaker 0: You can get Spider-Man in Japan, or Mexico, Europe, or Africa.
Speaker 1: You can get video games in Australia, too.
Speaker 1: It's just, they come out three months later and cost twice as much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know how much Spider-Man costs in, say, Russia.
Speaker 0: Do they have Spider-Man in Russia?
Speaker 0: Alright, we have a lot of non-.
Speaker 0: And how many issues behind are they?
Speaker 1: United States listeners, tell us.
Speaker 1: When do comics come out over there?
Speaker 1: How expensive are they?
Speaker 1: Do they all come out?
Speaker 0: Yeah, can you buy Spider-Man and Superman in the store?
Speaker 0: In your language?
Speaker 1: I'm just curious.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't think that- I just don't feel like they would sell that well.
Speaker 0: Can you get the trades in your country?
Speaker 1: I don't think that underwear perverts have quite the following in other countries that say certain shows have in Mexico.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, also, just a side note while talking about underwear perverts, in December, Marvel's doing something kinda good, but not super good.
Speaker 0: It's like they're getting closer to the right track.
Speaker 0: If you went to the comic store right now to get some Spider-Man, right?
Speaker 0: You'd have a choice between Amazing Spider-Man, Ultimate Spider-Man, Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man, Spectacular Spider-Man, I Can't Even Think But I Know There's More, alright?
Speaker 0: All these different Spider-Man comics, and they're all different.
Speaker 1: That alone was actually the reason I did not get into comics as a kid, because I got- my parents wanted to get me into comics.
Speaker 1: They got me this X-Men board game, and I was like,
Speaker 1: "Huh.".
Speaker 1: And it came with an X-Men comic, and it didn't make any sense.
Speaker 1: And they were like, "Oh, you gotta read 'em, a bunch of 'em, or else it doesn't make
Speaker 1: sense.".
Speaker 0: Actually, the reason they had all those different titles, right, is because, you know, each comic comes out monthly.
Speaker 0: So if they wanna have Spider-Man more than once a month, they make a different Spider-Man.
Speaker 0: Like, if you just read Friendly Neighborhood, it's like one story, but if you read Amazing, it's another story.
Speaker 0: And they sorta match up a little bit, but each one is like its own story.
Speaker 1: But I'm just saying, so I went, they took me to a comic book store, and I was like, "Okay, I'm just gonna buy a bunch of
Speaker 1: X-Men.".
Speaker 1: And then I learned that there's X-Men, X-Factor, X-Force, the Uncanny X-Men, and fuck it, and I gave up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: In December, if you go to the comic book store, you're only gonna see one thing.
Speaker 1: Well, you're gonna see Ultimate, and you're gonna- You're only gonna see one thing, a bunch of nerds.
Speaker 0: Well, Ultimate- that's true.
Speaker 0: Ultimate Spider-Man is its own separate thing, there's nothing to do with anything, so that'll still be there.
Speaker 0: And Marvel Adventures Spider-Man is for little kids, you'll still see that there.
Speaker 1: Honestly, that is my favorite Spider-Man.
Speaker 0: I think that's better than any other Spider-Man.
Speaker 0: Marvel Adventures Spider-Man is pretty good, I have it, did you read it?
Speaker 1: I flipped through it, and I liked it a lot, I just haven't had time to read it.
Speaker 0: It's alright, it's alright.
Speaker 0: But, if you go to the store in December, you'll see Amazing Spider-Man, Amazing Spider-Man, and Amazing Spider-Man.
Speaker 1: So they have three different comics called Amazing Spider-Man?
Speaker 0: No, it's one comic coming out three times a month.
Speaker 1: I know, I was making fun at the way you presented it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it actually is being written by Dan Slott, who in my opinion is the only guy who can write a decent underwear perfect comic these days.
Speaker 1: Oh, these days, I was gonna say, "Heh, Ellen
Speaker 1: Moore!"
Speaker 1: These days.
Speaker 0: So, I ordered all three and we'll see what comes of it, and if it's not bad, then I'll probably get the trades of the Amazing Spider-Man for that one.
Speaker 1: So, speaking of ADV, what do you got in the news?
Speaker 0: Speaking of ADV, right.
Speaker 1: I had no sequitur there, what do you want me to do?
Speaker 0: So there's big news about Genian going down the tubes, and who knows what the hell they're doing, it's not, whatever, they're done.
Speaker 0: ADV laid off 13 people, now people are like, "Oh man, the anime industry down the hole, who knows what's going on,
Speaker 0: whoa!".
Speaker 0: But actually, ADV is hiring people in other departments.
Speaker 1: I think this is much less a, "Oh my god, we're going under," and much more a, "Get rid of employees who weren't pulling their weight, reorganize the company to have more focus on what's
Speaker 1: important."
Speaker 1: Which should be marketing, maybe, maybe.
Speaker 0: Not counting freelance people, which, you know, I'm sure they have freelance designers and they have a lot of freelance voice actors and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: They only have like 100 employees, so firing 13 people is like, uh, more than 13% of the workforce.
Speaker 0: That's huge.
Speaker 0: But they're gonna hire people in other departments, so I guess they've realized that something about the way they were doing business wasn't working.
Speaker 0: And they're rethinking it, which, I don't know the specifics of what they're doing, so I can't give an opinion as to whether I think that's good or bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, partly because the anime industry is so secretive for no good reason in this country.
Speaker 0: It's because they're a private company, so they don't have to be any less secretive than they are.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, but it seems like a lot of companies, and sometimes it's justified, but like Google was that way for a long time, but they have this idea that if I'm not legally obligated to tell people something, I'm never gonna say anything.
Speaker 1: And I think that might hurt 'em a little bit, just 'cause- I think that hurts as an issue for every company.
Speaker 0: I think, in general, that with the internet, right, the way things work is people on the internet who are paying attention to information about your company want to know.
Speaker 0: And the more open you are with them, they'll be able to see right through you, and if they see that you're doing good things internally, so if you're confident that your company isn't stupid, then being wide open to the public,
Speaker 1: people
Speaker 0: who don't go on the internet and don't care, they're gonna see your company through your marketing face.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna learn anything about your company that they don't already know, 'cause they don't care, and they're not gonna pay attention.
Speaker 0: And people who do care are gonna find out everything, and if what your company is is good, they'll be happy, and if what your company is is bad, then, well, then you do have something to be ashamed of and regret, you probably should fix that and then open up.
Speaker 1: I just feel like, and this, obviously, I can't let it spawn off into a crazy tangent, because we'll have to do a show- It's already spawning, I feel it.
Speaker 0: We'll have
Speaker 1: to do a whole show on it separate, 'cause I got a lot to say, but I feel like the anime industry, as it is run in the United States, is barely alive and just on the verge of collapse at all times, and I think that they're really mismanaging something that could become gigantic and make a lot of money for a lot of people.
Speaker 0: I generally feel that almost any business could become and make a lot of money, and a lot of people just don't, and I don't know, you know, maybe 'cause, like us, they don't have the initial investment that's required to do that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: But these companies have a lot already, they already have the contacts, they have some capital, at least I assume they have some capital, they must make some money.
Speaker 1: I just, they don't, there are some semi-obvious things that these anime companies could do that would probably make anime a lot more popular, and as a result, allow them to sell more anime.
Speaker 0: Let's do an episode on like what we'd do if we ran an anime company of some sort.
Speaker 1: Let's just leave it at that, we'll do an episode sometime in the future on if we were in charge of ADV, what we would do.
Speaker 0: But I think it's generally good that, you know, I don't know if this shift that they're doing in priorities is, this specific thing is good, but the fact that the companies are trying to change to try to do better business is encouraging.
Speaker 1: That means a lot, because I have a lot more respect for someone who tries and fails than someone who never tries.
Speaker 0: Yep, who just goes with the status quo, and whether it's profitable or not, and just keeps cranking the crank.
Speaker 0: Yep, but like a good example- Try cranking a different crank if that one doesn't work.
Speaker 1: It's kind of an analogy, but you might notice that oftentimes Scott and I, malign, very obese people.
Speaker 1: But one thing I would never do is if I see someone who's really fat, and they're trying to work out, there's nothing funny about that, because they're trying.
Speaker 1: And the anime industry is a big fat guy right now.
Speaker 0: Unless it's that gif on Fark.
Speaker 1: That one gif?
Speaker 0: That one.
Speaker 1: That wasn't working out, though.
Speaker 1: That was King Leonidas.
Speaker 0: No, I'm talking about the one on the treadmill with the- I have no idea what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: The big fat lady on the treadmill going
Speaker 0: "dunkadunkadunka.".
Speaker 1: I have no idea what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: You've seen that animated gif.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 1: I don't generally go seek out animated gifs of fat people.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you're doing on the internet.
Speaker 0: It's on like all over, you can't possibly avoid it.
Speaker 1: What, like Goatsy?
Speaker 1: Or Lemon Party?
Speaker 1: I was just gonna make a nice analogy about how the anime industry is an 800 pound dude, and he's putting down the carrot cake.
Speaker 1: Now he might be picking up the cheesecake, we're not sure, but at least he put down the carrot cake.
Speaker 1: It's a start.
Speaker 1: Things of the day, and man, I really want some carrot cake now.
Speaker 1: I shouldn't have said that.
Speaker 0: I don't like carrot cake.
Speaker 1: Get the fuck out of this studio.
Speaker 0: I really don't like it.
Speaker 0: Cake is supposed to be made of sugary- I like carrots a lot, but- God, there's a lot of sugar in carrots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but carrot cake doesn't taste- cake is supposed to be made with, like, just like candy.
Speaker 0: Carrots are like candy.
Speaker 0: Cake is not made with candy.
Speaker 1: Cake is made with bread.
Speaker 0: Which is candy.
Speaker 1: Bread is candy.
Speaker 0: Well, cake bread.
Speaker 1: Carrots are not.
Speaker 0: Cake bread is candy.
Speaker 1: What about cheesecake?
Speaker 0: That's cheese.
Speaker 0: Cheesy bread.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's not crazy bread.
Speaker 0: No, it's more like cream cheese, but harder.
Speaker 1: I thought for my thing of the day here, which I found kind of randomly, that maybe I should explain who the person is they're talking about and what the game is they're talking about, but there's a man named Richard Garriott.
Speaker 1: Lord British.
Speaker 0: He is a famous geek.
Speaker 0: Of course, he's not- well, good or bad is up to you, but he's famous.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say this.
Speaker 1: He made a series of inscrutable, unplayable games you might know as Ultima.
Speaker 0: Get ready for the hate mails.
Speaker 0: Here they come.
Speaker 0: I agree with Rim, by the way.
Speaker 1: Those games were ass.
Speaker 1: They were some of the most obtuse, just crap games, and they have such a following, and the following is largely self-referential and made up of-.
Speaker 1: But this video effectively will tell you everything you need to know about a man named Richard Garriott, about the Ultima series, about MMORPGs, and about this game that I'd heard of but didn't know or care about, and I'm glad I don't know or care about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard the name of the game in the past, and of course I've heard of Richard Garriott in the past, but I never realized that they were like-.
Speaker 0: I didn't get the whole picture, and I'm very glad that the whole picture was presented to me by seemingly a person from Albion who agrees completely with me and would probably be my best friend.
Speaker 1: I think my favorite part of this video is when he talks about his opinion of MMOs and then how this game may or may not have changed his opinion on MMOs.
Speaker 0: This guy is definitely, like, the awesome guy, and I want to hang out with him.
Speaker 1: Looks like it's an escapist thing.
Speaker 1: You might remember The Escapist, which was awesome until it turned into nothing, but hey, check it out, I'm a girl gamer, by the way, you should play Eve Online.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder what it's like now.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll go read it this week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, god, I used to read that when I worked at IBM.
Speaker 0: Well, when it first came out, it was like, holy shit, there's this internet video game magazine- That's erudite and interesting.
Speaker 0: It's erudite, interesting, and only consists of, like, five really amazing essays every week.
Speaker 0: And then it went on and on and on.
Speaker 1: And all the essays were the same.
Speaker 0: And then all the essays were the same and it kind of went downhill, and then they were the guys who made the Gamers of Jobs podcast, which was, like, the only good video game podcast, and then they moved over to The Escapist, and then they stopped doing the podcast.
Speaker 0: And then they started doing the podcast at The Escapist, and then they stopped doing it again.
Speaker 1: Plus, when they started it back up, it wasn't good anymore.
Speaker 0: So as far as I'm concerned, The Escapist is responsible for the death of the best video game podcast, and they're responsible for, like, a few good essays about video games repeated week after week after week.
Speaker 0: So that gives them a negative in my book.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got for me?
Speaker 0: Except for this video, which might put them at breakeven.
Speaker 1: This video is pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: I got to admit, I lulled.
Speaker 0: So triumph, not the word triumph, which means, I guess, to, you know, conquer over something.
Speaker 1: Depends on what context.
Speaker 1: I mean, in Rome, a triumph with a specific and legal boon given to a regeneral upon a great success.
Speaker 1: Like, if you did blah blah blah and you were awesome, it would be granted a triumph.
Speaker 1: Meaning you could ride through the streets of Rome in a great parade with all the...
Speaker 0: Yeah, great.
Speaker 0: So, triumph is also a company that makes motorcycles.
Speaker 1: Booty of your conquests.
Speaker 0: And the one motorcycle they make is the Rocket 3, which is, I guess, the biggest motorcycle you can buy.
Speaker 0: At least the biggest, I guess, motorcycle being manufactured.
Speaker 0: I'm sure someone has, like, a custom bike that's bigger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus theoretically, I could take two wheels and stick, I don't know, a Saturn 5.
Speaker 0: Haha, awesome.
Speaker 0: So, they have a factory where, of course, they make these motorcycles.
Speaker 0: And here is a video of what goes on in that factory.
Speaker 0: And I think that is all I will say.
Speaker 1: It's a fascinating documentary.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of how they make the Triumph Rocket 3 motorcycle.
Speaker 1: Not just how they make it, but how they test it and all that.
Speaker 1: It's really kind of fascinating.
Speaker 1: And I didn't know much about motorcycles and their manufacture, but I feel enlightened.
Speaker 0: You can learn a lot from this video.
Speaker 0: I learned a lot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, like I said at the beginning of the show, I read a comic.
Speaker 0: Holy shit, RedRamaComic.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, wait, wait, who's that at the door?
Speaker 0: I think it's Satan.
Speaker 0: And he's wearing a sweater.
Speaker 0: Oh, what's that behind him?
Speaker 1: Of course he's wearing a sweater.
Speaker 1: It's like 60 degrees out.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, what's that behind him?
Speaker 0: It looks like a flying pig of some sorts.
Speaker 1: Haha, what's that?
Speaker 1: Mega Man's in Smash Brothers Brawl?
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: But not only that, one step further.
Speaker 1: We're talking about a comic that's about zombies.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh, that's gonna make a lot of people happy.
Speaker 1: It's gonna make a lot of people happy.
Speaker 0: Not only that, but this comic is not a manga.
Speaker 0: It's an American comic book.
Speaker 1: And not only that, but it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: And it's really popular.
Speaker 0: Like, consider this, right?
Speaker 0: In America, comic books come out like 24 pages a month about, right?
Speaker 0: Those little floppy things we talked about earlier.
Speaker 0: And then they eventually trade them, you know?
Speaker 0: They take each story arc and they make a little book that's a soft cover.
Speaker 0: This thing, this comic book here, other than stuff like Watchmen and whatnot, this is the only comic book in the United States that I know of where month after month, the sales figures on the trade paperbacks go up each month.
Speaker 0: So in month one, say trade paperback number one sells a thousand.
Speaker 0: I'm just making up numbers here.
Speaker 0: In month two, the trade paperback will sell like a thousand and twenty.
Speaker 0: And the next month after that, it'll sell a thousand and thirty.
Speaker 0: Which means that the readership of this book is growing a lot.
Speaker 0: All the time.
Speaker 0: As far as the last time I checked, it was just a few months ago.
Speaker 1: So, without further ado, tonight we're going to review The Walking Day.
Speaker 0: Now, what we read is the first two hardcovers, which are the same as the first four trade paperbacks.
Speaker 0: Don't even ask me which monthly issues that covers.
Speaker 1: Because it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: And beyond that, I today, because I just recently read both of these in one go, read the summaries of everything that's been released beyond those first two.
Speaker 1: So I know the plot as far as it has been released.
Speaker 0: The reason I have the hardcovers, which are the same as the first four trades, is because they were actually cheaper, the way I buy comics, to get the hardcovers than to buy all the trades separately.
Speaker 1: I'll just note it was interesting, but the author, there's extras in the back of these hardcovers, and there's a little bit of talk, like blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: And he expresses, I don't want to dwell on this, but he definitely expresses that sentiment that I hate so much in a lot of American comic people, where he talks about, in this wait for the trade industry...
Speaker 0: You mean spend less money and not give you more money for the same exact product, only worse because it has ads and it's in a bunch of little pieces?
Speaker 1: Yeah, people who say you should buy the trades because it supports the art, or you don't, god, not the trades.
Speaker 0: Buy the monthlys.
Speaker 1: Buy the monthlys because it supports the artists.
Speaker 0: Go listen to the episode we did last week, two weeks ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Geek Back, the special, the one about charity and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that one.
Speaker 0: This is not a charity.
Speaker 0: Go listen to that episode.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So this guy who writes this comic is Robert Kirkman.
Speaker 0: And Robert Kirkman, I've read a bunch of his books, not all of them, but a bunch of them.
Speaker 0: And he's a pretty popular guy.
Speaker 0: He writes a lot of popular things.
Speaker 0: And for me, personally, he's hit or miss.
Speaker 0: I mean, he wrote that Marvel team-up, the recent Marvel team-up.
Speaker 0: I like that a lot.
Speaker 0: That's like one of the only good recent underwear perverts.
Speaker 1: I've heard it was pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's basically just, like, underwear perverts in New York, sort of like what the world would be like, but just kind of fun, and yeah, this is how it would be, woo.
Speaker 0: And I like that, because it doesn't take itself all seriously, and it doesn't come up with some contrived BS.
Speaker 0: It's just fun, happy times in underwear pervert land.
Speaker 0: And it's good stuff.
Speaker 0: He also wrote Invincible, which is an underwear pervert book that is for Image Comics.
Speaker 0: And I never read that, but it's pretty popular with some people.
Speaker 0: Another thing he wrote that's popular is that werewolf, I don't know what it's called, but...
Speaker 1: It was a free comic book.
Speaker 0: It was a free comic book, so I read the free comic book.
Speaker 1: I just want to say it's so pedestrian.
Speaker 0: It was called The Astounding Wolfman.
Speaker 1: It was just, it was utterly pedestrian, and that's all I really have to say about it.
Speaker 0: Right, so the book that we're going to talk about is the one that I guess he is, like, the guy of.
Speaker 0: It's like his work, you know, is The Walking Dead.
Speaker 1: Now, there's someone else drawing it, and I think the artist actually changed recently, but we're not even going to talk about the art, because the art is just completely un-noteworthy.
Speaker 0: Well, the artwork is done by Tony Moore, who's the guy who does the artwork.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure someone else is doing it now.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, but the artwork that we looked at in these two hardcovers is Tony Moore, and he did stuff like The Exterminators, which I really like, and I tried to get Rym to read, but I don't know where he put it.
Speaker 1: It's somewhere in my room.
Speaker 1: I gotta find it so I can read it.
Speaker 0: That's better than Walking Dead, I'll tell you straight up.
Speaker 0: It's written by someone that's not Robert.
Speaker 0: In fact, The Exterminators, I just gotta say this right away, is written by someone who never wrote a comic before in their lives.
Speaker 0: Huh.
Speaker 0: And it's awesome.
Speaker 0: And it's like watching an- well, I guess both of these comics, The Walking Dead and Exterminators, reading them is sort of like watching one of those HBO TV shows.
Speaker 0: It's sort of the same kind of plot, like- Wow, yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: You could take The Walking Dead and adapt it straight up into one of those HBO shows, and it'd probably do super well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of the comics I read- In fact, the comic is basically just storyboards for the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So The Walking Dead.
Speaker 0: It's about zombies.
Speaker 1: Now, on one hand, it is obviously in the line of all the classic zombies.
Speaker 1: You know, Night of the Living Dead, Dawn of the Dead, Dusk of the Dead, Reform of the Dead, Dusk of the Dark.
Speaker 0: Asterisk of the Dead.
Speaker 1: And all those movies, and there's a little bit of homage to them, and at the same time, it takes a slightly different take on it, and the author actually went to great lengths to talk about how the one thing that pissed him off about all those zombie movies was that they ended.
Speaker 1: Which on one hand, you can think, "Wow, he just wants to make money by making a comic that never
Speaker 1: ends.".
Speaker 1: But two, he's kinda right in that every zombie movie either ends with, "Oh, everybody's dead.
Speaker 1: They
Speaker 1: lost.".
Speaker 1: Or, "Oh, they got away in the helicopter.
Speaker 1: The
Speaker 1: end.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, some other place in the world doesn't have zombies.
Speaker 1: Granted, all zombie movies actually end as always, "The real enemy was
Speaker 1: mankind.".
Speaker 1: Mm-mm-mm.
Speaker 1: I'll get to that.
Speaker 1: I really like this, but I have some issues with The Walking Dead.
Speaker 1: As in, I'm not going to buy any more issues.
Speaker 0: Forget about the hate mail for what you said before.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get serious hate mail if you hate on The Walking Dead.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna hate.
Speaker 1: Here's my problem.
Speaker 1: The Walking Dead starts out like everything I've ever wanted in a zombie media.
Speaker 0: It sure does.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 1: Because every zombie movie is almost always the same, and this one departs a little bit in that it's a lot more procedural, and it skips all the bullshit and gets right to the thing I care about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, other zombie stuff.
Speaker 0: We saw that movie, The Days Later.
Speaker 1: Oh, 28 Days Later was super good.
Speaker 0: It started off pre-zombie, right?
Speaker 0: Then the guy was in a coma, and then he woke up and there were zombies, right?
Speaker 1: And it was really good, except I thought the end was really kinda cheesy and lame.
Speaker 0: It was an okay movie.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a great movie.
Speaker 0: Did they make a sequel?
Speaker 0: I didn't see the sequel.
Speaker 1: As far as I'm concerned, 28 Days Later is an amazing movie up until they meet the military people, and then it's just crap.
Speaker 0: I think it's just an average movie overall.
Speaker 0: But Walking Dead skips over that whole "where did the zombies come
Speaker 0: from?"
Speaker 0: stuff.
Speaker 0: There's no mystery.
Speaker 0: It's not like, "Huh, where did these zombies come from?
Speaker 0: We should try to find out and then eliminate the cause of the
Speaker 0: zombies.".
Speaker 1: I sure hope we solve this mystery.
Speaker 0: Or, "Hey, how do zombies work?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Let's experiment.
Speaker 0: Oh, they get there when they bite in this
Speaker 0: discovery.".
Speaker 0: No, it's when it starts, the zombie.
Speaker 0: Well, there is some of that.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit of that.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of that later in the ones you haven't read.
Speaker 0: Oh, but mostly it starts off with, "The zombie apocalypse happened, people accepted it, and now they're working
Speaker 0: out.".
Speaker 1: Yep, so it starts with this main character who effectively is a lot like the main character of Firefly, Bao.
Speaker 1: It's the same kind of character in the beginning.
Speaker 0: He's just a badass, kind of normal, straight-headed dude who knows the score.
Speaker 0: I think he was an ex-cop, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was a cop.
Speaker 0: He was a cop, but then there was a zombie apocalypse, so "cop" doesn't mean much anymore.
Speaker 1: So he wakes up in the hospital 28 days later style, and what the fuck's going on?
Speaker 1: And then he discovers zombies, and he runs outside, and this is where I decided this comic was amazing.
Speaker 1: Because instead of the bullshit that happens in every zombie thing, you know what does he do?
Speaker 1: Gets some guns, goes out, tries to find people, does everything he can to be awesome, and doesn't fuck anything up.
Speaker 0: And eventually gets to his family.
Speaker 1: And they form this group of people who are living in a camp outside of the city of Atlanta, and they learn that all the city's collapsed, and everything's gone, and there's zombies about.
Speaker 0: They come up with a pretty good system.
Speaker 0: They're hanging out by this RV, they got people together, they got food and water, they got zombie defense.
Speaker 0: They got it covered.
Speaker 0: They're making do.
Speaker 1: And what I really liked was that, without bogging down on these details, this comic was really procedural about the zombie thing, and it skips a lot.
Speaker 1: It'll skip intervals of time without warning you, but in a really good way.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like the burning wheel in gaming, where it gets to a point where it's like, "This is what I was waiting for,".
Speaker 1: and it happens.
Speaker 1: And then maybe they foreshadow the next thing that's going to happen.
Speaker 1: They don't bother going through all the crap that happens between.
Speaker 1: It just kind of cuts to, "It's four hours later, and they've piled all the zombies they killed into a pile to
Speaker 1: burn.".
Speaker 0: If you watch a movie like Dawn of the Dead, it's compressed to an hour and a half, two hours.
Speaker 1: And there's a montage.
Speaker 0: But there are scenes like they're ice skating, or they're hanging out drinking coffee in the mall, or they're doing stuff.
Speaker 0: And it shows you them going on, and in The Walking Dead, it sort of just skips the day-to-day life of zombie dealing with it.
Speaker 0: And it assumes a lot of it.
Speaker 1: It cuts to the next interesting or procedural thing, like, "Alright, we're looking for a new place to
Speaker 1: stay.".
Speaker 1: It skips all the stuff on the road, except when they find interesting things along the way.
Speaker 0: It's only the interesting and important parts, and all the other zombie stuff is just taken for granted.
Speaker 0: Oftentimes, just killing zombies is taken for granted.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Yep, we're defending zombies,
Speaker 0: bam!".
Speaker 1: I like the fact that they set up the zombies to allow for a lot of drama.
Speaker 1: The zombies are basically the slow, stupid, easy-to-kill zombies that only get you if there's a bunch of them and they surround you.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's like if you have any sort of martial arts ability and perhaps dangerous weapons, you can kill a bunch of zombies and they won't bite you unless you're really, really dumb.
Speaker 1: Maybe if we ever do another zombie show in a couple years, we should just take this zombie scenario and say what we would do.
Speaker 0: What the characters do up until a certain point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Well, we do have that prison right there.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: But, you know, what goes on, it's like you still have.
Speaker 0: the drama of society has collapsed, there are zombies everywhere, the zombies used to be people, the moral dilemma of killing them, the...
Speaker 1: There's no moral dilemma.
Speaker 1: It's a zombie.
Speaker 1: You kill it.
Speaker 0: You gotta fight constantly, action movie kind of thing.
Speaker 0: You can have this human drama in this post-apocalyptic world and the zombies only show up when you need them to make a story.
Speaker 1: And most of all, just the fact that the characters are largely cool-headed and they generally do, even if not the smartest thing, I can understand why they do the things they do.
Speaker 0: They actually try to think about what they're doing and they go along with it and the only time anything gets in their way is if something unexpected happens, like, alright, they'll say, "Oh, there's an unexplored house.
Speaker 0: Alright, we gotta go check for food in this
Speaker 0: house.".
Speaker 0: And they're going real slow and cautious, like they got a plan to check out the house and keep everyone safe while doing it.
Speaker 0: And they execute that plan, but maybe something will happen, like the house will collapse or something that will be unexpected and that's the only time they'll be fucked, other than a human doing something stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now, once I had read the first hardcover, all the way to the end, and it ends on, not a cliffhanger, but for me, for the thing I wanted, because the first hardcover of this was amazing and it was everything I wanted in a zombie comic.
Speaker 1: And at the end of it, they stumble upon a thing and I think I kind of spoiled it, it's a prison, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: And that moment was like, "Oh, it's gonna be one of those kind of things where now it's gonna be all procedural, like they're smart, they're gonna go into this prison and clean it out and make a base and something
Speaker 1: cool.".
Speaker 0: I mean, that in itself is sort of a new idea.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, zombie, you know, we've had zombie movies and books and stories in malls, right?
Speaker 1: And houses, and nothing else.
Speaker 0: And houses, and office buildings and all.
Speaker 0: But a prison, really, when you think about it, is a really like this perfect setting for a sort of a zoomed in human drama zombie plot.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a place that has jail cells, which can be used for cool things.
Speaker 0: It's a place with a lot of food, there might be prisoners inside, that'll be really interesting.
Speaker 0: There could be zombies in the prison, which would be really interesting.
Speaker 0: There could be like police and weapons and guards in the prison.
Speaker 0: There's all this drama, but it's really defensible and hard to get in and out of, but it has a lot of land and, you know, you could live in a prison without any outside contact.
Speaker 0: And there's just so much in a prison that it's just the perfect thing for a zombie story.
Speaker 1: So I finished that, and I read the end of that book right before I got off the train and went to work, and I was like, "Hot fucking
Speaker 1: damn!".
Speaker 1: This is the best, oh my god, this comic.
Speaker 1: This is zombie porn for RIM.
Speaker 1: I'm so excited about this.
Speaker 1: This is great.
Speaker 1: I can't wait to see how they clear out this prison, and how they're gonna, like them defending against the various zombie attacks, and maybe they're gonna set up some agriculture inside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's got a fence, you don't really need to set up so much.
Speaker 1: It's got three fences!
Speaker 1: And like, one of the gates is broken.
Speaker 0: Barbed wires, sniper towers.
Speaker 1: Obviously there's probably riot gear and crap here.
Speaker 1: I wanna see them get that and suit up and use it and make a little society and then try to find local survivors.
Speaker 1: Now, here is where I went from liking this comic a lot to not caring about it at all.
Speaker 0: Oh, boo.
Speaker 1: So, the next hardcover starts up, and the procedural stuff kinda disappears.
Speaker 0: It's there, because they do- Barely!
Speaker 0: Oh, they do a lot of stuff, clearing out the prison and trying to figure out what to do and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: And that takes almost no pages, and nothing interesting happens.
Speaker 1: Because right away they introduce a bunch of prisoners, and unless you're dumb, it's so obvious what's gonna happen with these prisoners.
Speaker 1: And then, it's so obvious, everything's just telegraphed to the point of absurdity.
Speaker 1: And the characters all start becoming bitches.
Speaker 1: And I mean, every single character, every single human, becomes an absolute raging bitch.
Speaker 1: And when I say raging bitch, that has nothing to do with gender.
Speaker 1: The men are just as bad.
Speaker 1: And everyone's yelling and screaming and fighting, and it's not like, "Oh, the true enemy was
Speaker 1: mankind!".
Speaker 1: It's, "Wow, these people are all stupid?
Speaker 1: I would've shot them
Speaker 1: all.".
Speaker 0: I think what it is, though, if you look at it the way I saw it when I read it, was yes, everything was sort of foreshadowed and I kinda predicted everything.
Speaker 0: Except for that character who showed up out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know what, that character is crap.
Speaker 1: It is, I agree, that character is- That character is such a crap character.
Speaker 0: That was one charac- I thought that character was crap and stupid.
Speaker 1: And you don't even know, when this comic gets into the gladiatorial rings later, it's just dumb.
Speaker 0: I didn't get to any gladiatorial rings that were not in the parts that I actually read.
Speaker 0: Yes, this comic, I read the plot summaries, goes- The gladiator stuff is stuff that Rim read on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: We're only talking about trades one through four, hardcovers one and two.
Speaker 1: Yes, but as far as I read from the summaries, this comic goes down the fucking tube.
Speaker 0: Regardless of that fact, the way I saw it was, they showed up at the prison and they had the same idea that they had everywhere else.
Speaker 0: Which is, "Okay, this is how we're gonna do
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 0: But then, there were these prisoners, and the introduction of the prisoners was like this big monkey wrench in their well-oiled machine.
Speaker 1: Except it didn't have to be, they set it up where it could have been okay.
Speaker 1: It could
Speaker 0: have been okay, the problem was, is not only were the prisoners sort of the monkey wrench in their machine, but it showed that the machine they had going, which looked like, you know, a machine that was doing the best it could in the situation at hand, what did actually was a flawed machine, and that their own distrust that was imposed by the old human society and the prison, so their distrust of the prisoners is what they eventually, is what ruined them.
Speaker 1: Except they should have mistrusted the fucking prisoners.
Speaker 1: The thing is, the way they introduced the prisoners, it's like, there's the big black dude who murdered some people, and there's the little mealy guy who was a tax accountant invasion guy.
Speaker 1: And there's the little stoner guy, and then there's the big awesome guy.
Speaker 1: Well, uh, it's pretty obvious which of those people is the most dangerous, and it's the tax evader guy.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna worry about spoilers, 'cause it should be so obvious.
Speaker 0: Once you're introduced to the character, it is obvious when you see- They show the pictures of all of them.
Speaker 1: This
Speaker 0: is seen, the first time you see the prisoners, all of them are sitting at a table, and you see all these prisoners, and just by looking at them, and by knowing how people write, you'll know that, yeah, the tax evader guy obviously is hiding something, and that guy is totally cool.
Speaker 1: And, but beyond that, this is my problem, is that one, alright, so, you know, everything Scott said, and also just the stress of this situation is finally breaking these people down and all that, but one, that's what every other stupid zombie thing does.
Speaker 1: I don't need to see the same zombie movie over and over and over again.
Speaker 1: The reason I'd like The Walking Dead was that the first two trades were not like every other zombie thing.
Speaker 1: They were a breath of fresh air, and then you just turn to the same bullshit that every other zombie thing is, I might as well just watch Night of the Living Dead, which is better.
Speaker 0: See, I- oh, it's not better.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is that- Ah, Night of the Living Dead is the best zombie thing.
Speaker 0: Ah, I think Walking Dead is the best zombie thing.
Speaker 1: It would've been, except for the second hardcover on.
Speaker 0: I think the thing is, is that every zombie thing, even Night of the Living Dead, Dawn of the Dead, is the same thing.
Speaker 0: It's like, first it starts out procedural and people acting smart, and then eventually they lose their cool.
Speaker 0: I think what the thing is, is that Walking Dead had a whole two full trades of not losing their cool before it got to the part where the music- No it didn't!
Speaker 1: It had two full trades of one person not losing his cool and everyone else being a fucking moron.
Speaker 0: Ah, I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: Yelling at each other all the time.
Speaker 0: They were smart enough to go along with what the smart guy was saying.
Speaker 1: Only after the other guy dies!
Speaker 0: I guess, yeah.
Speaker 1: And also, just, there are a couple of problems.
Speaker 1: I think my real issue is that this comic does the same thing that every other zombie thing does, but it doesn't do it as plausibly in a lot of points.
Speaker 1: Like, the descent into madness and chaos is literally like- Ah-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo!
Speaker 0: Ahhhh!
Speaker 0: It was, I do agree.
Speaker 1: It's like suddenly all the characters are screaming at each other all the time.
Speaker 0: It was indeed a very rapid descent into madness, I must say.
Speaker 1: Panel one, everyone's talking.
Speaker 1: Panel two, everyone's fine.
Speaker 1: Panel three, guys smiling.
Speaker 1: Panel four, everyone's screaming.
Speaker 1: Panel five, two people were murdered.
Speaker 1: Panel six, two more people were murdered.
Speaker 1: Panel seven, the zombies fucking broke loose.
Speaker 0: I do agree that in the pacing of at least reading it the way I read it in these two hardcovers, that the descent into madness did come suddenly.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, at the end of the first trade everyone was saying, at the beginning of the first trade everyone was saying, you know, and then there was this slight distrust with the prisoners and the little weird stuff going on.
Speaker 0: But then by the end of the second hardcover, they've completely lost it.
Speaker 0: I'm like, whoa, you lost it really quick.
Speaker 0: And maybe on the one hand someone could say, well, they lost it really quick.
Speaker 0: That's the reality of a zombie world.
Speaker 0: That's why every zombie story is the same, because that's how it would be.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, it really does feel like a too quick a descent into madness.
Speaker 0: I could have bought it more easily if the descent into madness, they would have been completely mad at the end of, say, the third hardcover.
Speaker 1: It just, it wasn't well done, and it wasn't well paced.
Speaker 1: And because it was, in addition to that, the same as every other zombie thing, it lost all its pizzazz.
Speaker 1: Also, this comic has a tendency of, any time the writer, I guess, that gets bored, he just randomly kills someone.
Speaker 1: Or, "Oh, shit
Speaker 1: zombies!".
Speaker 1: Or, "Oh, shit serial
Speaker 1: killer!".
Speaker 1: Or, "Oh, shit crazy village run by some crazy guy who has a zombie daughter and has gladiatorial
Speaker 1: fights!".
Speaker 1: Or, everything they run into is just weird and implausible, and all the characters they meet along the way are... They don't act like humans.
Speaker 1: And like, there's a thing with a double suicide that happens, and it's just so out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: And it's not like, "Oh, I'm mad because they didn't foreshadow this, but they did foreshadow
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: There's a certain amount of foreshadowing that is required, lest you have everything just be a deus ex machina, or just a monkey wrench in the plot.
Speaker 1: And this comic either foreshadows things stupidly to the point that it's obvious what's gonna happen, or just has crazy bad shit come out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Could that also be, though, an effect of your enhanced reading abilities?
Speaker 1: You know what, if that's the case, then this is below me.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: I can't, I gotta go read, I don't know.
Speaker 0: No, I too saw through all the foreshadowing as well, and knew exactly what was gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Except for the things that weren't foreshadowed at all, or that were foreshadowed poorly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the fact that it was a prison, I was like, "Oh man, it's a
Speaker 0: prison.".
Speaker 1: The double suicide thing, when you get to it, is really dumb and not explained at all.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it's cool to have an unexplained thing in the universe, but it's unexplained in a really bad way and just doesn't make sense.
Speaker 0: I didn't feel so poorly.
Speaker 0: I mean, the double suicide wasn't, like, my favorite part or anything.
Speaker 1: It came out of nowhere and served no purpose.
Speaker 0: It didn't leave a particularly bad taste.
Speaker 1: And also, the characters who did it had no motivation to do that.
Speaker 1: There was nothing there for that, at all.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: There was some dialogue before they did it.
Speaker 1: No, the only dialogue was, "Huh, that one character is a little weird and creepy, but the other one's really normal and
Speaker 1: balanced.".
Speaker 1: And it just was dumb.
Speaker 0: Alright, well, do you wanna keep going, talking about it?
Speaker 1: I don't know, I said the art is completely... meh, and it is.
Speaker 1: The art doesn't really add or detract at all.
Speaker 0: Well, the art is... I think one thing to be said about the art is that it's black and white, which is really cool for, you know, a comic that's being made right now.
Speaker 0: You know, 'cause most comics made right now are not... well, it's not black and white, it's grayscale.
Speaker 1: The one thing I can say that a lot of action scenes, if you actually take the time to look at them, don't flow at all.
Speaker 1: There's no choreography in fight scenes.
Speaker 1: It is just... they give the impression that a fight is happening, but they don't actually ever let you see a fight.
Speaker 1: And it kinda bothers me, just because I liked where they were going with this kind of a procedural, like, "This is how they're dealing with it, this is the reality of the tactical situation of dealing with
Speaker 1: zombies.".
Speaker 1: And instead, they never actually show you, like, the zombie defense working, or the mundane encounter.
Speaker 1: Like, encounters.
Speaker 1: Actual encounters with zombies.
Speaker 1: It's just all kinda like, "And then they killed all the
Speaker 1: zombies.".
Speaker 0: As I think that's what they're doing, is they're trying to concentrate on the human drama.
Speaker 1: But the human drama is poorly written, the characters are very poorly done, and seem to have almost no motiv-.
Speaker 1: It's like the characters' motivations change randomly, depending on the scene.
Speaker 1: Burning wheel characters are better, 'cause at least they only have three things going, and they stick to those three things.
Speaker 1: It's like the characters are all bipolar, and they're either yelling, screaming crazy about something just weird, or they're just completely calm and normal.
Speaker 1: And it doesn't flow well.
Speaker 1: It could flow well, but it doesn't.
Speaker 1: Also, this isn't the writer's fault, I don't think, but there are a lot of grammatical mistakes.
Speaker 0: Are there?
Speaker 0: That's the editor's fault.
Speaker 1: He mixed up effect and effect more than once.
Speaker 0: I didn't notice that, really, 'cause I read comics real quick.
Speaker 1: There were, like, one or two misspelled words, but other than that- I'm not complaining about that, don't get me wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, blame the editor for that one.
Speaker 0: But, in general, I think that The Walking Dead is- there's actually a thing going around, people think there's too many zombie comics, I don't know what they're talking about.
Speaker 1: I think there aren't enough, because almost all- I mean, I'm not saying that The Walking Dead is bad, it's really good, but every other zombie thing is crap.
Speaker 0: I think The Walking Dead- it's not perfect.
Speaker 0: I mean, it does suffer some problems, because it's being written as, you know, a monthly 24-page thing, and I'm reading it in a hardcover, and I think that it's sort of written to be read in sort of little bits at a time, to let you digest those little bits slowly, and, you know, if you buy a little bit, you wanna feel like something happens in that little bit, and that affects the pace when you read a whole bunch at once.
Speaker 1: And I realized this, because I read the summaries of the ones I haven't read yet, just to, you know, know where the plot goes, because I wonder, you know, maybe it saves itself.
Speaker 1: And I realized something.
Speaker 1: Reading the summary of an issue I'd read was pretty much the same as reading the issue, because all it does is lay out what happens, but it skips the, you know, the human drama.
Speaker 1: But the human drama's not very compelling, because it's all kinda either really out there and doesn't really make sense in terms of how humans would act in any situation, or really pedestrian and just has played out and been done a million times before and not interesting.
Speaker 0: I think the human drama's a little more interesting than that, but I agree that it's not, you know...
Speaker 1: I can't care about these characters.
Speaker 1: I can't get into the characters.
Speaker 1: I can't understand their motivations.
Speaker 0: That is one thing, is that I didn't, most of the characters I did not care about.
Speaker 0: There were only a very few that I cared about.
Speaker 1: Some of the characters I couldn't tell the difference until one died and then there was only one left, and then I realized one was different.
Speaker 0: The ones that I did care about I could tell the difference.
Speaker 0: It was mostly, like, I could recognize the characters because the art was okay, but I could, the name matching.
Speaker 0: I didn't get quite right, you know, quick enough.
Speaker 0: But, overall, the few characters I did care about, a lot of them died.
Speaker 1: But what I was getting at is that reading the summary, like a two or three paragraph summary of the plot of one, gave me the same feeling that reading it did.
Speaker 1: And that's why I read the summaries of the rest, and I think I'm gonna read the summaries of all the rest of this comic on Wikipedia instead of reading the rest of the comic.
Speaker 1: They will, you know.
Speaker 1: The article on this comic is rather extensive in terms of plot summary.
Speaker 0: Scary.
Speaker 1: It also has a matrix of characters who were still alive and as of when.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Crazy.
Speaker 0: So, as far as I'm concerned, if you like zombies, if you like comics, this is the comic to buy.
Speaker 0: You should be buying this.
Speaker 1: As far as I'm concerned, the first two trades or the first hardcover is great.
Speaker 1: Read it.
Speaker 1: There's no reason not to read it.
Speaker 1: However, if you really like it, I will warn you that I feel that the comic goes effectively nowhere from that point forward.
Speaker 0: I think it goes from what I've read, which is the second hardcover, so trades three and four, that it goes a little bit downhill.
Speaker 0: But I don't think it's like this horrible, terrible piece of crap.
Speaker 1: The plot of what happens after what you have read from the summaries I read on Wikipedia is really, really dumb.
Speaker 1: Like, not worth reading dumb.
Speaker 0: Well, hardcover number three is coming pretty soon.
Speaker 0: That's all you.
Speaker 0: And I will read it, and until then, I will withhold an opinion of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'd get, like, I'm gonna do the one out of ten whatever.
Speaker 1: I would give the first one nine out of ten because it was a breath of fresh air and I fucking loved it.
Speaker 1: Second one five out of ten, and the rest of it from the summaries, like, four out of ten.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: I would give the first one also a nine out of ten, and I would give the second one maybe a seven, six and a half, something like that.
Speaker 1: See, the thing is, the second one was just kind of eh, and I think about, like, is there anything I'd rather be doing?
Speaker 0: The thing is actually towards, it's like, it's sort of like the beginning, the second one, the reason it's hard to give, what'd you give it, like a five, a four?
Speaker 1: Well, here's the problem.
Speaker 1: The first, like, quarter, or third of the second one.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: The second one is like this slope.
Speaker 0: It's like it starts out as nine, and it slopes down to, like, you know, five and a half.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the second book is just- Overall, I've got to give it something in between.
Speaker 1: It's like I start on this plateau, and I'm just running along this plateau, and it's great.
Speaker 1: I start the second one, and it's just a hill, and going down.
Speaker 1: And at the bottom of the hill, where the third one's gonna start, is a crevice.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 1: And at the bottom of that crevice is the Marianas Trench.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: I really am disappointed, because I really liked it, and the fact that, and, you know, I really wanted to, like, when I got to the parts that I didn't like in the second one, I kept convincing myself that it'll get better again, or it's not so bad, and I was trying to like it, and by the time I got the end, I was like, wow.
Speaker 1: I really didn't enjoy that at all, and I really don't want to read any more of this.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So, I guess if you are interested in reading comics about zombies, it's me versus Rim.
Speaker 0: We slightly disagree.
Speaker 0: But regardless, I think everyone should read the first two trades/first hardcover of The Walking Dead by Robert Kirkman from Image Comics.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, we didn't, did we say who wrote it?
Speaker 0: Robert Kirkman.
Speaker 0: I said that before.
Speaker 0: Let's see how much it costs on Amazon, and then we'll be out.
Speaker 0: Okay, on Amazon, each individual trade costs about, oh, $10.39.
Speaker 1: That's probably worth it.
Speaker 0: And the hardcovers are about $20, so it's like- Might as well buy the hardcovers.
Speaker 0: I mean, look, hardcover, $19.99, trade paperback, $10.39, so you're either gonna pay $20.80 or $19.99 to get a hardcover.
Speaker 0: I mean, you're saving money buying a hardcover.
Speaker 0: Can't go wrong.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology, Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs, Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catchalls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution NonCommercial ShareAlike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.