Speaker 0: It's Wednesday April 4th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we preview the new anime moonlight mile.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: those of you who listen to all four nights of geek nights might have heard a Wonderful clip yesterday from another show where one of the hosts of that show had some words for our dear friend Scott here It's hard not to laugh.
Speaker 1: Alright the deal here is we didn't really go into it yesterday partly because it was video game day and not many of our Listeners on Tuesday really care about the difference between shoujo and shounen manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's tell the story here.
Speaker 0: Alright, so we reviewed last week was the last week.
Speaker 0: there was indeed We reviewed a manga called to Tara and anime world order released their review of the same thing on the same night.
Speaker 1: Yep, slightly later.
Speaker 1: I might add.
Speaker 0: Yes slightly later.
Speaker 0: But apparently they said that was on purpose that we couldn't steal information from their review and use it in ours.
Speaker 1: How they even know we were doing it?
Speaker 0: because I told them I was bragging to him like, ah We're gonna beat you in the race to review to Tara.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: So you told him you were gonna beat him and then they conveniently.
Speaker 1: well, we're planning on waiting and yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway.
Speaker 0: So I had emailed them weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Let's see if I can find the exact March 7th.
Speaker 0: I emailed them.
Speaker 0: So a month ago, I emailed them and I said cuz I had just gotten to Tara in the mail and I'd read it and vertical the company that publishes publishes to Tara was advertising it and marketing it as a shoujo Star Trek or a sci-fi emo or whatever, you know They.
Speaker 0: they called it a shoujo and it is written and drawn by keiko.
Speaker 0: Takamiya who is a shoujo master.
Speaker 1: Yep, however, it was apparently published in Japan in a shounen magazine.
Speaker 0: So it was also a shounen manga.
Speaker 1: Well, all the deal is we showed it to a bunch of our friends.
Speaker 1: We got them all to read it and without question.
Speaker 1: They'd all ask after we gave it to him.
Speaker 1: So how is the shoujo?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I asked them, you know one asked Alex.
Speaker 0: when I gave it to him I said alright take this and just when you're reading it think about is this shoujo or not and Tell me what you think.
Speaker 0: and when he came back he was like, yeah, I don't think this is shoujo man.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I emailed anime world order because they know more about anime than we do supposedly but they think they do or at least I learned.
Speaker 0: I Learned a lot of things.
Speaker 0: I didn't know when I listen to their show.
Speaker 0: So I often go to them with my anime questions most of the time involving old robots But sometimes not old robots or directors that aren't listed in the anime news network.
Speaker 0: Yeah stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So I said hey, I don't get a paraphrase my email But I said wise to Tara marketed to shoujo when it's not and I said a bunch of other things.
Speaker 1: basically He said oh my god to Tara is awesome.
Speaker 1: It's almost as good as Tezuka.
Speaker 1: OMG.
Speaker 1: This shit is hot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I said it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll read my email cuz it's short.
Speaker 0: All right All right, guys, here's a tough question that might require all of your powers combined to answer.
Speaker 0: I just read to Tara volume 1 from vertical.
Speaker 0: the sales pitch They've been using is that this thing is shoujo Star Trek.
Speaker 0: The creator Keiko Takamiya is supposedly a great shoujo manga master.
Speaker 0: I said supposedly there because I didn't know who Keiko Takamiya was until a few weeks ago.
Speaker 0: So I said supposedly because that's what I heard After reading it.
Speaker 0: All I can say is I don't notice any shoujo at all.
Speaker 0: This is straight-up epic sci-fi manga.
Speaker 0: I mean this shit is awesome.
Speaker 0: I don't want to say it, but I might have to say it's on Tezuka's level.
Speaker 0: I never thought anything could be better than Phoenix, but this has the potential.
Speaker 0: it all depends on what happens in the rest of the volumes.
Speaker 0: Anyway, how the hell is the shoujo?
Speaker 0: the character designs are a little bit shoujo-ish But other than that, I noticed nothing that makes to Tara a shoujo manga.
Speaker 0: I mean if this is shoujo then so is Phoenix.
Speaker 0: volume 2. what's the deal?
Speaker 0: Is there gonna be some hidden BL and volume 2 that are not prepared for?
Speaker 1: I'd like to jump in to note that according to the PR people for it the answer is yes Warn me now.
Speaker 0: Also, there's two Tara anime coming out in April if it's as good as this manga.
Speaker 0: All I can say is woot.
Speaker 1: Now we I don't know what kind of response we expected.
Speaker 1: maybe a oh they're marketing it this way because of blah or oh.
Speaker 1: Well, technically it was published blah and blah and blah and all the stuff that we wouldn't know.
Speaker 1: but instead.
Speaker 1: now This is a paraphrase clip because if you want to hear the whole thing just listen to their show.
Speaker 1: I don't want to waste too much time on this, but this is the response Scott got more or less.
Speaker 1: There are multiple questions.
Speaker 2: Do you think that if I concentrate hard enough I could kill him with the power of my mind?
Speaker 2: The thing is like his email is stupid for reasons that have nothing to do with the fact that it's not.
Speaker 2: It doesn't take all our fucking powers combined because this is such a retarded question that No, any one of us could answer this.
Speaker 2: even if it was shoujo you would still be a condescending sexist asshole.
Speaker 2: Oh It's straight-up sci-fi.
Speaker 2: So it couldn't possibly be shoujo.
Speaker 2: You don't want to say that a shoujo work could be on par with Tezuka.
Speaker 2: I think Hagio moto You know the female Tezuka as she's referred to would have something to fucking say about that.
Speaker 2: first off Do you have any idea what shoujo means?
Speaker 2: you have any idea with these classifications mean in Japan?
Speaker 2: She's one of the women who helped to fucking define shoujo.
Speaker 2: God, how insulting is this?
Speaker 2: Like I just can't get over how dismissive this email is of shoujo manga Insinuating that oh, how could such a solid sci-fi series possibly be a girl's manga?
Speaker 1: and that kind of as if to imply that Only guys girls can't write sci-fi.
Speaker 2: You know, it doesn't excuse the stupidity of this email.
Speaker 2: Oh What that's retarded.
Speaker 2: There's no words for how retarded that is and I guess it pisses me off more cuz like this is geek nights.
Speaker 2: I mean these guys do a podcast where they talk about anime And you guys are always boasting about how much you know Mr.
Speaker 2: Is that we ran the RIT anime club?
Speaker 2: So our otaku cock is the biggest.
Speaker 2: what now?
Speaker 2: No, I'm not cool with this.
Speaker 0: Now every time it's funny to listen to it.
Speaker 1: now All the people we've asked about this who happen to hear this episode or whatever and I'll note that this audience includes both men and women Really don't know why that happened because they also wonder why this is.
Speaker 0: Let's let's just talk about a few points rather than going over the whole thing line by line.
Speaker 0: Alright, first of all my opening sentence of you know, it might require all your powers combined to answer.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: that's just a silly line to open an email with.
Speaker 0: it's not like a literal thing.
Speaker 1: If anything even if it was literal then wouldn't that mean that you're putting great stock in their powers and that it's something you don't Have the power to answer and you trust them to do.
Speaker 0: So perhaps it does also my My quip about.
Speaker 0: I might have to say it's on Tezuka's level.
Speaker 0: She was all like, oh you can't say a show Joe's as good as Tezuka.
Speaker 0: I'm like, no, I Scott say anything is as good as Tezuka except Will Eisner.
Speaker 1: Scott has this pedestal and on it are Tezuka and Will Eisner and there's pretty much no one else in the world is even close To the base of that pedestal.
Speaker 0: Alan Moore is on tier two, man.
Speaker 0: You got to watch out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's how high that pedestal is.
Speaker 1: If anything the fact that Scott said that this work approaches Tezuka's level is a compliment of the highest order.
Speaker 0: Secondly all that other stuff that she was going crazy about like, you know, uh Woman can't make good manga.
Speaker 0: Where did I say that?
Speaker 0: aside for the fact that did I say I just read my email.
Speaker 0: Did I say any of that stuff?
Speaker 1: Well, the best part is that if we're dismissive of show Joe How can we own a gigantic pile of show Joe?
Speaker 1: I mean didn't we just review?
Speaker 1: here is Greenwood which is obviously a show Joe.
Speaker 1: In fact, I believe the English release actually says the word show Joe on it.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: I was actually originally weirded out by that because not that I wasn't gonna read it or I didn't like it But watching the original anime knowing nothing about it.
Speaker 0: original anime.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it's not the original anime.
Speaker 0: I think the manga was the original.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I originally watched the anime and it seems just like a normal comedy show.
Speaker 0: It's not a show Joe show.
Speaker 1: well cuz show Joe in that case definitely has more to do with the target audience.
Speaker 1: also the fact that there is a lot of Implied BL in there.
Speaker 0: there is quite a bit of BL especially in the manga.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: But basically this all comes down to the fact that when I say the word show Joe and when I think most Anime people in America say the word show Joe they're referring to a genre based on content.
Speaker 1: Yes It doesn't help that the vast majority of show Joe manga that comes out in the US is all very much similar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean sure the Japanese definition of show Joe is whatever you say it is, but that's not the definition I'm using.
Speaker 0: so it's sort of like if rim says, I don't know Geek and nerd I guess it's sort of like geek.
Speaker 0: I mean rim says geeks should all die and to me the word geek means Jews.
Speaker 0: then rims an anti-semite.
Speaker 1: These eggs are anti-semitic anti-semite.
Speaker 1: Uncle Leo See not even care about that part Even though I do point out again that even a lot of the women who listen to our show Contacted us to say wow That was a little crazy It was quite the craziness.
Speaker 0: But I think in the end I'm actually happier with this kind of response to my email because if they just responded normally they would have been like no It's not a show Joe.
Speaker 0: It's a showing in.
Speaker 0: it was actually published in a magazine.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: I would have just been like huh all right.
Speaker 0: There's my answer, but instead I've gotten days of hilarious entertainment power.
Speaker 1: Now my favorite part is that aside from the show Joe whatever argument, and you can talk about that forever I mean look in America people say otaku, and they're proud of it.
Speaker 1: otaku is like.
Speaker 1: I'm a guy who likes anime, but in Japan otaku is.
Speaker 1: that's that guy Yeah, likes.
Speaker 0: hentai is used differently.
Speaker 0: the word manga if you want to use the Japanese definition spider-man is manga.
Speaker 0: Yo, I mean sure some people say stuff like a makomi, but sure it's also mug.
Speaker 1: Well Disney is anime I know right.
Speaker 1: and honey man anime is actually a French word if you want to get technical.
Speaker 0: so you know What is the standard we're gonna use?
Speaker 0: because because we are in geeks in the u.s.. Enjoy a great deal of Japanese culture.
Speaker 0: There is going to be many Japanese words that enter our vernacular And we're not gonna use them the same way the Japanese people do.
Speaker 0: we're gonna use them the way that is most useful to us.
Speaker 0: You know the way languages evolve and all that yeah And all languages are are symbols that represent ideas And it's up to people as a whole who use those symbols to represent ideas to decide which ideas are represented by which symbols.
Speaker 1: now the real interesting thing here is that one and A lot of people who have read Scott's email have to agree that you really would have had to go out of your way to take that much offense to a relatively benign question.
Speaker 1: and also, I would note that after a while she stops talking about all this argument and basically just starts ragging on the fact that we ran an anime club a long time ago and That we apparently have big penises.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe she I don't know they might they might be jealous of our gigantic otaku cocks.
Speaker 0: I've always gotten the feeling you know that maybe Clarissa didn't like us or something because we've Communicated a great deal with anime world order as a whole which is three people Gerald Darryl and Carilla.
Speaker 1: I mean the whole relationship started when I met Darryl at a con and he walks over to you with this little thing He's like you want to be recorded an interview podcast whatever and I was like I also do a podcast hello
Speaker 0: And you know mostly pretty much a hundred percent every time we talk to them It's either Darryl or Gerald talking back
Speaker 1: to us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Darryl and Gerald?
Speaker 1: all the time I talked to Darryl a lot and I didn't talk to Gerald a lot until after Otakon when we met and Pretty much the friendship was solidified in gold after they shot us in the face with clown pistols.
Speaker 0: Yeah But Clarissa never really talked to us And we never met her and I always got the feeling that either Maybe she just didn't want to talk to us or secretly hated us for some unknown reason.
Speaker 1: I would submit that she has been for the entirety of our existence Seething with both jealousy and rage and the two were in this bitter little ball And she would.
Speaker 1: I'll bet the next email we had sent to them would have elicited the same response you could have been.
Speaker 1: Hi guys I just wanted to say Clarissa's awesome And it would have been the same tirade that could have been could have been.
Speaker 0: she would have been like what's with the sarcastic email Saying I'm awesome.
Speaker 0: You say all kinds of stuff is awesome.
Speaker 0: And yeah, that means you hate it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all high and mighty with your RIT anime club just happens to have been the biggest anime club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, North America for number of years.
Speaker 0: The other thing is at the beginning of every anime world order they call themselves Holier-than-thou know-it-alls that or anything.
Speaker 0: But well, how can you yell at someone else for being a know-it-all when you proclaim it about yourself?
Speaker 0: That's sort of like saying man It's like a I don't know it.
Speaker 0: It's it's like a retarded person going up to someone and saying wow, you're retarded It's like you're making fun of yourself at the same time.
Speaker 1: now I also couldn't help.
Speaker 1: but pretty much at the part when she starts going on about do you know what these mean?
Speaker 1: Do you know what these words mean?
Speaker 1: and she says that a bunch more times?
Speaker 1: I just cut it out.
Speaker 1: But all I could picture was Napoleon Dynamite going surprised.
Speaker 1: You didn't know that gosh gosh.
Speaker 1: But anyway, since we don't want to dwell on that since we find it hilarious.
Speaker 1: We're not sure how many other people will find it hilarious, but in the news AFI Dallas, there's a one of the first movie reviews of paprika, which is we got to see it in one I don't even know.
Speaker 1: I just found a guy named Todd matter now ski.
Speaker 0: That's not fair.
Speaker 1: Well, he put this up on March 28th, that's really not fair.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that guy saw paprika way before us Asshole.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, does he even know what these movies mean?
Speaker 1: He talks about this movie in the reverent terms that I would expect someone to talk about this movie.
Speaker 1: He definitely definitely has the respect for Satoshi khan.
Speaker 1: He and I'm not gonna read the interview or the article.
Speaker 1: you can read it for yourself.
Speaker 1: But he basically says that paprika is really really really good and it uh-huh.
Speaker 1: It's a psychological thriller.
Speaker 0: Gee, I didn't see that one coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who would have guessed this?
Speaker 0: Satoshi khan the god of psychological thrillers the best person at it since I don't know I know he's not quite a Hitchcock, but he's I. just he's the new animated hit.
Speaker 0: We want to call me animated Hitchcock.
Speaker 0: might have to new dude now maybe on the back of the DVD for paprika They'll say, you know Satoshi khan is the animated Hitchcock geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's funny cuz I was just about to say that other than Hitchcock when you jumped in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've been on a Hitchcock kick for a while though lately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's got a good guy.
Speaker 0: everyone else out there.
Speaker 1: If you haven't seen every Hitchcock movie You should watch Just about every Hitchcock even the old ones because the new ones are really really really really really good and the old ones are either good or hilarious Or both.
Speaker 1: Yeah What was that when the man who knew too much with the dead?
Speaker 0: That's a good one the the the forty fifty nine steps forty nine steps.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many steps there were but I really was a number of steps.
Speaker 1: This was really good lady vanishes.
Speaker 0: I think is is man.
Speaker 0: It's a great best of the old ones.
Speaker 0: It's definitely Alright, so speaking of keiko takamiya and shoujo manga all that vertical Vertical the company that is putting out all the highbrow awesome mangas you should pretty much buy every manga They release as announced new manga woot.
Speaker 0: The first manga they have announced will come out in October.
Speaker 0: It is called Mu like mu mu by osama tessica.
Speaker 1: It might be mu mu.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's actually spelled like Mw.
Speaker 0: that's how it's spelled on the cover of the book.
Speaker 0: all right, but but it's pronounced mu mu mu whatever.
Speaker 1: Why did the cat fall off the slanted tin roof?
Speaker 1: Because he lost his mu.
Speaker 1: Yes mu being the coefficient of sliding friction.
Speaker 1: You see it's a physics chip.
Speaker 0: Yes well Anyway, it's a story of an unlikely union and forbidden love between an amoral banker and a priest.
Speaker 0: He set by guilt after they witnessed the massacre of a village.
Speaker 0: Aha, and that a government cover-up.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that this one's gonna be a lot like an ode to kira hito and not so much like Phoenix and not So much like Phoenix, so if you like the ode to kira hito's you're gonna want to buy this book in October.
Speaker 0: also They've announced Andromeda stories by keiko takamiya.
Speaker 0: It seems like people really wanted that other one by her.
Speaker 0: like the first Shonen I won whatever it was called the one that song wind and trees that one that one.
Speaker 0: That's the one that people really want, but actually I'm pretty happy They're bringing out this one because it's more sci-fi action.
Speaker 1: I pretty much want to read everything.
Speaker 1: She's written at this point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I'll buy whatever it whatever book this was they could have said it was like yeah Poop on a stick by keiko takamiya, and I would have still bought it.
Speaker 1: be the best damn poop on a stick ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that one's only gonna be $14, and I think it's also three volumes.
Speaker 0: So Good three volumes.
Speaker 1: I'm liking this not so long thing because I love here is Greenwood But as much as I love it over all these years I still haven't read the end because it's just.
Speaker 1: it's eight volumes, and that's not even a long manga, sir.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only way I can read I can't read a manga series.
Speaker 0: That's more than 20 volumes.
Speaker 0: Just period.
Speaker 0: I can't do it No matter no matter what.
Speaker 0: well, I guess initial D, but other than that.
Speaker 0: No I can't do it.
Speaker 1: See I couldn't even read initial D. I got one volume into that and said fuck this.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: And the only reason I could read initial D is because I do it one volume at a time every couple months.
Speaker 0: if you gave Me all of initial D at once.
Speaker 0: I just give you the finger.
Speaker 0: I'd be like no.
Speaker 0: I can't be done.
Speaker 0: Sorry, you know I mean granted Like 12 volumes is long.
Speaker 1: if somehow without compromising the pacing in the story Sanctuary had been 30 or 40 or 50 volumes long you probably just kept reading it in one straight.
Speaker 0: go Probably, but if it was all at once.
Speaker 0: I don't think I could could have done it.
Speaker 1: I think I could have.
Speaker 1: I think I could.
Speaker 0: I mean I have a hard enough time reading those big black marvel Essential books I get.
Speaker 1: uh I think there's a reason you have a hard time reading those more even the ones that I like.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, the third manga that they're releasing is the goo in saga Manga the seven magi by karu kurimoto.
Speaker 1: Did he done anything else?
Speaker 0: I never heard of this ever.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about it.
Speaker 0: I didn't research it I know nothing, but I think it's a fantasy and it deals with dragons and magi.
Speaker 0: Oh really Yep, I have been in a dragon dearth lately and people always talk about how you know anime fans.
Speaker 0: They like fantasy, but most anime tends to be sci-fi or not fantasy.
Speaker 0: What have been the last great fantasy anime?
Speaker 0: I mean obviously war eska flown a eska flown a twelve kingdoms.
Speaker 0: I didn't see that.
Speaker 1: I guess brave story the main stories fantasy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, definitely When you really get down to think about like you slayers.
Speaker 0: Yeah true, but if you ask someone like are there Rumono, I don't know if that really counts, but I think it does.
Speaker 0: anyway If you go up and ask someone like hey are there lots of fantasy anime that are awesome?
Speaker 0: someone will say yeah There are lots of awesome fantasy anime But then when you get down to counting them you can write them all on one piece of paper with big text.
Speaker 0: It's really not so many and even less that are really good, so if vertical thinks It's good.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, finally.
Speaker 0: We got a fantasy manga.
Speaker 1: That is the hotness I suppose, but Scott I thought you were a sexist who wouldn't read anything that girls wrote.
Speaker 1: so why are you excited about keiko's manga?
Speaker 0: Gee, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's cuz.
Speaker 0: uh I don't know.
Speaker 0: cuz it's awesome.
Speaker 1: Pitaka sui.
Speaker 1: gee.
Speaker 0: oh you got to start doing that.
Speaker 1: you remember way back We did a thing of the day where it was basically a bunch of these Rube Goldberg machine videos from this educational show on TV in Japan.
Speaker 1: Well that show has not failed to disappoint.
Speaker 1: aside from having those awesome awesome awesome shorts.
Speaker 1: They've also had these Algorithm dances.
Speaker 1: if you can't figure out what an algorithm dance would be I'd suggest you just watch this video And all will become clear rather quickly.
Speaker 1: continue watching and you will see what happens when you add ninjas to an algorithm dance.
Speaker 0: I get the feeling that this show is a lot like square one was to us.
Speaker 0: So I mean think about how far we've come if first we watch square one And then we wanted to watch square one But we couldn't and then we got the internet.
Speaker 0: so we searched for square one and we found it and now we're not satisfied.
Speaker 0: So we have to watch the Japanese equivalent of square one.
Speaker 1: It does make me happy.
Speaker 1: I remember as a kid like when the internet Remember used to not be able to find stuff like this.
Speaker 1: the ability to find video on the internet at all is A crazy new idea yet.
Speaker 1: We're already totally dependent on it.
Speaker 1: if YouTube disappeared.
Speaker 1: We wouldn't know what to do.
Speaker 0: All I gotta say is I really want to watch Russian square one.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes If you have to copy lists and one of them is executed in the back of the brother Anyway these things are about as amusing as the length of the video so just check it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's alright.
Speaker 0: I wasn't big a fan.
Speaker 1: I don't know I like stuff like this.
Speaker 1: I wish they would have been more complex But I have the feeling if they were more complex kids wouldn't be able to just figure them out and do them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well alright.
Speaker 0: I've been doing a lot of stuff involving old comics lately.
Speaker 0: You know I'm reading old Dick Tracy comics Reading.
Speaker 0: I just read cavalier and clay which is all about old comics and everyone should read that book.
Speaker 0: It's like my new favorite novel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah for those of you who think that American Comics just started it underwear perverts and stayed underwear perverts There is this whole era of detective stories and pirate stories.
Speaker 0: the comics really started as comic strips in the newspaper and But even back then Comics started out awesome in the u.s.. And then they got crappy and now they're getting awesome again mostly because manga is forcing the issue yes, and it was only crappy in the middle the long middle and Back in the day.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of people making comics in the early days.
Speaker 0: You know there was Will Eisner who's the best comics ever.
Speaker 0: there's Chester Gould the Dick Tracy guy.
Speaker 0: there were a bunch of other people too But one guy whose name keeps coming up but I didn't know anything about him is Milton Kniff or Milton Caniff can I FF?
Speaker 0: and He's famous for two things as far as I know.
Speaker 0: number one of them is Terry and the pirates Which I really want to read because it's pirates, but I can't find it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: a lot of things I have wanted to check out because they were pirates have turned out to be either at best a tenuous link to pirates or Absolutely god-awful.
Speaker 0: well no there.
Speaker 0: I can guarantee.
Speaker 1: This is not god-awful except for Polly and the pirates.
Speaker 0: yeah well right here I have my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: some guy was going through the the estate of Milton Caniff With his family because he's going to do a DVD release of the live-action Steve Canyon television series.
Speaker 0: that's the other thing he's famous for is the Steve Canyon comic in the newspaper and When he was there he found a bunch of inks of daily and Sunday Comic strips of Steve Canyon and with permission they've scanned them in and you can read them at this website.
Speaker 0: now Look at this for a second.
Speaker 0: look how awesome.
Speaker 0: This is.
Speaker 0: compare this to like I don't know 1960s Superman 1970s Spider-Man or 1980s Superman.
Speaker 1: 1990s Superman.
Speaker 0: yeah, this is like 1940s and 1930s 1950s like war comics.
Speaker 0: You know cowboys and navy guys and all that sort of stuff and you look at it, and he's just like wow Comics really went downhill didn't they?
Speaker 1: how did it go from that to the infinity identity gauntlet crisis whatever?
Speaker 0: Imagine if comics had gone from here and content.
Speaker 0: American comics had taken this and Continually improved instead of going downhill into the superhero crap shit, and that's like saying improving all the way until today.
Speaker 0: That's like saying imagine if Rome hadn't fallen and it continued on Rome hadn't fallen and we still had Roman concrete in Damascus.
Speaker 0: steel.
Speaker 0: how good these comics are.
Speaker 0: and Whether you're a fan of comics at all whether you were alive whether you've ever heard the name Milton Kenneth before whether you know Who Steve Canyon is it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: you should go and read?
Speaker 0: It's just like a handful of scanned in comic strips.
Speaker 0: There are three or four panels each.
Speaker 0: it won't give hurt you to take the 15 minutes to look at them And I just want everyone to see that old comics are Freaking awesome and superhero comics kind of suck.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes, I concur.
Speaker 1: So speaking of things that are awesome and things that suck a while ago We talked about how we were excited about this anime called Moonlight Mile.
Speaker 0: Yes, I download cuz I download pretty much.
Speaker 0: I go to anime ski every day and I subscribe to the RSS feed and if there's any show that has a number one that I haven't seen before or If there's a promo for a show I'll look up to see if the shows might be interesting and I'll watch a promo.
Speaker 0: it takes Five minutes why not?
Speaker 1: you also might remember that we used to review a lot of and well not review But I guess preview a lot of anime when one or two episodes came out just to talk about it and lately We've kind of been reviewing a lot of old stuff or things.
Speaker 0: That's because news shows stopped coming out.
Speaker 1: cuz we're in between Seasons now we also skipped a lot of those first episodes because they were all pretty bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know a new anime season is starting.
Speaker 0: if you go to anime ski right now there's like three or four number one episodes of new shows that are just being fansubbed.
Speaker 0: new anime are coming out people and We're gonna tell you which ones to watch and which ones did not even bother downloading.
Speaker 1: So there are certain genres in anime and manga.
Speaker 1: They're very much at least in the u.s.
Speaker 1: underrepresented.
Speaker 1: these are the genres that include such things as realistic mecha military conflicts Realistic military serious military conflict not you know gun and Gundam military conflict or gun parade march military Conflict yes political machinations and when I say political stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean gassaraki level because gossery level first president of Japan Eagle level.
Speaker 1: I mean if you think that Gundam wing or really any Gundam was actually a political show or a political manga No, gassaraki, which included giant robots was primarily about grain exports.
Speaker 0: Yep Yes, that's how political that shit is.
Speaker 0: but I mean the ghost in the shell also is kind of political.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's mostly about refugees.
Speaker 1: Yeah and ghost in the shell is right up our alley.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well a second gig anyway, the other parts of ghost Michelle and out of our refugees.
Speaker 0: They're about cyberspace, but they're also right up our.
Speaker 0: yes Oh, you watch the promotional clip for Moonlight Mile where they interviewed the you know The guys doing the anime and they showed a lot of clips from the show.
Speaker 0: and this show had all the following elements.
Speaker 0: You ready?
Speaker 0: politics robots space Mountain climbing mountain climbing badass people high to high Animation production values world politics and war.
Speaker 0: they showed Navy ships and big battles going on carriers and fighter jets and walking robots and flying Spaceships and factories on the moon.
Speaker 1: now most important is that astronauts it had and it was very obvious from this.
Speaker 1: It had that element that we loved so much that was in sanctuary and eagle and everything Where there's two men or two edges two people who together despite their different backgrounds have become friends and are now walking forward with their own two feet toward destiny.
Speaker 0: And we saw this promo and we said and that's gonna be a good show right there.
Speaker 1: Now consider this aside from just all the things that had the promo wasn't done.
Speaker 1: like a lot of the other promos We've seen it was high production value.
Speaker 1: The anime is obviously got a lot of backing behind it.
Speaker 1: It is definitely one of those high production.
Speaker 1: check this out.
Speaker 0: This is ah, well, it's based on a manga and I don't know much about the manga because there really isn't that much information.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was written by Yasuo Otagaki.
Speaker 0: Yep I saw it in the store because I was in the Japanese bookstore the last week and there are a lot of volumes of it which means this must be popular in Japan.
Speaker 0: and Just looking at the covers in the pages of the manga.
Speaker 0: It looked a lot like the anime.
Speaker 0: So that's all I can say about that.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Well the anime news network lists.
Speaker 1: This guy has having written Moonlight Mile the manga and Moonlight Mile the TV.
Speaker 1: He's credited as the creator of the manga on which it was based.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, that's good then.
Speaker 1: Yes But this promo aside from obviously making it known that this is the big production thing If anything, I'd guess that the manga was super popular and people have been looking forward to this in Japan for a while.
Speaker 1: But the promo gave us this feeling that rare feeling that this is gonna be one of those awesome show.
Speaker 0: I think the thing that really gave me a good feeling in the promo is they showed these two guys climbing Mount Everest and They showed that these guys on the top of Mount Everest could see space.
Speaker 0: They could see a space station and I was like, can you really see space for Mount Everest?
Speaker 1: and the scene was just done.
Speaker 1: so well you see these two men on the very top of the world and they've gotten there under Their own blood sweat got steel and they want to go higher.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not satisfied with that and they climb Mount Everest just to sit there and say I want to go up there.
Speaker 1: Yeah And then it cuts up and now space and that's where the show is actually gonna take place and it shut.
Speaker 1: the way it was Put together.
Speaker 1: there was no way this could be bad.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be the greatest anime ever made.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe not the greatest ever made but one of the greatest ever made.
Speaker 1: now I probably should have thought about this because I remember when this exact thing happened to us once before.
Speaker 0: when did it happen before?
Speaker 1: Well way back.
Speaker 1: We saw the promo for a movie called cash and The promotional trailer.
Speaker 0: I think it's called Casern Cas s h e r n.
Speaker 1: Well this but that was based on.
Speaker 1: well loosely based on Kishon or Kishon robot hunter Which is this god-awful anime?
Speaker 0: Yes, we didn't realize that at first.
Speaker 0: that was a trick cuz it was a different spelling.
Speaker 0: There was this great trailer for a live-action like sort of Japanese super action movie called Casern C a s s h e r n and we said that Trailer looks like the best movie ever made
Speaker 1: and we were excited about it and we were so excited
Speaker 0: with the high Expectation.
Speaker 1: it was one of those things where everyone we showed the trailer to said when is that coming out?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yes, it was like.
Speaker 0: I need to see that now.
Speaker 0: I need to see that yesterday ten times.
Speaker 0: Then it finally came out and we watched it and first thing we realized was oh, this is based on Robot hunter Casern C a s s a h n which again is one of the worst anime ever made one of the worst anime.
Speaker 0: And then we watched the movie and while it had lots of awesome special effects and the occasional But short action scene of awesome.
Speaker 0: It was pretty god-awful.
Speaker 1: Now we we've been bitten once by this and we didn't learn our lesson.
Speaker 0: There was no way I could relate moonlight mile to cuz haha.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I didn't relate to laugh to the fact.
Speaker 1: You see we were so excited about this and this promo made it look so awesome.
Speaker 1: I recommend if nothing else watch the promo to this and try to tell me this doesn't look like a great show Unless you're a crappy person.
Speaker 0: You don't like this sort of thing.
Speaker 1: So then we got a hold of episode 1 and the opening.
Speaker 1: See like the open at the opener the you know minute and 30-second thing.
Speaker 0: Thing that happens before the opener with the music like the prologue the thing that would say prologue on the DVD.
Speaker 0: it shows this woman on the moon and she's an astronaut and she's just astronauting around, you know.
Speaker 0: and Something I forget.
Speaker 0: something happens and it's no good and like her friend dies and she's alone.
Speaker 1: She's trapped on the moon.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a base on the moon and all this stuff, but she is too far away from anyone to get help.
Speaker 1: She's running out of oxygen.
Speaker 1: She's going to die.
Speaker 1: She knows of one place where there might be an oxygen tank or two Stash where she can maybe if she runs Crazily and practically killed herself from exhaustion can get there and survive for a few more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so pretty much she's dead.
Speaker 0: The only way she can possibly live is to run on the moon really fast Which you think would be easy because it's low gravity but it's actually pretty hard because you're wearing a heavy space suit that weighs hundreds of pounds and She starts running and jumping across the moon as fast as she can to get to this oxygen tank Which is the only way she can live.
Speaker 1: and she stumbles upon.
Speaker 1: this isn't a spoil.
Speaker 1: this happens right away.
Speaker 0: This is the first thing that happens in the show.
Speaker 1: She stumbles upon all this stuff.
Speaker 1: She comes over a ridge and there's stuff there.
Speaker 1: There's some sort of base There's all these century robots and she realizes immediately that she's just seen something that she was not supposed to see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's one thing if like the Apollo guys, you know They come with a little lunar land or whatever and then they see like a giant base.
Speaker 0: Now it's one thing if that base was put there by aliens and it's like oh an alien base.
Speaker 0: you have one sort of plot.
Speaker 0: what if that base is put there by some earth people and You're like the astronauts have this crap technology and someone else on earth has much better technology and it's on the moon already.
Speaker 0: Hey, no one knows about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah But you right now or even just along the lines of you've stumbled on to some sort of secret military thing that you weren't supposed to know about.
Speaker 0: yeah Running around in the desert and all of a sudden you were in area 51 and there were like stuff there that you weren't supposed to see.
Speaker 1: and This scene was really really well done.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's so great.
Speaker 0: Like as soon as I saw this scene I was like, oh, yeah That's what it's about and all of us are sitting around a while.
Speaker 1: This is actually gonna be a great anime and then the opening starts.
Speaker 1: the minute and 30 second music thing and the opener has the Most pump you up.
Speaker 1: This is going to be an epic political thriller music you've ever heard.
Speaker 0: I don't know the music actually in the opener.
Speaker 0: I don't think is that epic.
Speaker 1: Well, it's it pumps you up.
Speaker 1: It's definitely keeps you on edge.
Speaker 0: It does and the thing I think we're really is great about the opener is all the things they show you Because they basically show you all the stuff that you see.
Speaker 0: in the preview that we took that was so awesome is the showing you space and robots and Politics and aircraft carriers and people being badass climbing mountains and all that stuff is in the opener And you see that all and you go.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah This is the show because they're showing you all the stuff that you want to see and you're like.
Speaker 0: I can't wait to see all that some more now.
Speaker 1: Here's the.
Speaker 0: it's like a taste Early letting you lick the foie gras But then not feeding it to you.
Speaker 1: the earliest sign of trouble with this anime was that After all that the opener ends and the show starts that epic music pretty much keeps playing constantly in every scene and You know Sometimes music can build you to an emotional crescendo or can heighten a mood or pump you up a little bit or keep you on Edge.
Speaker 1: what if the music just doesn't stop and it's always just holding you on edge and keeping you in suspense And it just never lets up.
Speaker 0: I didn't really notice it after a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, until we watched the second episode and I noticed it through the whole thing because I was paying attention to it.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't even notice any music at all playing.
Speaker 0: I couldn't tell if you played the song for this show.
Speaker 0: I couldn't tell you really.
Speaker 1: the episode we just watched had epic music playing almost the entire time.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: if I think about it I'm like, yeah there was but I can't actually bring the music to my mind because it was not good or memorable at all.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it was kind of like if you're watching a movie the music they would play at the climax of an important action scene.
Speaker 1: It's just playing continuously throughout this show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they really should have called the the Hacksign noir person who does that music to do this show.
Speaker 1: music like that might have fit this show really?
Speaker 0: Well, I know.
Speaker 1: however all that aside it starts out much like you would expect with these two guys climbing Mount Everest and Backstories on them and all sorts of political thing.
Speaker 1: It kind of sets up the whole show in the first episode bit by bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the first episode is kind of weird.
Speaker 0: I've only seen two episodes but they were way different and the first episode obviously sort of touches on Every possible area of the plot a little bit so that anything they just jump into in the future You're not totally lost on.
Speaker 0: you know, it's like alright.
Speaker 0: Do you have these three or four plot lines?
Speaker 0: Maybe five?
Speaker 0: We're gonna start off each one of them But mostly we're gonna start off the big one Which is the two main characters who want to go into space and they climb Mount Everest.
Speaker 1: Yes, the basic plot as far as anyone will be able to tell you in this show Is that earth is typical earth and as always their energy it's in the future.
Speaker 0: So this high technology but not the too far off future.
Speaker 1: It's definitely the within our life the 20-somethings and They've discovered helium-3 on the moon, which they can now use in reactors to make energy.
Speaker 1: So the plan is to build nuclear reactors and mines on the moon and beam the power with microwaves back to the earth.
Speaker 0: That's the plan.
Speaker 1: now consider for a moment most anime.
Speaker 1: if they did something like that We just leave it at that and there'd be this plot semi unrelated to that in this show.
Speaker 1: You can already see where this is going a little bit because they treat it realistically.
Speaker 1: Alright, so we're going to spend massive effort to get a lot of energy from the moon.
Speaker 1: energy like that would marginalize a lot of Middle Eastern powers that currently have a stranglehold on the world's oil reserves.
Speaker 1: It would have great Sociopolitical ramifications.
Speaker 1: also the fact that only a few nations are flight our spaceflight capable.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, I'm currently in the real world.
Speaker 1: How many countries have the resources to go to the moon at all let alone do anything then?
Speaker 0: we can't even remember how to get There.
Speaker 0: we could do it in the 60s.
Speaker 0: We can't do it now.
Speaker 1: So this is obviously a huge huge huge deal and that is kind of where the plot is going.
Speaker 1: But the plot initially follows more these two guys the main characters climbing Mount Everest in their goal to eventually go into space.
Speaker 0: Yes, basically you have these two guys and all they do is they were mountain climbers.
Speaker 0: They wanted to go higher and higher and by the time one of them was like 22 years old They climbed the highest mountain on every continent.
Speaker 0: It was like oh where the you know They couldn't get any better.
Speaker 0: and then they in the first episode they climb Everest and it's like ah shits and it's like oh Where are we gonna go from here?
Speaker 0: Well, we have to go to space where there are no limits.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now the two men.
Speaker 1: it's one of those typical tropes of.
Speaker 0: one of them is a Japanese guy Goro and the other one kind of silly And he likes to drink a lot Women eyes.
Speaker 1: he likes to be naked.
Speaker 0: He likes to be naked.
Speaker 0: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: See, this is this is where the show really takes a turn.
Speaker 1: I'm really interested in the show.
Speaker 1: I think it has a lot of potential.
Speaker 1: However, one Goro is more naked more often Than is necessary to the plots to.
Speaker 1: the other guy is like this Boring straight man lost a man is the American and he's the smooth cool.
Speaker 1: Hello.
Speaker 1: I am the American Yeah, but it's like I've pilot fighter jets for a living.
Speaker 0: It's like Goro is like the cool nor normal Ish guy you can kind of relate to but he's kind of weird naked all the time.
Speaker 0: So you don't really want to relate to him.
Speaker 1: He's like a caricature of a really manly guy and they go a little too far with it.
Speaker 1: So it's not just like oh, he's a ladies man, but they continually show him having sex with women.
Speaker 0: yeah, and lost man is like Stereotypical like hard-ass doesn't say anything.
Speaker 0: He's like the Terminator.
Speaker 0: all see now.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's gonna be an issue because we've only seen two episodes.
Speaker 1: episode one set up the whole show.
Speaker 1: Episode two all about Goro.
Speaker 1: I'm almost certain that episode three is all about lost men.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it is.
Speaker 0: how could it not be?
Speaker 0: if it wasn't the show would make no sense.
Speaker 0: But it seems like with the show.
Speaker 0: I think the major problem I have with the show is that it tries to do a whole lot in a small amount of space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this might be mitigated later on but the first episode especially crammed like eight episodes worth of stuff and ideas into one episode.
Speaker 0: yeah episode two basically took Goro from Finishing climbing Mount Everest - yes now you can go into space in one episode.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa.
Speaker 0: That was a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: usually an anime would drag that out.
Speaker 0: It's like three episodes being like.
Speaker 0: is he gonna get into space?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there were definitely points in the episode where I thought wow this was a normal anime.
Speaker 1: They would have spent a couple episodes on that right there.
Speaker 0: I guess it's better than what some anime do where they have a big long story They want to tell and not so many episodes.
Speaker 0: So they either just cut it short and leave you hanging or they cram.
Speaker 0: They'll go at a normal pace and then cram the whole rest of it.
Speaker 0: It's like one episode.
Speaker 1: It's unintelligible Scrap princess where the entire show all of the plot took place after the eye catch in the last episode And like Beck Mongolian chop squad, which the the manga is actually really really good.
Speaker 0: But the anime which is equally good crammed there like they did 26 episodes of plot at the normal pacing and then After the end of the 26 episode during the credits they took the entire rest of the manga and crammed it into that Epilogue while the credits were rolling.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: The thing is the pace isn't bad.
Speaker 1: I mean this pace is working for me so far because every time I start to lose interest in anything that's going on at all Immediately the plot has progressed a little bit.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: However, I think the point where we really started to question it was during the first episode where everything's going along normally.
Speaker 1: I'll be a little confused Lee and then I think it was right.
Speaker 1: after the eye catch the show reopens With what looks like an orgy.
Speaker 0: for a second I had to go back and watch it cuz they didn't understand what the hell was going on or why there was an orgy.
Speaker 0: I didn't want it.
Speaker 0: Don't confuse it for wanting to see the orgy again.
Speaker 0: Ah, that's the easy joke to make.
Speaker 1: We're all sitting there.
Speaker 1: Was that a bunch of Sherpas having sex?
Speaker 0: I think that was a bunch of Sherpas having sex and we just go back and it's basically Goro having sex with a Sherpa girl and then lost men having sex with a Sherpa girl and they're right next to each other and they Have giant like Zangief style muscles.
Speaker 1: I don't know why all the men seem to have giant Zangief style.
Speaker 1: much.
Speaker 1: The thing is this does remind me in a lot of ways of like sanctuary in terms of what goes on and the pacing and I Mean, there's all this sexually charged content and especially in the second episode You'll often have characters having a conversation while they're having sex and they just show it pretty much straight up.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean sometimes you know I'm not against characters having sex and a lot of times it makes sense like in sanctuary pretty much all the time There's a sexy scene.
Speaker 0: It makes sense.
Speaker 1: Oh, you mean like the time where the creepy old politician says come ma Asami mount this woman with me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, prove that you have the guts to be a politician.
Speaker 0: That's a very important scene because of what he says right after that which is you know Hojo has to do things 10,000 times worse than this.
Speaker 0: and then you see hojo just sitting there like living it up Living it up with a cigar and drink.
Speaker 0: It's a hilarious joke.
Speaker 0: That's why it's necessary.
Speaker 0: But in this a lot of it seems kind of unnecessary.
Speaker 0: Like they didn't even say anything about the Sherpa sex and only upon thinking about it you realize oh There in case they die on Everest is one last fuck and actually the ball.
Speaker 1: it all really makes sense And it's done pretty well.
Speaker 1: and that idea that they live in life to the fullest they might die.
Speaker 1: So they're gonna do everything they can to enjoy their last day just in case.
Speaker 1: yeah And it's pretty.
Speaker 0: I mean as deep thing is they just kind of throw that orgy in there.
Speaker 0: You don't realize what it is unless you think about it and maybe watch it again.
Speaker 0: Like it was so quick but I guess it wasn't.
Speaker 0: I Never realized who was fucking who I just like.
Speaker 0: Oh my god norgy.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just popped out of nowhere like orgies tend to I guess.
Speaker 1: Now the thing is the second episode.
Speaker 1: There's two characters and other characters having sex and it's actually I really like the relationship between these two characters.
Speaker 1: They're obviously lovers yet at the same time But he starts out like the guy seems like he's using this woman to get ahead and this woman is like his spy And he has power over her.
Speaker 1: but then very quickly it is revealed that she is also Using him and as it says so she's like yeah, I'm using you also and she has equal power over him.
Speaker 1: They both have power over each other and blackmail and everything and they're both relying on each other.
Speaker 1: and it's like the most stereotypical.
Speaker 1: Yet well done marriage or alliance of convenience But yet.
Speaker 0: Alright, so there has also an alliance of convenient evil.
Speaker 1: So they're having sex.
Speaker 1: Alright, no big deal.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of scenes in sanctuary where two people are having sex while they talk about politics and it usually makes sense but then very shortly after there's another scene where they're in a hot tub now and they're still talking and While they don't say anything.
Speaker 1: It's so obvious that she was giving him an underwater blowjob.
Speaker 1: That is painful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I didn't need to know that you've already established that they're lovers.
Speaker 1: You've already established that there is a sexually charged relationship between these two.
Speaker 1: You don't need to keep showing them having sex Three more times during the episode.
Speaker 0: I get it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I get it.
Speaker 1: Oh guru is a crazy guy.
Speaker 1: likes to wear his underwear and have sex with women.
Speaker 1: I don't need to see him plowing some girl during his break in the crane more than one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, granted the fact that that girl became a little bit plotted later was kind of cool.
Speaker 0: It did redeem that scene a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically they're looking for Goro because they can't find him and eventually the woman who knows about him.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: if you realize that it's the same woman It's not as funny But it looks like she just goes to where he works looks around sees a woman and says where's girl hanging out?
Speaker 1: Like she's like that woman would just know because obviously girl has had sex with that woman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I think the thing with Moonlight Mile is that it has all the elements of a show.
Speaker 0: That should be the awesomest show but Because of the way it's done so far after watching the first two episodes, you know, I'd be willing to watch more.
Speaker 0: I might like to watch more.
Speaker 0: I hope that in the rest of the episodes.
Speaker 0: it goes more towards the serious political thing that the Trailer promised.
Speaker 0: but I'm just not feeling too strongly about it.
Speaker 1: the thing is every they're set up to do everything right and If I if I'm right in assuming that the manga is actually very popular and good then my best guess is that?
Speaker 1: The people doing it are trying to establish all the backstory as quickly as possible In order to then spend as much time as they can on the meat of the show because there's obviously a lot of meat there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I saw at least 20 volumes in the store.
Speaker 1: So yes, and the trailer alone gives you 15 or 16 solid pieces of meat that you're waiting for.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm actually.
Speaker 0: I kind of hope they bring the manga out in English.
Speaker 0: Oh, I do too cuz the next time an anime company asks what manga they should bring out in English.
Speaker 0: as for Moonlight Mile
Speaker 1: I'll also be very interested to see if and when this gets licensed because if it is as high production value or at least as Big as I'm guessing it will be in Japan Then I bet that the company involved is probably not going to want it licensed in the u.s Very quickly because that would of course entail a lot of re-importation of our cheap $20 American DVDs.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that this anime doesn't seem like the kind of thing that would be licensed in the u.s.
Speaker 1: And that's what I hate about living in America.
Speaker 1: all the manga.
Speaker 1: I want all the anime.
Speaker 1: I really want never come out here.
Speaker 0: Yeah They only bring out you know The same shoujo stuff and the same shonen fighting stuff that they always bring out.
Speaker 0: and they bring all that stuff out right away no matter what it is.
Speaker 0: and The stuff that might potentially be cool, or you know somehow Political.
Speaker 1: go to a Japanese bookstore and look in certain sections you'll see an entire wall of manga that look like they're just cool.
Speaker 1: yakuza guys talking to each other and shooting people or Politicians arguing.
Speaker 0: I saw a golf manga beat that beat that I don't know if that's quite in league with yakuza guys Looked like a serious like.
Speaker 0: you know manga for you know you know 40 year old golf players.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, I also saw manga that was about like 50 year old people romance.
Speaker 0: You don't see the 50 year old romance.
Speaker 1: all you see is the teen romance cuz that's not gonna sell to the 14 to 14 and a half year old demographic that the manga publishers in America seem to be rooting for right now.
Speaker 0: Would you read the 50 year old people romance?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I might.
Speaker 1: you never know.
Speaker 1: it might be good.
Speaker 0: Has anyone ever tried to release that kind of stuff?
Speaker 1: has anyone ever tried?
Speaker 1: I mean sanctuary and eagle were both released in the u.s.
Speaker 1: And I think it's one of the greatest crimes in manga publishing in the u.s.
Speaker 1: To date that they have not been re-released.
Speaker 0: well It's cuz when they originally brought anime and manga over.
Speaker 0: you know it's all about the violence and the sex and the oMG Japanimation.
Speaker 1: yeah check this out.
Speaker 1: cartoons can be violent and horrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean sanctuary and all that stuff was a recent originally released as comic books.
Speaker 0: the same format is all the shitty underwear perfect comics.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: every month another issue would come out and that's how they were sold.
Speaker 0: they were sold in comic book stores to comic book fans in the 90s and It didn't work out so well.
Speaker 0: And that's why they stopped doing it that way.
Speaker 0: and then when Tokyo pop and everyone started doing manga the new way they did it with the shoujo manga and things and That's what made the big money.
Speaker 0: so rather than risk it and try different genres They just stick with one the whole time, and it's kind of annoying.
Speaker 1: yeah We talked about this yesterday with the video game industry too about how risk-averse pretty much Every industry in the world is becoming lately.
Speaker 1: I mean it's true of video games It's true of at least American anime publishing and manga publishing yeah And it's it's pretty much turned into where you know.
Speaker 0: back in the day Nobody would think about buying something to support it.
Speaker 0: like that whole lot.
Speaker 0: that idea of buying something Just to you know help the company out or vote for certain sorts of products.
Speaker 0: I didn't exist like until the recent years.
Speaker 0: I never had heard that idea before.
Speaker 0: and now it's sort of sort of like.
Speaker 0: yeah if vertical puts out a manga You should buy it because that's where the awesome manga are and if you want more awesome manga We're gonna have to buy it or else.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna get any.
Speaker 1: oh well Maybe the tide will turn for the time being.
Speaker 1: if you like that sort of thing or any of the stuff We've talked about at least check out Moonlight Mile.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's definitely worth your time to watch the trailer, and if you like the trailer It's worth it to watch the first episode.
Speaker 1: just be warned that while it may be very good, and I'm not sure yet I'll have to see pretty much the whole show to be able to pass judgment on it because I'm Really really torn as to the whole time.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking do I like this?
Speaker 1: I like where it's going, but do I like it right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: yeah The only thing this show doesn't have is it doesn't give me that feeling that I need of.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah I just sit there, and I watch it, and I go.
Speaker 0: I just saw everything I wanted to see but I don't have any good feelings about it, but I don't have any bad feelings either Yeah, but at the same time how few shows ever in any job anything any medium not just anime.
Speaker 1: Give us that feeling.
Speaker 1: uh All the awesome ones yeah, but there aren't that many.
Speaker 1: no there really are.
Speaker 1: it's hard to find things that really transcend any medium Or genre or whatever and become one of those shows that you remember that you want to watch again.
Speaker 1: I mean escaflowne because we mentioned it earlier.
Speaker 1: That's a show that I liked so much that I've seen it a few times and someday I plan to watch it again.
Speaker 1: Just because I enjoyed it that much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think I'll ever watch Moonlight Mile again.
Speaker 0: I don't think so, but I'm gonna watch it once.
Speaker 0: I might watch it once I.
Speaker 1: I think I'm committed to watching it all the way through, but just be warned that this is not like other anime.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna look like what you expect.
Speaker 1: it's not gonna be paced the way you expect.
Speaker 1: the scenes aren't gonna be the kind of scenes you'll expect and That may or may not be a good thing.
Speaker 1: so give it a chance.
Speaker 1: if you like this sort of thing I'm sorry There's not much more of it out there.
Speaker 1: if you hate this sort of thing go back to watching Dragon Ball Naruto bleach
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh, and I guess this actually if you're the kind of person who listens to geek nights on Wednesday but you're not particular in the anime fan and This might be a show for you because it doesn't have a lot of the anime stereotypes
Speaker 1: in fact It has almost none of them.
Speaker 1: it has some manga stereotypes, but they're stereotypes from manga that many of you've never read.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it doesn't matter like hey Everybody's getting drunk, and then they draw a red line across their face and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: It's stuff that you're not gonna notice it.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna see.
Speaker 1: ah Sweat drop anime blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: You're just gonna see huh stylized guys doing stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep politics.
Speaker 1: Oh This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.