Speaker 1: It's Tuesday December 18th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: We review St.. Petersburg.
Speaker 1: Let's do
Speaker 0: this
Speaker 1: Alright, so back when the local gaming scene was a little bit better than it is now You know we met some cool people and one time we went over and played some games with this guy who was Much harder core into gaming than we were but much less core into other things that we were into like.
Speaker 1: I guess he wasn't a Big anime fan.
Speaker 1: you might have liked anime.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: we didn't know him that well.
Speaker 1: We knew well enough to go and play some board games with him because you don't really have to know someone that well to do that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, he was telling us about all these games.
Speaker 1: We didn't know about.
Speaker 0: yeah, meanwhile We're all playing shadows over Camelot and getting totally punked by the traitor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know that's a game Where.
Speaker 1: well let's not talk about that game now, but He showed us this game called dune.
Speaker 1: Yes, dune the same dune is written by By who?
Speaker 0: Scott Herbert Frank Herbert.
Speaker 1: yes, right that am I right, okay?
Speaker 1: Let me just let me tell you my dune situation here.
Speaker 1: I tried to read dune because I knew it was some famous sci-fi book way back way back like Probably between middle and high school or some long time 1965 something like that and I was not the fan and I didn't even finish reading the first book.
Speaker 1: And I'm pretty sure is the first book because it was just called dune and nothing else, and I was not a fan.
Speaker 1: Nowadays, I don't really remember it that well.
Speaker 1: so who knows if I'm a fan, but then again I'm not about to find out.
Speaker 1: cuz I got better things to do.
Speaker 1: then Read a book that I probably won't like cuz I didn't like it the last time.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've changed that much anyway.
Speaker 0: We'll probably get some hate mail.
Speaker 0: We got an email not too long ago from someone.
Speaker 0: it was one of those YTM n DS And it was crying Fremen, but it was crying Freeman.
Speaker 1: Yeah Blue eyes and this music playing and it said crying Fremen on it on top and I was like.
Speaker 1: He told me that it was a combination joke between dune and crying Freeman, and I was like.
Speaker 0: that much was obvious.
Speaker 1: The problem was is that rim has read some dune, but read not crying Freeman.
Speaker 1: And I've read all of crying Freeman, but not the dune.
Speaker 1: so we needed luckily our friends.
Speaker 1: We're here to help us combine to get the joke of course.
Speaker 0: then I looked at it And it's just the crying Freeman guy with blue eyes crying.
Speaker 1: yeah anyway so dune which I'm not a fan of.
Speaker 1: but The guy shows us the dune game, which is a Avalon Hill bookshelf game from 1979. the game is older than me now.
Speaker 0: I'm not much of a collector or anything like that.
Speaker 0: I mean we had a friend way back who brought over like a 1912 era board game that we played.
Speaker 1: it was a bad game.
Speaker 0: of course it was a bad game But at the same time it was interesting just to see this ancient thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as much it was the kind of thing you that would be.
Speaker 1: do just as well in like a glass case in museum.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the kind of thing they hungry Joe would have been playing as a kid exactly.
Speaker 1: so so this dune game.
Speaker 1: He we don't actually play the game when we meet the guy But he tells us all about it.
Speaker 1: first of all obviously it's out of print because it's incredibly old and no one would want such A thing, but the way the interesting thing about the game is I think there's six different sides that you can be all the different You know races.
Speaker 1: I guess that are involved in on the planet.
Speaker 0: well factions more like factions.
Speaker 1: all right and Each faction has a different power.
Speaker 1: But he he started to tell us the powers of the different factions.
Speaker 1: He told us the power of the first faction, and I'm like that is.
Speaker 1: I don't even know how the game worked at all But I could tell from his description of the power of the faction that it was totally unfair and stupidly powerful.
Speaker 1: It's like imagine if there were different factions.
Speaker 1: You could be a monopoly and I'd be like yeah, monopoly the top hat gets to roll four dice instead of two.
Speaker 1: you go fuck.
Speaker 1: No, that is so unfair.
Speaker 1: fuck that Top hat.
Speaker 0: every time he proceeds to tell us what the powers are of all the rest of the factions The dog starts with twice as much money The car starts with boardwalk monopoly and eight hotels.
Speaker 1: the battleship gets hotels for a dollar each.
Speaker 1: That's the game and the idea of a game with six different sides where each side You know it basically plays by the same rules, but they each have a ludicrous, but different superpower.
Speaker 1: That sounds like a good game, and it's it's a lot different from a lot of other games We played and after I've read the rules last night.
Speaker 1: basically I bought the game on eBay because it was very hard to buy and I managed to get a used copy for like 45 bucks Which is a steal because I tried to bid on like a new copy and it went for like 120 something.
Speaker 0: yeah I went back to millennium games because that's pretty much our.
Speaker 0: if we ever need a game We can always get it from those guys.
Speaker 0: And I got the owner and the managers business cards, and I go in and I'm like hey I'm looking for a somewhat rare out-of-print game And he's like hit me the dune game.
Speaker 0: He laughs and says no one who knows what that is would sell it.
Speaker 0: the game's great.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the game you can buy it on eBay.
Speaker 1: There are a bunch of copies there, but I got a Surprisingly good condition used copy with all the pieces For like 45 bucks, and I read the rules last night.
Speaker 0: It smells a little bit like grandma, but that's okay.
Speaker 1: That's fine That's fine, and I read the rules and I can tell you this game The only game that I find it really similar to is diplomacy.
Speaker 1: in a way cuz there's you can like bribe anyone with almost you know no restrictions and at almost at any time and They have to do whatever.
Speaker 0: the bribe was A game that allows that.
Speaker 0: I mean you can do that monopoly.
Speaker 0: you can do that in a lot of games But a game that actually has mechanics or requires people to follow through on deals Yep is a lot more interest.
Speaker 1: you can also make alliances and have joint victories But you can only make and break alliances at certain junctures in the game.
Speaker 1: and the third thing I'm gonna tell you about this game cuz I already told you three things.
Speaker 1: I guess there's a fourth thing.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you about the game fanatical devotion to the Pope.
Speaker 1: yes Yes for four things all right.
Speaker 1: the the other interesting thing about this game is you most games It's like information is either you show it or you don't write like Antigris and Euphrates.
Speaker 1: You don't show your tiles you don't show your points.
Speaker 1: It's not like you know but in monopoly you show your money.
Speaker 1: you show what properties you have right?
Speaker 1: In Dune most of your stuff you can choose to show or not to show.
Speaker 1: There's only one thing I think these treachery cards because there's a limit of four.
Speaker 1: I think we're at a certain point in the game Which is the point at which you can get more treachery cards you have to show how many you have so that way There's no cheating, but other than that I think you don't have to show.
Speaker 1: so it's I really like that that you can show or not show.
Speaker 0: Well, we've been partly because we don't have the you know five people around all the time to play the big five and six player games that we haven't exhausted yet, we've exhausted two and three player gaming and We need more games and get.
Speaker 0: and it seems like eventually we're gonna get to the point where the only games that are really Not solved or not broken or not random are the games that are.
Speaker 0: basically The game is just the setting and the actual game is more like diplomacy where you're gaming the other people you're playing directly Against other people where the stakes are kind of more up in the air.
Speaker 1: well I think you know what games like this game and diplomacy are is they're sort of like board games But they're really sort of role-playing games But also psychology games and you know the it's just you're.
Speaker 1: you're doing role-playing in Psychology in an attempt to manipulate the board.
Speaker 0: now granted rather
Speaker 1: than just manipulating the board directly with role-playing in psychology not mattering
Speaker 0: I've been known to do that sort of thing in say Shogun,
Speaker 1: but yeah There's a line where it sort of like goes from metagaming to role-playing and it's sort of like diplomacy and doing around one side And show guns on the other side.
Speaker 0: yeah, but regardless.
Speaker 0: I'm very much looking forward to playing this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though.
Speaker 1: I don't like dune.
Speaker 1: I'm sure this game will be cool at least from what I've read.
Speaker 0: So what do you got in the news since?
Speaker 0: uh?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's such a bad news week.
Speaker 1: You have no idea.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of good news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the how come it took you so long to find a news story, and I found one before you did.
Speaker 0: well There's plenty of good news, but there's not.
Speaker 0: I've already talked about all of it.
Speaker 0: I mean oh the Wii is selling out.
Speaker 1: host that's gonna be your news.
Speaker 1: You better not.
Speaker 0: the ps3 isn't selling out.
Speaker 1: Oh snap anyway, so there was announcement today or recently that there's gonna be all sorts of like better games on the iPod.
Speaker 1: You know and that's not surprising cuz yeah, there's there's new iPods out like they came out recently.
Speaker 1: they have better screens and better stuff all around and So that I think there's games like you know peggle and Sonic the Hedgehog.
Speaker 1: you're gonna come to the iPod.
Speaker 0: Sonic the Hedgehog is the one that got my attention here.
Speaker 1: Yeah now You know that I guess this you know something to be said for this and that there's a lot of iPods out there possibly even More iPods than DS.
Speaker 1: is that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: it's it's pretty close.
Speaker 1: I'd have to.
Speaker 1: I imagine there's more iPods But I don't know if more of the new iPods that are capable of playing Sonic the Hedgehog.
Speaker 1: We got to see.
Speaker 1: So it makes sense that you know someone to try to make and sell games for a device capable of playing them and You know try to make a lot of money that that makes sense.
Speaker 1: What doesn't make sense to me at least is why anyone would ever actually want to play a game on their iPod now?
Speaker 0: It's not just a matter of oh well What if you are just a casual gamer and maybe you don't have a DS even though you probably should especially if you're a casual gamer?
Speaker 0: but yep To me playing a game on like an iPod is just So unfun and not worth it that I'd rather be doing something else.
Speaker 0: It's like if I'm gonna kill time I might as well read a book or something because it's just not worth it to play a game on these not gaming consoles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like it if you have a camera right a cam imagine if you have a digital camera is designed to take pictures.
Speaker 1: It's possible.
Speaker 1: a digital camera has a screen and buttons.
Speaker 1: you could theoretically I see no reason why not write some software to play a video game on your digital camera.
Speaker 1: But because the design of the digital camera is such that playing the game would be so uncomfortable and painful.
Speaker 1: It's not even worth it.
Speaker 1: It's not something you would want to do It's it's.
Speaker 1: I'd rather play no video game at all then play a video game in such a painful way.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, so I think part of the reason people do play games on this is because they're probably people who don't have any gaming systems and They carry their iPod with them anyway And they're bored and they don't fee.
Speaker 1: I guess they might.
Speaker 1: they might be the kind of person who feels ashamed Whipping out a DS or something But they don't feel ashamed whipping out their iPod and pushing buttons on now.
Speaker 0: now I point out that this This brings up another.
Speaker 0: It was kind of tangential issue that I've noticed on the train a lot because I like you and like many other people in this Country take a train to work every day.
Speaker 0: I have a long commute where I'm sitting in a chair relatively comfortable, but there's nothing to do unless I bring something mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: and Almost every day I get on that train and I see a lot of bored people Without any form of entertainment on them whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Just sitting there really bored.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I see some people like they read a newspaper, but then they finish it.
Speaker 1: I see some people with a book, you know, there's plenty of people who do do some.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but there are a lot of people who don't.
Speaker 1: yes, it's Alma I might say it's like 40%.
Speaker 1: don't do anything.
Speaker 1: It's not as nice like look out the window.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and now you can argue some of them are sleeping.
Speaker 0: sleeping is okay No, but I can get to that too cuz I have a neck pillow and I sleep very comfortably on the train with earplugs and a neck pillow.
Speaker 0: I've seen one other person in the entirety of the time I've been commuting to New York City with any sort of pillow or anything to know.
Speaker 0: I see there's a good like handful of people but not not many most people who sleep that like their neck is just bent.
Speaker 1: Most people sleeping are just bent sideways, but there are people who have like, you know The little little mask so light doesn't get in their eyes.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Okay, that's a little too much.
Speaker 1: The earplugs in the neck pillow are enough.
Speaker 1: I take the 5-30 fucking train in I'm gonna sleep you can sleep and there's nothing wrong with sleeping on the train.
Speaker 0: But I think the the eye covering mask thing is too because then I don't have the light because sometimes the lights are on in The train.
Speaker 1: yeah, I don't like it.
Speaker 1: I wish there was a way to dig have.
Speaker 1: they should have one car in the train with the lights up.
Speaker 0: a lot of times They do but I don't know if that's usually by accident.
Speaker 0: But the issue is there are a lot of people who I see and there are people who aren't Entertaining themselves every moment because maybe they want to think or relax.
Speaker 0: But I know a lot of these people because I can see them fidget and see them just look around or like.
Speaker 0: they start watching The screen the silent screen of the DVD player that someone two seats up from them has and they just obviously they're bored out of their minds.
Speaker 0: They knew they were gonna be on a train.
Speaker 0: Why didn't they bring some form of entertainment.
Speaker 0: Why do people not think of that?
Speaker 1: I don't know I don't know.
Speaker 0: and as a result, I think a lot of.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of people playing just like they'll have their cell phone Out.
Speaker 0: they'll be playing like that broken pac-man that comes with a lot of shitty phones.
Speaker 0: That just doesn't even work.
Speaker 1: That pac-man is just so bad.
Speaker 1: It's not even fun.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's it's worse than no pac-man.
Speaker 0: It's worse than doing nothing.
Speaker 0: I see people doing things that I rather than doing now.
Speaker 1: I had a choice between sitting on the train and playing the shit Cellphone pac-man or sitting there bored.
Speaker 1: I would sit there bored because playing the cell phone pac-man is painful.
Speaker 1: It's like it's that would be like torture if someone made me play the cell phone pac-man.
Speaker 1: So I imagine Sonic the Hedgehog iPod is quite similar to that.
Speaker 0: But at the same time this I mean these are games like Sonic where you're gonna have to buy it, right?
Speaker 0: It's not just gonna be free.
Speaker 1: It's like five bucks on iTunes or something like that.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know exactly the cost but I guess it's five bucks.
Speaker 0: Who are they marketing to?
Speaker 0: I mean I'm.
Speaker 0: I would guess the only people who buy this are people who have an iPod and then they the idea of having a video Game on their iPod just makes them get all wet.
Speaker 1: Could be.
Speaker 1: actually, you know, the peggle doesn't isn't a game that would be too bad on the iPod.
Speaker 1: But even so peggle is a game that really needs more screen real estate and maybe on the iPhone It would work.
Speaker 0: but on the iPod, especially the nano Small this I would make the argument beyond that that peggle is not a game.
Speaker 0: It is merely a Carl a colorful time waster.
Speaker 0: There is no amount of skill in that.
Speaker 1: No, that's not a game of skill at all.
Speaker 1: It's just it's like pachinko, but I think the iPhone though I think games on the iPhone are pretty could be pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's got that big dual touch screen.
Speaker 0: Oh, you can basically run computer games on the iPhone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 1: We're talking about iPod here.
Speaker 1: I phone is actually a good gaming platform.
Speaker 1: I think and I think that is a a route that Apple should really Explore in greater depth.
Speaker 0: I just never understand why I see these people playing these chintzy games.
Speaker 0: They either Obviously didn't plan ahead and now are bored They have no form of entertainment or for whatever reason they just choose not to carry a form of entertainment.
Speaker 1: Also, those games are horrendously overpriced.
Speaker 1: on my Verizon phone is actually like a Phoenix Wright game I can buy right and I thought about buying it just good to play every Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: But I'm pretty sure it's just one of the episodes from Phoenix Wright one.
Speaker 1: So I don't really want it because I've already played it on the DS, but it's so.
Speaker 1: I've seen screenshots of it.
Speaker 1: It's just so bad and they charge like five bucks for it.
Speaker 1: And you know what for like five dollars on the virtual console I can get a whole Nintendo game.
Speaker 1: that's better than the cell phone Phoenix Wright.
Speaker 1: So it's just a ripoff.
Speaker 0: So in other news the the Wii is selling out.
Speaker 1: Oh gee, that's been news for like.
Speaker 1: since I bought one last year on the launch day I just I Guess I didn't.
Speaker 0: I mean I expected the Wii to do well and the fact that it's doing as well as it is is far Beyond what I expected.
Speaker 0: I'm not entirely sure what's gonna come of all this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just another tickle me almost situation.
Speaker 0: You'll see it is the thing is next year.
Speaker 1: There'll be plenty of them.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I know there'll be plenty of them.
Speaker 0: It's not like there's gonna be this perpetual shortage forever.
Speaker 0: But the thing is the Wii is selling like crazy and it's gonna keep selling like crazy for a long time and it's pretty much Probably going to be all told the number one console in terms of people who own one.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 0: DS is still ahead cut well home console.
Speaker 0: The DS is separate the DS is special All right, and PC doesn't count either.
Speaker 0: So think about that.
Speaker 0: basically Nintendo now is going to have the number one and the number two in terms of Units out there with people who will buy games in the world
Speaker 1: Which means game companies the third parties despite their hating of Nintendo will be forced to Make games for the Nintendo systems in order to.
Speaker 0: I do point out though a lot of franchises that shy away from Nintendo.
Speaker 0: I You also see a lot of those really crappy third-party people who make as many Gameboy and Wii games as they can possibly make at every possible moment every license every franchise every cats dolphins pigs whatever the next game is and every kids cartoon.
Speaker 0: you've ever heard of even the really obscure ones and I gotta say I think they have a much better racket going than a lot of these.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm a like Activision when they're like, oh, yeah, Nintendo consoles.
Speaker 0: We don't dig that anymore We don't it's not our bag.
Speaker 1: Well video games is a really weird situation like the market right now.
Speaker 1: I mean look look at the movie theater.
Speaker 1: right the movie theater.
Speaker 1: You've got these people.
Speaker 1: They're spending lots and lots of money on Movies that are large, you know, not all of them but blockbuster movies.
Speaker 1: They're generally mass appeal.
Speaker 1: You know low brow or lower brow than typical, but I'm quite low brow All right.
Speaker 1: Generally low brow on average.
Speaker 1: big budgets big profits big on the special effects and the fanciness of the mass appeal Right in in the art house movie theater.
Speaker 1: You've got the low budgets Relatively higher brow right more critically acclaimed type stuff only going out to a smaller You know group of people in the video games.
Speaker 1: You've got these high budget high production Typically higher brow more complicated video games going out to the smaller Hardcore market.
Speaker 1: and then you've got these low budget low brow Mass appeal things going out to the mass market and it's totally backwards and I wonder if it's ever going to correct it.
Speaker 0: So, I mean if you want to make money in video gaming for real and you're not really cell phone games Like we just said is where the money's not just cell phone games shit game.
Speaker 1: Yeah make a Tetris clone You'll make more money.
Speaker 0: make little crap games buy yourself a franchise License to whatever thing you think.
Speaker 0: kids you make more money with diner - than you will with Halo 4 That's for sure, especially because you could do diner - in a weekend by yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean even if Halo 4 makes you know hundreds of millions of dollars diner - can also make hundreds of millions of dollars and diner - only took one guy like an hour to make and maybe you Hired an artist for a few thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: But one interesting thing that is coming out of all this is that Reggie came out and basically said all right bundlers Listen up.
Speaker 1: Oh, I hate those bundlers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm seeing this in the city because you know a Lot of people at my work are trying to get wheeze and can they go to the Nintendo store?
Speaker 0: They can they just they can't get.
Speaker 1: it got one last year with me.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, yeah, but So this is one kind of high-brow.
Speaker 0: Oh the hoity-toity fancy.
Speaker 0: people will shop here electronic store right in Midtown and I walked out of that efficient.
Speaker 0: Might have I don't remember hate that efficient because I walk by this place.
Speaker 0: I see in the window It's got like it's red.
Speaker 0: They have a pile of like 30 wheeze and you can buy them for like $500 because they come with a million absolutely useless bundled things that no one wants.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the big money.
Speaker 1: if you're a retail store selling game consoles, you don't make too much money on the console.
Speaker 0: Oh, you may jack off in the car.
Speaker 1: You don't make too much money on the games.
Speaker 1: That's why they pre-orders that they can maximize their you know game selling profit.
Speaker 1: You think most of the money on the used game walls this you don't make most of your money on the used games.
Speaker 1: Well, you make the profit margins.
Speaker 1: the margins are biggest on the used things and the accessories.
Speaker 1: so when someone sells that we you know that the The reason that you would sell wheeze is because someone coming in to buy a we obviously doesn't have one yet and they're gonna need Some accessories.
Speaker 1: they're gonna need some extra controllers.
Speaker 1: They're gonna need some memory cards.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be whatever right?
Speaker 1: So the problem is a lot of third-party accessories out there that people don't normally buy a lot of or there are the unnecessary Accessories that just don't do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's some third-party company made this accessory that no one wants and no one needs.
Speaker 1: or this is unpopular Games that no one wants and no one will buy.
Speaker 0: though I got to say I saw an accessory that wallet is definitely dumb and not something I would get Whoever made.
Speaker 0: this is brilliant.
Speaker 0: It's this third-party thing and it cost quite a bit of money and it is the accessory kit for Wii Sports.
Speaker 0: All it is is a little tennis racket that goes around your remote a little golf club that goes around your remote and a little Baseball bat that goes around your remote.
Speaker 1: They have a little bowling ball that the remote goes into now.
Speaker 1: boo sucks Anyway.
Speaker 1: or a boxing glove no boxing glove.
Speaker 1: Oh fuck that, okay But you know, they make the biggest margins on those things.
Speaker 1: so if you've got say 50 wheeze and you're not gonna get any more wheeze because there's so few of them being made only 1.8 million per month in the world You want to sell as many accessories as possible along with those wheeze because that's the way to make the most money.
Speaker 1: So they put them all in a box with a bunch of accessories and they say If you want to buy the Wii you got to buy all this other shit.
Speaker 0: You don't want Now, uh, I wonder I don't think Nintendo has any sort of power over this because while Reggie said, uh, we've contacted them Whatever He didn't say anything specific.
Speaker 1: and also how do these gonna say anything specific?
Speaker 0: Cuz I don't think Nintendo is gonna do anything.
Speaker 0: There's nothing they can do.
Speaker 1: I think with Nintendo capitalism.
Speaker 1: No, I think what Nintendo will do is if you know retailers are being really egregious with their you know We bundling and Nintendo doesn't like it Nintendo will Decrease the supply of wheeze to read those retailers and think they won't care to other retailers because they're.
Speaker 0: it's almost Christmas Anyway, and the boom is gonna pretty much not die, but go back to normal right after the holiday.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile GameStop slash EB is a is a very egregious bundler, but Nintendo apparently is doing this nice Raincheck deal with them.
Speaker 1: So Go Nintendo.
Speaker 0: I was about to talk about that.
Speaker 0: last all right, there's a Nintendo announced a we rain check program and basically if anyone buys a we through this program through I think Any time in December, they'll be guaranteed a we before the end of January.
Speaker 1: not bad.
Speaker 0: So hopefully that could kind of fuck all the people who are bundling things because maybe grandma might be smart and say alright Jimmy I couldn't get you a we But I got you this piece of paper that guarantees you a we and I got you a bunch of games to play as Soon as your week comes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's good.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only other thing is that you know All the economist analyst people are saying that Nintendo is losing money because of all the people who want wheeze But can't get one because yeah supplies too low.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is who wants a we now and it doesn't get one?
Speaker 0: who isn't just gonna get one in February?
Speaker 1: well, I think that there's some people that not a number greater than zero of People who because they can't get a we for the kid or whatever on the holiday They had they feel as if they have to get something and they don't want to get the kid a piece of paper because that Makes them, you know feel bad because they're consumer materials tours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and They're gonna go out and buy something else.
Speaker 1: maybe an Xbox that you see but here's the thing.
Speaker 0: maybe a TV maybe the Fairly certain maybe an iPod just knowing people that anyone who does that the we is gonna get purchased eventually.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think there are a number of people who they buy for the holidays But I got something and they're not gonna get the we don't forget because then the kid Maybe next year look at the way the kid will be happy because he got a gift.
Speaker 0: But come February when all his friends have wheeze.
Speaker 0: How come I don't have a wee mom.
Speaker 0: Ah Zelda mom Zelda Zelda Zelda Zelda.
Speaker 1: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: I don't think I don't think it's gonna beg too much of an impact, but I think that is gonna hurt them some it.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not actually going to hurt them.
Speaker 0: I don't think is it they already made?
Speaker 1: well No, they're not gonna suddenly be in the poor house or anything, but they they potential money They could have made if they could have see I don't.
Speaker 0: I think it's negligible.
Speaker 1: I think it's absolutely Could have met the we demand.
Speaker 1: they would have made a lot more money than if they then did they are now.
Speaker 0: I think the only reason that is true is because having money now is worth more than having money later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there's more dude.
Speaker 1: I don't think I think the the people who analyze these things who are experts no more than you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what the people who analyze it.
Speaker 0: the articles I read didn't say Nintendo's gonna lose Jack.
Speaker 0: all what they said is Basically Nintendo's profits are going to be delayed because of this and Nintendo could have another billion Right now by the end of the year that they're not gonna have just because they can't sell them fast enough.
Speaker 0: But they'll have it for next quarter.
Speaker 0: So won't matter.
Speaker 1: Let's see if they have.
Speaker 1: I don't think they'll have a billion next quarter But anyway, not a billion.
Speaker 0: They're not.
Speaker 1: they don't have to worry about billion monies either way They don't have to worry about monies.
Speaker 0: That's we're not gonna sell a billion ways.
Speaker 1: a billion ways of ends.
Speaker 0: Ah Anyway things the day.
Speaker 0: let's not talk about Nintendo or wheeze for at least a couple months.
Speaker 1: All right It'll probably be a while because there aren't gonna be any games coming out for a while and I still got to beat all the ones We just get.
Speaker 0: yeah, we haven't even talked about Mario Galaxy yet.
Speaker 1: I haven't beat it.
Speaker 1: I laid it a whole bunch then I stopped playing it.
Speaker 0: I feel as though I should review Simon's quest now that I'm playing it again.
Speaker 1: No fucking awesome sucks, right.
Speaker 0: anyway The other day we were looking for stuff.
Speaker 0: for some reason we ended up talking about Ross Perot.
Speaker 0: So I start YouTube it I find videos of Ross Perot.
Speaker 0: We watch him talking about some intelligent things and some crazy things and NAFTA and you know being Ross Perot.
Speaker 0: And then you know, we're about to finish up Maybe go get some dinner.
Speaker 0: and we noticed that in the related videos section of something We looked at related to Ross Perot at some point Was what looked like a but and rim of course could not help but click on the.
Speaker 0: but well not right away We look at it in the titles in Japanese and I'm like, is that a but?
Speaker 0: and everyone looks at it says yeah I think that's a but but I thought we couldn't have butts on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I thought there was no policy.
Speaker 1: tube is but free.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's a sham, but I wonder what it is.
Speaker 0: so we zoom in Emily starting to read the Japanese and I just go screw it.
Speaker 0: I click on it and What I saw what I watched was something that did involve butts, but they were sham butts.
Speaker 0: They weren't real butts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what comes out of a sham?
Speaker 1: but Shampoo, oh man The joke made one person laugh.
Speaker 1: so hope someone listening left at my shampoo joke.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure how to describe this but it's a Japanese cover with the Numa Numa song melody but it's the lyrics are kind of like a Potomac party.
Speaker 0: and show me your butt and there's sham butts and this epic guy with an epic mustache and an epic leather jackets and It's crazy goodness, I don't know what to say about this.
Speaker 0: I think it's kind of awesome and I'm not sure why.
Speaker 1: No, you got anything else to say.
Speaker 0: watch it.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's worth watching at least once.
Speaker 1: funny video Alright, so, you know that guy Greg kostickian who I've become more a fan of lately.
Speaker 1: He's the guy who made the paranoia RPG and he runs the manifesto games and he has this new blog.
Speaker 1: play this thing Which I've mentioned before which is an awesome blog everyone should read and on that blog He mentioned this RPG that he wrote.
Speaker 1: I guess Basically some RPGs out there aren't actually meant to be played like a hall human occupied landfill.
Speaker 0: That is read that the rules to that game and they're fantastic.
Speaker 0: It is a hilarious book.
Speaker 0: play that game and you're stupid.
Speaker 1: It is something because an RPG is really just a book.
Speaker 1: I said, you know but it's a book that contains rules among but also other things and There seems to be this art of making RPGs where you don't even need to actually Play the game you could.
Speaker 1: just the book itself is is the enjoyable part, you know?
Speaker 0: Well, even when I was really young before I found people who would play D&D with me reading those D&D books was great.
Speaker 0: I would just pour over him.
Speaker 1: Yeah So they sort of people they make RPGs on purpose that aren't meant to be played or I guess they technically could be played.
Speaker 1: But it's not really Going to be realistic or fun or interesting to play it.
Speaker 1: But the reading the book and reading the rules is entertaining usually humorous.
Speaker 1: So He made his game called violence the role-playing game of egregious and repulsive bloodshed and I'm not gonna describe the game any more than that.
Speaker 0: It's it's probably all you need to know.
Speaker 1: It's not a game That's really meant to be played.
Speaker 1: I guess you could play it.
Speaker 1: But reading it is quite humorous and quite awesome and it's a free PDF.
Speaker 1: So if you like the RPGs and maybe if you can laugh it, you know stupid violence jokes then this is for you and it's free.
Speaker 0: so I Realized recently that we never really talked about this game in any depth on the show.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 1: no Well, I thought we talked about it kind of but I guess not.
Speaker 1: so let's who cares Even if we did a whole show on it before whether we did or didn't we're doing a show on it now.
Speaker 1: screw you St.
Speaker 1: Petersburg as in the Russian city not as in I guess the Florida City All right.
Speaker 1: Let me I can sum this game up real quickly.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 1: It's a game.
Speaker 1: It's a card game.
Speaker 1: There is a board.
Speaker 1: the version you can buy now has a board and some other pieces but it's basically just a card game, but that also has money and You have money.
Speaker 1: at the beginning of the game you buy cards Cards either give you money or points.
Speaker 1: Your goal is to get points.
Speaker 1: That's the whole game.
Speaker 0: It's a growth management game in that there are multiple kinds of resources money and points.
Speaker 0: Yep, you want money in the first part of the game because you need enough money to bankroll your point getting later in the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you just start out at the beginning of the game buying points or cards that get you points you will have no more money and you will not be able to get any more points and then You will be done and while other people
Speaker 0: who
Speaker 1: might buy things they get that money But then never buy any points will end up with just fistfuls of money and no points.
Speaker 0: and on the I guess on the surface That's pretty much how this game is.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: you're trying to balance your Expenditures of money so that over the course of the game you continue to get enough money to buy as many points as you can but not too many points because then you won't be able to buy any buy any more and you'll actually get less than you think You were gonna get or not too much money because then you could have bought points instead of you know buying money.
Speaker 0: So like I said a growth management game But the way it plays out is actually fantastic and while the game Eventually will break down as all board games do when you play it enough times I think the core concepts of this game and this is kind of important I think we'll talk about this at the end too could be used I believe to great effect in other kinds of games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is a game where every mechanic in the game.
Speaker 1: Is it an amazing?
Speaker 1: Beautiful perfectly executed game mechanic and all the mechanics work together very well But the resulting game just isn't a game that is strategically deep But all the mechanics of the game are great game mechanics that you know should be used in many other games to great effect.
Speaker 0: And the game is slightly strategic and very Tactical at least up until the point where you and all your friends have figured the game out completely.
Speaker 1: and then the game is also Fun, even if you four sort of figured it out.
Speaker 1: I have fun playing st.
Speaker 1: Petersburg, even though I know exactly what to do And you don't even need to play the first turn because it's automatic.
Speaker 0: at this point Sometimes the first several turns are basically automatic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but no seriously I think it speaks very well of this game this Rio Grande hands on.
Speaker 0: look game that Despite the fact that I feel as though our group has solved it and that winning basically comes down to Do the good Jews come up early on or do they come up later?
Speaker 0: Oh?
Speaker 1: All right, so you want to go in a little more depth to explain what the Jews are.
Speaker 0: well It's not just Jews there's also chairs and squares.
Speaker 1: Okay, so there's four kinds of cards in the game.
Speaker 1: There's the green worker cards which are the chairs because the symbol on them is a chair Or it looks like a chair and whether it's a chair or not?
Speaker 0: I don't get a card with a chair on it, and you get a little wooden chair yes.
Speaker 0: And then there's the buildings which are primarily the point generation things aka the Kremlin.
Speaker 0: yeah The green is a little Kremlin simple.
Speaker 1: the green workers mostly give money.
Speaker 1: They're your primary source of money.
Speaker 1: the blue Kremlins are your primary source of points, but they can sometimes give money.
Speaker 0: now the squares are the upgrades And it's just a big square.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those aren't actually things you can buy on their own.
Speaker 1: you have to upgrade existing things with them And it lets you get really powerful stuff.
Speaker 0: now the last kind of card is the nobility.
Speaker 0: they're orange, and they give you money and points and Extra bonus points at the end of the game which are very important.
Speaker 0: now you might have noticed that I didn't say nobility.
Speaker 0: I said something else.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: Scott actually pointed this out when we first started playing but I'll link to this.
Speaker 0: here's a picture of the four symbols from the game.
Speaker 0: now guess which one is the nobility and then from there?
Speaker 0: I want you to pay attention to certain features.
Speaker 0: it may have.
Speaker 1: It's Jewish possibly possibly.
Speaker 0: So we're playing this game for the first a second time.
Speaker 0: I think because I played it at a con once I didn't even think of this.
Speaker 0: and then Scott pulls up the thing and he's like all right time to draw the Jews.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm Jewish.
Speaker 1: That's what they are.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 1: I mean actually they're all Russians technically But Russian Jews.
Speaker 1: the icon that represents the nobility is it has a really big nose It's and it makes lots of money.
Speaker 0: I cannot help but assume that this is intentional.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: I can't assume anything.
Speaker 0: There is no way.
Speaker 1: This is not intentional all right, so Is there anything else really say about this game?
Speaker 0: I mean the way the game plays out is you know the cards.
Speaker 0: You'll go through four phases and every player you can play up to four.
Speaker 0: the game works kind of okay with three.
Speaker 0: It's kind of broken with two, but you can play it, but four is what you want to be.
Speaker 0: Everyone will have one of these tokens and then every round of the game You do the workers and then the buildings and then the aristocrats and then the squares.
Speaker 0: yep and the way you do it is there's.
Speaker 0: the cards are laid out on the board and Basically you fill the board up with cards of whatever phase it is.
Speaker 0: Then people can buy cards going round robin till their hearts content.
Speaker 0: once everyone has passed Then you score all the things that points of that type.
Speaker 0: so in the worker round you put out workers.
Speaker 0: Then you buy workers, but you can buy other stuff, but then you score only workers.
Speaker 0: You might have bought a Kremlin or a square But you're not gonna be able to get anything from those things.
Speaker 1: right and any You know.
Speaker 1: and if no one?
Speaker 1: but if something is put out on the board and no one buys it It just kind of sticks around for a while.
Speaker 1: and that means so it let's say we the board is empty And it's the Kremlin round.
Speaker 1: so you put out a whole row of kremlins and maybe half the kremlins get bought.
Speaker 1: okay The other half of the kremlins stay on the board and then we deal out the aristocrat Jews to fill up the other half Of the board.
Speaker 1: so if you want more Jews to get drawn from the deck you'll buy more kremlins.
Speaker 0: You see now this creates a very interesting even odd left-right mechanic to the game.
Speaker 0: We haven't talked a lot about left-right mechanics.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: we haven't reviewed a lot of those games But a lot of modern German style games.
Speaker 0: try to avoid the left-right phenomenon whereby The you have more of an effect or lesson of effect Game-wise on the person to your left or right.
Speaker 0: just by the way the game works.
Speaker 0: usually because to make things simple a lot of games Just go clockwise.
Speaker 1: yep I mean you know in any game where it's okay take your turn and the person to the left takes their turn.
Speaker 1: in Some of those games depending on the rules The person to your right might have a big advantage over you and you'll have a big advantage Over the person to your left, and then so on and so forth.
Speaker 0: now sometimes This is balanced very well But a lot of times it's just because it would have made the game too complex or not fun to play to skip the whole.
Speaker 0: Just go clockwise Mechanic.
Speaker 0: so a lot of older German games Have this problem where if I sit to the left or the right of Scott Matters a lot and how the game is gonna turn out in the end El Grande had this problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah for example if I'm gonna sitting down to play this game and I know that you have an advantage over the person to your left and A disadvantage to the person to your right
Speaker 0: I want to say Someone who's bad at the game
Speaker 1: I will sit to the right to the left of the newbie and I will sit to the right of rim to damage him the And I'll probably win if I do that.
Speaker 0: now this game gets around that in that you deal out the rolls Randomly at the beginning of the game.
Speaker 0: So I might start with the workers or I might start with the Jews or I might start with the Kremlin's or I might start With the square.
Speaker 1: is the square sucks in the first round.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, but at the same time I feel like you get an advantage in the long run for that, but it depends too because you do it randomly.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So clockwise counterclockwise the order that the things are in is random.
Speaker 0: And then after every set of four rounds before you start a new turn to use the old D&D around versus turn Everyone passes their little fetish their little token to the left Mmm, and then you continue.
Speaker 0: so if Scott has the Jews he's on my right and then I have the Kremlin's.
Speaker 0: I passed the Kremlin's To the person on my left and Scott gives me the Jews.
Speaker 1: Yep Alright, so basically the the the.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, I guess I didn't finish how that were the why.
Speaker 0: that's the even odd mechanic.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I guess not.
Speaker 0: So since you're drawing cards and buying cards and you only fill up say the Kremlin's when the Kremlin round starts Let's say no one buys any workers the workers thing stays full.
Speaker 0: Well, then it's my turn to do the Kremlin's and because I'm the one whose turn it is I get first pick of the Kremlin's and whoever has the chair gets first pick of the workers.
Speaker 0: If no Kremlin's come out, I kind of lose that advantage.
Speaker 0: So I kind of especially with Jews But I'll get to why.
Speaker 0: that's the reason.
Speaker 0: if I want a square or a Kremlin or whatever I have to make sure that at least enough of them will be put out to where.
Speaker 0: if everyone buys one I will be able to buy one.
Speaker 1: Yes, for example, let's say there are three players, right?
Speaker 1: And uh rim is to my left and he currently has the chair.
Speaker 1: That means Let you know that if I want to get a worker Which is the chair there needs to be at least three empty spaces on the board.
Speaker 1: if there's only two empty spaces And then we deal out two new workers rim buys one.
Speaker 1: the next person buys one if they want to which they probably will I will not get one.
Speaker 1: there will not be one there for me to buy it.
Speaker 1: how much money I have.
Speaker 1: So that gives me a strong incentive to buy a square or some other card Before that part of the game comes around so that there will be three open spaces meaning I can get a worker now.
Speaker 1: But once I open the third open space since the game goes around and around and around so everyone's done rim can then Buy another card opening up a fourth space.
Speaker 1: So he'll get two workers and each of us will get one and so on and so forth.
Speaker 1: So there's sort of this you trying to buy things to leave a good number of open spaces so that you will get The right number of you know new cards available to you.
Speaker 1: But you don't want to buy a bunch of useless crap just to be able to have the opportunity to buy useful crap later.
Speaker 1: Cuz then you're losing all your money on stuff that doesn't do anything.
Speaker 0: now this in addition to the Jew mechanic Which we'll get to and in addition to the hand which I'll also get to right now Actually adds a fairly Significant amount of tactical depth to the game mm-hmm even though it's a very simple set of tactics.
Speaker 0: at the same time you can buy a card or take a card or not buy a card and Force someone else to now have to buy a suboptimal card to get the thing that they know they need in the next round.
Speaker 0: There's definitely this game if you are fighting with other players to make sure you get exactly what you need every round and that the math All works out, and it's really not all that complicated.
Speaker 1: once you sort of play the game a couple times You know the hang this thing out the hand any any time.
Speaker 0: It's your you're sitting there, and it's your action.
Speaker 0: cuz you just keep going around.
Speaker 0: Robin all right I can buy a card or I can pass or I can take a card for free Into my hand, but you can only hold so many cards in your hand as a limit of three cards.
Speaker 0: yep now I've denied someone else that card and I can buy it from my hand anytime I want.
Speaker 0: so at any point when I could just buy a card from the board at any turn instead I can say no, I'm building this card from my hand.
Speaker 1: yep So for really awesome card the the basic strategy with the hand is this a really awesome card comes out.
Speaker 1: You have a chance to buy it because you can go first or whatever.
Speaker 1: You know that someone else is gonna buy that if you let it go But you don't have enough money to buy it yourself.
Speaker 1: So you pick it up and put it in your hand thus keeping it safe and buying it later.
Speaker 1: That's the basic strategy of the hand.
Speaker 1: It's also not the best strategy of the hand, but it is there.
Speaker 0: Well what you want to do beyond that is you also have to look at.
Speaker 0: well I need to make another card get drawn in the worker phase, so I got to buy another thing.
Speaker 0: But I don't want any of these buildings yet.
Speaker 0: It's too early in the game.
Speaker 0: I'll just take that library into my hand.
Speaker 1: Take the car into your hand.
Speaker 1: now There's an open space which means another card is gonna get dealt and the even-odd game.
Speaker 1: you win that right now.
Speaker 1: You don't have to spend any money right now And you took a card into your hand that would have otherwise maybe disappeared from the game And you can buy it later when if it would have shown up later.
Speaker 1: You would have bought it anyway now.
Speaker 0: Then again now you have the problem of I've already drawn two cards into my hand if I draw a third card And then some opportunity comes up later where I would need to draw a card.
Speaker 0: I can't Mmm, and the game is just.
Speaker 0: it's really fun as a result.
Speaker 0: with all this all right.
Speaker 1: So the worker cards are primarily a way to get money.
Speaker 1: You know the.
Speaker 1: you buy them.
Speaker 1: they give you money.
Speaker 1: the Kremlin's are primarily cards to get you points.
Speaker 1: you buy them to get points.
Speaker 1: The Jew cards the aristocrats the nobles whatever.
Speaker 1: they give you money but they cost a lot more than the workers and They usually give you less money than the workers, so it's kind of like why would you buy them?
Speaker 1: well some of the more expensive?
Speaker 1: Aristocrat cards give you money and points which a few other cards do that as well.
Speaker 1: But that those are really powerful cards and the game is actually sort of broken where if those cards show up right at the beginning Of the game then someone can get them buy them right away And then sort of win and there's not much anyone else could do about it unless they get similarly powerful cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much if the second biggest Jew in the normal deck comes up in the first round whoever gets that card is 95% likely to win the game.
Speaker 0: you might as well.
Speaker 1: just stop there.
Speaker 1: a total nub.
Speaker 1: But even if they are a total nub they might win because it's so that powerful.
Speaker 1: So a lot of people play with a rule where you reshuffle the cards if one of those powerful cards comes up in the first Turn, but anyway the.
Speaker 1: so why buy these aristocrat cards?
Speaker 1: Why are they so great if you know?
Speaker 1: They don't get you that much money, and they cost a lot, and they don't get in.
Speaker 1: only the really powerful ones are really powerful.
Speaker 1: The reason is this in addition to the points you get for buildings that give you stuff all the time You get points at the end of the game for the number of unique aristocrats.
Speaker 1: so for example at the end of the game I have five Authors authors, which is the lowest level aristocrat.
Speaker 1: that doesn't do much for me.
Speaker 1: now let's say I have an author a judge a building designing guy a The lady in waiting or mistress of something whatever his name is.
Speaker 1: I forget mister some ceremony misters of ceremonies And the comptroller.
Speaker 1: right that's five different aristocrats.
Speaker 1: right there's a little table on the board.
Speaker 1: now This doesn't happen all the time, but at the very end of the game you look at that table Just once.
Speaker 1: I have five unique different named Aristocrats.
Speaker 1: you get a crap ton of points all at once and that's usually the thing that means winning and losing.
Speaker 0: So you've got the one method of generating points where you get you build buildings earlier is better generally.
Speaker 0: And so say I build a building you give me two victory points Every round.
Speaker 0: for the rest of the game I get two victory points And I start pulling ahead.
Speaker 1: so buying that card earlier in the game gets you more points But buying it later in the game is probably a lot easier to afford it.
Speaker 1: So it's pretty tough because buying it earlier on might mean you don't have enough money to get more money because you need money to Make money.
Speaker 1: that's the rule of the world.
Speaker 1: Capitalism yep, but buying it later on when you have money you can afford to buy it.
Speaker 1: you get less points out of it.
Speaker 0: now There's some other fun things like if you buy a building that you are any card that you already have out in front of you You get a one discount for every one.
Speaker 0: you have right.
Speaker 1: so if I buy an author an author cost $4 Then another author shows up.
Speaker 1: I can buy that author for $3.
Speaker 1: if another author shows up I can buy it for $2 now.
Speaker 0: what all this?
Speaker 0: what this and all these kind of?
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: people generally want different cards just Depending on their situation, but the game seems to be set up to cause people to desire Cards sometimes the same card sometimes different cards and as a result creates a lot of tactical Situations that if the game were even slightly less complex would not be there at all and the game wouldn't be in any way enjoyable.
Speaker 1: I think the only other mechanic in the game is that If a card sits out on the board and no one buys it it eventually goes to the bottom half of the board where it's A dollar cheaper.
Speaker 1: so even if I have two authors an author comes out that could cost me usually two dollars But no one else wants it.
Speaker 1: it goes to the bottom of the board.
Speaker 1: now It cost me one dollar and now I have three authors.
Speaker 1: And you can you know by penny pinching like that and by biding your time you can really save a lot of money.
Speaker 1: But then you got to think about it though.
Speaker 1: if I would have bought that author a turn earlier sure it would have cost me An extra dollar, but the author would have given me an extra dollar from being in my pile for you know.
Speaker 1: So it's tough.
Speaker 1: It's tough all right.
Speaker 0: We could talk a little bit about how to win at the game.
Speaker 1: I think that's what we should do.
Speaker 1: first of all if the judge or the mistress whatever comes up in the first turn or the Comptroller the comptroller is pretty close.
Speaker 1: But any of those three incredibly powerful Aristocrat cards that give you points and money if any of those show up early in the game either buy them immediately Or pick them up put them in your hand and then buy them as soon as you can afford them Because you will make a zillion points and a zillion dollars and win and no one Really hard for anyone to stop you unless they do the same thing.
Speaker 0: to buy Workers always buy workers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as many as you can there.
Speaker 0: There is almost I could take pretty much in the last Two rounds of the game.
Speaker 0: or when you might not want to be buying workers you want to buy as many workers as you can Every time the opportunity presents itself.
Speaker 1: yes workers generally all the workers give you three dollars a turn.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: well The most expensive worker is the shit.
Speaker 1: the well the most expensive worker We're gonna talk about is the ships the ship making guy.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: There's one other one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well I know we're gonna talk about him, and he cost seven dollars, so if you buy him even on the first turn That's a good deal because the game is a lot longer than three turns.
Speaker 1: That's going to make you a lot of money It's worth it.
Speaker 1: and once you buy one ship guy Every other ship guy will cost you a dollar less, and there's a lot of them.
Speaker 1: so the second ship guy will cost you six.
Speaker 1: the next one will cost you five.
Speaker 1: the four there and The only time you don't want to buy a worker pretty much is like Let's say there's two turns left in the game.
Speaker 1: right and I know that the game well you can tell when the game is gonna end because it ends when one of the four decks of cards runs out.
Speaker 1: so if one of the decks is really close to running out and I think the game is gonna end in two or three turns and I don't have any shipbuilding guys and They cost seven and one comes up then buying one might be a bad idea because it'll cost me seven and the game Probably won't last three turns for me to make a profit
Speaker 0: now, too.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna tell you what round this is likely to happen in.
Speaker 0: likely it's pretty much guaranteed to happen unless you're playing with total nubs, but There there's a round where everything get reshuffled and you'll notice that a whole bunch of cards fall off the board after the square phase and a whole bunch of workers come out.
Speaker 0: you should be able to anticipate when this is going to happen and Have saved money so that you can buy all the workers that your idiot friends Didn't have money for because they didn't realize this would happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because generally the game starts and when the game starts they put out what it let's say is a three-player game You put out what.
Speaker 1: six workers or yeah Yeah And if it's a four-player game you put out You know eight work appeal by workers and then it fills up with Kremlin's.
Speaker 0: people buy some stuff fills up with you know.
Speaker 0: Then in the next round a lot of those cards go to the bottom half of the board where they're discount because no one can Afford them in the first round.
Speaker 0: They didn't have enough money and no one wants him in the second round.
Speaker 0: So they're going away.
Speaker 1: Yep so only a few workers come out in the second round but then in the third round a whole bunch of workers come out usually and this is the time when people finally have money because it's already been two rounds and Now there's a whole bunch of workers available.
Speaker 1: So you this is the time you have to if you don't have money at this point in the game To buy as many workers you possibly can you lose.
Speaker 1: basically because if you don't have money and you spent it on something else Everyone else is gonna buy a whole bunch of workers and you buying one less worker.
Speaker 1: You might think oh I bought one less worker than those other guys.
Speaker 1: They got one extra worker.
Speaker 1: Not a big deal.
Speaker 1: That's three money times the number of turns left in the game, which is a lot a whole lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically at any point know how many workers you have and know how many workers everyone else playing has if you were ever Down by more than one at any point.
Speaker 0: You're done.
Speaker 0: It's over.
Speaker 0: You've lost pretty much.
Speaker 1: cuz you know There'll be five turns left in the game.
Speaker 1: That's fifteen dollars.
Speaker 1: fifteen dollars can buy you something that gets you like six points per turn.
Speaker 1: Six points per turn times five turns of thirty points.
Speaker 1: Yeah, great.
Speaker 1: Good job Good job, not having that worker not having that money in the third round.
Speaker 0: Yep, now it's not just with workers there.
Speaker 0: there's a cycle where if there are points in the game where all four commodities will suddenly be out there in force and you'll Be able to buy a whole bunch You should be able to anticipate when this will happen and be ready for it.
Speaker 0: If it is the kind of card you want to capitalize on yep to the Jews Pretty much.
Speaker 0: you should always take a unique one the more rare it is.
Speaker 0: You should do whatever you have to do to get it.
Speaker 0: Just put take in your hand deny it to other people.
Speaker 0: look at what other people need and take them.
Speaker 0: you already have three authors.
Speaker 0: Take the fourth one so that Joe can't get one.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean you look at the.
Speaker 1: I've played this game a lot of times and hardly ever has anyone won without getting a significant number of the unique Aristocrats.
Speaker 0: you can win and not letting it and you also have to prevent other people from getting the unique Much as you can with a two or possibly three Aristocrat difference down as long as you have got the buildings to back it up.
Speaker 0: But that is difficult to do and if you're down by more than three.
Speaker 0: It's over because the there's.
Speaker 0: there are increasing returns for having more aristocrats.
Speaker 1: It's incredibly like if you have seven you get a bunch of points.
Speaker 1: you have eight you get a lot more points for having eight.
Speaker 1: It's a ludicrous number of points.
Speaker 1: when I look at the scale.
Speaker 0: There's a building an observatory and it lets you basically Buy like look at cards from whatever pile you want early and purchase them.
Speaker 0: you might think well I should use that on the aristocrats.
Speaker 0: at every opportunity to get more aristocrats early in the game.
Speaker 1: use it on the worker.
Speaker 1: Yes Good God think about it.
Speaker 1: you get an Extra.
Speaker 1: workers are hard to get early in the game because they're only so many to get dealt out.
Speaker 1: if you take a worker Extra early in the game.
Speaker 1: That's three dollars times the number of turns left in the game you win.
Speaker 0: There's another building the one that.
Speaker 0: what's the one that let the pub the pube the old boob.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep, it lets you pretty much just turn money directly into points.
Speaker 1: So if you have lots of extra money and you're having a hard time Getting the cards to get you lots of points The pub is a good way to just turn your money into a lot of points.
Speaker 1: If you can't do it any other way I will say this.
Speaker 0: there's a way to know pretty exactly how much you should put into the pub at any given time.
Speaker 0: the simple thing to remember is Later in the game is a better time to be putting money in the pub.
Speaker 0: Yeah early and you're putting money into the pub early in the game.
Speaker 0: You're doing it wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah at the end of the game if you're playing well You should have so much money that you can buy every single card that's worth buying and then money left over and that's the money That goes in the pub.
Speaker 0: Now go for combos.
Speaker 0: try to get like four customs houses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I try to do is early in the game I'll only I'll pick like either the markets or the customs houses or one type of building and then I'll buy as many of that Building as I can.
Speaker 1: so I spend very relatively little money and get a lot of points building up throughout the game And then I have as many workers as I can obviously And then I spend all my money trying to get a bunch of different aristocrats use.
Speaker 0: make sure Every round where aristocrats will come out that enough will be drawn to where you have the opportunity to buy one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're gonna be the fourth person to have an opportunity to purchase Aristocrats make sure there are four empty spaces on the board at the end of the Kremlin round so that four Aristocrats get dealt out at least now This is doubly so for workers.
Speaker 0: if you're going to have the chair next round meaning the chair is to your right and is Going to pass to you and it's a four player game.
Speaker 0: You want there to be Exactly five spaces or one if possible.
Speaker 1: Yes, or you know, perhaps Yeah, five is optimal.
Speaker 1: five is optimal because then you can buy two workers and everyone else can only buy.
Speaker 0: However, if you didn't listen to us, you don't have enough money to buy two workers then for the love of God Don't let two workers come up.
Speaker 1: Yeah Because then the guy to the left of you will be able to buy two workers without having to do anything and then all he owns.
Speaker 0: Yeah Remember any time you do not take it around he'll get two workers again because he'll have the chair from you any time.
Speaker 0: you do Not take advantage of a situation to deny someone else something.
Speaker 0: you've given it to them and that is worth a lot to them.
Speaker 0: Yeah here.
Speaker 1: I found the scale.
Speaker 1: if you have seven different Jews It's 28 points.
Speaker 1: eight different Jews is 36 points.
Speaker 1: nine is 45 points.
Speaker 1: So it's it's sort of a one plus two plus three plus four plus five.
Speaker 0: You can win this game nachi scale as a dark horse.
Speaker 0: That's not the right scale right with almost entirely Aristocrats and not much else.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: That's Fibonacci is the right one right now.
Speaker 0: I'd even listen to you.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to wrap this up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is gonna be a long episode.
Speaker 0: We got it curse.
Speaker 0: Luckily.
Speaker 0: The game's kind of solved.
Speaker 1: It's close to Fibonacci.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: What else is really important to winning this game?
Speaker 1: Playing it a few times to get the feel.
Speaker 0: All right in terms of knowing how like what?
Speaker 0: Worker to buy like you see a bunch of workers, which one do I buy?
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna tell you exactly because it's you can.
Speaker 0: basically you could be done by an algorithm.
Speaker 0: You should be able to look at any possible set of workers in front of you and workers on a board in a game of st.
Speaker 0: Petersburg and Not only know exactly which one you should buy but know exactly which ones every other player will buy.
Speaker 1: you can calculate this Perfectly, I mean it's sort of obvious because you pretty much everyone always wants to buy the cheapest possible worker They can buy.
Speaker 1: and if there is two workers that cost equal amounts to you because that's very possible By the one that you know, someone else really wants.
Speaker 1: thus They'll be forced to spend more on the workers.
Speaker 0: I and there's other things to it.
Speaker 0: But basically you should get to the point where you can look at the workers and know exactly Like the worker phase should be automatic.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't even have to play that phase.
Speaker 0: Everyone should just take the ones they know they'll get and pay their money.
Speaker 1: Yep, especially in the first round.
Speaker 1: But we play the first round of the game.
Speaker 1: We basically turn over the number of workers then see who goes first and then we just deal them out because we know exactly who?
Speaker 1: Wants which ones and there's nothing anyone can do about it.
Speaker 0: Start with six extra money because we know that everyone's going to have two workers and get six money at the end of that phase.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Are we done?
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 0: I mean beyond that Upgrades by the Jews.
Speaker 0: don't buy the buildings.
Speaker 1: Well, some of the buildings are okay.
Speaker 0: So my buildings opportunistically, yeah Do not ever buy a building if you could have gotten with unique aristocrat instead with the upgrade cards in general You are basically only trying.
Speaker 1: the only reason to get the upgrade cards is because there are unique Aristocrats in there that cannot be gotten any other way.
Speaker 1: So you want to have lots of like authors or administrators?
Speaker 1: extra duplicate administrators duplicate authors so that you can upgrade them to say Popes because there's only one Pope in the game.
Speaker 1: So if you don't have if you have an author only one and you upgrade it to the Pope you still only have one unique Aristocrat.
Speaker 1: give two authors.
Speaker 1: you upgrade one to the Pope.
Speaker 1: now you have two unique aristocrats and it's a huge jump in points and also buying that one aristocrat.
Speaker 0: even if you have a duplicate you get the Discount and then you've denied someone else because a lot of the higher level ones.
Speaker 0: There aren't so many in the game No and they're not guaranteed to come out there.
Speaker 1: other.
Speaker 1: to upgrade workers is usually a good idea earlier in the game because it allows you to get a sort of a continuing supply of points without diminishing your supply of money at all.
Speaker 1: and The upgrade buildings are sort of something you buy opportunistically.
Speaker 1: like you.
Speaker 1: don't go for them Unless you really try to win without the the aristocrats.
Speaker 1: But if let's say you have a building and an upgrade building comes out and it only cost you like one to get it Right and it'll give you like a whole bunch of money or something.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: You know, it won't hurt but I've never seen anyone win really big with those.
Speaker 0: now the last and most important thing And this is pretty much the key to victory pajamkins village.
Speaker 0: Well, you should always buy pajamkins village.
Speaker 0: Yeah always.
Speaker 0: but beside that When it there is a point in the game where you will have to make a conscious shift from Money generation as your focus to point generation as your focus That is the round where it you might even forego the aristocrats or whatever But suddenly you spend all your money on the library or something some big point building.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm doing that Right before everyone else does it gives you a 75% chance of winning but doing it a tiny bit early ruins you because you won't have enough money.
Speaker 1: and doing it a tiny bit late means everyone else got it before you and they Got more points than you.
Speaker 0: I've had very good success winning against people who aren't the front row crew.
Speaker 0: I played this game with a million times by switching to point generation in the third or fourth round.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you you basically the first part of the game get as much money as you can.
Speaker 1: right and because everything keeps making stuff as the game goes on you buy money now, you'll have money forever and Then at the exact right moment when you know You have enough money making resources to power you through the rest of the game just buy stuff that makes points as much as you possibly can and then that'll make you the most possible points of the rest of The game and that that could add up to like 30 40 points over the course of the whole thing.
Speaker 0: And I guess eventually you'll solve the game because you know Like we said, there's a few problems with balance in terms of if the early aristocrats come up big.
Speaker 0: But also like we said the game is super fun Even if you're playing it with three people who are playing optimum.
Speaker 1: I mean we've gotten to the point where we don't even really need to play the game like.
Speaker 1: we can just sit down deal the Cards out and I can tell you exactly what everyone is going to do on their turns.
Speaker 1: You know as long as they're all skilled players to know what they're doing.
Speaker 1: I'll be like you're gonna do this You're gonna do this you're gonna do this and I know exactly what everyone's gonna do and I'm not wrong.
Speaker 1: They'd like yes, I was gonna do that because there are only really two dark horse.
Speaker 0: There's the it's kind of like halas has this where there's the way to win and then there are the two dark horse Ways to win and beyond that every other strategy is suboptimal.
Speaker 0: Yep It's not a strategic game because you choose between the way to win and the slightly less likely ways to win and it's all just Tactics and numbers.
Speaker 0: you got to keep all the numbers in your head all the time.
Speaker 1: It's a super fun game.
Speaker 1: It's a super great game.
Speaker 1: It's super awesome game in every way except for the fact that eventually after playing it a lot You will just know exactly what everyone's gonna do and there's no real decisions going on right.
Speaker 0: and on that note I'm gonna go make some case ideas.
Speaker 0: All right This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you Can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.