Speaker 0: It's Wednesday March 7th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We review our comic book for a change with why are you doing this?
Speaker 0: by Jason?
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Say order this laptop, and I ordered it in the middle of February And it finally shipped.
Speaker 0: granted the fact that it took that long even ship I probably would have canceled my order at that point.
Speaker 1: They still haven't taken any of my money So I'm not complaining yet.
Speaker 1: I might get a free laptop because they're in so incompetent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz well when I went to Katsu card.
Speaker 0: They didn't bill me for the hotel until just now.
Speaker 1: Oh wow really.
Speaker 1: That's crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually when I charge something on my credit card.
Speaker 1: I see it in like a couple days this I charged on my credit card.
Speaker 1: It shipped, and it's still not on my credit card at all.
Speaker 1: so anyway It came by ups and they gave me no choice in choosing my method of shipping.
Speaker 1: You know they basically said we're shipping it to you.
Speaker 1: I mean I could have paid for super fast shipping or slow shipping, but I didn't have any other choices.
Speaker 1: I couldn't choose US Postal Service.
Speaker 1: I couldn't choose FedEx.
Speaker 1: It was pretty much as ups period.
Speaker 1: they didn't even let me know It was ups it was.
Speaker 1: all I knew is that it was being shipped.
Speaker 1: I didn't know it was ups until it you know arrived, and you know what it.
Speaker 1: It hasn't arrived because they marked it to be Only allowed to be delivered if it is signed in person.
Speaker 0: now that alone I wouldn't really complain about because it is a very expensive piece of equipment in a very small box.
Speaker 0: and well We live in an area where there's almost no crime.
Speaker 0: I can think of a lot of places I have lived where I would not want anything.
Speaker 0: I had ordered sitting out in public.
Speaker 1: that is true You know I even though you know we have never had anything stolen off the porch.
Speaker 1: And we get packages very often with very expensive goods in them, and they just sit outside, but until we get home They've never been stolen.
Speaker 1: But I still worry just a little bit that it's not gonna be there when I get home.
Speaker 1: So a laptop that cost almost $2,000.
Speaker 1: of course I would worry about leaving it on the porch.
Speaker 1: however because of the way UPS delivers packages and because I Actually go to work and make enough money to buy things There is no way I can get this package without skipping out on work.
Speaker 0: Yeah Think of this.
Speaker 0: they'll only deliver between whenever they start in the morning Which is long after either of us would have gone to work and like 630 or 7 Which is pretty much right as we're getting home.
Speaker 1: So unless there's a guarantee that they will show up at 7 and I rush home as fast as I possibly can like to get One earlier train there's no guarantee that anyone will be in the house to sign the package.
Speaker 1: not every house in the United States has a family with someone staying at home or a butler or Losers who don't have jobs.
Speaker 1: People go to work.
Speaker 1: houses are usually empty on any weekday for most of the day.
Speaker 0: Well even worse is when you call them to try and just drive to the UPS store and pick it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, so I can go to the UPS store to pick it up between Monday and Friday 1 p.m.. And 7 p.m..
Speaker 0: Wow that's great.
Speaker 1: Yeah I have to do it.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna have to leave work early tomorrow And then drive like 20 minutes to Poughkeepsie to this UPS place because it's not just any UPS store.
Speaker 1: They don't just leave it at the nearest UPS store because this is a pretty close UPS store.
Speaker 1: It's like 10 minutes away.
Speaker 1: No it has to be a UPS shipping center.
Speaker 1: You know they can't bring it to a nearby UPS store or leave it at your local post office Which is five minutes away?
Speaker 1: No they have to frickin and there's no way.
Speaker 1: I can't tell them I don't care about a signature.
Speaker 1: leave it on my porch anyway.
Speaker 1: I can't tell them that they will not accept that there is no way They will leave it on the porch.
Speaker 0: see if I were you.
Speaker 0: But maybe it's just because when my ire is drawn.
Speaker 0: I am much more likely to follow through with it.
Speaker 0: I probably would have canceled my order and told the laptop company Exactly why I canceled my order because they didn't give me an option in shipping and the company they chose to ship it could not Deliver it to me without me leaving work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well I that's the reason I chose to go to the UPS place as opposed to just coming home early and scheduling a delivery after I Got home is because number one at least this way I'm guaranteed to you know not have the delivery guy show up five minutes before I get home and B I can raise a stink when I go there like this is BS.
Speaker 1: Don't you realize people have fucking jobs?
Speaker 1: What the fuck is wrong with you?
Speaker 1: They should deliver seriously.
Speaker 1: UPS should deliver packages to houses between 5 p.m.
Speaker 1: And 10 p.m UPS guy doesn't have to work all day.
Speaker 1: Let the UPS guy stay home and do nothing all day and that he works five to ten because guess what as the only time His job is useful.
Speaker 0: Well unless you're delivering to businesses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: So the business delivery guys do it during the day so the home delivery guys do it night.
Speaker 0: now Why do that?
Speaker 0: it costs a lot more money when you could just do what they do now because people like us are still the Minority and they're not gonna make any more money by Catering to you and me and the five other people who care about this.
Speaker 0: most people are gonna use UPS anyway.
Speaker 0: They don't care well.
Speaker 1: I can tell you this even though FedEx often costs more money FedEx has never actually given me a problem because even when FedEx has a thing that says We're a signature required the guy has always left it on the porch for me And it's never been stolen.
Speaker 1: and they always get stuff to me a lot faster than UPS does.
Speaker 1: so for now on I'm paying the extra money for FedEx if it's an option.
Speaker 1: if it's not an option I'm gonna complain to whoever didn't give me the option.
Speaker 1: yeah But I just don't see this changing anytime soon because no one cares, but you yeah well It still sucks and there needs to be a solution for it because it's a big problem in that.
Speaker 1: Peep you know the kind of people like not a big problem.
Speaker 0: It's only a problem for a very small minority of people.
Speaker 1: but the thing is the people who are Likely to buy more likely to buy things on the internet and thus more likely to need shipping are people who are more likely To not be home to get those packages, but you know what they keep buying the stuff anyway.
Speaker 0: So there's no incentive for anyone to change their business model.
Speaker 0: The worst thing is when we had that old TV And we wanted to get rid of it there was no way for us to get rid of that TV and There were a bunch of people we could pay to come and pick the TV up and not a single one of them would come Outside of the hours of 9 to 5 and they wouldn't come in on weekends.
Speaker 0: So there was absolutely no way for us to legally dispose of our television without one of us taking a day off work It's and you know how many days off work am I gonna get here?
Speaker 0: It's like well I'm not gonna take a day off work for that.
Speaker 0: when I can take a day off work to be at the beach I know seriously it's just fucked up in that.
Speaker 1: you know in other countries people get a lot more days off work or they have like siestas or tea or bunches And things like that where they have time off of work often That they can use to conduct the date the business of their personal lives.
Speaker 1: You know go to a doctor's appointment or the dentist.
Speaker 1: or you know take do some maintenance on your car All these things that you have to do.
Speaker 0: I get plenty of days off.
Speaker 0: for all that I get a month of vacation plus my holidays plus my long-term sip sick, which is totally separate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most people don't get all that in this crazy country.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even then that's nothing compared to what you should be getting which is like three months of vacation.
Speaker 1: Yes, the problem is that has a lot of ramifications for our economy Except for the fact that you would probably do just as much work no matter how much vacation They gave you.
Speaker 0: no because most people wouldn't?
Speaker 1: Those people don't deserve to work or have money or have houses.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get into argument with this with you because you probably haven't thought this through at all, but anyway UPS sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, luckily this doesn't affect me at all because when I buy things that are more expensive than a few hundred dollars I usually buy them in person.
Speaker 1: There's no way to buy this laptop in person or from any other company.
Speaker 1: There's only one way to obtain it.
Speaker 0: Well, this problem only affects you so I can't really say that I care very much.
Speaker 1: There might be other products you want in the future that are only obtainable from one source.
Speaker 0: Not really I'm kind of a skin flint and I don't buy I've.
Speaker 0: I never buy a laptop so it won't matter.
Speaker 1: You don't buy anything so you really don't count.
Speaker 0: I spend all my money on food and books and things.
Speaker 1: yeah I buy food and books and other things also.
Speaker 0: I buy a lot more food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever okay, so in the news Alright, my news is spoilerific if you care about underwear pervert comics Whatever.
Speaker 0: It was on all the main news, so it's not a spoiler.
Speaker 1: This is why it's my news because all the underwear pervert fans were like OMG.
Speaker 1: Why is the mainstream news always spoiling our comics?
Speaker 1: for us like don't go to yahoo.com?
Speaker 1: It's on the front page.
Speaker 1: everybody don't go there.
Speaker 1: There's a spoiler?
Speaker 0: Well, maybe because the comic industry well the underwear pervert industry because indie comics don't do this.
Speaker 0: obviously They use character deaths as a means of promoting their products because it means that whenever they kill a big character They'll get into the media.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz okay, so let's spoil it right now.
Speaker 1: They killed Captain America.
Speaker 0: OMG probably temporarily.
Speaker 0: they admitted straight up that it's not unlikely that he won't come back.
Speaker 1: We should just start a betting pool Where if you like guess the month where he's coming back you win like a hundred bucks And if you guess the exact comic and issue he comes back you win like the whole Jackpot, but see
Speaker 0: no one would bother because there's a much easier way to win a hundred bucks by betting getting Dave and Joel to attempt to beat us at air hot.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's pretty stupid.
Speaker 1: it shows that superhero comics really don't have anything going for them.
Speaker 1: You know especially like if you read the stories the mainstream media is writing about it They're pretty like they're showing their contempt for the superhero comics that we also have.
Speaker 1: It's like uh most people think this is pretty stupid.
Speaker 1: They don't care.
Speaker 1: It's just that the there are certain superheroes who are also happen to be sort of these national icons in a way that a lot of characters are like.
Speaker 0: you know Snoopy or Garfield or Lots of care Mickey Mouse, and you know see other than the spider-man other than the x-men and a few of the DC guys.
Speaker 0: I really can't name many underwear perverts anyway.
Speaker 1: I can't name that many either.
Speaker 1: compared to you know underwear pervert fans.
Speaker 1: I can pretty much name the major guys, and that's it
Speaker 0: if I start throwing around semi random combinations of words colors And it's
Speaker 1: almost guaranteed you're gonna name something especially if it's like blank man blank woman super something
Speaker 0: flash man Bottle man fat man,
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure there's a fat man.
Speaker 0: There's got to be a fat man captain something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, captain man, but anyway it just shows how shallow and lame Superhero comics are yet again where the only way they can sell anything is by Killing off iconic characters, and then they bring them back because without the iconic character.
Speaker 1: They have nothing to sell.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean when died at the end of No there wasn't a press release.
Speaker 0: no anime company was like guess who died an episode People just get the story, and there's no media circus.
Speaker 0: anytime a major character dies, or there's a plot development.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, we just we think it's dumb.
Speaker 1: We don't like it.
Speaker 1: This is why we don't buy those comics or read them or condone reading them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not to say that we don't read comics.
Speaker 0: I mean We're finally due to popular demand reviewing a comic again tonight because I finally got rimmed to read one.
Speaker 0: Also our friend I don't reminded us when we were talking about how all comic convention on the East Coast suck.
Speaker 0: Mocha doesn't suck in fact.
Speaker 0: It's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Didn't we mention mocha?
Speaker 0: I think we mentioned the San Diego comic-con.
Speaker 1: I think I don't know.
Speaker 1: I remember saying something about mocha in a recent episode.
Speaker 1: I don't remember what or when.
Speaker 0: probably we were talking about an artist or dr.. McNinja or something.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mocha.
Speaker 1: There's the Museum of comics with a car cartoon comics and cartoon art which is in New York City.
Speaker 1: I think he used to be in Florida I don't remember But it's a pretty cool museum and every year they have many events.
Speaker 1: one of those events is the comic festival.
Speaker 0: granted There's almost no underwear perverts at it and the people who attend and the people who?
Speaker 0: Well attend as guests are generally a very different crowd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty much all indie comics and webcomics people all hanging out having a good time And you're just gonna see awesome stuff there And you're not gonna see too many underwear perverts.
Speaker 0: it also doesn't cost a lot of money compared to what you get.
Speaker 1: It's also of course it does only take a few hours to see everything there But you can spend a lot of time talking to people and hanging out with cool people and not being scared by Nerdy people.
Speaker 0: also, it's in a lively part of New York City as opposed to at the Javits So there's stuff around.
Speaker 1: yeah, cuz it doesn't need.
Speaker 1: it's not big enough to fit into a Jeff It's it doesn't need to be there.
Speaker 0: But anyway speaking of Manhattan last weekend Emily And I went to the children's film festival in New York City where we saw the American premiere of Toki wo kakaru Shojo aka the girl who leapt through time.
Speaker 0: It's an anime movie directed by Mamoru Hosoda, and it's very much about what the title Would lead you to believe.
Speaker 0: it is about a girl who for various reasons Acquires the ability to jump a little bit backwards in time.
Speaker 0: It was really really cool.
Speaker 0: I very much enjoyed it and if any of you live anywhere near New York City I'd highly recommend that you attend the New York Children's Film Festival.
Speaker 0: But we only went to see this movie and the short before it just because it was actually difficult to get tickets to anything And we didn't really realize we were gonna go until fairly shortly before just to see this film.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a children's film festival.
Speaker 1: Is this like a children's movie?
Speaker 0: Well, no I mean they.
Speaker 0: it's a children's film festival.
Speaker 0: bring your children to it and it has shorts aimed at various ages of children ranging from Little kids to young adults and this is an anime That's light-hearted enough even though it is kind of dark at times to be shown at a festival for children.
Speaker 0: It's a just a generally good movie.
Speaker 1: How come like?
Speaker 1: no one heard about this movie and I never heard of it.
Speaker 0: You'd heard of it.
Speaker 0: Emily talked about it a lot And then we both talked about it quite a bit when we got back from seeing it and we talked about it when you Went to see it and she told you about it specifically after she saw it over the summer.
Speaker 1: I don't remember that all right, but yeah, it wasn't unlike any anime news or anything like that.
Speaker 0: There was brave story.
Speaker 1: really brave story.
Speaker 1: was there a little bit on the news.
Speaker 1: It was just a tiny bit, but this one was like non-existent.
Speaker 0: Well, this is very much a better movie than that and I highly recommend it.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's kind of weird though how like anime used to be all about anime movies like remember in the 90s like almost every anime You saw was an anime movie.
Speaker 0: Well part of that was that a movie is a lot easier to promote because it's a single unified thing.
Speaker 0: You could throw it as one thing sell it as one thing.
Speaker 0: you don't need people to buy in or continue wanting it.
Speaker 0: You only need them to buy in once immediately and once they've bought it.
Speaker 0: You don't care anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true But nowadays, I mean the rate of anime movie production hasn't really declined.
Speaker 1: They make quite a few anime movies every year at least a handful But we're not seeing as many of them brought over.
Speaker 1: I mean the Miyazaki's always make it over.
Speaker 0: What movies aren't we seeing coming over then?
Speaker 0: Brave story this one any other anime movie made in recent years And I'm sure that both of these are gonna be released on DVD over here eventually.
Speaker 1: I don't know man.
Speaker 1: There's barely any talk about them.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, whenever even the lowliest new anime series that's on TV like that's on the two in the morning in Japan It's a shit ton of coverage.
Speaker 0: movies probably also cost a lot more to license I'd imagine.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I wonder what that's a good good point there.
Speaker 0: Well too bad We can't find out because the American anime companies will not talk about anything ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I would be interested to find out.
Speaker 1: you know I mean, you know, we kind of know we're how much it costs to license an episode of an anime.
Speaker 1: I wonder how much it costs to license a movie.
Speaker 1: That's hmm.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this movie is really really good.
Speaker 0: The.
Speaker 0: the animation is beautiful.
Speaker 0: The characters are extremely well done.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed it very very much.
Speaker 0: I would probably put it in my top 10 anime movie list.
Speaker 0: I got to think a little bit more and I'd like to see it one more time.
Speaker 0: But if you get a chance to see this you find a torrent or it comes out on DVD.
Speaker 0: pick it up.
Speaker 0: It is so worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah We should definitely Keep track of what anime movies are coming out so we can spread the word because no one else seems to be doing so things of the day.
Speaker 0: So yesterday I had this kind of tutorial video about super dodgeball for the NES.
Speaker 0: Well, I had another thing for the thing.
Speaker 0: today like I often do just before the show I look on dig and I saw something so compelling that I just had to share this with the world.
Speaker 0: Now it was a video purporting a trick to pad out research papers or any sort of paper.
Speaker 0: You're writing for a class in college high school middle school, whatever, you know, I gotta say something.
Speaker 1: I went through elementary school middle school high school and five years of college and I had to write many papers.
Speaker 1: I think the longest one I was ever as to write was I think maybe ten pages.
Speaker 1: Really yes, and I I never had a problem Writing that many pages or more and I never used any silly tricks to extend the length of the paper.
Speaker 1: You know to be more pages.
Speaker 1: besides, you know writing more I did once.
Speaker 0: I had a 15 page paper as a research paper.
Speaker 0: I forget what it was, but something to do with Propaganda and that sort of thing like controlling the media.
Speaker 0: I forget exactly what it was, but I wrote a really good paper Except it was about a page short and there was nothing I wanted to add to the paper.
Speaker 0: So I made the margins on 16th of an inch bigger on both sides and that made it the requisite number of pages.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I also don't want to start a big debate about this but it is my opinion that requiring any particular length on papers is sort of silly and Teachers should just read your paper and determine if what you said was intelligent and complete.
Speaker 0: Yes, I might give a guide like.
Speaker 0: I expect this paper to be around 15 pages.
Speaker 1: I mean obviously if you hand in one page that you probably didn't say enough or maybe it's you just single-spaced Font-sized forward it.
Speaker 0: that's true.
Speaker 1: You might have done that in which case I can't read it.
Speaker 1: You better Do something about that.
Speaker 0: Well, first off I probably wouldn't accept papers except an electronic format.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and an non.
Speaker 1: it would be an open format only.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't accept no word doc files.
Speaker 0: Well, if you wouldn't accept no word doc files the I know right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're gonna be accepting and grading papers sometime in the near future.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I saw this video the guy purporting like I'm gonna tell you how to pad out your papers.
Speaker 0: I expected this to be some crap, you know make the margins bigger.
Speaker 1: I thought it was gonna be some cool thing where Like he has a script that looks at the words in your paper and goes on Wikipedia and grab some random Sentences and tosses a man or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but no no This kid was actually pretty clever and he doesn't just tell you how to do it straight up He tells you how to do it in the same kind of documentary.
Speaker 0: How-to tutorial style.
Speaker 0: is that dodgeball thing?
Speaker 0: and the actual technique he uses is basically to take all the you know 12-point font periods.
Speaker 0: you've got and Up them to 14 and it'll give you quite a bit of padding without making any noticeable change to the paper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean already there are things.
Speaker 1: see I said I never used any tricks to make the paper longer.
Speaker 1: That's true because you're supposed to have such in like one inch margins.
Speaker 1: You're supposed to have a 12-point Times New Roman font double space You're supposed to double space it and you're supposed to put two spaces after every period.
Speaker 0: by the way By the way to all of you in the forums They're only like four or five of you that do this but put two spaces between your sentences not why?
Speaker 1: Paragraphs not sentences.
Speaker 0: No between sentences.
Speaker 1: Oh after the periods.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought okay Never mind, not to carriage returns.
Speaker 1: Yes, you want to put two returns between the paragraphs because putting just one makes it hard to read on the Internet's.
Speaker 0: of course I've always done that in any paper I've ever written for the most part.
Speaker 0: I never used standard indentation rules.
Speaker 0: I always use business style block notation or block paragraphs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I always in debt on you.
Speaker 1: normally when I'm writing I do the the block type stuff on like on the Internet's.
Speaker 1: But when I wrote papers for school, I indented the first line by like a half inch or so.
Speaker 1: But yeah increasing the size of all the periods the 14 point when your font is 12 point will Be not noticeable to the eye unless it's a trained Typographical person.
Speaker 0: and even then I mean he shows the zoom in and he goes into great detail and there's almost no way this would be noticed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had a teacher once who claimed that they were like an editor of a newspaper and our printer and they knew all This shit so that if you fooled around they could tell just by looking at it.
Speaker 1: I'm sure yeah I didn't really believe them so much.
Speaker 1: All right my thing of the day It's actually it's sort of an advertisement for someone that I've never spoken to.
Speaker 1: so it's basically I'm just chilling for no reason.
Speaker 1: Some company named digital meme who I've never heard of is putting out a for DVD set called the Japanese anime classic collection.
Speaker 1: It's coming out April 27 supposedly It's an all region set with you know, it obviously has Japanese dialogue, but the subtitles are English Japanese Chinese and Korean.
Speaker 1: it's NTSC only.
Speaker 1: So if you live somewhere with pal, you're probably not gonna be able to watch it without a converter and It's gonna be like a hundred and ten dollars or so and you can pre-order it now.
Speaker 1: now What is on this DVD you ask?
Speaker 1: Well, it basically has the oldest anime Possible.
Speaker 1: I look the oldest anime on here is from 1928. it's called Tyree Tairiki Taro no mucha Shugyo.
Speaker 0: So basically it's a collection of early Japanese animation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the latest anime on there is like 1950 and there are some that they don't know when they're from and I think there are 55 Anime in total.
Speaker 1: some of them are silent movies.
Speaker 1: some of them have like a narrator like reading things.
Speaker 1: I guess if you I don't know maybe some anime if you went to see them in the theater and like the 30s of the 40s.
Speaker 1: there were narrators there.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling we'll be buying this and then reviewing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah They also have some on there that are what are known as Gramophone talkies where in addition to sending the film to the movie theater They would send a record to the movie theater and they would start the film and a gramophone player separately.
Speaker 1: at the same time.
Speaker 1: They basically what these people have done is taken those gramophone records and the film Synchronized them and now you can watch them on a DVD with the audio.
Speaker 0: But see now the P. the purists will be mad because you got to have in the original format.
Speaker 0: You got to have the vinyl and the gramophone and the film.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it's not the authentic experience and you have to say you won't get the full panning through the center channel And you have to sit there and play with.
Speaker 1: you have to actually go buy a gramophone.
Speaker 1: a regular turntable won't do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just you know, it doesn't look like this is gonna bring, you know hours upon hours of entertainment.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know as much as I love steamboat Willie It's really not that entertaining these days even though I really really like it.
Speaker 0: I don't know steamboat.
Speaker 0: Itchy is always good to watch steamboat.
Speaker 1: Itchy is fantastic with steamboat Willie.
Speaker 1: Not so much.
Speaker 1: So watching these watching these is gonna be a lot more entertaining in the Historical documentary type fashion that it will be in the anime watching fashion.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I'm probably gonna get it anyway, and if you are interested in old Oh Incredibly old Incredibly old anime then you should probably buy this as well.
Speaker 0: So Scott how many amusing or exciting anecdotes have you lived that you'd be able to relate during an evening with friends?
Speaker 0: a lot You see.
Speaker 0: that is the operative question in why are you doing this by Jason?
Speaker 0: Which is what we're going to review tonight?
Speaker 0: I'll more than one of you have pointed out that we haven't reviewed too many comics lately Partly due to the fact that I read very few comics.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much the only reason.
Speaker 1: if rim read more comics You could have more comics to review than we knew what to do it.
Speaker 0: granted We also realized that in all this time.
Speaker 0: We've never talked about Watchmen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna do that as soon as whoever borrowed it gives it back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or maybe it's in the house somewhere.
Speaker 0: I got to do some searching.
Speaker 1: cuz I have piles of books in various place I'm actually considering shelling out the huge pile of money to get the big giant Oversized hardcover edition the absolute one.
Speaker 0: Does that come with anything?
Speaker 1: it comes of its big.
Speaker 1: it's better printing better.
Speaker 0: They come with anything other than just being a better version of itself.
Speaker 1: I think it has some extras in it.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll look it up.
Speaker 1: All right, but it's it's huge.
Speaker 1: It's like bigger than an Atlas.
Speaker 1: It's it's Atlas sized and it's a big thick hardcover and it's almost $100.
Speaker 1: But I can get it for like 40% off.
Speaker 0: But why are you doing?
Speaker 0: this is a short comic by Jason.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: Jason who was born in Norway But lives now in France like most can tune it.
Speaker 0: cartoonists his glasses and his balding.
Speaker 1: and that's all we know about Jason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because that's all it says in this book and I looked around online.
Speaker 0: I didn't find much more about it.
Speaker 0: granted I didn't search very much.
Speaker 0: What I did discover is that much like Cher or Prince Jason's only name apparently is Jason.
Speaker 1: He seems to be a creator of comics most of them anthropomorphic but not in the porn way.
Speaker 1: in the the Looney Tunes.
Speaker 0: Okay way, I hate the fact that when you say anthropomorphic you have to add and not in the porn way.
Speaker 1: Yes It's definitely not in the porn way.
Speaker 1: It couldn't be further from the porn way.
Speaker 1: This is less porn than Looney Tunes or Mickey Mouse.
Speaker 0: It's almost.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't call it noir But it gives me that feeling.
Speaker 1: Yeah kind.
Speaker 0: I mean everything's very dark and subdued and all the characters are very expressionless and sad and Everything's kind of melancholy and dark the whole way through.
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of it.
Speaker 1: Is that while it's the art is anthropomorphic.
Speaker 1: I mean you got dog people and bird people and rabbit people.
Speaker 1: those seem to be the only three and It does see I didn't notice any others.
Speaker 1: Do you do you?
Speaker 0: well, I didn't see any others even in the covers of other books.
Speaker 0: He's done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but everything and you know, it's drawn in a very cartoonish style.
Speaker 1: I mean he only colors with a bucket tool it seems but he's very good at choosing what colors he puts where You know.
Speaker 1: so that when it's nighttime, everything's darker and when it's daytime, everything's bright, you know.
Speaker 1: but he's only using the bucket tool as far as I can tell to do all the coloring.
Speaker 1: and Yet what happens is very real and very gritty and not unrealistic in any fashion.
Speaker 1: and it's completely And plus.
Speaker 0: while they can I mean the character designs are Incredibly incredibly simple and expressionless and yet they can convey a lot of emotion just for the way He uses them and the way they emote while they talk.
Speaker 1: I mean look at the feet the all these animal people.
Speaker 1: their eyes are just white holes And he sort of alters their size and position.
Speaker 1: you know to change where the people are looking and he does a lot with the mouths and the hair and Like the bodies like.
Speaker 1: I could pretty almost draw some of these characters that they're so simple.
Speaker 1: But the way like the poses he has them in in each panel.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know exactly what's going down.
Speaker 1: He doesn't need to make it any more complex to get across the story And at the same time the poses are very natural.
Speaker 0: the way the characters walk and act are much more like real people as opposed To a lot of comics where everything's very stylized.
Speaker 0: in that regard.
Speaker 0: I mean the main character is usually Slouching or sitting kind of looking down or away or generally not standing in any sort of cool or interesting position.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think that goes right along with the fact that all of the words in this comic all the writing mostly the dialogue is perfectly natural and Real world dialogue.
Speaker 1: Well, it kind of throws you off because you don't see that in a comic like even great Non-underwear pervert comics don't have dialogue like this.
Speaker 1: It's like whoa.
Speaker 0: I mean the cadences are natural The writing is simple and it's almost Hemingway esque in that the way the characters interact and the things they say to each other are just so short terse cut and dry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is similar to Hemingway.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: Also Hemingway is brought up in during the course of this comic.
Speaker 1: Oh is oh, yes Yeah, I just remember that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean the thing I said at the beginning is a direct quote that pretty much Tells you what this comic is about in a very broad sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well they bring that quote up like two or three times during the story to sort of say Hey, this is what I'm trying to say in sort of you know, except he's not Yeah, it's the only thing he does non subtly I think in the whole book.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is he's.
Speaker 0: it doesn't appear that he's trying to say anything particular.
Speaker 0: It's more that he's brought up an issue and he's explored the issue from about three or four different angles But he doesn't actually conclude with the typical and this is the way you should look at here.
Speaker 0: Here's how I feel.
Speaker 0: He just says like you end and you think well, isn't that interesting?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I don't.
Speaker 1: I think he is trying to say something.
Speaker 1: It's just that the thing he's trying to say is a question and not an answer.
Speaker 1: I don't follow you as in I'm trying to say something.
Speaker 1: the thing I'm trying to say is a question mark at the end of It as opposed to saying something like this is the way it is.
Speaker 1: But is this the way it is?
Speaker 0: I don't think that's any different from what I just said where basically he raises a question and then looks at it from a few different Perspectives.
Speaker 1: this comic is really short.
Speaker 1: It's maybe what like 50 pages.
Speaker 1: you think 40 pages something like that?
Speaker 0: Well almost I mean they list a bunch of his other works in the back and they all range from 64 pages to a Hundred or so pages.
Speaker 0: They're not very one of them's 48 pages.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: They're all about the same length.
Speaker 1: I think I'm definitely gonna get some of those other works after reading this one.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: They're from Fantagraphics books Fantagraphics.com.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all his stuff is published by Fantagraphics who also publishes lots of other awesome things.
Speaker 1: But I forget any specifics now, but I know I have some I just don't remember what they are right now.
Speaker 0: Now basically, this is the story of two four.
Speaker 0: It starts out There are two friends.
Speaker 0: one of them apparently has been dumped by his girlfriend or has broken up with her there.
Speaker 0: They don't really go into exactly what happened But you can kind of piece together as the comic goes on exactly why he's down in the dumps.
Speaker 0: So he's doing that typical.
Speaker 0: I'm a depressed guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, no his girl trouble thing.
Speaker 0: So he's basically schlubbing it living alone in his house not going out not going to a job sitting around watching King Kong Sitting on the couch being a bum and he's got his smart cool friend.
Speaker 0: He was basically trying to knock him out of this slump and get him to get on with his life.
Speaker 1: That's that friend is very smart and very awesome.
Speaker 0: So then the friend goes out of town for a little bit and he's worried about him.
Speaker 0: So as a kind of a plot to get him outside doing things again He asks him to water his plants while he's gone.
Speaker 0: So no big deal.
Speaker 0: He goes to water his plants.
Speaker 0: I can't really say what happens from that point on without spoiling it but something Momentous occurs and the plot takes off from there.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's sort of hard with such a short comic to reveal any plot deals Details whatsoever because it's like the first plot.
Speaker 1: detail is like a Quarter of the way through the book and that gives away the whole thing And then there's no point in reading it.
Speaker 0: if I tell you what happened Suffice to say I highly recommend this and I'm actually looking forward to reading pretty much everything else.
Speaker 0: This guy's written this comic for as short as it is tells a compelling story from start to finish Very succinctly and very well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I agree with one of the quotes on the back of the book that said it was Hitchcock.
Speaker 0: That is a very good way to describe it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you like like Alfred Hitchcock type of stuff where or like likes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where there's sort of a complex criminal element going on where you don't know who's on what side or what people want or You're not sure which character is really doing what but you see them do some things and you get some ideas And maybe there's a twist at the end.
Speaker 0: It's definitely a thriller though.
Speaker 0: It's much more subdued than what you might expect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like while there were Some things were happening in the comic where in any other comic would be sort of fast paced and high energy.
Speaker 1: But here, you know, even though things were tense.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like I didn't feel like I was rushing.
Speaker 1: It was like moving along at the same pace the whole time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the pace of this thing is generally very slow.
Speaker 0: You're kind of drawn from panel to panel at this steady slow rate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the panels are also all the normal square panels.
Speaker 1: He didn't do a lot of you know, fancy manga style weird shape panels.
Speaker 0: Everything is very simple spreads I mean from the character designs to the art to the backgrounds to the panel design to the dot.
Speaker 0: Everything is just extremely simple.
Speaker 1: So the art doesn't in any way distract you from the story and the story is about as high quality as a comic story can be.
Speaker 0: Now before we end this slightly short episode I like to take incredibly short episode point out that we do have a contest running.
Speaker 0: We announced it last week and we're going to continue it for a while.
Speaker 0: The contest is very simple.
Speaker 0: MD.
Speaker 0: Geist is the second worst anime ever made.
Speaker 0: There is no arguing or disputing that.
Speaker 0: I think everyone in the world agrees.
Speaker 0: the UN is ruled.
Speaker 0: the United States Congress has passed a bill the Constitution of every country in the world that has a constitution has been amended.
Speaker 0: MD.
Speaker 0: Geist is it?
Speaker 0: the question is What is the worst anime that you have ever seen?
Speaker 0: We're not asking about what is the worst anime ever because that is Nearly as interesting.
Speaker 0: is the worst anime that you have personally seen all the way through?
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I mean I could go out on the internet and find out about some hentai.
Speaker 1: Where horrible things happen in the animation is blah or I could go out and watch earthy in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of bad anime I could go find out about but it's not often unless your name is Dave and or Joel that you sit around watching bad anime on purpose, so There are very few terrible animes that I've personally seen although there are some.
Speaker 1: So we want to hear about the worst anime you've actually seen and why?
Speaker 1: Don't just tell us what the anime is because a lot of people are just like oh this anime.
Speaker 1: Now you got to tell us all about it.
Speaker 1: Tell us why it was bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, give us details.
Speaker 0: If you're not sure what kind of details we want check out anime world orders.
Speaker 0: review of MD Geist.
Speaker 0: That is what we want to hear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't just and also don't just tell us about the anime and why it was bad.
Speaker 1: Tell us the story of how you watched it and how you were feeling when you watched it.
Speaker 1: Yes, and what you did after you watched it.
Speaker 1: I mean even if you finished watching was it?
Speaker 0: your parents went to the store knew that you like those animations saw wicked city and decided hey I'll buy this for little Jimmy or Was it?
Speaker 0: you're hanging out in college with your friend Scott who decides to bring over some anime that turns out to be porn?
Speaker 1: Or were you at an anime convention and they were guy was selling DVDs for a dollar.
Speaker 1: So you figured what the hell.
Speaker 1: how can this be so bad?
Speaker 1: and then you spend a dollar and wish you hadn't Or you listen to this show.
Speaker 0: when we told you not to watch something then you decided to watch it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, despite all warnings great digital target.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't think many of our listeners have bothered to watch a great digital target, which is good You shouldn't you know, we've only seen it once even though it was probably the worst anime we've ever seen.
Speaker 0: I don't I mean Len mere is right up there.
Speaker 1: The legend of levity are is bad But I don't think it's great digital target or
Speaker 0: the lens min which
Speaker 1: while
Speaker 0: I've seen the lens min Seven or eight times over the course of my life I have never seen it all at the same time without falling asleep at some point during it.
Speaker 1: Well, the books are really good here at least He's not.
Speaker 0: well, I don't know if the movies that bad.
Speaker 0: I always fall asleep about three-quarters of the way through.
Speaker 0: then I wake up at the end and I have no idea what's going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anime some anime just bad.
Speaker 1: What can you do now?
Speaker 0: Of course, whoever gives us the best story here will win the original soundtrack to MD Geist.
Speaker 1: Why would someone want to enter then?
Speaker 0: because as Dave and Joel pointed out the music's actually okay.
Speaker 1: Oh, is it really?
Speaker 1: I didn't listen to what.
Speaker 1: we just kind of ripped the mp3s off of the thing and it's not the best Music ever but it plus.
Speaker 0: I mean you get the actual original CD with all the liner notes and fun stuff.
Speaker 0: Now if someone gives us a particularly good entry to where you don't only win, but you super win I'm gonna include the genocidal st as well, which I also have laying around.
Speaker 1: We also ripped the mp3s off of that.
Speaker 0: I don't know how the music is because CPM apparently was trying to murder me as you might have found out when we reviewed the New York comic-con.
Speaker 1: Yeah way to go CPM.
Speaker 0: So I guess in conclusion for this Wednesday.
Speaker 0: I almost said anime world order.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's it for this episode of anime world order.
Speaker 0: Yeah tune in next week when we'll talk about three more obscure things You'll never be able to buy in a store.
Speaker 0: Make sure if you get a chance check out.
Speaker 0: Why are you doing this by Jason?
Speaker 0: and if you get a chance check out the girl who left through time?
Speaker 0: Excellent movie excellent comic.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.