Speaker 0: It's Thursday October 11th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about our fantastical dumpster diving adventure.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: rain today Rain tomorrow, right?
Speaker 0: You know rain is awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna dwell on this I'm not gonna do what I always do and talk about all the crazy traffic I saw or whatever.
Speaker 0: But it still bothers me that every time there's even a small amount of rain in downstate, New York There's like a hundred car accidents immediately on every Parkway.
Speaker 1: because when the snow people do try to drive more carefully They don't.
Speaker 0: well even more accidents.
Speaker 1: Well, that's because people suck at it, but they do.
Speaker 1: you know these people who don't a lot of people without SUVs You know.
Speaker 1: they realize that there's snow and they drive a little slower right when there's rain.
Speaker 1: You will drive as normal.
Speaker 1: They don't even think that the you know.
Speaker 1: they don't understand just how slippery the road can be when it's just wet Especially like if you know oil's been building up on the road for many weeks, and then it rained suddenly and slippery shit.
Speaker 0: I do have to say that I mean usually it's just ah someone stupid caused an accident But I actually got a little bit of a close-up encounter with the people involved in the accident that held me up for an hour And a half this morning.
Speaker 0: Oh, and uh I laughed out loud and the cop looked at me.
Speaker 0: So basically there's this bridge.
Speaker 0: There's only two ways to get to New York City from here unless you take like the New York State Thruway Which I'm not unless you cross the Hudson and then cross the Hudson again Which would mean I have to take 287 which is a nice road in Jersey.
Speaker 0: But if any of you are ever in the state of New York And you see a road that is called Interstate 287 and it is very useful road But it is a Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday or Friday Ah Don't go anywhere near it.
Speaker 0: I'm tapping.
Speaker 1: all hope happens.
Speaker 1: He bridges included on that road You enter here.
Speaker 0: that is the worst road in the world.
Speaker 1: It's very useful though It goes like straight across.
Speaker 0: you need to go you need to get somewhere.
Speaker 0: That's the road except that it's not actually a road.
Speaker 0: It's a parking lot.
Speaker 0: It's a 20 mile long parking lot that goes across the Hudson River and the Tappan Zee bridge is real long.
Speaker 0: So if you have to pee and you get stuck on that bridge I have sat on the Tappan Zee bridge for more than an hour.
Speaker 1: They actually have installed a thing on the Tappan Zee bridge years and years ago where if they can drive this truck down the middle Of the bridge and it moves that barrier
Speaker 0: so scary if you see it moving Yeah,
Speaker 1: it basically moves these giant concrete slabs to the right or to the left to add lanes to the inbound or outbound.
Speaker 1: You know You can subtract a lane from the inbound and add a lane to the outbound or vice versa.
Speaker 0: It throws those concrete blocks and they're pretty big.
Speaker 1: it's just a thing that goes forward really slowly and it picks up blocks and moves them back and forth and Eventually, you know, it moves block block block block eventually moves the entire lane barrier.
Speaker 1: But they have that and it still doesn't help.
Speaker 0: Well part of that is because even if all the lanes were going in one direction and they just didn't let people go the other Direction, it's still too many cars.
Speaker 0: Yep, but so I'm driving I'm stuck in for like an hour in this traffic horrible Whatever and I eventually get up to the bridge and I see oh, there's an accident on the bridge.
Speaker 0: Oh, it looks like the police just arrived probably because they had to fight through the same traffic.
Speaker 0: I've been sitting in and It's like five cars in a line and they all hit each other except the guy in the front who did was didn't call.
Speaker 0: I mean the guy in the front was the only one who can't be blamed because he didn't hit anyone He didn't do anything wrong.
Speaker 1: All right, so, you know, I mean, why did the guy behind it?
Speaker 1: The guy in the front hit him in the back.
Speaker 0: probably it was tailgating.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay, probably people don't.
Speaker 0: people just ride.
Speaker 0: people tailgate me all the time.
Speaker 0: And yeah, I'm one of those people who sometimes I'll just make my brake lights turn on without braking and just to see what they do.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of tailgating on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Lots of barbecues out behind trucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you went to that football game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's a tailgating really is.
Speaker 0: so I see that the cop you're talking about is following.
Speaker 0: the cop was talking to the second to last person in this line of accident cars And I roll down my window cuz he's right there.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna drive by it like one mile an hour.
Speaker 0: so I get to hear some of this conversation.
Speaker 0: And as I roll down my window I hear the cop say you realize this accident is mostly your fault and the guy starts going like no It isn't.
Speaker 0: that guy stopped too quick blah blah and the cops like By law.
Speaker 0: if you hit anyone from behind It's your fault because you were following too closely and you were probably speeding.
Speaker 0: and at this point I just started laughing and the cop looked up at me and he didn't have an angry look on his face.
Speaker 0: He just kind of had this look of like, you know I'd probably laughing too if I was you and the guy's officer not allowed to laugh.
Speaker 1: I have to keep this cold and stern demeanor that makes no one like me.
Speaker 0: I have seen police officers crack up on occasion and it's often hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz it's got to be real funny because they practice that stern demeanor.
Speaker 0: Yes, they do.
Speaker 0: They probably go to school for it.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I wanna while I'm remembering before I forget Next week we're gonna do all week is gonna be ask rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: four days We're gonna.
Speaker 1: all we're gonna do is answer questions from you people.
Speaker 1: so if you have some sort of tech question or maybe a video game question or You know If you ask a question make sure you ask it for the right day of the week.
Speaker 1: and if the question isn't a Monday Tuesday Or Wednesday question.
Speaker 1: It's a Thursday question.
Speaker 1: You could ask any question in the whole world.
Speaker 1: Nothing is off-limits Nothing, you could ask anything like what's your social security number?
Speaker 0: I just won't answer or I'd probably make something up or I'll give you Scott.
Speaker 1: one one one one one.
Speaker 0: Actually, if someone asked that I do have a funny answer, but I'm not gonna ruin it.
Speaker 1: in case someone actually asks it I'm sure someone will now that we've talked about it.
Speaker 0: I mean there really is a funny and interesting answer.
Speaker 1: Yep, but if you want Us to actually answer your question on the show.
Speaker 1: Here are some tips.
Speaker 1: Don't ask a question with an incredibly long answer.
Speaker 1: Well, if you do, we'll probably turn it into an entire episode instead of doing you just a question.
Speaker 1: Don't ask a question that could be answered with a Google search.
Speaker 1: Don't answer.
Speaker 1: don't ask a question that has been answered on a previous episode of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Don't ask a stupid question.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I can't really think of anything else while rim is getting up What looks like a Rico law?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know why I'm just coughing a lot tonight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually have the throat sickness I guess cuz it migrated from the nose to the throat I guess with an overnight drip, but I'm not coughing nearly as much as rim is.
Speaker 0: I've said the sudden coughing thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I gave it to you.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, cuz that one thread in our forum isn't gonna go alight with the idea of Scott giving me a disease of the mouth Mana.
Speaker 0: So I've already had mono.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so yeah ask us questions in the forum or by email And I guess we're gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make the deadline actually I think Sunday because on Sunday, I'm gonna sort of combine all the questions to Sunday.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say Saturday at midnight say, okay, so that's even for the.
Speaker 1: you want to even make that even for the Thursdays also.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if we don't get it by Saturday like late That's what I'm gonna go through and sort of you know, get all the questions together.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I'm sure you know you might ask a really good Thursday question on Wednesday and I might see it.
Speaker 1: and I guess if it's really good and I Notice it then I'll throw it in.
Speaker 1: but I'm gonna compile the real list on Saturday.
Speaker 1: So or Sunday something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we did this kind of thing a long time ago.
Speaker 0: It was super fun and really popular.
Speaker 0: We want to do it again.
Speaker 0: And also we we used to plan ahead geek nights.
Speaker 0: we actually have a whole internal system of planning ahead geek nights and we've been busy for a while and we hit the end of that geek nights planning last week and We've just been kind of winging it since then Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So so what do you got in the news?
Speaker 0: Cuz I got almost nothing.
Speaker 1: Well, there's this basketball player named Gilbert arenas.
Speaker 1: That's all I know about him is that he's a basketball player and he's I guess he's good and somewhat famous At least in the NBA United States, whatever, right?
Speaker 1: So This guy he plays the halo 3. a lot of people are playing the halo 3.
Speaker 1: They've made 300 million dollars off the stupid game.
Speaker 1: A lot of people are playing it.
Speaker 1: not surprising that a famous NBA player would be playing it.
Speaker 1: He could afford it.
Speaker 1: Apparently he was according to a lot of I guess Evidence that we have here even though it seems to be anecdotal evidence, but it seems to be pretty certain that he cheated.
Speaker 1: What this guy was doing is he would start a game of halo 3 have his friends join Then his friends would leave and he would win and this would make his rank go up.
Speaker 0: That's You realize that that went on in the 90s on like the CLQ and all those things And I guess he could afford a whole bunch of Xboxes.
Speaker 1: so he could really like make a machine out of it.
Speaker 0: In fact, I did that once to see if it would work.
Speaker 0: We made a server that gave you a whole like more points than you should have gotten for everything And a few of us just played on it all the time and sure enough I was.
Speaker 0: there was a time when I was in the top 10 according to the CLQ of like weapons factory players in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hardly cheating.
Speaker 1: So because Xbox Live makes all these things like really obvious, you know, they're like, huh?
Speaker 1: well look at that.
Speaker 1: and someone says that like they were invited into his party and then they Got booted once he got there and then he noticed what was going on and he uncovered the whole thing.
Speaker 0: So, uh, who cares no one.
Speaker 1: but I just think it's a pretty interesting sort of.
Speaker 0: There's all sorts of drama about oh now he was outed now But there's forums all over the internet that are all abuzz about that.
Speaker 1: well I'm actually the news I'm getting is from a forum where the guy is saying that he discovered this and They let me reload it actually because it might have increased.
Speaker 1: Hold on.
Speaker 1: I think these are actually the official halo forums.
Speaker 1: It's Bungie dotnet Wow, the.
Speaker 1: there are currently 32 pages in this forum thread where they uncovered his cheating ways.
Speaker 0: See it's kind of like with forums how the conventional wisdom in forums was always to have like a post count thing or some sort of ranking system and Video games do the same thing often because a lot of people want that.
Speaker 1: but well The reason they do it is because I think blizzard started it with Warcraft 3 at least that's the first one that worked is Where they wouldn't rank you.
Speaker 1: they would rank you to say who's the best in the world and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But mostly there was a ranking so that if you wanted to play Warcraft 3 and you were a nub You would get matched up with nubs instead of getting matched up with gods, you know Cuz before used to be random who you'd match up with?
Speaker 1: all you know is their name.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah The only point I was getting is that whenever you have a way to may have a stat generated by any means That will allow a 12 year old to say that he is better than another 12 year old.
Speaker 0: Every 12 year old is going to try to cheat at that system and someone is going to succeed thus making the system pointless.
Speaker 1: And that's a World of Warcraft is all about.
Speaker 1: is instead of saying Don't do that other out of bounds thing to make the numbers go up.
Speaker 0: here The game is making the numbers go up play it But then notice how many players say it's cheating if you use a bot or if you level with a macro.
Speaker 0: I'm of the mind that if any game will let you level up with a macro then leveling up is not actually an activity.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if the computer can do it, why should I do it?
Speaker 1: Why would I spend my time doing something a computer could do automatically?
Speaker 0: But yeah, we're not going to get into that.
Speaker 0: I think my thoughts on Memorials was perfectly defined by that Richard Garriott thing from yesterday.
Speaker 0: man Scott you're coughing more than I am now.
Speaker 1: Suddenly I agree with you.
Speaker 0: It's kind of passing back and forth here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the passing cough.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should call this episode passing cough Like the twit episode naming scheme.
Speaker 0: It is kind of the twit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what's your news there?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah my news, so I don't.
Speaker 0: the actual article is shit.
Speaker 0: I don't have much to say about it, but there's a lot of meta to talk about around this article.
Speaker 0: So someone made a list and posted it on the internet.
Speaker 1: because a list on the internet?
Speaker 0: because it was about Blogging and all that stuff something about blogging.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: He got dug way the fuck up.
Speaker 1: Well, it meets the dig digging formula.
Speaker 1: I mean about blogs.
Speaker 1: It's a list That's a million digs.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: Perfect.
Speaker 0: No three points.
Speaker 0: the one thing I'd like to note is that this article claims to be 41 reasons why your blog probably sucks and supposed to be.
Speaker 0: you know 41 like things you should do to make a blog better, but All of the advice here is pretty much Here's how to make a blog that will make a bunch of money with Google Ads.
Speaker 0: Here's how to wake a blog.
Speaker 0: It'll make a bunch of money with other ads.
Speaker 0: Here's how to monetize your blog.
Speaker 0: and the other half of this article is Pretty much like the distilled like core of what the blogosphere like.
Speaker 0: everything I hate about the blogosphere everything I hate about all these bloggers Especially at the bottom here.
Speaker 0: this last one Things you should never ever do Openly insult another blogger.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: The blogosphere is a lot smaller than you think.
Speaker 0: Insulting bloggers are calling them out Will backfire on you possibly for longer than you'd expect and this applies to saying things that people misinterpret as insults These people.
Speaker 0: and also there's this whole thing of deep linking and I was like what.
Speaker 0: I don't think they know what deep linking means.
Speaker 0: Cuz they're saying they use this term and in kind of not the right way and I dug a little.
Speaker 1: linking is when say rim has a website with an image on it and then on my website, I Actually put his image in my website.
Speaker 1: that's loaded from his web server.
Speaker 0: or if I want to link to a story on Fox News I don't link to Fox News.
Speaker 0: I link to the story inside of Fox News.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Well now bloggers when they say deep linking what they mean is every time you post an article You should have a bunch of links just within whatever you wrote To other articles on your blog in order to have this incestuous Internal series of links that'll make you better for the spiders and better for Google to find you.
Speaker 1: this whole sort of culture of Search engine optimization and making money from ads.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like these people have this fantasy.
Speaker 1: They want to just blog and type things on the internet and not have to work.
Speaker 0: And yet all these a lot of these bloggers like one of these things talks about don't try to run too many blogs.
Speaker 0: You won't be able to handle it Like anyone will ever have more than one blog.
Speaker 0: you get the impression that these people Want to run like four or five blogs about whatever.
Speaker 0: they don't care what their writing is.
Speaker 0: They just want to make money from ads and be a blogger.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like this.
Speaker 1: actually I would consider Google Adsense to be like a very very popular video game that pays real money and these people Try to figure out like the secrets of Google in order to try to just make more money by typing into.
Speaker 1: you know Their web servers or whatever.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm gonna let them in on a little secret.
Speaker 0: You know how people always rationalize the blocking of ads.
Speaker 0: if like well, I wouldn't block a tasteful ad or blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say that I block Google Ads.
Speaker 0: I block all ads.
Speaker 0: The only ads I can't block are ones that are actually in line text.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: I don't go to websites that have that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I also block all ads.
Speaker 1: So if your website doesn't have useful content, I don't go to it.
Speaker 0: I just this.
Speaker 1: the fact it's actually kind of jarring when I see a website with ads cuz it's like Whoa, that's what that website looks like.
Speaker 0: Oh god, cuz I don't use Windows much.
Speaker 0: So I didn't install any Firefox plugins in my windows.
Speaker 0: I went to a website the other day in Windows and There were ads everywhere.
Speaker 0: The internet is full of ads.
Speaker 1: It's scary.
Speaker 0: I kind of forgot that there's this.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like going into the Wild West without a gun.
Speaker 0: Things of the day, you know.
Speaker 0: way back when I was a kid I went to the Michigan State Fair and at the Michigan State Fair There was a ride.
Speaker 0: I don't remember what this ride was called.
Speaker 0: I got to find out from my mom what it was called because I'd really like to look up the information about this ride.
Speaker 0: But I learned as a kid after the fact that the ride was actually banned in most of the country And it was banned in Michigan not too long after I wrote it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Apparently this ride Super dangerous and is seriously harmed a lot of people in its relatively short tenure as a carny ride.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much like during our Childhood that all the dangerous rides at amusement parks went away.
Speaker 0: and they I was at like Farm City week this little festival in Macomb when There was some ride that I used to ride all the time because I loved it.
Speaker 0: We're like spin, you know, one of those spin you around a bunch rides.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and The two-inch thick chain.
Speaker 0: that kind of drives.
Speaker 0: the whole thing just snapped and flew out into the crowd.
Speaker 0: It didn't hit anyone.
Speaker 0: some by some miracle It just kind of flew out into the crowd and hit a lamppost.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that was kind of scary and my mom never let me ride it again.
Speaker 0: Yep, despite my argument that the safest place to be when that happened was on the ride.
Speaker 0: There's no way it could have hit me there.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm And the fact that it just broke now that they put it just a brand new chain on it's right the safest ride in the park.
Speaker 0: But I'm not gonna talk about the dangerous ride because I don't know the name of it and I don't have all the research.
Speaker 0: What I'm gonna talk about is this video of a ride that while not dangerous Might make even someone like me vomit.
Speaker 1: it would make me vomit I or pass out from dizziness almost guaranteed and granted.
Speaker 0: I have a person who once rode the Gemini at Cedar Point 25 times in a row.
Speaker 1: now the thing with this video is that it's a perfectly normal ride.
Speaker 1: I've seen this ride in many parks.
Speaker 1: I've ridden it once or twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this one is a little different.
Speaker 0: I mean I feel like I should just make you watch the video to be like just watch it and see if you can figure out what?
Speaker 0: Is different about this ride, but I'll just tell you So it starts spinning around upside down and that's what this ride does.
Speaker 1: It's an upside down spinny ride.
Speaker 1: You've probably seen this ride if you've been to amusement park and it doesn't stop.
Speaker 1: someone reprogrammed the ride.
Speaker 0: It just it kind of gets into this cycle where it spins in the perfect way and it just keeps doing it and doing it and the crowd just counts down and Wow, yeah, I mean a man, you know the Viking ship right.
Speaker 1: the Viking ship goes back and forth Right and it's some Viking ships go upside down some of them upside down some of them don't but let's say of an upside-down Viking ship right.
Speaker 1: It's programmed to go one way go over the top three times Go back.
Speaker 1: the other way go over the top three times and then stop right you can just reprogram it to go over the top 200 times in a row.
Speaker 1: and That's sort of what this video is only not the Viking ship.
Speaker 0: Luckily.
Speaker 0: No one vomits.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these see they clapped when they had the ride stop They're like woo and I wasn't sure if they were applauding like yeah, we're awesome or yay.
Speaker 1: This is finally over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So I've been looking for a multi-tool for some time, you know You got the Leatherman's the Gerber's.
Speaker 0: every time we go to Home Depot Scott's like I'm gonna buy one Today's the day and then after 20 minutes, he's like But they're all they're all of them.
Speaker 0: match my purse in the shoes.
Speaker 1: God damn it.
Speaker 1: The thing is none of the.
Speaker 1: you know I've been looking for it with those for a long time and I'm looking for one that has like certain things like I need a Screwdriver and an rj45 crimper.
Speaker 1: Yeah and a plier, you know.
Speaker 1: and it's one knife.
Speaker 1: and oh, you know There's certain things I need and there's things I don't need.
Speaker 1: and it seems like They either have a whole bunch of crap I don't need or they don't have everything I do need.
Speaker 1: or they're too big or they're ugly or they they're too much money Right, so I've sort of held I don't you know, I haven't suffered without one But I think if I did have one in my bag, I'd be using it a lot.
Speaker 1: Well another monkey wrench Pun intended I guess was is just thrown into my multi-tool worries.
Speaker 1: There's a company called Atwood knife and tool and they make multi-tools.
Speaker 1: However, unlike say a Leatherman or a Gerber their multi-tools do not fold open.
Speaker 1: Aha, they are instead just one Solid piece of metal.
Speaker 0: I've seen things like that and that's it.
Speaker 1: and this one piece of metal Which doesn't move and has no joints or anything.
Speaker 0: It's just you can't have pliers or tweezers or anything.
Speaker 1: Nothing that nothing.
Speaker 1: that's moving.
Speaker 1: but you know, it's it's like a screwdriver and a Bottle opener and a knife and It's like five to ten things all at once and that it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: You'd be like a file and It's it's pretty appealing.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's really small.
Speaker 1: It does a whole bunch of things at once and there's no moving parts and that has a cute name Right.
Speaker 0: So both are things that they were kind of lame.
Speaker 0: Let's just get out.
Speaker 1: Once you go go look at it and you'll be more impressed.
Speaker 1: My description was pretty poor.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'll just say that my choices were either what I did or Scott was trying to get me to do a Salt-and-pepper shaker.
Speaker 1: It was only pepper like our 2d2 our 2d2 pepper shakers.
Speaker 1: Isn't that cool?
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 1: I'm getting them, right?
Speaker 0: So One time in college a pepper grinder.
Speaker 0: Sorry kind of on a whim But actually the story of why we did this is kind of interesting into this day.
Speaker 0: I don't know what prompted this.
Speaker 1: Okay Well, basically, but it was the same thing that prompted everything else.
Speaker 1: you go and you people right?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I think you forget that something specific prompted us to do this a Conversation with a website.
Speaker 0: no before that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I think Scott forgot what happened.
Speaker 1: We went so websites were talking about dumpster diving.
Speaker 0: No, no, it was before that.
Speaker 0: It was before that.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Maybe you're making something up.
Speaker 0: No, because I what happened was one day I was sitting at my computer and we had a friend.
Speaker 0: We don't really need to talk to this person anymore but out of the blue he kind of aims me and I'm aiming back a little bit like yeah, whatever we're talking and Then he says something about dumpster diving and I was like what he's like Yeah, you guys should totally go dumpster diving blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: You can make all this money blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: and I was like, why would you?
Speaker 1: because this guy never really aimed me anyway, like I hardly talked to this kid If I always if anyone ever comes up and tells you yeah those online casinos you can totally make money from them It's not bullshit.
Speaker 1: or there's a there's a way you can game the system or yeah If you totally do this, you'll make money if they're not doing what they just told you to do.
Speaker 1: Don't do it They're lying to you.
Speaker 0: I wasn't sure if he did it or not but I talked to him a little bit and I thought just was like, huh and Then it's just dumpster diving stayed in my head and Scott and I started talking about it and we were like Why would he just talk to us about that out of nowhere?
Speaker 1: And if it was really profitable Why isn't he dumpster diving every night?
Speaker 0: and then we wondered is he dumpster diving?
Speaker 0: I wasn't sure.
Speaker 0: I asked him and he kind of said that he did but he wasn't super clear on it.
Speaker 0: I was like, where did you go?
Speaker 0: And he's like, yeah, you know But the seed was planted and less than a week later Kind of out of the blues Scott and I got in my car.
Speaker 1: There was.
Speaker 1: there was help from the internet.
Speaker 1: cuz you know like anything, you know The internet encourages pretty much every activity you can think of.
Speaker 1: I mean, how many times is there a thing on dig like check out this new thing?
Speaker 1: You can do it and suddenly people are doing it, you know, like buying moleskines or something.
Speaker 0: Actually, there's one of those that none of you were gonna guess.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone out there is going to guess what we're doing But we were inspired to do something by the internet, but we'll talk about that later.
Speaker 1: Matchstick rockets.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: Oh, I kind of want to make some of those again, even though it never worked It worked barely.
Speaker 0: it worked barely Anyway, so we just kind of like let's go dumpster diving.
Speaker 0: so we looked online for like 20 minutes and then we just got in my car and drove over to Best Buy.
Speaker 1: and Best Buy uses a big trash compactor compressor thing.
Speaker 1: so you can't actually get in no one.
Speaker 0: There is nothing on this earth that would get me to crawl into a trash compactor.
Speaker 1: You can't even get in.
Speaker 1: It's not possible because it's basically in the store.
Speaker 1: There's a chute that goes into it and a button that Activates it and you have to be in the store to get into that.
Speaker 1: and if you went into that There's a chance you could be compacted and killed.
Speaker 1: and you chance you can't get out because like Trash compactor is on the detention level and it'll be quick - you'd be dead real fast.
Speaker 1: And - it's probably also the dangerous shit in a Best Buy compactor.
Speaker 1: God spray staples Yeah, it's death.
Speaker 1: and three.
Speaker 1: There's no exit hole on it.
Speaker 1: It's because it's taken away by a truck.
Speaker 0: So now I learned that from from some Best Buy employees because a lot of businesses do this now Especially businesses like Best Buy.
Speaker 0: the two main reasons they do that is one They don't want hobos going through their garbage for various reasons Even though I think if someone's gonna reuse something that's great.
Speaker 0: Mmm, but part of it is worry of liability - It's really easy for an employee to just kind of throw something away knowing that his friend Will just go grab it out of the dumpster that night.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So that's the primary reason is to prevent employees from stealing crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz you know, I mean someone returned Something and then it's not gonna go back in the store shelves the store policies throw it out or sell it super discount or something Right, but the store policies throw it out.
Speaker 1: They don't want someone like, you know getting it and not paying.
Speaker 0: Yep So undaunted we continue in our track and we drove around much of Henrietta Just looking for dumpsters and then when we found them Trying to convince each other to go into them and look for stuff.
Speaker 1: and what did we find?
Speaker 1: Well the Toys R Us we found.
Speaker 0: let's get to that last cuz.
Speaker 0: that was the only success story.
Speaker 1: It wasn't really a success story.
Speaker 0: Well first block Blockbuster.
Speaker 0: we were actually tipped off to go to blockbuster.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh So we went to blockbuster and we look in and we see Thousands upon thousands of DVD cases and we think hot damn jackpot.
Speaker 1: We got plastic cases for DVDs and CDs for as long as we'll live.
Speaker 0: They were all empty, but they were full-on.
Speaker 0: real DVD cases.
Speaker 1: Just yeah the ones that they use for rentals.
Speaker 1: just with those late, you know, they just had piece of papers in them.
Speaker 1: So if you just take the paper out, you've got a blank DVD case.
Speaker 0: So we're like a garbage bag full of them and stuck them in the trunk and we kept going.
Speaker 1: we didn't take those with us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 1: I don't think we did.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure we did Give them to the anime club.
Speaker 0: The anime club was like a and then we didn't.
Speaker 1: I don't cuz where are they now?
Speaker 1: What happened to them?
Speaker 0: probably where everything else went from that dumpster diving?
Speaker 1: We threw them being around colony.
Speaker 0: So they Anyway, yeah, we go there were DVD cases of blockbuster not much else and we went to the Wegmans and there was garbage in there.
Speaker 0: So we didn't go in there.
Speaker 1: It was smelly and stinky.
Speaker 0: We didn't want to touch that and almost everywhere we went that we thought would be a score with technology Was just a trash compactor and no actual dumpsters and Ever else.
Speaker 0: we went.
Speaker 0: the dumpsters were too scary and smelly to go into.
Speaker 1: Yeah at big lots Actually, there was a dumpster but like there were actual homeless people diving in that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like there were already people there and we felt awkward.
Speaker 1: It was like a homeless family at this dumpster.
Speaker 1: We're like, ah, let's go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz there were.
Speaker 0: there was something I don't know.
Speaker 0: It felt kind of sad if I'm a college hipster, dude And Scott's a college hipster dude and we're out dumpster diving because the internet and some guy told us to and these people are dumpster Diving partially for subsistence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I felt like I was kind of intruding into this space where I didn't belong But at the same time free stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Well before we get to the Toys R Us thing We didn't really know what to expect.
Speaker 0: like we read the internet and there were all these tips But in the end we both put on like old blue jeans and boots and I had a pair of bike gloves that I was wearing because we didn't have work gloves or anything.
Speaker 1: and Work gloves would helped a lot because I would have touched a lot of things.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have otherwise touched Yeah, but the cost of work gloves would have totally mitigated any gains.
Speaker 1: work gloves like two dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah I point out the gains from our adventure.
Speaker 0: So we're really getting kind of disillusioned because the internet was like yeah dumpster diving is awesome.
Speaker 0: And again, this guy kind of told us to dumpster dive and to this day I wonder why he told us to dumpster dive, but we weren't really finding much and it was just kind of scary He's.
Speaker 0: ever we went we were always worried The police would come or we'd run into scary homeless people which happened a few times or we'd run into a stoner which wasn't uncommon in Henrietta.
Speaker 0: or.
Speaker 0: and Then we swing by the Toys R Us thinking oh man action figures gonna be the win and uh jackpot Sort of well, it would have been a jackpot.
Speaker 0: The problem is we didn't follow through with the swing.
Speaker 0: We kind of ended up bunting and then getting called out at first.
Speaker 0: So, uh, we're looking in.
Speaker 0: there's two Toys R Us dumpsters and one of them had nothing in it Just like pallets broken pallets and like dead like broken cardboard boxes from toys.
Speaker 0: But the second one I look in and there is more Perfectly good bike paraphernalia than we could fit in my car not paraphernalia parts of bicycles like a derailleur derailleur a wheel You know some handlebars intact bikes by frames Perfectly functional bike frames.
Speaker 0: and I looked there was nothing wrong with them But there were no.
Speaker 1: there were no total bikes, but there were enough parts to make some bikes.
Speaker 0: There are enough parts to make a bunch of bikes Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the biggest thing is there were some bike helmets and there were a bunch of weird like bike buzzers and things.
Speaker 1: and you know Every Toys R Us is an official Nintendo repair place But it's also they have a bike repair guy that comes, you know, once a week or so.
Speaker 0: a little hints.
Speaker 0: Never take a bicycle to get repaired at Toys R Us unless it was a Huffy you bought at Toys R Us.
Speaker 1: No repair for free.
Speaker 0: Never repair a Huffy bike.
Speaker 1: My story, you know, I guess the guy was repairing Huffy's and then all the extra parts got just tossing the dumps.
Speaker 0: No, I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: I worked at construction.
Speaker 0: Well, like the summer after my freshman year at Kmart though at Kmart But also at Toys R Us and a few other places just kind of was construction crap.
Speaker 0: and at one place I went to I was doing construction and an employee came up and said hey you come here And he went to the back and there were like four bikes and he was like fix these bikes.
Speaker 0: and then he walked away And I think that's how a lot of those bikes actually get fixed.
Speaker 0: Yeah but I think the biggest score was that there were some boxes at the bottom and I opened these boxes because I jumped into the dumpster first.
Speaker 1: eventually Scott came in because he it was actually a pretty nice dumpster to walk in because it was Long and low and flat and there wasn't much in it.
Speaker 1: But bike part.
Speaker 1: so you stand on the bottom of the dumpster and they're just bike parts sitting around.
Speaker 0: But there's these cardboard boxes at the bottom and I go to pick one up and it's really heavy.
Speaker 0: So I open it and it's full.
Speaker 0: if you know those like trick bars that you stick on a BMX bike They may mean pegs.
Speaker 0: Yeah those stupid things that I think have no place outside of the extreme games.
Speaker 1: Yep, it was.
Speaker 0: it was a box of pegs and there were many boxes and I knew from personal expand.
Speaker 0: I went looked on eBay later and sure enough those pegs Even used go for not like not a lot of money, but you know 15 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not bad.
Speaker 1: people want to add pegs to their bikes is all culture of bike bike modding.
Speaker 1: And so we like parts.
Speaker 0: all of these boxes are full of perfectly functional usually looking brand new pegs Matching sets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we took them all and it took a while cuz they were really heavy.
Speaker 0: We had to kind of like empty the boxes and like work.
Speaker 1: We didn't take all of them, but we took a good deal of bike part.
Speaker 0: I took as many as I felt comfortable taking.
Speaker 0: we had putting in my strong pedals and some handlebars And okay, and then.
Speaker 0: and then we're like hot damn dumpster diving is awesome.
Speaker 0: We're gonna sell all this shit on eBay and make some money not a lot of money But some money and we get back to colony and we unload the car and it was a lot of stuff and it took a while.
Speaker 0: Cuz this stuff's heavy and it's all made out of metal.
Speaker 0: and then we're all our friends for the next day.
Speaker 0: We're like, yeah, we went dumpster diving last night.
Speaker 0: And of course their response is what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Why the fuck's wrong with you dumpsters?
Speaker 0: What are you hobos?
Speaker 0: and we're like no look at what we got.
Speaker 0: and we have all these bike parts.
Speaker 0: We're gonna sell them on eBay.
Speaker 0: We're gonna make like 500 bucks if we sell all of this stuff.
Speaker 1: We thought we were so cool and everyone else is like, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we're like, yeah great All we got to do is sell this stuff on eBay That box.
Speaker 1: first of all, let me just say right now in my whole life I have never once sold something on eBay.
Speaker 0: I've never even tried to sell anything on eBay.
Speaker 1: No, I never even tried either.
Speaker 1: and in addition to that the box of bike parts sat there until we moved out.
Speaker 0: In fact, I remember working at de Bella's the summer after that when we'd been living in that apartment for a long time already and For various reasons I came home with a garbage bag full of bread and I set that garbage bag full of bread on top of The several boxes full of bike parts that had not moved since the day.
Speaker 0: We went dumpster diving.
Speaker 0: Yep, those boxes.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like we kept trying to sell them and they didn't sell on eBay.
Speaker 0: We basically said alright We just have to sell these on eBay.
Speaker 0: and the boxes did not move Until the day we moved out of colony and on that day we threw them in a dumpster.
Speaker 0: The sad thing is I feel like if we'd followed through he would have made the money.
Speaker 1: Maybe there was a potential for making some money.
Speaker 1: I don't think all the stuff would have sold though and there were like four auctions for pegs and two of them were up to like 20 bucks Yeah, but I think a lot of the stuff was kind of used in cruddy and it would have been hard.
Speaker 0: The pegs the pegs were mostly brand-new.
Speaker 0: They were in perfect condition.
Speaker 1: They were matching sets So shiny as you seem to remember.
Speaker 0: those the pegs were.
Speaker 0: nothing else was the ball.
Speaker 0: The other parts were kind of scuffy whatever fine.
Speaker 0: I think the lesson lesson here is if someone aims you and says hey do X?
Speaker 0: The default answer should be don't do X.
Speaker 1: Well, is that dumpster diving it as an activity?
Speaker 1: I mean homeless people got to do it.
Speaker 1: That's what they do.
Speaker 1: Let let them do their thing, right?
Speaker 1: But it can be a profitable and enjoyable activity because it's about as close as we have to.
Speaker 0: you know Like treasure hunting, you know that we haven't in modern items If nothing else for two guys in college who were bored one night because it's not like we ever did homework or anything or went To class.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we'd already played a bunch of counter-strike that day.
Speaker 0: I mean, what else were we gonna do?
Speaker 0: So we went out dumpster diving.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It was a pretty adventurous night all together and I would never do it again.
Speaker 0: But I think that experience by itself like the amount of time I spent dumpster diving that one night was worth the amount of fun.
Speaker 0: I got in return.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like metal detecting like, you know, you do it once you're like woo and then from then on It's the worst thing ever there's.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 1: some lady wrote a really good article about how she tried to get into metal detecting and Eventually realized it was just a stupid and pointless and crap hobby.
Speaker 0: Well, what got me was when I was a kid and my dad informed me that all those articles you see about how someone found a bunch of ancient money Whatever metal detecting are usually fake and our ads paid for by metal detecting companies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that seems to be true.
Speaker 1: Yep Metal detectors all that stuff just going around looking for shit.
Speaker 1: the thing is that the sad truth is that while one man's trash another man's treasure, it's true.
Speaker 1: and While there is a chance you'll find something great in the trash and get it for free.
Speaker 1: That's awesome.
Speaker 1: The amount of time you have to spend to get a good chance of finding anything good.
Speaker 0: our net profit was The negative cost of all the gas I spent driving around
Speaker 1: and the time we spent Go and look at in things and the dirtiness we got Climate and dumpsters and the risk to our health and
Speaker 0: the risk to you know, we could have been arrested.
Speaker 0: We ran afoul of people and then we had to lug all that stuff out of our own apartment again and throw it away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really I mean if anyone is feeling adventurous and crazy.
Speaker 1: I recommend doing it maybe once but other than that It's not so.
Speaker 0: there's only one time you should ever go dumpster diving and that is if you're actually homeless though.
Speaker 0: well Yeah But if if you're bored and you're in college and someone gets you on instant messenger and says hey dumpster diving The stars just aligned and you're gonna go dumpster diving whether you want to or not I didn't want to go dumpster diving.
Speaker 0: Remember that the moral really was just that.
Speaker 0: it's really weird that that guy messaged me out of the blue and I hardly ever talked to him like ever and he was like man dumpster diving like totally out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: and the fact that it worked and I went Dumpster diving it was like it was the elaborate plot to get me killed Like maybe he'd hired assassins and they were waiting by the Walgreens dumpster.
Speaker 0: But we just never went to Walgreens.
Speaker 0: like the one place we didn't go is where the ninjas were waiting to kill me.
Speaker 0: I don't know, but it was just weird.
Speaker 0: and To this day, I'll always remember that I went dumpster diving for no good reason.
Speaker 0: Yep, so so I feel like all of you should go dumpster diving.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't think I would suggest you not go dumpster diving But there's something I would suggest you definitely not do and that is this recent trend of freeganism.
Speaker 1: If you heard people, I think we talked about it a little these people basically their philosophy is they're boycotting the evil Economic system of food selling and distribution, which I granted there are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what these people do is they eat
Speaker 0: food
Speaker 1: out of dumpsters and this they got pictures on their website of like someone like Pulling perfectly good potatoes out of a dumpster and putting them a bag and someone else like getting sealed Unexpired loaves of bread out of a dumpster.
Speaker 1: like hey look a loaf of bread.
Speaker 1: it passed the sell-by date But the sell-by date was yesterday and it's still edible today.
Speaker 1: I got it at the dumpster at the grocery store.
Speaker 1: look at this free bread and I guess that's cool, but Don't do this unless you absolutely have to to survive.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is I remember back and we did our you know ten minutes of dumpster diving research before we went out to dumpster dive and a lot of the websites talked about how most of The food you find is gonna be okay, and I just kind of ignored all that and didn't think about looking for food.
Speaker 1: I think I've learned enough from my friend who works Inspecting food in the state of New York that a food I mean, I'm the kind of person who if the milk is one day past the day.
Speaker 0: I Really feel uncomfortable drinking it and I throw away perfectly good food.
Speaker 0: sometimes You throw a pretty good food just because if I feel like food is bad It gets tainted like it's the psychosis I have where if I think food is bad Even if it's probably not I really can't bring myself to eat it.
Speaker 0: But at the same time you do have that problem.
Speaker 0: However at the same time if I drop food I'll eat it off pretty much any surface that I've dropped it on to.
Speaker 1: you do have that problem.
Speaker 0: you correctly Admit it, but like if food is rotten.
Speaker 0: I won't eat by.
Speaker 0: it is dirty.
Speaker 1: I don't care whatever but Eating food out of a dumpster even if like the sell by date was yesterday and it's bread in a plastic bag And it's still sealed Probably not the best idea.
Speaker 1: I mean stuff could have happened to it that you don't know that there's a reason they threw it out.
Speaker 1: It's it's not fit for human consumption, and you know you might get away with it a few times.
Speaker 1: But if you make a habit of being like a freaking and you keep eating food out of dumpsters and things You are going to get some sort of foodborne illness within weeks.
Speaker 1: I guarantee it pretty much.
Speaker 0: someone at RIT got hepatitis because they were eating food that was coming through the dish line at Gracie's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh We could do a whole show on Gracie's.
Speaker 1: Maybe you should expand that but we don't want to do more episodes on food though.
Speaker 0: No not on food.
Speaker 0: Do you think there's food at Gracie's?
Speaker 1: ha ha ha actually you know the food wasn't really that bad.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't, but that's kind of the joke you got to make.
Speaker 0: you know watch hard It's got to get all the way to Gracie's.
Speaker 0: I Actually look back on those days fondly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those were good days, but
Speaker 1: I guess I think
Speaker 0: if you if you think dumpster diving would be fun and adventurous to do by all means go do it Because it is kind of fun to do it once and
Speaker 1: there are websites that will tell you all the appropriate Precautions to avoid if
Speaker 0: you're in college and not on a weekend But like on a weeknight Especially if you have like class the next morning And it's late at night and only a few of you go Because it's kind of the same surreal experience of watching Space Ghost like it's just this weird.
Speaker 0: you're in a place that you're not supposed to be and you're doing stuff you're not really supposed to be doing and Your con your rational brain says this is dumb, but your Space Ghost brain says I'm just gonna keep doing it anyway.
Speaker 0: And it's just it's.
Speaker 1: the thing is if you if you before you're disillusioned about it you go out And you think you're really gonna find something.
Speaker 1: so the member with pretty much everything in life the anticipation is better than the reality.
Speaker 1: Driving
Speaker 0: around like we're going up to Best Buy, and I see the big dumpster And
Speaker 1: I'm sitting there, and I'm thinking about like all the like Disc men that are gonna be sitting in there in packages I'm just gonna take them like a freak disc man,
Speaker 0: and I was like what if someone threw away a scratch TV?
Speaker 0: hot shit.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: Give her that 70s TV.
Speaker 1: She didn't get rid of for you, but That TV that survived a rainstorm and sitting outside for a week yep, but Yeah, we got there and the reality was much worse than what we thought it was gonna.
Speaker 0: But at the same time the reality was only worse after the fact while we were doing it there was still that sensitive Yep even like right.
Speaker 1: even immediately after we got home it still felt just even the next day.
Speaker 0: We're like this was awesome.
Speaker 0: It was the day after the day after we did it.
Speaker 0: It wasn't that it became on awesome It was that we just kind of forgot about the whole experience.
Speaker 1: We're like hey never mind that yep We noticed we didn't do it again even while we still thought it was so only dumpster died.
Speaker 0: And you know that kind of.
Speaker 0: this is gonna be fun way.
Speaker 0: if you actually want to get stuff One go to a Goodwill store.
Speaker 0: those places are like the hidden off.
Speaker 1: Yes The way to actually get stuff for free or almost free is going to Goodwill stores and tag sales and used bookstores.
Speaker 0: And I own three sport jackets.
Speaker 0: one of them is Okay, but I don't really like it.
Speaker 0: one of them because it's from like high school.
Speaker 0: one of them is super fancy and awesome like it's super expensive, but it was my dad's and it has to be tailored because it doesn't fit me at all.
Speaker 0: and The third one that I own looks super good on me.
Speaker 0: It's like the best sport jacket I've ever owned and I bought it for like two dollars from a Goodwill and it has a stain on the inside.
Speaker 1: You know what I'm the hobo.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: it looks really snappy, and I really like If you ever see pictures of me like doing live shows I'm often wearing a sport jacket.
Speaker 0: It's almost always that $2 sport jacket.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so tag sales and Goodwill stores are in garage sales or whatever you call them in your area
Speaker 0: and as Emily for
Speaker 1: our Superior to die
Speaker 0: on that if you go to a Goodwill store That's in the middle of like a really snooty upper middle-class area You're gonna find a lot of designer stuff at that Goodwill more than you'd expect Seriously, and it's all like a dollar.
Speaker 1: and this is why when I get rid of old clothes I put them in the in the bin.
Speaker 1: that like goes to Africa as opposed to the Goodwill bin because I know that just someone Else in town might buy the Goodwill stuff, but this way it's going around the world which is farther away from me where I like it.
Speaker 0: Also, if you really want to get pretty good furniture and all sorts of stuff like that or just anything really go to a college Campus in the week before and week after it's time for the kids to move out.
Speaker 0: College kids get a lot of stuff from their parents.
Speaker 0: I'm talking like full dining room sets and everything.
Speaker 0: But the college kids are poor and while parents are often gonna give kids stuff once they go off to college They're not gonna give them money once they're already at college.
Speaker 0: So a lot of kids move out of apartments in the you know in summer and they have all this furniture.
Speaker 0: They can't afford to store it.
Speaker 0: They can't afford to get a truck and take it with them.
Speaker 0: They just leave it out.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they leave it out.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they try to sell it by hanging flyers.
Speaker 0: We left the.
Speaker 0: the Scott had this dining room set that just.
Speaker 0: our apartment was too small and it was just in the way And it was a nice set but we couldn't keep it.
Speaker 1: That was like the kitchen table for like my house for like my child, but we just couldn't keep it.
Speaker 0: So eventually we put it outside and we put a sign on it and it was literally 59 - - which is our dress.
Speaker 0: back then come in and give us five bucks or just take it and You know what I saw in beacon driving to work the other day.
Speaker 1: What do you say, you know those those couches relay sideways?
Speaker 0: Oh, I really like those and it's like roll.
Speaker 1: It's like just like a rolled up thing on the right one side and then just flat, you know, those are very Greek.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the kind of thing.
Speaker 0: We'd have to have those.
Speaker 1: What's this street for plank?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's one on ver plank with a sign on.
Speaker 1: it said free You'll see here's the thing but it was gonna rain Uh in college and it was sort of like plushie.
Speaker 0: The only thing is I will take a lot of furniture from the street.
Speaker 0: I've done that in the past.
Speaker 0: I will never take any furniture that is cushy or soft or as cushions because I Always imagine crabs in the mattress.
Speaker 1: I always imagine Exaggeration.
Speaker 0: that there's bugs in it or bedbugs or something and I just don't want to deal with crabs in a mattress is a very real Problem.
Speaker 1: you mean mattresses are the most scary.
Speaker 1: But you see my couch and then stuff gets are crawling out of it.
Speaker 0: If you see a liquor cabinet grab it.
Speaker 0: if you see like an end table grab it.
Speaker 1: if you see a chair That's solid.
Speaker 1: grab the mattress.
Speaker 1: No, yeah, never take a used mattress.
Speaker 0: God ever.
Speaker 0: Oh gathering by a used mattress.
Speaker 0: They're you unless you need something to set on fire Dude, I wouldn't take a used mattress from someone I knew.
Speaker 1: Used matches the worst thing.
Speaker 1: I take a used mattress for my mom because I know about the mattress I'd probably take.
Speaker 1: don't take a strange used mattress.
Speaker 0: Yes, especially if you don't know where it came from.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless you know the entire history of the mattress don't take it.
Speaker 0: I'd be more inclined to take the mattress that was on fire than the mattress I just came from.
Speaker 1: no matches that was on fire.
Speaker 1: to them crabs in it.
Speaker 0: At the very least.
Speaker 0: I carried the mattress on fire in front of someone else's apartment so I can get into my next to the Flaming bag of poo.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anything else to say?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: the show kind of went nowhere because what we went?
Speaker 0: dumpster diving Because someone told us to and we spent 10 minutes researching it.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe 20 minutes researching it on the internet and We didn't.
Speaker 1: nothing came of it and it's not the greatest thing ever.
Speaker 1: Just go on eBay and find exactly what you want and try to get.
Speaker 0: it really is kind of a dumpster and instead of spending Time you spend money.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You also spend some time a plus plus plus plus plus plus, you know, it's not based on luck So you're saving a lot of time.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.