Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, May 9th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight Watchmen.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Well over the weekend.
Speaker 0: Thanks to Emily getting tickets for me.
Speaker 0: I got to go see brave story in the theater, but we already saw it in the house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what the movie is pretty enough to where it was really worth seeing it again Just to see it in the theater.
Speaker 0: That is a really beautiful movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, you're about just about everything so I don't really consider your opinion.
Speaker 1: It says the person who hates 99% of everything there is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, particularly comic books.
Speaker 1: I think I think the difference is that you either hate something or like you like it.
Speaker 0: No No, I have very man.
Speaker 0: I have a very wide range of feelings on many things.
Speaker 1: Oh, you seem to either be like that sucks or that's awesome.
Speaker 1: And I seem to be man on almost everything.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: What do you man about?
Speaker 0: most things Really Yeah, most anime that come I just ate.
Speaker 0: I just ate.
Speaker 0: I just don't like it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't seem to always say me Well, what do you mean?
Speaker 0: I may isn't something you have to say?
Speaker 0: may is the default opinion?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's what it is Is that you sort of only express the.
Speaker 0: I don't express a non opinion.
Speaker 0: if I watch a show that's kind of boring like skull Man, I say huh and I just don't react to it because I have nothing to say.
Speaker 0: I think I think a middling opinion is is an opinion, but it is an opinion But I don't express it because there's no reason to.
Speaker 0: Besides the point is I think brave story is a great movie and I highly recommend that anyone out there who likes anime see it.
Speaker 0: Also, I will note that while the movie and the dub was pretty piss-poor.
Speaker 0: I gotta say really.
Speaker 1: But then you seem like a movie that was hard to dub either.
Speaker 0: No I expected it to be a pretty and it and it and it seemed okay.
Speaker 0: at first until Until I started hearing more than pretty much from him on Every single character's voice actor sounded like they were yelling all the time Regardless of whether or not the person on screen was yelling everyone's voice was either gravelly or mealy.
Speaker 0: so the dog basically sounds like They was that kind of movie.
Speaker 0: no, it was.
Speaker 0: so far it was so cheesy in the dub and the dialogue itself.
Speaker 0: Isn't that cheesy?
Speaker 0: It's just the way it was dubbed in the way.
Speaker 0: They decided to do it was really bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could definitely see how that could be.
Speaker 0: However Especially with that circus scene Even if you end up seeing the dub if you can catch this movie in a theater as opposed to just on the bit Torrance I'd recommend it.
Speaker 1: It's definitely worth watching this movie once if you can But you know, it's not the best thing ever of course.
Speaker 0: more importantly while we were in the city There is a dish a culinary sensation a thing that I've never actually had before but I knew of the existence by name only and I knew it was Canadian and Particularly Quebecois.
Speaker 0: and finally also Emily decided to buy some for me.
Speaker 0: I had put in Alright, it's basically a cup filled with super fat french fries gravy chicken in bits cheese Curds and Pretty much awesome wonderfulness.
Speaker 1: So it's just a heart attack in a cup.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it had to be at least 800 calories.
Speaker 0: Alright, it was so awesome.
Speaker 0: I think I have a new favorite food.
Speaker 1: I think I'll just stay away from that for the sake of my arteries.
Speaker 0: It was almost as good as a White Castle.
Speaker 0: Ah Disgusting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see I don't know what your problem is with White Castle.
Speaker 0: Those are quality little burgers for what you pay.
Speaker 0: In fact, if you take into account the price versus the unit quality It's probably the best deal on food in the world.
Speaker 1: It's pretty bad.
Speaker 1: If I was a starving person in Africa, maybe I'd eat a White Castle.
Speaker 0: But other than that, no, dude when I was growing up in sterling heights White Castle and Taco Bell were banned from sterling heights due to very good reason.
Speaker 0: so so and also White Castles were hard to find up there.
Speaker 0: we ended up fairly often in high school getting a big group of people together crammed into a car and Drive in a half hour just to get to the one White Castle we could find.
Speaker 0: That was smart and by in sex.
Speaker 1: you couldn't have possibly spent that money in time in any better way.
Speaker 0: What money guess cost practically nothing back then and the burgers cost less?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but imagine if you added up all them together, you know what.
Speaker 0: you could have gotten a one video game Which is better than all the White Castles now because those White Castle trips while not quite a Harold and Kumar level were generally minor defining moments in my childhood.
Speaker 0: You know kids in some places go down to the levee but the levee was dry.
Speaker 0: well we drove out to White Castle.
Speaker 1: We just went to the diner where we had decent food.
Speaker 1: Oh, we went to the diner to buy onion rings by the foot.
Speaker 0: See we went to the Coney Island diners where I could get an entire meal for a dollar 99.
Speaker 1: We went to the real diner where you'd get a stack of pancakes for $6 real diner.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Yeah real diner now with real food that is good and edible and dude compared to some places in Michigan in the Midwest or Pretty much anywhere on the Jersey Shore or pretty much anywhere in New Jersey.
Speaker 0: You don't have any diners in Connecticut.
Speaker 1: There's diners in Connecticut.
Speaker 1: What do you know?
Speaker 1: how many diners in Connecticut have you eaten it?
Speaker 1: Oh, which one I don't even know.
Speaker 0: But I stopped at two different diners.
Speaker 0: Remember all those times I end up stopping at your house on the way home from a con or something Way back when I lived out here alone.
Speaker 0: every time I left your house I'd always stop at some diner along the way to eat.
Speaker 1: Oh the diners that are on the way to here from my parents house and not the best ones in, Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Okay, the good ones is a good one in Westport and there's a good one in Fairfield.
Speaker 0: and see when I'm in Jersey?
Speaker 0: I don't need to ask that question.
Speaker 0: I just go to any diner.
Speaker 1: Well, New Jersey does have better diners than Connecticut.
Speaker 1: But regardless Connecticut has better diners than Michigan.
Speaker 0: I'm just a. Michigan has really good Greek food surprisingly.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of Greeks in Michigan into southeast Michigan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're not diner Greek there, you know shawarma falafel place.
Speaker 0: No, they're they're all diner Greek.
Speaker 0: There's very little shawarma falafel out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah Great besides the best diners.
Speaker 1: while they may offer great Greek food.
Speaker 1: I'll usually have to offer non Greek food as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sadly most diners they go to now don't have great Greek food and they just kind of have mad diner food.
Speaker 1: You got to go to diners like the Athena something something or the out Zeus something.
Speaker 0: Olympus diner What's the one we go to in Wildwood the star diner?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that one's a pretty good diner.
Speaker 1: It's a good diner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the best diner I've ever eaten is the tick-tock diner in Jersey.
Speaker 0: Ah Anyway in the news, it's really not much of a news and I had something else.
Speaker 0: But I just found this kind of funny when Scott clicked on it while we were sitting in the living room.
Speaker 0: There's a poll on the anime news network and the poll is do you read?
Speaker 1: Protoculture for the culture addicts.
Speaker 1: Ah Protoculture addicts is a magazine.
Speaker 1: It is the oldest.
Speaker 0: Wait.
Speaker 0: Wait a magazine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's what kind of thing is that?
Speaker 1: It's it's sort of like this paper that they stick together and write shit.
Speaker 1: It's like someone prints out a web page and they try to sell it to you.
Speaker 0: Oh, I've seen those.
Speaker 0: they cost a lot of money.
Speaker 0: The pages are all glossy.
Speaker 0: They're more ads than content.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those things.
Speaker 1: Yeah those things.
Speaker 1: so protoculture addicts is the oldest anime magazine in the United States and surprisingly enough There have been a lot of anime magazines the United States in English.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of them were pretty bad.
Speaker 1: Well, some of them were good.
Speaker 1: Some of them were bad.
Speaker 1: I'm you know, some of them were manga, you know They were.
Speaker 1: they tried they were like manga anthologies and some of them were just actual magazines about anime with anime news and ads and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: and Some of them have failed and some of them are still around in various forms and whatever.
Speaker 1: Protoculture addicts is the oldest one.
Speaker 1: It's still around and I think in 2005 they teamed up with the anime news network in a bid to stay alive And they are still alive.
Speaker 0: Well for now because this poll pretty much went exactly the way I expected.
Speaker 0: You see Scott clicked on the poll because we saw the poll and we both don't really read magazines anymore at all.
Speaker 1: Maybe if I'm in a dentist office and I forgot my DS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm in the waiting room So never because you always have your DS exactly.
Speaker 0: maybe the battery went down.
Speaker 1: maybe I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the dentist made me wait all day.
Speaker 0: But I mean the last magazines I bought or subscribe to were dragon magazine Which I realized after six years of subscribing that it was useless.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I was like one day.
Speaker 0: I was like, why do I subscribe to this?
Speaker 0: I only kind of read through it briefly and then I stick it in the pile.
Speaker 0: And it's a lot of money and I'll talk about new type in a minute, but So Scott clicks on the pole and there's a million possible answer.
Speaker 1: I thought it was gonna be yes No, but no there were like 20 different answers to choose from.
Speaker 0: so Scott's sitting there going.
Speaker 1: I was just looking for the answer that I knew was the one I wanted.
Speaker 0: now meanwhile because I guess I have the rim I when it comes to rim and Scott opinions while I was reading from top to bottom.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just zeroed in on the option that pretty much says exactly how I was sure Scott would feel.
Speaker 0: quote.
Speaker 0: I don't read any anime print magazines nor do I intend to.
Speaker 1: that is the correct answer to the question.
Speaker 1: Do you read Protoculture Addicts?
Speaker 0: Well that answer is definitely winning the poll and I point out the wallet is winning.
Speaker 0: number three is What is Protoculture Addicts?
Speaker 1: If they want me to read their anime magazine, they are going to have a number.
Speaker 1: Oh god They're gonna have to find some way to basically make it illegal to put anime news on the internet for free.
Speaker 0: See in general.
Speaker 0: I think that most Magazines now there are exceptions.
Speaker 0: I I'm not gonna go in it.
Speaker 0: I mean there are magazines that do serve useful purposes.
Speaker 0: There are also things like journals and such.
Speaker 0: but when it comes to things like anime or video games or anything like that I really think that this thing called the internet has Obviated the need for this entire market and I can't believe it still exists.
Speaker 0: who gets their opinions on Video games from a video game magazine?
Speaker 1: someone who doesn't know how to read penny arcade Kotaku or joystick?
Speaker 0: I mean if anything the best case unless they've employed nothing But actual psychics which if they did I would probably subscribe.
Speaker 0: Yep, but There's no way they could beat the internet to any news because they have to print.
Speaker 0: meaning there is a point.
Speaker 0: Well before you get the magazine whereupon they had to say Alright this is as up-to-date as this issue is going to be because now we are going to kill a bunch of trees Put a bunch of ink on it put it in plastic and make a bunch of people drive around the country putting them in people's Mailboxes.
Speaker 1: Yeah now even if a magazine does have a couple advantages.
Speaker 1: number one They can get information because they're you know real media, you know as opposed to underground internet media They can go and get exclusives from the source that they won't tell to a blog.
Speaker 1: So for example Nintendo power they know things that no Nintendo blog knows about and they can put those things in their magazines.
Speaker 1: So if you want to find out first You'd have to get you have to subscribe to the magazine.
Speaker 1: The problem is as soon as that magazine comes out someone types in what the hell it says and I find out five minutes later.
Speaker 1: Yep, not a big deal.
Speaker 0: Plus.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of people say oh, yeah blogs are real journalism, but you can't really Deny them outright because as time goes along that sort of media is becoming more and more legitimate and Legitimate.
Speaker 0: people out there are starting to pay attention to them and give their press releases to blog.
Speaker 1: Yep Despite the fact that any video game blog the average video game blog I'd say is 50% complete bullshit rumor-mongering and 50% just video game stuff.
Speaker 1: despite that fact Which I can't deny by reading video game blogs and pretty much nothing else about video games I get more information about video games than I ever got subscribing to GamePro and I know when all the games are coming out.
Speaker 1: I know which games are good.
Speaker 1: I know which games are bad.
Speaker 1: I know all about Xbox teams even though I don't have one and don't care and I know that all sorts of stuff is going on and it works regardless of the crappiness of the quality in general.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I used to subscribe to PC gamer and Back then there really wasn't an internet like there is today.
Speaker 0: So I needed something like that to find out about PC games And you got the demo CDs because you couldn't download giant demos like that Which were basically free games because by the time I got done playing the demos.
Speaker 0: You didn't want to play the game anymore now because either the game was dumb or it was awesome.
Speaker 0: But oh look the next set of demos came out.
Speaker 0: I mean I played that one must fall.
Speaker 0: 2097 demo for like.
Speaker 1: oh, I played that so much You have no idea by the time I finished playing the demo.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I don't think you could actually purchase.
Speaker 0: one must fall anymore.
Speaker 1: I think that was the.
Speaker 1: well you can get it for free now, but well now you can.
Speaker 0: and what we should talk about that Someday, that's one of my favorite fighting games ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that is one of the best fighting.
Speaker 0: pretty much that in Bushido blade - I don't like Bushido blade You suck.
Speaker 1: I like the idea Bushido blade now.
Speaker 0: I've never actually read Protoculture Addict.
Speaker 0: So if anyone could think of any reason why I should I'll hear you out.
Speaker 0: But I would like to mention New Type magazine Which I'm not.
Speaker 0: I can't speak as to how cool or interesting Protoculture might be But the story of New Type magazine because remember used to at least our interaction with you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it used to not be in English, but all the cool kids had the Japanese new types.
Speaker 0: You'd buy him at cons.
Speaker 0: You'd see him around people would carry him to the anime club.
Speaker 1: people at the anime club would subscribe to the Japanese new.
Speaker 0: Yeah, in fact at the RIT anime club we had the library.
Speaker 0: we could check out anime and manga and all sorts of things.
Speaker 0: You know we had God hundreds and hundreds thousands of tapes tapes tapes hundreds of tapes not thousands.
Speaker 0: Well, we broke a thousand during our time thousands.
Speaker 1: That would be at least 2,000.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah well thousands of Tapes because we also had the tape right.
Speaker 1: yeah If you count every centimeter of duct tape as one tape yeah Yeah, anyway,
Speaker 0: anyway, we had a lot of tapes a lot all that stuff and not only could you check out New Type magazine But a lot of people did and it was in Japanese and when I first opened a new type.
Speaker 1: It's gigantic and Beautiful it's like you in Japanese.
Speaker 1: New Type is the greatest magazine ever to an English-speaking person because it has these amazing pictures of all these anime.
Speaker 1: They and you can kind of figure out like when they're coming out or if they're good or not and what they're about
Speaker 0: and they'll Have character profiles and all these shots and pictures and beautiful fold outs
Speaker 1: all sorts of extras like showing you the characters from every Angle and every character in the whole show even the minor characters and all the robots and all the weapons.
Speaker 1: And it's pretty freakin cool to be able to you know because usually you watch an anime everything's moving Stuff doesn't stay on the screen very long at the angle.
Speaker 1: so a new type.
Speaker 1: you can look at the characters That you know and really look at him for a long time and inspect them, and it was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I read well quotes in the air read New Type every month for like five months when it was in Japanese And I can't read Japanese at all me also.
Speaker 0: all I could think was that Goddamn if this was in English would be the best thing ever because I was entertained enough by the pictures.
Speaker 0: But I saw all this Japanese words, and I knew that those words were telling me interesting things.
Speaker 1: So what was it Otakon?
Speaker 0: First or second Otakon?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna look it up all that it was years ago.
Speaker 0: It was back when I was poor because I couldn't afford to subscribe to New Type and in fact I ended up subscribing anyway.
Speaker 0: And then I got a bunch of issues, and then they stopped sending him to me when I didn't pay.
Speaker 1: yeah So this must have been Otakon 2002. they hand it out in the dealer's room because ADV does the New Type USA.
Speaker 1: They handed out free issues of New Type USA number zero which had Raza fine on the cover.
Speaker 0: now Much like when Sailor Moon finally sees behind tuxedo masks mask and find out that He's actually that guy I like or that guy I don't like or whatever New types mask fell off.
Speaker 0: as I could now read all those previously mythical words and That's not going to much more detail because I want to get done with the news it was drivel.
Speaker 0: it was Absolute drivel.
Speaker 0: there was no reason to ever look into a new type again.
Speaker 1: those words were meaningless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean when New Type USA came out.
Speaker 1: I got a few of the issues.
Speaker 1: I did you buy him or did I buy him?
Speaker 0: I got.
Speaker 0: I just said how I got him.
Speaker 0: I didn't pay for him and eventually they stopped sending him to me.
Speaker 1: Alright right you said it's a subscription card.
Speaker 1: They sent you a few issues, but you never paid the $75.
Speaker 1: yeah the $75 a year right.
Speaker 1: so at those first early New Type USA's I read them, but I didn't read the words.
Speaker 1: I read them the same way.
Speaker 1: I read the Japanese one.
Speaker 1: I looked at the pictures, and then I put it away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, room was in the magazine once though.
Speaker 0: I was in fact myself and Scott Johnson were in New Type.
Speaker 0: We were featured in this page thing about the pretty much the legendary Scott Johnson was actually called the legendary club anime club Master or something to that effect.
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 0: I've got the issue laying around.
Speaker 0: yep In fact I should scan it in and post a picture of it because my ego is so big.
Speaker 0: and the awesome Awesome thing was that it mentioned Scott Johnson a few times, but all the pictures were of me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's only one picture.
Speaker 0: No there were two.
Speaker 1: was there.
Speaker 0: there were at least two I don't remember cuz I had two different angles and both of them clearly I'm the one speaking and I'm the one centered, but Scott got the legendary title, so I couldn't really.
Speaker 1: yeah I don't think I don't remember anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though.
Speaker 0: We talked to the guy afterward.
Speaker 0: He's like ah shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't really put all the effort.
Speaker 0: I should have into that article.
Speaker 1: It's a tiny article that no one read.
Speaker 1: so who cares?
Speaker 0: well no one reads anything in New Type because it's garbage.
Speaker 1: Yep, all the magazines are garbage.
Speaker 0: well particularly New Type because I've actually read it and the words there was so little substance.
Speaker 0: It was like I knew less about the anime than when I started.
Speaker 1: I remember I also bought a couple issues of like anime insider Which is like the wizard anime magazine and that was I don't I dare say it was worse than wizard magazine Which is Wow one of the worst magazines ever.
Speaker 1: hey remember scry God I've had a few of those.
Speaker 1: so did I mostly for the list of magic cards.
Speaker 0: yep So I could find out how much my mox emerald was worth.
Speaker 1: all right, so here's an anime news.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be quick with this.
Speaker 1: you know Satoshi khan our Living anime.
Speaker 1: God yes Crater of all the awesome anime that if you haven't seen stop listen to this podcast because they're better than this podcast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got it perfect.
Speaker 0: blue is Fantastic.
Speaker 0: millennia matrix actress is really really good.
Speaker 0: Tokyo godfathers paranoia agents.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's all he made.
Speaker 0: okay paprika.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's gonna be out real soon.
Speaker 1: He did some interview in Portuguese.
Speaker 1: I don't know if he was speaking Portuguese, but he must had a train.
Speaker 0: Oh, he's fluent in Portuguese.
Speaker 1: is he really?
Speaker 0: I have no idea either.
Speaker 1: He didn't interview.
Speaker 1: the interview is in Portuguese, and then it was translated from Portuguese to English.
Speaker 1: You can read this interview with Satoshi khan And if you thought he was a genius based upon his artistic works You will think he is a double genius based upon his interview.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the point I would make is that when it comes to things that are awesome and the people that make them Sometimes something is awesome Despite the person who made it and sometimes something is awesome because of the person who made it.
Speaker 1: Let's see Star Wars case of the former Harlan Ellison case of the former.
Speaker 0: yes The latter I mean you'll.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of complexity to the things he's made and you get the impression that that was all intentional.
Speaker 0: Entirely like he puts a lot of thought into the works.
Speaker 0: He does Cosmo coke.
Speaker 0: Now also I would like to do a geek back.
Speaker 0: No Because we haven't done geek backs in a while, but their whole episode of one yeah But I mean that was wasn't really a geek bag.
Speaker 0: that was more of a episode on the future of geek nights that we foiled With the question.
Speaker 0: someone asked it wasn't like a geek bag stuck into a show.
Speaker 0: all right and partly because we've been asking a lot Of people to send us a lot of feedback and a lot of you have the people coming out of the woodwork and actually Talking to us.
Speaker 0: You're all awesome because you have already moved beyond consumer and become Interactor.
Speaker 0: you're one step away from producer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've talked about this before and that for any given work of art or media or whatever 90% of the people just observe or consume that work.
Speaker 1: 10% of people interact with that work.
Speaker 1: That's a hundred percent and You get the idea and then 1% of people You know actually produce works.
Speaker 1: yes, so Most people listening to this podcast nine to about 90% of you.
Speaker 1: All you do is listen to this podcast.
Speaker 1: you don't do anything else involving this podcast.
Speaker 1: You don't post in the forum.
Speaker 1: You don't email us.
Speaker 1: You don't voicemail us.
Speaker 1: You don't make your own podcast.
Speaker 1: You don't do anything now.
Speaker 0: I understand that some of you probably do something out there.
Speaker 0: We're not talking to you.
Speaker 0: I mean if you're crazily active unlike the comic geek speak forums or something We don't expect you to also be crazily active with us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but some people out there You're just listening to geek nights not doing anything else, and you know what I say to you You're in the 90%.
Speaker 1: is that cool.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: It's not so cool.
Speaker 1: You want to move into the 10% then you'll be in the 90th percentile better than most people as opposed to just being Most people plus.
Speaker 0: I will point out that if you like geek nights Which you must because you're listening I'll point this is your first time.
Speaker 1: What's up?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you might hate it which is fine but if you go to our forums pretty much everyone in there thinks along the same lines you do and I really think that our forums are some of the better forums on the internet, and I'm not just kidding about that.
Speaker 1: Well you if you want to be cool and like rim and scott you should wait wait a minute.
Speaker 0: We're using peer pressure in order to tell people to resist the bandwagon.
Speaker 0: Yes, we're trying to get you off of one bandwagon under another bandwagon, but we're not lying to you.
Speaker 1: We're actually trying to help you out and move you to the superior bandwagon.
Speaker 1: So anyway of not being the sheep, but being the sheep dog.
Speaker 0: ah sheep dog because the next step up is the shepherd Which is really hard to be except where the shepherds.
Speaker 0: well I guess the step up from that is the pirate in The post-apocalyptic fist of the North Star world who kills the shepherd then kills the sheep.
Speaker 0: That's also me Anyway, so a while ago We did an episode on the worst podcast ever and we called out a bunch of podcasts and somebody's still doing the geek bag.
Speaker 0: yeah, and some of those podcasts responded to us and Not too long ago one of the hosts of anime world order had a crazy Hissy fit about something Scott said and That was hilarious, and I realized something and this feedback is going to really put in the relief for you.
Speaker 0: I'll read the feedback first.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you what I learned from it.
Speaker 0: This is from one sin.
Speaker 0: I first heard about geek nights from anime world order during a con report I think.
Speaker 0: then after the whole Clarissa to terror thing I began to consider giving geek nights a shot.
Speaker 0: I finally subscribed.
Speaker 0: after listening to the worst podcast episode.
Speaker 0: I found out about it from some anime pulse fans who were Indignant and whatnot over how badly their precious show got owned.
Speaker 0: I figure anyone decent decent enough to see through that show was worth listening to.
Speaker 0: now the moral of this story Is that the more anyone out there puts the hate on us the more listeners we get?
Speaker 0: Because this isn't the first time I've gotten a feedback like this.
Speaker 0: I've gotten at least I'm not gonna exaggerate here one two I've gotten six or seven emails or feedbacks that basically said yeah, I found your show because someone said you sucked.
Speaker 1: So if anyone out there still believes that there's a such thing as bad publicity you're wrong.
Speaker 1: Yes This is why part of the reason why we are one of the few pot it seems like a lot of podcasts are just afraid To be critical especially of other podcasts.
Speaker 1: This is why we fear nothing and we'll say whatever the hell we want Because number one will be known as the podcast that says whatever the hell we want which makes I think makes us a better podcast.
Speaker 1: I think so and two will occasionally get bad publicity, which is good.
Speaker 0: Yes So one sin, thanks for joining the forums.
Speaker 0: It's good to have you here.
Speaker 0: things of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be real quick here.
Speaker 0: There's a video of a little turtle and a cat and the turtle like a little machine just won't leave that cat alone.
Speaker 0: It's like an attack turtle and it's hilarious.
Speaker 1: I'm not a big fan of animals, but I kind of like that turtle.
Speaker 0: I really like turtles for one.
Speaker 0: I think they're cute.
Speaker 1: I like the way its arms and legs move because they're kind of like backwards C's and they kind of.
Speaker 0: And that's not just a normal turtle.
Speaker 0: That is a turtle on a mission Scott.
Speaker 1: Why do you care about that turtle?
Speaker 1: It's not you.
Speaker 1: So for all you people out there especially you Scott bot Who are not too up on the superhero fan culture that is?
Speaker 1: Around the world of nerdom I guess if you ever wondered the kind of crazy collections that crazy nerds have take a look at this.
Speaker 1: This is a guy who likes dr.
Speaker 1: Strange now.
Speaker 1: I like dr.
Speaker 1: Strange.
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 1: Strange is cool.
Speaker 1: This guy really likes dr.
Speaker 1: Strange.
Speaker 1: He likes dr.
Speaker 1: Strange so much.
Speaker 1: He owns pretty much.
Speaker 1: It has to be every piece of dr.
Speaker 1: Strange merchandise ever.
Speaker 1: Wow So here you go every piece of dr.
Speaker 1: Strange merchandise ever and a whole bunch of original dr Strange art and a dr.
Speaker 1: Strange costume and a whole lot of dr.
Speaker 1: Strange shit.
Speaker 1: pretty much.
Speaker 1: if you're looking for anything, dr Strange it'll be in one of these pictures.
Speaker 1: So you'll know what to look for Right.
Speaker 0: So anime world order.
Speaker 0: when they talk about an important show or a big show and it's one of those things that they really Care about they always seem to get nervous.
Speaker 0: Like I hope I don't fuck this up.
Speaker 1: I hope I do this show justice and they prepare well in advance and they have a whole bunch of stuff written down.
Speaker 0: Well, that is very much how I feel about what we're about to talk about but I have not done any more preparation than I Normally, no, I didn't prepare it all but that is correct.
Speaker 1: This is a show that is not to be fucked up.
Speaker 0: Well a show a and yeah, I'd love it to be a show but it isn't yet.
Speaker 1: Well, I meant as this is a show not to be fucked up as in the show.
Speaker 1: We're making right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay Okay.
Speaker 0: Yes, you saved it.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but tonight we are going to talk about perhaps one of the greatest works in the history of American comics.
Speaker 1: It may be perhaps the greatest work of graphic storytelling ever in the history of the world.
Speaker 0: It is in the very least a seminal work Watchmen written by Alan Moore and illustrated by David Gibbons.
Speaker 1: It is originally I think how many issues?
Speaker 0: 12 issues in the mid to late 80s.
Speaker 1: Yeah as a 12 issue series of actual comic books printed in the 80s by DC.
Speaker 1: and Now you can buy those individual comics if you want you can find them someplace I mean dragons then has them all for like I don't know how much but you or you can be smart and buy One book that has all of them in it for like 20 bucks
Speaker 0: now one.
Speaker 0: We are not going to spoil anything in this show because that is a crime worthy of death.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's not like it's his sled or it's actually a man.
Speaker 1: Funny that you say it's his sled because Watchmen is basically the Citizen Kane of comics.
Speaker 0: Yes, and we're not kidding here This if you have not read Watchmen, I don't care if you love comic books hate comic books, whatever.
Speaker 0: I mean remember I almost entirely dislike the entire genre of comic books involving underwear perverts Superheroes, I don't like the idea of superheroes.
Speaker 0: I think the way they're done is often lame.
Speaker 0: I consider Watchmen to be one of the best comic books ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: If you are the kind of person who just only reads manga and you hate American comics if you're the kind of person who hates Comics and think they're for kids and you don't want to read comics at all Everyone who knows how to read and if Watchmen is printed in your language, you should read it.
Speaker 0: Yes, Watchmen is not just a comic book.
Speaker 0: Watchmen is literature.
Speaker 0: I Watchmen is better than a lot of novels.
Speaker 0: I have read.
Speaker 1: it's probably if on a list of all-time books ever Probably near the.
Speaker 0: actually it is the only graphic novel to appear on Time magazine's 2005 list of the 100 best English-language novels from 1923 to 2005. it's really that good.
Speaker 0: So what is the Watchmen?
Speaker 1: The Watchmen is a story.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: How can I put this?
Speaker 1: It's about superheroes, but only one of them is actually super yes, and They're sort of retired.
Speaker 0: It's more.
Speaker 0: Imagine a world very much like our modern world only while the Cold War is still going on.
Speaker 1: So it's an 80s world.
Speaker 1: the Cold War is going on.
Speaker 1: Superheroes used to exist, but they don't really anymore.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: imagine if there were superheroes or as they call them a costume heroes or masks in this.
Speaker 0: Imagine if in the real world there were superheroes But they were actually just normal people who for whatever reason were very highly skilled or very well-equipped or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much every superhero was like Batman.
Speaker 0: Just a guy with some gadgets Yes, and not some of the lame Batman, but we're talking about the dark gritty realistic that the good Batman imagine a superhero story that is 100% believable and as Realistic as something like that could ever be and in with one exception.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much straight-up realistic.
Speaker 0: Yep, and It said in this slightly alternate history Cold War only a few things are different.
Speaker 0: I really don't want to ruin anything but suffice to say imagine it.
Speaker 0: because of these superheroes So America won the Vietnam War and the Soviet Union and the United States the nuclear issue is a little bit more on the forefront and nuclear war is a little bit closer than it ever got in the real world
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: The world's generally a pretty gritty dismal place to be in.
Speaker 1: and you have these people who used to be superheroes And they're just living normal lives.
Speaker 0: now some of them some of them are doing other things some of them are still superheroes But now they work for the government.
Speaker 1: Yep, and one day one of these superheroes a pretty important one is Murdered.
Speaker 0: now actually just a man is murdered in New York and one of his friends Rorschach who was a masked hero in the back in the day And it was still a masked hero despite the fact that they have been outlawed as being vigilantes.
Speaker 0: Yep Investigates and discovers that this man who was murdered was actually one of his friend costume heroes the comedian Yep, now it sort of gets Cthulhu on you from there.
Speaker 1: You know how I talked about Call of Cthulhu once on the show.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you listen to that show But it's all about a guy who finds like a bas relief and he starts to investigate and he finds out things he doesn't want to know and shit just gets worse and worse and worse and he wishes he never would have known in the First place.
Speaker 0: you found the tip of the iceberg and you have no idea what lies underneath the sea level.
Speaker 1: too bad It's a giant horrible iceberg with a monster frozen in it.
Speaker 1: That'll fuck up your brain or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep, even though unlike Cthulhu.
Speaker 0: This isn't a story of super villains.
Speaker 0: calm.
Speaker 0: There's no super villains It's just it's a. it's really hard to describe what it is.
Speaker 0: It's really
Speaker 1: weird because it's like you think superheroes story All right, so his superhero and this super villain committing a crime and the super the hero has some flaws But he fights through them and learns something and he does a big scene where he beats up the villain and the villain goes to Jail and the superhero goes home having learned his lesson.
Speaker 0: It's not like that at all.
Speaker 1: There aren't even in really any combat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no fights There's.
Speaker 0: there isn't even really a traditional villain.
Speaker 0: In fact for most of the story.
Speaker 0: you don't even know if anything bad is actually going on.
Speaker 1: all you see are these people living their lives and the only bad thing that's happened and the only question you've got is who murdered the comedian and why.
Speaker 0: and basically that the story is that Roshach is kind of a Conspiracy nut and a right-wing conspiracy nut.
Speaker 0: Yes, and he's kind of crazy and he's definitely crazy Yeah, but at the same time he's one of the most lucid characters in the entire novel.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I'm gonna call it the work from now on.
Speaker 1: Okay, the work the work.
Speaker 1: It is definitely if anything should be called the work.
Speaker 0: this is it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean here's an example of how well executed is this character.
Speaker 0: Roshach is insane.
Speaker 0: He is an insane man who believes in crazy conspiracy theories and he is currently following this conspiracy theory of Regarding the murder of his former friend the comedian and seeing where it will lead him.
Speaker 0: and despite the fact that he's completely insane He is the most lucid character in this entire world and everyone else is just a normal person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would definitely identify with him.
Speaker 1: second most of all the characters in this book.
Speaker 0: I hate to say that I agree with Roshach, but I in the end in most ways do in most ways.
Speaker 1: Yes Pretty much because he's the only one who goes in a particular direction, but I'm not gonna spoil any more than that.
Speaker 0: Yes, I think it's safe to say that we're not going to talk any more about the plot of Watchmen because there is absolutely no way to talk about it without ruining things or without giving it such a superficial Treatment that you really wouldn't have any idea of actually how good it is.
Speaker 0: So I think instead we're gonna talk a lot about why the Watchmen is good.
Speaker 1: Yes Well first let's talk about the structure of the comic.
Speaker 1: each individual issue Of course has an awesome cover.
Speaker 1: The covers are all amazing.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: I love these covers.
Speaker 1: I can just keep looking at him I'm looking at right now.
Speaker 1: I'm flipping through the book.
Speaker 0: Also, I like the every issue ever of the 12 and they're all in the trade.
Speaker 0: paperback obviously begins with a clock That's slowly ticking down to midnight as the comic progresses and despite that now consider that that also There has been the doomsday clock in the real world for the longest time and the doomsday clock exists in this world, too.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a bunch of experts Deciding how close the world is to nuclear holocaust at any given moment and depending on the situation of the world They change it and I believe in the setting of the Watchmen.
Speaker 0: when Watchmen begins The clock is set to five minutes to midnight with the tension going on in the world at the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you look at the the top left corner of any of the covers like here chapter one at the first cover of the first Issue of Watchmen in the top left.
Speaker 1: There is a clock.
Speaker 1: It's set to about ten to midnight.
Speaker 1: the cover of issue.
Speaker 1: Let me flip to one here.
Speaker 1: cover of is chapter five.
Speaker 1: It's upset at about seven eight minutes to midnight and the final issue The clock on the cover is set to midnight and if the cover is actually a picture of a clock That's like one second away from midnight.
Speaker 0: now along with that There's I think I don't know if it's every chapter every issue but I think it is there's always like an abbreviated version of a quote at the beginning and then the Full-quotation at the end and is usually something that sums up in a very elegant way What happened in that issue?
Speaker 1: usually the quote will be after the final panel on the final page in the corner like here the the first issue after the Final panel is a small panel on the right that actually also has a clock in it with a time and it says at Midnight all the agents and superhuman crew go out and round up everyone who knows more than they do Bob Dylan.
Speaker 1: It's always a quote from something real in the real world like Bob Dylan or an old poem or an old song or me.
Speaker 1: I don't know something in the Bible.
Speaker 1: I don't really remember the.
Speaker 0: now that sort of thing is often kind of cheesy and hackneyed in a lot of works.
Speaker 0: But in Watchmen, it really is done so well And I don't want to sound pretentious even though I think anyone who uses the word pretentious on the internet Immediately labels themselves as an idiot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because that word is so useless now.
Speaker 0: but the amount of thought that went into choosing these quotations and reading through Watchmen, especially the second time and Looking at these quotations you really understand more and more layers of what was going on in this work.
Speaker 0: Another aspect it's called the Watchmen.
Speaker 0: The Watchmen in terms of the story doesn't really come up.
Speaker 0: There's no group the Watchmen.
Speaker 0: There's no superhero.
Speaker 0: the Watchman There's but there's a lot of subtle elements and symbolism that come together Under this name Watchmen, there's a lot of clocks.
Speaker 0: in fact One of the superheroes the one who the one person who is actually a superhero who has powers Because of something that happened was a watchmaker.
Speaker 0: Clocks are everywhere time and time.
Speaker 0: ticking is always a huge factor in this.
Speaker 1: that quote of who watches the Watchmen just keeps coming Up all over the place.
Speaker 0: quiz custodian is post custodians.
Speaker 0: who will watch the Watchmen?
Speaker 0: It's from a juvenile satire and I know that the rest of that quotation the why it.
Speaker 0: basically Bolterin constrain her, you know talking about someone's wife But who will watch the Watchmen?
Speaker 0: the wife arranges accordingly and begins with them.
Speaker 0: The person that you're trying to lock up the person you were fighting against the person you have a Watchmen.
Speaker 0: So a guard to keep an eye on is the first person Who will be attacked or will succumb to the thing you were trying to prevent the thing you were trying to fight And there's.
Speaker 0: I really can't say much more about that without ruining elements that are in the story.
Speaker 1: now There are two other things I want to talk about the structure of the comic itself that Differentiates it from other American comics.
Speaker 1: at the end of every issue after that final panel with the quote there are usually about six pages or so
Speaker 0: of
Speaker 1: Text sometimes with some pictures, but it's mostly text and It kind of a lot of people I've noticed like not most people But there are plenty of people out there a scary number of people who do not read this text.
Speaker 1: They get to the end of this amazing comic and the six pages of plain old text and they don't want to read it because You know They're used to looking at a picture with a few words in it and then another picture with a few words and they're reading very Quickly and then all of a sudden you're gonna spend just as much time as you spent reading You know 26 pages of comics reading six pages of text.
Speaker 1: a lot of people don't want to do that And I understand the feeling but if you don't read it, you're an idiot.
Speaker 0: Yes these these things these addenda at the end of each issue are Basically if you take the world that Watchmen is set in and pretend that it's real.
Speaker 0: these are primary documents from that world.
Speaker 0: one of them will be just a Newspaper article that was published about one of these masked heroes back in the day.
Speaker 0: one of them might be the psychological profile of Rorschach.
Speaker 0: that was done by a Psychologist who examined him.
Speaker 0: one of them is just a bunch of poetry and talking about owls.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it is very very important that if you read this comic you do not skip over The text at the end of each issue.
Speaker 1: it is so ludicrously Futurously important for you to understand what's going on that you read that perhaps more carefully than you read the comic itself Because otherwise you'll miss a lot of the very deep and very well executed meaning and symbolism that is present.
Speaker 0: That you know, we talked about utenna before it.
Speaker 0: It was kind of the same thing shoujo kakumei utenna the anime where you have something that's so complex and well thought out that it's almost Cyclical and themes recur again and again and again and there are microcosms of the entire story taking place within Itself, it's like a recursion.
Speaker 1: Yeah speaking of stories within the story the final structural thing about this comic that is very different from other comics is that there is a Kid there's an african-american kid who hangs out by the newsstand and the newsstand has a grumpy old You know a newsstand selling guy who always complains about the world and how it's all shitty.
Speaker 0: Those two are some of my favorite characters just for the scene the last scene with them near the end of the comic and This african-american kid sits there and he just he doesn't care about this old man yapping.
Speaker 1: He wants to read comic books and the pirate the comic he chooses to read is about pirates.
Speaker 0: now This is definitely a work of meta fiction because inside of the watchmen There is this pirate comic this pirate comic that could be a comic all in its own It is if you just pulled it apart in reddit.
Speaker 0: It is a straight-up comic that is in and of itself Independently very good very meaningful and very enjoyable.
Speaker 0: however do not Read it on its own without reading the watchmen.
Speaker 0: at the same time
Speaker 1: also if you're reading the watchmen Don't skip over the pirate comic
Speaker 0: because the without ruining much the pirate comic is very much a parallel for not just the overall theme of watchmen but for Multiple characters and multiple different things that are going on in the work.
Speaker 0: And it's it acts as a foil a counterpoint it kind of and you may not realize exactly what it's saying.
Speaker 0: But there's a point at the end where the pirate comic ends simultaneously with something happening in the comic and That is the.
Speaker 0: that is the moment where I actually put the watchman down and said out loud.
Speaker 0: Wow Cuz I I knew it was coming.
Speaker 0: It's like utenna.
Speaker 0: you see Everything was there.
Speaker 0: you could have put it all together And then finally you figure out what's happening at the moment it happens And it was too late for you to figure it out, and it's just it's beautiful.
Speaker 1: Yeah the other thing about the pirate comic that I didn't catch until like the second or third reading is that the Pirate comic that it exists in the world of the watchmen as a physical object Actually has a place in the plot not the contents of the pirate comic But the physical pirate comic itself not the paper the kid is holding on to but the work of art that is the pirate comic has a place in the plot of the watchmen that you will not catch unless you pay close attention and Read the text at the end of the chapters and read the pirate comic and pay attention to all the words that are there And then at some point you will notice something happening in the plot of.
Speaker 1: That is related to the pirate comic in a direct way, and it's not easy to see.
Speaker 1: But when you finally realize it you go.
Speaker 1: oh That's ah fuck.
Speaker 0: Watchmen is one of those rare works And I say rare because I have very little free time.
Speaker 0: Scott has very little free time and yet despite the fact that I am Constantly deluge deluge with all sorts of media all of which I want to consume and interact with I will take the time to Reconsume certain media over and over again.
Speaker 0: I've watched cowboy bebop three or four times.
Speaker 0: I've read the watchmen twice straight through and I really want to read it all again right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm already starting to read it right.
Speaker 1: Thank you take already read it like four times.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking of taking it on the train tomorrow if you don't.
Speaker 1: yeah I don't know.
Speaker 1: We'll see how much I can read tonight.
Speaker 1: I got other stuff to read tonight, but yeah, but if you really like watchmen There's a version of the what you can buy the normal trade paperback Which is what we have for 20 bucks, which is good enough.
Speaker 1: you can also buy absolute watchmen Which is a gigantic beautiful hardcover book.
Speaker 1: it's like 50 bucks on Amazon And if you respect the watchmen because you're not an idiot It's actually kind of worth it to buy that giant thing Monstrosity if you will.
Speaker 0: now another interesting thing is a lot of comics particularly the kinds that I dislike.
Speaker 0: They'll always have like a character doing something in the close focus.
Speaker 0: you're like you're zoomed in on the superhero with his arm back and the motion lines like he's gonna punch someone and the yellow text at the top says You know Superman punch the dude and then it shows Superman saying I'm gonna punch you and then it shows them.
Speaker 0: Maybe if the comics from the 70s they stopped doing a lot of that stuff, but a lot of comics use thought bubbles Independent of all that showing characters thoughts showing what they're thinking.
Speaker 0: Watchmen never does that.
Speaker 0: it is entirely cinematic.
Speaker 0: you can guess at what characters motivations are from Monologues from their diaries that you'll read from their body language from the things they say But you never actually see into anyone's head.
Speaker 1: You know that the thought bubbles and superhero comics when I had a style years ago, right good Thought bubbles in a long time.
Speaker 0: good because then comedic come because I really really hate thought bubbles.
Speaker 0: in fact I often don't like it when I read a novel and I see inside someone's thoughts Yeah, what they do.
Speaker 1: sometimes though is they have that you know the narration boxes Which now Watchmen does have.
Speaker 1: you know like it says from the something something narration in a square box?
Speaker 1: And then you know the comic gets going yeah, and they're definitely.
Speaker 0: the narration jumps around a lot.
Speaker 0: You know a lot more than the characters do at any given time.
Speaker 1: Well, I think you know, but rim does make a point in that this doesn't have thought bubbles But thought bubbles in comics.
Speaker 1: superhero comics in America didn't go out of style until years later.
Speaker 1: Watchmen was way ahead of its time.
Speaker 1: I mean if you took this and you gave it to someone you know especially the absolute edition with the superior printing so they couldn't Guess by the print quality you know.
Speaker 1: hey When was this written?
Speaker 1: and they read the whole thing and they say oh, I think this was written in year X. It's pretty hard for people to guess the late 80s, but that's when it was written, and that's when it was published.
Speaker 0: now Also, I mean I use the word cinematic and a part of that was because you know you don't hear characters thoughts like that's.
Speaker 0: the big Problem with in my mind when they made Death Note into an anime is that most of Death Note is thinking is a character thinking To himself and turning that into a monologue really isn't that great.
Speaker 0: But if it weren't for the fact that it would be hours and hours and hours long.
Speaker 0: Watchmen could probably be directly Word-for-word scene for scene turned into a movie And it would work perfectly.
Speaker 1: the thing about Watchmen is one of those things where you know while you're reading it It's sort of like you're watching like one of the most amazing movies ever you know and After you're done reading it if you've ingested it fully and you know it then you can in your mind Play the movie Watchmen one of the greatest movies ever.
Speaker 1: But you know that if someone actually tried to make this into a movie on film There is no way they could possibly capture.
Speaker 1: What is in this book on film.
Speaker 1: It's just it's unfeasible.
Speaker 0: I mean V for Vendetta did a pretty good job in terms of taking the spirit of that work and Translating it to the screen, and I think V for Vendetta was a thousand times easier to do than Watchmen.
Speaker 1: How about ten thousand times?
Speaker 0: I don't trust anyone to make a Watchmen movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people are trying.
Speaker 1: It's been like one of those rumors on the internet for a long time.
Speaker 0: I don't think it could be.
Speaker 0: it would have to at least be a series In one time.
Speaker 1: it may come to pass that there will be a Watchmen movie But it will be so difficult for that movie to appease anyone who can appreciates the comic.
Speaker 0: I mean this would be about as difficult as when they made the Lord of the Rings movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Lord of the Rings like managed to pull it off by some miracle It would be.
Speaker 1: it would take a miracle ten times that power to do the Watchmen.
Speaker 0: Well at least of that power at least at least at bear.
Speaker 1: that to be a satisfactory job And you'd pretty much demand an awesome job.
Speaker 1: so because you have reading this comic in your mind This image of everyone who reads this and understands it has in their mind the Watchmen movie.
Speaker 1: That is so amazing.
Speaker 1: So if you actually tried to watch a real Watchmen movie if it didn't live up to the movie in your mind It would probably wouldn't sit well.
Speaker 1: I imagine with most people.
Speaker 0: so let's talk about the art.
Speaker 0: the art is gritty dark and Incredibly thought-out planned in detail.
Speaker 1: well the thing about it's like the art Like the quality of the art the drawing and the coloring itself is actually it's slightly above average for a comic of the 80s But it's really not so amazing.
Speaker 1: It's not like an Alex Ross Painting of amazing detail or anything like that.
Speaker 1: What's more important about the art.
Speaker 1: you know to me is not how well it's drawn But what is drawn like if you look at any frame of Watchmen right like his two characters talking, right?
Speaker 1: But there's all this other stuff in the picture too.
Speaker 1: There's stuff in the background.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: you know the characters are doing things.
Speaker 1: There's is all sorts of little details in every single frame.
Speaker 1: then unless you read it incredibly slowly and look At every single thing in every single frame you're missing out on more than half of the comic.
Speaker 0: also There are symbols that you probably won't even recognize on the first read-through, and then you'll read through again, and you'll see him Everywhere and you didn't even realize it.
Speaker 0: or one really interesting thing is pretty much any time There is a scene transition that is meaningful.
Speaker 0: Look at where one scene ends and where the next scene begins.
Speaker 0: the transitions are laid out as though It were a film as opposed to a comic book.
Speaker 0: There's probably a word for that.
Speaker 0: in fact I think when Emily took me to a lecture with one of her professors way back in the city We watched bits from Citizen Kane where they did the same thing.
Speaker 0: But I don't know what the word is and I feel kind of dumb here.
Speaker 0: So I'll just leave it be.
Speaker 0: But it's like that where like you focus on one thing and the scene changes around that thing and becomes the next scene and it's Just seamless and beautiful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think what really gets me Is that every time it's part of the reason why I can read it so many goddamn times Is that every time you read it like you'll notice in a particular like in a tiny panel a normal average panel?
Speaker 1: You know look here is a nine panel grid.
Speaker 1: on some page in each one of these panels there's something in the background.
Speaker 1: there might be a billboard or a newspaper on the ground or a graffiti on the wall or Some stranger character, that's not actually a named character doing something with someone else or a Shadow of someone doing something and all of it is meaningful in a way.
Speaker 1: That is obvious if you take the time to notice it.
Speaker 1: It's not like a tenor where it's some symbol.
Speaker 1: like you know some character keeps Hitting their stopwatch and random numbers are showing up, and you don't know what that means.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is if you see it, and you're not an idiot.
Speaker 1: It's obvious like oh my god.
Speaker 1: Look at that there.
Speaker 0: Holy shit, I do keep comparing it to a tenor, but at the same time as much as I love utana.
Speaker 0: I think watchmen is Deeper and especially the commentary that is in watchmen and the thick is it.
Speaker 0: you know anything can have a lot of well-executed Symbolism, but not only is the symbolism and the meaning beneath it relevant That's in watchmen, but it's relevant directly to the world we live in now And it touches on a lot of very uncomfortable issues and issues that I don't actually have a strong opinion on Because I'm about as conflicted as the characters in the story are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's that the issues that watchmen brings up are so powerful that I like I. it's weird usually when some other work of art brings up issues.
Speaker 1: You know it's like I start to form an opinion.
Speaker 1: I see what opinion they have of it.
Speaker 1: I decide if I agree or disagree and watchmen that doesn't really happen.
Speaker 1: like I just kind of Go with it, and it's just waiting.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm waiting through this muck But the muck is rich with awesome art And I don't even bother trying to decide if I if I'm going that way or if I'm going the other way or what?
Speaker 1: I think I just take it in and let it go because there's really no other way And I just try to get as much of it as possible Because it's just so thick if I really wanted to get everything out of it.
Speaker 1: It's like if I read it so slowly that I poured over every single panel to get everything out of it Then it would take me so long.
Speaker 1: Then I forget like the two issues ago And I wouldn't get all of it into my brain.
Speaker 1: and if I read it too quickly I wouldn't see everything in every panel.
Speaker 1: It is oh God.
Speaker 1: Oh, God.
Speaker 0: And I think at that point without ruining anything because I don't even want to ruin Who all of the characters are.
Speaker 0: all I can really say is that you should read this work.
Speaker 1: I don't recommend if you're listening to this show and anyone you know even like people who don't care about Talking your parents your children your brother Anyone who is age appropriate?
Speaker 1: I don't think little kids should probably read no no by anyone who's like high school or older and Who knows the English language or a language in which Watchmen is printed which I imagine is many.
Speaker 1: if it's not many It's a crime should read the Watchmen no matter what it's like required reading for all human beings Even if you can't even afford the book.
Speaker 1: if you cannot afford food, but you're going to live you should read the Watchmen.
Speaker 1: Let us close with a quote that it's from the Watchmen, but Watchmen takes it from elsewhere.
Speaker 1: Yes our favorite quote ever.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to read the entire poem even though it is also one of my favorite poems ever But it is in Watchmen.
Speaker 0: so you might hear me say and Scott say words from this often in fact Especially if you're playing with us in any sort of DS game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is one of our common phrases.
Speaker 1: You know I said there are quotes at the end of every issue.
Speaker 1: This is the quote that is at the end of chapter 11 the second to last chapter and on the pedestal these words appear My name is Ozzie mandy.
Speaker 0: as king of kings look on my works Ye mighty and despair.
Speaker 1: look on my works ye mighty and despair despair.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.