Speaker 1: It's Tuesday December 11th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: worms to open warfare or worms open warfare - Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll be brief about this since I assume any new listeners at least tried to listen to yesterday.
Speaker 1: But just in case if you're looking for our New York anime festival coverage You'll probably want to listen tomorrow Wednesday night, which is the night we talk about anime and manga and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep, and hence since it was an anime convention technically.
Speaker 0: I think it actually was primarily an anime convention.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about it on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: however We can talk a little bit about what gaming there was to be had at the New York anime festival since we usually after a Con will always do like the Tuesday after the con We'll talk about the game and going on there because you know Otakon has their crazy gaming room and katsu kon has the best Gaming room of any con ever and packs.
Speaker 1: Well, we haven't been to yet, but I can only imagine Gaming paradise I did if I'm to be believed.
Speaker 1: if if I if you are to be believed.
Speaker 0: Yes, exactly Alright, so at the New York anime festival, there was some gaming going on.
Speaker 0: I mean there were some gaming events like the video game magic.
Speaker 1: Well first off next door to the New York anime festival in what I can only assume was a startling coincidence the world championship of magic.
Speaker 1: the gathering was that money the wasting.
Speaker 1: and It's funny, you know you walk into the con.
Speaker 1: there's this giant Seraph angel statue like wow, is that for the anime con?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's for the magic tournament.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't even realize.
Speaker 0: and that was apparently the world championship of magic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I went in there and it wasn't very crowded.
Speaker 0: It was pretty crowded crowded, but it wasn't as crowded as you would imagine.
Speaker 1: When did you go in there?
Speaker 0: Oh only I only went down there like when I first got you know before you even there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was going on later.
Speaker 1: I walked in.
Speaker 1: it was pretty mighty crowded.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, yeah money the wasting.
Speaker 0: so in the New York anime festival the gaming situation.
Speaker 0: Well, first off there were a few dealers selling of course the gaming merchandise and the imported game stuff.
Speaker 0: You know typical what you have at every other anime con in the Northeast.
Speaker 1: though Now that Emily has the DS I think the DS import games are of much more interest to us as a crew at least to her because she can read the Japanese Yeah, and she can go on man.
Speaker 1: You guys don't know what you're missing, you know.
Speaker 0: And even though there's a whole bunch of games which don't really require You know much reading of Japanese and the DS is region-free I'm generally disinterested in those games because of the exorbitant price you must pay to obtain them.
Speaker 0: Oh, but roms anyway I don't do that.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yes, you do.
Speaker 1: You just don't have a card.
Speaker 1: yet You wait every day for a card to come out.
Speaker 1: that'll do that.
Speaker 0: It supposedly is a card and there's funny things to say about how people are selling that card.
Speaker 0: But I'm not gonna talk about that now because I have to spend 10 minutes finding the link again.
Speaker 0: All right Anyway, anyway So the first thing that was notable about this the gaming at the con was it was like Devil May Cry 4.
Speaker 0: OMG now I played Devil May Cry 1 for what the ps2 I think right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we played that at the capstone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I played that in college basically when it first came out on someone else's.
Speaker 1: now I remember we all went over there and you know, they're like check it out.
Speaker 1: I got Devil May Cry and For like a much hyped game for like a half hour.
Speaker 1: That was the best game I'd ever played because I jump up and then in slow motion while falling back down.
Speaker 1: I would shoot at a skeleton.
Speaker 0: It wasn't so much that he fell down in slow motion.
Speaker 0: It's that he didn't really slow down time It's just he fell really slowly like he could sort of levitate in the air and would fall to the ground.
Speaker 0: It would take him like like you jump up high Instantly and then it would take him like a good 30 seconds before he landed on the ground again.
Speaker 0: as long as you held down the jump.
Speaker 0: it was really cool Yeah, and you could shoot while you're up in the air.
Speaker 0: So I jump up in the air where a bad guy couldn't hit me and then shoot you Until the bad guy died.
Speaker 0: and those fun times.
Speaker 1: I didn't really play the game beyond that so I can't speak as to its quality.
Speaker 0: I think I played like the first half of a level maybe and then I got tired of it because it Was the same thing over and over again, and it was kind of easy.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it gets harder later, but I was done with it at that point.
Speaker 1: Well, you know we were in college.
Speaker 1: We had to go play some D&D instead.
Speaker 0: exactly So Devil May Cry 4 which I am pretty sure in fact I'm a hundred percent sure it is not a game you can currently purchase anywhere was playable at the New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 0: You had to wait in line and go in this little booth And then you could play out in one of their little TVs there that you know and it was surrounded with a black curtain.
Speaker 0: so You couldn't like get you know screenshots or photos or anything.
Speaker 0: I didn't go in and play it because I really didn't care But other people went and played it and they said it wasn't bad.
Speaker 0: They kind of liked it.
Speaker 0: You know we probably could have.
Speaker 1: we had those like solid gold professional badges.
Speaker 1: We probably just gotten right to the front of the line, but I had no desire to do so.
Speaker 0: Like it's like if you want you know sure playing a game.
Speaker 0: You know before its release is pretty cool But I have to want to play it or yet to give me some incentive.
Speaker 0: I just really didn't care about Devil May Cry at all.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there was also a video game room Which was one of the saddest video game rooms ever.
Speaker 0: the video game room was being run by New York Tokyo the people who ran the New York Tokyo music festival.
Speaker 1: Did we ever do a show about that?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe cuz that was Kind of awesome, but at the same time it was also kind of a bait-and-switch.
Speaker 1: And it was like come see all this awesome j-pop Oh my god Japanese music, and then we got there, and we got to see you know boa Do a small set.
Speaker 1: that was awesome.
Speaker 1: Then we got to see some other like j-pop artists do something and then it turned into like this four hour long boring techno party.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then we had to sleep on the streets of New York City only because we didn't get back to the train station.
Speaker 1: Cuz we sucked.
Speaker 0: cuz we sucked.
Speaker 0: we don't suck anymore.
Speaker 0: We'll never make a mistake like that again, but regardless this video game room right it had a few good things and mostly bad things.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: first of all it was really really tiny Incredibly tiny.
Speaker 0: and for a con where at least on Saturday where it was crazy crowded The the video game room in proportion was not large enough at all.
Speaker 0: I mean Really damn.
Speaker 0: was it small.
Speaker 1: I think it was helps my bedroom.
Speaker 1: I think it was helped by the fact it was literally smaller than my bedroom.
Speaker 1: yes But I think what really hurt it or helped it was that I don't think most people at the con knew it was there.
Speaker 0: Well, it was hidden in like the back hallway.
Speaker 0: I didn't know.
Speaker 1: there was a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: There was a Japanese art like kimono exhibit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's where the art show was.
Speaker 0: wasn't the art show also in there?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't matter cuz I didn't even know that kimono exhibit was there And I never went to it.
Speaker 1: I went over to what I peeked in.
Speaker 1: I had a drinks.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't let me in I didn't come back later.
Speaker 0: I only found out about it today when I was looking at the map of the con.
Speaker 0: That was sitting in the living room And
Speaker 1: there was the I think manga library or something a
Speaker 0: manga library which I've gone through before which is pretty much the best And I think the first manga library,
Speaker 1: but yeah, I think it worked out because honestly I mean I even I heard a kid as we were leaving the con on Sundays.
Speaker 1: We was walking out, and he saw the video game room, and he said oh, man.
Speaker 1: There's video games here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much That's that was.
Speaker 0: you put him in a back hallway like but
Speaker 1: at the same time if it was such a small room that was Probably for the best because there was never really a line to get in and you could just walk in and they're Reasonably short amount of time play a game.
Speaker 0: I heard from people that it was smelly on Friday But it was not smelly on Saturday or Sunday I guess I went in once just to look around with with anonymous from Apple geeks.
Speaker 0: We looked around and then we walked out and basically what was going on in there is they didn't have a good Selection of games and some of the good things they had were in the middle of the room were two tables and they had DS Is like tied down to the tables of games in them so you could play like that and that was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: They had a cooking mama They had cooked and signs above each television saying which game it was.
Speaker 0: you didn't need to like.
Speaker 0: go over and look real closely at Each one.
Speaker 0: you just kind of look around the room.
Speaker 1: I get the impression that it was super high quality.
Speaker 1: It was just too small.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was very few games You know and on one wall, they had a projector where they were doing all tournaments and such.
Speaker 0: I forget what do they think they were doing?
Speaker 0: a guilty gear something when I was in.
Speaker 1: Well when I walked in there were three projectors pointed at that wall.
Speaker 0: No, there was only.
Speaker 0: I think there may have been three pointed at the wall But I think only one was on taking up.
Speaker 1: I think it speaks well of Nintendo that to this day probably the most popular game in that room was Smash Brothers melee.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's gonna change in a couple months.
Speaker 0: Yep But anyway The one thing that I noticed that was especially high quality about the the room there was that there was a guy who was sort Of emceeing the tournaments and he was quite skilled in the ways of the emcee.
Speaker 1: Isn't that what we offered to do at Katsu khan last year and then just didn't?
Speaker 0: yeah, I think he's sort of like a. You know, I guess New York Tokyo must have people with that kind of talent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because that seems like the kind of thing they would have.
Speaker 1: Let's make sure Katsu khan has that going this year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I kind of need it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, other than that, it was just a tiny little game room with a good assortment of games ranging from you know The hardcore to the not hardcore the DS to the 360 to the ps3 and the Wii
Speaker 1: and Smash Brothers to cooking mama - yep
Speaker 0: And it was there and I guess it was good at getting like, you know Maybe 50 people could have been.
Speaker 0: I got to say when I walked in there people would have been a crowd.
Speaker 0: So, you know it kept a handful of people out of the rest of the con It had.
Speaker 1: they had a trauma center - in there.
Speaker 1: and I'm just walking around the own trauma center.
Speaker 1: No, but I see a kid and he picks it up and he's playing through some surgery.
Speaker 1: I don't know which one it was.
Speaker 1: I haven't played the game yet.
Speaker 1: But uh, I This was inexplicably and unexpectedly hilarious.
Speaker 1: so he starts playing right and dogs like do this do this to this and Then he like he looks around and then he just starts slashing Wildly with everything he can until the patient died as fast as possible that he laughed and walked away.
Speaker 0: He just took the scalpel away cutty cutty cutty.
Speaker 1: It was like.
Speaker 1: so he was careful.
Speaker 1: He was like think think think think And then he walked away going he after the guy died.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, it's a kid.
Speaker 1: I was just I was on.
Speaker 1: it was a little kid - he was like 14.
Speaker 0: What is this world coming to?
Speaker 1: Well when a 14 year old doctor murders a patient in a in a video game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how many Sims or Simoleons have you murdered in the course of your life?
Speaker 0: Not on purpose.
Speaker 1: Oh, ah You bulldoze more than one church or school to make more high-density residential blocks Maybe.
Speaker 0: but I've also summoned Godzilla only to get only so that I could get rid of him with my soldiers.
Speaker 1: You have also sent that one lone Horseman around the world only to die lonely and afraid in the Arctic wastes as you were trying to make your way to some other continent.
Speaker 0: No Anyway, that reminds me of that video where they they keep making the soldier walk into the wall.
Speaker 1: That was a good video.
Speaker 1: I think it was the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I think it was So in the news speaking of soldiers That game that I waited 10 years for and then promptly got sick of.
Speaker 1: well game was a team fortress - alright that one well valve collects Inordinate amounts of statistics from their game.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what they did is they learned from doing their valve survey.
Speaker 0: You know were they the hardware so that people really like to see statistics.
Speaker 0: No, no that they make a lot of money from that survey.
Speaker 0: Like they have companies calling them up and asking them, you know, we you know, who's using?
Speaker 0: are they using more invidious more?
Speaker 0: ATIs, you know is this and that is this a popular thing is and that's valuable data to collect and because of their steam platform They're pretty much the only ones who can collect it, you know, I know why.
Speaker 0: cuz I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: Let's say someone like I don't know.
Speaker 0: What's a recent popular PC game?
Speaker 1: Well, you're saying PC games because Microsoft can do a similar thing with Xbox Live if they want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but what are you gonna survey?
Speaker 0: Everyone has an Xbox.
Speaker 0: They're all the same.
Speaker 0: You're talking about serving PC hardware, you know, so with You know, so valve learned from surveying PC hardware the gathering data about games.
Speaker 0: It would be about gamers and the way they play the games is valuable and they've been collecting that since.
Speaker 1: but anyway they've released a big dump of a whole bunch of statistics from Team Fortress 2 and a Lot of people are making a big deal about these.
Speaker 1: but I actually saw very few interesting or surprising things.
Speaker 1: I mean they show you don't like if you count the total percentage of time played.
Speaker 1: Most people are scouts or engineers or soldiers and then it drops down pretty steadily and no one wants to play the medic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, you know because those those are the classes that are more sort of generally useful.
Speaker 1: You know points per hour sniper heavy spy soldier and then it's just down from there.
Speaker 1: You know average kills per hour heavy soldier sniper pyro The interest.
Speaker 1: well, I guess this isn't interesting at all either.
Speaker 1: but in terms of assists the medic is number one.
Speaker 1: but that's because I think the medic gets points for healing and the assist whatever.
Speaker 1: but The pyro is pretty much the number two along with the heavy and that kind of People on fire, but then they die from something else.
Speaker 1: Yep I go on and I mean obviously the scout gets the most captures per hour with the pyro being number two.
Speaker 1: I can't use the pyro more than anything.
Speaker 0: I capture is the scout mostly cuz I scout practice, but I haven't played this game in like months.
Speaker 1: yeah engineers live the longest medics live the least.
Speaker 1: so I guess Dave was a Very good in making his comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah And it goes on.
Speaker 1: and on this guy.
Speaker 1: I want to point out one really interesting thing that kind of emerged from all this?
Speaker 1: people play gravel pit the most which I don't understand because I don't like that map at all and They love here it is.
Speaker 0: I didn't play the game long enough to match the nap map names with the maps.
Speaker 1: So the map pretty much.
Speaker 1: if it's not to fort fuck you.
Speaker 1: But unless it's one of those kind of like weapons factory maps that was hacked into some custom server somewhere.
Speaker 1: but percentages of wins by team color versus stalemates.
Speaker 1: now I'm to fort.
Speaker 1: there's a tiny blue advantage, but you know, it's perfectly symmetrical.
Speaker 1: So you could obviously argue that you know, it's close enough except for the fact that if you count stalemates There's red loses a lot.
Speaker 1: red loses a lot on team for on our CTF to fort and CP well and TC hydro and CP greater e really is blues a barrier.
Speaker 1: But yet on dust bowl and gravel pit red kicks their ass.
Speaker 1: Dust bowl is very clearly weighted toward red.
Speaker 0: I know see wait are these?
Speaker 0: see it depends which maps are symmetrical, right?
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing to fort is perfectly symmetrical, right?
Speaker 1: And yet blue edges out like over the 50% mark winning and then there's a wide band of stalemates And then red comes in right?
Speaker 0: So here's the question Is that a psychological thing because of the color of blue versus the color of red?
Speaker 0: Which could is probably a good explanation both in terms of maybe dumb punk kids pick red the same way dumb punk kids pick scissors Or more a psychological thing like, you know blue is calming, you know, and red is more us You're.
Speaker 0: you're shooting faster when you see a red guy or it's easier to see a red guy.
Speaker 1: It might be that he's easier to see a red guy.
Speaker 0: It could be that.
Speaker 0: or is it something where?
Speaker 0: Players who are better tend to pick blue because they you know and there's something psychological in Color choice and also skills.
Speaker 1: the type of person with high skill is also Correlates heavily with the kind of person who picks blue, you know It is weird because I have to admit when I played weapons factory I pretty much would always join the blue team unless I was prevented from doing so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would always pick the green team no matter what it is red and blue.
Speaker 0: I know that's why there is when it's red I use auto-pick.
Speaker 1: There was a green team in quad CTF Mmm, that was great.
Speaker 1: It was just regular quake to like lithium CTF, but there were four teams and four flags and four bases.
Speaker 1: It got crazy.
Speaker 0: or could this be some sort of fluke thing?
Speaker 0: for example Let's say you join it.
Speaker 0: There's a new server starts up right and you click auto join.
Speaker 0: Does that put you on blue first or on red first or is it random?
Speaker 0: Cuz if it says if for example if it's blue first That would make a lot of blue wins, wouldn't it?
Speaker 1: Well, the other cool thing is they have heat maps of where people die the most.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 1: It's really cool to look at and I just want to point out that on a granary.
Speaker 1: It's almost perfectly Identically symmetrical and in the exact center is this epicenter of carnage?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would study those I was still playing I would study those maps and I would avoid those areas Avoid those areas and shoot at those areas.
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these stats are kind of cool.
Speaker 1: I wish they'd gathered more stats because I really want to see statistics in terms of I Don't know very exact numbers as to how many stalemates there are and all that sort of thing and people
Speaker 0: statistics and heat mass for counter-strike broken down by version from beta 1 up.
Speaker 1: Oh man Because you know when they first added the p90 that there were there was pretty much carnage everywhere And then when they toned down the p90 there was still carnage.
Speaker 0: ever happy people quit the game and then a hundred more people joined.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got for me?
Speaker 0: All right, so Remember I talked about before there's a Hokuto no Ken DS, which is sort of like elite beat agents.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's manga plus, you know elite beat agents action.
Speaker 0: Well, they're taking it a step further and a step better.
Speaker 0: Instead of making sort of interactive manga for the DS one company is pretty much saying you know what?
Speaker 0: Let's just make manga for the DS straight up.
Speaker 0: Not even like interactive manga just manga for the DS.
Speaker 0: I mean you have the ability to like, you know bookmark and stuff like that, you know.
Speaker 0: And maybe there might be a little bit of animation who knows whatever.
Speaker 0: but they're putting out Phoenix for the DS.
Speaker 1: damn what just like you buy a cartridge its Phoenix.
Speaker 0: you buy cartridges and there's like five volumes of Phoenix on There.
Speaker 1: at least one kid is gonna buy that or get that thinking it's a game and gonna be so pissed off.
Speaker 0: The DS cart packs in between four to five volumes of manga.
Speaker 0: But it's unknown which tales will be a part of the package something something something.
Speaker 0: It's kind of cool idea stylus scrolling and useful bookmark feature for short reads.
Speaker 0: Oh and sound effects Sound effects.
Speaker 0: you say sound effects.
Speaker 1: I don't know how I feel about this.
Speaker 1: I feel like on one hand I would never use something like this because I have the manga and it's much easier to read the Book and I guess if I wanted an e-reader, I would probably buy that Sony thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, DS really not the best for e-reader, I'm pretty much waiting off on e-readers until until there's something perfect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: Well, then again, there's two perfects cuz I'm living fine without one.
Speaker 1: Just well, there's three perfects.
Speaker 1: It kind of relates I guess now to the the thing Scott and I just watched that we're probably gonna talk about next Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but for me perfect is one.
Speaker 1: I just hit a button and the information is in my brain as though I had read it.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm not waiting that long or two.
Speaker 1: I can just see the word scrolling in front of my eyes with whatever Translucency and color I want at any time.
Speaker 0: that is also perfect.
Speaker 0: But I'll still.
Speaker 1: I'll still buy something that's less than three glasses that do the same thing So it doesn't have to be in my.
Speaker 0: it's more realistic.
Speaker 0: But I'm still or for buy something less than that.
Speaker 1: if it was just it felt like a book and it looked like a book But I could just put a flash card in the bottom.
Speaker 1: I just flip the pages.
Speaker 0: I would buy that too, but that's also more than what I'm willing to buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I don't know beyond that I'm thinking just Handheld device doesn't hurt the eyes to look at it.
Speaker 0: Good battery life.
Speaker 1: That's only things getting close.
Speaker 0: I got a sense too big and has all the problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's close.
Speaker 1: It's a lot closer than I expected.
Speaker 1: We were we would be about now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's still not close enough though It's somewhere somewhere in between.
Speaker 1: I'll say this when I'm
Speaker 0: a digital book and that like
Speaker 1: even now if I'm reading cuz I have you Know Safari books online I can read whatever tech books I want there But I often find myself printing out a chapter and reading it somewhere when I could just be sitting in front of the computer.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking like iPhone with a with a special book screen or book screen mode.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm thinking for realism in the near future things of the day.
Speaker 1: So we found this last week and I didn't get a chance to talk about it since I think we put up the questions episode Last Tuesday, so I think it's about time.
Speaker 0: I thought it was less.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: No, maybe I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I think it was last Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I don't remember cuz otherwise I think we would have talked about this.
Speaker 1: but there's a game a little video game made by Jason Rohrer For the Coco Romis gamma 256 event which looks like it was some sort of video game contest and there's a bunch of little games that people have made and I think the rules worry.
Speaker 1: it had to be a Windows XP game that used the Xbox 360 controller Mm-hmm, and people made a bunch of really weird little quirky games.
Speaker 1: They vary wildly, but this one in particular really stood out.
Speaker 1: now the main reason I want you all to see this game and play it is that Every now and then people make the argument that video games aren't art or that video games are somehow lower different.
Speaker 1: or I Contend that this game is effectively what I you know subjective and all that high art.
Speaker 1: I think this game is proof beyond any reasonable doubt that video games as a medium are most definitely Artistic.
Speaker 0: not only that.
Speaker 0: this is like maybe a masterpiece of art.
Speaker 0: I would not know what is technically masterpiece mean because I mean it's not like, you know Picasso level but it's like right below that.
Speaker 1: this is a game.
Speaker 1: That's so simple.
Speaker 1: I almost feel like I don't want to ruin it by telling you about it.
Speaker 0: No But just the entire game is a metaphor.
Speaker 0: every single thing in the game is a very obvious and very simple metaphor.
Speaker 0: That is very poignant.
Speaker 1: and yet the game is 100 pixels by 16 pixels Yep, and you only get to play in 100 by 12 of those pixels.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I'd say play it more than once you might discover some things.
Speaker 1: the game I think poignant.
Speaker 0: the only controls in this game Are you push any button to start the game and then use up down left and right and make sure you try to use up Down left and right in every way you can because you will learn more things.
Speaker 1: and make sure that you have sound because the music Is very important to this.
Speaker 0: Mmm, very important.
Speaker 1: And uh, yeah, you you can bring a person along or not in the game.
Speaker 1: You'll see that I just want to point that out because I we didn't notice that at first.
Speaker 0: and You can go right you can go down you can go up you can go left Poignant and a little sad but yet at the same time a little inspirational.
Speaker 0: Yeah, seriously.
Speaker 1: I'm not kidding check this out.
Speaker 0: We're not making stuff up here.
Speaker 1: And if you don't like this game, well, you're probably dead inside.
Speaker 0: No, most definitely Oh, and if you're dead inside this will deaden you more inside.
Speaker 0: if such if such a thing is Possible all right.
Speaker 0: So I was having a tough time figuring out which of my many things that I have collected to use.
Speaker 0: but check this out.
Speaker 0: Right, there's a guy on YouTube and his YouTube name is soda Popinski 75.
Speaker 1: All right He's already awesome because soda Popinski is my band soda Popinski.
Speaker 0: Oh, man Sorry, so this dude he made an arcade cabinet like, you know pieces of wood TV Buttons joystick.
Speaker 0: the whole works, right, but he made his arcade cabinet with a special theme if you will.
Speaker 0: He made it with the Metroid themes.
Speaker 0: It's it's a. it looks if there was such a thing as a Metroid arcade machine.
Speaker 0: This is pretty close to what it would look like.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's probably better than what the actual thing would look like.
Speaker 0: In this video he sort of plays a Metroid remix while he you know shows off his you know Cabinet that he made and It's sort of annoying this video because he keeps showing you like mostly this like mother brain sculpture He put in the side of it that has like a little in like a little lit up chamber Sort of on the side of the cabinet.
Speaker 0: and it's sort of annoying because you don't get to see.
Speaker 0: you get to see that More than you get to see the actual entire cabinet itself.
Speaker 0: But you do get to see the cabinet itself and it's a YouTube videos.
Speaker 0: Just pause it whatever and take a look.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I wish I could make an arcade cabinet like that because that'd be cool to have in the house if I had room Next to my air hockey table, right?
Speaker 1: So without further ado tonight what we're gonna talk about a game that I feel we should review Worms 2 for the DS.
Speaker 0: I think it's worms to open warfare.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the technical name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should probably look it up, but it's worms - yeah All right.
Speaker 0: Let's just start off by saying that there there worms is a game that's on many platforms.
Speaker 0: on the DS There was worms open warfare and I think worms to open warfare or worms open warfare - I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: worms the original worms just worms for the Nintendo DS is Perhaps one of the most disappointing games ever made in terms of what it should have been what it could have been What it was and what it was was something that you couldn't fucking play.
Speaker 0: Okay, here we go worms open warfare.
Speaker 0: The first one right was for the DS and the PSP and the DS.
Speaker 0: Oh worms open warfare was Terrible like unplayable shit.
Speaker 0: Don't even buy it.
Speaker 0: Don't even look at it pretend.
Speaker 0: It doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: All right worms open warfare 2 for the DS Not bad, and that's the game we both bought.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the worms franchise is like 13 years old and we're not really gonna talk about that because it's kind of interesting But not really.
Speaker 1: it's been released on like every platform.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's just let's talk about what worms is in general, right?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: It's one of those I'd call it a scorch like well worms a little different from scorch.
Speaker 0: Oh it is it is It is a thing.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about scorched earth.
Speaker 0: We ever talked about scorched earth?
Speaker 1: I don't know we should probably do a show on that by itself.
Speaker 1: But there back in the day, you know when video game PC gaming was in its infancy There was a game called I think tank wars or tanks.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of similar games.
Speaker 0: There are many many games.
Speaker 0: I mean I played one on the old Mac that was called cannon fodder and I know there's another game called cannon fodder But I don't know what that game is like.
Speaker 1: But there all these games eventually culminated in perhaps the perfection of that game and it was a game called scorched earth Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: You have little tanks and you use your money you buy weapons and you shoot at all the other little tanks and this game is Fucking legendary.
Speaker 0: Oh, this game is amazing.
Speaker 0: basically, the way these games work is that there's a map a 2d map and you're looking at it from the side and tanks are positioned randomly or perhaps not randomly on the map and this hills and this terrain and whatever and You control.
Speaker 0: your tank doesn't really move so much and you can control the angle of your tanks gun Like it's a piece of artillery.
Speaker 0: so you can.
Speaker 0: the angle you can control either, you know 180 degrees of motion.
Speaker 0: It can either fire straight left straight right straight up or anywhere in between.
Speaker 0: you can't fire down though Cuz you're a tank you can't really shoot below your treads.
Speaker 0: That doesn't work.
Speaker 0: and then you adjust the level of power with which you are going to shoot.
Speaker 0: so you can shoot with Full power which pretty much would make it a straight shot or you can shoot with less power Which sort of make an arcing shot, you know would shoot and then it would lose speed and energy and it would sort of fall to the ground and gravity would you know, take it control and the idea was to manipulate the angle and the power of your shots to hit the other tanks and you sort of had to Sort of is like artillery, you know, you shoot thought you shot too far.
Speaker 0: lower the power.
Speaker 0: Okay, that was too close You know lower the angle.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: He's got a bead on me.
Speaker 1: I got a move.
Speaker 1: I knocked the ground out from under him.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's got a parachute.
Speaker 1: He's got a deflector shield.
Speaker 1: That's okay.
Speaker 1: I got a nuke.
Speaker 0: you start to throw in all sorts of weapons and items and abilities.
Speaker 0: Yeah, suddenly the game gets crazy go nuts.
Speaker 0: and when you include the you know, the extra strategy of manipulating the terrain of the game You know creating more terrain Eliminating terrain because a lot of it would be like, you know, there's two guys the hill in the way It's it's who can shoot over the hill accurately.
Speaker 0: Okay, what do I just destroy the hill then I shoot you.
Speaker 0: You know that that's that's what these games come down to and they're pretty fun.
Speaker 1: He's a ride bomb.
Speaker 1: get may put someone a little depression then fill it with napalm.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's the best.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe not the best but one of the best.
Speaker 1: Now these this game is great and worms is on the surface very similar to this game, but definitely on the surface It's a. it's a similar game but instead of having tanks little worms and instead of shooting, you know, nuclear weapons and bombs and napalm and all these things you shoot Buffaloes of lies and Uzi's holy hand grenades and sheep and super sheep and also bazookas Donkeys.
Speaker 0: the bazooka is the default weapon.
Speaker 0: The grenade is also the default weapon.
Speaker 1: I think the buffalo of lies is my favorite weapon at any game ever.
Speaker 0: just for the name I kind of like the buffalo of lies.
Speaker 0: It's not bad.
Speaker 0: yeah, and you have all these different weapons and some of the weapons are actually other things like rope and teleporters and jetpacks to let you move around.
Speaker 0: you can actually You know, basically the way it works is on your turn one of your worms is activated and you can move that worm for some specified amount of time and you can jump and move left and right and you can even do a backflip to jump up instead of sideways.
Speaker 0: and Then at any point you can use some of your weapons, right?
Speaker 0: And you have a whole bunch of weapons and some weapons like say the jetpack or the rope.
Speaker 0: You can use them and your turn won't end when you use them.
Speaker 0: so you can jetpack and then use another weapon right after that.
Speaker 0: But other weapons like the bazooka or grenade or pretty much anything that does damage It's gonna end your turn after you use it.
Speaker 0: So if I shoot my bazooka, I shoot it and maybe I hit you.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't.
Speaker 0: and then if the game might give me like five seconds to like move around.
Speaker 0: So maybe if I want to like drop a stick of dynamite I could drop the stick of dynamite on the ground because you really can't throw it and then run away before it kills me.
Speaker 0: Cuz you know it drops right next to me.
Speaker 1: So if scorched earth was a game of accurate shooting and weapon selection, this is much more a game of Platforming and positioning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's sort of like what versus Mario.
Speaker 0: in a way It's like on your turn you get to Mario it up, but it also weapons, you know so and you sort of have to have the skill of jumping the skill of positioning the skill of navigating terrain and the skill of utilizing various equipment to help you navigate terrain.
Speaker 0: and You know get yourself in a good offensive position Doing as much damage using you know a weapon and all the weapons even the really powerful ones Take some amount of skill to use and yet to know which one is best except the donkey.
Speaker 1: the donkey requires zero skill.
Speaker 0: Some of them require more skill than others.
Speaker 0: The donkey requires a tiny bit of skill.
Speaker 1: It doesn't kill.
Speaker 1: it requires at least the some section of your prefrontal cortex to be intact.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the that skill in a way the the boomerang where however it requires a great deal more skill than the donkey.
Speaker 0: and You know you use a weapon if you want which you probably should and then you you know Try to get into a defensive position and then you continue and you just keep.
Speaker 0: everyone takes turns until someone wins By killing all the other guys worms.
Speaker 1: now this game.
Speaker 1: I mean nominally.
Speaker 1: there's a single player and you can play it to get good at the game.
Speaker 1: But this game is basically nothing unless all your friends buy it and you play it together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there is a way you can play the multiplayer with single cart mode.
Speaker 0: It sucks.
Speaker 0: It's good for introducing someone to the game.
Speaker 0: It's good for I got nothing better to do right now Let's play some worms, but really it sucks because it's it's random.
Speaker 0: first of all It's a basic a random shitty map limited weapon selection limited customizability of the multiplayer mode And the person who owns the cartridge or is using the cartridge always goes first Which is a big advantage especially in a two-player game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's talk about the Customizability a bit because you can customize Everything you can.
Speaker 1: you name all your worms you name your team you make your flag.
Speaker 1: My flag is up somewhat distinctive my flag.
Speaker 0: I'm still drawing my flag.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my flag is up something distinctive and Scott's is like a quarter of a boo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta draw the rest of that boo and you know you pick what color your worms are what dance they do it.
Speaker 1: There's so much stuff in this game and you make your only little team.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you go.
Speaker 0: Every worms game has had that but this worms game continues that you know proud tradition.
Speaker 1: It looks like it's got my seat too, but I haven't tried it.
Speaker 1: Oh, does it have hot seat and it looks like I could make more than one human opponent and a non Multi-cart like non multiplayer game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, if you have multi-cart multiplayer or perhaps hot seat.
Speaker 0: I haven't tested it.
Speaker 0: Well some reviewers we are right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well because we're so awesome you can have a fully customized multiplayer game and the way this works is.
Speaker 0: you make a scheme in this sort of the scheme editor for All the rules of your particular worms game and you can set pretty much any rule.
Speaker 0: You can say worms can move worms can't move.
Speaker 0: after shooting you get this many seconds to move around.
Speaker 0: before shooting you get this many seconds to move around.
Speaker 0: these weapons are available and these other weapons are available at this time to Get this much ammo and this yeah You can set it to be like, okay on the first turn Everyone only has airstrikes and you get this many of them.
Speaker 0: and then on the third turn you get this many.
Speaker 0: You know bazooka shots.
Speaker 0: and on the fifth turn you you can change Everything to make exactly the kind of game you want to play.
Speaker 0: you can make it crazy weapons.
Speaker 0: You can make it know only melee weapons you know.
Speaker 1: the coolest thing is that you make.
Speaker 1: you set all this up and you save all these presets and Then you can sit around and hey you want to play the blah blah blah preset.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's go.
Speaker 0: the game comes with a few presets, but some of them are not so good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even better.
Speaker 1: You can pretty much make any freaking terrain you want.
Speaker 1: It has a fantastic terrain editor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the terrain editor is a little.
Speaker 0: you know Any terrain editor is a little weird and hard to get used to at first.
Speaker 0: But as soon as I figured it out, I was making terrain like a champ.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the learning curve is steep.
Speaker 1: But when I say fantastic, I guess I should say that in the sense that you can do anything.
Speaker 0: Anything is possible.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is the game doesn't really come with such as great selection of maps.
Speaker 0: so you pretty much have to make a map which is good and bad.
Speaker 0: cuz Good because well you and all your friends since you'll have the cartridge will all be making maps and you'll be able to you know play maps other people and I think you can trade maps, but I'm not quite sure how and You know, you can make really big maps that way which provide the most interesting play experiences.
Speaker 0: But then again, you have to put an effort to make a map.
Speaker 0: if you just use random maps or auto-generated maps It's gonna be kind of boring and crappy now.
Speaker 1: This is one of those special games where Skill is a very large factor in who will win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, for example When I had played beaten the single-player and I played against people who like rim who had barely played it I pretty much won every time because I knew how to use all the weapons.
Speaker 0: I'd practice using all the weapons I knew which ones to use in which situations and You know I could.
Speaker 0: I was better at navigating to terrain and I used it took me less time on my turn to do things Which allowed me to get into better positions, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: But then after playing against him a bunch and then you know Actually starting to play the single-player the tie turned a bit.
Speaker 1: because now Oh rims really good with grenades Yeah, you know it there's.
Speaker 0: there is also a certain amount of randomness in the.
Speaker 1: well That's what I was getting at.
Speaker 1: Yeah skill is a big factor But at the same time like I one game I totally hosed Scott like partly because he started in a really bad spot just randomly.
Speaker 0: I think that is the biggest random factor in the game is starting positions Especially on a map where it's possible to just fall in the water.
Speaker 0: because I mean worms have health, right?
Speaker 0: Unlike say scorched earth.
Speaker 0: Well scorched earth yet takes that health.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yes, they did.
Speaker 1: They had like they had a hundred health.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you hit him with a direct hit with it with the big the baby, you know the normal shot Yeah, but direct hits were kind of rare especially when you also had shields and things.
Speaker 0: and yeah Well, you had to get the shields and things happens later.
Speaker 0: But basically the worms have a hundred health and pretty much nothing does a hundred damage.
Speaker 0: in order to do a hundred damage like you have to get someone in a situation where you hit them with like a really powerful weapon and they happen to be standing next to dangerous stuff and After that stuff blows up it knocks them into more dangerous stuff Which also blows up.
Speaker 0: or use the orgy or they get a lot of falling damage.
Speaker 0: Donkey.
Speaker 0: the donkey or the banana bomb will also do a lot of damage, but those are the only ones.
Speaker 0: So it's pretty much impossible to kill a worm in one shot except Knocking them into the water or off the map sort of in a Smash Brothers style.
Speaker 0: So you'll see on a map where it's possible to be knocked into the water.
Speaker 0: The best strategy is pretty much Get over directly next to your opponent Especially if they're near the edge of the map and use like the you know The dragon uppercut, you know, which is a direct copy from Street Fighter, you know sure you can and just knock him in the water.
Speaker 0: and That's what everyone does.
Speaker 1: This game despite the fact I mean, it's you know, it's really skill based but there's also a lot of randomness there.
Speaker 1: It's really fun.
Speaker 1: And it's not like.
Speaker 1: you know, you play a German board game and you realize this random you lose and it's ah I lost because the game just fucked me.
Speaker 1: There's nothing I could have done and your friends go.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's how it goes.
Speaker 1: Haha, and this game is like, oh man, I totally just lost.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think what makes the game so great is that no matter how many times you play it right in every single play of The game especially a big multiplayer play Something crazy always happens at least once something absolutely crazy hilarious Like someone will throw a grenade and you know what they're trying to do and then something totally unexpected happens like a worm You know gets blown, you know to the other side of the map maybe.
Speaker 0: and then something crazy like a crazy coincidence like something falls out of the sky and then something blows up in an Unexpected way and something moves in an unexpected way and then oh my god It's hilarious.
Speaker 1: or I blow up the last worm and and I win I'm God killed him but his body Flies and just bounces off the ceiling and lands right next to my worm and then blows up.
Speaker 0: Cuz there's me.
Speaker 0: every time a worm dies He detonates himself which makes a little tiny explosion and most of the time that doesn't have much of an effect.
Speaker 0: But if you kill someone who's right next to you or right next to one of your guys That especially if you're really close to the bottom of the map where you know It could make a hole and drop you both in the water.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty awesome Pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: So if you have friends who have DS's you should buy as many copies of worms, too For the DS as you have friends and DS's at least up to four.
Speaker 0: I mean there are lots of iterations of worms for the PC and many other systems and some of them are good and some Of them are bad.
Speaker 1: I think this is the best one only because of the ease of play with friends.
Speaker 0: I definitely have to say that even if there are other Editions of worms.
Speaker 0: I haven't played every edition of worms out there.
Speaker 0: There might be a better one.
Speaker 0: there might be not who knows but because this one is portable and because it's on the DS and because of the Features inside of it I definitely recommend it more highly than any other other ones.
Speaker 0: because worms is sort of like the game that Perfectly lends itself to portability more more than anything else.
Speaker 0: if you whip it out You can play a game in like five minutes.
Speaker 0: It's hilarious every time and awesome.
Speaker 0: You wanna say anything else?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think that kind of wraps it up.
Speaker 0: It's kind of short.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: We can do a short episode.
Speaker 1: We'll have a lot of long episodes to come.
Speaker 1: I think tomorrow when we talk about the festival we'll go on for a bit.
Speaker 0: Yep Alright, but yeah worms and you know any other kind of worms type game also.
Speaker 0: There are also some 3d worms type games, but I don't know if you want to play those.
Speaker 0: I've played them a few times and they're the ones of the GameCube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kind of it's fun, but it's fun in this really frustrating way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not quite good.
Speaker 0: Oh one more thing to say about worms though is that there's a rope in in worms Which it's pretty much.
Speaker 0: it's like you shoot it and it grabs on to a wall or ceiling.
Speaker 0: that rope is great And you can you can you know lengthen or shorten the rope and you can swing back and forth and you know Do both at the same time and many games have tried to implement some sort of grappling hook mechanic.
Speaker 0: This game implements the grappling hook mechanic better than any game ever even better than bionic commando and every other 2d game that wants to have some sort of rope or hook should just Copy worms 2ds.
Speaker 1: So of course just to remind you tune in tomorrow night Wednesday night geek nights Wednesdays anime manga comics And you'll hear all about the New York anime festival.
Speaker 1: We have some some shoutouts to give.
Speaker 1: We've met a lot of cool people at that con and we'll probably talk a lot about the con and the pros and cons.
Speaker 0: the pros and cons of the con.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives Visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.