Speaker 1: It's Wednesday July 18th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim Scott's in the other room packing for Otacon and this is geek night.
Speaker 1: Tonight we present to you our Kinetic on 2007 con report.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Man, this week just flew by.
Speaker 0: Well, you only work three days.
Speaker 1: Those are three quick days, especially when it's not just oh, I'm working three days Then I get a long weekend.
Speaker 1: It's I'm working three day or working three days and then I'm taking a long weekend and then I'm taking a week and another Weekend, I've basically taken seven work days off starting tomorrow.
Speaker 0: So that's a total of 7 8 and 10. a lot of days 11 days of no working and oh that's gonna reset the old Machine, I think I'll be feeling mighty good when we get back or mighty tired from vacationing and eating another vacation.
Speaker 1: No, because our vacations in Wildwood typically are actually relaxing.
Speaker 0: I know it's it just.
Speaker 0: you know, a lot of people especially typical US Stereotypical family they leave on Friday night.
Speaker 1: They get back Sunday night They go to work on Monday and they do stuff the whole time They're out they run around doing touristy crap that tires them out and then they don't actually relax or rewind or unwind or anything.
Speaker 0: so Yeah, Otacon this weekend.
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't really have any news about it.
Speaker 1: We already talked about what panels were doing.
Speaker 1: The only thing I really want to point out is that apparently?
Speaker 1: Gerald over at anime world order has a far lower opinion of himself than we do with him.
Speaker 1: So I have to retract my Statement that he's gonna do something awesome at the end of the panel.
Speaker 1: It turns out he's going to do something really really lame and boring.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, I guess that means he's just gonna show up and be his usual self.
Speaker 0: Oh, he's gonna.
Speaker 0: he's gonna talk like Sam the Eagle for maybe a half hour and then leave.
Speaker 1: Now apparently he was just concerned that I was pimping up like his final segment for the gecky got panel And he's worried that I was gonna raise the expectations too high.
Speaker 0: so, uh don't expect so much such a high percentage of the people that are gonna be there listen to this show and They're all expecting something big.
Speaker 1: In fact, I almost feel like we should kick anyone out who already listens to us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you already hear this stuff.
Speaker 1: You already know half of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is gonna be mostly entertainment for the Hentai plebeians out there.
Speaker 0: All right, so I actually believe it or not?
Speaker 0: have an underwear pervert news.
Speaker 0: Amazing spider-man is pretty much the spider-man comic.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm always complaining about how there are other spider-man comics like Spectacular spider-man and friendly neighborhood spider-man even though that one's not so bad.
Speaker 0: and I guess there's some other ones.
Speaker 0: I don't know a web of spider-man.
Speaker 0: I don't think they make web of spider-man.
Speaker 1: I think that man's really the only underwear pervert.
Speaker 1: I like yeah, even then I don't like most Batman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway Marvel is doing one smart thing.
Speaker 0: This is why this is such big news.
Speaker 0: ready They're canceling everything except for amazing spider-man Really?
Speaker 0: Yes, and they're only gonna.
Speaker 0: they're gonna make amazing spider-man three times a month Which is a big deal because now you don't have to deal with the bullshit of reading a bunch of different comics.
Speaker 0: You just read one comic and I'm sure it was three issues coming out a month.
Speaker 0: that means they'll probably be trades every two or three months.
Speaker 0: and Spider-man if it's.
Speaker 0: if they write a good spider-man story, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I might read some spider-man cuz I kind of like spider-man.
Speaker 1: I just remember when I was a kid and I thought hey, I should check out this comic thing.
Speaker 1: I know other people read quote-unquote comic books.
Speaker 0: That's the problem.
Speaker 0: is you read them in the early 90s when they were shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is most of them are still pretty bad.
Speaker 0: 90% of them are still shit Yes, but in the 90s in the early 90s, it was more like 99 point.
Speaker 1: But my problem was specifically that I thought alright, I'll read this one and it's called the x-men.
Speaker 1: Yeah, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: How come the story doesn't make sense between it?
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I have to read this other comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah this other comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll fuck this.
Speaker 1: I'm going back to my Nintendo.
Speaker 0: So it's good to see they're finally moving away from that in however small away.
Speaker 1: I wonder how much crazy fanboy outcry there's been.
Speaker 0: there has been Fanboy outcry in both directions surprisingly really?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Ooh, maybe we'll get some sort of fanboy war.
Speaker 0: Yes, we'll see.
Speaker 0: some of the concerns of the fanboys are that you know?
Speaker 0: Let's see if you read amazing spider-man now, right?
Speaker 0: Every issue of amazing spider-man is written by one guy and artist by another guy, right and every issue of friendly neighborhood Spider-man is written by another guy and artists by another guy but it's consistent within the title.
Speaker 0: so all the friendly neighborhoods are written by one guy and all the amazing sir written by a different guy and The.
Speaker 0: the thinking is that now that it's three a month It's gonna be a different writer for each one during the month and a different artist for each.
Speaker 0: Because no, you know American comic artists are all lazy and they can't you know Do the work of a manga artist of like 10 pages a day?
Speaker 0: And they have to add the colors in and they have to do all this fancy printing and shit.
Speaker 0: So they can only make you know, 24 pages a month Whereas a manga artist with their crew makes that much in.
Speaker 1: It depends on the manga artist.
Speaker 0: some Artists are super slow.
Speaker 0: Yes, like the trygun guy, but you know freaking Tezuka man He put out a zillion pages all by himself and anyone who doesn't live up to that, you know.
Speaker 0: Well, you're just not as good as he is.
Speaker 1: But anyway in other news I would just like to point out that Lupin the third is one of my favorite franchises of anime and manga ever.
Speaker 1: I just on the third upon the third.
Speaker 1: Well on July 27th in Japan, they're going to air the 40th anniversary upon the third television special.
Speaker 1: now apparently this is the 18th or 19 such special and they got someone cool to sing the opening theme for it and it is called Scott.
Speaker 1: that is so annoying.
Speaker 0: I Was trying to keep it up the whole time.
Speaker 1: It's called a Lupin the third kitty.
Speaker 0: No elusive Mmm, we might have to watch that somehow.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: perhaps there will be a Torrent.
Speaker 0: perhaps there might be with some subteeth lays granted.
Speaker 1: We're definitely not gonna see until we get back from our vacation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing Lupin is a really interesting Series in Japan because it had like two or three TV series, right?
Speaker 0: It has a whole bunch of movies a lot of which were made for TV movies and it seems that more than any other You know anime manga property.
Speaker 0: Lupin has like a billion TV specials all over the place and it's really hard to see them all and I really let alone the Gigantic quantity of episodes of the shows.
Speaker 1: Yes, and all the movies and the manga I and don't forget the live-action Strange psychokinetic strategy.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: We got to buy the DVD of that.
Speaker 1: I saw that.
Speaker 0: I gotta see it.
Speaker 1: I mean it was good enough to where we're at katsu-kan and our hotel room was Literally like at the top of a little stairway and at the bot like it was stairway to our room.
Speaker 1: Go down the stairs open the door.
Speaker 1: You're in the middle of the con like crazy yelling right there.
Speaker 1: So Scott goes it's go Joe not Scott the other Scott.
Speaker 1: Let's see the other Scott.
Speaker 1: We know your.
Speaker 0: I wasn't there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the year before Scott came to katsu-kan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I don't know there'll be no such year again.
Speaker 1: I was there with the the surrogate Scott the the older Scott the some would argue superior Scott Some like he would.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's about it.
Speaker 1: Well, uh, he says I'm getting up early to go see this Lupin and I'm laying in bed with a slight hangover thinking You know I'm gonna stay here for a while and he calls my phone like four times and then he comes back upstairs.
Speaker 1: It says rib.
Speaker 1: You gotta come down.
Speaker 1: It's freaking awesome.
Speaker 1: So in my pajamas, I stagger downstairs and stagger into the showing room and uh, it was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we'll pick that up.
Speaker 1: I'll warn you though It was really dumb, but it was dumb in that awesome way.
Speaker 0: Was it better than size and Jotaro?
Speaker 1: Uh, it was dumber.
Speaker 1: No, no, it wasn't dumber.
Speaker 1: It's hard.
Speaker 1: You know, you can't compare him because eyes and Jotaro is the Absolute line between bad and funny.
Speaker 1: It is the thin edge if you go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz part of it's funny and part of it's just bad.
Speaker 1: if you go any more bad It ceases to be funny because it's just really bad.
Speaker 1: You don't want to watch that's true.
Speaker 1: If you got any less bad or less dumb, it's just lame and you don't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also.
Speaker 1: oh, it's right there.
Speaker 1: There is nothing closer to the line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the Lupin is funny bad.
Speaker 1: Lupin was awesome and stupid.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: All right Thing of the day.
Speaker 0: rim didn't want to bother with the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Well, I could done like there's a ghost riding old grandma.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a good one.
Speaker 1: I'm saving that for a Monday.
Speaker 1: All right wider Technological and techno society ramifications.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about the socio-political impacts of such.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, my thing of the day is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: It's Japanese TV.
Speaker 0: Of course the source of all things of the day.
Speaker 1: Do you think we should just be done with it and just have a thing of the day be Japanese TV?
Speaker 0: It's basically what this area is, but this is a monkey and a dog Riding the train without any visible help from human beings.
Speaker 1: It's quite interesting and somewhat hilarious.
Speaker 1: And I think my favorite part is the end.
Speaker 1: when he books through that turnstile Yeah the monkey is actually.
Speaker 0: you can see that he not only did he learn beforehand how to use the train ticket machine and how to Use the train turnstile and all that stuff, but he learns in the process of executing his you know practiced Maneuver that the turnstile is sort of scary and it'll hit him if he messes up.
Speaker 0: So he is afraid of the turnstile.
Speaker 1: I just I mean they always zoom in on his face and he's obviously sitting there Thinking about what to do next and how to go about it and he succeeds.
Speaker 0: He actually does a better job than a lot of humans.
Speaker 1: I've seen in the city I do recall not one but two of our friends when we took them to New York City for the first time Proceeded to swipe their metro card and then push the turnstile around thus depriving them of getting access.
Speaker 0: Yes, but they still did better than the monkey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they did but I have seen people who haven't.
Speaker 0: yes I have seen people who have not done as well as this monkey.
Speaker 1: So yeah, so instead of a thing of the day very briefly We're just gonna tell you about all the things we're doing at Otakon.
Speaker 1: Also, I want to point out again that Gerald has something really lame planned for the end of our gecky god panel.
Speaker 0: All right anyway Friday most of our first of all, we're gonna be in the artists alley.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be in the back of the artists alley near the bathrooms and left unless the map changes somehow.
Speaker 0: So if you want to see us We're gonna probably be spending a lot of time there when we're not doing anything else and at least one of us or one Of the crew will be there most of the time.
Speaker 0: I want to say I don't know.
Speaker 0: So yeah, come see us in artists alley if you can't find us anywhere else.
Speaker 0: So yes, we will be in the artists alley much of the con if you cannot find us anywhere else.
Speaker 0: However, we are also doing some panels for you to enjoy.
Speaker 0: first of all, I want to say There's gonna be an OC remix panel pretty much like at the start of the convention.
Speaker 1: It was pretty hot last year.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend it.
Speaker 0: Yes The OC remix panel is one of the high quality panels.
Speaker 0: That is not to be missed.
Speaker 0: I was on the wrong page.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm messing.
Speaker 1: Oh, I need to open the schedule.
Speaker 1: Do I need to handle?
Speaker 0: No, I had the schedule on the wrong page.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm good to go.
Speaker 0: Oc remix panel is in panel 4 at 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: Friday.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: The next panel I care about is the bandai visual USA Q&A at 2 p.m.
Speaker 0: On Friday and panel 2 now.
Speaker 1: if no one else asks the question We're going to ask it and furthermore I'm going to record the entire panel and I'm not gonna record it craptacularly like whoever recorded the last one did.
Speaker 0: Yes, so we're gonna go to the bandai visual panel and we're gonna say hey Why the fuck is your frickin anime so expensive?
Speaker 0: goddamn?
Speaker 0: we want to watch all your shows But we don't want to pay 40 bucks for a goddamn 20 minutes of anime.
Speaker 0: Get your freaking head out of your ass bandai visual and we're gonna see what they say.
Speaker 0: Cuz as long as we keep asking them the same question at every convention eventually they'll cave in.
Speaker 0: That's the only way we can do it.
Speaker 0: So everyone team up for great justice.
Speaker 0: In fact, the greatest justice would be if we ask the question we sit down Someone else stands up and ask the question again and they sit down and so on.
Speaker 1: Well only if they don't give a straight answer like we're just trying to rip you off or we don't understand the American.
Speaker 0: But if they do that, we'll have it recorded and we'll put it on the internet and that'll be awesome.
Speaker 0: All right now for the panels that we're in Friday night 9 p.m Anime Club back end summit in panel 2.
Speaker 0: You should go if you care about anime clubs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott Johnson technically runs that one, but I've been on it for like the last five years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we will talk about the one we ran at Connecticut because we actually ran it a little bit differently this year.
Speaker 0: There's a good chance you'll see us there.
Speaker 0: you should show up Immediately.
Speaker 0: after that there's a one-hour break.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not like a one-hour break in the convention.
Speaker 0: I mean the stuff's still going on But we have a one-hour break as in we're not doing anything that hour.
Speaker 0: Hence that is the official geek nights listener meetup.
Speaker 0: meet outside of the anime club back in summit.
Speaker 0: So outside of panel 2 at 10 p.m.
Speaker 1: On Friday if you want to come and be all disruptive Well, don't be disruptive but you can still come to the anime club panel if you want Yeah, but yeah, if 10 p.m.
Speaker 0: Isn't good for you We have the artists alley table, but if you want to meet all the other listeners and everyone get together at the same time There's a nice hour there that you know the 10 p.m.
Speaker 0: Hour.
Speaker 1: It was pretty fun when we did it last year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm sure more people show up this year.
Speaker 0: immediately after our Non-official geek nights listener meetup at 10 p.m.
Speaker 0: On Friday.
Speaker 0: at 11 p.m.
Speaker 0: On Friday is the podcasters roundtable panel Also in panel 2.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna be there the ninja consultants Dave and Joel a few other people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard that Dave and Joe are getting there.
Speaker 0: It's like Friday night.
Speaker 0: I Don't know what's with them and showing up to conventions late or getting kicked out of hotel room Yeah, but that's sure to be a pretty cool panel.
Speaker 0: well We'll arrange something cool to talk about and entertaining and at the very least you'll get to see a bunch of Podcasters all at once and hear all of us talk about things and ask us all questions.
Speaker 1: And of course, uh, Dave and Joel just cuz I'm mentioning them You might want to listen to our Wednesday night show next week because they are the guest hosts of geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's quite awesome.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: We I've already listened to it twice.
Speaker 0: It's double a-plus And immediately after the podcasters roundtable is the Friday night.
Speaker 1: the meat of Friday night concern tomorrow night.
Speaker 0: In fact, not tomorrow night two days from right is for two days from this recording at night at midnight.
Speaker 0: So that's actually Saturday at zero in panel two right after the podcasters roundtable 18 plus only sorry under 18 year olds Gekiga putting the man back in manga with me rim and Gerald.
Speaker 0: Gerald.
Speaker 1: rim and I we ran this Just myself and Scott at Connecticut and it went really really well.
Speaker 1: the people were there really dug it and I'll admit that at Connecticut we did it kind of half-assed Lee because uh, I Was exhausted my throat hurt and Scott was exhausted.
Speaker 0: Yes, and even then it was awesome.
Speaker 0: so if you take that awesomeness and you add a lot more people in the audience and you add rim doing more and Gerald being There and actual visuals and perhaps we might even bring some of the manga Gaki got pass them around
Speaker 1: as I don't
Speaker 0: think we're passing them around.
Speaker 1: We got extra Eagles.
Speaker 0: I guess we could pass around extra Eagles, but it's gonna be quite an awesome hour of Anime entertainment.
Speaker 0: get manga Gekiga entertainment and you should be there if you like this show And you're a man or a woman All right.
Speaker 0: The only other panel that I see on the schedule that's worth caring about is the kendo demonstration by our friend katsu.
Speaker 0: He is a kendo master.
Speaker 0: He will show you the ways of kendo that are not fooling around or stupid and it is listed as a kendo demonstration.
Speaker 1: There is a long story that might be told at the panel but if Otakon will let us do it there might be finally closure to the fact that technically I am the undefeated vice president of the RIT kendo club and Technically I was there for the best kendo or other than katsu ever
Speaker 0: And that's technically correct.
Speaker 1: and while that is technically true.
Speaker 1: That is not really true.
Speaker 0: That's not even close to being really.
Speaker 1: I'm uh, I'm bad at Tecna a techno.
Speaker 1: I'm bad And the only reason I remained undefeated was that I never actually went to a single kendo club meeting.
Speaker 1: Thus no one could challenge me for the position.
Speaker 1: Yes So katsu has had a grudge since then.
Speaker 0: if you want to see this kendo demonstration It will be at 2 30 p.m.
Speaker 0: On Saturday in panel 1 at Otakon.
Speaker 0: other than that Yeah, not much else we're doing.
Speaker 0: There's some things I'm probably gonna be interested in going to see like there's something at 1 a.m.
Speaker 0: On Saturday night.
Speaker 0: That's being a live-action movie called killing machine.
Speaker 0: That's got to be good.
Speaker 1: That might be this year's each of the killer.
Speaker 1: SARS wars Ebola syndrome.
Speaker 0: It might be but it doesn't say like 18 plus on it.
Speaker 0: So I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's got to be ultra-violent I don't know.
Speaker 1: What's the point?
Speaker 0: It's called killing machine.
Speaker 0: I assume it's something ultraviolet.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the deal is.
Speaker 1: Anyway, briefly what we're gonna do tonight.
Speaker 1: Maybe not briefly.
Speaker 1: We'll see is we're?
Speaker 1: you know, we're going Otakon this weekend.
Speaker 1: But last weekend we went to Connecticut and it was nothing to sneeze at.
Speaker 0: no, it was not.
Speaker 0: Actually if I let's talk about Connecticut not from the panel perspective, you know panelers perspective But from the goer the con goer perspective.
Speaker 0: and if I went to Connecticut as a con goer I imagine I would have spent the vast majority of my time in the tabletop gaming room.
Speaker 1: now granted a big part of that Is that Connecticut has better gaming than a lot of gaming cons.
Speaker 1: for one that is true.
Speaker 1: The aiming at Connecticut is awesome and two That's just the kind of that we're really into that.
Speaker 1: So that's the kind of thing we do if we go to gaming cons a lot We want to go to a lot more gaming cons.
Speaker 0: Yep The artists alley a typical artists alley, but it was twice as big as last year's.
Speaker 0: the definite plus.
Speaker 0: The dealers room actually pretty high quality a lot of the same dealers as last year.
Speaker 1: We bought $80 worth of mom.
Speaker 1: Well $80 of manga from the buy one get three free comic opiate a table.
Speaker 0: Yes comic opiate quite awesome with the cheap old mom.
Speaker 1: We pulled a Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: You should see the job.
Speaker 1: We walked away from that table with more manga than we could easily carry.
Speaker 0: I bought these Astro Boy figures and the only I'm.
Speaker 0: usually I'm pretty much done buying figures, but they were a dollar.
Speaker 0: a dollar That means like other figures are like eight dollars each and these were a dollar.
Speaker 0: Of course the dealer selling them was actually the anime store.
Speaker 0: that's down the road from us, but that's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also our friend Luca runs hammer girl.
Speaker 0: The anime store was there so we got to hang out with them Had offered all of offered by Kazuo Koike, so I bought that from them, of course, of course No one else had that.
Speaker 0: Yeah dealers room.
Speaker 0: Not a bad dealers room.
Speaker 1: Yeah now one interest.
Speaker 1: apparently on Sunday there was a small but somewhat a bit of a problem with people trying to steal things from dealers and we debated a lot about whether it's the demographic of the con or the area or whatever.
Speaker 1: and Then we discovered that the dude who was arrested was might have been a professional shoplifter or just an idiot But the rest of them might have all been punk kids from the same summer camp that seems to dump all of its kids at Connecticut every year on Sunday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think some of the biggest shoplifters.
Speaker 0: It's something like this, you know little kids at summer camp They don't have money the the money they get.
Speaker 0: basically the way summer camps work is their parents put money in an envelope that the camp director holds on to And then when the kid goes on a trip the camp gives them some money from the envelope.
Speaker 0: not all of it Just some of it.
Speaker 0: and that's all the kids got.
Speaker 0: So these kids want stuff and little summer camp kids are pretty much very good at thieving.
Speaker 0: They've got lots of peer pressure.
Speaker 0: They don't have any consequences of actual school You know, they're being herded by college kids and teenagers.
Speaker 0: They're.
Speaker 0: they're very Likely to steal things especially from an anime con dealers room where there's lots of little things that they really want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course kinetic on definitely alter their policy somewhat and they went from normal con to Super.
Speaker 1: crack down on people who steal police there to arrest the scary dude.
Speaker 0: That's how it should be.
Speaker 0: Yep Video game room not typical.
Speaker 0: Yeah It wasn't the greatest video game room mostly because the way the video game their room there works is that it's Sponsored by like Best Buy and GameStop and those people supply the equipment that is used by the game room and they got shortchanged by the sponsors.
Speaker 1: so to me that would have been nice because actually as a result it was more spread out and it was a lot nicer to Physically be in that room than most anime con game room.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: But at the same time there were very.
Speaker 0: I walked through it a couple times and there was really nothing I wanted to do in There.
Speaker 0: but there's one guitar hero machine.
Speaker 1: even at Otakon.
Speaker 1: I'd never care about the video game room.
Speaker 1: to me video game rooms at cons other than tournaments and guitar hero type things Exists for the same reason that anime showings do.
Speaker 0: they're just there except the katakan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, katakan is different But it's just to keep people Who aren't doing something currently out of the way and not feeling like there's nothing to do Especially people who don't want to socialize.
Speaker 0: the one problem which everyone seemed to recognize is that to get into the game room?
Speaker 0: You need.
Speaker 0: they had a bag check.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know many people complained about this at the con feedback session.
Speaker 0: We actually answered more than the staff did about the head basically because the sponsors that the GameStop and Best Buy basically said Hey, if you don't have a bag check, we won't let we won't give you this stuff.
Speaker 0: So they had to do a bag check it in order to get the free stuff from the sponsors.
Speaker 1: now the real answer I would put forth is that they're gonna need to have a bag check anyway, because those controllers are gonna get stolen Otherwise, yep.
Speaker 0: I mean the controller costs as almost as much as your con badge.
Speaker 0: So if you can steal two of them you win You just leave and you buy another con badge.
Speaker 1: and I think what bothered me was mostly that the people who complained About the thing about the bag check were the kind of people who probably wouldn't have gone into the video game room Anyway, or more importantly they complained about it Like it was terribly run.
Speaker 1: what I got to say it was run better than any Yes in con bag check I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: the problem with the bag check was not that it was run poorly.
Speaker 0: the bag chin was.
Speaker 0: the Bagcheck was run excellently much better than the katsu con bag check.
Speaker 0: The problem with the bag check is that I would walk up to the video game room with an urge to go in But only a slight urge and when they said you'll have to check your bag I said well I would rather not go in there than check my bag and many people felt the same way
Speaker 1: at the same time.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: That way if someone goes in there, they're up for a bunch of video gaming and that's gonna walk in and out.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's a tough line.
Speaker 1: I think katsu khan is gonna have the right idea next year.
Speaker 1: We've got two ideas for how to change the way the bag check works to make it more awesome, but we'll see.
Speaker 0: we will see What else is going down at the kinetic a lot of panels?
Speaker 1: We didn't get to go to any because we were doing our seven.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not gonna go into every single panel.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 1: we talked about him how they went.
Speaker 1: they all went really well.
Speaker 1: What I do want to say is that one we ran the how to run an anime club panel and we ran it completely differently from the way we've ever run that panel before and I think it's a much better panel now, and I want to run it this way in the future.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 1: basically the deal is usually Scott Johnson or whoever runs it will you know talk to the audience.
Speaker 1: let the clubs all shout Out.
Speaker 1: it'd be kind of like a club summit.
Speaker 1: What we've learned is that you don't let the audience talk Because most of them can't speak well in public and most of them as the same stupid boring questions that no one else cares about Except for the one cool question last year.
Speaker 1: There's always one cool question always but other than that most of the people who go to the anime club summit No offense to you guys But it's pretty obvious what they're doing because I can see how I might have done that back when I was still running an anime Club.
Speaker 1: you ask a question that basically is formatted like this Hi plug my club plug.
Speaker 1: plug my club.
Speaker 1: plug my club my question.
Speaker 1: Show how smart I am Shaw smart.
Speaker 1: I am Shaw smart.
Speaker 1: I am show smart.
Speaker 1: I am really dumb question that we might have already answered.
Speaker 0: That Was so accurate.
Speaker 1: I no offense to you guys, but seriously we can see right through you.
Speaker 1: So what we did is.
Speaker 1: all we did was ask the crowd if they were people who like raise your hand if you're Running a club want to run a club as opposed to plugging a club want to join a club and most people want it.
Speaker 1: We're running club or wanted to run a club.
Speaker 1: So we pretty much just sat there and talk shop and just told them straight up exactly what you do.
Speaker 1: We didn't let the industry do their.
Speaker 1: you know the industry stuff and we didn't do the lame like.
Speaker 1: well anime showings are important because blah and blah and blah and you have to show wide variety and we were like You trick people into coming with these techniques.
Speaker 1: the executive board has to be structured like this and act like this But you have to act like this behind closed doors.
Speaker 1: You got to get rid of these people and don't let them be in your club and you got to open it.
Speaker 0: You got to make it feel like it's democracy when it's actually an oligarchy, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you know what the crowd fucking loved it.
Speaker 0: I gotta say yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: it was our first panel.
Speaker 0: It was well attended and the people seemed to enjoy it.
Speaker 1: people actually lined up outside to get into it.
Speaker 1: I was somewhat surprised by that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, some of the most of the people stayed for our Immediately following panel a podcasting panel, which not the greatest podcasting panel we ever done.
Speaker 0: Well partly
Speaker 1: because it was weird there was an audience and almost everyone in the audience Already knew about podcasts so they didn't really want to hear about how you know to listen to one like we usually do with these things and They weren't podcasters except one girl was and I think Scott has the relevant quote from her I think was great, but I I just want to say she was the only podcaster in the audience So everyone else.
Speaker 1: we asked them.
Speaker 1: So what did you come here for?
Speaker 1: What do you want us to say?
Speaker 1: and none of them knew.
Speaker 1: so we just kind of explained all the I don't know the things We thought that are interesting about podcasting and it went pretty well.
Speaker 0: It was okay, but I think our Otacon podcasting panel from last year was far superior.
Speaker 1: Yes Well, the larger crowd helped a lot in the bigger room and the fact that the people didn't know about podcasting.
Speaker 0: Yeah things to say.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think what we should start doing is maybe we need to start making a panel like Secrets of the podcasters or something like that.
Speaker 1: That'd be more like a workshop at a big like a trade.
Speaker 0: No, not secrets like that secrets.
Speaker 0: Like yeah, we say this.
Speaker 0: we mean that the same thing Same thing we do at the Anime Club Summit like we you know, we could do a whole demo on.
Speaker 1: like Alright, wait, tell try to tell.
Speaker 1: what is rim really laughing?
Speaker 1: and what is rim radio laughing?
Speaker 0: Started out fake became real.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, that that could be pretty good.
Speaker 1: But there's a girl in the audience who is trying to get into podcasting.
Speaker 1: She just started and apparently she blogged about us after the fact.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I found her blog by a referral link and I think she said that we were lovably harsh about the realities of podcasting.
Speaker 1: And we really were.
Speaker 1: we were pretty.
Speaker 1: we sat there and we basically said what we always say to you guys Which was most podcasts like most things suck.
Speaker 1: It is not easy to make a podcast.
Speaker 1: Contrary to what Apple and the internet want to say if you just plug a microphone in and talk It's gonna sound like Animal Crossing and other games or possibly anime pulse.
Speaker 1: I I Had to get a dig in because people in our forums just won't let the anime pulse thing go.
Speaker 0: really they keep Bashing somebody else.
Speaker 1: I think we should cuz I don't know.
Speaker 0: it's because I've got a real hanker in to bash someone.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know cuz I don't know who deserves bashing because anime pulse deserved it mostly in a jocular way And it was kind of friendly bashing.
Speaker 1: I don't know what would happen if we seriously bash someone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe I'll wait it out.
Speaker 0: after Otacon.
Speaker 0: You might hear me seriously bash another podcast like.
Speaker 0: I'll actually just come out and say they suck And I hate them.
Speaker 1: Do you have a podcast in mind?
Speaker 1: Of course?
Speaker 0: I have a podcast in mind.
Speaker 1: I think I know which one you think you definitely know which podcast talking about.
Speaker 1: yeah, I know I do know exactly which one you're talking about and I Have opinions about that.
Speaker 0: show you agree though.
Speaker 1: I do agree.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: nor with anime pulse like.
Speaker 1: it's all in good fun because our more our stance on podcasting is still You're creating content that already makes you better than most people.
Speaker 1: you're kings among men, but at the same time at least anime pulse tries and the It should go.
Speaker 1: actually emailed me afterward.
Speaker 1: I gave him some hints and he's a cool guy.
Speaker 1: It's not but this other podcast.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna get into it now.
Speaker 1: now all our friend podcasters are probably thinking crap.
Speaker 1: Is it us?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Who are they talking about?
Speaker 0: Well, you can all stay in suspense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, obviously, it's not Dave and Joel's fast-cross Because they're like my favorite podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah Because it's the best podcast.
Speaker 1: and it's not anime world order because while we fight with them pretty much all the time We are friends with them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though I think Clarissa actually does hate Scott.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's their problem.
Speaker 1: Well, that's her problem Yeah, or your problem.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: She might be armed a clown pistol.
Speaker 1: Oh My god, they're gonna be there.
Speaker 1: There might be clown pistol.
Speaker 0: No, Daryl's not gonna be there.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but tell Gerald to bring us something.
Speaker 0: How's he gonna get him there?
Speaker 1: I could just picture.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's gonna be on an airplane.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can just pick what we need to do someday.
Speaker 1: I want to see Daryl Surratt and an anime con just open up like Il Duce.
Speaker 1: Was it one guy with six clown pistols?
Speaker 1: That's just stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Duke.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I'll just skip.
Speaker 0: What else did we do?
Speaker 0: a kinetic on?
Speaker 1: Let's skip to our big thing.
Speaker 1: You see the story is we told kinetic on.
Speaker 1: we can run two game shows for you but one of them is gonna be a beta test.
Speaker 1: and Brianna who is pretty cool said all right, you can run your two and we said hey We need a celebrity guests and we got an email right before the con saying you've got celebrity guests.
Speaker 1: We're good to go.
Speaker 0: now We're sitting there right and we're.
Speaker 0: we get to kinetic con.
Speaker 0: We have our itinerary which tells us where to go at what times where our events are and all the guests have similar itineraries that tell them where to go at what times.
Speaker 0: and We're sitting there and it's time for our anime match game where we need our celebrity guests and we haven't been told who the celebrity Guests are or even if they're actually coming.
Speaker 1: so we go find a person in the staff where we can ask Who's a guest first.
Speaker 0: the guy who handles guests a guy we know now What actually happened.
Speaker 1: was he misunderstood our question and thought we were asking about something else?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what he basically said was no just go round up some webcomic guests to which we said ah shit.
Speaker 1: So we ran around the con and we got a knob from Apple geeks and we got IDO from fallen.
Speaker 0: we were gonna get anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah and we try ask Luke from hammer girl and we asked Mookie and we pretty much went around trying to grab people and Rethink we're all set.
Speaker 1: We got our friends Corbin and Wyatt to be the peanut gallery.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it was gonna be all good.
Speaker 1: So we're sitting there and we're like, alright we can do this.
Speaker 1: Are we ready?
Speaker 1: And meanwhile while we're sitting in the room going are we ready?
Speaker 1: I go outside and discover that there's a line wrapping all the way around the artist alley trying to get into our event.
Speaker 0: Alrighty.
Speaker 1: so, uh, alright pressures on and then the door open.
Speaker 0: There's no pressure because the anime match game cannot fail.
Speaker 0: It is a guaranteed recipe for awesome.
Speaker 0: No matter what you do We could have had six random people from the audience up there and it still would have been awesome.
Speaker 1: So, uh the door opens and pretty much all the guests of honor from the con walk-in.
Speaker 1: So we had I'm just gonna go and order on the website We had Vic aka Edward Elric from Fullmetal Alchemist the dub that dude.
Speaker 0: All I gotta say about this guy is that he makes the fangirls scream as do many voice actors But he does it on purpose Like he's just doing everything he possibly can to make them scream as much as he can.
Speaker 0: and while it's kind of cool I know Not cool.
Speaker 1: I find it great because you could just have a panel and I'd love to see this.
Speaker 0: We're never like three of those panels.
Speaker 1: You could have a panel where he just sat there and there was a spotlight and periodically he smiles.
Speaker 1: He waits to lay down.
Speaker 1: He smiles.
Speaker 1: I Believe Emily coined the turn by tea kettling.
Speaker 0: Oh it is.
Speaker 0: I don't think she coined that.
Speaker 0: I think she got it from someone else.
Speaker 1: I thought she coined it.
Speaker 1: Did she?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not sure cuz I've heard it elsewhere.
Speaker 1: I heard it from her first.
Speaker 0: I did hear it from her first.
Speaker 1: So we'll try to deny her credit?
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: but let's all right.
Speaker 0: Let's pretend that she coined it into proven.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we had a Daniel Kevin Harrison who he voice acted in a bunch of stuff But most importantly he was in KO century beast which makes him automatically awesome.
Speaker 0: that is true
Speaker 1: and honestly we set it up where Vic was in the middle of the panel of the you know, The celebrity panel and on one end we had the one guy who I'll talk about last Because I got to talk about him
Speaker 0: and then on the
Speaker 1: other end We had Daniel Kevin Harrison and the two of them together were like the anchors of the panel and it was like crazy guy straight Man, and it was.
Speaker 1: it was just perfect.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I got before.
Speaker 1: I couldn't have asked for a better panel of celebrity guests Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So then we had Caitlin glass who is a voice actress in a million things.
Speaker 1: She was Winry from Fullmetal Alchemist.
Speaker 1: The sardonic biting humor that came from her lips was a classic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was quite.
Speaker 1: it was funny where sometimes she'd make a like a kind of biting answer and for a second I think is she serious or is this just a joke?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I don't care cuz everyone's laughing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she'd be.
Speaker 0: sometimes she'd be like something actually silly or something actually serious.
Speaker 0: Sometimes she just be like now retards and I'd be like, oh she really doesn't like the not her tires.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I don't either me either but she was just like now retards.
Speaker 1: or we had a non from Apple geeks.
Speaker 1: You know who's been on this before.
Speaker 1: we like him We had I do from fallen who's a very good friend of ours and she's I think she's actually like from being on our match game She's become a pro.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she like.
Speaker 1: it's funny.
Speaker 1: We'll read the question and she knows exactly what answer is the funny answer.
Speaker 1: We were expecting someone to give and she just writes it down.
Speaker 1: Yep, and last and certainly not least in fact I want to say most because this man without any coaching was probably the best Celebrity panelist I have ever had running the match game.
Speaker 1: It was none other than Stevie B Steve the man Bennett.
Speaker 0: for those of you don't know about Stevie B I have her.
Speaker 0: the first time I ran into him was at my very first con Ohio con to
Speaker 1: worse current
Speaker 0: worst con effort, but he was there and The general impression I had of him at that point was that he was a sleazy dude Kind of scary, you know, definitely hip with the fans.
Speaker 0: Definitely had the skills of an animator.
Speaker 0: I mean the animated stuff in Japan is no lie.
Speaker 1: The thing is all of this came to us second hand from semi random people Yep, and I think some of it still might be true.
Speaker 0: You know, he likes him the cat girls.
Speaker 0: He does seem like the kind of guy who's probably has done or does do some sort of sleazy kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you mean by sleazy.
Speaker 1: Well, you know by that token we could also accuse Certain other podcasters of the same.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, they're guilty, too.
Speaker 0: But you know, I've heard things about him like he has a wife, but he's getting on with cat girls.
Speaker 1: I don't know how true that is though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever the point is regardless of any rumors or facts about him that may or may not be true.
Speaker 0: Steve Bennett is a thousand percent awesome at playing the match game.
Speaker 1: I mean one.
Speaker 1: he's got the credentials I mean the dude animated in Japan on anime like that.
Speaker 1: That's pretty hardcore if you talk about being an anime fan.
Speaker 0: He's also old-school.
Speaker 0: He knows about shows, you know, it's it's People on the match game.
Speaker 0: often their biggest problem is they just don't have the breadth of anime knowledge to come up with an answer.
Speaker 0: You know, that's why I think a lot of our answers were always FMA Naruto something bleach something.
Speaker 0: so, you know, but
Speaker 1: he was the one who would come up with the old-school hilarious answer and He basically like usually yeah,
Speaker 0: we were like who's the sexiest man in anime and he's like crayon ginger And we're like all men's
Speaker 1: and he did all the stuff that normally we have to coach guests to do and also normally we have Plans for if the guests like don't have a lot to say to kind of
Speaker 0: speak
Speaker 1: over him and cover it up and make it Funny.
Speaker 1: this man required nothing from us.
Speaker 1: This man could have run the match game on his own.
Speaker 1: He could have been the only guest panelist filling in all the fans Steve Bennett to be on every anime match game I ever run for the rest of either of our lives.
Speaker 1: I shake that man's hand with pride.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anything else you have to say about him, whatever.
Speaker 0: He's awesome at match game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, draw your own conclusions.
Speaker 1: Just meet the guy because no matter what you may or may not think about if the dude has some motherfucking charisma He sure does and the humors.
Speaker 1: So the match game was crazily awesome.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be running it with and I just got confirmation I don't know who yet but similar celebrity panelists at the New York Anime Festival in December.
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 0: Very nice challenge around fire.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna talk about it.
Speaker 1: All I want to say is we learn something from the beta test and what we learn is that the vast majority of anime fans Who go to conventions at least as far as we could tell?
Speaker 1: Don't actually watch anime like.
Speaker 1: not only could they not really name a single a character at all outside of like Pikachu and Ichigo.
Speaker 1: But they couldn't name anime that were made outside of the span of like 2001 to 2002 and a half.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like.
Speaker 0: they could recognize a Sailor Moon and a Dragon Ball and a Naruto and a bleach and possibly a trans.
Speaker 0: none of them had ever Seen eska flown a or lane or try gun any show that was slightly outside of the mainstream Cartoon Network to Nami kind of lineup.
Speaker 0: They just didn't know about at all.
Speaker 0: Most of the people sure there were some people actually had the anime knowledge.
Speaker 0: They they knew.
Speaker 0: you know what the shows were but the vast majority had no freaking clue.
Speaker 0: They were like You know Evangelion.
Speaker 0: they knew eska flown a what and it's like try gun.
Speaker 0: They knew vash.
Speaker 0: That's about it.
Speaker 0: They could name anyone else.
Speaker 0: They could even name Masato a secondary character from Evangelion.
Speaker 1: I have them couldn't actually name Shinji.
Speaker 1: I just knew he was from Evangelion.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we've decided to revamp it and I'll have some details later.
Speaker 1: But suffice to say I think challenger on fire in the future is going to be us challenging people like Daryl Surratt to prove how hardcore they are and Get it instead of you know, cuz.
Speaker 0: the problem is is that with this single elimination kind of game?
Speaker 0: You might just eliminate everyone in one fell swoop.
Speaker 0: I think we're gonna add some Japanese game show style punishments to the people who drop out to make it a little more entertaining.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we did a bunch of other panels.
Speaker 1: We hung out with the Apple geeks crew and they're pretty awesome and we all go with our friends.
Speaker 1: and the only other thing Is that on Sunday morning?
Speaker 1: We did a German board gaming panel.
Speaker 0: Oh, right and this is our last panel, by the way We did six panels Saturday and one panel Sunday.
Speaker 1: There was this fat nerdy scary guy who actually was there for this elf panel like a panel on fairies and elves but he missed it.
Speaker 0: that was the panel before us.
Speaker 1: so he decided to stick around and He was a heckler is the first heckler I've ever run into it.
Speaker 0: there are four people in the panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was 9 a.m.
Speaker 1: On a Sunday.
Speaker 1: We didn't expect anyone to be there.
Speaker 0: So especially a panel about German board gaming.
Speaker 1: So, uh immediately this guy takes offense to the term German board gaming But that is disrespectful to all of the other games that come out of Europe.
Speaker 1: So we say fine euro gaming but that is disrespectful to all of the wonderful tactical and strategic games that come out of America.
Speaker 1: Are you saying that there are no strategic American games?
Speaker 1: And I try to say like.
Speaker 1: well from popular perception most American games are things like Monopoly and you know Candyland and life and there's the rare gems like connect for but even that's not that great and chess.
Speaker 1: But most people think of games like Monopoly and then he's like well No it's it's disrespectful to call them German or European.
Speaker 1: and then he names like ten games and I play a lot of games like I'm I'm more into German board gaming and like Board games and war games and D&D and all that them and they're like anything.
Speaker 1: and I'd never heard of a single one of the games.
Speaker 1: he said and I was like God I hate to break it to you But those games don't sell compared to the games that actually come from Germany and it was just downhill from there.
Speaker 0: The guy basically made a bunch of some valid some invalid arguments about I don't know what.
Speaker 0: I don't know What he was trying to say But he basically all you were trying to do is tell people about our cool hobby of playing German games.
Speaker 1: Here's what our panel actually was going to be if this guy had not been there.
Speaker 1: If you've never tried these games before you should check out settlers of Catan and Carcassonne.
Speaker 1: Hey, here's a copy of Carcassonne.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna give it away to you guys.
Speaker 1: If you want to come hang out and play board games with us We're gonna go right over there.
Speaker 1: These games are really cool and you should try them.
Speaker 1: but uh No we had Captain McFarty pants and the thing is there's this girl with him and the whole time like he argued over every Statement either of us made and meanwhile the girl is sitting there kind of glaring at him like come on.
Speaker 1: Let's just go Let's just go.
Speaker 1: I have better things to do than watch you argue with two guys at an anime con over nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he eventually wonder how guys like that get a girl and in the first place, maybe she was a sister or something.
Speaker 0: Maybe I have no idea.
Speaker 1: and other than that kinetic on was pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: The con feedback session made me realize something that I guess I've known.
Speaker 1: It's a truth that I've known for a long time But I finally noticed it.
Speaker 1: go to a con feedback session and I want to see if you notice the same thing.
Speaker 1: The vast majority of the complaints may like 90% are always from cosplayers about the cosplay in the masquerade.
Speaker 1: That is true and no one complains about any.
Speaker 0: I have never been to a con feedback session where less than 50% Of the complaints were about were something other.
Speaker 0: You get my point.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying the cost players complaining about the cosplay accounts for more than half the complaints at every con feedback.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying their complaints may or may not be legitimate.
Speaker 1: All I'm saying is that they are the squeakiest wheel and either cosplays have problems or Cosplayers have problems or both, but something I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 1: I just want to point that out because it's always like someone complains about The bag check at the video game room Which is always coming up and then they complain about the video game tournaments being disorganized.
Speaker 0: but now they're playing.
Speaker 0: but these people are complaining like The stage didn't have enough room on it or there were wires on the stage or they didn't have time to like Examine the stage or that we didn't get the dimensions of the stage beforehand.
Speaker 0: or and I'm like what the hell you complaining about.
Speaker 0: I don't see the problem.
Speaker 1: Well, see I couldn't tell if they were legitimate or not Every single con is the same thing.
Speaker 1: So something's up Kinetic on.
Speaker 1: I mean we made a bunch of constructive criticisms last year and I just want to say that Kinetic on followed up on pretty much every single concern we brought up in last year's con report to the best of their ability And I gotta hand it to him.
Speaker 1: They ran a pretty damn good con this year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they definitely the things we said they took into account and they improved and I could tell at the con feedback session They were listening closely and they actually cared about what people had to say.
Speaker 1: They did everything we asked.
Speaker 1: so Kinetic on props to you.
Speaker 1: I had a really good time Yeah and I think next year they're gonna do more awesome things and improve things that I can better way guarantee we're gonna be a Kinetic on pretty much for as long as Kinetic on goes.
Speaker 0: now, even if Kinetic on fails Massively in every respect that board gaming room is still gonna be there and I'll go just for that.
Speaker 0: So I know comes to worst.
Speaker 0: I'll sit there all weekend playing games.
Speaker 1: It's late and we're going to Otacon tomorrow.
Speaker 1: So I think that's the end.
Speaker 0: it is the end.
Speaker 1: indeed This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.