Speaker 0: It's Thursday March 1st, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We talk about the podcast we listen to as opposed to the podcast we used to listen to.
Speaker 1: let's do this.
Speaker 1: I Started a new job today.
Speaker 0: So you know you can't just sit around the house lazing about doing nothing yet somehow still being tired every day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I really wish now.
Speaker 1: You know while I was lazing around the house doing nothing I was kind of like you know.
Speaker 1: uh Wow, I just didn't say anything.
Speaker 1: How can you be tired?
Speaker 0: you had all this time to do nothing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and in that time.
Speaker 1: I did nothing and I kind of felt bad for doing nothing and now that I'm doing something I want to do nothing, but yet even when you were doing nothing you were still tired all the time.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: it's sort of like if you wake up you get some energy But then if you don't do anything your body goes.
Speaker 1: why the fuck did I get up go back to bed?
Speaker 1: You're not doing shit.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: like like the the lion the lion just kind of sits around going.
Speaker 0: Are you comparing yourself to a lion?
Speaker 1: nah in only one aspect all right?
Speaker 0: Sleepiness, I'll accept that.
Speaker 1: perhaps also a sloth Maybe a snail.
Speaker 1: meanwhile turtle
Speaker 0: I was at work to my normal work And I had a couple hours to kill at the end of the day because mostly I was just doing mindless paperwork and telnetting into Routers so I could then telnet into other routers so I could then telnet into switches so I could look at their stuff and get Their serial numbers.
Speaker 0: wow yeah, that was awesome, but I had some time to kill so I was thinking about it And then before I left work.
Speaker 0: I started and I'm going to finish this at home over the next few months I'm gonna write a small textbook on how to podcast because most podcasts like we're gonna talk about today Kinda suck at least audio quality wise
Speaker 1: yeah, also I'd like to point out you know this is an insult to anyone in particular, but most how-to podcasts are Generally aimed at the absolute idiot And they'll tell you like yeah Just get audacity plug in a microphone and push record and they don't give you enough information how to do things properly.
Speaker 0: They seem to or they I mean they seem to fall into two categories.
Speaker 0: It's either that you know the crap guy that doesn't really give you anything useful And then there are the guides that oh well just buy a 48 port digital mixer and use The fastest Mac you can find with some firewire, and oh yeah these $500 ksm microphones exactly what you need.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and no one really made a guy mean.
Speaker 0: I don't want to sound like I have a big head But I think we're one of the best sounding podcasts out there professional or otherwise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least in the top 15 or 20.
Speaker 1: I mean considering that we're putting it at MP3 We make pretty much the best MP3 you can make of two guys talking.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean pretty much all the things I have to do to make it sound the one or two percent better is Tiny trial and error and when I get a faster computer.
Speaker 0: I got some filters.
Speaker 0: I wrote that the only reason I don't use them now is that it would take 20 minutes on my slow ass computer Unlike the computer.
Speaker 1: I now have at work.
Speaker 1: Which is a core to duo now.
Speaker 1: I never used a core to Anything before.
Speaker 1: in fact the fastest computer I ever used for more than like two seconds is probably that one You're that's right next to you right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've been a little lucky in that at IBM I got to play around with some blade machines that were faster than all I could ever fathom.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess technically at RIT I had like those big Sun servers that I would get to do stuff for.
Speaker 0: yeah But like you weren't running a desktop.
Speaker 0: well Yeah, so I were like I didn't run quake on those blade servers.
Speaker 1: yep, so work.
Speaker 1: I have a core to duo.
Speaker 1: It's just a Dell, but I put Ubuntu on it.
Speaker 1: And let me tell you holy shit is it fast?
Speaker 1: and holy shit is it nice to have a wicked fast computer?
Speaker 1: Holy crap, holy crap again.
Speaker 0: It's been a long time since I've had a computer that responded immediately to anything I asked it to do.
Speaker 0: that was trivial.
Speaker 1: I mean the computer I have my desk at home is 1.8 gigahertz Athlon XP.
Speaker 1: right this core to duo has Two cores.
Speaker 1: each core is 1.8 gigahertz, but they're not the same cores.
Speaker 1: These are Intel cores of new fanciness and not old busted Athlon XP cores.
Speaker 1: So the fact that they're at the same clock speed as an old busted core yet They're super awesome cores of like a zillion times more transistors in them and better logics and efficiency.
Speaker 1: It is so stupidly fast.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so my new work.
Speaker 1: It's better than my old work because well there are people there.
Speaker 1: the people are cool.
Speaker 1: Ish they talk?
Speaker 1: They're intelligent and not idiots they.
Speaker 0: Well, you're making your old job sound really bad.
Speaker 0: if these are the good points Well, I mean I guess it just comes down to the fact that Scott And I and I know there's a lot of I mean our friend Alex is pretty much all our friends Except for all the art people who seem really happy with what they do.
Speaker 0: We're never happy in any job.
Speaker 0: No matter what how great a job is after maybe we should have become artists.
Speaker 0: Yeah, after about a month.
Speaker 0: It's like how many Cisco routers.
Speaker 0: Do you need me to configure?
Speaker 0: I did it once.
Speaker 0: It's not fun anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, the work at this new work is not exciting work.
Speaker 1: it's actually pretty a work, but the people there seem to be cool and They're paying me, and I had fun today at least even though you know my day was long.
Speaker 1: but I'm sure tomorrow will be a shorter day and Hopefully, I'll keep this job for a while, and we'll see where it goes if it starts to suck.
Speaker 1: I'll just quit again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to watch out for that problem of.
Speaker 0: you know you interview for the eighth job.
Speaker 0: They're like huh, so you've had seven jobs in the last year Yeah, and you quit all of them.
Speaker 1: actually the bigger problem is you know my previous job I was alone in the middle of nowhere so finding a new job was easy now.
Speaker 1: I got to find a new job While showing up somewhere where there are people watching me.
Speaker 0: It's really not hard to do really.
Speaker 0: you just take sick days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I get unlimited sick days technically, but if I abuse it then I'll be in trouble whoa?
Speaker 0: so how much vacation do you have?
Speaker 0: I don't need to ask all the personal details of your job, but that's an interesting policy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just unlimited sick days.
Speaker 1: if you're sick don't come into work dumbass.
Speaker 0: see my company's all complicated.
Speaker 1: I don't get sick days, but if you actually abuse the sick days You know you you lie, or you do it a whole lot, and you're obviously Faking then they'll pun you maybe fire you.
Speaker 0: I've never worked at a company small enough to get away with that And I kind of wish I did now.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't have sick days at all.
Speaker 0: I just have this kind of choice time bank.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we like as we barely have any personal days, and we get like two weeks vacation But if you don't use vacation, then it rolls over.
Speaker 0: yeah mine rolls over too.
Speaker 0: That's a really nice thing.
Speaker 1: but also Just the default holidays.
Speaker 1: We actually get What's it called two extra days off?
Speaker 1: Oh, I get two days off at this company that I did not get off at the previous job.
Speaker 1: Huh at the previous job.
Speaker 1: I got off Labor Day Memorial Day Independence Day.
Speaker 0: You need to list all the days.
Speaker 1: no New Year's Day Thanksgiving Day Christmas Day.
Speaker 1: I think that's it.
Speaker 0: you could have just given me the diff.
Speaker 1: yeah anyway the diff is now.
Speaker 1: I also get off MLK Day Black Friday And the day before Chris and the day before Christmas you get Black Friday off Yep, huh, and the day before Christmas.
Speaker 1: so Christmas Eve two additional days off by default.
Speaker 0: That's interesting.
Speaker 1: yep Yep, yep, yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah I never understood the whole Personal days as opposed to vacation days.
Speaker 1: see to me a personal day was like when you have to do something that can't like you Have a dentist appointment.
Speaker 1: That's a personal day to me.
Speaker 1: You know that's what it's supposed to be But I guess I don't know.
Speaker 0: it seems sort of outdated and unnecessary especially considering Maybe it's just me But I was always smart enough to be sure that I never had to use a personal vacation whatever day for anything like that.
Speaker 0: So I can maximize my time spent Vacationing.
Speaker 1: yeah, it seems like the difference between the personal days is that you don't have to earn the personal days You just get them and the vacation you have to earn over time.
Speaker 1: You know oh well.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm just really glad that I was.
Speaker 0: I kind of strong-armed my company into giving me my vacation time upfront in full and then it Accumulated ever since.
Speaker 0: yep, cuz I pretty much said give me that or I'm not gonna work here.
Speaker 1: That's what I did also, so I'll see you guys.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, Oh - can I anyway in the news?
Speaker 0: This is a bit of a personal news for me.
Speaker 0: you see for any of you who use dig Which is pretty much the premier social bookmarking content filtration meta Commenting whatever whip 2.0.
Speaker 0: Fancy site That everyone uses.
Speaker 0: by the way since we haven't talked about this in forever.
Speaker 0: We're on there.
Speaker 0: You could dig us if you want.
Speaker 0: we haven't mentioned that in a while because we generally don't care about that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: But since it comes up yeah anyway a lot of people in the blogosphere Which I have a lot of colorful use them isms for the blogosphere, but I'll just use that word.
Speaker 0: I'll use their word I'll be nice.
Speaker 0: They've been talking about how dig is unfair or how dig is manipulated by a small core of Vigilantes known as the berry brigade who descend upon stories that and there's all different theories.
Speaker 0: some people say Oh, they bury anything That's positive about Sony or they bury all the truth about 9/11 or the federal income tax or the freemasons or UFOs I wonder why.
Speaker 0: or they bury anything involving Christianity.
Speaker 1: Oh, I wonder why.
Speaker 1: well
Speaker 0: so someone made a little thing that would have watched dig parse various things and list who was burying things and The dig guy came out to point out that this list was kind of bunk It wasn't gotten very well, and he talked a bit about their philosophy of burying and blocking.
Speaker 0: Now I've read this article.
Speaker 0: I didn't think anything of it here at home.
Speaker 0: I actually clicked on the data that everyone was talking about and my name came up fairly Prominently as a member of this so-called berry Brigade.
Speaker 1: Really rim is dig like paying you to subvert their system and bury stories They don't like.
Speaker 0: um you see I wish that were true But the fact is I am an embittered human being and when I see stupidity or spam I don't just bury it.
Speaker 0: It's like a mission to me like if I'm browsing dig You know I got some time over lunch, and I see a story like ah here's the secret of the UFO that actually knocked down World Trade Center seven because of the Freemasons.
Speaker 0: I don't just bury that.
Speaker 0: I click on whoever submitted that's profile and make sure That that wasn't just a one-off fluke and if it turns out that they're one of those people who submits nothing But that I proceed to bury everything they have ever submitted and then block them all right.
Speaker 0: so Also, pretty much anything stupid.
Speaker 0: I see I bury at a whim.
Speaker 0: I don't ever dig people down.
Speaker 0: I block immediately if anyone is not worth listening to.
Speaker 0: I've blocked at least three or four thousand people to date.
Speaker 1: So in other words rim is a vengeful digger in fact.
Speaker 1: I would be hesitant to call him a digger.
Speaker 1: I would say he's a vengeful barrier.
Speaker 0: I have buried more things than I've dug.
Speaker 1: yes I mean you give rim the home page of dig and it's all new stories.
Speaker 1: He hasn't seen yet What percentage of those do you think you're gonna bury on a given fraud?
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 0: Bury an average of one story for every two pages of the front page news.
Speaker 0: wow now If that's not talking about upcoming oh god.
Speaker 0: I pretty much very everything cuz it's all spam yep.
Speaker 1: So if there's like 20 people out there who are like rim, and you know where there's one.
Speaker 1: There's more That explains your crazy Barry Brigade conspiracy.
Speaker 0: well here is the Wonderful deliciously ironic conclusion to all of this.
Speaker 1: this story about the berry brigade was buried by rim.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: It's so much more eloquent and not eloquent elegant than that all right.
Speaker 0: So I looked at this data and the dig guy Kevin Rose basically said yeah This data is not a hundred percent accurate.
Speaker 0: it got the berries right But it didn't always say which story would have been buried and it wasn't always right.
Speaker 0: like it Attributed berries to people who didn't bury.
Speaker 0: So I went and I clicked on the 12 things that it said I had buried in that time And I actually buried four of them.
Speaker 0: the rest, and I look I had buried stories at those times But I had buried different stories.
Speaker 0: however I looked at the stories that said I buried that I didn't and with one exception I buried all of them because they deserved it And it felt kind of good.
Speaker 1: rim is the mad barrier.
Speaker 1: there is no dig conspiracy.
Speaker 1: There are just a few more people like rim besides rim.
Speaker 0: well I could talk at length about my reasons for that because it's not just on dig.
Speaker 0: It's on any sort of ranking system.
Speaker 0: I always feel that in general people are far too lenient When they grade or rank things and they're far more willing to give something a good grade than a low grade.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of grade inflation going on pretty much everywhere.
Speaker 0: also Giving a very low score or using a block or a berry Always has more of an impact overall than giving something a little plus or a little nudge or a little dig.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: You know giving something one dig doesn't like send it Skyrocketing but giving it a berry is like.
Speaker 1: it's a lot more than counting as minus one dig you know.
Speaker 1: so If you were if you really want to clean up the system you can actually get ahead a lot more by Burying things that that you don't like them by digging things that you do like.
Speaker 0: also I cite sturgeon's law 99% of everything is crap and Contra and filtration is more important than content sorting at least in my mind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right, so that's enough of that.
Speaker 0: What do you got captain?
Speaker 0: you didn't have any news, so it's actually my news.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: Apparently there's some Republican.
Speaker 1: was the senator?
Speaker 0: He's a. no he's a member of the house.
Speaker 0: Greg Walden Republican from Oregon who is a member of the house Telecommunications subcommittee right.
Speaker 1: this guy is worried that something awesome will happen now.
Speaker 0: It's complicated because I can't tell where this guy stands because he's all over the place But he envisions he fears he expects that the Supreme Court May in various upcoming suits that he is watching Strip away the FCC's power to regulate decency on the airwaves.
Speaker 1: Why would you worry about that?
Speaker 1: That would be the greatest day in history.
Speaker 0: I But if that happens I would probably take the day off work to celebrate with champagne.
Speaker 1: I would also probably take the day to go to work cuz I'd go to the city and celebrate somewhere doing something awesome.
Speaker 1: I would also be sure to listen to the radio a lot And I'd probably go and get a TV to watch it see.
Speaker 0: the thing is I don't think writing radio right away There'd be a lot of funny bits of people saying stuff You imagine like as soon as the gavel comes down at the Supreme Court Like every radio station in the whole country.
Speaker 1: be like fuckity-fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck Fuck, yeah shit, yeah Fuck shit shit cock shit cock.
Speaker 0: see I don't think television though would change very much.
Speaker 0: I mean I think people would start using the word fuck in television shows.
Speaker 0: the thing is Americans use that word a lot anyway.
Speaker 0: the word has almost no impact.
Speaker 0: just that maybe Maybe it's just because we're, you know, hip twenty-somethings, living in downstate New York, working in New York City, and we went to a liberal, technology-filled geeky school, and we're on to internet where people swear worse than sailors ever could.
Speaker 0: But the word "fuck" has no impact.
Speaker 0: If I say "fuck you," that doesn't really imply malice anymore.
Speaker 0: I mean, the words I have to use to imply malice are actually not obscenities.
Speaker 0: The things I could say when I'm actually angry have far less regulation and draw far less ire than the words that mean nothing to me like "fuck shit piss damn son of a bitch
Speaker 0: whore.".
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: Fuck your mom.
Speaker 0: Your mother's a whore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, seriously.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: The reason he says this is that there are currently three major lawsuits against the FCC from three major television networks over the fact that, basically, the FCC will fine you if you violate one of their rules.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, they refuse to publish or enumerate their rules, because if they enumerated them, then you could do anything they didn't say you couldn't do.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So as a result, there's this magic, unwritten set of rules, and all you can hope for is that they might warn you before they fine you, but usually they don't.
Speaker 0: They just fine you.
Speaker 1: Millions and millions.
Speaker 1: This actually reminds me of a case I read about in Texas.
Speaker 1: I think I might have mentioned it on the show before, but I remember reading about a court case in Texas where a guy was, like, fine for violating the building code or not being up to the building code.
Speaker 1: And part of the building code required that you do certain things to the building, and that certain thing you had to do to the building was some sort of patented process or item or something.
Speaker 1: And thus it was a trade secret of some other company, yet it was part of the code.
Speaker 1: And so he couldn't do it because he couldn't find out what to do because it was a secret.
Speaker 1: But it was the law that you had to do it.
Speaker 1: And the judge ended up saying, as I remember, I'm not 100% sure on this, that you can't keep the law a secret.
Speaker 1: People can't follow the law if they don't know it.
Speaker 1: If something is the law, you have to tell people what the hell it is.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of argument that this same precedent will eventually force governments to not use Microsoft software in any sort of... Well, I mean, internally.
Speaker 0: they could use it, but they couldn't require, say, you to submit grant applications in a Microsoft Word document.
Speaker 0: Or require that you have Internet Explorer to access a website on the government.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, require that you have any particular operating system to do your taxes online.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's all good by me.
Speaker 1: But yeah, anyway, this guy, he's worried that the FCC will not be able to enforce its twisted, illogical morals upon the broadcasting authorities.
Speaker 0: See, it's hard to say because, once again, he's all over the place and this article is very short.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then he starts saying...
Speaker 0: He's like, the FCC, there should be an increase in FCC fines.
Speaker 0: And apparently he also owns five radio stations.
Speaker 1: And then he says something about he doesn't want, like, a nanny state.
Speaker 1: But it's like, what?
Speaker 1: You just said you did want more of a nanny state.
Speaker 1: It's like he doesn't consider punishing someone for swearing as nanny state.
Speaker 0: Granted, this is not the best news site, and I'm not gonna blame him because they might just have not understood what he said.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might just be, it looks like a bad news site, I can see it from here.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty mediocre news site.
Speaker 1: I think the whole, the only thing that we should take out of this story is that, you know, even if this whole story is completely BS, if the FCC ever loses its power to censor the airwaves of both TV and radio or whatever, that is going to be the awesomest time.
Speaker 0: And yet at the same time, it's probably gonna prove to all the nutjobs, at least the more rational nutjobs, that, "Oh look, the world didn't end.
Speaker 0: Kids aren't suddenly having naked seven-year-old sex in the streets.
Speaker 0: People are still having normal conversations.
Speaker 0: They're not continually saying the word 'fuck'.
Speaker 0: Society moved
Speaker 0: on.".
Speaker 1: Of course, if it does happen, I will be the first person to purchase a UHF transmitter and have a nice porn station going on 24/7.
Speaker 1: And I'll put the hardest core porn before the kiddies go to school and when the kiddies get home from school at three.
Speaker 0: You mean the Saturday morning porns?
Speaker 1: That's right, the Saturday morning porn tunes.
Speaker 0: See, the thing is, don't forget, the FCC will still have the power to regulate the airwaves.
Speaker 0: They just can't regulate the content of it, so you still couldn't broadcast.
Speaker 1: Well, I'd just get a broadcasting license, and then they said, "What are you going to
Speaker 1: broadcast?"?
Speaker 1: And I would say,
Speaker 1: "Television.".
Speaker 0: And they would say, "Fine, give us ten billion dollars, 'cause that's what we
Speaker 0: charge.".
Speaker 1: And considering how much advertising money I would make from having a porn station, I would say, "Yes, sir, here is your
Speaker 1: money.".
Speaker 0: I don't think there's one, 'cause there's people who already have licenses who could just show pornography.
Speaker 0: Oh, and they do it?
Speaker 0: And pornography-related items.
Speaker 1: Well, if they do my job for me, then my job is done.
Speaker 1: I don't need a porn station.
Speaker 0: Things of the day!
Speaker 0: We're going to conclude Scott's somewhat theme week here.
Speaker 1: Yes, all week, the things of the day have been openers to mostly cartoon shows, but the openers are in different languages from around the world.
Speaker 0: Oh, snaps!
Speaker 1: Today, I give you perhaps, uh, I don't know if it's my favorite one, 'cause that German Sailor Moon is freakin' addicting as all hell.
Speaker 1: [singing in German].
Speaker 0: [singing in German].
Speaker 0: It's been in my head all day.
Speaker 0: I had to go to YouTube and listen to it around lunch just to get it out.
Speaker 1: Yes, but here I give you, uh, something that may not be familiar to everyone listening to this podcast.
Speaker 1: [singing in German].
Speaker 0: [singing in Spanish].
Speaker 1: [singing in Spanish].
Speaker 1: Yes, for those of you who do not know, there was a Warner Bros.
Speaker 1: cartoon that was, I guess, created by Steven Spielberg in some way, known as Freakazoid.
Speaker 0: Now, you know, there was kind of this progression.
Speaker 0: Like, there was Tiny Toons, which was zany humor, but it was also really kind of not based in reality, but grounded in some level of... of sense.
Speaker 0: It was like skits.
Speaker 0: And then Animaniacs was like the next step up, where, while there were skits in it, it was a little bit more out there.
Speaker 0: Freakazoid was, like, two steps beyond that.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the thing about Freakazoid is that it was real nerdy.
Speaker 1: Like, the plot of Freakazoid is a nerdy guy gets sucked into the internet through his computer...
Speaker 0: Bear in mind that they're really...
Speaker 1: ...and turns into a superhero who is nerdy.
Speaker 0: As far as we're concerned, there really was no internet back then yet either.
Speaker 1: I know, so it was way ahead of its time.
Speaker 1: And almost every joke in Freakazoid is some sort of pop culture comic book guy kind of joke, you know?
Speaker 1: And thus, the show really appealed to geeks like me.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna need more rope.
Speaker 1: Yes, R.I.M.
Speaker 1: has quoted the greatest Freakazoid, uh, bit ever.
Speaker 0: Also, one of the, I don't know, three episodes of Freakazoid I could stand to watch.
Speaker 0: I didn't like that show.
Speaker 1: Oh, you suck.
Speaker 1: I don't know, I just... Freakazoid rules.
Speaker 0: I really liked Tiny Toons as a kid.
Speaker 1: I liked Tiny Toons also.
Speaker 0: And I really liked Animaniacs.
Speaker 1: I liked Animaniacs also.
Speaker 0: Of course, then again, when I think about it, right about when Freakazoid came out is right about when I pretty much stopped watching television.
Speaker 0: Ah... Like, as it was coming out, I remember seeing that show and thinking, "Wow, this is just... fuck it,".
Speaker 0: and I just stopped watching TV.
Speaker 1: See, Freakazoid for me came out at sort of like the high point of Animaniacs, and it was like a double whammy.
Speaker 1: It was like, "Not only is this the high point of Animaniacs, but goddamn, there's Freakazoid as
Speaker 1: well.".
Speaker 0: See, right around then, I was spending more and more time playing video games and messing around with my computer.
Speaker 1: The one problem with Freakazoid was that the time slot made it inconvenient to watch, so I did not see as much of it as I wanted.
Speaker 1: But, if you have not seen Freakazoid, I suggest you go on the internet and look for the episode of Freakazoid known as "Candlejack," and watch it, because it is awesome.
Speaker 0: In fact, I remember Scott had, like, the worst copy.
Speaker 1: No, that's 'cause Ian, I think, had it on a VHS, and I ripped it with the Aver.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was about to say exactly that.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: So, we have this... we have probably the worst video capture thing ever.
Speaker 0: It's an external USB 1.0 Windows-only S-video.
Speaker 0: That doesn't even take S-video, I don't think.
Speaker 1: I think it does.
Speaker 0: I think it took RCA and coax.
Speaker 0: It did.
Speaker 1: Oh, it did.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And Scott ripped this already piss-poor VHS into this horribly piss-poor 320x200 MPEG, and then we watched it.
Speaker 0: It was unwatchable.
Speaker 1: It's on YouTube now, you can find it, I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: But yeah, my thing of the day is the opener to Freakazoid in Spanish.
Speaker 1: And they haven't changed any of the animation, so you can still see the word "Freakazoid" spelled out in the alphabet that we use, that Spanish people also use.
Speaker 1: But they don't call it Freakazoid, they call it Phenomenoid.
Speaker 1: Which, alright, but don't the Spanish people see that it says Freakazoid?
Speaker 1: Aren't they gonna be like, "What the hell's up with that
Speaker 1: shit?"?
Speaker 0: Don't the Americans see that the signs are all in Japanese in their anime?
Speaker 1: Well, but the thing is, Japanese is a different character set, it's a different alphabet.
Speaker 1: We can't, you know, unless you know it, you don't know it, but if you're watching a Spanish show, you can figure out what the word is.
Speaker 1: And if some guy says in English, like Freakazoid, and on the screen it says Phenomenoid, you know that something's up.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway, by the same token, I'm finishing it out.
Speaker 0: Now, I find this one interesting, 'cause I always wondered why people didn't do this when they had openers where they could get away with it.
Speaker 0: Like, in other languages of South Park, they had a voice actor do Kenny.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Which didn't, I just found that kind of funny, but anyway, this show I watched semi-religiously as a kid was called Cops.
Speaker 1: I never even heard of this show until they told me about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all of us were watching the Zelda DVDs, and we saw the opener to Cops in English on the DVD as an extra, and we watched it a couple times, 'cause Cops was a pretty good show.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a cross between Tank Police and RoboCop.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: And Carmen Sandiego.
Speaker 1: Carmen Sandiego's awesome.
Speaker 1: Man, if there was a DVD of, like, you could watch old Carmen Sandiego game show episodes.
Speaker 0: Oh, the game show.
Speaker 0: I thought you were gonna say the cartoon.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say, "What the hell's wrong with
Speaker 0: you?".
Speaker 1: Oh, fuck the cartoon.
Speaker 1: No, the game show of Carmen Sandiego.
Speaker 1: People don't realize that Carmen Sandiego started out as an awesome game show on PBS, and that was where the action was.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean an awesome game show where the kids on it were dumbfucks?
Speaker 1: I know, but that's what was so great about it, is that you would sit there, and they'd be like, "Hey, kid, put a glowing stick on South Africa," and he'd put it in, like, Egypt, and you'd be like, "Fuck you, you dumbass!
Speaker 1: Fuck
Speaker 1: you!".
Speaker 0: Good thing the FCC can't get us.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So, no, the opener to this show is basically other than a guy saying, "Blah, blah, blah, crime.
Speaker 0: Blah, blah, blah,
Speaker 0: cops.".
Speaker 0: It's just this techno kind of thing, and a guy saying the word "cops" over and over again, just
Speaker 0: "cops."
Speaker 0: "Cops.".
Speaker 0: And while, obviously, they dubbed the show in German, they didn't re-sing the song.
Speaker 0: It just says
Speaker 0: "cops.".
Speaker 1: That's something I realized while researching, well, I guess researching, if that's what you want to call it, all these different openers in various languages, is that Disney and Warner Bros.
Speaker 1: and the big boys seem to be able to afford having lots of vocals in their openers, you know, actual composed songs that didn't suck that badly, and they actually seem to also be able to afford to get people to sing those songs in other languages in other countries, whereas smaller-time studios that usually just made shows for syndication could not afford to have their, like, lyrics composed for their songs, and if they did, they couldn't afford to have them translated, or at least less often.
Speaker 1: Like, Thundercats, if you watch it in another country, they still go,
Speaker 1: "Thundercats.".
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: "Thundercat" would probably be a really cool word in German.
Speaker 1: Thundercats rule.
Speaker 0: I'm just getting that vibe.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Alright, anyway, we didn't know what to talk about tonight.
Speaker 0: Scott got home late, and I was playing Super Mario World for a good 45 minutes.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And it's a Thursday.
Speaker 0: You'd think, "Oh, we can talk about anything.
Speaker 0: That'd be
Speaker 0: easy.".
Speaker 0: But nah.
Speaker 0: Nah.
Speaker 0: 'Cause everything we thought of was either something that would require research, which is pretty much the bane of our existence at this point, or something we just didn't want to talk about anything complicated.
Speaker 0: I mean, I got a lot to say about politics right now.
Speaker 0: I got a lot to say about, I don't know, a bunch of stuff sitting on my desk.
Speaker 0: I got stories, but...
Speaker 1: I have to go to bed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Scott was lazy, and as a result, blaming Scott, we didn't have a topic for tonight.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna talk about those zombies.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We couldn't delay it anymore.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about another aspect of fighting off the zombie apocalypse.
Speaker 0: Last time, I remember we talked a lot about reconnaissance, you know, how do you figure out what's going on, but... I don't know, I'm just not feeling it.
Speaker 0: I think we should talk about something else.
Speaker 1: That sounds good to me, because zombies are messy and slow, and they like to eat brains.
Speaker 1: Hey!
Speaker 0: This is a podcast.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about podcasts!
Speaker 1: Oh, that's gonna be real good.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I got not- 'cause we actually came up with a great idea for a contest.
Speaker 0: But I'll get to that later.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Just 'cause I realized over the past few months that my taste in podcasts and what I've been listening to has changed fairly dramatically over time.
Speaker 0: And it seems like for every ten podcasts I pick up and listen to, I only keep one of them.
Speaker 0: And of the ten of the ones I keep over the ten months or so, I'll only keep two or three of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I noticed that as well.
Speaker 1: When I first started listening to podcasts, I sorta just picked 'em up here and there.
Speaker 1: And the ones that I listen to, like the day- 'cause I got an iPod Nano.
Speaker 1: the day iPod Nanos were announced.
Speaker 1: Steve Jobs pulled it out of his pocket, and I went to the Apple website and I clicked.
Speaker 1: Mostly because my iPod Mini was busted.
Speaker 1: I wonder how that happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so not because I'm a sucker for Steve Jobs, because I'm not.
Speaker 1: Anyway, and as soon as I got that iPod Nano a couple days later, I started listening to podcasts 'cause I started using iTunes.
Speaker 1: And, well, I subscribed to a whole bunch of podcasts.
Speaker 1: And almost none of those do I still subscribe to.
Speaker 1: Like, maybe two.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: I mean, we've talked about this before, and we did a long, very popular thread in the forums about it, but this is kind of an update.
Speaker 0: Like, what we're listening to right now.
Speaker 0: Partly 'cause I wanna give props to all the podcasts I actually like, 'cause I don't listen to many podcasts.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I mean, now I'm prob- you know, for a while, like recently, say the past few weeks, maybe the past month, my podcast listening has declined.
Speaker 1: Like, I subscribe to a bunch of shows, and I see them there in my iTunes, and I say, "Man, that's a good show.
Speaker 1: I like that show, I don't wanna unsubscribe from
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: But every time I go and pick up my iPod and say, "Alright, I wanna listen to a podcast now,".
Speaker 1: I look.
Speaker 1: And I just don't feel like listening to most of the stuff that's on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I gotta admit, and it really gives credit to Dave and Joel, Fast Karate for the Gentlemen, but whenever I sit down at my iPod, they're usually the first ones I go to after I listen to the news.
Speaker 0: It's like, I listen to the news, and then I look, and I've got a Dragon's Landing that's been sitting there forever, and I've got, like, one of all the podcasts I respect.
Speaker 0: And I always just go for the Dave and Joel, then the Anime World Order, and then...
Speaker 1: I go for those pretty quickly as well, but I don't know if I'm gonna shamefully admit that I go for Twit right away.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: You still listen to Twit?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean, I can't really put a finger on it, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't enjoy Twit very much.
Speaker 1: I get the same feeling of listening to Twit that I get from reading Slashdot, like, in the year 2002.
Speaker 1: Ah, I can see that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's kinda why I go for it.
Speaker 1: Plus, it only comes out once a week.
Speaker 1: Oh!
Speaker 1: Alright, you know what podcast I go to right away?
Speaker 1: And you're not gonna like this, but... There's a TV show on ESPN.
Speaker 1: Oh, that thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that thing, called Pardon the Interruption.
Speaker 1: Now, I know a lot of people listening aren't sports fans, and if you are, you're probably not a mer- football!
Speaker 1: You're probably not sports fans in the United States, so you probably don't know about this show, 'cause I think it's only on in the US and Canada.
Speaker 1: It's basically a show where these two sports journalist guys do basically sorta what we do, not really.
Speaker 1: And they, like, have a rundown of all these sports topics on the right, and they just go through 'em real quick, and they always argue with each other.
Speaker 1: And then, they'll play a fun game, like, they'll have a game called, like, Oddsmakers, like, you know, uh, what are the chances that this is gonna happen?
Speaker 1: And one guy will be like, "30% chance that that will
Speaker 1: happen!".
Speaker 1: The other guy will be like, "0% chance that that will
Speaker 1: And they get, you know, they do fun stuff.
Speaker 1: And the show's only, like, a half hour long, so a lot of short trips, it's, like, really convenient, whereas most other podcasts seem to be at least an hour long.
Speaker 1: At least most other good podcasts.
Speaker 1: So it's, like, one of the few podcasts in that mid-length range, 'cause it's an audio recording of a TV show that you don't really need to look at.
Speaker 1: 'Cause who wants to look at these ugly journalist faces?
Speaker 1: And they cover, you know, pretty much all the entertaining sports news.
Speaker 1: Like, they don't cover, like, who won and who lost.
Speaker 1: They cover, like, all the drama of sports, like, "That guy's going to court with
Speaker 1: roids!".
Speaker 1: Or, "Oh, this guy, you know, he's lost five in a row, even though after he talked big, what
Speaker 1: now?".
Speaker 1: And it's kinda funny.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, if we're talking about absolute what I go for first no matter what, hands down is 12 Byzantine Emperors.
Speaker 1: Ah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Or 12 Byzantine Rulers, if you will.
Speaker 1: See, that's another one of those ones where I like it a lot.
Speaker 1: But, and I have it, and I subscribe to it, and I've listened to a bunch of episodes, but I still have some episodes that I haven't listened to.
Speaker 1: Like, six or seven of them.
Speaker 0: Like, if one comes out, I will go out of my way to listen to it.
Speaker 0: Like, if one came out on a weekend, I would probably sit in my room and listen to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've got, like, six or seven most recent ones I haven't listened to, and not because I don't want to, but, like, the mood never strikes me.
Speaker 1: Like, I look at it, and I see it there in the iPod, and I just don't feel like it.
Speaker 1: But I leave it there, because I know one day I'll feel like it.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean, I've listened to all of them that are out right now, twice.
Speaker 0: And I usually, right after I listen to one, I go online, I find maps, and I kind of correlate where all the stuff happened, and where the armies were, and try to get a sense of everything.
Speaker 0: But then again, I've been on a really big Roman/Byzantine/Parthian history kick lately.
Speaker 1: I mostly like Byzantine Emperors more as, like, I treat it less as a historical thing, because I can't remember all that crap, and it doesn't really matter to me.
Speaker 1: But I listen to it more of, like, a drama, fictional type of thing.
Speaker 1: Like, "Oh man, that guy totally punned that
Speaker 1: guy.".
Speaker 0: Yep, that's the brilliance of it.
Speaker 0: That's why I think it's one of the best podcasts out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because he takes history, and he shows you the entertaining drama that sort of maybe really happened.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, earlier in the podcast run, when he's talking about when the Byzantine Empire was still much more like the Roman Empire in the West, it's much more historically verifiable than some of the later ones, because, you know, the world was slowly descending into the medieval dark ages, so it goes a little more fanciful as time goes on, because history wasn't as well recorded.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But that also leads to a lot of humor.
Speaker 1: Humor and history?
Speaker 1: Those don't mix.
Speaker 1: Yeah, 12 Byzantine Emperors is great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, honestly, pretty much right after that, I always go right for "NPR, it's all
Speaker 0: politics.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used to--see, when I first--that's another one--when I first started listening to podcasts, I had like three or four NPRs.
Speaker 1: Like, I had NPR, like, best thing of the day, you know, and I had NPR technology, and I had NPR something else, and now I don't listen to NPR anything.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: I mean, NPR, health and technology--or, sorry, health and science, technology.
Speaker 0: Now, I just recently added the BBC World News, whatever, along with BBC Documentary Archives, and the NPR, it's all politics.
Speaker 0: I listen to all of those.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, I would listen to, like, the NPR, like, headlines, like, the headlines of the day, the biggest news.
Speaker 1: I would listen to that, too, but not anymore.
Speaker 0: I used to listen to All Things Considered, but it was the opinions bit, and, like, four of them in a row were really disagreeable opinions from fairly stupid people.
Speaker 0: So, I kind of stopped listening, and now I looked and I realized that it was just a bad run, so I'm thinking about picking that back up.
Speaker 1: I guess it's just that, like, the NPR stuff, since it's mostly news, I read Google News, I'm actually using that WeNews quite a bit, and I really don't care what other people's opinions are so much, 'cause I just form my own.
Speaker 1: And I get the information from somewhere, so listening to a guy say it feels like it takes a longer time than it takes me to read it.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like a waste, and it doesn't entertain me.
Speaker 0: All the news sites on the internet, other than pretty much Google News, and even there, they, like, the science section on Digg, is mostly garbage.
Speaker 1: That's why I block the science section on Digg, I don't look at it at all.
Speaker 0: So I listen to NPR Health and Science, and I learn all the stuff that I wouldn't learn on the internet, because there really aren't good websites that are fun and easy to read.
Speaker 0: that cover that.
Speaker 1: That's true, I guess I'm just not interested in learning about Health and Science.
Speaker 0: Because they aid me in forming my own opinions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I also actually really like hearing the opinions of experts.
Speaker 1: The problem is, every time I listen to a podcast, and I think that, you know, I'm looking for expert opinions, I always go away feeling like they're not experts.
Speaker 1: And, I don't know, it's like when I was in college, like, I would hear, like, political...
Speaker 0: Like?
Speaker 1: I would hear political scientists speak about things, and I was like, damn, they know what they're fucking talking about.
Speaker 1: And I haven't found a podcast, other than Byzantine Emperors, but that's history, not political science, where people talk about that stuff, it gives me the same feeling of that guy knows what he's fucking talking about, that I got in college.
Speaker 0: That was very eloquently stated, in a very non-eloquent way, Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's people, you're like, I want fucking educated shit out there, man.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: That's great.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: No, but actually, it's all politics guys.
Speaker 0: I mean, obviously they do their research ahead of time.
Speaker 0: But they know a lot about American politics, and the inter- I mean, they treat it the way sports fans treat sports.
Speaker 0: So instead of the commentary being like, well, you know, no baseball team has ever won the World Series if it lost eight games in February.
Speaker 1: They don't play baseball in February.
Speaker 0: I know, hence what I just said is 100% accurate.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Think about it.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 0: No team has ever won the World Series if it lost eight games in February.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but they point out things like that in politics.
Speaker 0: Like recently I learned that no Republican has ever been elected President of the United States without having won the Republican primary in South Carolina.
Speaker 0: The first Southern Republican primary.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: And that's really interesting.
Speaker 0: And I'm curious to see how that plays out in the current political climate as things start moving toward the U.S.
Speaker 0: presidential election.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so keep your eye on the South Carolina primary for Republicans.
Speaker 1: However that turns out, if that guy isn't nominated- No, these guys- Or that person isn't nominated, and if that person is nominated, we'll see if they're going to win or not.
Speaker 0: These guys are old, and they were talking about the Tonight Show with Carson.
Speaker 0: And then they were talking about the guy before Carson.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know who that is.
Speaker 0: Me either.
Speaker 0: But they kept talking about it.
Speaker 1: And they were talking about it- All the old people listening to our show just had heart attacks.
Speaker 0: The first thing I thought was, there was somebody on that show before Carson.
Speaker 0: I thought he started the show.
Speaker 0: Because I didn't know.
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: I never even saw the Carson.
Speaker 0: I saw Carson's show like twice.
Speaker 1: I never saw it.
Speaker 1: But I never really watched Letterman or Leno or anybody.
Speaker 0: Nah, me either.
Speaker 1: I don't watch those shows.
Speaker 0: The only show I ever watched like that was- I saw Once in a Laundromat.
Speaker 0: The Daily Show with Craig Kilbourne.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And then The Daily Show with Jon Stewart, who was far superior.
Speaker 1: I saw some Public Access show also.
Speaker 0: Well, let's see.
Speaker 0: Actually, one that I listen to regularly, but recently I went through the archives and listened to pretty much every episode I had any interest in is Movies You Should See.
Speaker 0: I really like that podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Movies You Should See, I sort of get this, it's like a sine wave of interest.
Speaker 1: Like, about five or six of them will build up, and then I'll really want to listen to them.
Speaker 1: And I'll listen to one.
Speaker 1: And then that one will like, it'll like prime my attitude for the rest of them.
Speaker 1: And I'll be like, "Oh, that was
Speaker 1: great!"
Speaker 1: And I'll listen to the rest.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And then I'll clear them all out, and then I won't have any.
Speaker 0: It's like an avalanche.
Speaker 1: And then when they start building up again, I'll be like, "I don't want to listen to
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: I think part of it, and this is going to sound funny, but I mean, they're smart people, and they know what they're talking about.
Speaker 0: But they talk with Albionic accents, which to Americans tends to sound educated.
Speaker 1: I don't know why that is.
Speaker 0: Or villainous.
Speaker 1: But it's true.
Speaker 0: It's one of the two, it's either educated or villainous.
Speaker 0: And they're obviously, with the possible exception, well I'm not going to get into that, villainous.
Speaker 0: So they sound very educated.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it lends a certain air of authority to their show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let this be a note to anyone from Albion.
Speaker 1: If you have an accent, it is likely that you can sound very intelligent.
Speaker 1: And Americans will respect what you have to say.
Speaker 0: I can think of one or two Albionic accents that don't particularly garner that respect.
Speaker 0: "Oi!
Speaker 0: Put the flowers in the vase!
Speaker 0: Get
Speaker 0: in!".
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't talk like that.
Speaker 1: Then Americans will just think you're insane or something.
Speaker 1: Let's see, what other, oh, another good example of a podcast where, when I first started listening to a podcast, the IT conversations, you know that whole network of podcasts there?
Speaker 1: Yep, yep.
Speaker 1: I subscribed to a whole bunch of those.
Speaker 1: The problem was, is while when it was a hit, it was a hit.
Speaker 1: You would hear some guy doing a presentation at some tech conference that you couldn't afford to go to or fly to.
Speaker 1: And it would be the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: But then the next three or four of those, because they would do every single panel and presentation from every conference, would be like crap and useless.
Speaker 1: And it was like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: So I stopped listening just because I had a hard time weeding out the wheat from the chaff when it comes to the IT conversations.
Speaker 1: But now I actually realized that most of the ones that I liked were ones that dealt with open source and Linux and the stuff that I'm interested in.
Speaker 1: Gasp!
Speaker 1: That's a big surprise.
Speaker 1: So now I actually listen to, I don't listen to any IT conversations, but I do listen to Floss Weekly, which is not so weekly.
Speaker 1: It's one of those Twit network podcasts, but it basically has Chris DeBona, who's a guy who I think worked at Slashdot, but he works at Google now.
Speaker 1: And the Leo guy.
Speaker 1: And they get like the hot shit in the open source world and they interview them.
Speaker 1: And even when they get people I never heard of, it is like every single episode of that podcast, even though it's far from weekly, is hella interesting.
Speaker 1: Like when they interview the freaking Python guy and they interview the Open NMS guy and they get Evan Moglen, who's like the Free Software Foundation lawyer on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I listened to that one.
Speaker 0: He's a really interesting man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot.
Speaker 1: Every episode of that podcast, even if you don't know anything about open source software, holy shit is that one fantastic show.
Speaker 0: But I've been listening to Security now all night.
Speaker 1: Oh, see, there's another one that I listened to when I first started listening to podcasts.
Speaker 1: Now I don't listen to it all.
Speaker 0: See, I listen to it very selectively because they periodically seem to get on these stints and they talk about nothing but like Vista Security.
Speaker 0: I don't care at all about Vista Security.
Speaker 0: I care about that less than I care about just about anything.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: There are things I care about less than Vista Security, but Vista Security is pretty low, I got to admit.
Speaker 0: But I tried to listen to it because I'm interested in law and law school and all that.
Speaker 0: So I thought, all right, I'm going to find a law podcast.
Speaker 0: And aside from the million prepare for the LSATs, which I really don't want to bother with, I thought, hey, I'll check out This Week in Law, Twill.
Speaker 0: And I listened to two episodes.
Speaker 1: Didn't one of those have the Calacanis guy?
Speaker 0: Oh, whatever, that wasn't the...
Speaker 1: I got to let everyone know, Jason Calacanis is a guy who was like a Netscape AOL big time blog guy.
Speaker 1: Like he had something to do with Engadget and stuff.
Speaker 1: He's sort of an important Internet guy.
Speaker 1: But don't listen to any podcast he is on because he is the most annoying, interrupting, annoying guy ever.
Speaker 0: But there was none of that on the show.
Speaker 0: All I got out of it is that this was the most boring podcast in the world.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: And they didn't even really talk about law.
Speaker 0: It's not like they were talking about complicated things and therefore the uneducated rim was bored by it.
Speaker 0: It was just boring.
Speaker 0: Everyone talked in this, not even like the NPR, This Week on NPR News, we're going to... It was just, it was so boring I almost fell asleep at the wheel listening to it.
Speaker 1: I never listened to the show, so now I'm not going to.
Speaker 1: I wonder if, you know what would be really cool?
Speaker 1: This may or may not exist, I've never searched for it.
Speaker 1: But if there was like a law podcast that just reviewed court cases that happened recently.
Speaker 1: Like, oh, This Week in Court, so and so, case of so and so, and they just talked about the case and why it was interesting.
Speaker 1: Or even past cases.
Speaker 0: No, I just got to look more, I really just want to find a nice law review podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just like, this case of so and so for so and so, let's talk about it.
Speaker 1: Well, this guy was complaining about this shit, and this guy was complaining about this shit.
Speaker 1: In the end, this happened, and this is why, and this is the law, and this is why the judge interpreted it that way, and the jury decided this because...
Speaker 0: I imagine there are good ones out there, I just haven't, there's really still no easy way to find podcasts.
Speaker 0: Especially now that dig podcast searching suddenly broke.
Speaker 1: I don't know, maybe it's fixed again.
Speaker 0: I don't know, I haven't checked, but it's kind of useless.
Speaker 1: And iTunes podcast searching has never been that great.
Speaker 0: I hate iTunes podcast searching.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if there's any good law podcast out there, let me know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'd be cool.
Speaker 1: Let's see...
Speaker 0: I tried to find a few Learn Japanese podcasts, they were all okay.
Speaker 0: I found a Learn French podcast that was so bad I could cry.
Speaker 1: Let's see, what other podcasts am I way into?
Speaker 0: I always keep at least one Roadhouse and one Derek the Bandit, but that's just in case I need some music to listen to and I don't have any music on me.
Speaker 1: Well, I actually paid to get Roadhouse Premium that has extra songs and no ads.
Speaker 1: And it was totally worth it because the price was so ridiculously low.
Speaker 1: It was like 20 bucks for a year or something like that.
Speaker 0: I would, except I don't listen, I listen to more of my own MP3s than I do podcasts.
Speaker 1: See, that's the other thing is that I don't really load music on my iPod so much.
Speaker 1: Just because I'd have, you know, I'd have to set up a big thing, I'd have to make playlists, and it's a whole to-do.
Speaker 1: So, and I also don't download music as frequently as I used to.
Speaker 1: So I listen to the Roadhouse to get awesome blues music, and I listen to Derek the Bandit to get awesome trance from South Africa.
Speaker 1: I need, like, a rock podcast.
Speaker 1: Like, I've listened to a few, but they all sort of have that indie, like, hip alternative kind of rock.
Speaker 1: And not the old school hard rock that I like.
Speaker 0: I've found a lot of podcasts that sound like they're about music, or they'll have music in them.
Speaker 0: Then you listen to them, and it's just some guy talking about the music for like 45 minutes, and then they play one song.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, those are no good.
Speaker 0: I found an awesome Happy Hardcore podcast that disappeared after three episodes.
Speaker 0: Granted, I think he was just pirating mixes, but whatever, I want my Happy Hardcore.
Speaker 1: I think the reason that, you know, of all the music podcasts, that the Roadhouse and Derek the Bandit really kind of stick around, is because they mostly play music, and there's an awesome person emceeing the music, and that awesome person comes in between songs to tell you what the song was, and maybe a few other interesting bits, but they keep it brief, and they don't overdo it, and the music they play is awesome, and within the genre, and the production value is high, so yeah.
Speaker 0: Now, scarily, and Scott has mentioned this to me independently of me noticing I've been doing it, but more often than you would expect, I find myself listening to Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do it too.
Speaker 0: See, usually I put, like every week, I put one or two episodes on my iPod.
Speaker 0: I don't listen to them, I don't plan to listen to them, other than to spot check in my car to make sure the audio sounds okay in different settings.
Speaker 0: Like, I'll listen to it in my work on the computer, just briefly.
Speaker 0: I'll listen to it in the car.
Speaker 0: briefly, just to make sure that the levels are okay, whatever experiment I'm doing with the compressor didn't make anything sound bad, all that.
Speaker 0: More than half the time, I end up listening to the whole episode, and it's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 1: In the early days of Geek Nights, I always felt weird listening to the show.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, you know, because I hadn't done so many shows, I remembered everything I said, because it was like the third show or whatever.
Speaker 1: So listening to it was kind of like, just like, yeah, I'm here, I remember saying that, I remember saying that.
Speaker 1: And it wasn't entertaining or anything, I just was like, eh, alright, I'm tired of listening to myself.
Speaker 0: It's just kind of weird, I mean, there is something awkward about hearing your own voice on the radio.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was just weird and not entertaining at all.
Speaker 1: Nowadays, you know, sometimes I'll pop in a Geek Nights episode.
Speaker 1: You know, especially if it's one like, I remember like the initial D1 and the Utena one.
Speaker 0: Where we did something weird with music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because
Speaker 1: we put lots of music in it, and I wanted to hear how the music sounded, and I listened to the show, and like, as I listened, I didn't remember everything we said, but it came back to me as I listened to it, and the music was awesome, and I was actually entertained a lot listening to my own show.
Speaker 0: Now this brings up a serious question.
Speaker 1: It's like more than many other podcasts I listen to.
Speaker 0: Because I overheard at, I think it was Otacon, three years, I forget, but two artists in the Artist Alley were talking about drawing pornography, and they were debating whether or not it's weird to get off from pornography that you yourself had drawn.
Speaker 0: I see where you're going with this.
Speaker 0: That's a lot like where we're going with Geek Nights right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, if you're out there and you're a podcaster, right, tell us if you are entertained listening to your own podcast.
Speaker 1: Because we kinda are, even though we didn't used to be.
Speaker 1: And I don't know what to think of that.
Speaker 1: Does that mean our show is so awesome that even the people who make it are entertained?
Speaker 0: Or are we just such fucking egoists?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what does it mean?
Speaker 1: I don't know what it means.
Speaker 0: Are we narcissistic?
Speaker 0: Are we stupid?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have no idea.
Speaker 1: We need some help.
Speaker 1: You know what, if you're a person who does television, tell me if you enjoy watching your own television show.
Speaker 0: Well wasn't it, Penn Jillette was talking to one guy who apparently keeps archives of everything he's ever done on TV and watches them all the time.
Speaker 0: Oh, alright.
Speaker 0: That was a while ago.
Speaker 1: Wait, if that guy's weird though, are we weird for people like that?
Speaker 0: I don't know if he was weird or not.
Speaker 0: I barely listen to Penn anymore.
Speaker 0: I listen to him like once a week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I also barely listen to Penn anymore.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is.
Speaker 1: It just seems like after a while all the shows felt kinda the same.
Speaker 1: I only listen- And it was just background- it's good background noise still.
Speaker 0: I only listen when he's interviewing someone interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but most of the time it's just the same old stuff and it's like, "Yes Penn, I've heard you say this before.
Speaker 1: Yes,
Speaker 1: alright.".
Speaker 1: Yes, you know, I guess part of it is also because I can't call into the show.
Speaker 1: Like maybe if I was listening live it would be a little bit better because then I'd call in all the time.
Speaker 0: Well, the only time I've ever interacted with the show, I had an argument with Michael Godot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And basically I was trying to educate him as to some Linux things and such and he was getting kinda, "Eh, you stupid computer people, blah blah
Speaker 0: blah."
Speaker 0: And it ended on somewhat terse terms.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: At least he responded.
Speaker 0: I'll give him credit for that.
Speaker 1: It's not like he's got anything better to do.
Speaker 1: He's a juggler.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: But to wrap this up, I mentioned earlier a contest and we thought about this downstairs and during the show.
Speaker 0: I thought about how I want to do this.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna start one contest for each day of the week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we'll just generally have a contest for each day of the week all the time.
Speaker 1: So yesterday we started the contest for MDGeist, right?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Very briefly, listen to yesterday's episode.
Speaker 0: We'll mention it every Wednesday for a while.
Speaker 1: Wait, I think we should just do the contest.
Speaker 1: We should only mention the contest for the day of the week that they're for.
Speaker 0: Alright, yeah, so listen to yesterday or next Wednesday if you want to hear about the MDGeist contest.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the Thursday contest, and I'm interested in this for a number of reasons.
Speaker 0: I want you to find for us and tell us why it's bad the worst podcast out there.
Speaker 1: No, wait, I gotta put some restrictions on this.
Speaker 0: Oh, I already wrote down a bunch of restrictions.
Speaker 1: Alright, number one.
Speaker 0: Wait, it's too easy to just find like a podcast with one episode that wasn't even in iTunes.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: It's gotta be a podcast that keeps going.
Speaker 1: It has to have some sort of regularity.
Speaker 0: One, it must have at least 20 episodes online available for download in the feed.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: Two, it must- What if the feed is only 10 episodes but there's 20 on the site?
Speaker 1: It's gotta be 20 episodes available.
Speaker 0: Alright, 20 episodes available and the feed must be active.
Speaker 0: Two, the feed must be listed in iTunes.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 0: 'Cause if you can't get yourself in iTunes, you fail this podcast.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of people who aren't allowed in iTunes.
Speaker 1: Like I don't think Happy House of Hentai is in there.
Speaker 1: You know, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So what should you do about those guys?
Speaker 0: No, leave them out.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: 'Cause that's also too easy.
Speaker 1: But I know that there's like also like this pro-pedophile and there's another like pro-white supremacy podcast that aren't allowed in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't care about that.
Speaker 0: I don't care about the content.
Speaker 1: 'Cause those could be the worst podcasts ever.
Speaker 0: No, 'cause I'm not talking about that.
Speaker 0: I wanna hear the worst podcast in terms of it's just bad and unlistenable regardless of the content.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Not necessarily audio quality.
Speaker 0: Maybe the people have annoying voices.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're just so incompetent.
Speaker 0: Maybe they don't know how to edit.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's a guy going um um um for 10 minutes and he says one sentence.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They also, this podcast, the worst podcast ever, has to have a website.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: And it has to have put up an episode within the last month.
Speaker 0: At least.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: That sounds good.
Speaker 1: Oh, and you can't like just suddenly make like 20 podcasts in one day that are as bad as you can make them.
Speaker 1: It can't be something that's made by you or anyone you know or you can't make a podcast for the purposes of winning this contest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, think of it this way.
Speaker 0: We want you to do recon for us.
Speaker 0: Partly because we wanna make fun of podcasts.
Speaker 0: Partly 'cause I'm curious just how bad and deep the rabbit hole goes.
Speaker 0: Because the worst podcast I've heard I found and they had some level of respectability.
Speaker 0: But they were still crap.
Speaker 0: Yet there were podcasts that had a fraction of the listeners that they had.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: And I can't imagine what those podcasts are.
Speaker 0: I wanna know.
Speaker 0: I want you to find for me the bottom.
Speaker 1: So what are they gonna win?
Speaker 0: I haven't decided that yet.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do this contest.
Speaker 1: So how are you gonna encourage people to enter a contest to win a mystery prize?
Speaker 0: Well, because I guarantee we'll have a good prize by the end of it.
Speaker 0: And I'm gonna run this contest for at least a month.
Speaker 0: I want people to spend some time on this.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: So mystery prize.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: It could be poop in a box.
Speaker 0: I guarantee it will not be poop in a box.
Speaker 1: It'll be an empty box.
Speaker 0: Seriously, it'll be a real prize of some kind.
Speaker 0: We have a real prize for the MD Geist contest.
Speaker 1: Poop in a box.
Speaker 0: Well, in a manner of speaking.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: Is this show over?
Speaker 0: I think it's over.
Speaker 1: One last note is that we didn't mention every podcast we listen to.
Speaker 1: But I keep my OPML on my website and you can go look at it and see what I'm subscribed to right now.
Speaker 0: And also to all of our friend podcasters, if I didn't say that I listen to your show, remember that part of that is due to the fact that I really only listen to podcasts in my car.
Speaker 0: And I'm only in my car 10 hours a week.
Speaker 0: And I have about 30 to 40 hours a week of podcasts subscribed to.
Speaker 0: So you can see where that goes.
Speaker 1: Oh, and also all our friend podcasters, if Rym doesn't listen to your show, I listen to it sometimes.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rym and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com.
Speaker 1: Or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.