Speaker 0: It's Tuesday August 21st.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight making babies with tempest.
Speaker 0: Let's do this You know until today.
Speaker 0: I'd never been on a train that just broke down.
Speaker 1: I was on a train that broke once but it only broke for a short while and then kept going again.
Speaker 0: See I'm riding I'm Fighting the elite four and doing okay despite the fact that I'd never played a pokemon game before.
Speaker 0: so I didn't realize that Once I start I got to go all the way to the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I had just four Pokemon with me and two bibberell And I hadn't bought items pretty much for the entire game
Speaker 1: You need if you're this is the first time you're going to the elite four and you're not super high level like you didn't level Up extra you need to bring in like a fistful of hyperpose.
Speaker 0: actually let me put it this way despite having almost like I was rationing like the few normal potions I had left and Despite only having four Pokemon all of which were below the levels of the Pokemon that the Masters had yeah I'd be at all the elite four with no problem.
Speaker 1: Did you beat the Pokemon champion?
Speaker 0: I just I killed two of her Pokemon, and then I had nothing left, but two bibberells Yeah, and I had no more revives or potions.
Speaker 0: basically
Speaker 1: the thing you have to do is you have to do it at least once And fail to figure out what Pokemon they have and which Pokemon they have that are trouble Pokemon And then make sure you bring in attacks that can get rid of those Pokemon way, and then it's real easy.
Speaker 0: I don't like most of the Pokemon that are available to me before I beat the game, so I really only have four Pokemon Because I don't have a fire Pokemon because all the fire Pokemon are either crap or everybody uses them.
Speaker 1: Yep, I don't want to wrap it as the thing is because they get all the good fire Pokemon are after you beat the game Yeah, or any other games.
Speaker 0: I refuse to use a rapid ash just because everyone has one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I stopped using mine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I brought.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna bring over anyway.
Speaker 0: so I'm fighting through that.
Speaker 0: and then the HVAC the cooling air conditioning whatever just kind of stops.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: It wasn't so necessary today.
Speaker 1: It was kind of cold and raining.
Speaker 0: actually the super heat was on.
Speaker 0: oh And then the lights flicker and come back on and then the train just kind of slowly rolls to a stop with The river on one side the cliffs on the other side, and it was one of those sections with only two tracks.
Speaker 0: So we're now blocking all northbound traffic.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right sit there for a while.
Speaker 0: I'm just kind of relaxing.
Speaker 0: It's actually really nice.
Speaker 0: There aren't many people in my car.
Speaker 0: There's an old guy sitting next to me reading some history book.
Speaker 0: I'm just sitting there, and there's a young hip yuppie kind of guy who immediately rips out his cell phone and starts texting furiously.
Speaker 0: So after about five minutes the conductor comes on and says yeah the Engine just kind of stopped.
Speaker 0: We're trying to start it again.
Speaker 0: We expect to be on route shortly.
Speaker 1: can't they just get another engine to come down and grab your train?
Speaker 0: And do you know how much of a pain in the ass that would be and how much time that would take?
Speaker 1: I thought Engines could just like grab engines or yeah Behind the train push it Scott.
Speaker 0: I don't think you understand at all how trains are routed.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like air traffic in that there's zones and Once a train enters a zone no other train can enter that zone for a period of time until the train leaves the zone.
Speaker 0: And zones are one way and you have to you have to do all this stuff basically to send another train in.
Speaker 0: they got to Get another train get it ready get it into position But it would take so much time that they basically sat there trying to get this engine going so they wouldn't inconvenience.
Speaker 0: Of course you do that that duh, but I don't think they didn't even plan to send anything else.
Speaker 1: yet What if they couldn't get it fixed?
Speaker 0: the only plan if they couldn't get it fixed was to send an auxiliary train on the southbound Track to pick everyone up and take us to our destination, and then I guess delay all southbound traffic for a while.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's kind of sucky.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then eventually send some way out to get this train out of the way.
Speaker 1: They just had those things.
Speaker 1: they put them on the track and you pump up and down.
Speaker 0: yeah So I don't care.
Speaker 0: I put away the Pokemon because after I was getting it home too late, so it wasn't so bad.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, it wasn't so bad, but I sat there for a good half hour And the thing is it's all cool.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I'm in no hurry, so I'm just kind of sitting there.
Speaker 0: It's raining outside.
Speaker 0: I stopped playing my Pokemon cuz.
Speaker 0: I'm pissed off that I died.
Speaker 0: Start reading my plutar.
Speaker 0: the old man next to me is just reading his book.
Speaker 0: We're all cool.
Speaker 0: The announcer says again all right.
Speaker 0: We think we got it.
Speaker 0: Give us a minute and the train is gonna continue.
Speaker 0: We're gonna get to garrison and then the guy the conductor walks by and the uppy guy starts grousing Loudly.
Speaker 0: and then when the conductor reaches his seat He grabs the conductor and stops it and basically says so obviously the trains just gonna limp into garrison and then we're gonna have to change to the whatever train that just passed us because I saw the 652 whatever train just passed.
Speaker 0: so why did you just announce that?
Speaker 0: why lie?
Speaker 0: and the conductor?
Speaker 0: Completely ignores him and keeps walking.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then we get to our stop at garrison And he says garrison station and the yuppies crumbling and grousing and yell at him blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Why don't these tell us we're gonna have to change?
Speaker 0: and then the doors close and the train keeps going to cold spring.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then it goes to beacon and the guy totally got owned Punned.
Speaker 0: the guys wouldn't shut up thought.
Speaker 0: I don't get the people who if your life causes a problem You're stuck somewhere you have a problem, and there's nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 0: the moment there is nothing you can do about a problem any complaining and anything you do other than just accept it and Mitigate it as best you can or do something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know something or shut up Scott I already said it's beyond your control.
Speaker 1: well sometimes you can do something.
Speaker 0: I already say if beyond your control once it is beyond your control by definition There's nothing else you can do beyond your control.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of things beyond your control.
Speaker 1: could you could get out and push the train?
Speaker 0: No you can't.
Speaker 0: that's illegal.
Speaker 1: You could try.
Speaker 0: you can't even get out.
Speaker 0: You don't have the key.
Speaker 1: you could try.
Speaker 1: no the emergency window.
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 0: Regardless the situation is beyond your control.
Speaker 0: grousing about it's not gonna help.
Speaker 0: being angry is not gonna help.
Speaker 0: what I did?
Speaker 0: I kept reading my plutarch, and I just sat there relaxing on the train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you're supposed to do, but all you know you can do other things like I just said, but they have consequences.
Speaker 0: But any I just I don't get people who get so worked up about things that they have no control over like Can't they think don't they realize all right?
Speaker 0: Yelling at the conductor is gonna get a whole bunch done the trades is gonna start moving immediately.
Speaker 1: some people they live with the the don't worry be happy and Some people don't and those people are generally less happy, and it's their own damn fault.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much but anyway I don't want to talk about that because there is kind of big news in the role-playing games world and Big is a very relative term.
Speaker 0: Wizards of the coast has decides ours update coast that they are going to release a new edition of Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 0: Yay, this is going to be fourth edition so so far.
Speaker 0: We've had Dungeons and Dragons and all its iteration
Speaker 1: advanced Dungeons and Dragons which
Speaker 0: was my favorite Dungeons and Dragons because then there was advanced Dungeons and Dragons second edition which was in my opinion overall the best Dungeons and Dragons system for role-playing, but I think the only reason it was good is because of its crippling flaws.
Speaker 1: perhaps.
Speaker 0: Then they released third edition which was supposed to revolutionize role-playing and revolutionize Dungeons and Dragons and It basically just turned D&D into Super D 20. super everything has a rule for it basically made it a video game with some role-playing kind of tacked on and Then they didn't sell so well because most people started pirating it and people really got disillusioned and whatever.
Speaker 0: They released third and a half edition and tried to get everyone to buy these books all over again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they made a whole.
Speaker 1: the idea of Dungeons and Dragons is they make their money by selling books.
Speaker 1: if they sell one book to Everyone who plays that's not really enough money for a big game company like WotC.
Speaker 1: So they make another book and another book and another book and another book and they all add together.
Speaker 1: and there are a bunch of People out there not me, but there are people who buy many if not all of these books.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: the worst thing about third and a half edition was that they release new books and They change a bunch of relatively minor rules all over the place and while they release little erratic sheets Like here are the changes.
Speaker 0: It was basically impossible to use a third edition book effectively in third and a half edition and I'm convinced that they designed this Update specifically to sell to everyone who already had the book.
Speaker 0: It was crap.
Speaker 0: The only reason I bought a third and a half book was that my third edition book fell apart like physically it was unusable.
Speaker 1: Yep, that me also my third edition book kind of and you know while you know I could have lived with just the third edition book because it wasn't as bad as rims He was turned in terms of condition.
Speaker 0: I was pretty bad.
Speaker 1: This was on what I call unreadable.
Speaker 0: The thing is mine was perfectly readable.
Speaker 0: The problem was that about the pages.
Speaker 0: the only pages that were missing were the pages at the end that had the monsters because that book came out before The Dungeon Master's Guide and the monsters manual came out.
Speaker 0: remember I bought that book the day Third edition D&D was renounced and released.
Speaker 1: I did also bought the very first printing of that book, but it wasn't the day.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 0: it was the day my whole D&D group went out and got it.
Speaker 0: And in fact also remember that book came with that CD.
Speaker 1: Yep, now the CD that there's.
Speaker 1: only one thing you're allowed to do with that CD.
Speaker 0: I believe it was Chuck it after breaking it.
Speaker 0: Yes It was actually kind of ritualized among the front row crew.
Speaker 0: anytime we found someone who had the CD We basically forced them under threat of death to take it out and of their own free.
Speaker 0: Well their own relatively free will break it with their own hands and throw it away possibly spitting on it.
Speaker 1: Basically, the CD had this really shitty character generating software on it Bullshit thing on it - I don't remember but it's a shitty character generator.
Speaker 0: It was just crap.
Speaker 0: so Fourth edition I'm gonna come out right now and say that I Generally get the impression that fourth edition is crap.
Speaker 0: However, I can't say it's crap.
Speaker 0: universally.
Speaker 0: I can say it's crap for people like us and when I say people like us, I mean people who roleplay
Speaker 1: well, basically from what everything I've read and I've read some not as I haven't read everything, but I've read some and Fourth edition if everything that has been said about it is correct is a better.
Speaker 1: Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 1: They're going to fix things that are wrong with Dungeons & Dragons like for example familiars won't suck anymore and be ignored and You know stuff like that stuff that is wrong with Dungeons & Dragons itself.
Speaker 1: However, if you are like us and your main complaint with Dungeons & Dragons is that it is Dungeons & Dragons Guess what fourth edition D&D is still D&D.
Speaker 1: They're not changing it to something else They're just fixing it within itself sort of like the way that World of Warcraft is still a mud.
Speaker 1: It's just a fixed mud.
Speaker 0: The thing is when Scott says fixing it basically from what I can gather the majority of the changes are fleshing out combat more and making combat more complex Making the decisions you make with your characters creation and leveling in regards to combat much more meaningful and generally just making the combat system a lot more robust.
Speaker 0: and I don't see really anything about doing anything else other than making combat more robust and changing the way classes work a bit and changing the way races work a bit and changing the alignment system and having optional alignment systems and Completely changing the way feats work and all that sort of business.
Speaker 1: They're making it go to 30 levels instead of 20 levels before you get to you know Epic power and I think that's for this system.
Speaker 1: I think that is a better Dungeons & Dragons because part of Dungeons & Dragons this sucks is that you only Increase in power and and progress very, you know, relatively rarely and progressing is very fun.
Speaker 1: However, the real solution is burning wheel constant progression of gradual.
Speaker 0: Well, not just that.
Speaker 0: the real issue is that they're adding 30 levels, but I get the impression that they're adding 10.
Speaker 0: Well, they're adding 10 levels to the 20 levels.
Speaker 0: They're just adding the 10 levels on the end instead of that epic stuff.
Speaker 0: They did.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think they're spreading the 20 levels.
Speaker 1: That's what it seems like to me.
Speaker 0: it seems like they're basically just adding to combat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one of the specific really is in the book is combat.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read a quote from some shit blog because there's really no good.
Speaker 0: It's not a blog but whatever it is there's no good gaming press.
Speaker 0: most of the sites I found were either wrong or Just linked to the D&D website or quoted the D&D website directly in poor choice.
Speaker 0: And the D&D website is actually kind of useless because it's all just videos that I don't want to watch.
Speaker 0: Yep But here's an excerpt from this side I'm looking at.
Speaker 0: the fighter is the only current fourth edition class with capabilities that depend on the weapon They have chosen to train with the most.
Speaker 0: even at first level a fighter who uses an axe will have different power Selection than a fighter who relies on a flail or a rapier or a pick.
Speaker 0: uh Walt I don't know what I want to say about this.
Speaker 0: second edition was kind of cool in that They really broke it down.
Speaker 0: weapons didn't matter.
Speaker 0: They all just did kind of different damage.
Speaker 0: But they used to have weapon speed and initiative was determined per round.
Speaker 0: So as a result Yeah Did at least decide do I want the quick weapon or the slow weapon that does more damage?
Speaker 0: and they kind of got rid of?
Speaker 0: That in third edition.
Speaker 0: as a result very few weapons had really anything to make them different from other weapons.
Speaker 1: The only things that differentiate weapons in third edition are Some of the weapons can critical hit more than others but very few.
Speaker 1: Some of them have an extended range But very few.
Speaker 1: and all of the ones that are weird require you to have crazy Proficiencies.
Speaker 1: so barely anyone can use them.
Speaker 1: and the rest of them just either Ranged or not ranged and they do an amount of damage.
Speaker 1: and that's it There's.
Speaker 1: no really, you know a sword is a sword.
Speaker 1: one does slightly different damage from the other.
Speaker 0: I guess the bottom line is as far as I can tell they're not really changing anything in Dungeons & Dragons other than making it more third edition and forcing everyone to buy new books so they can make more money.
Speaker 1: because if they just sold one edition forever Eventually everyone would own the books and no one would buy it anymore because they're not trying to get more players They're just trying to sell more shit to the existing players.
Speaker 1: the same you shit.
Speaker 1: That's wrong with comic books.
Speaker 1: if
Speaker 0: you like combat in Dungeons & Dragons by fourth edition If you don't like the combat or
Speaker 1: you don't like buying more than one book
Speaker 0: or if you care about any of the things Other than combat at this time I see zero reason to buy fourth edition or to even bother considering it, you
Speaker 1: know If you buy Burning Wheel, you won't need to buy another book for the rest of your life.
Speaker 1: in terms of role-playing It's just one book though.
Speaker 0: I will point out there is another fairly significant change and I kind of like this.
Speaker 0: You know, there's the old the living Greyhawk.
Speaker 0: if you don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna bother explaining it.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 1: They're doing all this online stuff.
Speaker 0: no, not even that just living Greyhawk has been around for a long time and Greyhawk was kind of the like official generic setting for Dungeons & Dragons for god knows how long.
Speaker 0: They're dumping that because no one gives a shit about Greyhawk and no one likes it good.
Speaker 0: Finally They're making Forgotten Realms the fucking official thing.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell it's now gonna be Living Forgotten Realms and they're just dumping Greyhawk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think they're actually.
Speaker 1: they're doing a lot of online Stuff right that I've heard like they're gonna make some softwares you could play online and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: and This is good business because there's a lot of people out on the internet and around the world who want to play Tabletop role-playing games, but they can't because people who they're losers with no friends in their area who would play with them.
Speaker 0: Also, I note that I always say that third edition and I guess fourth edition combat.
Speaker 0: They basically made it like a video game.
Speaker 0: It's getting to the point where it'd be easier and more interesting if you all just sat around a computer and did your D&D Combat with the computer handling all the rules for you.
Speaker 1: I think there's gonna be a convergence between the D&D books and like the D&D games like, you know That every winter nights and the Mara wins.
Speaker 0: I think they're gonna expect people to play D&D with their friends using the online tool to handle combat or Play it with their friends around the world using an integrated talk to each other dice rolling combat.
Speaker 1: Hoping they're gonna be able to still make money from this property They own by selling software and internet services as opposed to books, which no one wants from that perspective.
Speaker 0: They're doing everything, right?
Speaker 0: They're making a system that becomes more and more tedious to use tabletop and more and more awesome to do online or with a computer.
Speaker 0: and They're catering to this really important thing of.
Speaker 0: a lot of people play a lot of D&D in high school And then they go to college and they miss their old D&D group.
Speaker 0: if they set it up where it's really easy to play D&D specifically online a lot of people are gonna use their online service to continue to play games With their old gaming groups when they move or when they get jobs and don't have time to get together for eight hours every month.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, it's great business, but It's it's not great as far as I'm concerned personally.
Speaker 0: But I'm glad that they're given Forgotten Realms the nod because I got to say the Greyhawk setting was crap.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say that straight up.
Speaker 0: It was bullshit.
Speaker 0: It was garbage.
Speaker 0: I hated it.
Speaker 0: It was just really bland and uninteresting and poorly thought-out.
Speaker 0: Forgotten Realms just for the wealth of novels and everything.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a high fantasy kind of la-di-da setting.
Speaker 0: It's really fucking fleshed out and I think it's a great place to run a Dungeons & Dragons Gaming if you're not gonna make your own campaign setting.
Speaker 1: I'm just not a real fan of any of the campaign worlds.
Speaker 0: You're not a fan of campaign settings period even if someone makes it from scratch pretty much Which I think is kind of dumb, but I'm not gonna get into that.
Speaker 0: And I thought Planescape was always kind of cool though a bit crap.
Speaker 1: Some of the ideas of the settings are okay.
Speaker 0: Just playing it never fleshed out.
Speaker 0: Well playing Planescape was always kind of eh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course granted part of that was that most of the Planescape I played was third edition and I don't like third edition.
Speaker 0: So it's tainted and Dark Sun.
Speaker 0: they just kind of abandoned.
Speaker 1: Dark Sun is the best idea.
Speaker 1: that doesn't work.
Speaker 0: and Ravenloft They just kind of abandoned which is fine because Ravenloft is a cliche boring idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah I've never played a good Ravenloft.
Speaker 1: The only good thing about in Ravenloft is Vecna and that's it.
Speaker 1: It's whatever.
Speaker 0: and then there was Dragonlance and all I want to say is fuck Dragonlance.
Speaker 0: I'm a dude who loves dragons.
Speaker 0: anything involving dragons I'm all about and I got to say Dragonlance, which is all about dragons is One of the worst things I've ever encountered and I don't limit that to D&D or role-playing or anything.
Speaker 0: I'm talking ever.
Speaker 1: I don't even know much about Dragonlance, but I know it's shit.
Speaker 1: That's how bad it is.
Speaker 1: The books are crap.
Speaker 1: I can smell it from a mile away how shitty it is.
Speaker 0: Raceland is crap, and that's all I got to say about that.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I've heard that name somewhere before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't bother looking up what it is.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Can I can I do stuff?
Speaker 0: I think you can do stuff.
Speaker 1: Okay Basically, if you haven't been paying attention It is crazy.
Speaker 1: Like we had it I was talking a week or two ago about how it's video game season.
Speaker 1: again.
Speaker 1: It is stupid video game season.
Speaker 1: It is like video game world series right now.
Speaker 1: You got your Bioshock coming.
Speaker 1: You got your Metroid 3 coming.
Speaker 1: It should be out.
Speaker 1: Everything's coming up the hell right now.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, press a press a zombies in your room.
Speaker 0: It killed your parents.
Speaker 1: his actions on fire, right?
Speaker 1: So it's come to my attention that you know a lot of people out there Unlike myself are not too familiar with the Metroid and they might have wheeze cuz a lot of wheeze out there.
Speaker 1: But you know and they this Metroid corruption is coming out and they're not quite sure what the deal is with Metroid.
Speaker 1: Luckily Nintendo is smart and they just put the original Metroid and Super Metroid on the Virtual Console.
Speaker 1: and I'm gonna tell you right now If you have never played Super Metroid and you don't want to emulate it or anything because even though you could why not?
Speaker 1: It is worth it to buy it on the Virtual Console.
Speaker 1: I never legally owned that game So I bought it on the Virtual Console for eight Wow eight dollars.
Speaker 0: I'm the dude who doesn't like Metroid games that much and I own that game Super Metroid, I'm gonna do a geek fight on this.
Speaker 1: by the way right now Is perhaps one of the best?
Speaker 1: five video games ever Period there is.
Speaker 1: there is nothing bad to say about Super Metroid.
Speaker 1: It is perfect in every way that that game could be.
Speaker 1: you couldn't do anything to the game to make it better except maybe Make it longer But even then the length feels just so right now before any you jump in and on Scott.
Speaker 0: and now the Metroid one egg was.
Speaker 0: That was the classic legendary.
Speaker 0: whatever.
Speaker 1: Metroid one is nostalgic and retro but it's not as good as game is.
Speaker 0: super Metroid one is a great game for the kind of purse like back in the day when Exploring the glitches of a video game and dealing with a Nintendo game and all that mystique Was still an issue in video games as a game.
Speaker 0: It wasn't.
Speaker 0: I mean it was a great revolutionary game But it wasn't that great because it was really fucking hard and it had some problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, super Metroid is like the sake cuz.
Speaker 1: Metroid 2 if you don't know for the game boy It was for the game boy original wasn't at all like Metroid 1.
Speaker 1: It was like you fought Metro is all the time and you know It was sort of completely different.
Speaker 1: in a way, even though it was still sort of, you know an exploring game.
Speaker 1: It was much more linear and less exciting.
Speaker 1: Super Metroid was a return to the original Metroid style of play to Planet Zeebs and In full force man.
Speaker 0: it had one of my favorite moments in video gaming.
Speaker 0: when I'm playing the first part of that game and I'm in the same world from Metroid 1
Speaker 1: you come you fly in on your ship You land on this planet you get out of your ship you go in and you go down an elevator and you're in the place Where the head boss of Metroid 1 was and it's the same room The
Speaker 0: rotted out remains of mother brain and you
Speaker 1: go you go to the next room and you go to the next room and you go.
Speaker 1: Holy shit, it's the beginning part of Metroid 1.
Speaker 1: It's the first room and it's the exact same map that it's laid out in the same way But it looks like Samus has already been through here.
Speaker 1: Just like you were already through here in Metroid 1 Everything feels like rotted and decrepit and decayed and really cool things were decrepit and decayed in.
Speaker 1: Metroid 1 feels dusty.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is that the all the organic stuff was cleaned out by Samus and you go in and it's cleaned out mostly But you know and then you go back and it's either these cameras they see you and then you have to go back after you get the ball and The space pirates come out and you're like, oh shit And that's how the game gets crazy.
Speaker 1: go nuts and all the organic stuff comes back and you're back to the Metroid business.
Speaker 1: basically this game if you like Finding secrets that are actually Secret and awesome not like finding a secret in Zelda.
Speaker 1: We're like, oh, there's a key door.
Speaker 1: I wonder where the key is and you find the key but like hey There's a wall the wall opened up sort of like it's.
Speaker 1: it's like a lot like finding secrets in Wolfenstein 3d.
Speaker 1: in a way It's sort of brute force But also sort of intuitive because you have this arsenal of items that you kind of know what they're just things like, huh?
Speaker 0: I just hiked for five minutes and now there's a dead end and some lava, huh?
Speaker 1: Or hey, that floor is cracked.
Speaker 1: you do do do do.
Speaker 1: Ah, look what's over.
Speaker 1: there is something something or Missiles, I can see something over there.
Speaker 1: There has to be a way to get that missile pack up there.
Speaker 1: I wonder how do I come into it directly?
Speaker 1: Do I come into it from the other side?
Speaker 1: and you have this arsenal of weapons bombs ball?
Speaker 1: hookshot power bombs missiles super missiles and All sorts of different beams the wave beam and stuff and you use them all together in sort of non obvious but intuitive complex ways to get to different places.
Speaker 1: and Basically, the awesome thing about Metroid games is that the game doesn't direct you.
Speaker 1: you go wherever you want to go Until you do what you have to do to get to the end part
Speaker 0: and the game will in a lot of ways let you Go places that are fucking dangerous that you shouldn't be yet
Speaker 1: and you'll just die because you don't have what you need to handle yourself There.
Speaker 1: Oh Super Metroid is so great.
Speaker 1: If you haven't played Super Metroid.
Speaker 1: You're basically not.
Speaker 1: it's like not playing Zelda 1 or not playing Mario Brothers.
Speaker 1: you if you play video games You must play it.
Speaker 1: You should play it now.
Speaker 1: Why are you listening to geek nights unless you're listening playing Metroid at the same time?
Speaker 1: Which you shouldn't because the music is awesome and you should be listening to it.
Speaker 1: Good God Metroid.
Speaker 1: and then you know if you like that you should probably get Metroid Prime and Metroid Prime 2 and Metroid Prime 3 and all the Gameboy Metroids and I can't think of a bad Metroid really.
Speaker 1: I mean some are better than others, but they're all good as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: things of the day Now.
Speaker 0: actually last night when I saw this I didn't even watch a video yet.
Speaker 0: I basically Ran into Scott's room yelling.
Speaker 0: All right, I got my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: You got to see this.
Speaker 0: Oh my god This is like.
Speaker 1: I made this my number one on dig And I made it my number one.
Speaker 1: it cuz it's that great.
Speaker 0: what this is very simply is a gentleman are our girl?
Speaker 0: I didn't actually look up who did a Japanese person, obviously.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Well, they might have just happened to have been using the Japanese ROM.
Speaker 1: No, I'm pretty sure Japanese first.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this person has modded Super Mario World.
Speaker 0: They made custom levels in Super Mario World.
Speaker 0: They didn't change anything other than making custom level.
Speaker 0: That's the Super Nintendo one where you get with Yoshi and everything and the capes Yeah, and what they did is basically make a whole bunch of Rube Goldberg machines in the game Whereby a world will start and without any control input whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Mario will make his way from the beginning to the end Without dying and not just like oh he sits on a platform the whole way.
Speaker 0: This is awesome.
Speaker 1: You just have to see it.
Speaker 1: I don't know how much I can explain it Otherwise, but if you understand Mario at all you watch this and you'll see very quickly Why I made it my number one on dig.
Speaker 1: and oh my god.
Speaker 0: when I saw this last night I was it was hip I watched I think there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there are a couple of videos where he cheats and like he holds down a button at some point or something.
Speaker 1: but other than that most of them are.
Speaker 1: And it's like you think oh, there's only so many different mechanisms.
Speaker 1: He could come up with.
Speaker 1: no He keeps coming up with new mechanisms all the time.
Speaker 1: It's like holy shit.
Speaker 1: He came up with something different.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: He gave us something different.
Speaker 0: This is real impressive.
Speaker 0: It's impressive one because it's really cool what he sets up.
Speaker 0: It's impressive too because it shows you the Tolerances and the precision that is in that game Super Mario World because he sets these things up extremely precisely.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what makes you know That's it.
Speaker 1: Basically, I think the thing that with this video does for you is if you don't understand why some platform game and flash is kind Crappy and why Mario is awesome when on the surface.
Speaker 1: They both look like platform games.
Speaker 1: This will show you the reason that Mario games in particular are so far above and beyond other Jumping platform games.
Speaker 1: It's just the way the system the game works.
Speaker 1: It's just so far above and beyond what anyone else has tried to do.
Speaker 0: and three The idea the sheer idea of it of all right.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make a Rube Goldberg machine and Pre-existing video game.
Speaker 0: that's hot.
Speaker 0: that idea is solid platinum.
Speaker 1: Someone's got to try to do this with some other games.
Speaker 0: No Not only that the only thing I want to see because at first when I saw this I thought he set him up in The game without doing anything like in levels that existed.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's crazy.
Speaker 1: That's crazy.
Speaker 0: But then I watched the first one and I'm like, I don't remember that level.
Speaker 0: Oh But that does not diminish the awesomeness of.
Speaker 0: no it doesn't at all because what I'm asking for may be impossible.
Speaker 1: It's impossible.
Speaker 0: There might be some crazy game.
Speaker 1: Maybe some physics game Perhaps but not in Mario.
Speaker 0: But anyway, this is pretty badass and that's all I have to say.
Speaker 0: It's super badass.
Speaker 0: Check it out.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day is a Skit from Saturday Night Live.
Speaker 1: Let's not talk about Saturday Night Live for like 20 minutes here.
Speaker 0: No, no Let's just skip that.
Speaker 0: We'll probably do a show about it someday.
Speaker 1: Even though I didn't watch it that much in my life I watched a lot.
Speaker 0: I've seen like four different.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I said we're not gonna do this.
Speaker 1: So this sketch is a funny sketch called the first person in the world to ever dance ever so.
Speaker 1: obviously it cuts to two cavemen and you know that one of the cavemen is gonna dance at least.
Speaker 1: and Let me just say this is funny because they bring in an anachronism and you go Oh, man The anachronism.
Speaker 1: and then the dancing itself is funny and then there's another anachronism and that's the win To me.
Speaker 0: what did it?
Speaker 0: for me is that it's kind of like when I used to live with two cats in Poughkeepsie on the top of a mountain and I had a laser pen.
Speaker 0: and you know cat plus laser pen is like better than a DS.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So two DS's.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it was But one of the cats could see the laser pen dot and one of them could not.
Speaker 0: The cat wasn't blind.
Speaker 0: It just could not see the laser pen dot and never reacted to it.
Speaker 1: Maybe it just didn't care.
Speaker 0: The thing is it reacted to flashlights and all sorts of other things and it reacted to a green laser pen Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so whenever I'd play with the laser pen, the one cat would be like, oh my god There's not.
Speaker 0: I go get it.
Speaker 0: Oh my god It's a dot.
Speaker 0: I gotta go get it and the other cat would just stare at that cat Like what the fuck is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: What are you doing?
Speaker 0: and the cat would always kind of walk over and like paw at the cat like stop it You're weirding me out just stop it.
Speaker 0: and that is exactly what the caveman's companion is doing to him while he's dancing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what he's doing right there because obviously the one caveman does not does not hear the music.
Speaker 1: I think what also makes this funny is how the a lot of people in this world they feel awkward dancing, especially when other people are not dancing and this sort of Takes a modern-day feeling and puts it in a caveman setting which is very entertaining.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also kind of this inspirational message of if you hear music Metaphorically or not dance to it regardless of whether a caveman is throwing sticks at your feet or it's just funny.
Speaker 1: Cuz this is that an in live sketch.
Speaker 0: Yeah well Just this is one of those few SNL sketches that was just so perfect because the music starts coming in and I'm not gonna say What song it is, but it's the perfect song for this sketch.
Speaker 1: I'm sure half our listeners can actually name the song and half can't because I know the name of the song and rim doesn't.
Speaker 0: I Didn't actually know the name of the song, but I knew who did it.
Speaker 1: You didn't pronounce it correctly.
Speaker 0: A lot of people don't I know mostly because people have mp3 files that don't give you the accent on the last letter.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure I didn't realize there was an accent there until just now.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the look on the caveman who dances face when the music starts coming in and he realizes It's kind of like when the monkey in 2001 picks up that thing and realizes that he can hit other monkeys with it.
Speaker 0: Mmm It was that kind of moment.
Speaker 0: But anyway, speaking of cavemen tonight we're gonna talk about the ancient Greeks because we have played a game that is basically a Perfect simulation of life in ancient ancient ancient Mediterranean cultures.
Speaker 1: Well, the game isn't.
Speaker 1: I was being funny Yes, but the game isn't specifically Greek, but it is.
Speaker 1: it is There's.
Speaker 1: no it's not a specifically Greek themed game, but it kind of fits the gameplay.
Speaker 0: It is very much early.
Speaker 0: early like Bronze Age if not earlier.
Speaker 1: Mediterranean culture like all the way up until airplanes like I might even say pre-dorian invasion Greeks Yep, all the way up until airplanes and trains and all that other kind of.
Speaker 0: but it doesn't really.
Speaker 1: it doesn't really but that on The board there's a picture of an airplane at the end of the game.
Speaker 0: now when I say that this is a perfect simulation of Life back then I'm gonna sum the game.
Speaker 0: The game is called tempus or temp this if you want to be funny because they write that you like a V and it's all Stylized.
Speaker 0: Yep tempus if The game is basically you control a culture and your options throughout time in this culture are Sit around and think you know think about things.
Speaker 0: Yep make babies Yep, send those babies off to die in war Move around.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah move the babies around usually with the objective.
Speaker 0: You can move around with or without war Yeah, but you're gonna have some war eventually and you can build cities.
Speaker 0: You can try to build cities But mostly you're gonna spend your time making babies moving them around and making babies moving babies making babies moving thinking about stuff Thinking think make move think make move.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the way the game works, it's kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: The first awesome thing in the game is the map because the map you get to make the map which is super fun.
Speaker 0: Yes, there's a system where you have a bunch of these hexes and there's big blob.
Speaker 0: There are a lot like the pieces in Attica Yeah, and then there's big blobs of hexes and you go around and take churches putting them out there.
Speaker 1: So someone the first person puts out the first map tile and the second person puts at the second map tile.
Speaker 1: so it's sort of like a Strategy of.
Speaker 1: I want to make it so that there's a good spot on the board for me and not good spots on the board For the other people, but if you're like going third you want to make sure there's gonna be three good spots.
Speaker 1: That way you get a good spot no matter what.
Speaker 0: the rules for placement are really really minimal and you can do a lot.
Speaker 0: You're just constrained by the board.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I just got a point out that in our group the front row crew We have never played this game like the first time we played.
Speaker 0: of course the absolute Most crazy least likely most broken map is what we made every time.
Speaker 1: Yeah basically We try to make the silliest most Far out map instead of making a normal map where we just kind of put the tiles together nicely made for some interesting games.
Speaker 1: Did they also sort of made for some broken games?
Speaker 1: if if the map is made in a certain way Then you the person who gets to go and put their guys in the board first could have a huge advantage.
Speaker 1: You know, for example the first time we ever played I wasn't really thinking about the initial placement not thinking it was so important.
Speaker 1: It's stupidly important.
Speaker 0: I went first.
Speaker 0: He's like, this is the best spot and it wasn't.
Speaker 1: it was shit.
Speaker 0: well, it was the best spot.
Speaker 1: if no one else was playing I Guess but basically what happened was because the way the map was I'd never played before and they had.
Speaker 1: They just cut off huge sections of the board for themselves and I was stuck sort of in the middle Not being able to get around so much.
Speaker 0: it was great Make enough babies just got kind of goes raw and tries to bust through my lines and fails and then he goes And tries to bust through Alex's lines.
Speaker 0: But by then Alex has built up and Scott was weakened from fighting with me and it failed.
Speaker 1: That was the end.
Speaker 1: I learned my lesson in the future games.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: The game is really fun.
Speaker 0: I'll say right now I don't think it's a very enduring game in terms of being very indicative of these relative skills of players because the game in the end is Gonna come down to a lot of randomness, but it speaks Well of the game that I really really enjoy playing it Even though I feel like there's a lot of randomness that I can't do a lot about.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's definitely a good game.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say it's like some great amazing game.
Speaker 1: I do enjoy playing it depending on the mood, you know It's like.
Speaker 1: sometimes they'll be like I don't want to play tempest, but sometimes it's like yeah, let's play tempest.
Speaker 0: All right tempest is really the middle ground between for us at least a light game and a heavy game because It has a lot of the elements of a heavy game in all the decision-making.
Speaker 0: you have a lot of options There's a lot of rounds but at the same time it's a light game because while you have a lot of options a lot of decisions to make the Conflict resolution system and the results of the decisions you make are extremely straightforward and extremely simple to calculate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically the game was billed originally as being like hey a civilization game That is very.
Speaker 1: that doesn't take so long, you know, and everyone loves civilization games.
Speaker 1: So one that doesn't take so long is like holy shit.
Speaker 1: The civilization games usually take like five hours.
Speaker 1: if there's one that takes like less than two hours That's amazing and this does.
Speaker 1: it is a civilization game that takes less than two hours and in that it is awesome.
Speaker 1: However, when you make a civilization game that only takes two hours something has to be cut back.
Speaker 1: So it does not contain everything that a full-on Civilization game has and thus is missing.
Speaker 1: it feels like it is missing something that the full civilization games do have.
Speaker 0: So the basic gist of this game is that you know, there's the territory little hexes with a little You know different kinds of land like forests and agriculture and mountains or whatever and you start with some little discs which are your guys and you put them out there and every turn Every player gets a number of actions and you go around just clockwise.
Speaker 0: So I take my first action.
Speaker 0: Scott takes his first action Alex takes his first action Emily takes her first action I take my second action and we keep going around.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: the tricky thing is there are ways where sometimes People will have more actions than other people.
Speaker 1: dumb dumb dumb, that's how you win.
Speaker 1: I always try to get as many actions as I can because Even if I do things less efficiently than other people if I do more things Period when the game by the time the game is done.
Speaker 1: I'm probably gonna win.
Speaker 0: now the actions you can take our thing.
Speaker 0: They're very very very simple and they come down to things like have ideas which is draw some cards and keep them in your hand or Make babies.
Speaker 0: put more guys out there but you can only do that on certain types of terrain and there's limits on how many guys you can put out or Move guys.
Speaker 0: the slow laborious and terrible process of moving guys hex by hex around the map.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it sucks moving guys or wage war and I love this.
Speaker 0: the conflict resolution I mean remember.
Speaker 0: earlier I said that this game kind of fills this niche for us of.
Speaker 0: we like the really hardcore games But not when we're really tired and we like to really like games sometimes and but not when we're all awake.
Speaker 0: Tempest is like the perfect middle-ground game because it has all the decision-making and all the feel of a hardcore game But the decisions you make are simple and the conflicts arising from them are resolved Very very in a very straightforward and easy manner.
Speaker 0: and that's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whoever has more guys wins, but you can use cards to help you end of story.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you can move guys around and it comes down to you have to decide what you want and spend your actions as efficiently As you can to get it all the while taking risks.
Speaker 0: things like alright I can move in next to Alex and grab some of his territory early But he might just attack me and if he has good cards, I'm fucked.
Speaker 0: I gotta take that chance though It's too good to pass up.
Speaker 1: Yeah Generally a lot of the feeling I get when I play the game is I want to do something But I don't want to.
Speaker 1: you know It'll take maybe more than one action to get it done usually when moving guys because as rim said Moving guys is very slow.
Speaker 1: So I'll move some guys am I?
Speaker 1: I'll have an end goal in mind of where I want the guys to be But the intermediate states because it's gonna take like two or three move actions
Speaker 0: And you only get like if you only get four actions in a turn and it takes you three Actions just to set up the thing you wanted to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but so I'm gonna spend a bunch of actions to make this thing happen that I want to happen.
Speaker 1: but all the intermediate states I'm vulnerable.
Speaker 1: So I got to figure out either a way to not be vulnerable or a different goal or something So that I don't take the chance of someone else just ruining what I'm doing in the middle of it for ruining like You know my whole turn and screwing up my whole game
Speaker 0: now on one
Speaker 1: hand that
Speaker 0: it kind of has this age of steam feel I'll get to that in a second in that the game.
Speaker 0: you can get so little accomplished with each action that it feels like just This war against the game.
Speaker 0: to get anything done.
Speaker 0: you want to get that land.
Speaker 0: That's in the next hex over.
Speaker 0: You got to make a baby and move and move and move and then make another baby and move and it's gonna take you multiple turns to do it, but Everyone has the exact same limitations like everyone has to deal with the same crap.
Speaker 0: So while I feel like ah, I gotta waste four actions to get over there.
Speaker 0: Well, ah Scott has to waste four actions to do the thing He's trying to do.
Speaker 1: I kind of like this because when I'm when I play civilization, too I'm the kind of person who likes to not talk to the other civilizations or meet them for a long time.
Speaker 1: I just send out a bunch of settlers without worrying about it and build a nice big Empire and build a bunch of stuff and Then interact with the other people.
Speaker 1: so when you play a game like this and everyone is forced to go really slowly Even on a cramped board you sort of get to do some business before you have to worry about the other people Which is which is nice because it's like ah, I'm not suddenly attacked by a giant monster before I set up my stuff.
Speaker 0: Hooray, no, I said combat is really straightforward.
Speaker 0: It really just comes down to you don't want to.
Speaker 0: it's not a game like conquer everyone.
Speaker 0: combat is quick brutal and dangerous.
Speaker 0: You could lose a lot of babies and all it is is if you have a stack of guys and you want to attack another Stack of guys or a city whoever has the most guys wins and that's it.
Speaker 0: And the only way to augment that is.
Speaker 0: we say, you know There's cards.
Speaker 0: when you have ideas you draw cards and you keep the card secret.
Speaker 0: cards serve two purposes.
Speaker 0: on one hand all the cards will match different terrain out there and in general in combat or in Innovation which we'll talk about last because that's the coolest part.
Speaker 1: That's what makes the game awesome.
Speaker 0: one card no matter what it says counts for one thing if it matches the territory.
Speaker 0: That's relevant at the time.
Speaker 0: So if I'm attacking a Plains all my Plains cards I can play to add plus one to my stack.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's sort of random because when you have ideas you just get cards and you have no idea what they're gonna be.
Speaker 1: So you sort of in one hand you have to play on the board and then get enough ideas So that you have cards that will help you do what you want to do.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand you can have ideas and then sort of change your plan so that you can use your ideas To get the most effect on the board.
Speaker 1: Maybe there was a one strategy that be the best but all your ideas are for a different kind of terrain and they one Of them lets you do something special.
Speaker 1: So you go and do something else instead.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now at the same time the cards have this other purpose and that you can play them during your turn to do stuff.
Speaker 0: So in addition to just using them in combat instead there's cards that give you like a super bonus to defend.
Speaker 1: So you'll see sitting there with like a card and the card might say something like I don't know The religion one which lets you steal a guy from someone else All right But it's a forest and someone's attacking you in a forest.
Speaker 1: so you can either save this for later to religion someone which is awesome or Add one defense right now and it's like ah, I can't do both But sometimes you can do both like let's say you have a card that says add two to defense and it's a plains and you're Defending on a plains.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: It adds three to defense on the plains.
Speaker 0: So the part of the game that I really want to talk about because this is what makes this
Speaker 1: is what makes the game Awesome
Speaker 0: There is this innovation track because the game there's a track that everyone will go down from the top to the bottom and it lists All the limitations and abilities of all the players.
Speaker 0: So like the number of cards you get when you take ideas the number of babies you get when you do baby, right?
Speaker 1: So at the very beginning of the game, right if you make babies you make like one baby And if you have ideas you get one idea.
Speaker 1: and if you move guys You can move like one guy one space.
Speaker 1: All right, and that's it.
Speaker 1: The technology is caveman technology.
Speaker 1: You can't do a lot There's very little your guys can do.
Speaker 1: at the end of the game if you choose the action of say move people You can move like three guys five up to five spaces each.
Speaker 1: You can make three babies.
Speaker 1: You can have three ideas.
Speaker 0: I think you can only ever make two babies.
Speaker 1: two babies, but you a lot more than one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they all these attributes go up in the tech tree.
Speaker 1: So the higher technology you have when you spend an action the more you can do with one action.
Speaker 0: now The really cool thing about the tech tree is that there can be Disparities in tech because the way it works is the tree goes down and every step of the way Has a kind of terrain next to it.
Speaker 0: and at the end of every set of turns before we do the next set We innovate we go to each player clockwise and we count how many?
Speaker 0: Tiles or how many hexes of the terrain that the next advancement requires.
Speaker 1: a let I have right?
Speaker 1: so let's say the next advancement is is trains which lets you move a lot of guys, right and We look at it and we say okay.
Speaker 1: It's forests who has the most forest?
Speaker 0: So we look at me and I have three forests and I have four Forests and Alex has one forest and two cities because cities count as anything.
Speaker 1: Yep So it's four three and three, but I have no cards.
Speaker 0: now see that's the other thing.
Speaker 0: I said you can play cards in combat.
Speaker 0: You can also play cards and innovating and The way it works and in combat is the same way.
Speaker 0: This is another one of the cool things that makes this game.
Speaker 0: when you play cards You declare how many you're playing and you don't show them.
Speaker 0: so in the innovating part, let's say it's come to know.
Speaker 0: we all look at the board and Scott has three forests and I have four.
Speaker 0: I have three cards in my hand and Scott doesn't know what they are.
Speaker 0: I Have what four cities or four points toward innovation and I have played two cards which could be like anywhere from zero to four point.
Speaker 0: because there's no guarantee What card I played.
Speaker 0: I can play a totally irrelevant card.
Speaker 1: I lose the card, but I can bluff Yep, and then it's up to me to decide.
Speaker 1: Well, do I think he's bluffing?
Speaker 1: Am I gonna spend cards that might not do anything at all for me?
Speaker 1: What am I gonna do here?
Speaker 1: and then whoever has the most and if there's a tie it doesn't matter you both win Gets to advance on the track.
Speaker 0: So but you can only have a disparity of one at every given time.
Speaker 1: Yes so what happens basically is every time Everyone goes up to the highest level that you're at currently and then whoever has the most jumps forward.
Speaker 1: So you people are either gonna be at the default level or one step up and there's no way to be one step up The entire game unless everyone else sucks.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much set up to where You're gonna have to look at the track and look at where you started and look at your cards.
Speaker 0: And like a really good strategy is to forego a couple of advancements to get the big one.
Speaker 1: You really wanted Yep, so like I'll wait and I'll know.
Speaker 1: Alright, if I get if I advance now, I will get one more action than everyone else in the game.
Speaker 1: So that's way more important to me than that other advancement which would have.
Speaker 1: let me have one more baby.
Speaker 0: now advancement happens No matter what the game.
Speaker 0: every round everyone advances.
Speaker 0: The question is just some people advance more.
Speaker 0: that round like everyone catches up.
Speaker 0: So that's how the game ends.
Speaker 0: you follow the tech tree to the end and then the game's over.
Speaker 1: But some people they figure out airplanes and some people don't.
Speaker 0: well airplanes.
Speaker 0: at the end is just there's one final tech advance.
Speaker 0: Whoever wins the last innovation gets three victory points, which is big.
Speaker 1: that's made the difference before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it has.
Speaker 1: I would have won except on time.
Speaker 1: Alex got the airplanes and I lost the game.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else I could really say about it.
Speaker 0: It's just it's really fun.
Speaker 0: It seems to kind of play out in three stages.
Speaker 0: We're in the first part of the game is like posturing and you set up and you decide what you're gonna do and yay.
Speaker 0: And then the second part of the game is the borders kind of stabilize as everyone gets out to the limits of their influence and power.
Speaker 0: and then there's the jockeying for control.
Speaker 0: and then the third phase of the game is Balls out.
Speaker 0: everyone takes out the crazy strategy that they've been trying to secretly put together through the first two stages.
Speaker 1: Yeah I noticed it being a little different than that.
Speaker 1: I've noticed it being the first part everyone sort of gets ready and the second part everyone executes their crazy strategy.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: third part people just try to scrape up all the remaining points in the second part.
Speaker 0: It's not like the crazy hidden strategy It's just alright.
Speaker 0: I have now come into contact with Alex's civilization and Scott's civilization and the whole second part of the game is Dealing with that trying to move your guys around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what the Last part is.
Speaker 1: just there's only like ten points available left on the board.
Speaker 1: scrape them up if you can.
Speaker 0: The third part of the game is where maybe I should have been more clear.
Speaker 0: The second part of the game is the standard fighting against other players moving around strategies.
Speaker 0: But it seems like the third part of the game is when everyone has at least one.
Speaker 0: Alright, I got this crazy idea.
Speaker 0: Well, if I pull it off I'm gonna bust up.
Speaker 1: eventually happens is after everyone scrapes up the remaining points on the board There's still a little bit of game left and you you there's ways in which you can take big risks For possible reward because there's no other rewards to get.
Speaker 1: there's only so many rewards left.
Speaker 1: So people are willing to sacrifice things to get those rewards because you're not gonna use those resources anywhere else.
Speaker 1: Where are you gonna use them?
Speaker 1: There's no other place to go.
Speaker 0: Now this game.
Speaker 0: I mentioned before that the game feels like it's constantly holding you back a lot like age of steam.
Speaker 0: Well, this game was designed by a man named Martin Wallace who is responsible for such games as age of steam Just team third edition age of steam expansion
Speaker 1: Railroad
Speaker 0: tycoon and I'm curious about this game called age of arguments, but I
Speaker 1: Gotta buy that game just for the game.
Speaker 0: Oh, it looks super ghetto.
Speaker 0: Oh, it is super ghetto.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: I might have this is this ghetto is thing I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: It's kind of cute.
Speaker 1: Oh my Anyway tempest is.
Speaker 0: it's not the greatest game ever, but it's a pretty good game, especially if you like to make babies and Sit around and have ideas and throw babies at walls of death as you try to take over cities and fail.
Speaker 1: yeah, if you like civilization games, but you don't want to spend many hours and you're willing to sacrifice the folks, you know, the Complete fullness of a full-on civilization.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: I'll go one step further.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend this game to anyone who has played all the beginner basic intro level German board games and you want a game that'll kind of Bring you into the more complex games without hitting you over the head immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this game definitely does that that's for sure.
Speaker 0: This is a good transition between the carcass owns and the settlers.
Speaker 1: It puts on a friendly face, but there's more to it than that, but not so much that it'll scare you.
Speaker 0: It's not the Tigers and Euphrates in the Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: No It's not.
Speaker 0: but it'll prepare you for those games kind of in the sense that you'll get used to the mechanics.
Speaker 0: You got to play pretty much one of these games and then one of those wooden cube games and then you're ready.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this will help you out with sort of the the action mechanic, which is prevalent in a lot of games like to call and such.
Speaker 0: Alright, I think that's the end of that.
Speaker 0: there may or may not be a show tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Most likely there will.
Speaker 0: it's probably going to Be something special.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it all depends on if my dad suddenly flies into New York City tomorrow Depends on my work and their party.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much it's either gonna be no show or me and Emily you're gonna do a show where you do show on.
Speaker 0: We got some ideas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll do it.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll be back.
Speaker 1: You know, just late.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: It doesn't affect us.
Speaker 0: We'll do the show early.
Speaker 0: Like we always do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: All right We actually did the show late tonight.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to sleep.
Speaker 1: I gotta go try my laundry and go to sleep.
Speaker 0: awesome sauce.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at Frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.