Speaker 1: It's Thursday April 26th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is big knives.
Speaker 1: tonight Thursday we totally cop out.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So probably for the past.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: let me do some math here.
Speaker 0: 20 for 19 years of my life I've carried around stuff with me.
Speaker 0: where I went.
Speaker 0: you know if I went places I needed to bring shit with me, and I brought that shit in a bag specific style of bag.
Speaker 0: the backpack.
Speaker 1: see I had one backpack the exact same backpack up until halfway through high school where For various our reasons an apple ended up sitting in the outside pouch until it became powder.
Speaker 1: Okay, well it was in there, and I thought and I kept forgetting about it.
Speaker 1: and finally I open it one day, and there's this rotten apple, and it's all there.
Speaker 1: I didn't want it didn't want it didn't want to deal with it.
Speaker 1: I just closed it and Every day that went by it was one day worse to actually deal with it.
Speaker 1: So I never dealt with it, and it turned to dust yeah, and then the backpack was okay.
Speaker 0: It added water and drank it.
Speaker 0: it tastes like apple juice.
Speaker 1: That's a great idea alright.
Speaker 0: So anyway when I was a kid you know I had probably some cartoon characters.
Speaker 0: I don't remember what kind of backpack I had until eventually I got a blue LL bean backpack and I replaced that like four or five years ago with a black LL bean backpack.
Speaker 1: I had a black backpack.
Speaker 1: I don't know who made it.
Speaker 1: well eventually the apple dust and other incidents forced me to buy a new backpack Which I then used until today, and I still use.
Speaker 0: yeah, they I still have the black one by the way, but yeah LL bean is pretty cool because if you get a backpack from them It's got this lifetime warranty.
Speaker 0: so if anything happens to it You just say hey give me a new one and they give you a new one when you send them back the old one It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: You know theoretically.
Speaker 1: I still have the lifetime warranty on that bike that I just got repaired.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, the thing is the warranty only applies to the lifetime parts Which if I read it closely is only the frame and nothing else and every single other component has been replaced.
Speaker 0: pretty much every Bike has the same kind of deal where the frames have super warranties and the other parts don't anyway.
Speaker 0: So I got this laptop recently.
Speaker 0: we talked about it before.
Speaker 0: It's really small and I wanted to carry it around and just dumping it in my backpack was not working so well.
Speaker 0: But I didn't really want to buy a new bag.
Speaker 0: because well my backpack didn't feel very old I mean it's still in great condition, but I realized hey this thing's like five or six years old.
Speaker 0: I can totally replace it without worrying about it.
Speaker 0: Why shouldn't I replace it?
Speaker 0: so I did.
Speaker 0: so I went around.
Speaker 0: I tried to find a bag.
Speaker 0: you know not necessarily a backpack, but a bag.
Speaker 0: You know the site the messenger bags that are all hip and in cool in the style That would hold a ten point six inch widescreen laptop.
Speaker 1: Yes, also not a crappy one because I did buy a messenger bag a little while ago from an outlet store and One of the straps broke immediately.
Speaker 0: Wow Immediately that sucks, so I went looking around.
Speaker 0: I went to a store in the city that sells just bags and nothing else and Basically I could find plenty where that were close.
Speaker 0: But none of them would hold this tiny laptop and efficiently and hold all my other stuff efficiently.
Speaker 0: And it just wasn't gonna work out buying a laptop bag, so I said to myself.
Speaker 0: I know what to do.
Speaker 0: I'll get a laptop sleeve to protect the laptop and then just a normal bag.
Speaker 0: I could just dump the sleeve into it.
Speaker 0: the problem of course was it was just as hard to find a ten point six inch Laptop sleeve as it was to find a bag that supported ten point six inch laptops.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised he didn't go with the classic bindle.
Speaker 0: the bindle the bindle Oh, you mean the the hanky on a stick hanky on a stick hanky on a stick is not going to work for a $2,000 laptop.
Speaker 1: if you get a good hanky and a good stick Maybe there's a market for upscale landle laptop bindles.
Speaker 1: You know you get a nice to titanium alloy stick a geek bindle.
Speaker 0: calm Yeah, it could work.
Speaker 1: same kind of people who buy you till a kilts and all that'll probably buy a geek bindle.
Speaker 0: Oh that that sounds like a good idea to me.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should go for it anyway.
Speaker 0: I finally found a laptop sleeve And it's such a good laptop sleeve that I'm going to recommend it to you.
Speaker 0: if you're in the market for a sleeve of some Sort to protect your laptop especially if your laptop is some weird size.
Speaker 0: But also if your laptop is a normal size you should go to the website Shinza.com Shinza.com and I'll probably link to this and they sell these zero shock 3 Laptop sleeve and all sorts of sizes including 11 inches which is perfect.
Speaker 0: It's like 30 something bucks, and it super protects your laptop on all sides.
Speaker 0: It's got this nice zipper, and it's made out of this foamy stuff, and it's great.
Speaker 0: So I got me one of those.
Speaker 0: But then I needed a bag and I went looking around at bags, and you know there are some bags that were okay.
Speaker 0: You know there's like.
Speaker 0: there's a urban Manhattan something brand that is like made in the city or something.
Speaker 0: And there's some other brands that were looking okay like the targets and the whatever's But nothing was really like you know standing out to me because I don't want to have the same bag as like every other Shmuck on the street, so I finally found the answer.
Speaker 0: you might have seen people around who have messenger bags that have a swirly on them.
Speaker 0: I've seen them around rim.
Speaker 0: you ever seen them around?
Speaker 1: see I never had until you pointed it out And now I notice a few of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see like I would see them around from time to time And I you know it never even occurred to me that the swirly was a brand or anything.
Speaker 0: It's just like I would see messenger bags with swirlies?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I guess I don't spend my time walking around Manhattan and looking at other men's bags.
Speaker 0: I look at all kinds of stuff while I'm standing.
Speaker 0: Anyway that swirly is the brand logo of a company called Timbuktu T-I-M-B-U-K the number two.
Speaker 0: not to be confused with the mediocre board game by the same name No, and not to be confused with the place in geography, and they make all sorts of crazy bags.
Speaker 1: I like you say the place in geography like it's not a real place, but just a thing you learn about in school.
Speaker 0: Well, have you ever been there?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Do you know anyone has been there?
Speaker 0: Possibly so.
Speaker 0: it's essentially equivalent to North Dakota except.
Speaker 1: I know someone who lived in North Dakota lived.
Speaker 0: They say yeah, and on the conspiracy ha ha I see.
Speaker 0: so Timbuktu sells all kinds of cool bags.
Speaker 0: But what's especially cool is that if you want a messenger bag?
Speaker 0: You know the kind that's all hip it in style.
Speaker 0: you can customize it at their website.
Speaker 0: It can get pretty expensive But it's worth it if you actually are willing to pay to get exactly what you want.
Speaker 1: the bag I gotta say that you got is pretty nice.
Speaker 0: It's real nice.
Speaker 0: It's made in San Francisco I assume by a combination of hand and machine and you can customize all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: you see all their bags Have the same design of three panels of material so it's like three stripes And you can choose the color of each stripe, so you can get one.
Speaker 0: That's like you know black purple red or Green yellow green.
Speaker 0: again, I got gray black gray because Everything I'm getting lately seems to be black and silver and such.
Speaker 0: so I wanted to make everything match.
Speaker 0: And then you can choose the color of the swirly and you can choose what kind of straps you want.
Speaker 0: And you can choose what you want on the inside whether you want one compartment or two it can.
Speaker 0: you can choose to have a handle or not and you can choose all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: and I bought this bag and It was kind of annoying because you know I wasn't too sure spending like a hundred bucks on a bag.
Speaker 0: You know I might not like the bag.
Speaker 0: What am I gonna do?
Speaker 0: and since it's a custom bag.
Speaker 0: It's non returnable So it's very.
Speaker 0: I was very cautious, and then the bag showed up, and I got the bag and let me tell you It's a good bag.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, man I think the moral and this seems to be the moral in almost every situation you can ever come across in your entire life Is that in almost any time where you have a problem money is always the answer.
Speaker 1: Money will solve your problems for you.
Speaker 0: I think the other moral is if you have the choice between buying a mainstream mass manufactured product that's just the same thing a thousand times or Customizing something to your personal needs.
Speaker 0: if you can afford to customize something to your personal needs You'll probably be much happier doing so.
Speaker 1: yes It's just.
Speaker 1: it's like you had.
Speaker 1: it costs X dollars more to get the.
Speaker 0: To get the same bag as me at that bag store in the city was like 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: I basically paid twice as much in order to get exactly what I wanted.
Speaker 1: That's really not that much money though at all.
Speaker 0: Considering this bag is probably gonna be my primary bag of bags for carrying shit around for I don't know at least five years I think that's worth $100.
Speaker 1: consider that there was this messenger bag that was made out of leather for sale at some fair.
Speaker 1: I was walking by in the city, and it was $300.
Speaker 0: whoa Who the hell would buy that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: the thing is I'm walking around the city with my cool bag.
Speaker 0: That's got all sorts of compartments, and it holds stuff real efficiently, and it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And I see all these other people walking out with their doofy bags And I'm like hey, I gotta admit my bags pretty doofy, and I hate it.
Speaker 1: I hate it hate it hate it.
Speaker 1: My backpacks okay, except.
Speaker 1: It's kind of broken.
Speaker 0: my backpack still okay It's just.
Speaker 0: I got this laptop now So I'm not gonna carry.
Speaker 0: I was definitely not gonna carry a separate laptop bag and the backpack.
Speaker 0: that wasn't gonna happen.
Speaker 1: But that messenger bag I got now is just not doing it.
Speaker 1: riding my bike with that thing is like the worst experience ever.
Speaker 0: actually the Timbuktu bag has this Additional feature that it's pretty much.
Speaker 0: It's not an additional feature It's a standard feature.
Speaker 0: it has this cross strap.
Speaker 0: you attach to one of these little rings And you can you know pull it really tight onto your body And it's meant to be ridden Worn while riding the bike.
Speaker 1: now one thing I find interesting a bag like this Would never have been necessary or even an idea.
Speaker 1: I would have thought of in most of my life.
Speaker 1: It's only that I live here in New York where I often end up taking trains around in mass transit And I'm usually very far away from my car as opposed to the rest of my life Where no matter where I was my car was always there, so I kept anything I needed in my trunk.
Speaker 1: I have to be more and more able to carry things.
Speaker 1: I need on me on my person at all times, so Basically and Scott's the same way we need purses now as opposed to just cars.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean it used to be that I would just carry a wallet wherever I went and maybe a key.
Speaker 0: yeah And a cell phone was added and then a laptop was Ed.
Speaker 1: once I hit the once I got a trench coat and I became One of those guys who wears the trench coat.
Speaker 1: way back in high school I started carrying everything I needed in the trench coat which was great in the winter And really sucked in the summer because I didn't have anywhere to put all that stuff.
Speaker 0: actually before the laptop was added the iPod was added and the digital camera was a. And you know the train ticket, and it just gets out of control.
Speaker 0: you need a murse.
Speaker 1: Well it helped that when I was a kid I didn't need to carry around.
Speaker 1: you know a bunch of credit cards and a bunch of health insurance cards and my metro card And my train tickets and my work ID and all the IDs for the other jobs.
Speaker 0: And a DS needs to be carried around - oh yeah, I can't everywhere I go which is probably why I broke my first DS and DS games and It's just too much stuff.
Speaker 0: and this bag.
Speaker 0: it does the trick.
Speaker 0: so if you are someone who needs a bag to carry your shit around with and You got some money to spend Tim buk - calm it's.
Speaker 0: if the bag is made in San Francisco 100% It's a little bit expensive But you can customize it to be exactly right for your lifestyle.
Speaker 1: It gives me the same feeling that that Jimmy wallet gives me.
Speaker 1: it does give me domestically produced by non slave labor Company seems pretty cool.
Speaker 1: They make a great product, and it's the exact right price.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It's not the exact right price.
Speaker 0: I would have much rather paid the $50 I mean if this thing had anything disappointing about it.
Speaker 0: I would have been very upset because like it was non returnable Yeah, but they do guarantee the quality.
Speaker 0: so like if it was broken like say the strap was ripped in half when it came They would have fixed that for me.
Speaker 1: I'm probably gonna get a similar bag once I get a laptop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing was is these are the only people actually who would sell a size of the bag small enough like that was.
Speaker 0: my Goal was to get the smallest bag possible.
Speaker 0: that would still hold on my shit.
Speaker 0: It's like the medium sized bag that they make is way big.
Speaker 0: It's like 18 point 75 inches.
Speaker 0: see my problem.
Speaker 1: I usually carry a pair of clothes with me.
Speaker 1: now because I take I bike to work.
Speaker 1: Well, I bike to the train station, and then I change at work.
Speaker 1: There's a shower and everything there.
Speaker 1: Cuz I forgot woke up late one day, and I just put on my normal business clothes And I went to work and no big deal.
Speaker 1: I'm riding my bike ride my bike and Maybe it's just cuz.
Speaker 1: I haven't ridden my bike a lot since it was broken now.
Speaker 1: It's finally repaired.
Speaker 1: I forgot that riding any bike will basically tattoo the inside of your right leg with grease.
Speaker 0: That's what it does.
Speaker 1: so I tattooed and tore one of my dress parents.
Speaker 0: That's what happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's happened to me quite a few times.
Speaker 1: Yeah granted when I was a kid I pretty much had a permanent grease slash scar stain on the inside of my.
Speaker 0: that's why they make those little strings that you can Like tie your pants.
Speaker 0: You know I'm talking about on my leg But I'm saying you know for the the torn dress pants.
Speaker 0: They make the little string you can tie your pants close to your legs.
Speaker 1: Yeah I much prefer just putting on shorts riding to work wearing shorts on the train getting to work put my stupid business pants on taking Them off at 4 getting back on the train.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right you keep doing that yeah, but yeah They make bags ranging from extra small to extra large, and I got enough about the bed.
Speaker 1: We talked for like 13 and a half minutes about your stupid bag.
Speaker 0: I know cuz it's such a great bag I can't stop talking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to talk about something more important.
Speaker 1: all right build my new computer, right?
Speaker 1: The forums and found the perfect motherboard.
Speaker 1: everything was set.
Speaker 1: I was gonna come home today Cuz I can't get to Newegg from work.
Speaker 1: click buy and just wait for my new computer to come.
Speaker 1: but today Mana that clock never rings.
Speaker 0: So I almost rang.
Speaker 1: almost so I'm poking around on the Ubuntu forums Ubuntu and the Gentoo forums and I start noticing that people don't have a lot of great things to say about that motherboard in Linux and that Several of its key functions seem to have a lot of problems.
Speaker 1: and these posts were from a couple months ago And I didn't see any resolution really and I started getting leery.
Speaker 0: yeah Well see there's a big problem in that.
Speaker 0: recently motherboards have done a few cool things that have caused trouble.
Speaker 0: First they've made onboard sound cards that don't suck.
Speaker 0: That's good because now you don't have to go out and spend extra money on a sound card And that somehow didn't increase the price of motherboards.
Speaker 0: So it's like everyone gets a free sound card doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: The bad part is many of those sound cards work poorly if at all in Linux Yep.
Speaker 0: Secondly the people have started adding lots of SAT a ports and raid and all sorts of other Awesome storage features.
Speaker 1: the AV 9 has 10 serially ATAs.
Speaker 0: I was so excited about that motherboard 10 serial ATA connectors three different serial ATA controllers to handle all those connectors.
Speaker 0: But of course all these different you know controllers that handle these connectors.
Speaker 0: some of them work better than others in Linux.
Speaker 0: You know some work perfectly some don't work at all some work, but have problems.
Speaker 0: It's really not so hot.
Speaker 1: so I think Despite the fact that I really wanted to go straight up and tell all the way.
Speaker 1: I'm probably gonna have to buy an n-force board which I used to love n-force, but now all the new n-forces They're all SLI so they all cost a lot more money than they need to.
Speaker 0: yeah, this is what's doubly annoying right?
Speaker 0: Oh, I forgot.
Speaker 0: also network cards are starting to be built into motherboards which isn't a big deal because network cards cost like 10 bucks, but it does save you a slot.
Speaker 0: and The thing is some network cards work in Linux and some don't.
Speaker 1: luckily most of them do.
Speaker 0: yeah But it's like when you had when you couldn't get one on your motherboard And you would go and buy one separately.
Speaker 0: you would just always buy one that worked in Linux And it wouldn't matter what motherboard you got.
Speaker 0: you weren't restricted in any way.
Speaker 1: so so the moral is.
Speaker 1: now I'm looking at motherboards all right the SLI home and SLI.
Speaker 1: I don't want but every motherboard has it.
Speaker 0: That's what's annoying is that Nvidia is really pushing this SLI because they want everyone to buy two video cards with two Nvidia chips.
Speaker 0: They make more money, but every benchmark.
Speaker 1: I read shows that SLI gets marginal performance.
Speaker 0: It would be one thing if SLI actually was almost like twice as fast as one video card like if it was 175 percent the speed of you know what the video card that you chose to get to of.
Speaker 0: that would be alright But it's not.
Speaker 0: it's like a hundred and twenty five percent and in some cases It's actually slower if you have two video cards than if you have one and every n-force chipset works really well in Linux, but Every motherboard that has an Nvidia chipset also has SLI.
Speaker 1: no big deal except.
Speaker 1: They're all expensive as a result.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's like you got to pay $200 for a motherboard that you're only going to use a hundred and ten dollars worth of Just to get the chipset that works in Linux because the other ones don't work, so here's the worst thing.
Speaker 1: This is perhaps the nail through my palms The motherboard that is the best price per all the features it has.
Speaker 1: that supports everything I want.
Speaker 1: It's not other than the goddamn a bit fatality motherboard.
Speaker 0: for anyone who doesn't know Fatality is like a famous FPS playing guy.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he's technically still the best in the world, but he's definitely the most famous.
Speaker 1: He's one of the best FPSers ever to live.
Speaker 1: yeah pretty much other than perhaps Dan Greer who for some reason never really competed.
Speaker 0: You know he should have so and fatality is this famous guy.
Speaker 0: forget his name, but if you told it to me I'd say that's the one.
Speaker 0: but He has a licensing deal with a bit where they put his name on the motherboards in order to sell them to gamers.
Speaker 1: now That's a bullshit gimmick.
Speaker 1: It's garbage however.
Speaker 1: This motherboard is not that bad.
Speaker 0: It's like I would be ashamed to buy a motherboard with this kid's name on it.
Speaker 1: You know what it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like if when you're a kid right back when the Air Jordans were like 90 bucks Or you can get it out of 200 bucks Or you could get a very good day to get a pair of kids for like 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: It's like if suddenly the Air Jordans were less than the kids And you don't want to buy them because you're buying into that bullshit branding.
Speaker 1: But at the same time it's a good shoe, and it's cheaper now than the nominally cheap shoe.
Speaker 0: I will tell you I never owned them But I am a hundred percent sure the original Air Jordan is an excellent shoe perhaps one of the best shoes ever.
Speaker 1: it was Because I did in fact own a pair however.
Speaker 1: I got them on a discount because I bought the previous year's model.
Speaker 1: How unfashionable could rim be?
Speaker 0: Actually if you go on eBay and try to look for like old Air Jordans that are still in one piece They go for quite a bit of money.
Speaker 1: Really yes like a lot.
Speaker 1: well unluckily.
Speaker 1: I wore mine out.
Speaker 0: Yep, I knew a guy who still had his old Air Jordans from when he was a kid Hey, and he sold them for he didn't sell them, but he kept wearing them all the time.
Speaker 1: So anyway in the news, and I'll be quick about this Fark has changed.
Speaker 1: Fark looks different.
Speaker 1: That is all also.
Speaker 0: There's some other news about that.
Speaker 0: actually Farks policy on copyright now hasn't changed in many years, but it still sucks.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing and luckily the the people in charge of Fark talked about it almost right away.
Speaker 1: when because people notice suddenly that hey Fark claims copyright on anything I post it's like.
Speaker 0: well It's like they changed the website so now people could actually navigate and find the page that said that it says it at the bottom.
Speaker 1: It's always said it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was so hard to miss the terms of service on Fark.
Speaker 1: You'd have to be an idiot to not see them.
Speaker 1: I've known about them for as long as I've used far I've never looked at them.
Speaker 1: so here's the deal the skinny from Drew Curtis And I trust the dude because this guy has never done anyone wrong as far as I can see.
Speaker 1: He basically said that the language is such as it is so that one and well This is me reading between the lines the radio stations around America like to rip Fark off all the time.
Speaker 1: If you've listened to any wacky wacky waving morning show where they talk about the crazy jungle blah blah blah They're pretty much just reading Fark.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember I listened to this one morning show in Rochester a few times and all they did was it didn't seem like the actual radio host.
Speaker 0: Guy knew about Fark or what it was or anything.
Speaker 0: it seemed like there was a producer somewhere who would get stories off Fark and Feed them to him.
Speaker 0: and of course people who listen to the radio in the morning Aren't Fark readers 90% of the time.
Speaker 0: so they hear these incredibly hilarious news stories And they go OMG this news this guy in the radio so hilarious When really he's just a guy reading Fark to you because you're too inept.
Speaker 1: And it wasn't just finding the stories on Fark.
Speaker 1: these DJs would often read the headlines like they were their own or actually read through The comments and make jokes that people on Fark made.
Speaker 0: that's what they would do.
Speaker 1: also a lot of websites would rip off Fark Photoshops all the time.
Speaker 1: so the real purpose of this is so that when other websites or Newspapers or radio or whatever rip off from Fark Fark can sue them.
Speaker 0: has Fark actually sued anyone?
Speaker 1: Fark has gone after people Several times, I don't know if they've actually sued But they have written angry letters and sent cease and desist.
Speaker 0: if I was Fark I would just make a forum cease and desist and send it to every single Morning zoo radio show in the entire country.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't send one to Howard Stern.
Speaker 1: no because he actually Whatever your feelings are on the guy the man's smart, and he doesn't just rip off a Fark.
Speaker 0: no He does not rip off a Fark however.
Speaker 1: I don't actually listen to Howard Stern.
Speaker 0: I know about him.
Speaker 0: the only time I ever listen to Howard Stern was I think when I was driving around trying to listen to My iPod with an FM transmitter and some guys serious satellite radio overpowered me.
Speaker 1: Oh, you mean like what happened to me every single goddamn day until I took the antenna off my car.
Speaker 1: Yep, see Howard Stern is like Larry Flynn don't like the guy don't really like what he does But I respect everything he stands for.
Speaker 1: yeah That's pretty much what it is because all he stands for is freedom to do what I want freedom of speech.
Speaker 0: the FCC is bullshit Yeah, and his radio voice is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Howard Stern has one of the best radio voices ever.
Speaker 0: That's because he's pretty much the most professional radio guy there ever was.
Speaker 1: if I had a few thousand dollars I can make Scott and I sound a lot like that.
Speaker 1: I think we also need a giant vocal cords like now because you can do a lot of that in post-production.
Speaker 0: Yes, no, I can't anyway.
Speaker 1: yeah part of the key is to talk.
Speaker 1: really close the microphone But then you got to do all sorts of stuff riddle clip and my voice is definitely not suited to it without a whole bunch Of other post-production, so let's go get away from that.
Speaker 0: get back towards the geek news here.
Speaker 1: all right well far change.
Speaker 1: That is all.
Speaker 0: yep Ken kutaragi.
Speaker 0: if you don't know who Ken kutaragi is you should.
Speaker 0: he's basically the father of the Playstation.
Speaker 0: if you Consider Miyamoto and Iwata and those people to be the fathers of Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Ken kutaragi is the father of the Playstation.
Speaker 0: if you like Playstation games Playstation 1 Playstation 2 if you care about gaming at all you should know about this guy.
Speaker 0: he is very very important and He's really important, but today something crazy happened.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: He didn't die he quit slash resigned.
Speaker 0: Slash was forced to resign slash retired now.
Speaker 1: is this because he's old and wants to retire Or is this because of issues that may have arisen in Sony's current fiscal situation?
Speaker 0: yes I am not quite sure.
Speaker 0: basically the obvious conclusion to jump to is oh the ps3 sucked so he was forced to quit.
Speaker 0: oh.
Speaker 0: But there are many analysts who know a lot more about like behind the scenes game business than we do and they're saying such things as well.
Speaker 0: Sony doesn't really need a visionary right now.
Speaker 0: They just need someone to get the job done and So they're gonna switch up to someone who's good at just making a lot of stuff and getting stuff out on the shelves real Fast making license plates yep.
Speaker 0: There's also some other talk like ah well You know sure he's gonna quit and let someone else do the job so he can spend more time thinking about stuff and be more Advisory.
Speaker 0: so I have linked here to an article that contains many for more professional opinions than ours And you can read about it and make your own conclusion because there's not much said about it anywhere.
Speaker 0: It's sort of that's why I said we don't even know if he retired or quit or what because no one's talking so much At ABC pricked me with an AIDS infected needle.
Speaker 0: Good luck with all that.
Speaker 1: I can't believe I never made this a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: This is one of those old classic things that you probably should have seen it, but just in case you didn't here It is.
Speaker 1: you see Seinfeld ended and as a goof They got Seinfeld and the cast from Oz and they made us kind of mini episode trailer of what it would be like if Jerry Seinfeld were in the Oswald maximum-security penitentiary and let me tell you it's pretty terrific.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I never.
Speaker 0: I watch Seinfeld a lot obviously, but I never really watched this Oz show.
Speaker 0: I knew is it was a show about a terrible prison with lots of rape going on.
Speaker 1: actually It's a really good show and I've seen most of it.
Speaker 1: It's actually in the Netflix queue because I never saw how it ends Aha.
Speaker 0: Well if you like prisons and rape and good TV shows You should probably get it from your Netflix or buy the sets or whatever.
Speaker 1: You should probably in fact watch all of Seinfeld and all of Oz.
Speaker 0: Anyway, when you combine these two things It doesn't really matter if you actually know anything about Oz or Seinfeld.
Speaker 0: of course, it helps it makes it funnier But it's pretty funny.
Speaker 1: I will give you one little hint.
Speaker 1: the guy who asks Seinfeld Are you a Hebrew?
Speaker 1: He is basically the skinhead Nazi leader of the Aryan skinhead Nazis in the prison.
Speaker 1: That is why there there are numerous instances where they talk about him nailing someone up somewhere or well He asks Jerry if he's a Jew and Jerry's like, yeah But people are okay with that.
Speaker 1: in a national The best part is the one guy.
Speaker 1: you'll know which guy he pulls off an absolutely flawless George Costanza.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if you haven't seen Seinfeld you won't know who it is.
Speaker 0: doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: if you've seen any Seinfeld You'll know which guy I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: It's beautiful like props to that actor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's generally funny when you combine two things Especially when it's not it.
Speaker 0: this isn't like a combination done by like some guys cutting and pasting these two shows together.
Speaker 0: This is Seinfeld and the guys from Oz actually got together and did this.
Speaker 1: I gotta admit I would have been very intimidated to be on that set with those people because seeing that show Having seen Oz it is very hard to convince myself that those are not those people and that they are actors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean when you're acting like a scary dude.
Speaker 1: Adam Eazy is a scary motherfucker.
Speaker 0: in real life He's just some guy who'd be like hey, how you doing?
Speaker 1: Except of course that hat.
Speaker 1: and to this day How the hell does that hat stick to his head?
Speaker 0: I don't know what Adam Eazy looks like so a Gigantic black dude.
Speaker 1: He's he's the most evil dude ever and he's just in this pretty pricked people with AIDS infected needles.
Speaker 0: I imagine he's a bad dude.
Speaker 1: It's probably one of the tamest things he's ever done.
Speaker 0: Whoa When you stab someone with an AIDS infected sword So he has this stupid little hat that's kind of stinks someone with an Ebola infected gun.
Speaker 1: that kind of Sticks on the side of his head and it doesn't fall off and it just sticks there.
Speaker 0: It's always stuck there with glue.
Speaker 1: It's hilarious.
Speaker 0: It's part of his head.
Speaker 0: He's actually got all like a big lump there.
Speaker 0: He's covering it up.
Speaker 1: I would assume he shaves his head.
Speaker 1: He probably leaves hair there and just sticks it to the hair.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 1: So what I would do if I was at a BC.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is a video.
Speaker 0: I saw him dig today cuz.
Speaker 0: well I couldn't think of anything better to show you and I actually watched.
Speaker 0: I Expected something completely different from this video than what I got.
Speaker 0: You see the video was like, you know tiger attacks man on elephant and I'm like, okay It's gonna see an elephant stepping on a tiger.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be pretty cool cuz.
Speaker 0: Tigers can't really beat elephants unless there's a lot more than one of them.
Speaker 1: No but we learned something from this video and what we learned was Just because you're on an elephant does not mean a tiger does not have the ability to kick your ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if I was on an elephant and there was a tiger way down on the ground and my elephant was a big elephant And not say a baby elephant personally before seeing this video.
Speaker 0: I would not have been worried.
Speaker 0: I would have been like, huh?
Speaker 0: My elephant can beat that tiger.
Speaker 1: not even that I would have thought why would a tiger wouldn't even Attack me.
Speaker 1: I'm top of the giant elephant.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like if you're on a deck or on a balcony you feel real safe even late at night in a bad neighborhood But if you're on the ground floor not so safe.
Speaker 0: Yep well this video you'll see a guy riding on an elephant and the cameras sort of behind him and You'll see all this grass everywhere and everyone knows he's in the tall grass.
Speaker 0: The tiger is hiding in the tall grass with the Pokemon and of course about a minute into the video the tiger appears and Starts to go at this guy.
Speaker 0: I think this guy is some sort of Ranger of some sort because he's got stuff that I think he's using to Get the tiger.
Speaker 0: Maybe I think they're looking for the tiger.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 0: regardless.
Speaker 1: He doesn't appear worried.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he doesn't appear worried.
Speaker 0: I think he's like a tiger go-getter or some sort of zoologist or something an animal person Scientist.
Speaker 0: so this tiger comes running at him and I'm like, oh that tiger.
Speaker 0: He's alright.
Speaker 0: What's he gonna do?
Speaker 0: He's gonna like slash the elephant the elephant will bonk him or step on him or something.
Speaker 0: The tiger jumps way Way up and then the video cuts out.
Speaker 0: and whoa, you got to see this shit now.
Speaker 1: This is much different from the other tiger attack video on dig right now Which is not what you think it is.
Speaker 0: There are two tiger attack videos on dig right now.
Speaker 0: The one I'm talking about is one that's actually a tiger attack.
Speaker 0: The other one is hilarious.
Speaker 0: You should watch.
Speaker 0: Let's just link to both of them.
Speaker 0: The other one the other tiger attack video.
Speaker 0: It's a guy in a zoo and there's some tigers behind a fence and one of the Tigers rubs up against the fence and you're thinking Ah, this guy's tiger is gonna knock this fence down and eat this guy or this guy's gonna stupidly pet the tiger.
Speaker 1: the tiger is gonna scratch bite him or Maybe another tiger is gonna come or something, but the Tigers really cute.
Speaker 1: He's just kind of rubbing up the fence like aah like cats do and then something happens.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna spoil but it's hilarious.
Speaker 1: All I have to say is I personally witnessed a lion Do a similar thing to a child at a zoo when I was when I was also a child and my whole life I have often thought man.
Speaker 1: I hope that that is never me.
Speaker 0: I will guarantee that that is never me 100% cuz I'll never put myself in a situation where they could be me ever.
Speaker 1: So it's Thursday and we were gonna.
Speaker 1: well see I'm gonna give you a little insight into how we do geek nights here.
Speaker 1: You see we have this calendar that's got set up on our personal front row crew g-man.
Speaker 0: Well, we used to not have a calendar.
Speaker 0: We used to come up with the show idea the day we did the show and then I said hey this sucks Let's make a calendar and we'll put the show topics on this calendar.
Speaker 1: So we've used this for quite some time and Monday Mondays are full Tuesdays are full pretty much forever as our Wednesdays Thursdays.
Speaker 1: there was only One more show left and the thing is this is a show that we kept every Thursday.
Speaker 1: We'd think ah and we push it off and make up something else on the spot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and finally we got to today and we didn't have anything like crap.
Speaker 1: We have to do this show.
Speaker 1: and then I thought of a show to do and then I just didn't feel like doing it Mainly because we went long in the first half of the show and I got a lot of stories.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go long tonight because I got a pack so I can go to toricon tomorrow And
Speaker 0: I'm not going to toricon tomorrow or Saturday But I am doing a whole bunch of other crap this weekend and I don't really want to have to you know Waste a whole bunch of time important precious time now thinking of a show.
Speaker 1: So the show we kept avoiding because it didn't seem like it would be funny It would mostly just be informative and serious was about resumes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay people write a resume don't make it suck Yeah, make it like a lot of other resumes but don't make it exactly like every other resume and make sure that there's actually good stuff to say about you to put on a Resume.
Speaker 0: if you can't think of anything to put on a resume, you probably suck and don't deserve a job.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe maybe if you're just out of college you want to put classes you took you want to put your major your GPA?
Speaker 1: All that stuff unless they suck Yeah, and you definitely want to focus on your skills.
Speaker 1: have whole list of things, you know things you're good at names of software You know how to use if you protect if you work for more than a few years.
Speaker 1: List all the companies you've worked for and the things you did for those companies.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, that's pretty much it All right, so then we decided all right.
Speaker 1: forget that I just had a flat tire.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about car trouble because we have a lot of car trouble stories over the years.
Speaker 0: Yeah well anyone who lives in the US where public transportation is kind of a and you have to drive to get anywhere as a Car most people have a car and they drive quite frequently perhaps daily or more than daily.
Speaker 1: I drive.
Speaker 1: Well, I did.
Speaker 1: now I take the train so I don't but I used to drive 500 miles a week.
Speaker 0: Yes, I drove quite a bit as well for the period where I was working in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: and well People drive a lot and when you drive a lot, you're gonna have trouble with cars at some point or another.
Speaker 0: They'll break the.
Speaker 0: you know, they don't last forever.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of moving parts in there there's a lot of different systems with many different points of failure and Sometimes they can cause you a great inconvenience.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot to say about that.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, we've got a bunch of anecdotes that I was gonna go over.
Speaker 1: I just don't feel like it.
Speaker 1: but the moral of all of them and I'll tell you this right now the secret to avoiding car Trouble or to getting out of car trouble have money.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: If you have money You'll do the relevant repairs and your car will last practically forever.
Speaker 1: If you have money and your car breaks down It is so easy to fit.
Speaker 1: if your car breaks down on the freeway and you're on a trip somewhere You either need to have triple-a or a credit card.
Speaker 0: Both of those things are pretty much equal.
Speaker 1: and the thing is triple-a won't actually save you.
Speaker 1: they'll fix a little thing.
Speaker 1: They'll fix your busted tire.
Speaker 1: They'll tow you somewhere.
Speaker 1: But if your problem is more than I'm out of gas or my tire is flat They're gonna tow you somewhere and then you still need the credit card.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's there's no way out.
Speaker 1: You can't fix it on your own.
Speaker 1: You can't even move the car on your own on most US freeways.
Speaker 1: You can't even tow it on your own.
Speaker 0: You got even if you were a mechanic and even if you had tools in the trunk.
Speaker 0: You're gonna need parts probably if anything serious is broken.
Speaker 0: You're also.
Speaker 1: Most repairs you could make on the road may or may not be illegal to continue driving with Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It just sucks all around and I've broken down a couple times way back when I was younger Didn't have any money.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you Every time I was only saved by the fact that while I didn't have money I knew someone nearby who did.
Speaker 1: there is no way out.
Speaker 1: If you don't have money You're gonna have to pay to tow.
Speaker 1: you have to pay some stupid amount of money to get the car fixed.
Speaker 1: If you can't get it fixed, you're gonna have to pay somehow to get where you're going or to get home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what if I was Bill Gates and my car broke down I'll call a cab and leave the car there and not care about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'd go buy a new car.
Speaker 1: I might hire someone and say you take care of this car fix it up and sell it or whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I'd sell it to someone right there.
Speaker 0: I put a for sale sign and wait.
Speaker 1: Haha I wouldn't wait my time's too valuable.
Speaker 1: I'd hire someone to stand there with a for sale sign and the deed.
Speaker 0: I'd sell it to the guy with the tow truck.
Speaker 0: I just give it to whatever.
Speaker 0: I'd sell to the cabbie.
Speaker 1: I'd give it to a charity right away.
Speaker 1: I'd take the tow truck and say here's the deed give it to a charity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that works too.
Speaker 1: Of course, you know, the tow truck guy would give it to the me charity.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Whatever kids getting used who cares?
Speaker 1: So yeah That's it.
Speaker 1: we had nothing else in the Thursday queue other than we have several shows we could do.
Speaker 1: that have been suggested by listeners.
Speaker 1: However, every one of these requires me not to be lazy Scott not to be lazy.
Speaker 1: us to do some small amount of research Us to not spend 25 minutes doing the first half of the show because otherwise us to not spend 15 minutes thinking about what?
Speaker 0: We're gonna do the show on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also the fact that I'm lazy and tired and I got a pack and I got a bunch of stuff to do tonight.
Speaker 0: So I just want to point out again in the forums.
Speaker 0: There is a thread that's been there for a long time.
Speaker 0: This is show reminders.
Speaker 0: It's sticky.
Speaker 0: You can't miss it.
Speaker 0: You should probably put some Thursday show ideas in that thread.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we do look there.
Speaker 1: We often ignore or put off or do shows later, but we always look there.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean I just looked there right now and I was sitting there and not knowing what to do the show on and I didn't Find anything.
Speaker 1: I think the problem with Thursday is that there's no limit.
Speaker 1: So it's like it when you're role-playing.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean Dungeons & Dragons is a pretty crappy system.
Speaker 1: all things considered it is like really crappy and we use it Only because when role-playing while it is possible It is usually not very fun to role-play in an entirely open environment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, imagine if you were just role-playing with some people right and it was.
Speaker 0: there were no rules.
Speaker 0: There was no restrictions whatsoever.
Speaker 0: You'd be like, huh?
Speaker 0: I fly off into the something plane that I just made up where my friends I just made up and I we get the ultimate powerful thing I just made up and now such role-playing can work, but it's very difficult to do.
Speaker 1: well, you have to have a good group of people and Even then even if you're doing it very well, it often bogs down and becomes unfun because there's no restrictions.
Speaker 1: There's no arbitrary limitations that force you to be creative.
Speaker 1: while D&D is a bullshit system and we only use it Because it happens to be a system that everyone we know knows and is very accessible Yes, yes and has lots of dice that are fun.
Speaker 1: And we're also and also it's one of the only systems that works very well with the kinds of games we play for now well very well being relative but we
Speaker 0: are
Speaker 1: as fast as we can learning burning wheel and Hopefully you're going to play many more burning wheel games than we ever will play D&D games in the future.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about the burning empires - yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm still slowly writing my Napoleonic Wars men on a ship Horatio style burning wheel game.
Speaker 1: that's gonna be totally awesome.
Speaker 0: I might buy that burning empires book yeah,
Speaker 1: but despite that D&D as crappy as it is is Wonderful in that all it does is provide an arbitrary set of limitations that we can use to focus our role-playing and In getting around and dealing with the arbitrariness and the limitations We often find even greater strengths than we would have on our own.
Speaker 1: Monday Tuesday and Wednesday are a lot like that.
Speaker 1: We're forced to pick a topic that fits into some mold.
Speaker 1: Thursday we could talk about my nuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's talk about your nuts.
Speaker 0: Pistachios are pretty damn good.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm a big fan of cashews.
Speaker 1: I really like Sunflower I could eat.
Speaker 1: I got like a half pound of sunflower.
Speaker 0: flower seeds aren't nuts.
Speaker 1: Alright, I'm being vague anything nutty like that.
Speaker 1: Sunflower seeds are close enough.
Speaker 1: I categorize them as nuts in terms of how they're edible and how I use them you suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're putting food I would put cashews which are also not a nut right aren't they something else too?
Speaker 0: Cashews are nuts.
Speaker 1: Well, I do know that cashew the outside of a cashew is poisonous and dangerous.
Speaker 0: that is very true.
Speaker 1: I know that much.
Speaker 1: but peanuts cashews Brazil nuts Almonds sunflower seeds they all fall into the same food category as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: Well, they do sell them in the same action of the grocery store.
Speaker 0: Yeah But but some flower seeds are still not nuts.
Speaker 1: their seeds My left nut is somewhat but not too terribly larger than my right nut.
Speaker 0: my nuts are.
Speaker 0: There's probably a difference in size and shape and volume but it's not perceptible with the hands.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of hair on my nuts Partly due to the fact that I've mountain biked most of my life.
Speaker 1: There's actually no hair on my inner thigh either.
Speaker 1: It's all been rubbed off.
Speaker 0: My inner thighs tend to be lacking a lot of hair But and my nuts don't have as much hair as other parts of my body There's quite a few scraggles here and there.
Speaker 1: I have very few scraggles.
Speaker 1: I have a lot of hair above but below on the actual relevant nut bits almost nothing.
Speaker 1: There's like eight hairs on the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's significantly more than maybe more than eight.
Speaker 1: I better give this a look.
Speaker 0: I've got a lot more than eight, but there's still not so many down there compared to the other parts.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So now rim is counting his nut hair.
Speaker 0: I think he ignites has descended into chaos.
Speaker 1: There's only like 50 hairs on my actual nut sack.
Speaker 0: All right That's great.
Speaker 1: See that's what happens when we don't have Thursday ideas.
Speaker 1: So you better get cracking out there internets and nut cracking.
Speaker 1: granted A lot of the ideas you guys have suggested we are going to do I really like the political debate idea where Scott and I just straight-up sound off on a very specific issue.
Speaker 1: But I don't feel like doing that tonight.
Speaker 1: I'm tired.
Speaker 1: I got stuff to do.
Speaker 0: I hardly ever feel like doing that lately.
Speaker 0: I'm just not into the whole Politics arguing thing anymore.
Speaker 0: I'm just so tired of it.
Speaker 1: See now this annoys me greatly because I still like to argue about it a lot and Scott like I'll be like Hey, and actually a lot of interesting stuff is going on in the legislative and executive branches of the US government right now.
Speaker 1: There's a lot going on I think just just now like Condoleezza Rice basically gave the Congress the finger and said subpoena I'm not testifying Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's basically just.
Speaker 0: there's just been so much bullshit for so many years constantly every goddamn day.
Speaker 0: I'm just like.
Speaker 0: that's enough.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: nothing I do is gonna matter besides voting.
Speaker 1: I don't think of it that way.
Speaker 1: I think of it in that it's a fascinating field of study, and I'm interested in it And I like watching how things fold out and I try to learn how things are.
Speaker 1: not all things are related on paper.
Speaker 1: I mean if you look at the powers of the president of the United States They're actually kind of few and far between.
Speaker 1: they're a lot less than you'd expect but yet it feels like the president has crazy amounts of power and It's interesting how how things are on paper versus how things really work, and it's fascinating to me.
Speaker 1: But I've always been interested in politics and he says hey Whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I like me some political science.
Speaker 0: But you know I just really I'm just worn out, and I don't care anymore.
Speaker 0: Why don't we have and I'm gonna cut you know?
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna worry myself about all this bullshit.
Speaker 0: That's just never going to stop.
Speaker 0: Well Scott always concentrate on my geeky stuff that I care about their politics geeks.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of politics I'm talking about my you know my video games and my animes and things lame.
Speaker 1: We're geek nights.
Speaker 1: We encompass all of geekdom.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of politics geeks out there.
Speaker 1: I knew many of them at RIT.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know they exist and I just don't care anymore.
Speaker 1: in fact one of my favorite classes ever was a Politics and communication which was a seminar of me nine other people and this awesome professor And we basically sat around a roundtable and debated about the Democratic primaries for the entire quarter Uh-huh, and it was fascinating.
Speaker 1: I loved the class.
Speaker 0: That doesn't sound too exciting to me.
Speaker 0: It actually really was.
Speaker 1: I learned a lot.
Speaker 1: also I think the best part was that it's you know RIT quarters ten weeks right, so there's like nine people in the class.
Speaker 1: Basically every week one member of the class had to teach the entire lesson the entire unit the entire topic sounds like a lazy teacher To me.
Speaker 1: no because the teacher was a hard-ass and basically if you didn't do an awesome job He would step in and provide everything that was needed to make the lesson awesome, and he would then destroy you for being an idiot.
Speaker 1: It was actually really cool.
Speaker 0: That would be entertaining no matter what that the class was about.
Speaker 0: yeah That's could have been about like fish, and that would have been great.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well it also helped that.
Speaker 1: it was a pretty interesting time in politics and we were just coming up on the Democratic primaries and no one knew who was gonna win and the professor was like 60% sure that John Edwards was gonna get the nomination, and he thought that it was gonna be due to so-called NASCAR dads and this whole thing.
Speaker 1: that didn't really pan out But no one thought John Kerry was gonna get it.
Speaker 1: not a single person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, that's what happens, but that was before Howard Dean and his Yeah, even though that was all BS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, oh well well I can tell I'm boring you Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, why don't we have a fun argument like John Adams politics versus Thomas Jefferson politics?
Speaker 0: Because I only know the most general of details the most general.
Speaker 1: okay What are the most general if we won't get into it?
Speaker 0: federalist any federalist?
Speaker 1: there's more to it than that States.
Speaker 1: How about we debate Jefferson's Navy a?
Speaker 0: Whole bunch of little boats?
Speaker 0: yeah, I get rid of the pirates.
Speaker 1: I respect Thomas Jefferson But the guy didn't seem to know a lot about naval warfare And he wanted to revamp the US Navy.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like one of those ideas I come up with like well What if we did this?
Speaker 0: we wouldn't wouldn't that work?
Speaker 0: and then someone says no wouldn't work because of this.
Speaker 0: only No one says that and you actually try some crazy stupid idea.
Speaker 1: everybody in the world has like eight big boats.
Speaker 1: Why don't my?
Speaker 1: why don't I make 20 little boats?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'll work so much better cuz you won't be able to hit him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, but they also won't be able to do anything.
Speaker 0: It's like a giant castle like hey instead of having one castle I'll have a thousand spearmen.
Speaker 0: That's not gonna work, man Just catapult you.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah, oh well.
Speaker 1: so luckily We spent a good 20 minutes now basically copping out And I think we're gonna end it here.
Speaker 1: have a good weekend.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna be anywhere in upstate New York check out toricon at the Rochester Institute of Technology on Saturday.
Speaker 1: I don't know from when to when but I got a panel about podcasting and internet radio sometime I think six six thirty.
Speaker 1: I got a look at the email before I drive out there.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna be there because I'm gonna stay home, and I'm gonna go to Mars, so if you're in the Poughkeepsie, New York area the mid
Speaker 1: Hudson Valley downstate, New York You can
Speaker 0: go to the Dragon's Den on Saturday And I'll be there at some point and playing awesome board games.
Speaker 0: And then I'm probably gonna go around Buying some pairs of shorts and a new belt to replace my broken belt.
Speaker 1: if you come to toricon and you're super cool There is a decent chance that I'm going to be leading an expedition into the New York or the Rochester subway Because there are several people who missed it the last time and there's still fear that they're gonna seal it up or get rid of It.
Speaker 1: so also there's a professor an unnamed professor who really wants to go.
Speaker 1: apparently.
Speaker 1: so if the police?
Speaker 1: Yeah, this would be cool because if the police bother us.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be this old dude along with us Who's a professor at a prestigious University?
Speaker 0: Hilarious.
Speaker 1: yeah, what are you kids doing on there?
Speaker 1: I'm a professor.
Speaker 1: This is my doctorate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he'll be like can we see your papers, please see papers.
Speaker 0: No ticket no ticket.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 0: We're done.
Speaker 1: I think we're done.
Speaker 0: that teaches you every law.
Speaker 0: lesson.
Speaker 0: Thursday ideas chop chop.
Speaker 1: Yes, cuz if you don't you're gonna get me counting the hairs on my nut sack, or we just won't do Thursday.
Speaker 0: What do you do about that?
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: What will you do?
Speaker 1: What would you do?
Speaker 1: Yeah, shoot the hostage?
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.