Speaker 0: It's Wednesday October 3rd.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We discussed two shows, but mostly get some end to hanky Mina.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So as you might have noticed from the forums and from the other shows this week and all next week probably we are taking your questions.
Speaker 1: I had this up now, so we don't forget to talk about it later.
Speaker 0: if you want to know things That Google does not know that you know are things only known to me and rim ask us.
Speaker 0: This is your chance perhaps your only chance yep.
Speaker 1: I mean a while ago We did a you know ask for him and Scott and most of the questions were personal questions But a lot of them were you know computer II whatever and we decided Partly due to people demanding another show like that to do a whole week of questions Sometime in the future once we have questions.
Speaker 0: yep now if you want your question to actually be answered because of course we're not just gonna answer every question make sure that the question is a question that can't be answered by Google.
Speaker 0: make sure it's a question that Doesn't take forever to talk about it because then we'll probably just turn it into a show idea instead of a question.
Speaker 0: Make sure it's a question.
Speaker 0: That's not stupid.
Speaker 0: And if you want us to answer it on Wednesday make sure it's an anime manga or comic question.
Speaker 1: Yep, either go to the forums and post it there in the relevant thread I'm sure you'll be able to find it or email us.
Speaker 1: You know geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Also, please when you send us your questions Try to send us just the question and not like this giant essay with a question hidden somewhere in there.
Speaker 0: Just ask the question.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not gonna put the effort to find your question.
Speaker 0: yeah, just just ask the question in as few words and concisely and I guess not the way.
Speaker 1: Scott just told you how to answer exactly.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got in the news?
Speaker 0: Well, you know Tintin, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: Yeah Tintin's that's good comics right there.
Speaker 1: I've never actually read Tintin.
Speaker 0: I read a little Tintin and I've seen some Tintin cartoons and I know I want to read some Tintin.
Speaker 0: But it's sort of hard to.
Speaker 0: it's sort of hard to figure out what to buy because it's not like like now I'm reading like Dick Tracy and stuff because IDW is publishing like Dick Tracy Volume one a whole lot of it.
Speaker 0: volume two a whole lot of it in order the whole thing, right?
Speaker 0: But Tintin is.
Speaker 0: there's not really anything like that and there's some like censored volumes, you know and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I'd imagine reading Tintin is a lot like reading Harlock just pick one and go with it.
Speaker 1: And don't worry Don't even try to figure out what chronology there is or what.
Speaker 1: what happened when?
Speaker 0: yeah, it's mostly just you know, separate adventures.
Speaker 0: It's not like Johnny Quest.
Speaker 0: You don't have to watch them in any order, you know.
Speaker 0: This is a multi-parter but a multi-parter that all the parts will be included together.
Speaker 0: So Tintin is cool.
Speaker 0: I like Tintin.
Speaker 0: It's fun.
Speaker 0: Classic adventure stories.
Speaker 0: Well They're gonna be making some United States live-action, I think live-action Tintin movies, huh?
Speaker 0: Three Tintin movies one with the Peter Jackson action one with the Steven Spielberg Action and one with the we don't know who action.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it's gonna be motion capture with 3d not live-action.
Speaker 1: Oh, Yeah, outstanding way to read that article.
Speaker 0: we're yeah, we're bringing the news Article so someone else can read it and catch us when we don't read it.
Speaker 0: But yeah This is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And I think that this might encourage someone to reprint the Tintins in an accessible format So that way they can profit off of the heightened interest due to the movie, huh?
Speaker 0: And also I'll be able to buy the Tintin comics that I wanted.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I guess I hope the movie's good.
Speaker 1: I mean, we know how movies go when they're adapted from comics or anything.
Speaker 0: Well, it's being written by Steven Moffat who is the writer of the new Doctor Who and some other BBC show called Jekyll.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know cuz I've never seen either of those whether this guy can write or not.
Speaker 1: I hear that the new Doctor Who is kind of awesome, but I haven't actually seen it.
Speaker 0: I've never seen old or new Doctor Who's there?
Speaker 1: Oh, man, the old Doctor Who is the bomb diggity.
Speaker 0: So, what do I know?
Speaker 1: Well, you know that you should watch some Doctor Who.
Speaker 0: I know I should read some Tintin, right?
Speaker 1: So we've mentioned this off and on obliquely, but I think now that it's been announced officially We don't have to really beat around the bush anymore.
Speaker 1: We are going to be guests at the New York Anime Festival in Manhattan at the Jacob Javits Center December 7th through 9th yep, and If you were anywhere in the New York City area I would highly recommend you come at least for Saturday because we'll have a table.
Speaker 1: We're doing four shows.
Speaker 1: We'll be hanging out doing some match game action.
Speaker 1: As long as our artist who may or may not still be working on it finishes We'll have some t-shirts to sell there.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, they better hurry up with that where the time's running out here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta call our artist probably tonight or tomorrow and ask what the dealio is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah Um, I was originally skeptical about how this convention was gonna go because it is a for-profit.
Speaker 1: You don't need to give this speech every time.
Speaker 0: I gotta give this speech again.
Speaker 1: It's a for-profit con by the same people who did the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 1: We wonder if that's gonna be good or bad but it seems like these people know what they're doing because they're actually Asking people who know about anime cons how to run an anime con and they've got a lot of talent here and everything seems to Be run the way it should be run and we're optimist at
Speaker 0: the very least.
Speaker 0: least if the convention sucks balls And is the worst thing it could possibly be will be there and our stuff will be awesome.
Speaker 1: Not only will we be there and we are doing our four events But we have some special guests who are going to be there with us People in tow if you will none other than Dave Riley and Joel White.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know what you want to say?
Speaker 0: They're definitely gonna show up.
Speaker 1: They said they're definitely gonna show up.
Speaker 1: They confirmed with me.
Speaker 1: They have badges.
Speaker 1: They are coming.
Speaker 1: All right, if they don't come well, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: But see I don't like to like say that kind of thing and then if they don't show up it makes us look bad.
Speaker 1: No, it'll make them look bad.
Speaker 1: Believe me.
Speaker 0: I'm if they don't show up remember don't tell us They screwed up not me.
Speaker 1: No, they said they're coming.
Speaker 0: All right, they confirmed.
Speaker 1: I have the.
Speaker 1: I have the email where they don't show up for post that email and the very least Dave said that both of them were coming.
Speaker 1: Joel did not directly contact me.
Speaker 0: Well, Joel also supposedly has disappeared from the face of the earth, but that happens semi regularly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean the New York Anime Festival is gonna be big.
Speaker 1: It's in the Javits, but there's one other thing.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a dual news here that they're doing that.
Speaker 1: I saw the news and I thought I but then I actually read it And I'm intrigued.
Speaker 1: Apparently the New York Anime Festival is doing a cosplay Masquerade kind of the way we always wanted it to be done.
Speaker 0: Well sort of they are Pre-selecting.
Speaker 1: there are only going to be 40 acts and they are going to pre-select them based on what you send them ahead of time.
Speaker 0: 40 X is a lot of X. so they must predict that there's gonna be a big turnout at the con.
Speaker 1: Well, there probably will be because one if the New York Comic Con both iterations was any indication.
Speaker 1: if you advertise something at all In the New York City area pretty much.
Speaker 1: Everyone's gonna come no matter what it is.
Speaker 0: It's either gonna be crazy crowded or not.
Speaker 1: I imagine it's gonna be crazy crowded.
Speaker 0: In fact, I hope so.
Speaker 0: It's good for me I'm a guest there.
Speaker 1: Yeah But they're pre-selecting 40 acts and each act is gonna get three minutes on stage and all that business.
Speaker 1: so it's probably gonna be The best that a cosplay in this area could be because it's gonna be as far as they'll be able to tell the 40 best Most prepared most professional acts out there.
Speaker 1: But here's why I think they're gonna get 40 good acts.
Speaker 1: This is not just the cosplay or the masquerade for the New York Anime Festival But they're going to send the winners to the world cosplay summit.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, this is a real prize and not just someone saying you're awesome, but an actual prize.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever big prize whatever act wins if it's stupid, you know, two people can go.
Speaker 1: so if it's an act of six people they have to pick two which I Can just imagine the drama that is going to have to pick the two before you get before you.
Speaker 1: I can still imagine the drama of any cosplay group with more than two members trying to decide who gets Designated as the person who will go if they win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is they have to decide before they get up there so there'll be no grumpiness.
Speaker 1: after they go There will be grumpiness, but they won't be able to fight over it cuz it'll be set in stone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: It might actually discourage cosplays.
Speaker 0: more than two people
Speaker 1: it might but at the same time just the way this is set up If they're gonna pick the 40 best even if a big, you know group of six goes and if they don't expect to win I Imagine this is gonna be 40 pretty damn good cosplay skits.
Speaker 1: I might watch it.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'm gonna watch it because you know, even if you take let's say 70 people sign up and you pick the best 40.
Speaker 0: You know only me, you know, how many of them there might be the 40 best.
Speaker 0: But what if there's only 10 good ones at all?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it depends.
Speaker 1: Otacon last year had I think two or three good ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah Otacon seems to average two or three good ones.
Speaker 1: But Otacon lets anyone come in.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, it'll be interesting to say the least.
Speaker 1: if anything I imagine this is going to attract a lot of those professional semi-professional super serious.
Speaker 1: I are serious cat.
Speaker 1: this our serious business.
Speaker 1: cosplayers.
Speaker 0: Hopefully so hopefully.
Speaker 1: so yeah Because whatever people may say about cosplay calm and all those people who are a little too much into cosplay They are too much in the cosplay.
Speaker 0: They're not people I would hang out with or talk to and I kind of don't like their attitude But they the people who take the cosplay seriously, they take it seriously.
Speaker 0: Thus they tend to do it better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and people who don't take it so seriously Things of the day.
Speaker 1: So Emily showed this to me.
Speaker 1: She showed it to Scott and then me and it was pretty damn cool.
Speaker 1: So I want you all to see it.
Speaker 1: It's an animation by someone who attended the gobelline school in France, which is it is a school in France.
Speaker 1: I think it's in Paris where people Study visual art and animation that sort of thing and their film festivals tend to bring out a lot of awesome Animations, but Emily told me that you know like at NYU, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone sort of has to make their own project.
Speaker 0: You know and you might get some help from people and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But you know you if you have an it's an animation class you make your animation and you submit it and it's yours.
Speaker 0: But apparently at this school like they they team up, you know, like the whole group of people makes one thing.
Speaker 0: So even though they're just punk animation students and usually, you know an animation student project is not as quality as you know A real, you know big a Pixar production.
Speaker 0: That's not
Speaker 1: to say they aren't awesome No,
Speaker 0: but when you have a bunch of them teaming up together on one thing instead of everyone doing their own thing there is a opportunity there for high quality things to be produced and Things that come out of the school because they're all done by groups of kids and students.
Speaker 0: They're pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: So thus Pirates, which I like to alternately call the way one piece should have been because I got to tell you there's a fight and it Ends in about a minute.
Speaker 1: Someone my god, the fight is choreographed.
Speaker 1: It's not just people yelling.
Speaker 1: people don't say a word.
Speaker 1: One piece could have been so awesome.
Speaker 0: I like how we go from Student animation.
Speaker 0: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Why you should watch it to one piece sucks.
Speaker 1: Well, there's the thing and this just reminded me again because every time I see Anything about one piece or any art from one piece or anything from anything else that reminds me of one piece.
Speaker 1: I remember Oh, yeah, one piece has everything going for it.
Speaker 1: It's happy stylized pirates.
Speaker 1: Nothing could be more up my alley than happy stylized pirates unless there were also air pirates and had dragons, but One piece just didn't deliver.
Speaker 1: one piece is garbage.
Speaker 1: I can't stand that show.
Speaker 1: it goes on forever and nothing fucking happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just can't stand any show where stuff goes on forever.
Speaker 0: Nothing happened.
Speaker 1: You watched a lot of one piece.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch that one piece.
Speaker 0: I read 11 volumes of it, which I think I just talked about last two weeks ago.
Speaker 0: You talked about it recently at some point.
Speaker 1: But yeah, yeah, regardless.
Speaker 1: This animation is pretty cool and I like how it ends.
Speaker 1: That's all I want to say All right, my thing today.
Speaker 0: I had this thing of the day in the hopper for a while So of course is no longer on YouTube because the BBC must have told them to take it off YouTube.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna link to the BBC page about it and it's up to you to go find video of it.
Speaker 0: be that Legally or illegally it's it's up to you.
Speaker 0: Basically, you know spider-man, right?
Speaker 1: I know Spider-man.
Speaker 1: spider-man is spider-man.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It was the original.
Speaker 0: spider-man was written by Stanley and we talked about that before.
Speaker 0: But the who's the original artist who drew spider-man before anyone else?
Speaker 1: fuck if I know Stanley.
Speaker 0: no Stanley can't draw I don't know anything about comics exactly the original artist of spider-man with Steve Ditko.
Speaker 0: and there's a reason.
Speaker 0: nobody knows that except for Superhero fans.
Speaker 0: it's because he's a total recluse hermit Ha kind of like Bill Watterson sort of it pretty much.
Speaker 0: I mean after he quit.
Speaker 0: You mean well even while he worked for Marvel Comics, right?
Speaker 0: He wouldn't get he wouldn't interview with anyone.
Speaker 0: he wouldn't let anyone take his picture.
Speaker 0: He wouldn't you know make any sort of public?
Speaker 0: you know front of facing appearance of himself sort of the opposite of Stanley and I think he was quoted at least many places on the internet quote him as saying, you know I want people to.
Speaker 0: you know, just look at my work.
Speaker 0: and you know not consider, you know My personality in in the work, you know, just it's it's about my work.
Speaker 0: Look at my work.
Speaker 0: Don't look at me.
Speaker 1: Well, at least he didn't bold his drawings randomly.
Speaker 0: No He's actually if you take all that the words out of like an old spider-man comic.
Speaker 0: you can see Steve Ditko is pretty awesome with the the comic drawing but He drew a whole shit ton of comics for Marvel and he invented Doctor Strange and a whole bunch of other cool stuff and eventually Quit Marvel.
Speaker 0: He didn't say why he never said why.
Speaker 0: ha yep, and he's an interesting person to learn about man.
Speaker 0: He's actually an excellent artist.
Speaker 0: I like his art a lot.
Speaker 0: That's one of the reasons I still buy those big black books essential books full of Marvel comics Even though most of the comics are not the greatest because his art is awesome in there.
Speaker 0: But this thing of the day is a BBC documentary called in search of Steve Ditko And this guy named Jonathan Ross goes around talking to Steve Ditko's co-workers looking up everything He can find about the guy and I watched a bunch of it on YouTube before I got taken off.
Speaker 0: I didn't see the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll try to get a DVD or something.
Speaker 0: See me, you know, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think the BBC actually don't.
Speaker 0: they let you download their shows from their site?
Speaker 0: I don't know I don't know but it's a really cool documentary.
Speaker 0: You can learn about Steve Ditko and there's one part at the end.
Speaker 0: That's super awesome.
Speaker 0: You want me to tell you what it was?
Speaker 0: Probably because people might not be able to find the video All right, so at towards the end of the thing, right they find out Steve Ditko.
Speaker 0: They know he lives in New York and he works in New York and he still makes comics.
Speaker 0: He just doesn't work for Marvel or do anything famous.
Speaker 0: now They knew where his office was.
Speaker 0: so this Jonathan Ross guy and Neil Gaiman go they're like, we're gonna go up there We're gonna go up there.
Speaker 0: So there's a they don't you know, they have a cameraman.
Speaker 0: but basically in the in the documentary because I watch this part they don't actually like go up there because You know with the camera because they don't let the camera guy up there and he doesn't want to take his picture hidden camera YouTube.
Speaker 0: I know I know but you can get in trouble because it's in his private office.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just stand outside the office or whatever?
Speaker 1: he has to walk out So there's no one knows what he looks like.
Speaker 1: just take pictures of everyone who walks.
Speaker 0: He's like an 80 year old man now.
Speaker 1: So take pictures of everyone who walks out and then put a huge thing up where you're like.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: Anyone who recognizes any of these other people tell us so we can take him out of the list of possible people.
Speaker 0: he goes out The back door with a mask and he he goes out like spider-man swing on.
Speaker 0: No, but they went up there and then when they got down they talked about what happened up there and apparently he was really nice And he gave them comics and he talked to them for a while But he wouldn't do an interview and he wouldn't had let them take his picture, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: but yeah This is something really cool that anyone who cares about comics should probably pay attention to.
Speaker 0: and even if you don't care about comics The documentary is actually really interesting in more ways than one.
Speaker 1: So since we went super long yesterday talking about burning wheel Even though I get the feeling we said the same thing over and over again and not so many words But I get the same feeling as well, but I was super tired.
Speaker 1: This show might not be super long But at the same time to make up for the fact that we don't know how long we'll go about the show We were gonna talk about we're talking about two shows.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, luckily I don't have a lot to say about this show which is sad because I Expected when I saw the title of this show and when I saw the first two minutes of it that this was going to be The shit the business something awesome, but now Chibi kara go Nagai world is Gonna guys characters.
Speaker 1: you may remember going a guy from such things as what?
Speaker 1: Well, you you should know who going a guy is by now if you listen to geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what did he make?
Speaker 0: Devil, man, what else?
Speaker 0: devil lady what else?
Speaker 1: but this is a kind of anime of super deformed versions of his characters all fighting and interacting with each other and some sort of Weird, I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's really crappy and that's all I really have to say about it.
Speaker 0: I think the biggest problem with it is that it actually tried to make a plot to explain the super deformity.
Speaker 1: Not only that but it's really really really slow.
Speaker 1: You'd expect funny things to happen But no It's just a scene that takes forever and nothing happens.
Speaker 1: and these little super deformed characters Just talk and talk and talk and talk and talk and talk and sometimes they don't talk.
Speaker 1: They just walk and walk and walk and walk and walk and walk and none of the jokes are funny Even if you rather or not, you know what they're referencing.
Speaker 1: It's still not funny.
Speaker 1: It's gets a semi serious every now and then and it's so not worth watching and it's so much longer than it should be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we only watch like part.
Speaker 0: I think we watched one whole episode of it and if something's chibi It's got to be crazy and energetic with stuff happening all over the place and crazy fun time.
Speaker 1: It's got to at least be like dragon half.
Speaker 1: This is not dragon hand.
Speaker 0: This is like a really bad excuse to make some going a guy fan service.
Speaker 0: They took going a guy characters drew them in a chibi way and combined them all together in one sort of law drawn-out Slow plot.
Speaker 0: that's not interesting and is very cliche.
Speaker 0: and Blair and it could have been way cool I mean, you know get some messenger versus cutie honey.
Speaker 0: action could have been pretty awesome But no they didn't do that.
Speaker 1: So I guess you could call this a geek bite because it's so short, but I anti recommend this so hard.
Speaker 1: Just don't even think about watching it.
Speaker 0: Yes, if you're like some huge going a guy fanboy you might be able to extract some enjoyment from this But I don't know how much there's fast forward while you watch it.
Speaker 1: It's just so slow and you wouldn't expect something like that to be slow.
Speaker 1: You'd expect people to be killing each other.
Speaker 1: I couldn't.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even force myself to keep paying attention to what was going on while I was watching it and doing nothing else At the same time.
Speaker 1: I almost fell asleep.
Speaker 0: All right, we gotta talk about the show.
Speaker 1: really want to talk about the real show cuz I'm done with this crap All right.
Speaker 0: So the show we're actually gonna talk about today is called get cement.
Speaker 1: Oh, hey Kimina We might know it as that bunny girl show, right?
Speaker 0: We only watched one episode of it, but I think that's enough.
Speaker 0: now the story behind the show is this there is a another thing.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's an anime, but it's definitely a live-action movie and a manga and series of novels I think called densha otoko which translates to train man and The story of train man is I'm pretty sure it's a true story But it's sort of hard to tell these days because it's become sort of like a modern mythology of you know, this this otaku.
Speaker 0: He's a nerdy otaku in Japan and he's got no friends and no life But he's an otaku and he like helps some woman on a train, you know.
Speaker 0: Well, he's riding a train as you know even otaku ride the train and he helps some woman who's a normal woman and Then they fall in love and get married and live happily ever after.
Speaker 1: Ray.
Speaker 0: and in densha otoko There is an anime much like in genshi ken.
Speaker 1: you have the kuji biki unbalanced Which is I think I like genshi ken, but I really liked kuji bk.
Speaker 1: The problem is when they made kuji bk into an actual, you know anime because it was so popular They didn't make it as crazy as it was in genshi ken.
Speaker 0: Yep It should have been exactly as stupid and crazy as the genshi ken version was and it would have been awesome I agree, but it's sort of also like the itchy and scratchy to the Simpsons, you know, so Get cement.
Speaker 0: oh hey Kimina is the anime that is in densha otoko and This is that anime on its own.
Speaker 1: now I guess the one thing you'll have to know if you decide you want to watch this show is that it's not a show That's meant to be taken seriously.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, here's the plot of the show.
Speaker 0: You ready?
Speaker 0: There are aliens.
Speaker 0: Aliens like earth sports sound similar to buzzer beater.
Speaker 1: You're wrong You know, I'd forgotten about buzzer be.
Speaker 1: I know I had gotten past that in my life and you had to bring that.
Speaker 0: It's just funny that this two shows involving aliens and sports.
Speaker 0: You got to admit this.
Speaker 0: That's a strange coincidence.
Speaker 1: See we got to get bugs bunny in here because that was the members.
Speaker 1: I'll be jam.
Speaker 1: talk about that on a Thursday space.
Speaker 1: Yeah space jams pretty damn good space.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the original space jam awesome and add Newman in it Yeah, so there the.
Speaker 0: the thing is the aliens aren't playing sports, but they're fans of sports on earth and Occasionally those alien sports fans come to earth and they cause trouble because you know They're aliens and they're all you know, like a normal crazy sports fan,
Speaker 1: you know, it's like trouble
Speaker 0: in the stands.
Speaker 1: It's like if a Mets fan goes to a Yankees game and causes trouble.
Speaker 0: All right, but now you've got these aliens who are not only like bad fans, you know, they're troublesome fans But they're also aliens.
Speaker 0: they cause double trouble like, you know They're a giant pile of slime filling up the stadium or something like that.
Speaker 0: And you have this girl and this girl doesn't like carrots and She's trying to be like a TV anchor.
Speaker 0: That's like she's like an intern for the.
Speaker 0: they got a TV anchor in this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's also one of those high school student really cute really spunky really motivated kind of anime girls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Actually, she's not stupid, you know, and she's she says funny things and she yeah, she's not perfect.
Speaker 0: but then again, she's not just so dumb that you're like what the fuck's wrong with you and She's trying to do.
Speaker 0: this apprenticeship and at that part of the show with the apprenticeship for the TV station is sort of like Myko 2010. we have a mast of like a production crew for a show and they're all different kinds of characters Mixing it up and there's fun times.
Speaker 1: now a little warning Myko 2010 the anime is really really funny and worth watching.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just a bunch of these really short episodes about this radio station that has a robot for its you know radio show host.
Speaker 1: but Myko 2010 the anime is based on Myko 2010 the manga.
Speaker 1: and I remember once I see cuz we we saw Myko 2010 the anime at the RIT anime club when one of those are not
Speaker 0: here 2000
Speaker 1: because one of those who shall not be named fan sub did in his secret fan sub cloister and showed it to the club As like this special deal at a Saturday something.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, uh, it was all obscure No one could watch her find it.
Speaker 1: and then the manga came out and I saw it in the store And I thought hot damn the Myko manga.
Speaker 1: I'm totally gonna get this and I open it up and the first word I see is sex a bot.
Speaker 0: Yeah closes the original manga.
Speaker 0: Myko the robot Host was actually a robot sex bot that was used for being a show host instead of for sexing It's.
Speaker 1: it was really a creepy perverted manga and I don't recommend reading it.
Speaker 1: But I'm watching the show because it's really fun.
Speaker 0: The anime just removes all the pervertedness mostly and this has the same kind of vibe.
Speaker 1: and I'll warn you though that the other half Of the show, you know Scott's the other their production news anchors, whatever This girl is a superhero magical girl.
Speaker 1: She turns into a bunny girl and with carrot rockets on her butt, but yeah, he's carrots and the carrot rockets are really cute.
Speaker 0: I think she turns into the super cat bunny girl when she eats a carrot which she doesn't like something like that But she I think she forced herself to eat some carrots later.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, I've only seen one episode but there's like this bunny based like this rabbit fighting force of superhero people and They fight against the aliens who screw up the sports on earth.
Speaker 1: this part of the show has a very gatekeepers vibe just because when it when the funny girl wakes like awakens and all that business and it cuts to the bunny girl base on the moon and It's just yeah, it's yeah.
Speaker 0: pretty much this show is Gatekeepers plus mico 2010 plus a little bit of high school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but mine was no it has the same amount of high school.
Speaker 1: It's gatekeeper said what I guess what it lacks is the really dumb parts of gatekeepers at least so far because gatekeepers I got to admit really disappointed me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well the action parts of gatekeepers for the business though Yeah, and they only lasted one episode.
Speaker 0: They didn't drag him out They were all cool and choreographed and
Speaker 1: I think the problem with gatekeepers was that it didn't go anywhere And that I mean the best part of that show as far as I was concerned was the fact that the base was like under The school and no one ever knew.
Speaker 1: and those dust storms just randomly came the pointing commander.
Speaker 0: Oh, man Phoenix Wright's Godfather is God.
Speaker 1: we used to imitate that all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was kind of a thing.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's something about the pointing.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if if you're looking for a comedic anime, this is sort of recent I mean it came out January of this year.
Speaker 1: It's one of those.
Speaker 1: just don't worry about it.
Speaker 1: Just kind of sit back suspend your disbelief And roll with it and it's gonna be pretty funny that the main characters nemesis girl.
Speaker 1: She's one of those Nemesis, but she doesn't get annoying at least not yet.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I think there's 11 episodes according to anime news network.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really light-hearted and really fun And I mean there are other comedies out there But I I could see myself watching the rest of this one if I didn't have anything better to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like some amazing life-changing anime But if you're looking for fun times and you want to fill those fun times with some short cute funny stuff.
Speaker 0: This is gonna work pretty much for anybody unless you're not human.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.