Speaker 0: It's Thursday April 19th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we ramble a bit about taxes particularly income taxes in the United States of America.
Speaker 0: Because they're so awesome Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I haven't been wearing headphones during the show for the past couple of weeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, partly because we have a bunch of audio equipment a bunch of cables all the fancy stuff laying around.
Speaker 0: But we kind of got it all ad hoc.
Speaker 0: So the cable Scott was actually using to sit across the room and still have headphones Was probably the most dubious cable we have ever owned.
Speaker 1: Well, actually I bought that cable a long time ago like high school days so that I could Sit in my bed while still wearing headphones attached to the stereo across the room far away.
Speaker 0: I used to have a similar cable from what I wanted to record audio from my tape player to some other device in my house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically this the cable works.
Speaker 1: run one end There's a big hole so you can put in your big headphone cable into it And on the other end is a tiny stick that you put into the stereo to get the music to come out.
Speaker 0: the holes Jerry the hole the holes.
Speaker 1: I'm putting this in the non-technical terms And it's like 20 feet long so you can just run around the house all willy-nilly without worrying about it so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the old cable not working so well yep.
Speaker 1: So now that I'm podcasting I use this cable to get the headphones from across the room over to the mixer Which is sitting over on the other side of the room.
Speaker 1: of course what happened is after a time the cable didn't work so well and I Couldn't hear in one ear and I would have to like twist and turn the connector on the cable in order to hear in both Ears that like unplug it plug it back in and it just got worse and worse.
Speaker 0: You know you should.
Speaker 0: here's what it sounds like through my headphones because these are really fancy Expensive nice headphones that I got as a gift a hundred years ago fifteen years ago Yeah, and I think it was from my brother in fact, and they're.
Speaker 0: they're held together by tape and hope and that's about it.
Speaker 1: I had also good headphones that I bought for 40 bucks like in high school days.
Speaker 1: Those are the ones that I used with that cable Originally, but they were the kind that had foam not the foam that has like leather around it.
Speaker 1: just saw the foam like on the ear parts.
Speaker 1: ah and Over time that foam got nasty and disintegrated and bad stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there would always know there's nothing I could do.
Speaker 0: it always kind of rub off of those things into little horrible balls that stuck to everything yep.
Speaker 1: So I threw those out and even though they were really good when they were new yeah now I have these $20 shitty radio shacks where there's separate volume controls for each ear which is actually sometimes useful.
Speaker 1: We wouldn't expect.
Speaker 1: yeah Surprisingly basically they're crap, but they work well enough.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: meanwhile mine are awesome But they barely work, so I don't know which one of us is in a better situation.
Speaker 1: I don't know either.
Speaker 1: But I went to Radio Shack today because it's next to the grocery and I bought a new cable The same kind of cable only new and it works.
Speaker 1: and now I can hear again And I can tolerate wearing these headphones again.
Speaker 0: Yep, semi randomly though the Radio Shack moved everything around and they had a little flexible microphone arm.
Speaker 0: Well they've always had those yeah But I never really noticed him and it was actually cheaper than I thought it would.
Speaker 0: you just wanted to buy something.
Speaker 0: No, I actually had wanted something like this for a while.
Speaker 0: I just never noticed it at Radio Shack.
Speaker 0: I didn't really look too hard.
Speaker 1: I've seen him there before.
Speaker 0: well I got it and while I was walking out of the store I thought you know Radio Shack sells crappy microphones that are really light.
Speaker 0: I wonder if this thing will be able to hold up my very heavy real microphone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I probably don't need to worry about it.
Speaker 0: I came home.
Speaker 0: I put it all together I set it up and it immediately falls over in droops.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so now I've fixed the base to my desk until I get a heavy weight to stick under it.
Speaker 0: So there's some duct tape action there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Scott got the boom and I kind of got jealous because it's really nice to have the microphone Just hovering in front of you.
Speaker 0: You don't have to bend over.
Speaker 1: I mostly got the boom only because now I can have both hands on the laptop or whatever else I'm doing or you know, just hands-free without having to hold the stupid microphone Of course even better.
Speaker 0: my final important upgrade the thing that's bugged me forever was that I have as far an awesome CRT because I bought it.
Speaker 0: God knows how like eight years ago.
Speaker 1: That means CRT means old-style monitor.
Speaker 1: That's like a TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this thing is gigantic.
Speaker 0: It weighs an infinite number of pounds.
Speaker 1: No, because you can lift it.
Speaker 0: It uses quite a bit of electricity.
Speaker 0: It makes noises.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it makes smell.
Speaker 1: Yep, those things are all true.
Speaker 0: However, it works very well, and I would have kept it for a long a lot longer.
Speaker 1: It doesn't work as well as rim says it does but it works well.
Speaker 0: All right, leave it this way.
Speaker 0: It works a lot better than the LCD.
Speaker 0: I'm currently looking at.
Speaker 1: Uh, no, not really.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, that LCD is alright.
Speaker 0: Have you used this LCD for any amount of time?
Speaker 0: because the colors come and go.
Speaker 1: that's me.
Speaker 1: That's not the LCDs problem.
Speaker 1: That's the the computer.
Speaker 0: now I don't know mother before I plug it into the Mac I get issues with it.
Speaker 1: Really I didn't have issues when it was when we were using it at.
Speaker 1: katsu kana had no problems with it.
Speaker 1: I thought it was great.
Speaker 0: I'd keep angling it cuz sometimes the contrast would just go buggy for a while.
Speaker 1: I think you got a problem.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't have that problem.
Speaker 0: But anyway, yeah, the thing is also just ugly and not the greatest thing.
Speaker 0: It is an ugly but anyway LCD little known fact that one of the things I learned about audio early on.
Speaker 0: So I got this these microphones and I'm sitting there and I'm doing recording and drop trying it out.
Speaker 0: And then we go to do the show and I pick up this low hum and I do a bunch of research and I try To figure out where this hum is coming from.
Speaker 0: and I can't isolate it.
Speaker 0: No ground loops.
Speaker 0: Everything's fine.
Speaker 0: Look what the hell?
Speaker 0: Well, I bought these microphones.
Speaker 0: I get a hum.
Speaker 0: What's the problem?
Speaker 0: And then one day I my monitor I turned it off for some reason and the home was gone and I eventually figured out that because we were using dynamic microphones the moving alternating magnetic field from the CRT was Moving the actuator in the microphone at a number of Hertz equal to my refresh rate
Speaker 1: and it's true That's.
Speaker 1: that's what'll happen.
Speaker 1: So for anyone out there doing some podcasting action if you got microphones that are the dynamic variety Which you should which is condenser microphones are for suckers and rich people.
Speaker 0: Yep, or professional people, which you aren't Yeah, but even a lot of professionals actually use dynamic mics because they're not really worse.
Speaker 1: Yeah you Usually just get high-end expensive dynamic mics But anyway, uh Don't use them near a CRT and get an LCD if you can because there's no magnets in there The more there's no oscillating ones.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm buying a new computer soon.
Speaker 0: I talked about this for a while because this computer is barely alive Barely alive.
Speaker 1: It's it's like a miracle computer three more days.
Speaker 1: It's like the story of Hanukkah like one bit of oil last eight days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like one shitty ass bit of computer last eight years.
Speaker 0: I remember a month ago when I turned this computer off and it didn't turn back on Magically it turned back on an hour later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that should have been it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but real soon I'm gonna buy a new computer.
Speaker 1: Well, it would have.
Speaker 1: actually if you think about it The original plan was you were just gonna replace it with that Mac Mini, but the Mac OS didn't hold up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whose idea was that?
Speaker 1: It was a good idea.
Speaker 1: Everyone else agreed with me.
Speaker 1: It was a good idea on paper - we know what we both learned from that lesson.
Speaker 0: I will say it was a good idea on paper because when I actually analyzed it I agreed with you and I thought you know what Mac's are awesome.
Speaker 0: screw this non Mac bullshit.
Speaker 1: Well, at least you know, I considered everything you did and I looked at the piece of paper and said hey Everything rim does the Mac does.
Speaker 1: but we didn't know.
Speaker 1: is the Mac did it shitty?
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is the.
Speaker 0: the Mac would have been fine If I was also willing to pay for the requisite audio software as opposed to using the free things that don't work.
Speaker 1: True.
Speaker 0: also the fact that the thing is you technically paid for the garage band.
Speaker 1: It's not free Yeah, but I life that you pay for it in the price of the machine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had words about garage.
Speaker 0: Hey, I think people remember that two-week stint where I did nothing but bitch about it.
Speaker 0: Yep But I realized that LCD prices haven't come down in several months.
Speaker 1: so I just I'm gonna buy a gigantic widescreen LCD tonight and it'll get here probably Monday and So long CRT, yep I bought a lot of stuff recently too and I'm buying some more stuff and I'll probably tell you all about the things I am Buying next week.
Speaker 0: God, we're vinyl.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm buying this DS light in this monitor.
Speaker 0: You bought that awesome laptop.
Speaker 0: and now the laptop stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm buying stuff.
Speaker 0: We're buying speaker.
Speaker 0: We're just going on this spending spree.
Speaker 0: That's probably not going to end.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm looking at a new car.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not looking that far bought a car.
Speaker 0: Yeah paying for that thing Hey, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So anyway in the news, I don't think this is really news to any geeks.
Speaker 0: I want to bring it up only because it makes me feel Incredibly in tune with everything.
Speaker 0: That is awesome.
Speaker 0: But at the same time Incredibly old.
Speaker 0: you see the Simpsons as of today is 20 years old and I wait 20 years since it was on TV 20 years since Matt Groening thought about it 20 years since.
Speaker 0: on April 19th 1987 on the Tracy Allman show there was a two-minute animated short.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the first appearance Yes, and I saw that on TV with my family.
Speaker 0: My family loved the Tracy Allman show.
Speaker 0: I often would stay up and watch it and I watched every episode of the Simpsons from 1987 until when I went to college and gave up TV.
Speaker 1: think about this, right?
Speaker 1: The Simpsons were on when I was in elementary school.
Speaker 1: people kids talked about that like in fifth grade.
Speaker 1: I remember kids talking about the episode where he jumped over the gorge on the skateboard.
Speaker 0: In fact, the Simpsons when we were young was controversial.
Speaker 1: It was controversial.
Speaker 1: They were like, oh kids shouldn't be watching this.
Speaker 0: Yeah There were parents who would talk to my parents and say things like how do you let your kids watch that trash?
Speaker 0: and I'd love To go back in time and show them Family Guy?
Speaker 1: And people think that the censors are winning.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, but I mean like, you know it was controversial cuz it was a cartoon and up until then the closest to cartoon got to having mature themes was the Flintstones and Cartel.
Speaker 0: you mean the honeymooners animated?
Speaker 0: Yes with dinosaurs.
Speaker 1: I like the Flintstones though.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I really like the Flintstones to yeah a lot more than the Jetsons.
Speaker 0: Uh, see I like the Jets Different way.
Speaker 0: remember the movie where they meet.
Speaker 1: it's not a good movie.
Speaker 0: It's not that bad.
Speaker 1: But anyway What was I saying?
Speaker 0: I don't know right?
Speaker 1: Simpsons old elementary school geezers.
Speaker 1: Are we?
Speaker 0: yes old we feel now.
Speaker 1: Imagine the people who are like middle-aged when the Simpsons were new.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like when I'm all today.
Speaker 0: I was listening to it's all politics from NPR News and They were talking about the Tonight Show, but not with Johnny Carson, but with the guy before him Was a guy.
Speaker 0: I know that's what I thought I was like.
Speaker 0: what what are you talking about?
Speaker 0: There's no guy before Johnny Carson, and I never even saw Johnny.
Speaker 1: I never.
Speaker 1: actually I don't watch it now either.
Speaker 1: I never really watched any of those late shows.
Speaker 0: I'll admit I'd really until the Daily Show.
Speaker 0: I hated shows like and now I'm Supposedly making one I guess Wow.
Speaker 0: I never really thought of that.
Speaker 0: We're the red.
Speaker 1: I mean if we had we're imitating something We're not a fan of and we don't watch.
Speaker 0: the thing is I'm really a fan of the Daily Show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Daily Show isn't a late show though.
Speaker 0: It's no it's not it.
Speaker 0: I figure that it's the successor to the idea of the late show because time shifting has made that idea obsolete in my mind.
Speaker 1: You know granted a lot of people don't time shift yet People who are middle-aged when the Simpsons came out.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine that.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine scheduling my life or having to worry about when some when some form of entertainment I wanted to see was available to me.
Speaker 1: Yep All right, so I got a tech news, but it can't wait until Monday.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna give it to you.
Speaker 1: nice and easy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is some pretty good.
Speaker 1: This is the big news.
Speaker 1: It's all over.
Speaker 1: You can't possibly miss this unless you are completely detached from all internets.
Speaker 1: The new version of Ubuntu Ubuntu the feisty fawn is out.
Speaker 1: It's not a beta.
Speaker 1: It's not an alpha It's the real deal.
Speaker 1: You can go and get it right now.
Speaker 0: and I gotta say and this is coming from Captain cynic of the USS cynical about any advance in Linux technology Mister doesn't update software unless there's a reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or I resisted Firefox up until like 0.9 something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was using Firefox 0.6 when it was Phoenix.
Speaker 0: So I used what I used it when it was still.
Speaker 1: no I used Phoenix 0.5.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 0: I remember it might have been 0.7.
Speaker 0: I used it when it was Phoenix and then I bitched.
Speaker 0: when they changed it to fire bird and I didn't call it firebird.
Speaker 0: I kept calling it Phoenix and then they kept called it Firefox and then I started saying Firefox probably because I like Foxes and I like fire.
Speaker 1: see that was the point in time where I still believe that name changes wouldn't work.
Speaker 1: people would just rebel And keep the old name.
Speaker 1: and now I see the truth in that I like old names and I want to fight to keep them But it's always a losing battle.
Speaker 1: It was the last time you called the Wii the revolution game over.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: You know when the last time I called the Wii the revolution was when on an episode of this show when I said Fuck if I'm gonna call it the Wii.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: So for anyone out there if you've never tried Ubuntu if you're afraid of Linux if you're anti Linux if you tried Linux at one point you hate it.
Speaker 1: Maybe you already using it, which means you just update and I don't need to tell you anything.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: You should try this.
Speaker 1: there is absolutely.
Speaker 1: it costs you nothing except maybe I don't know a half hour of your Time as long as it takes to download a CD and there's absolutely no risk Whatsoever.
Speaker 1: you cannot possibly ruin your computer.
Speaker 1: You don't have to erase any of your data.
Speaker 1: You.
Speaker 1: this is there's no risk at all.
Speaker 1: You might well.
Speaker 0: Theoretically if you get the free CD from Ubuntu Ubuntu and the person who packages it has the Asian bird flu and it gets shipped to you.
Speaker 1: Okay, and then so here's what you do.
Speaker 1: Here's what you do.
Speaker 1: you ready?
Speaker 1: Step one make sure you have a CD burner.
Speaker 1: step two a blank CD.
Speaker 1: step three an internet connection.
Speaker 1: go to Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: calm Download dot-com.
Speaker 1: you got to stop saying that.
Speaker 0: I gotta say it's really.
Speaker 1: you know you say Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: I have to say boom - that's actually.
Speaker 1: it's like hurts when you say that in my headphones?
Speaker 0: really yes doesn't hurt me Whatever.
Speaker 1: so you go to Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: calm you click on That you go follow the links to the download section and it'll say what release do you want?
Speaker 1: you want desktop edition 7.04 which means April.
Speaker 1: oh seven seven oh four uh-huh ooh Yeah, boom - what type of computer do you have?
Speaker 1: you say you have a standard personal computer?
Speaker 1: But you might have another kind.
Speaker 1: just choose.
Speaker 0: yeah You'll know.
Speaker 0: cuz if you know it's the simplest form.
Speaker 1: then it says where do you live?
Speaker 1: you pick a country?
Speaker 1: And then you click start download.
Speaker 1: it will download an ISO file.
Speaker 1: you need to burn this ISO file to a CD.
Speaker 0: the way you do that is you use something like Nero or Roxio or I forget the name of it, but I've installed it on every Windows PC I've ever used.
Speaker 0: I'll post in the forums a link to it.
Speaker 0: But there's a thing.
Speaker 0: you can download that because Windows 2000 and XP might have been just XP I don't remember can burn.
Speaker 0: ISO is natively with no software.
Speaker 0: however Microsoft hid that from you, and you have to install a program that will open it up.
Speaker 1: yep But anyway you burn this ISO file to a CD.
Speaker 1: congratulations.
Speaker 1: Now you take the CD, and you keep it in your CD-ROM.
Speaker 1: You don't take it out.
Speaker 1: you restart your computer.
Speaker 1: Your computer should boot not from your hard drive But from the CD.
Speaker 1: if it does not boot from the CD And it just boots into Windows normally or boots into Mac normally Then you have to do some sort of.
Speaker 1: you have to change your BIOS or hold some key Combination or go to your boot menu to tell your computer to boot from the CD-ROM Before it boots from the hard drive.
Speaker 0: in fact if you are unable to make it boot Post in our forum, and we or someone will help you.
Speaker 1: yes I will tell you what you need to do to make it boot from the CD.
Speaker 1: But in most cases it should just boot from the CD.
Speaker 1: it might take a while But it'll boot from the CD and you'll say I would like to install or run Linux Ubuntu Linux, and don't worry It's not going to install yet.
Speaker 1: It'll just run and it'll run and it'll boot Ubuntu Linux from the CD.
Speaker 1: it won't write or read any data from your hard drive At all.
Speaker 1: none of your Windows data will be touched.
Speaker 1: you can try Ubuntu Linux Completely risk-free to see what it's all about and not have to worry about anything and when you don't want to use it anymore Just shut down the computer and take the CD out and you'll be back to Windows like Linux was never there.
Speaker 1: You have no excuse not to try this so that you can actually discuss it intelligently and with experience.
Speaker 1: You don't have to like it You don't have to switch to it and erase your windows and install Linux.
Speaker 1: But you have to try it because there's no reason not to at this point And this is the best Linux ever for desktops.
Speaker 1: do it now.
Speaker 1: What do you still listen to this for?
Speaker 1: I guess you could listen and solve the same thing.
Speaker 0: Ubuntu Things of the day now.
Speaker 0: because it was the 20th anniversary of the Simpsons I figured I should have another anniversary kind of thing for my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: well, it just so happens that this week was the one-year anniversary of Probably one of the oddest funniest Sadest and most painful to think about things that I've really ever seen on the internet.
Speaker 1: to talk about how significant This is.
Speaker 1: it was the only place that this existed on the internet was a story on Fark basically And I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't read Fark.
Speaker 1: I get Fark via other people talking about it, and I remember this.
Speaker 1: That's how big it was.
Speaker 0: now basically a Someone posted.
Speaker 0: he was a total Farker and he posted the following to Fark.
Speaker 0: now the way Fark works.
Speaker 0: if you post something It's kind of like dig whatever you submit stories And it appears in total Fark where only the super super super nerds who pay for total Fark which it costs real money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like five bucks.
Speaker 0: It's almost nothing, but it's real money.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is you get it.
Speaker 0: basically you see everything that's submitted to Fark.
Speaker 0: if you need to kill some time on the internet Total Fark is still by far the best way.
Speaker 1: well No, you can go to dig and put the upcoming stories, which is just as crazy I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think Fark is better because you get more of the information in a much more condensed and Immediate form perhaps, but either way it's a whole bunch of crap at a whole little bit of space.
Speaker 0: Well someone posted under the advice category quote.
Speaker 0: I am stuck to my chair I'm so very scared help uh-huh.
Speaker 0: and immediately in that he made a post And the post is I'm going to read it as far exactly all right without going into too much detail.
Speaker 0: Here's the situation.
Speaker 0: I am total Farking in my boxers and sitting on a chair that has slightly spaced out planks.
Speaker 0: Suffice to say that part of me is now lodged and any attempt to move just pinches the crap out of me.
Speaker 0: Can't move need advice Soonish.
Speaker 0: oh God it hurts.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's still funny that the second post is haha pull hard take video.
Speaker 0: the third post is a picture of Nelson from the Simpsons
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: What follows over the course of a far too many posts is The people who were on total Fark at the time and then real Fark because this was green-lighted to the main page Trying to help this gentleman get out of the situation.
Speaker 0: The situation was basically he has this kind of chair and the chair is a picture of the chair.
Speaker 1: Okay, I can't imagine it.
Speaker 0: You can just go to the threads.
Speaker 0: in fact the the end of this saga is a picture the guy took of himself flipping off the chair Not backflipping middle finger flipping.
Speaker 0: it's this kind of chair where it's.
Speaker 0: the seat is made out of like three or four pieces of wood like slats and There there's there's tiny tiny gaps between them.
Speaker 0: now The guy is kind of heavy so he sits down and the gaps all kind of spread out a little bit And if they pinch around something or something gets pushed in there from using the chair you get up Let's let's come back together and pinch it.
Speaker 1: So why didn't he just sit down some more to spread them out again?
Speaker 0: He tried and then as soon as he tried to get back up and pinched again.
Speaker 0: But you you sit down you lift up the boys and then ride and basically the thread is people saying smart things Like.
Speaker 0: we're saying well have you tried this?
Speaker 0: why don't you just do this?
Speaker 0: and he tries things they don't work And they're stuck in there pretty deep.
Speaker 0: This is the slats are pretty widely.
Speaker 0: It's not a good situation And that the epic saga that unfolded with people submitting various ideas The point at which I left out loud because I'm still working at IBM at the time And I was just sitting in my office following this thread over the course of is right away.
Speaker 0: Someone's like well.
Speaker 0: What's within reach of you, and the guy says what he can get to.
Speaker 0: and Someone's like should I call 9-1-1?
Speaker 0: whatever?
Speaker 0: and one guy says I see you have access to matches.
Speaker 0: the chair is made of wood.
Speaker 0: Right set it on fire problem solved.
Speaker 1: So true but yeah, this is a great moment in internet history that should be remembered for years to come and recognizing it on its anniversary is pretty good because People who didn't see it the first time can go back and see it again.
Speaker 1: and while I'm against old news And if someone would have come up to me and said hey, did you hear about this guy?
Speaker 1: I would have been like that is such old news, but saying hey There's old news to check out in case you missed it is okay.
Speaker 0: So the on FARC on the anniversary they had a thread the one-year anniversary of one of the funniest FARC threads of all time.
Speaker 0: and Early on in this thread there was someone who hadn't seen the original thread who saw a picture of the chair and basically said oh My god.
Speaker 0: I had a chair exactly like that.
Speaker 0: fuck that chair.
Speaker 0: That happened all the time.
Speaker 0: There's a picture of a chain link fence with two tennis balls.
Speaker 1: So this is a lesson to everyone.
Speaker 1: if you buy chairs do not buy chairs made with wood slats Yes, and do not sit in them in your boxers.
Speaker 1: get a office chair with a nice cushion.
Speaker 0: Yes You see remember the operative thing here is that one.
Speaker 0: the guy was using his computer in his boxers for long enough for the nuts To migrate into that little crack.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, and two this is if you can't visualize the situation Anyone who's used a trackball especially an older one a lot of times the edges of the trackball would like catch your finger and pinch You.
Speaker 0: it's a lot like that.
Speaker 0: That's only worse happening to your nuts.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're you're screwing him.
Speaker 1: I don't imagine the actual nuts getting stuck in there.
Speaker 0: I will point out from because he actually did post a picture of the business and They were in there a little deeper than you might have thought.
Speaker 0: Uh Now it wasn't like the worst possible situation where.
Speaker 0: imagine if the nuts were somehow beneath entirely and inside was just Like.
Speaker 1: I could imagine that maybe some like the connecting tubes would have been stuck.
Speaker 1: that could have been bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah This thread was hilarious and horrible and the funniest part of all this is that Fark made this thread linking to the original thread on The anniversary.
Speaker 0: now the original thread had been archived on Fark So it was either on a different server or handled a different way.
Speaker 0: the traffic from the main thing pointing to that.
Speaker 0: Fark Farked itself and brought his own archive down from the number of people clicking on this old thread.
Speaker 0: awesome super awesome My god, yeah, I just saw one of the old pictures and I'm laughing.
Speaker 0: it's an Oregon Trail Screenshot and they're in the river and the rivers flooded and it says big z2k got his nutsack stuck in a chair *laughter*.
Speaker 1: Okay anyway Some compare- by comparison my thing of the day is chump change, but it's still funny.
Speaker 0: That's okay cuz you've punned me a couple times on things of the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: it's a. basically it's a photograph of a mobile billboard and the billboard has a picture of a cop with a Radar gun pointing straight at you and it says speeding.
Speaker 1: What's your excuse?
Speaker 1: question mark.
Speaker 1: and I can't tell if it's actually spray-painted on the sign or if it's Photoshopped onto the sign but it doesn't matter what it says on the sign in spray paint or what looks like spray paint is Helping you bastards pay for donuts smiley face.
Speaker 0: I Got to admit I laughed out loud.
Speaker 1: I laughed quite a bit when I saw this one and if you're not laughing now go take a look and then laugh because it's funny and true.
Speaker 0: The fact that the smiley face is a little off-center and a little crooked for some reason that is the exact thing that did it To me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just the way the smiley face is painted Like.
Speaker 1: it's just perfect sort of like in that I am confident that this box contains cell phones Just the way the spider was grabbing his entire eyeball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the example I always go to for you know.
Speaker 1: Visual like image humor like when the image itself regardless of what the joke is is funny.
Speaker 1: Just to look at it, you know.
Speaker 0: All right today, so For those of you who live in the United States, you're aware that very recently Taxes were due where they do you this week.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah the 17th New York State being bitches said hey, they're due the 16th, but they were actually due the 17th, but I won't get into that No, but yeah, I don't know really how taxes work in other countries so much.
Speaker 1: I know you pay a lot more of them and some places a lot less.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot more.
Speaker 0: the thing is a lot of the places that you pay a lot more.
Speaker 0: It seems like you get more back per dollar.
Speaker 1: It's a tough call.
Speaker 1: we'd have to actually do some math to figure that out.
Speaker 0: Well, just in terms of I look at the social services that I see in various socialists and semi-socialist countries And not saying that they're all the greatest places to live but
Speaker 1: a lot
Speaker 0: of them Seems like not only do they take more of your money But they deal with the money more efficiently and you get enough back to where it's worth
Speaker 1: it.
Speaker 1: I think what it is that they spend most of the money on The people like the citizens as opposed to we spend the money on stuff.
Speaker 1: It's just not stuff that the citizens Oh, you mean like foreign wars of occupation.
Speaker 1: Well, no, not just that.
Speaker 1: yeah percentage-wise.
Speaker 1: That's not so much.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about stuff like farm subsidies where if you're a farmer you notice if you're not a farmer you don't notice or Stuff that you don't realize the government's paying for like keeping airlines in business.
Speaker 1: Yeah stuff like that.
Speaker 1: That's where a lot of our money goes into bullshit.
Speaker 1: instead of other countries They spend their money on things that go directly to people like medicine goes directly to people or school Which we do spend money on school, but not as much.
Speaker 0: Yep now we're not gonna get into a whole argument about Socialism and taxes and capitalism and all those things because our views are complex to put it lightly.
Speaker 1: Yes, we're gonna talk about the actual process of filing taxes in the United States and how not to be stupid about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now we're gonna generally.
Speaker 0: we're not gonna go into detail about how it actually works on the deep down.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna give tax advice either because I don't think we're allowed to do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also the advice I would give would pretty much be just fill out the form and mail it.
Speaker 1: It's not hard That's that's my advice.
Speaker 0: but more especially to those of you who aren't u.s.
Speaker 0: Ian's I don't think you understand the sheer level of Incompetence ignorance stupidity poor planning Hysteria and just mass chaos that goes with paying taxes every year.
Speaker 0: Yep Also how absolutely in crazily complicated taxes can be in the United States can be but don't have to be unless you do weird shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like own a house or go to school exactly.
Speaker 1: But actually if anyone is in another country in this episode, you know Maybe you should listen.
Speaker 1: just cuz it'll be interesting to hear how our taxes work and why we're crazy about them.
Speaker 1: But I want to hear how your taxes work cuz I really have no idea about Anyone else just like you probably have no idea about us.
Speaker 0: now very briefly.
Speaker 0: The United States is Ostensibly a federalist system and I say ostensibly with the weight of ten years of anger On my part to only ten.
Speaker 0: Well because I wasn't aware of How I felt about that issue until I learned a lot more about it.
Speaker 0: Well into that but we have states and we have.
Speaker 0: we have.
Speaker 0: we have towns - oh, yeah I'll talk about fucking Yonkers.
Speaker 1: We have towns states and the federal government itself and you have to pay taxes to all three of these Government bodies.
Speaker 0: Well, usually only two.
Speaker 0: that is why usually all the grace.
Speaker 0: But you see we Scott and I are residents of the city of Beacon.
Speaker 0: We are also residents of the County Duchess.
Speaker 0: we are also residents of the state of New York.
Speaker 0: we are also residents of the United States of America and that's about it and every piece along the way is semi autonomous.
Speaker 0: you see this it's changed over the years, but generally in the United States each state is on most matters an Entirely separate entity like its own tiny country and it can administer itself within certain guidelines.
Speaker 0: However, so it wants and some states are kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I states different in many ways Yep and not just in the way people act but in the way the laws are.
Speaker 0: there are a lot of things that are legal in One state or illegal in another state or like we were talking about in the forums.
Speaker 0: in Michigan You can just go get a handgun license by filling out a form.
Speaker 0: in New York You can't get a gun in New York City.
Speaker 0: You double can't get a gun or like in Florida.
Speaker 1: You can get Fireworks and in New York, you can get sparklers if you're lucky.
Speaker 0: Yep in Tennessee You can get what are effectively explosives and in Connecticut.
Speaker 1: You can't get anything.
Speaker 0: Yep in New York You can't even get those little snakes that don't do anything except start a small fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in some states you can buy alcohol anywhere at any time.
Speaker 1: in some states.
Speaker 1: You can't buy it on Sunday.
Speaker 0: You know I actually was a little bit chagrin once when I moved out of Michigan where it literally you just buy alcohol at the grocery store.
Speaker 0: You don't even think about it.
Speaker 1: Liquor liquor at the grocery.
Speaker 1: So I went like hodak.
Speaker 0: so I went to a grocery store outside of the state once and I was like Where's the booze section?
Speaker 0: and the guy looked at me with this look of what the fuck is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Yeah So the states are all different and all that and each state collects taxes.
Speaker 0: the federal government on top of that Collects its own taxes some of which goes to the states some of which goes to federal stuff some of which goes to Paying off the national debt.
Speaker 0: not gonna get into that either.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna talk about where the money goes.
Speaker 1: you're not about how they take the money from you not how they use it Yep And also towns and cities.
Speaker 0: some of them take taxes and this is just the income tax the tax that is taken off of any wages Anyone makes in the United States?
Speaker 1: Yes, the way this works is a Technically, they could do an income tax where every year they come along and they say how much money did you make?
Speaker 1: Well, this is how much money we're going to take from you.
Speaker 1: and the problem with that is of course if I made say a Million dollars in a year, which I don't make anywhere close to that and they came along at the end of the year And they said all right, how much money did you make this year?
Speaker 1: And I'd say a million dollars.
Speaker 1: They would say you owes two hundred thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, well I spent the million.
Speaker 1: So now I can't give you and that would be a big problem because pretty much everyone would spend all their money no one would have the enough left over to pay the tax and It would ruin the whole thing because they wouldn't have enough money to run the government.
Speaker 0: Yes The thing you have to keep in your mind is that the majority of Americans don't understand how the taxes work for one two don't understand how to do them or file them.
Speaker 0: and three have no concept of Actually paying attention to what you spend money on or budgeting or anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should use that SNL as a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: So the way it works is they have withholding.
Speaker 1: you fill out a form whenever you get a job and you could change the.
Speaker 1: you know You can refill out the form almost any time you want.
Speaker 0: Basically, the government will take the amount of money that based on a very rough metric They think you are going to owe over the course of the year and they take it out bit by bit of each of your paychecks.
Speaker 0: You have to worry about it.
Speaker 1: So you can write on this form for instance the number zero which says okay government take out a crap ton of money from my Paycheck every month every paycheck cover.
Speaker 1: often you get paid and the government will take money Before it even gets into your hands.
Speaker 1: Your employer is gonna pay you right whoever hires you to do your work and instead of giving you all the money in your salary They just give you most of it and they give another bit to the government and every paycheck They keep giving more to the government.
Speaker 1: the government holds on to it Yep.
Speaker 0: Now the problem here is that the way you determine unless you do it the complicated way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're gonna go real briefly over this.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get a lot simpler than what we're.
Speaker 0: the core course run now.
Speaker 0: But basically you tell the government about how much they should take out and they take that out.
Speaker 1: All right, no big deal.
Speaker 0: But if we're already paying it automatically, how come there's this big taxes time every year?
Speaker 0: The answer is the government always either takes too much or too little.
Speaker 0: and if they take too much Then you have to fill out a whole bunch of paperwork to get them to give the extra you paid back Mostly because the government isn't taking away from you the exact right amount.
Speaker 1: That's so difficult requires so much math to figure out the exact right amount The government should take from you and then if you get a raise or then if you do anything weird It's like such a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: So you tell the government kind of how much to take away from you automatically and they take it and they hold on to it.
Speaker 1: They invest it I hope wisely to get interest money on it and that's the government uses that to do stuff.
Speaker 1: and then at once a year You actually sit down and do a bunch of math to figure out how much you know of all the things you did in the previous Year, you know from January to December how much should the government really have taken from you?
Speaker 1: and then you take that number and you take the amount of money that you actually Gave to them and you figure out whether you owe the government more money or whether they got to give you some money back.
Speaker 0: Now here's the best part.
Speaker 0: if they owe you a bunch of money You have to fill out all this paperwork and then they send it to you without any interest.
Speaker 0: So you basically you've lost out on the opportunity to use that money for other things.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's you don't want to get a lot of money back.
Speaker 1: a lot of people like hooray I got a bunch of money back.
Speaker 1: Well because they're stupid that's cuz you're stupid if you gay You're basically let the government hold.
Speaker 1: Let's say I get $1,000.
Speaker 0: It's giving someone an interest-free loan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like that would be the same as if I lent rim $1,000 and then later he gave me back $1,000.
Speaker 1: Usually when you loan someone money they pay interest on it.
Speaker 1: So I would loan rim $1,000 and then when he paid it back a year later, he'd give me $1,100.
Speaker 0: why Scott are you familiar with our stage usury laws?
Speaker 1: Not really Okay No,
Speaker 0: but if you don't pay enough if they don't take enough out then not only do you have to pay it all back At the end of the year But if you're off by more than a little bit and you owe more than some small amount of money They actually penalize you and make you pay a fine on top of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they will come and the worst is if you do anything wrong, they'll come and get you again.
Speaker 0: Yes in fact now you have to fill out all these forms and you have to keep everything you fill out for three years and any time during Those three years.
Speaker 0: the government.
Speaker 0: Well, not the government the IRS Not gonna get into that either.
Speaker 1: No, we're not.
Speaker 1: it's basically what it comes down to is every year You have to figure out on paper or using computers or somehow how much money you actually owe the government.
Speaker 1: Then you have to either pay the government the money you didn't pay or they give back the money that they took extra Which you don't want either.
Speaker 1: one of those you and if you had it, perfect You wouldn't owe them anything and they wouldn't know you know anything.
Speaker 0: if you had it Perfect, you would owe them the exact amount One cent short of having to pay a penalty.
Speaker 1: No, that's true.
Speaker 1: Yes But Yeah, then I forget where I was going right.
Speaker 1: if you mess up and you do this math wrong at all There's a chance that they might notice you did the math wrong.
Speaker 1: Usually you have to do it really wrong for them to be a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also if even if you do it wrong They're not gonna do much to you except fix it and amend how much money you owe or get back.
Speaker 1: But there is a chance that if you do it really wrong you could go to jail.
Speaker 1: You could be in serious shit for doing it wrong now or lying or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Luckily the vast majority of people who get audited by these sorts of checks and get in a lot of trouble Didn't just make an honest mistake.
Speaker 1: They were actively trying to scam Yes A lot of people you see because the government is nice and that they let you do this math.
Speaker 1: instead of them doing the math For everyone and investigating your personal business They let you fill out the paperwork To tell them how much money you owe the government according to all the rules that they set
Speaker 0: for despite the fact that The numbers you put in are filed with the government anyway, so they already have a lot of this information.
Speaker 0: They just haven't put two and two together unless they really feel like doing so Yep.
Speaker 1: but yeah If you lie a lot on purpose or try to get out of it or try to get the government to give you back a Bunch of money where you actually owe them money or anything scammy or anything sleazy or anything like that They'll come after you and put you in jail and it kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: now even better Talk about how we had to pay federal taxes to the government and state taxes to our state government.
Speaker 0: Well, every state has its own tax laws and its own tax forms And they're all completely different from one another and completely different from the federal one
Speaker 1: Yep, so while everyone in the country does the same federal taxes with the same rules that change every year though But it's the same set of rules for everybody.
Speaker 1: Every state has a different set of rules as well and those rules change every year and you basically have to keep Taking this test every year to figure out something and it keeps changing.
Speaker 0: yeah, basically every year you go to the post office or if you're if I guess if you're on the government radar as being some Sort of productive citizen they'll mail you a gigantic book that tells you how to fill out your taxes.
Speaker 0: it's basically a textbook full of forms and full of instructions and It's a mess.
Speaker 1: and then it says like, you know, all right start here, you know Put this information here from the form that you got in the mail a few weeks ago.
Speaker 1: you know the and all the forms have names like w2 I 1040 something something and it's really.
Speaker 1: it's like they purposefully make it as obtuse as possible.
Speaker 1: They could just say, you know the name of the form like how much money you made form how much money you owe.
Speaker 0: Think of this.
Speaker 0: they're they're like.
Speaker 0: the worst part is not only that but it's some forms are optional some forms you can use if you want but they're not as good at getting you more money back and What it really comes down to is that you can do.
Speaker 0: the taxes are really really simple to do in this country Unless you're very rich.
Speaker 1: all you have to have or doing something weird with your finances But all you besting.
Speaker 0: but even if you do stuff like that The only thing it takes out of you is time and intelligence.
Speaker 0: You have to sit down Read a bunch of instructions follow the instructions.
Speaker 0: If you just go through the book read everything put every number in and follow it from start to finish in the end Your taxes will be 100% right as long as you were smart enough to read the instruction and use the calculator.
Speaker 0: The problem is the instructions are very long and very obtuse at least to the average American and a lot of people Honestly don't understand the instructions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's just because they shouldn't have graduated high school.
Speaker 0: and here's the best part.
Speaker 0: Generally not understanding the instructions or not knowing how to do the complex thing won't get you in trouble.
Speaker 0: In fact, it'll work just fine and they encourage you to use the simpler methods.
Speaker 0: But the simpler you go The less money you're gonna get back because now you're not filling out the forms to get the extra money The government technically owes you like.
Speaker 0: for the federal There's the form you fill out in the United States for the federal government is the 1040.
Speaker 0: That's your main federal tax form and it's gigantic and long and the thing is the vast majority of it Doesn't apply to most people.
Speaker 1: they basically says hey, did you do this weird thing with some capital gains?
Speaker 1: No, did you do this weird thing?
Speaker 1: Did you buy like a boat?
Speaker 1: Did you invest in some company or buy a company?
Speaker 1: or or did you sell stock or something?
Speaker 1: No And then you skip like big chunks at a time every time you say no.
Speaker 0: So people they made a much simpler form called the 1040 a which you could fill out instead.
Speaker 0: now There's rules.
Speaker 0: some people aren't allowed to use that form.
Speaker 1: Just like there's also an easy form, which is really Oh God See they made.
Speaker 1: are the anyone's allowed to use that?
Speaker 0: actually?
Speaker 0: no most Americans qualify for that.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: I used to qualify for it, but not anymore.
Speaker 0: The only remember.
Speaker 0: there's two.
Speaker 0: there's qualifications where if you don't meet them, you can't use the easy form.
Speaker 0: There's also a lot of times you could use the easy form, but you shouldn't cuz you'll lose a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Yep, I could only use the easy form when I was making chump change in college and high school.
Speaker 1: Yes, I got a real job.
Speaker 1: I made too much money.
Speaker 1: I wasn't allowed to use the easy form anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've never actually been able to use the easy.
Speaker 1: easy form is so easy.
Speaker 1: It's like who cares if you're not getting the money back.
Speaker 1: It's so worth it.
Speaker 1: Just to have this one page God you write down how much money you made but basically like two things you're done.
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: the less apt or capable you are or the less you are able to do or just You are or lazy or any of that the simpler forms you go The more money you're gonna end up paying to the US government that actually you didn't really owe them or you won't get credits You were supposed to get or all sorts of things.
Speaker 0: basically you pay for laziness by not getting the most bang for your buck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now there is a way around this.
Speaker 1: there are people who as a living they will prepare your taxes for you.
Speaker 0: This is a many many million dollar industry.
Speaker 1: Yes, the big names are like H&R block and TurboTax which is a computer Software where H&R block is a store that sort of.
Speaker 1: it's a temporary store Like they open up these stores in like April and then they close them after April.
Speaker 1: but you go there and you bring all your paperwork with you and someone else will fill out your taxes for you and supposedly they will fill them out in a way that gets you a lot more money back than you could figure out because they're experts and they know all the way to fill out taxes and they know the shit and You know for the most part.
Speaker 1: I guess they do fill out the taxes faster than you would because they know what they're doing.
Speaker 1: they've done it a thousand times and They might do it better than you because they know things that you don't know.
Speaker 1: but then they charge you money.
Speaker 1: So I could go and do it myself and maybe I'd get $200 back for the government.
Speaker 1: I can go have them do it and I'll get $400 back from the government But then I'll have to give two hundred dollars to the guy who just filled out the forms for me.
Speaker 1: So you end up not making anything.
Speaker 0: see now my entire life I've always done my taxes entirely by myself even when I was well I didn't really have a job in high school, but right after high school when I got my first job I just right away sat down.
Speaker 0: Try the 1040 easy found out I couldn't use the 1040 easy because I cashed a bunch of bonds for college to buy a computer.
Speaker 0: I used a 1040 a. Use the 1040 a the next year and the next year and now I fill out a regular 1040.
Speaker 1: Yep I just in high school and like the days I said I used the 1040 easy Which is really easy and I just didn't care because that's the amount of money was so small.
Speaker 0: Now here's the best part about all this.
Speaker 0: most Americans wait until pretty much the day before to suddenly decide to do their taxes and Actually, all the post offices are usually open on the tax deadline until midnight.
Speaker 0: yeah, and you like you'll try to go to a post office on the day taxes are due and there'll be an infinite number of people there and Mailboxes will fill up like you'll go to a mailbox in the street and it'll be full Thing.
Speaker 1: I can't blame people for mailing it at the last second because let's say you can do your taxes in January if you want Which I did him in February March I don't remember but let's say the gut.
Speaker 1: I owe the government a hundred dollars extra this year, right?
Speaker 1: Because I didn't pay enough.
Speaker 1: They didn't take enough out of my paycheck.
Speaker 1: I If I file in January, I'm gonna owe them $100 in January.
Speaker 1: You got to pay right away.
Speaker 1: I have to send a check with the forms.
Speaker 1: if I wait until the last second then the government holds on to my money for Less time.
Speaker 1: so it's better.
Speaker 1: that doesn't excuse you doing the math at the last second.
Speaker 1: You could do the math as soon as the year is over.
Speaker 1: the math isn't gonna change.
Speaker 1: So Mailing it on the last day I can't blame people for that because you should mail it at the last possible second if you owe the government money.
Speaker 0: Actually, what I usually do is I file my federal return real early because they always owe me a bunch of money.
Speaker 1: I guess no matter what I owe you money You want to send it as soon as possible to get that money back as soon as possible.
Speaker 0: Well, the feds always just screw up and take too much no matter what I do.
Speaker 0: But the state of New York is spot-on and every year I'm within like five or ten dollars.
Speaker 0: New York State.
Speaker 1: Only eight owed me 80 bucks this year, which is the most ever like last year.
Speaker 1: They owed me like 50 cents.
Speaker 0: this year.
Speaker 0: they owed me $24, however, that was because one and Fucking Yonkers.
Speaker 0: So when I first moved to New York, I had to fill out this crazy stupid long form for New York State taxes and it was doubly complicated because I had also had a job in Michigan that year and Michigan didn't care.
Speaker 0: So Michigan was easy to deal with.
Speaker 0: New York was like you worked in another state.
Speaker 0: Well, good luck.
Speaker 0: fill out this and this and this and this and this and this and this.
Speaker 0: you asshole How dare you work in another state?
Speaker 0: But there was this whole section where one it was like if you were a resident of New York City.
Speaker 0: Oh my god extra paperwork.
Speaker 0: All right, I expect that.
Speaker 0: New York City, you know But the best city in the world with crazy number of people there.
Speaker 0: If you live in Yonkers all this crazy stuff and I thought Yonkers and then said if you work in Yonkers But do not live in Yonkers If you work in Yonkers and live in Yonkers what?
Speaker 0: and then I know I just always laughed like a Yonkers.
Speaker 0: Haha, that's a funny name for a place.
Speaker 0: and while they have weird taxes.
Speaker 0: Well, I didn't really think about it until tax time this year, but the new job I got my office is in Yonkers.
Speaker 0: Oh I just that totally didn't even think about it until I sat down to do my taxes and I was like But up it up it up it up it up working Yonkers and I'm about to put zero.
Speaker 0: and then I think oh fuck.
Speaker 0: But so with the Yonkers tax it was dead.
Speaker 0: even I owed New York State nothing.
Speaker 0: It was like a five cent thing.
Speaker 0: It was perfect.
Speaker 0: I had done it right for the first time ever.
Speaker 0: I was perfectly set and then I noticed that there's a credit if you make less than like a hundred thousand Dollars in Yonkers.
Speaker 0: and I qualified for it because I'm a man and an adult and I have a job and all that business Mm-hmm, and the credit was just enough to get me like 20 bucks back.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, yeah Yonkers charges like this point something percent tax on any money anyone makes in the city if they don't live there.
Speaker 1: Yep, unlike rim I do my taxes with software instead of doing it on paper.
Speaker 1: just because I don't do anything on paper I avoid paper at basically every possible turn.
Speaker 0: The reason I use paper is really stupid and I'm not going to use paper next year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I feel dumb.
Speaker 0: So I'm not even gonna bother telling you guys why I do it the long hand way.
Speaker 1: It's some reason that you won't be able to defend.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, no, no, no, I can defend it.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: I e-filed online with with all the online stuff for free.
Speaker 0: But I did it when I was at RIT and then the next year I thought alright I'm gonna e-file again and I went in and basically to e-file again.
Speaker 0: I had to have a few exact numbers from certain fields from my previous e-filing.
Speaker 1: You know if you forget those there's still ways you can go I know.
Speaker 0: but that year I waited until the last minute and by then it was too late and the paperwork I would have had to fill out to be able to e-file.
Speaker 0: I couldn't do it in time I wasn't worth it.
Speaker 0: So I do it longhand and then I stashed the paper somewhere forgot about him lost him the next year.
Speaker 0: this year E-file.
Speaker 0: ah crap.
Speaker 0: I still don't have the numbers and I waited too long.
Speaker 0: God damn it this year.
Speaker 0: I got the fucking papers.
Speaker 0: They're sitting in my file folder.
Speaker 0: I'm ready for next year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see when I e-file I always at the end when it says print out the stuff I print out the stuff and then I keep it.
Speaker 1: and then next year when it says hey Do you remember these numbers I go back to the printout from last year and there they are.
Speaker 0: I just hate keeping records and I tend to throw things away right away.
Speaker 1: I still need to get a file cabinet because I right now have just a pile of papers.
Speaker 1: That's not too good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I need to go through that.
Speaker 0: my file cabinet is slowly becoming disorganized.
Speaker 1: But yeah, when you do it online, it's a lot I guess easier on the brain even though it's not the best.
Speaker 1: What you do is first you have to find a website to do it.
Speaker 1: There are a bunch of websites to do it at and I do TurboTax because I trust it more than the others even though I don't like the company and I think they're evil.
Speaker 1: But well, I know that they're not gonna fuck me and I know that it's gonna work and it's not.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get screwed I have a bone to pick.
Speaker 0: Yeah about that.
Speaker 0: now I'm gonna go over this issue very briefly But here is an example for all of you foreigners out there all of you non citizens of the proud and wonderful United States of America.
Speaker 0: You see the IRS and you do taxes through this organization called the IRS the Internal Revenue Service and They set up e-file where you can file electronically.
Speaker 0: because one they save a lot of money.
Speaker 0: so basically our tax dollars become more efficient if they do it electronically.
Speaker 1: because now is the IRS costs money to run and The more money we spend running the IRS That basically tax money is lost.
Speaker 0: this saves money because now there's no way.
Speaker 0: I mean You don't have to hire people to sit there.
Speaker 0: look at some assholes handwritten form.
Speaker 0: Figure out whether that's a four or a nine and type it all in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't have to print as many books You don't know.
Speaker 1: it saves a lot of money to do things electronically.
Speaker 0: So alright, the government obviously says well It has to be free to e-file because otherwise that that's not cool and all this business.
Speaker 0: so alright, the IRS is gonna set up a way where you can just e-file and it'll be great.
Speaker 0: the Companies that do taxes for people made a big stink and lobbied and basically forced the government Because the government can't compete with private industry Even though this private industry exists solely Because of a required thing that all American citizens have to do to interface with their governments.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they basically got it set up that the IRS is not allowed to let you e-file with them directly for free.
Speaker 0: Instead you have to go to one of these companies.
Speaker 0: now the agreement was that alright these companies have to offer a Free way of e-filing and these companies hide that fucker as best they can in like the bottom back corner of their website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if some of them don't link to it at all that some of them I swear to God.
Speaker 0: They have a website.
Speaker 0: you can pay for them to do your taxes and do it online.
Speaker 0: You have to find the website they have up that is not linked to by them anywhere.
Speaker 0: that lets you do it the freeway.
Speaker 1: Yes, for example, you go to TurboTax.com.
Speaker 1: TurboTax.com says hey you want to file your taxes TurboTax You can spend 10 bucks to get this.
Speaker 1: you can spend 30 bucks and we'll do it even better.
Speaker 1: You can spend 50 bucks and we'll do it the best we can.
Speaker 1: hallelujah.
Speaker 1: If you go to the IRS website There's a link there to TurboTax in the back door of TurboTax.
Speaker 1: that lets you use TurboTax for free Because they have to.
Speaker 1: that's.
Speaker 1: the only way to do it is to go in the secret back door.
Speaker 1: If you end up paying money to use TurboTax You're a fool because you didn't have to.
Speaker 0: now the other great thing is that there's no such rule for the state taxes.
Speaker 0: So every place they'll do your federal taxes, then they say you want to do your state taxes with us to only 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the thing is I ended up actually having to pay to do the state taxes because some places will do the state taxes For free and but they have rules like we'll do this state tax for New York for free if you make less than X dollars Or we'll do these states, Connecticut California, Kentucky, Ohio for free if you make less than $30,000.
Speaker 1: so depending on how much you make and where you live you might be able to do your state taxes or free online somewhere.
Speaker 1: But I Now make enough money where I can't.
Speaker 1: so I had to pay money to do the state taxes online And I just said fuck it.
Speaker 1: I just paid.
Speaker 1: it was 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: big deal thing is.
Speaker 0: next year I'm probably gonna pay because I I'm not.
Speaker 0: it's not that hard to do your taxes and all the people who panic about it I think are just lazy or Not that bright when you do ever.
Speaker 0: however New York state taxes are so Stupidly obtuse it just it sucks to do them.
Speaker 0: It is painful.
Speaker 1: That's the reason I do it online because when you do it online all it Does is hey it asks you a question in almost plain English, and if you're unless you're an idiot You don't know anything about your own finances, which case you have a problem?
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's easy to answer all these questions Yes or no most of them and the ones that aren't yes or no.
Speaker 1: we're like type in your name type in how much money you Made.
Speaker 1: you just go down the list and it keeps asking you questions one after another.
Speaker 1: It asks you so many questions though it takes like 90 minutes to do the whole thing.
Speaker 1: But when you're done it says okay, you're done.
Speaker 1: It's not much money.
Speaker 1: click.
Speaker 1: Okay type in your credit card number.
Speaker 0: now Here's the thing that got me when I first II filed way back, and I thought it was great.
Speaker 0: So I did my federal taxes.
Speaker 0: It was free.
Speaker 0: and then it comes up with the state tax.
Speaker 0: it says you want to pay 20 bucks to do the state And I said you know what fuck you I'll do the state ones in paper, so I said no and then it popped up another window.
Speaker 0: that said warning Many states will not accept or will blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And it basically said that if I II file federal and try to file state paper That it'll mess up my taxes and I'll have trouble down the road which as far as I can tell is as close to a lie as they can legally get.
Speaker 0: and That infuriated me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty much a lie.
Speaker 0: I saw through it but I think a lot of people wouldn't because it comes on with an air of authority and you Wouldn't think that people would lie outright about something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a good thing.
Speaker 1: My friend's dad is a tax lawyer.
Speaker 1: if I actually saw that message I would have called him up and been like hey hey, and he would have been like huh, huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah, luckily for the first time in a long time I didn't have to do anything complicated for my taxes So I didn't have to worry not like when we moved and I had to deal with all those Moving things to get money back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what it comes down to is you know you can take your standard deduction Or you can itemize your deduction don't?
Speaker 0: we're not gonna get into I know.
Speaker 0: Basically you can either take a default value for a lot of things or you can figure it out manually.
Speaker 0: and figuring it out Manually can save you a lot of money But it's very hard to do and you have to keep records of every goddamn thing you do all year.
Speaker 1: the other thing is Even if I figured it out manually I know the answer to figuring it out manually is less than the default value.
Speaker 1: So I always take the default value until I do something weird where that'll make my manual answer increase.
Speaker 0: I've actually done it manually twice.
Speaker 1: I mean I do try to do it manually but it like very quickly.
Speaker 1: as soon as I do all the big-ticket items It's like oh, I'm there's no way I'm gonna beat the default number and I stop and I just go with the default.
Speaker 1: yeah You just check it every year to make sure.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: We're talking about the income tax now.
Speaker 0: remember that in America We also have sales taxes property taxes gas taxes that are separate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well sales taxes.
Speaker 1: basically whenever you buy something you that price goes up.
Speaker 1: So like in New York State's like 8% tax I think we pay.
Speaker 1: I don't even know if I buy something.
Speaker 1: if I buy a hundred dollar video game that doesn't exist.
Speaker 1: There's no hundred dollar video game, but all right.
Speaker 0: Let's say I buy OGO all right.
Speaker 1: Let's say I buy two fifty dollar video games at the video game store.
Speaker 1: right the guy will say 108 dollars, please That's the sales tag.
Speaker 0: now the thing is the sales taxes are almost always state taxes.
Speaker 0: And here's the fun bit that relates to the internet.
Speaker 1: every state is different.
Speaker 1: sales tax go, Delaware.
Speaker 0: Not only is every state different in that regard But there is an idea called a use tax.
Speaker 0: and basically in America if I live in New York Let's say I buy a computer online, and they don't charge the sales tax online because they're not in New York.
Speaker 0: They don't want to deal with New York's boy.
Speaker 1: I bought a computer from some computer company.
Speaker 0: if I don't on my own keep track of every single thing I buy Online where sales tax was not charged for New York.
Speaker 0: I have to report that and pay a use tax on it.
Speaker 0: furthermore It's not just online.
Speaker 0: say I drive or I'm on a road trip, and I pass through.
Speaker 0: I don't know Delaware, Pennsylvania And in Pennsylvania I buy something and then I bring it back to New York and use it.
Speaker 0: in many cases I have to report that and pay a use tax on it technically.
Speaker 0: furthermore in Men in some cases if you go to a different county in the same state and buy like clothes there You have to report that.
Speaker 0: It's such a bullshit thing and it's so complicated and stupid.
Speaker 0: But the government is your friend like the computer and the government wants to help you and make it easy.
Speaker 0: so the option is either keep track of it all and based on all your receipts and everything report the exact amount you owe or There's a handy-dandy chart you can look at to guess what you should owe and it's probably more than what you do.
Speaker 0: But you're always safe picking that option as opposed to doing it.
Speaker 1: man You always pick that option because it's always less than what I do.
Speaker 1: Oh because I buy a lot of shit online.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: if it's actually less then you can get audited and fucked.
Speaker 1: I know I know but whatever yeah It's basically a hey.
Speaker 0: if you pay us 20 to a hundred dollars depending on how much money you make and all these other factors You're a lot less likely to get audited on all that shit you bought on the Internet.
Speaker 1: The thing is I'm not actually sure if it's less or not.
Speaker 1: I've never actually bothered to figure it out.
Speaker 1: The thing is I just keep paying the estimate every year.
Speaker 0: I'll be honest.
Speaker 0: I pay the estimate because I don't want to get in trouble and - I honestly don't keep track.
Speaker 0: I'm not trying to scam.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna keep track of every single thing I buy for a year and whether or not I bought it on a site in New York and whether or Not sales tax was paid and to what state it was paid and what I'm supposed to owe.
Speaker 0: and it's I'm not gonna do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think that's entirely unreasonable.
Speaker 1: to expect anyone to keep track of everything they buy Every and where the things they buy and how much tax they paid on it That's just completely unreasonable and I refuse to do it no matter what.
Speaker 1: if they come after me for it I'm just gonna do some Gandhi action on them.
Speaker 0: We'll have a great show if that ever happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, Delaware is a great state because they don't charge sales tax.
Speaker 1: So you can just go to Delaware by TV and if you ignore the use tax You can just bring it back to whatever state you live in.
Speaker 1: and you know two video games in Delaware cost $100.
Speaker 1: all right, we've got $0.99 in Delaware and you give them a dollar.
Speaker 1: they give you one penny back.
Speaker 0: We've gone on long enough.
Speaker 0: I think yeah, that was entirely incoherent and rambling.
Speaker 0: We didn't really have a point a moral a lesson or anything.
Speaker 1: We think well, I think the point is stupid.
Speaker 0: people don't know how to use taxes But they still suck to do even if you're smart.
Speaker 1: People in other countries now understand how American taxes kind of work barely sort of.
Speaker 0: no All they understand is that it's a frustrating and complicated process that sucks.
Speaker 1: and we just did it and had to do it.
Speaker 0: And yeah I think one of my favorite tax jokes ever was on the Simpsons way back when it's tax time and The news has this thing about everybody's rushing doing their taxes at the last minute and Homer sits there He says suckers.
Speaker 0: I did my taxes last year.
Speaker 1: Hahaha All right.
Speaker 1: So one last thing before we're done here this Saturday, so if this is Thursday night We're recording this tomorrow's Friday.
Speaker 0: the next day is Saturday the 21st the penultimate rim waiting for buying his computer Day day and the 21st of April 2007 from 1 p.m..
Speaker 1: To 1 a.m.. Yes, ooh weird hours at Marist College University and you can find Marist.
Speaker 0: yeah Marist Marist in New York State it's in the Mid Hudson Valley kind of downstate near the Hudson River.
Speaker 1: Yes, kind of near where we live near the city of Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 1: It's over there.
Speaker 1: We are going to be there because they're having an event called gaming for hope that we went to it last year as well.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's just a nice gaming party.
Speaker 1: They got console games.
Speaker 1: they got Land parties.
Speaker 0: they got they have generally copious amounts of various caffeinated beverages.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this you know and it's free absolutely free.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's like.
Speaker 0: there's a Suggested donation and the money goes to a good cause.
Speaker 1: yep They have raffles and they sell pizza and stuff in order to make money.
Speaker 0: Oh god They sold pizza like at eight different intervals throughout last time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they take all that money.
Speaker 1: They donated the child's place and then actually making anything off of it And it's basically a school gymnasium full of gamers for 12 hours.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of fun.
Speaker 1: We'll be there if you're anywhere within driving range.
Speaker 1: You should probably go as well for fun.
Speaker 0: It's well worth it.
Speaker 0: We're gonna bring a bunch of German board games.
Speaker 0: We'll probably have our DS's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely a lot of DS action going on last year.
Speaker 0: I remember it was just after Tetris came out and Metroid hunters Yeah, but it was mostly Tetris action that was going on and we played a lot of Mario Kart 2 And I schooled a bunch of nubs though.
Speaker 0: I think my skills have dropped off since I haven't played the game in like seven months.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure that this year there'll be Probably some puzzle quest if you have it, we don't have it some Diddy Kong probably still some Tetris.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't know.
Speaker 1: Pokemon is not gonna be out yet, huh?
Speaker 1: So probably not Pokemons yet, but it's gonna be a fun time this Saturday and Maris.
Speaker 0: So gaming for hope and also if you have to be around New York City.
Speaker 0: Scott Emily and I are going to the Mets game on Sunday Not that you have any way of finding us.
Speaker 1: No, where are we gonna sit?
Speaker 1: I've never sat like.
Speaker 0: I got the tickets But they're out of reach.
Speaker 0: so I'm not gonna bother looking.
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: Okay I've never actually sat in the red seats before which are the highest up seats cuz it's a stadium.
Speaker 1: It's like orange is the closest seats then blue then green then red and red is the upper deck.
Speaker 1: like upper deck.
Speaker 0: I figure Emily got him super cheap and we have nothing else to do and it'll be a fun day.
Speaker 0: Plus it's gonna be sunny.
Speaker 0: God damn.
Speaker 1: Yep Even if the game sucks, which I don't think it will I always like going to a baseball game.
Speaker 1: Just sit outside and the warmness and yeah.
Speaker 0: But if you're the enjoyment if you're a superfan and for whatever reason you can't get to gaming for hope and you really want To hang out with us Let us know and we'll be around that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can go to Shea Stadium on Sunday and maybe we'll see you after we could take the subway somewhere have some fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe if we're doing anything, maybe we'll get a group and go do something fun in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 1: Sunday at 3 p.m.
Speaker 1: In the city.
Speaker 1: I forget the name of the bar, but there's gonna be an Ubuntu feisty fawn release party.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be a feisty fawn release party and I don't know where it is, but you can look it up on the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's a whole website full of feisty release party information.
Speaker 0: can't say if we'll be there or not.
Speaker 0: We're still debating.
Speaker 0: we could take the train now we could drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's also gonna be a feisty release party in Rochester, but I don't know any other information about it at all.
Speaker 1: I don't know when or where anything but there is gonna be one so check that one out.
Speaker 1: Heck wherever you live look for the feisty release party.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz you'll meet.
Speaker 0: if nothing else you'll meet a bunch of people who would be more than glad to help you install feisty Or you'll find the geeks who live nearby.
Speaker 1: if you think you live somewhere where there are no geeks check to see if there's a Party near you and go to it.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.