Speaker 1: It's Pi Day!
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we discuss the not-so-new anime Juu-O-Sei.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Behold internet.
Speaker 0: we are back.
Speaker 1: Aha our link to the outside world and the source of infinite information has been Re-formed.
Speaker 0: I guess it is a sign that we're becoming moderately popular.
Speaker 0: the shared number of complaints Compared to how many complaints I would have expected to the fact that we uploaded one episode late.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh people you know they can't have anything Change even slightly in their daily routine.
Speaker 0: What are they gonna do if we change the music or something?
Speaker 1: They'll just like kill themselves.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: or what if you get throat surgery, then I die and get replaced with Emily?
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: Will the show even continue at that point?
Speaker 0: I see the show continuing well.
Speaker 0: It'll be kind of like the Tonight Show.
Speaker 0: it'll just have a different host.
Speaker 0: when we get old and die We'll appoint someone else to take over.
Speaker 1: someone will eventually be the Johnny Carson of Geek Nights And hopefully they won't be the Jon Stewart and people will think back.
Speaker 1: Oh rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: They suck this.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's way better.
Speaker 0: I almost feel bad for Craig Kilborn, but then I don't because I liked him But he wasn't even half as funny as Jon Stewart.
Speaker 1: No not really.
Speaker 1: Oh, well yeah apparently this whole time.
Speaker 1: It was the cable modem that was broken.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now now think about that for a minute.
Speaker 0: We had a tech come and He looked at our cable modem and said wow your internet's not working.
Speaker 0: And I assumed I assumed that he considered the possibility that the most obvious direct Common point of failure might be the problem.
Speaker 0: But no he climbed up the utility pole and looked at the wires up there and even replaced some of them.
Speaker 0: He looked at the wires to the house.
Speaker 0: He fixed them.
Speaker 1: He replaced all the connectors outside the house called some guys to come the next day and replace some of the wires outside.
Speaker 0: He tested all the cables in the whole house, but he didn't actually check the cable modem and sure enough That was what was broken.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was kind of weird too.
Speaker 1: I mean cuz the cable modem.
Speaker 1: It's a as far as we're concerned.
Speaker 1: It's a black box.
Speaker 1: We know nothing about it.
Speaker 1: It's just a cable modem.
Speaker 1: a cable goes in one end and internet comes out the other end And we have no control over it or anything.
Speaker 1: and looking at the lights on the cable modem is about all the information We've got and those lights Indicated that the cable modem was working as well as it ever had.
Speaker 1: so how did we know it was I?
Speaker 1: Didn't even consider that it'd be broken because it looked like it was working well.
Speaker 0: apparently the new one Emily was is she had to deal with this.
Speaker 0: the story is second hand but he comes and he sets it up And then he asks for Internet Explorer because he has to connect to the thing and configure it to which she says Internet Explorer, that's that's not the kind of thing that this household would have Which is pretty much true.
Speaker 1: that's that the only place that it's in this has to household right now is if you reboot my desktop or This laptop that I'm going to install Ubuntu on probably tonight Because now I have internet so I can do this.
Speaker 0: if you reboot my computer And that's currently in Linux into Windows safe mode you can get to Internet Explorer.
Speaker 1: It's not easy to use Internet Explorer in our house unless you bring your own.
Speaker 1: so the guy you why oh, I?
Speaker 0: Apparently this guy couldn't fathom the possibility of their existing another web browser let alone that someone would have a reason not to use Internet Explorer.
Speaker 0: and Somehow he is a the senior most senior Tech for cable vision or at least the last one they sent.
Speaker 1: Maybe they said that they were sending like the most senior guy possible and that they wouldn't leave until they fixed it.
Speaker 0: Well it got even further because he's asking like what kind of people don't have Internet Explorer, and she's explaining well It's two computer guys, and I do computer animation and to it.
Speaker 0: Here's the interesting thing He didn't understand what computer animation was at all.
Speaker 0: She had to explain it to him in simplified dummy terms.
Speaker 0: Like you know Pixar isn't.
Speaker 1: this is a town full of art.
Speaker 1: people don't?
Speaker 1: they all have Macs.
Speaker 1: what the hell?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he he looks at the Mac And he says I don't see Internet Explorer, and she says just click on the other on Firefox.
Speaker 0: to what she says what?
Speaker 0: So she shows him and he tries to use Firefox And it totally doesn't work with whatever garbage is on this cable modem, so eventually he uses Safari, and it works.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: shouldn't the cable modem?
Speaker 1: just be plug-and-play?
Speaker 1: Why does it need any sort of configuring?
Speaker 0: actually it needs quite a bit of configuring?
Speaker 0: Usually that's not ahead of time, but a lot of times There's a ID in there so they can identify it.
Speaker 0: sometimes some of them have routers or DHCP stuff built in.
Speaker 1: yeah But I mean if you get a cable box for cable television even a digital one they configure it from the cable headquarters.
Speaker 1: They don't need to come there to configure it.
Speaker 1: They plug it in with the coax and they configure it from that end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why should there be any configuration?
Speaker 0: because there's no difference and usually remember It's not like he had the pre-configured one ready.
Speaker 0: He came decided to replace it and pulled a virgin one out of his truck.
Speaker 0: It's true it had to be configured for our house.
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe you had to tell it not to show us actual TV or Maybe you had to disable the telephony because it's got two telephone lines in the back.
Speaker 0: for if you want to use that special voice Over IP business that they offer yeah yeah, oh well is.
Speaker 1: the other modem that we got rid of was like the same brand, but smaller and older and It was always very hot.
Speaker 0: so all cable modems are always very hot I know.
Speaker 1: But I'm wondering like what did it in?
Speaker 1: because the way it broke was very strange where the internet was slow Working not working working not working.
Speaker 1: I'm willing to bet that the heat over time damaged the goods.
Speaker 0: Well, that's a very common thing.
Speaker 0: That's what destroyed my geforce 2 GTS.
Speaker 0: Eventually.
Speaker 0: The heat was just too much and the GPU.
Speaker 0: I don't know what happened.
Speaker 0: I think the RAM actually on the mother on the video card went bad because that was when it started Showing the wrong colors of things and the display was all weird, but the video card otherwise worked just fine.
Speaker 1: Well now that this new cable modem is plugged in I'm gonna go see if it's hot.
Speaker 1: because if it's not hot Then I will assume because that's all I really can't assume that it is very likely that the old modem was always broken.
Speaker 1: It was just only.
Speaker 0: I would doubt that cuz art.
Speaker 0: I think part of the problem is that our cable modem was actually pretty old Compared to the one that they gave us now And I've never in my life had a cable modem or seen a cable modem that wasn't extremely warm And it was on.
Speaker 1: I've seen them that they're they the ones when they used to be the size of cable boxes Oh, those were even hotter or when they used to also be your cable box those weren't?
Speaker 1: some of those weren't really hot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were at least the ones I had.
Speaker 1: Oh different cable boxes different places.
Speaker 0: yeah remember I had a cable modem in like 1995.
Speaker 1: you really need is people keep in gadget.
Speaker 1: especially they keep complaining about this cable card support that is supposedly in Vista.
Speaker 1: and if anyone doesn't know if you have cable television in Your cable box you might notice like a credit card sticking out the front of it.
Speaker 1: That's a cable card.
Speaker 1: supposedly this is technology that no one is implemented for consumer use where you can take that card and put it in another Cable-card device such as a TiVo or a computer running Windows Media Center or anything like that.
Speaker 1: And now you don't need a cable box.
Speaker 1: You just need any device that has a coax input that can also house this card that so that way they know you're not stealing cable because you have the card and You don't have to rent a cable box from the cable company or anything.
Speaker 1: you can use whatever device you've got.
Speaker 1: This technology exists.
Speaker 1: It's all.
Speaker 1: the cable boxes come with cable cards in them.
Speaker 1: You know it's there.
Speaker 1: It's ready, but the devices that can hold these cable cards?
Speaker 1: No one's making them even though Vista technically has support.
Speaker 1: And I'm wondering maybe once we get over the hurdle of having cable card support for television Transmission we could just get routers with cable cards, so I go to the store by any router I want.
Speaker 1: I don't need their crazy cable modem from the cable company.
Speaker 1: I just put a cable card in my own router.
Speaker 0: um you would still need a cable modem because what that does is It's a modem.
Speaker 1: it translates yes analog signal, but I would get my own like I might have do that.
Speaker 0: now even with our current cable you can just buy a cable modem and Configure it.
Speaker 0: however they say and it'll just work.
Speaker 0: huh in fact.
Speaker 0: We'd save money if we did that.
Speaker 1: No, cuz we pay a flat rate.
Speaker 1: There's no it doesn't break down.
Speaker 1: I looked at the bill.
Speaker 0: well Every other cable I've ever had in my life broke down And you were renting the cable modem And it cost like five bucks a month within your normal bill.
Speaker 0: And if you called them specially and said I already have a cable modem They wouldn't give you one and they charge you five bucks less.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe we'll look into that because it's not worth.
Speaker 0: the cable does break all the time.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm thinking if you had a computer that you would say also using as a firewall and a DHCP server and all that other Besides it would also if you had a router like that you'd get really hot.
Speaker 1: well You'd have like a PCI card that was a cable a PCI card that would get really hot.
Speaker 1: yeah But you could have a fan Which the cable modem does not have a fan.
Speaker 0: so you want a fan on a little PCI card in the back of your PC.
Speaker 1: No, I'd have one of those fans that takes up a PCI slot next to it.
Speaker 0: You know you'd be better off having What some sort of box outside of your computer separate from the computer that could cool itself and you didn't have to worry about it.
Speaker 1: maybe maybe maybe a Cable modem, but this one doesn't have a fan either.
Speaker 0: It doesn't need a fan.
Speaker 0: it only needs a fan if it's in your computer generating heats and eating your dudes.
Speaker 0: Anyway anime day so Probably my favorite manga creator ever going a guy.
Speaker 0: It's not your favorite manga creator ever He's my favorite in terms of name recognition and name Recall.
Speaker 0: I like saying going a guy.
Speaker 1: okay going a guy is fun to say But I think you might recall Osamu Tezuka more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't don't recall isn't recalling the name in order to say it.
Speaker 0: I don't say haha Osamu Tezuka all the time, but I say haha going a guy going a guy.
Speaker 0: well and also The guy who made gogo 13 and a whole bunch of other mangaka in Japan are Suing the everliving shit out of some kids who were running a website that was hosting scans of their manga.
Speaker 0: Really, they're suing for 22 million yen in damages and apparently these guys already lost another lawsuit Not too long ago over the same website.
Speaker 0: the website is currently down.
Speaker 1: Wait wait.
Speaker 1: so who lost the guy?
Speaker 1: the kids or kids?
Speaker 0: I'm obviously all right.
Speaker 0: You read the same article.
Speaker 0: This was your news before I took it.
Speaker 1: Why didn't I actually read it?
Speaker 1: I was going to.
Speaker 1: so what were you gonna say?
Speaker 1: well?
Speaker 1: I just looked up the two million.
Speaker 0: twenty two million yen is well the article is kind of almost $200,000 because the article says and I quote blah blah blah are seeking 22 million yen Approximately 20 million u.s.. Dollars in damages.
Speaker 0: nothing about that for a minute.
Speaker 0: That's saying that a yen is worth about a dollar, which I don't think our currencies fallen that far yet.
Speaker 1: No, it says right here according to Google.
Speaker 1: I typed into Google 22 million yen in dollars.
Speaker 0: so good job.
Speaker 0: anime news that it says you were once again the source of Perfectly factual news.
Speaker 1: well anime news network is attempting to hire a new editor.
Speaker 1: Maybe that will help them with their false information.
Speaker 0: I'm not too worried.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is this article is kind of useless - they don't actually say like was this cancellations?
Speaker 0: Was it just scans?
Speaker 0: was the website primarily for Americans?
Speaker 0: was for Japanese people?
Speaker 0: was it just a straight-up bootleg?
Speaker 1: There's none of that doesn't really say who was running the website or like what the website had on it exactly.
Speaker 0: even better They said a source right source my Nietzsche.
Speaker 0: They link to my Nietzsche the front page So I couldn't even follow this.
Speaker 0: see a lot of people on dig and all over the internet.
Speaker 0: We're talking about this.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're gonna go after the scans laters, but we don't know if this had anything to do with that.
Speaker 0: This might have been just straight-up piracy in Japan.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling it was just piracy in Japan.
Speaker 0: and yeah, if that's the case I have to give the Balls award to these two guys for just openly running a non obfuscated straight-up piracy server on their own.
Speaker 1: and If you do that, this is what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I mean they were running it in Japan, too.
Speaker 0: It's not like they were running it in Russia or Belarus.
Speaker 1: dudes at least use a bit torrent or something.
Speaker 1: So you don't get caught like this.
Speaker 0: I mean where sites like that existed in 1995.
Speaker 1: oh Wow, you're right where sites don't really exist anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, remember cracks.
Speaker 0: Are you is that still there?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure like I'm gonna type it in hasta la vista might still exist cracks.
Speaker 0: Are you is not loading?
Speaker 0: I think it's gone.
Speaker 0: So I'd like to talk about the ramifications of this.
Speaker 0: But I have no information other than the anime news network.
Speaker 0: for all I know they just made this story up.
Speaker 1: So the news that was originally Manga pirates pond is actually anime news network.
Speaker 1: Not so good at reporting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a little from column a little from column B I mean the fact that it involved going a guy is the primary reason I brought it up.
Speaker 0: Also the fact that nothing else happened.
Speaker 0: There were some release dates.
Speaker 0: I don't care about that's about it.
Speaker 1: Not much going down in the anime world is mostly game news lately.
Speaker 1: and well we didn't do news yesterday.
Speaker 1: So there's gonna be a flood next week in the week after.
Speaker 1: Alright, so last week cats in America died.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, if you don't know by now Wow, are you living under a rock?
Speaker 1: And if you don't know by now, you're probably someone who doesn't care.
Speaker 0: I probably wouldn't have known if I weren't doing a podcast and reading the news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: I mean I wouldn't have known either I didn't.
Speaker 1: I don't read those comics unless I wasn't hanging around a comic forum and listen to the podcast.
Speaker 0: I'll let money.
Speaker 0: he's back within two years.
Speaker 1: almost definitely.
Speaker 1: I saw actually pictures today of like some covers that may or may not be fake of like the punisher is gonna be Captain America For a while, which is typical Superhero fan crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know who should be if anyone's gonna take over Captain America's job.
Speaker 0: It's gotta be the comedian.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so there's a hubbub about this actually and of course You know you make a comic where someone dies and it gets all over the news.
Speaker 1: So there's gonna be a run.
Speaker 1: the demand is high for this comic.
Speaker 1: They're actually gonna make in a second printing which is not as common as it used to be.
Speaker 1: So, of course the price is high.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna pay the usual cover price for this thing.
Speaker 1: If you want this you're gonna have to pay like five bucks Maybe unless you go to a good comic book store where they just charge cover price in which case They're probably sold out until they get another batch in.
Speaker 1: however No, nobody knew that Captain America when it's gonna die in this comic before it showed up at the store I mean the comic guys ordered Captain America number 25 Just like they ordered number 24 and they get it and they read it and then they put it on the shelf.
Speaker 1: And it wasn't until that day that it hit shelves that people knew it was going on in it.
Speaker 1: now people at Marvel knew because Well, they made it but nobody else knew.
Speaker 0: Well, obviously the people at Marvel and all their friends and family and then all the friends and family of all them I don't know.
Speaker 1: There were actually people at Marvel who didn't know.
Speaker 1: it seemed that only kept it close to the chest on this one.
Speaker 1: However people at Wizard magazine perhaps one of the worst magazines in existence at least, you know It's not what it.
Speaker 1: I guess it's not the worst magazine in existence because there are far worse magazines Like I don't know the Enquirer and such weekly world news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, weekly world news is at least funny though, and it doesn't take itself too seriously.
Speaker 1: But the wizard magazine it's supposed to be like it has the potential to be an awesome magazine because it's about awesome stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like nerd magazine.
Speaker 1: It could be great, but it just falls so flat.
Speaker 1: But they knew.
Speaker 1: now the problem is is that wizard magazine is a journalistic Entity, you know, they write about comic books and other nerdy things.
Speaker 1: So there's nothing wrong with them Knowing.
Speaker 1: they also happen to be an exit a company that runs conventions.
Speaker 1: All right, not a big deal.
Speaker 1: They also happen to be a company that sells comic books.
Speaker 1: They were selling this issue on eBay with many variant covers and all that jazz Before it hit shelves before it was delivered to stores.
Speaker 1: They knew in advance and they took advantage of that to make a bunch of money and rip people off on eBay.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 0: They probably found out some.
Speaker 0: while I guess it well I'll bet it wasn't that hard for people in the industry to find out if they really needed to.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, this particular incident, you know is kind of sketchy if you care and I personally don't care because it's such small Stupidity that it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: but there are other instances where this sort of activity is not so hot.
Speaker 1: That's why we have laws against insider trading and that's why a lot of people are worried about.
Speaker 1: like video game magazines We're like at one point game Pro might have made a video game and people were like, oh no if they do that, then it'll all be journalistic integrity and You know sketchy insider Jobins that are no good,
Speaker 0: but the video game review industry is already like that.
Speaker 0: Even if PC gamer made games, it wouldn't be any different from how it is now.
Speaker 0: I know so I've never heard these concerns.
Speaker 1: people have expressed these concerns.
Speaker 1: people are talking about like what if GameStop made a game and that they also have Game Informer magazine and They own the store.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: They all that they just wouldn't have to bribe themselves.
Speaker 0: Usually you have to bribe someone to get them to give you a good review now.
Speaker 0: I just don't have to do anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just sort of like, you know like what if the New York Times published a book and then he did a book review on it saying that's fine book ever because You know who made the game and you know who's reviewing it.
Speaker 0: So there's no problem at all.
Speaker 1: The thing is most people don't know.
Speaker 1: we went to GameStop.
Speaker 1: the guy at GameStop didn't even know the Game Informer was made by GameStop.
Speaker 1: Remember that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: I guess I just care so little.
Speaker 0: I mean I've never.
Speaker 1: I also care so little but it's just.
Speaker 1: you know there is an issue here of Being ethical and such.
Speaker 0: I don't really see much of an ethics problem because it was a secret and if it depends if it got out secretly or not.
Speaker 0: But even if it was done blatantly in order to make money I still don't see much wrong with it because it's not like this was anything that mattered in the world.
Speaker 0: This was just that I literature.
Speaker 1: I agree that it was something that matters.
Speaker 1: Absolutely not.
Speaker 0: but it is a case of using Information to gain an unfair advantage, but at what point does in using information to gain an advantage become unfair?
Speaker 0: What if you're just smarter than everyone else and you figure it out?
Speaker 1: That is the important question, isn't it?
Speaker 0: or what if you find out and then you realize you can capitalize on it?
Speaker 0: What if you find out by espionage?
Speaker 0: What if you find out by murdering someone?
Speaker 1: There's this whole slide the murdering in the espionage here at unethical to begin with.
Speaker 0: What if you're going through?
Speaker 0: Marvel's public garbage?
Speaker 0: because it's perfectly legal in most cases to go through someone's garbage.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess it all depends on the circuit because remember a trade secret.
Speaker 0: the onus of protecting a trade secret is on the company.
Speaker 0: Who has the secret?
Speaker 0: So if you accidentally reveal or if you leave of like the test issue in the garbage and someone finds it You're at fault and you can't sue the person who releases it to the world in most cases.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 1: However, if someone comes in and takes your trade secret or like if they worked for you and then they reveal the trade secret without You telling them to only if they signed an NDA that's true They have to sign.
Speaker 1: that says they will not tell the trade.
Speaker 0: surprisingly my new company didn't really make me sign any NDA's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't have to sign too much at my current.
Speaker 0: I had to sign stuff for hospitals.
Speaker 0: all the you know various requirements for not giving outpatient information But anything else.
Speaker 0: I'm really.
Speaker 0: it's fair game if I wanted to talk about it.
Speaker 1: I mean I signed the non-compete and the don't.
Speaker 1: ah Compete and ice also signed the don't.
Speaker 1: you know poach the employees if you quit but it only lasts six months.
Speaker 1: So it's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: I would never sign a non-compete.
Speaker 0: I would not work for a company That would make me sign a non-compete.
Speaker 1: It's not a big deal.
Speaker 1: It's saying if you leave here, you can't work for someone else who does the exact same thing.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, what exactly did it say?
Speaker 0: Did you have a lawyer?
Speaker 0: Look, it actually said competitors and that that could be interpreted broadly.
Speaker 0: I would have a lawyer.
Speaker 0: look at it.
Speaker 1: I'm not worried about it.
Speaker 0: I just in general won't sign non-competes.
Speaker 0: IBM had one and I just didn't sign it.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: So we were catching up on all those dig videos that we missed since we didn't have the internet for a while and one of Them caught our eye.
Speaker 0: It was entitled first erotic film now.
Speaker 1: We that's gonna really catch your eye.
Speaker 1: the first erotic.
Speaker 0: Well part of it was that it wasn't that long ago.
Speaker 0: We went to the New York Sex Museum and we not only saw effectively the first erotic film But we also saw the first erotic animation one of the first erotic animations But perhaps also the most hilarious erotic and it is.
Speaker 0: it is so high quality.
Speaker 0: if there was a DVD I would probably buy it.
Speaker 1: Maybe there is a DVD.
Speaker 0: We should look anyway.
Speaker 0: So we assume that this is probably one of the things we saw at the museum.
Speaker 0: We click on it and not to spoil anything but it is not that it is in fact an animation a rather recent one from the Anisee film festival in France an animation festival and it is done by this guy Gabby Liddon's in 2002.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was actually submitted to the festival or if it was a promotion for the festival But it is rather hilarious and it is actually pretty much safe for work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you get fired for watching this at work, you shouldn't be working.
Speaker 1: That's not someplace you want to work at all.
Speaker 1: And yeah, this this video is not will be expected and it was a thousand hilarities and it was really short.
Speaker 1: It was just like.
Speaker 1: it was like a one-liner joke turned into like a 10-second animation.
Speaker 0: I mean the first half is kind of a. do you get the joke yet?
Speaker 0: Do you get the joke yet?
Speaker 0: Ah Now you get the joke and then there's another joke the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's awesome.
Speaker 1: Everyone should watch it.
Speaker 1: unless you're I don't know everyone should watch it.
Speaker 1: if you're listening to this show There is no way this would bother you That's true alright, so remember Lensman guy the Doc Smith who wrote all the lens.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah I wasn't sure if you meant the director of the anime?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, the director of the anime can goes dying a fire.
Speaker 0: who did direct that.
Speaker 1: That's a good question.
Speaker 1: We'll look that up later.
Speaker 1: but anyway The guy who wrote lensman deep doc EE Smith, I think actually EE stands for Edward Elmer one of his books namely Triplanetary which is the first book in the lensman series Chronologically speaking, but it's I think the fifth book in terms of When it was published, so you're actually supposed to read it fifth.
Speaker 1: So I haven't read it yet because I've only read three lensman books.
Speaker 1: However, this book is on project Gutenberg now.
Speaker 1: But that's not the news because that you know big deal of a book is on project Gutenberg.
Speaker 1: I noticed two interesting things about this particular project Gutenberg release number one.
Speaker 1: It says Copyright status not copyrighted in the United States.
Speaker 1: if you live elsewhere I checked the laws of your country before downloading this ebook.
Speaker 1: I have a copy of the book published in the United States.
Speaker 1: so Either that person gave up the copyright because they had it at one point or I don't know but that's sort of dubious.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe the publisher here just had the right to publish it But the copyright still expires regardless of who we've given rights to.
Speaker 1: that could be true because it is very old.
Speaker 1: The second thing I noticed they didn't just put the words of the book online.
Speaker 1: if you look at this in HTML format These books all these lensman books weren't originally novels.
Speaker 1: They're originally pulp serials with like a chapter to every week in some magazine.
Speaker 1: they actually put the chapters from the magazines up there and the Pictures the illustrations that were in the original pulp magazines up there as well, huh?
Speaker 0: Did he do the illustrations or did he hire?
Speaker 1: I don't know who did the illustrations but they're there on the project Gutenberg if you read it in HTML format, huh?
Speaker 1: and that is way cool because pulp literature magazines do not exist anymore.
Speaker 1: and Reading these kinds of stories now you get them in novel paperback books and you don't realize that they were originally.
Speaker 1: You know serialized pulp action and see the original stuff that was there and I don't know.
Speaker 0: it depends on the thing.
Speaker 0: I mean I could not but I could not bring myself to read the Count of Monte Cristo in its original form.
Speaker 1: Oh, what is the real French but serialized?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean if it's serialized, but you have all the bits in one big HTML file Then it's no different than reading it in the book form.
Speaker 1: Yeah But it has it You know split up in the correct fashion and the and all the original pictures are there.
Speaker 1: instead of like I have some different Publishings of some of the different lensman books and the art is all completely different for the covers and stuff.
Speaker 1: So having the original art is sort of different from how.
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 0: if there's art There's a big difference.
Speaker 0: but aside from art if something was published in one format and I read it in another format that doesn't bother Me at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus it's sort of a. it's like a presence of art where the only art I have for the lensman books I've got is the covers and this.
Speaker 1: there was some inside illustrations that you never would have seen and it's pretty cool Are they good?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're actually pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: like because sometimes you have a hard time and lensman figuring out like what the ships look like and what certain aliens look like because he describes them but he doesn't describe them in super detail.
Speaker 1: like he'll say like there's a Slimy appendage or something you got it.
Speaker 1: It could be any kind of slimy appendage.
Speaker 1: It could be a pseudopod It could be a tentacle.
Speaker 1: It could be a big tentacle small tentacle.
Speaker 1: You're not always a hundred percent sure and you kind of get a picture over time of what the things look like.
Speaker 1: But it's it's not always easy to tell You know He spends a lot more time talking about these sizes and powers of things and that you get the general feel for what something's like.
Speaker 1: But not everyone has a different picture because the you know, the it's not the most adjective filled.
Speaker 0: All right That's the exact opposite of the Count of Monte Cristo which describes an intricate detail every object ever Presented to use over the course of the novel.
Speaker 0: That's why it's so long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, lensman reads pretty fast and it's pretty fun.
Speaker 0: So tonight we're going to preview we haven't done that in a while and anime that we have only seen a few episodes of Suffice to say we have.
Speaker 0: we're suitably impressed by it to where we feel the need to talk about it And also we get the sense that a lot of people have passed it by or haven't recognized that it exists.
Speaker 1: Well, it was on the air in April and to June 2006 which means that's probably when it would have been a bit.
Speaker 1: Torrance and I usually download episode 1 of just about anything And if I had downloaded this episode 1 I probably would have kept watching it I don't know.
Speaker 0: you seem to give shows off in.
Speaker 0: the.
Speaker 0: look at it for two seconds You see one character you don't like and you say this show is crap and deleted.
Speaker 1: But if I would have seen these it's kind of hard to watch the first episode without seeing outer space.
Speaker 0: You know watch the first episode you would have clicked through seen two pretty silver-haired boys And so this is crap and deleted it.
Speaker 0: I know You've done that to other shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah shows where I go click click click and I see some moe girls and then I see and it's pretty obvious what the show Are and I don't have to actually watch them.
Speaker 0: So tonight we're gonna talk a bit about duo say or Planet of the Beast King.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like it's hard to figure out exactly the correct Romanization of the name.
Speaker 0: I mean, well, it's only it's not difficult.
Speaker 0: It's just that they listed here twice.
Speaker 1: Well, I've seen it spelled like three or four different ways.
Speaker 0: Oh because the internet knows what it's talking.
Speaker 1: I know right I've seen people say three separate words Jew.
Speaker 1: Oh say I've seen Jew.
Speaker 1: Oh say j-u-u-o-u-s-e-i.
Speaker 0: Never seen anything other than those twos.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: I saw one that was like j-y-u-u-s-e-o-e some fan summer?
Speaker 1: Yeah, not so good.
Speaker 0: It's directed by Hiroshi Nishikiori who you might know from Azumanga Daioh.
Speaker 0: Oh really?
Speaker 0: Not that it's anything like Azumanga Daioh.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, it's not like Azumanga Daioh at all.
Speaker 0: Now we're gonna spoil things from the first episode later on so we'll warn you in progression.
Speaker 0: So once we'll tell you when we're gonna spoil stuff We'll hold off for a bit because the reason that we like this show is Basically a spoiler for the very beginning of the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think we should spoil that in this episode But we can.
Speaker 0: definitely we'll have to spoil where the plot goes because it starts in one place and ends up somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty impossible to spoil.
Speaker 1: and if we don't spoil that you really can't do a faithful review of this show because You you won't really know what the show is about if I only tell you first episode stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but to go over very briefly what the plot is we're gonna talk more about our impressions of it.
Speaker 0: It is two brothers twin brothers Thor and Rai.
Speaker 0: They are silver-haired pretty boys living in a space station.
Speaker 0: They are very young.
Speaker 0: their parents are obviously bigwigs.
Speaker 0: They you know, they're at a museum or something.
Speaker 0: They're living their normal lives and you expect this to be some sort of silver-haired boys in space drama.
Speaker 1: I expected it to be sort of like a Gundam type of thing.
Speaker 1: Maybe you know like they're gonna do there They have they're so smart and they're so great at sports and everything and they're gonna somehow become Action military heroes of some sort and fight other guys in space.
Speaker 0: Yep Well three of the genres listed on anime news network are in fact adventure drama and military.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you watch five minutes of this show and if you've seen anime before you know where that shows going.
Speaker 1: That's what you're thinking.
Speaker 1: You can't imagine anything else happening with this show.
Speaker 0: So I expected it to be a generic show but Emily had highly recommended it.
Speaker 0: Emily was watching it in fact, she'd seen most of it and She's got all of it here and we're.
Speaker 0: so we all sat down since she wanted to show it to us and we watched the First episode and it starts out in this generic way.
Speaker 0: So, huh?
Speaker 0: I wonder why she likes this so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean it started out in a generic way but I was already hooked because there are just so few anime these days that aren't a moe show or a harem show or A furry show or any of those sorts of you know high school craps.
Speaker 1: So I was like finally someone decided to make another sci-fi show other than ergo proxy Which is the other recent sci-fi show the other one that we have to finish watching.
Speaker 1: Yes, so I'm like, yes a sci-fi show.
Speaker 1: I must support this show and watch it just so we get more real shows.
Speaker 0: now you do get the sense the Coordinator sense you look at these kids and the way they act and the way they talk and you would think while they're obviously genetically augmented in some way to be badasses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I looked at him and I was like, alright, so what did they do to these kids to make them all weird?
Speaker 1: What are their special abilities?
Speaker 1: You know, I was just waiting for it to show up.
Speaker 1: I was like, you know, why is their hair white and their eyes all perfect?
Speaker 1: and you know, tell me the plot.
Speaker 1: I already see it a mile away and you haven't even said one word about it.
Speaker 0: now You know a show like this that it takes a while for the plot to develop and you there's a certain pace to this sort Of things, you know, there's gonna be an episode or two or generic whatever hinting at the plot.
Speaker 0: Then the event will happen.
Speaker 0: the event like the Gundam appears.
Speaker 0: that causes them to break out of their normal lives and have their Gundam inspired life.
Speaker 0: and then the real plot starts, you know seven episodes after that.
Speaker 0: Then there's the recap episode around episode 14 or 15.
Speaker 1: take that Archduke Ferdinand.
Speaker 0: So this show pretty much skips all of that and Immediately jumps to the meat.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem is the meat is Most of the show as far as I can tell and the meat is not what you think you're gonna get.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like a jelly doughnut.
Speaker 1: You see the doughnut and you say ah Doughnut and you imagine sugary fried dough.
Speaker 1: you bite it and you taste sugary fried dough, but not a second later.
Speaker 1: Jelly filling and most of what you get for the next 20. how many episodes?
Speaker 1: is it 26?
Speaker 0: Here's the other thing.
Speaker 0: It's only 11 episodes.
Speaker 1: So the most of what you get for the next 11 episodes is gonna be jelly.
Speaker 1: and Then at the end on the other side of the doughnut, there's a bit more frosting.
Speaker 0: See, I would say that's a bad analogy just for me personally because I really don't like jelly doughnuts I know but I'm tied off like a blow pop, you know Pops you just seem don't don't like anything.
Speaker 1: that works as an analogy.
Speaker 1: Do you all right?
Speaker 0: How about a Boston cream doughnut?
Speaker 1: All right, you bite it expecting doughnut and then it's mostly just cream.
Speaker 1: But you didn't think it was gonna be cream because you didn't know.
Speaker 0: so we'll avoid spoiling it for a bit.
Speaker 0: I really want to mention the opening theme deep in your heart by Koichi Domoto.
Speaker 0: I don't know who they are anything, but it's not the kind of music I've heard coming out of Japan Maybe because I haven't looked very much lately recently and I really like it.
Speaker 1: I kind of like it.
Speaker 1: It's a good one.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not one of those amazing openers of all time like German Sailor Moon But it's.
Speaker 1: but it's not one of those bad painful openers like ah, I just skip over it.
Speaker 1: You know, I would if I was watching this on DVD since there's only 11 episodes.
Speaker 1: I might actually watch the opener all 11 times.
Speaker 0: There are only a few shows will do that for I mean ghost in the shell standalone complex first and second gig.
Speaker 0: We watch the opener every time Gundam seed.
Speaker 0: I watch the opener every time I started skipping it towards the end.
Speaker 0: Just cuz.
Speaker 1: well just cuz you know, you're getting it in the heat.
Speaker 0: But yeah also because once you get to the last opener It's it's actually not as good as some of the openers before it.
Speaker 1: Yeah That when you have five different openers It's hard for them all to be so great.
Speaker 1: the fact that all of them are as great as they are is a miracle.
Speaker 0: Utena I watched the opener most of the time and I watched the closer The second half like when they got to the good opener at the end.
Speaker 1: Well in a ten I'll always watch the closer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the opener the opener I will.
Speaker 1: I will skip some time.
Speaker 0: It depended on the episode or what was going on.
Speaker 1: It does depend a lot.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's one of those shows where I like the open.
Speaker 0: also the show is very prettily animated It's not I wouldn't say it's very friendly Compared to like.
Speaker 0: it starts out like one of those guns those shows where it's animated pretty like it's really good.
Speaker 0: It looks good and shiny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looks like the best, you know, Gonzo's good works.
Speaker 0: That's what it looks like, but it doesn't seem to decline like all those guns.
Speaker 1: Oh, how many episodes we watch.
Speaker 0: like five or six or Emily's seen almost all of it.
Speaker 0: She seems to have a high opinion of it.
Speaker 1: still it didn't seem to decline at all.
Speaker 1: Every episode seemed to be equally animated Although they were drawing very different things in the first episode compared to the other episodes.
Speaker 0: Yes though it is a good credit to this show that it starts with this one world then it throws you into this whole other business and Yet after about ten minutes of watching that other business you almost forget about the original plot entirely And you get so immersed in what's going on now that you just totally forget what's actually going on.
Speaker 1: I just really hope they go back to the original plot at the end, which they almost have to.
Speaker 1: you know The way the show is going but it's the same thing that brave story did.
Speaker 0: where?
Speaker 0: There's the original plot and then the show kind of like in The Simpsons will have the beginning plot than the real plot.
Speaker 0: yeah, so you're watching and you get drawn into this other world where you don't care about what was going on in the beginning and You're so immersed in it that you forget that there's this whole other plot thread.
Speaker 0: That's actually the driving force of the show.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's actually sort of the opposite of The Simpsons because The Simpsons.
Speaker 1: they have the opening plot Which isn't the real plot of the episode and then they get to the real plot.
Speaker 1: true This is the opening plot that they give you in the beginning is the real plot and then you're on sort of this Like journey in order to get back to the plot through the whole show and then at the end Supposedly, I hope you get back to it, but I don't know.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen the end, huh?
Speaker 0: Talked about The Simpsons and Jelly Donuts in one show Mmm Donut RDRR Okay, okay.
Speaker 0: All right We're going to spoil at this point pretty much the first plot development in the entire show Which happens almost immediately in the first episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there's kids in space and they're they're obviously very smart and young and in school and whatever.
Speaker 0: and there's all this.
Speaker 0: You know all the typical they're talking about.
Speaker 0: Oh, it'd be nice to be on a planet with a sky.
Speaker 0: Oh They live in a space colony and there's a lot of atmosphere.
Speaker 0: like you see the sky and then later from a different angle You realize that the sky is actually kind of painted onto the ceiling.
Speaker 1: yeah, and there's two brothers and they're obviously special and their parents are like high ups in the government involved in sort of important science type stuff and There's some genetic stuff that they're obviously modified and better in some way.
Speaker 1: But even though they're twins one of them seems to be smart and Athletic and the other one seems to be kind of wussy, but smart.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of them is definitely the whiny annoying kind of guy.
Speaker 1: He the ray is the annoying right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the up Thor Yes.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: See we've got Thor and ride.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of Norse references in this show like they say They mentioned Odin and they mention all sorts of crazy.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of mythological references in general.
Speaker 0: I mean if they're talking about all the different names of planets and colonies and everything and pay attention to that I'm not sure how much that's going to come into play.
Speaker 1: I'm willing to bet Loki shows up at the end in some symbolic way.
Speaker 1: I mean, it would be so hard not to do that that it's almost inevitable if you pay attention at all.
Speaker 0: So they go home after being at the museum or whatever they were at and right away something's wrong.
Speaker 0: the doors unlocked.
Speaker 0: Confident brother starts to handle the situation goes in to see what's going on.
Speaker 0: whiny brother follows him in.
Speaker 1: the house is dark.
Speaker 1: Nobody's making any noise.
Speaker 1: what's going on?
Speaker 1: Where did our parents go?
Speaker 0: They're supposed to be home come around the corner Oh snaps parents are dead.
Speaker 1: This is pretty much the first thing that happens in the show.
Speaker 1: now in other anime that might be the last thing that happens in The show or that would be the thing that happens at the end of the third episode.
Speaker 1: Yes, this is something that happens in the middle of the first episode.
Speaker 1: So that's that's.
Speaker 1: you got quite big balls to kill the parents right away like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not only that but kids are then kidnapped by shadowy people with various gases.
Speaker 1: I mean killing the parents is not like the climax of a plot arc or the mo or like.
Speaker 1: The thing is that thing that finally breaks a straw that gets the character to do what they're supposed to do.
Speaker 1: It's the impetus for the whole rest of the thing.
Speaker 1: without that happening the whole rest of the show wouldn't happen.
Speaker 0: You know what it is every RPG for a Nintendo system ever.
Speaker 0: You know you start and the parents were just dead and you're living with the uncle or the dead disappeared or something.
Speaker 0: This show just started one day before all those RPGs start.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 1: instead of you know, waking up when your mom wakes you up and then you know Your mom gets killed by the evil sorcerer the next day while you're at school or your link and you wake up in Malin and House and you don't have parents.
Speaker 1: this is you know, hell you freaking your parents or die right in the first episode.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: So then they wait you wait, they wake up and they're on this planet.
Speaker 1: Well, no some guys come and attack them and then well, I already said that they got kidnapped.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: They got kidnapped and they wake up right now.
Speaker 0: This is where the show begins in earnest.
Speaker 0: They wake up on this planet and it's obviously a planet blue skies, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's not exactly the kind of place they're used to being in.
Speaker 0: it is effectively this harsh inhospitable deadly jungle filled with the derelicts of society who have been cast aside to this Effectively from what you would gather a prison planet or an exile planet to fend for themselves.
Speaker 0: It's a super dangerous world.
Speaker 0: the play There's no animals.
Speaker 0: There's all plants and the plants are super deadly.
Speaker 1: I think that's actually the number one thing that makes this show pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Is that the world that most of the story takes place on is just an awesome world.
Speaker 1: I mean the plants in this place are so wildly varied.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like if your whole planet was covered with Cthulhu type plants and they're all different and they're all.
Speaker 1: some of them are useful and they always sort of come in at just the right moment as useful plot devices.
Speaker 1: and It's all.
Speaker 1: the plants are pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Like there's one kind of plant that like totally destroys the city But it brings water from underground.
Speaker 1: it lets them live.
Speaker 1: or
Speaker 0: there's the one with the super poisonous bits
Speaker 1: Yeah, and like it's pretty cool because people they stress right away as soon as you're as soon as they start meeting the prisoners and People on this planet that if you know more about the plants then you will get ahead in this world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they show you that.
Speaker 1: yes, that is the case if you know about the plants and pay attention to them.
Speaker 1: That's the key to survival.
Speaker 0: See you can effectively call this show an exercise in Darwinism Because the people that are on this planet have adapted and it is a rough.
Speaker 0: only the fit survive.
Speaker 0: In fact here only the strong survive the ones who throw away their humanity and become the beasts humans once were.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's from the plot summary on anime news network.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much sums it up right there.
Speaker 0: So they run afoul of people here.
Speaker 0: There's there's a bunch of tribes of people that have kind of formed on various parts of this planet.
Speaker 1: They divided up themselves into rings like the Sun ring and the something else ring like all kinds of rings You know.
Speaker 1: and and basically they have this ranking system or whoever's the strongest is in charge of the ring And you'd be like number one or number two or number three I gotta say the third.
Speaker 0: the guy we meet is really cool.
Speaker 1: I think it's one of the best characters in the show him and the girl you meet right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Then there's someone who's the Beast King, you know and to be the Beast King You have to be the leader of all the Rings and only the Beast King can leave the planet.
Speaker 1: But they don't tell you how.
Speaker 1: and it's sort of this mystery like,
Speaker 0: uh, yeah you get this idea that there's obviously this fighting for who gets to lead the Rings and who what's going on and there's obviously this Quest or you could fight and become the leader of this planet and the leader seems to get a special privilege where he can return To their you know, the actual civilized world or something like that because otherwise there's no way off this planet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a pretty typical Anime type of set up.
Speaker 0: there could easily be a shonen fighting show.
Speaker 1: it could easily be an RPG or shonen fighting show and You know, it leaves you wondering the whole time like huh?
Speaker 1: Howdy.
Speaker 1: Is he gonna become the Beast King?
Speaker 1: Probably that's kind of obvious, but I don't know if he does yet.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen that part so it's not really a spoiler.
Speaker 0: but what I like so far is that the Situations that come up in the show as far as I've seen are not the straight-up stereotypical scenes in a lot of anime recently.
Speaker 0: They're very.
Speaker 0: you can't predict what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: the characters react in pretty convincingly realistic ways.
Speaker 0: They don't react in expected ways all the time.
Speaker 0: They're the characters seem pretty well developed, especially for a little of the show I've seen so far.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the characters and the other thing is not only do the characters act in I mean, they're not the smartest character.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they do kind of stupid stuff, but they're all pretty cool like that nerdy guy with the glasses Yeah, who has like no interested in being the leader.
Speaker 1: He's a cool guy.
Speaker 1: the guy who's actually the number one Was really cool.
Speaker 1: that like that the one fight scene though like the one real Shonen style fight scene that we saw was actually really awesome because it was short and it said Aha, the smart guy beats the big guy.
Speaker 0: I think part of what makes this show good so far seems to be that it's 11 episodes.
Speaker 0: So they've dispensed with filler.
Speaker 0: They've dispensed with anything that isn't necessary for the plot.
Speaker 0: It's just the plot the characters the mood and that's it and they're just plowing through Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: another thing is this show.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna spoil anything, but there are things that happen pretty early on in the show.
Speaker 1: You know soon after the parents get killed we're talking like episode one two and three here Where I'm not gonna tell you what they are because there's no point watching the show.
Speaker 1: Suffice to say suffice to say the writers of this show have big nuts Like.
Speaker 1: there is stuff that no show would even think of doing in such an early point in the story And they just do it like BAM it's done and you're like, whoa, you can't do that There's no way you just did that.
Speaker 1: Yes, and then the next episode you're thinking they did it.
Speaker 0: Something happens early on where I remember thinking to myself that didn't really happen.
Speaker 0: That's that's gonna be undone or that's that.
Speaker 0: did that happen.
Speaker 0: Did they really do it?
Speaker 0: Wow, and I really couldn't believe it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then your couple episodes later, but at the same time it's done.
Speaker 0: I was cheering because that sort of thing is what I want out of anime these days.
Speaker 0: very It's rare now that an anime will surprise me.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean that's what I liked about Anime in the first place when I started watching is that they had the kinds of plots and the kinds of stories that weren't in The other mediums that I was experiencing at the time, but now that I've seen enough anime I've seen all the anime plots there are to see.
Speaker 1: So when you come out with a new anime plot one that I haven't seen already It doesn't even have to be super awesome.
Speaker 1: It can just be really great like this one is and I'll go woohoo Something new all right.
Speaker 0: So I'm pretty much looking forward to watching the rest of the show and hopefully we'll do it this week or next week at the Latest.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean only 11 episodes.
Speaker 1: It can't take us that long to finish this thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really doubt it's gonna have a US release anytime soon.
Speaker 0: So check it out.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can find a torrent somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe the torrent box or whatever box torrents, right?
Speaker 1: They usually have torrents of like a whole series and there's only 11 episodes.
Speaker 1: So it won't take you that long to download.
Speaker 0: now, of course before we end for tonight I would like to point out one that last night's episode was actually uploaded today due to us getting our internet back.
Speaker 0: So if you missed an episode yesterday tonight is a matinee.
Speaker 1: Well this afternoon was a matinee and now is the actual geek night.
Speaker 1: So lucky you.
Speaker 1: two and one to.
Speaker 0: the contest for the worst anime you've ever seen is still going.
Speaker 0: Now just to clarify because people have just been sending us entries that were basically naming a bad anime.
Speaker 0: Don't just tell me which anime is bad.
Speaker 0: I know which anime is bad.
Speaker 0: I do a podcast about anime.
Speaker 0: I need you to tell me why it's bad.
Speaker 0: I want a small essay.
Speaker 0: I want some humor here.
Speaker 0: We're basically gonna pick the best write-up not the worst anime for this prize.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that's the point of a contest.
Speaker 1: I mean anyone can name an anime.
Speaker 1: you don't win a prize for telling me that what I already know that Grey digital target is terrible.
Speaker 1: You have to humor me.
Speaker 1: I should read some text that you have written and I should laugh.
Speaker 1: and if I laugh at yours or if I am more entertained by yours or if I go oh shits That one is awesome.
Speaker 1: Then you are going to win a prize for doing something for being cool Not just for writing down the name of an anime.
Speaker 0: if you want an example of what we're looking for Listen to anime world orders review of MD guys.
Speaker 0: That is what I want from you.
Speaker 0: I'm also gonna up the Annie.
Speaker 0: if you win and your entry is good enough You're not just going to get the OST to the second worst anime ever MD guys You're also going to get the OST to genocider.
Speaker 1: Oh great.
Speaker 1: Yes Maybe that's why no one's entering this contest cuz it's not worth writing an essay to win Soundtracks to bad anime.
Speaker 0: No, I think maybe I don't know because the contest for Thursday night Which has a yet to be determined prize.
Speaker 0: We haven't even announced what the prize is.
Speaker 0: We've gotten dozens of quality entries.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I'm gonna do with.
Speaker 0: they're all good.
Speaker 1: We'll have to find out.
Speaker 1: and if you keep the people if you want us to have Contests and give away shit that we don't want then you should enter them because if no one enters our Contests then that tells us no one cares about them and we'll stop having them.
Speaker 0: Maybe after we finish the current Thursday contest, we should have a contest contest for whoever comes up with the best contest wins.
Speaker 1: We'll see how many people enter that contest and then decide whether they continue having contest.
Speaker 0: However, don't think you're clever because if you enter the contest contest and your idea is a contest contest You're not gonna win anything.
Speaker 1: Oh, what if your idea is a contest contest contest?
Speaker 0: That might.
Speaker 0: that might be in consideration.
Speaker 1: Uh, oh well Jose is a show that you should watch.
Speaker 0: I'm very excited about it.
Speaker 0: I really want to see how it ends.
Speaker 0: Emily has seen so much to where she knows a bunch of spoilers and apparently something horrible happened near the end Because I was standing in the room and she was watching it and I was avoiding the screen and luckily I don't understand enough Japanese, but I hear kind of this gooey squick noise followed by Emily going.
Speaker 1: Ah That was probably a plant doing something a plant Squish noise, it's probably a plant because the planet is covered in horrible nasty plants.
Speaker 0: Yes, and don't think that these are plants like tentacle monster hentai plants.
Speaker 0: These are plants like just bite you in half and that's the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, think of it like big planet of horrors instead of little shop.
Speaker 1: That's what this is.
Speaker 0: feed me see more.
Speaker 1: maybe that's the end of the anime.
Speaker 1: is the whole planet.
Speaker 1: It's just one big plant that eats you.
Speaker 0: Somehow I don't think the nature of the planet is going to be the plot.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's not gonna be a KO century beast.
Speaker 0: Nah We still got a review KO century these we will.
Speaker 1: we will watch it soon.
Speaker 0: Let's bring it to Kate and Adam's house this weekend and watch it there because I know Kate hates it.
Speaker 1: Sounds good to me.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.