Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, June 18th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm Rim.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, the Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art Arts Festival 2008.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So you know Frank Miller?
Speaker 0: I know him personally, in fact.
Speaker 1: Sin City, 300, Dark Night Returns, famous comic writer.
Speaker 1: You know, everyone knows who he is now, right?
Speaker 1: Even if you didn't know who he was a few years ago.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Actually, it's funny because Ananth was reading The Prince of Nothing at our recommendation, and he basically, his question to me after he'd gotten a little bit into it was, "All right, I've only met one woman in this book so far, and I gotta ask you, is this guy pulling a Frank
Speaker 0: Miller?".
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: My answer was not all the way.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Frank Miller, you know, people always talk about his famous works and one of his most famous works is Frank Miller's Daredevil.
Speaker 1: And it's not, you know, he didn't invent Daredevil.
Speaker 1: Daredevil existed for a long time before Frank Miller did it.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's his run, you know, from this issue to this issue was when Frank Miller was working on it, right?
Speaker 1: So you can actually buy all of these issues in one giant book for like $100.
Speaker 1: But I was like, "Fuck that
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 1: You could also buy in three separate trades, but those trades are sort of out of print and old.
Speaker 1: But I managed to get them from some guy, so I'm all right.
Speaker 1: So I'm reading these.
Speaker 1: And the first trade, I didn't realize, is when Frank Miller was doing the art but not the writing.
Speaker 1: And it's pretty much Stan Lee's style.
Speaker 1: And it's not Stan Lee, but it's Stan Lee's style.
Speaker 1: And you've got I Hit You, You Little Guy, you've got narrations, you've got all that business, right?
Speaker 0: Nothing's worse than I Hit You, You Little Guy, with the picture of the guy hitting the little guy.
Speaker 1: The second and third trades, I mean, it's not the greatest thing ever, but you can definitely see.
Speaker 1: it's really cool, because you see this transformation.
Speaker 1: Like the first Frank Miller issue where he writes it is still pretty Stan Lee-erific.
Speaker 1: It's not as much as the ones before it, but it's still pretty heavy on there.
Speaker 1: Then it just keeps going more and more and more towards, you know, the Dark Knight Returns Frank Miller that you know.
Speaker 1: And then when you start to get to like the end of the second trade, it's like the second to last issue.
Speaker 1: And that second trade is like, ah, yeah.
Speaker 1: And then the third trade is sort of like, ah, he wraps it up.
Speaker 1: So Daredevil, if people don't know out there, because he's not like, you know, super popular like Spider-Man, but I guess there was a movie, right?
Speaker 1: Anyway, Daredevil's about this blind lawyer who kicks people's asses, right?
Speaker 1: I'm on the train today reading the third trade, wrapping it up.
Speaker 1: I finished it.
Speaker 1: And sitting across from me, blind dude.
Speaker 1: And you know what's really cool is he had like this Braille machine.
Speaker 1: It was a really fascinating machine and it was quite amazing how fast he could operate this machine and read the Braills.
Speaker 1: I got to say, I want to get me one of those machines.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: It's just, it was a really fascinating machine.
Speaker 0: So that's the, oh man, I got something to talk about.
Speaker 0: Show.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think about that.
Speaker 1: You're reading comic about a blind guy who can't see that.
Speaker 1: you're reading a comic about a blind guy and there's a blind guy.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's not that far out of the realm.
Speaker 1: Hey, it's, you know, he had a really cool machine.
Speaker 1: I'm going to go figure out what that machine was and how it works.
Speaker 0: It was a Braille machine.
Speaker 1: I know, but like, it was weird because I had like these buttons up top, but it just had like, it had like, like nine buttons up top and they didn't really, it wasn't like a keyboard, but it's like, somehow he knew which ones to push.
Speaker 1: They were unlabeled.
Speaker 1: I guess it didn't matter if they were labeled or not, but you know, it was just buttons sort of arranged up there.
Speaker 1: And I was like, how did those work?
Speaker 1: And the thing switched up the Braille so quickly.
Speaker 1: It was like, it was, I really want to know, like, you know, sort of how it worked and what the principle behind it was and how it functioned.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: It's probably a lot like, I mean, I've heard there are these machines you can have with you if you're, if you're not blind, if you can see that we'll use electricity to change the arrangement of pixels, right?
Speaker 0: To show letters and it'll change those letters.
Speaker 0: It's kind of cryptic, but if you get used to all these letters in order, you can read stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh, wait, here we go.
Speaker 1: The nine key Braille machine on flicker.
Speaker 1: So I guess that's what that's.
Speaker 1: Let's see if that's okay.
Speaker 1: That's a really old fashioned machine, but I'm betting the machine he had was, uh, based on a similar principle.
Speaker 0: I imagine your thing of the day at some point in the near future is going to be the Braille machine.
Speaker 1: Once you learn about it and find a video may, I'm sure there's probably someone out there coming in blind.
Speaker 1: People can listen to podcasts.
Speaker 1: Sorry, deaf people.
Speaker 1: Um, and uh, perhaps someone out there is blind and will tell us all about awesome Braille machines.
Speaker 1: It had like a compact flash card and stuff in it.
Speaker 1: It was, it was definitely something cool going on.
Speaker 1: I couldn't figure it out though.
Speaker 1: And he was really fast.
Speaker 0: All right, so I'm going to pretty much jump right into my news because this is one of those, the internet had a tempest in a teapot about it.
Speaker 0: And mostly I just, wait, wait, teapots people losing their shit on the internet, their shit lost.
Speaker 1: I mean, if I had a penny for all the shit lost, I would not have to learn work.
Speaker 0: Well, uh, that wasn't quite true because if you had a penny for all of it, then you'd have a penny.
Speaker 1: If I had one funny for each shit that was lost.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Otacon pretty much the biggest and best anime convention.
Speaker 0: That's run by fans in America.
Speaker 0: It's, it's, it's, it's my favorite con lately.
Speaker 0: I've been saying that to a lot of the staffers of cons, but no Otacon is my favorite con.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm really, I don't think I have a con that is like the favorite con period.
Speaker 1: I have cons that are favorite in different ways.
Speaker 0: Katsu con is my favorite.
Speaker 0: be staff at it.
Speaker 0: Con Connecticut is my favorite.
Speaker 0: Let's go do a bunch of panels with very little planning.
Speaker 0: Con Otacon is my favorite.
Speaker 0: being at it for the entire weekend.
Speaker 1: Con partly because I haven't been to it yet, but I'm feeling packs is going to be my favorite.
Speaker 1: be at it for the weekend.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: Plus Otacon has the promise of shore.
Speaker 0: afterward packs has the promise.
Speaker 1: That's not something you can attribute to Otacon.
Speaker 0: It's been so many years.
Speaker 0: I mean, from the day.
Speaker 1: packs is great because there's a space needle nearby.
Speaker 0: It's when we conceived the week of awesome, called it that immediately and then went forth and did it.
Speaker 0: The week of awesome is a week of awesome.
Speaker 1: I didn't say it wasn't a week of awesome, but the people at Otacon and the Otacon convention itself has nothing to do with that.
Speaker 1: They should not really know as, as much credit as they deserve.
Speaker 1: They do not deserve credit for it being awesome to go to a beach.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: They deserve credit for at least one.
Speaker 1: I mean, remember the beach.
Speaker 0: I did not say it is the best.
Speaker 0: It is my favorite con.
Speaker 0: My favorite con can have all sorts of factors like whether or not it was Tuesday.
Speaker 0: I guess, but even so man, a con on Tuesday, you're judging which con is your favorite based on nonconvention based on the overall experience that I'm at Otacon and Sunday at Otacon.
Speaker 1: That's like if I said, Oh, Mario's my favorite game.
Speaker 1: Cause it came out on a Tuesday.
Speaker 0: I think it is Sunday at Otacon.
Speaker 0: If you're not going to the beach for a week, afterward is kind of this back to work tomorrow.
Speaker 0: But if you're going to the beach after it, it's I'm going to the beach.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I think I've made my point.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So Otacon is pretty much this year.
Speaker 0: They've changed up a lot about the way to handle panels and the submission deadline for panels came and went, they had a nice web form and all the rules were pretty clear and cut and dry.
Speaker 0: And a little while ago, they started sending out their acceptance notices.
Speaker 1: They also send out no notices.
Speaker 0: They also started sending out their rejection notice.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't have sent out rejection notices.
Speaker 1: I want to put one notice on the website saying we sent out all the acceptances.
Speaker 1: If you didn't get one, you're rejected.
Speaker 0: This is probably a better way because one that now people who don't get a notification, because I think some of this, I mean, I don't have a lot of transparency into the system this time around, but you know, what if someone doesn't accept like, all right, we've accepted your panel.
Speaker 0: Then they decide not to do it or something.
Speaker 0: They don't confirm that they're going to do it.
Speaker 0: So you kind of, once you send an acceptance, it is confirmed, but you can at least send to all the people that you're definitely not going to let do a panel.
Speaker 0: Hey, you're not going to do a panel.
Speaker 0: Better luck next year.
Speaker 0: Now they sent a nice concise little email and there was a little bit of that explosion that I kind of expected on the Otacon forums, not nearly as much as I guess I kind of hoped for just because I love, you love a hubbub.
Speaker 0: I love internet hubbub.
Speaker 0: I love watching people just go crazy on the internet because there's nothing they can do.
Speaker 1: You're basically trolling by proxy in that case.
Speaker 1: Cause someone else did something that, you know, we'll get other people riled up and you're just, you're like a troll spectator in a way, but they're not even trying to get the reaction.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, someone is going to do something that is not trolling, but we'll have a trollish effect and you just can't, you can't wait to see it happen.
Speaker 1: Cause it's like, it's like trolling when someone did it for you and they're not a troll.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the, the, the story here is that Otacon received about 175 applications.
Speaker 0: That's not bad.
Speaker 1: Cause they're, they have, they, you know, they have close to that many panels, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, they only, they're only going to have 70 panels.
Speaker 1: That's not bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good percentage.
Speaker 0: Little less than half.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, uh, actually the, uh, the New York, uh, I forget which it was.
Speaker 1: I forget it was the Comic-Con of the anime festival.
Speaker 1: They had like 200 something panels is crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: However, most of them were pretty bad, pretty bad, but anyway, Otacon, the real, they're really changing it up.
Speaker 0: They're trying to make the panels better, raise the quality, make them more academic, make them more relevant, get rid of the lame panels.
Speaker 0: Don't keep a panel just because it's tradition to have this panel.
Speaker 0: And as a result, there, there wasn't the general outcry of a million people saying, Oh, I didn't get my panel, but I've seen a lot of here and there internet hubbub from specific people who kind of felt entitled to a panel that didn't get their panel.
Speaker 0: Allow me to read an excerpt from the Otacon forum.
Speaker 1: Oh, excerpts are excellent because now no one can say, Oh, you're just making stuff up or whatever.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Frankly, I am a bit upset.
Speaker 0: I'm part of a group that has run the digital fan subbing panel at Otacon every year since 2002.
Speaker 0: Uh, it's funny.
Speaker 0: That's actually the first year we ever did a panel.
Speaker 0: We have, we have a six year uninterrupted streak and you're rejecting the panel application this year.
Speaker 1: Actually, that's probably a good reason to reject because then now it's every year.
Speaker 0: Now this is when it gets, ever since his ham dang moved on from panels, we've had nothing but problems.
Speaker 0: This is an outrage.
Speaker 0: I can't believe this is how you treat the people who've literally helped build Otacon into what it is.
Speaker 0: Who can I about an appeal now?
Speaker 0: Now the answer to appeal was basically no.
Speaker 0: And then this wonderful followup was posted.
Speaker 0: That's being said, of course, the panel has evolved tremendously over the years, along with the evolution of digital fan subbing, digital fan subbing, and therefore piracy is the number one issue the anime industry is facing in this day and age to not have a panel dedicated to it puts you in league with anime expo, which is not a con.
Speaker 0: One would imagine you'd want to be associated with.
Speaker 0: We were actually planning on having a panel discussion with members from the industry attending and discussing the issues with the very experienced and influential fan suburbs participating.
Speaker 0: I'm certain your convention is making a mistake by not tackling this issue.
Speaker 0: If there's an explanation for why it was rejected, I'd like to hear it.
Speaker 0: Thanks.
Speaker 1: So is there an explanation?
Speaker 0: Oh, are there explanations?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: You're going to read the man, Jim Vowels, the man, you might know him as alabaster in the forums, but I don't want to, I use the word favorite a lot so far today.
Speaker 0: You know, this is my favorite count.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: I think Jim Vowels is my favorite con staffer in the entire history of con staff.
Speaker 1: I'll agree.
Speaker 1: I'll agree with that guys, but he didn't invent the beach.
Speaker 0: I want to read his statement because it pretty much sums up everything that is good about what Otacon is doing with panels this year.
Speaker 0: Quoth alabaster, aka Jim Vowels, one very good thing that's come out of the last few years is that we are seriously looking at balancing fan panels with more for want of a better word, serious academic panels, meteor subjects, tighter presentation, more credible panel leaders.
Speaker 0: These are all in the mix in the past.
Speaker 0: We've been criticized rightly for having too many of the Y show XYZ rocks panels.
Speaker 0: I wonder if we were one of the prodding efforts here.
Speaker 0: Anyway, to continue I've attended some of these myself, though not at Otacon.
Speaker 0: There are few things more frustrating than being a far more qualified and informed person than the panelists on stage.
Speaker 0: I've had that happen to me on occasion, usually for Dr.
Speaker 0: Who related panels.
Speaker 1: Ah, bringing in the Dr.
Speaker 1: Who.
Speaker 1: That's definitely Jim Vowels, not an imposter.
Speaker 0: And you don't need three panels on the same general.
Speaker 0: why ninjas beat pirates?
Speaker 0: nonsense.
Speaker 1: That's true also.
Speaker 0: We have the ability to pick and choose and we were trying to build for diversity as much as anything.
Speaker 0: Lacking any other context, here's what I would rationally assume.
Speaker 0: This is referring to someone asking why their panel wasn't accepted pretty much in response to the wonderful person above.
Speaker 0: One, there was a better similar panel on offer from another panelist.
Speaker 0: Popular topics get a lot of submissions, yours might not have been the best.
Speaker 0: Number two, the subject matter wasn't relevant to the con's mission.
Speaker 0: Ninjas versus pirates is rather pointless, to use a silly example, and not particularly relevant outside of a discussion of One Piece.
Speaker 0: Internet memes, for example, are a waste of convention time and resources.
Speaker 0: I'll bet there's not going to be a 4chan panel.
Speaker 1: Those are best kept to the hallways, which is where they belong.
Speaker 1: And in fact, if not having them in the panels means more in the hallways, I'm all for it.
Speaker 1: Because hallway enjoyment of the memes is one of the pleasures of the Otacon.
Speaker 0: Three, your subject matter may have been deemed inappropriate or simply done to death.
Speaker 0: A why furries suck and why you should hate them panel, for example, is unlikely to get much traction.
Speaker 1: I think that's the one we're going here, is the done to death, as in there is a fan sub panel at every con.
Speaker 1: I mean, he himself said there's been one at Otacon for six years.
Speaker 1: Do we really need to have the same panel every single year?
Speaker 0: Subs versus dubs isn't worth arguing about anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 0: So yeah, but to go one step further, a lot of people were asking, and somewhat earnestly, why wasn't my panel submitted?
Speaker 0: Why didn't I get my panel?
Speaker 0: How am I God?
Speaker 0: What do I need to do better?
Speaker 0: And Meredith, the head of panels, who was also the head of panels last year, did a pretty damn good job considering the circumstances surrounding the panel situation last year at Otacon.
Speaker 0: Quote, be professional, not only in your application, but in all of your dealings with the panel staff.
Speaker 0: We hold the department to very high standards, both staff wise and panelists wise.
Speaker 1: Actually, despite your tone of voice, you know, that forum posed by the person was moderately professional.
Speaker 0: Which one?
Speaker 1: The one you read about the fan subbing panel.
Speaker 0: He had more to say.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: And remember, basically it was, he said this, people responded.
Speaker 0: He said it again with a little more, you know, blah, blah, blah, Anime Expo.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Someone else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Anime Expo bit was an unprofessional bit right there.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And then there were more similar discussions about this.
Speaker 1: That's a very fan boy thing to say.
Speaker 0: Plus, I'll point out, this is also posted from, I believe, Meredith from the staff.
Speaker 0: I wish I didn't have to say this, but please do not ask people to email us with requests to put your panel back on the schedule.
Speaker 0: I wish I didn't have to say this leads me to believe that a lot of people whose panels were not allowed or not accepted are getting all their friends to email the panels, people and bother them.
Speaker 0: I can't confirm that I'm reading into this statement.
Speaker 1: That is super unprofessional to be doing shit like that.
Speaker 0: Plus, honestly, looking at most of the people like this on the internet, on average, all the blog posts and people talking about how their panel was rejected and what an outrage it was did not look like the most confident or together panel producing people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Here's here's a here.
Speaker 1: I'll use this to give a tiny lesson in professionalism from Scott.
Speaker 1: He who accepts no as an answer gracefully is much more likely to receive an answer of yes.
Speaker 0: Ah, but I think much more important is he who spells words right and respond correctly.
Speaker 0: Goddamn emails.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Are you done with your whatever?
Speaker 1: I'm
Speaker 0: pretty much done with it because the end result is that Otacon is doing a big shakeup and it looks like they've gotten rid of a lot of panels that have kind of been around for a long time for no real good reason, other than the fact that they've been around for a long time.
Speaker 0: I mean, as far as I can tell there, I don't think there's going to be an anime club summit this year.
Speaker 0: I don't think there are going to be any podcasting panels, which is probably good.
Speaker 1: I mean, if I had an anime convention, if I was running one, I would not repeat any panel unless I thought I felt that there was something new that was going to be said.
Speaker 1: Like if I had, you know, a history of, uh, um, if I had history of guy in X panel last year, why would I have it this year?
Speaker 1: Has anything significantly changed in the history of guy next in the past year?
Speaker 1: Do you really need to do the same thing again?
Speaker 1: No, we could do something new.
Speaker 1: So, you know, even though that's a good panel, probably not two years in a row, in fact, once ever, you know, and there's something to be said for, well, different people would go to it, you know, and whatnot, but not the immediate next year, maybe a few years from now or something, you know, maybe you could switch it up, do history of me as a studio Ghibli instead.
Speaker 0: See, the thing is just basing my, my experiences at, I don't know, the dozens and dozens of anime cons I've been to for all these years, the majority of panels, just why I'm not talking about Otacon, but in general are usually pretty bad.
Speaker 0: And Otacon is in the, they're so rarely in the situation where they have such a wide group of people from whom to choose panels that there's no excuse for Otacon not to have the best of the best, the best that the fans have to offer.
Speaker 0: And this year with this shakeup and the way they're changing everything, I think these are going to be the best panels Otacon has ever had.
Speaker 0: And I don't think it's going to be amazing.
Speaker 0: I think it's just going to be a major improvement after one more year of this, because remember, as we learned last year, they're keeping a lot more track of who goes to what panels and how well they were received and how professional the panelists were and all that business.
Speaker 1: I think sadly, a lot of who goes to what panel doesn't have anything to do with how good the panel is.
Speaker 1: It has to do with the time, place and title of the panel.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much those three things combined are what determines panel attendance.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, you can normalize the data based on like, if you know the average attendance of a given generic Friday morning panel, then you can say, well, this Friday morning panel that normally Friday morning panels get 50 people.
Speaker 0: This one got 300 and there was a line out the door.
Speaker 1: Another thing I would do is if I was running a convention, I would, you can't really change the times so much or the rooms, but cause there's always going to be, you know, a panel at every time in every room, supposedly,
Speaker 0: but I would
Speaker 1: move the better titled panels to the less trafficked hours.
Speaker 1: So sort of even it out, you know, maybe someone, you know, if I put this really popular panel at the really good time, it'll be stupid full.
Speaker 1: It's much better to put that at the really shitty time or it'll be normal full.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, a less popular panel, but not a shitty panel.
Speaker 1: Cause I don't have any shitty panels, a less popular panel at the really good time.
Speaker 1: And then people would go to it because of the time.
Speaker 0: you say, I just feel like this year's Otakon in a lot of ways is going to transcend all previous Otakons.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of indications, like a lot of things have changed a lot of subtle things.
Speaker 0: And this panels thing is it's going to be a big deal.
Speaker 0: I think after this year and after we see how well this works starting in 2009, I think Otakon's panels are going to blow you out of the fucking water for better or for worse.
Speaker 1: Cause you know, who knows?
Speaker 1: I give mad props to anyone who actually has the balls to try to stir shit up.
Speaker 1: I mean, stuff doesn't get better unless you change it.
Speaker 1: And whenever you change anything, people always get upset because no, they don't like change.
Speaker 1: If someone has the balls to say, screw you, I'm changing it.
Speaker 1: Even if it turns out poorly, I give them the props anyway, because they had the balls to change.
Speaker 0: Despite change, always being unpopular changes, always a good example was that anime club summit, whatever that, you know, we were on since what, 2002 at Otakon.
Speaker 0: And then one year randomly, we were like, all right, we've done this panel forever.
Speaker 0: We're running a kinetic con.
Speaker 0: let's completely change it up.
Speaker 0: And it turned into this completely different panel that I think was a thousand times better format wise.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: You done?
Speaker 0: I think I'm done though.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to announce it yet until we know the time, but I will say yes, we're doing a panel at Otakon in case all our listeners were wondering.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was the strongest of the, I don't know, 11 or 12 we offered to Otakon, but, uh, I think it'll go over really well.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So check this.
Speaker 1: Uh, I'm going to explain this a little bit because I'm sure some people out there still don't understand this, but when you buy comic books in the O S you buy, you know, usually one issue or a trade of a single title.
Speaker 1: So if Naruto was an American comic book, every month you'd buy an issue of Naruto.
Speaker 1: And then every few months you would buy a book of Naruto that has a whole bunch of the previous, like five or six issues in it.
Speaker 1: Right in Japan, it sort of works differently.
Speaker 1: They have these anthology magazines, they're magazines like, but they're big.
Speaker 1: So you would subscribe to Shonen Jump and every week Shonen Jump would come in the mail, or you could buy it in the newsstand every week.
Speaker 1: And in one Shonen Jump, you would get one issue of Dragon Ball, one issue of Naruto, one issue of One Piece, an issue of Death Note, et cetera, et cetera, right.
Speaker 1: Depending on which ones were in there that week.
Speaker 1: Cause not every single one is in there every week.
Speaker 1: And then eventually when there's enough issues of Shonen Jump, they print the ones that we read, the manga that we read in the U S such as the Tonko bond, which is, you know, we're just going to take the last, you know, six chapters of Death Note and put them in one book.
Speaker 1: So the problem here is that even though people might know a lot of manga titles, right.
Speaker 1: And you might know, you know, where certain ones were originally published.
Speaker 1: It's sort of hard.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, okay, there's this manga title, which one of these magazines was originally in, which chapters were in which magazines.
Speaker 1: And it's, there are a lot of magazines, like a lot.
Speaker 1: And over the course of history, many of them have come and gone.
Speaker 1: And it's quite difficult to sort of sort this whole thing out.
Speaker 1: Even on like Wikipedia's and anime news networks, this in for this sort of information is very, very, very incomplete, but apparently they have launched in Japan, uh, in Japan, the post-war Japanese Shonen and Shojo magazine database.
Speaker 1: It has listings for 1,221 magazines.
Speaker 1: And there's three parts.
Speaker 1: There's the era of post-war Shonen, Shojo magazines, monthly magazines, and as the weekly magazines.
Speaker 1: And, um, it's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Cause now we have like the most full database of which mangas were published, where and when that has ever existed.
Speaker 1: And this is going to be totally awesome and cool.
Speaker 1: And they need something like this for American comics because for American comics, pretty much, you know, you can get a lot of information, but there's still no really super complete databases.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's some sites that are working on it, like comic book DB, but that's sort of like the Wikipedia of comic books.
Speaker 1: You know, it's all human edited and there's nothing that's like super, super complete like this thing is.
Speaker 1: So I know very cool.
Speaker 1: I say, plus, I mean, 1,221 magazines.
Speaker 1: I can only name about like maybe 20 magazines if I try really hard.
Speaker 1: So the fact that there were 2,221, that's pretty fantastic.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's actually one more thing I should really talk about before we get into things of the day.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So just so you're all aware, Inuyasha is ending, right?
Speaker 0: The manga, the manga, the manga.
Speaker 0: It's going the anime.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I stopped watching it after like six episodes.
Speaker 1: I started watching it after one episode.
Speaker 0: I actually really liked it.
Speaker 0: The problem was it just, you know, it's Rumiko Takahashi.
Speaker 0: It goes on forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I've already seen enough of her.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's actually going to end.
Speaker 0: I'm probably going to pick up the last volume of it just to see how it ended.
Speaker 1: End in English or end in Japan?
Speaker 0: End in Japan.
Speaker 1: Oh, OK.
Speaker 0: Obviously.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't be news that it's going to end in English because that would mean that we already knew.
Speaker 1: Well, it could be.
Speaker 1: the last English manga volume is coming out soon.
Speaker 1: That's a news.
Speaker 0: But we would have already known then.
Speaker 0: Some would have already announced like they are now that, hey, it's ending in Japan.
Speaker 0: Oh, snap.
Speaker 1: I guess.
Speaker 1: We might have missed it though.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So things of the day.
Speaker 0: I don't have much here.
Speaker 0: I got kind of a reserve thing that I'm saving for a rainy day, but I want to get right into mocha.
Speaker 0: So Emily showed me this opener to a TV series called Wok Fu.
Speaker 0: And apparently Wok Fu is a video game, some sort of tactical MMO.
Speaker 0: I don't know exactly what the deal is, but it's reminiscent of way back when we saw something called Eretz Waju.
Speaker 0: We found this and we thought that it was an anime.
Speaker 0: And back then, when we hadn't seen that much anime yet, and especially when we had enough time to watch every anime we came across, the opener looked like, oh, man, this show is going to be awesome.
Speaker 0: And we looked for it and we looked for it.
Speaker 0: And then a long time later, someone was like, oh, yeah, that was a shitty fighting game.
Speaker 0: That wasn't a show.
Speaker 0: And we were like, well, was there a show based on the game?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Mostly the awesomeness of Eretz Waju was not actually what was in the video, but the music to the opener.
Speaker 0: That was a damn good song.
Speaker 1: It's still a damn good song.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, link to that if I can find it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, this instills a slightly similar feeling in me, except this time it actually is a TV series.
Speaker 0: It's a trailer.
Speaker 1: Oh, good.
Speaker 0: It's very fighty, but unlike the kind of fighting shows I hate, there's a small chance that it's fighty.
Speaker 0: in the there are choreographed fights that end and take less than an episode.
Speaker 1: That's the only kind of fight I could tolerate pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But imagine if they were like, if if Naruto had been otherwise the same, except no fight, no fight.
Speaker 0: And if there was a tournament, then the entire tournament lasted longer than 15 minutes, then the show would only be like five episodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it would have been a great five episodes.
Speaker 1: It sure would have been.
Speaker 0: There would have been more characters talking to each other in a context outside of.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's all I got.
Speaker 0: That's all I got.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So you probably know this.
Speaker 1: All my things today are things you probably know.
Speaker 1: And then elaborating on them.
Speaker 1: But Japan is the land of vending machines.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 1: Are they loaded with the vending machines of all shapes and sizes?
Speaker 0: I wish we had vending machines like that.
Speaker 0: I want to get coffee from a vending machine.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But anyway, canned coffee, not not coffee in a star.
Speaker 1: There is some.
Speaker 1: you can get crazy things in vending machines.
Speaker 1: You can get normal things from crazy vending machines.
Speaker 1: You get crazy things from crazy vending machines.
Speaker 1: It's Japan is vending machine crazy.
Speaker 1: And some guy went to Vendex, which is the vending machine convention in Japan.
Speaker 1: And he brought back a bunch of pictures of crazy shit that's going down there.
Speaker 1: And that's my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: And he also sort of talks a little bit about the history of vending machines in Japan, which is also cool.
Speaker 1: But yet check out the crazy Japanese vending machines.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: It's pretty hot.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is pretty hot.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So two weeks ago, because we haven't been doing geek nights every week like we used to, we went to the Moka Art Festival, which is not a coffee art festival.
Speaker 1: It is the Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art Art Festival.
Speaker 1: And no, that is not redundant.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, most people when they sit like people don't seem to realize that Moka is a thing independent of the Moka Festival.
Speaker 1: The Moka is the museum.
Speaker 1: It is the Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art is in New York.
Speaker 1: It is very close to my work.
Speaker 1: It's you should go there at least once.
Speaker 1: But usually you want to go there depending on what exhibition they have.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not really a big museum, even though they do have a lot of material.
Speaker 1: It's not always all out, you know, but whatever.
Speaker 1: They are very good museum despite having very little physical space.
Speaker 1: And every year they make most of their money by having an art festival, which is perhaps one of the best comic conventions on earth.
Speaker 1: And it's in New York.
Speaker 1: And we go.
Speaker 1: we've been there the past three or four years, I think.
Speaker 1: I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: I think this is the third or fourth.
Speaker 1: I can't remember anyway.
Speaker 1: And it is awesome.
Speaker 1: And awesome things go down there.
Speaker 1: And it really seems like every year you go to the Moka and it's always the same but different.
Speaker 1: It's like you see the same people in the same places.
Speaker 1: But everyone always has something new to show you.
Speaker 0: For example, last year there was one big not for sale poop sign.
Speaker 0: This year there were a lot of little $8 poop signs.
Speaker 1: Oh, poop signs.
Speaker 1: We'll get to that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And you know, some people have the same table in the same spot.
Speaker 1: Old trustee.
Speaker 1: But some people it's like a whole new person at a whole new table.
Speaker 1: And you go, oh, man, look at this completely new thing.
Speaker 1: And you could watch.
Speaker 1: It's weird because it's like we walk around for a few hours and really as great a convention as it is, it's still a comic convention.
Speaker 1: So it's pretty much look at all the tables, go home.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not really a reason to stick around.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are panels, but it's pretty much one panel at a time.
Speaker 1: So if there's one you really want to go to, then you should go to the convention when that one is happening.
Speaker 1: But you don't want to sit around and go to all of them.
Speaker 1: You'd be pretty bored eventually, unless you really, really liked all the panels, I guess.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I've never been to a panel at MOCA, so I can't say.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's like you go to all the rooms and eventually after walking around all the rooms, you sort of feel like you've seen everything, even though you haven't seen everything and you really can't see everything.
Speaker 1: You feel like you've seen everything and you sort of you leave.
Speaker 1: But going year after year, it really becomes easier to see everything because a lot of stuff is like, I know everything you've got.
Speaker 1: I saw it last year.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But what was at the MOCA were some pretty awesome things.
Speaker 1: Do you want to?
Speaker 1: do you want to talk about some of the awesome things?
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: I figure we wouldn't even bother talking about the awesome things we saw at MOCA.
Speaker 1: Oh, OK.
Speaker 0: I think first and foremost, we have to point out that Jason was there.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: And actually, we happened to find the place where Jason was going to be.
Speaker 0: And we found that Jason was going to be doing a signing.
Speaker 0: We discovered that the signing was going to take place in like three minutes.
Speaker 0: So we just sort of stood there and we're looking around debating whether or not any number of the people we saw milling around were Jason.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, basically there's a guy.
Speaker 1: he lives in France, but he's from Norway, right?
Speaker 1: I think it's from Norway.
Speaker 1: And he makes the comics that we love the most.
Speaker 1: And he came to the US for this convention so awesomely.
Speaker 1: And we were like, oh, man, we're going to see the Jason guy.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think we reviewed.
Speaker 0: Why are you doing this?
Speaker 1: We should do an episode on all the Jason's together.
Speaker 0: I think we're going to have to do a Jason episode.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: And we only know his name is Jason.
Speaker 1: And no one was wearing a name tag, but we knew it was at the fan of graphics booth and we knew that Jason was doing a signing in like 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: So he couldn't be far away and he wasn't sitting at the signing table at that moment.
Speaker 1: So we're like, is it that guy?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Is it that guy?
Speaker 1: And I'm looking at all the Jason books they have available.
Speaker 1: And I said, I'm going to buy all the Jason books.
Speaker 1: I don't have.
Speaker 1: The problem was I had preordered a Jason book, but I did not know which one I had preordered.
Speaker 1: And of the books on the table, there were three I did not own.
Speaker 1: And I was like, I know I've preordered one of these.
Speaker 1: So we bought two of them and we guessed wrong.
Speaker 1: So now we're going to have doubles of one of the books, which is perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: And we have none of one of the other books.
Speaker 0: I have so little to say about Jason.
Speaker 0: that is not outright praise, if not hero worship.
Speaker 1: Yes, something like that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we bought.
Speaker 1: I forget which ones we bought, but we didn't buy.
Speaker 1: The Last Musketeer, which is probably by the cover is a robot holding a dude.
Speaker 1: And that's the one.
Speaker 1: I didn't preorder it.
Speaker 1: And I just, I love I didn't buy it.
Speaker 0: So I need to get titles of his works because they're, you know, sometimes you want like Bocorano.
Speaker 0: The anime was a good example.
Speaker 0: where it's like the opening song or the title or something like that has a phrase.
Speaker 0: And then it has meaning after you've seen the whole work that you didn't expect or that is much more profound than I guess would have been warranted.
Speaker 1: That's how a title is supposed to be.
Speaker 0: Not a lot of times it's not.
Speaker 0: I mean, Hamlet is about a guy named Shakespeare wasn't about the titles.
Speaker 1: He wasn't.
Speaker 1: He wasn't selling it on his shelf with a big title on the side.
Speaker 1: He was putting it in a theater.
Speaker 1: I was in a big circle.
Speaker 0: All right, fine.
Speaker 0: I picked one example, but a lot of a lot of books like the title is.
Speaker 0: But Jason's works, I mean, like the one that we picked up there that I read just recently, Hey, that was a good one.
Speaker 0: That was really sad, though.
Speaker 0: But the coolest thing is, Jason, this guy, I have so much respect for him even more so now, because when he does a signing, he's not just like, hey, here's a signing.
Speaker 0: Go away next.
Speaker 0: Hey, go away next.
Speaker 0: He pretty much sat there and drew an entire picture for every single person in line.
Speaker 1: I mean, he was it's sort of like he got in his groove on some of the people in front of us, you know, and he would basically draw like one of the characters in his style because he does sort of like these anthropomorphic but not furry characters.
Speaker 1: You know, everyone's like a dog man or a crow woman or whatever.
Speaker 0: I really like his style.
Speaker 1: I need your little stuff around it.
Speaker 1: And then he would be like, you know, sort of smile at you.
Speaker 1: Well, he first after he was finished drawing, he would sort of like put it out in front of him and pull his head back and sort of like, oh, yes, that is correct.
Speaker 1: Then he would like smile and then he would like give it to you.
Speaker 1: And the thing he was so like, it was weird because you read his comics and you try to figure out what kind of person he was.
Speaker 1: And I thought that he would be like an older kind of person, maybe sort of clever and kind of hey.
Speaker 1: But he was like relatively young, maybe 30 something, I guess.
Speaker 1: And he was all quiet and shy and not saying much.
Speaker 0: He carries himself the way the characters in his works carry themselves.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: It was not very short on words, but the words that are said are very meaningful.
Speaker 0: I didn't try to interview him or anything because he seemed very shy, but he's at the same time like, well, of course, Scott did something awesome.
Speaker 0: But Emily took up Hey, wait, you know, and he'd already been primed because of the way we talked to him a little bit.
Speaker 0: So he basically drew an entire new cover for Hey, wait inside of Hey, wait.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: No, but I gave him my.
Speaker 1: instead of giving him one of the books we just bought, I gave him the pirate sketchbook and it's like, draw pirate.
Speaker 1: And then he drew a Jason pirate.
Speaker 0: It was great because he stops and he's thinking for a and I think skies remarked, Oh no, we made him think.
Speaker 0: And then he starts drawing a pirate.
Speaker 0: And the cool thing is when he sketches, he doesn't sketch it.
Speaker 0: He's one of those people that's so rare where he just starts drawing and every line is exactly perfect.
Speaker 1: He just takes the pen, you know, screw the pencil.
Speaker 1: He just takes the pen and he draws a line.
Speaker 1: And then another line.
Speaker 1: I mean, like he thinks about each line before he draws it.
Speaker 1: And then he draws it like deliberately and correctly, but he just goes, eh, eh, eh.
Speaker 0: The coolest thing though, sometimes like he'll stop and look at something and then he'll like, you'll see him move the pen around over the paper without drawing.
Speaker 0: And he'll go like, nope.
Speaker 1: It's like, he's making like his practice lines in the air.
Speaker 0: And the funny, like he'll draw the character.
Speaker 0: And then it's especially with Scott's thing.
Speaker 0: Cause I think that was when he really got into his groove in terms of drawing for people.
Speaker 0: Cause then he did the same thing for Emily, where he finishes the character and then he stops, he looks at it.
Speaker 0: Then he adds like a little thing and then another little thing, like a little back palm tree and then he's like cloud tree, another cloud.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: He just started, started getting with the flavor, getting, uh, getting going on.
Speaker 0: If nothing else though, I'm very glad that we're not alone in our love of Jason because the line was long and continuous.
Speaker 0: for what the three hours he was doing this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I'm sure he came back the next day and I think he had an event in Brooklyn on like Friday night.
Speaker 0: So I felt really bad.
Speaker 0: I don't remember who it was.
Speaker 0: The guy who had the spot next to him for that three hour interview blog.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There was a guy sitting next to him.
Speaker 1: What was the, what was the book that he was selling?
Speaker 0: Uh, belly button.
Speaker 1: So yes, it was something about the, like the bottom was belly button or something like, look it up.
Speaker 1: I'll go to the fan of graphics website, but it actually looked pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It looked really cool.
Speaker 1: And it was like this giant book and it looked pretty impressive, but I didn't read it and I wasn't about to pay for it, you know, cause it was so large and rather expensive for something I didn't know much about.
Speaker 1: And, but the guy seemed like a cool guy and he was nice and he was sitting next to Jason, you know, with his belly button book and just, he had no line.
Speaker 1: No one was coming to see him.
Speaker 1: because you know, Jason was next to him and it was like, Oh, Oh, I feel bad for you, but I can't help you.
Speaker 0: It was funny though.
Speaker 0: Cause me, Scott and Emily get up to Jason and we're just like, we're basically, we're paralyzed with school girl giddiness.
Speaker 0: And we're like, we really like your works.
Speaker 0: They're so good.
Speaker 0: Oh man.
Speaker 1: There's a poll on the side of the fan of graphics website.
Speaker 1: It says which of your favorite of Jason's recent books.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Enough.
Speaker 0: The hero worship.
Speaker 0: Jason is great.
Speaker 0: And we got to meet him.
Speaker 0: He drew stuff for us.
Speaker 0: Scott should scan in the pirate picture.
Speaker 1: I'll try.
Speaker 1: Oh man.
Speaker 1: It's a tough vote here.
Speaker 1: Uh, 37 votes for, I killed Adolf Hitler 37 votes for left bank gang 27. for why are you doing this?
Speaker 0: Why are you doing?
Speaker 0: this is the best one.
Speaker 1: I know, uh, living in the dead 13 last musketeer nine meow, baby seven.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the rest of mocha it's, they always break it up in the same kind of way.
Speaker 0: We're like, there's one area where it's all the web comics and like the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They got, they got three rooms going on is the big room.
Speaker 1: They sort of like the internet, cool web comic room.
Speaker 1: And as the upstairs room, which has added last year, right?
Speaker 1: And things are sort of thematically arranged a bit like the big, oh, there's also the, the, the front room, the front room usually has the big publishers in it, except top shelf, which is in, uh, they have the bar in, in the big room.
Speaker 1: And then in the big room is just sort of like all the indie people all around.
Speaker 1: And then the upstairs room is sort of like, you know, it's, it's sort of upstairs room is sort of like the quirky kind of room.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like you got, uh, Vertigo, Vertigo, which is DC comics up there, but you've also got like just a guy who's not even selling comics is just like art.
Speaker 1: And then you've got like the foreign comics up there.
Speaker 1: Uh, and in the front of the upstairs, you've got like this, uh, sign, uh, sketch area where you buy tickets and then the famous people sit there and they'll sketch for you if you buy a ticket and it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so do you want to sort of go room by room or do you want to go buy what we bought?
Speaker 1: or how do you want to do this?
Speaker 0: Let's just go buy impressions because I didn't buy a lot, but everything that I bought is absolutely high quality.
Speaker 1: One thing is last year I regretted it.
Speaker 1: I held back.
Speaker 1: I was like, I'm going to hold back.
Speaker 1: I'm only going to, you know, cause I was like, I'll pre-order it online.
Speaker 1: I'll hold back.
Speaker 1: I'll hold back this year.
Speaker 1: I'm like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm not holding back.
Speaker 1: I'm not holding the back.
Speaker 1: I'm going to buy, buy, buy, buy, because there's a lot of stuff in mocha.
Speaker 1: You can't get not at mocha.
Speaker 1: And, uh, I held back less than last year, but still I'm feeling like I didn't unleash enough.
Speaker 1: I should have bought more.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: The thing is that if I buy more, I'll end up buying everything and I'll be poor.
Speaker 1: That's not a good thing.
Speaker 0: See, very pointedly.
Speaker 0: I didn't carry a lot of cash on me.
Speaker 1: I carried $300, but I didn't spend it all.
Speaker 1: Not even close, but I was pretty much just like, yeah, I'll buy it.
Speaker 1: Here's a 20.
Speaker 1: Good guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Pretty much the one thing about the mocha, if you ever go to it is that there is no way to go around in a group easily.
Speaker 0: You're pretty much going to have to split up and then meet back periodically and talk about the things you saw.
Speaker 1: You've got narrow aisles, you've got small tables, you've got multiple rooms and you've got a crowd.
Speaker 1: It's, you can't really go around with multiple people.
Speaker 1: You got to go around on your own looking at stuff.
Speaker 0: Plus, especially if you want to go see something that is popular, you'll pretty much, it'll be a four foot long table and there'll be like 10 people desperately pushing to try to be in front of that table
Speaker 1: blocking off the adjacent tables, you know, because they'll be going lining up horizontally because you can't line up vertical.
Speaker 1: You'll just bug.
Speaker 0: the aisles are so narrow and of course, everyone's got a gigantic bag full of swag.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So you sort of go around and when you bump into people, you know, you're like, Hey, and then you sort of go check out what I got.
Speaker 1: What's up.
Speaker 1: How you doing?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the upstairs is kind of empty.
Speaker 0: Well, the upstairs is a big ballroom and it's, it's a much different, it's more airy.
Speaker 0: People seem to go up there to chill.
Speaker 0: There's a lot more.
Speaker 0: Now I don't want to say lower level, but more like just starting out independent stuff up there.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, we also, we met a listener there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Kind of randomly.
Speaker 0: It was a little bit of an ego stroke, but I'm standing there.
Speaker 1: Well, it was an RIT person.
Speaker 1: So the ego isn't stroked that heavily.
Speaker 0: It's still stroked.
Speaker 0: Anytime you're in a public place and you hear the words, excuse me, are you rim and sky of geek nights?
Speaker 0: Oh man.
Speaker 0: I listened to your show.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: I can't believe you're here.
Speaker 0: I forget what the guy's name was, but you were totally cool.
Speaker 1: He was a cool dude.
Speaker 1: He was an RIT dude.
Speaker 1: He knew what the score was.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah, RIT anime.
Speaker 0: And I was like, Oh, so the later years, blah, but no, he was the early years.
Speaker 0: He was there from the administrations previous to us.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: It's like, I fully expect someone who is on RIT at the same time as us to found out about us, but someone who was there before us, it's sort of like, huh?
Speaker 1: Well, you know, while there is the connection, it's like the connection wasn't so strong.
Speaker 1: How did they, where?
Speaker 0: from what I've gathered, we're, we're kind of legendary at RIT a little bit.
Speaker 0: And that like the people in the animal club still by and large, remember us, which is not altogether comforting.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: Cause we don't even know who's an anime club anymore.
Speaker 0: I met the coming in administration.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So let's start talking about some comics here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Cause that's really the only way to go about this.
Speaker 0: I interviewed some people.
Speaker 0: I'll, I'll put some clips from random stuff that we didn't get a chance to read or review or anything yet at the end, just so you guys can get a, I don't know, more well-rounded mocha picture.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So later I'm going to start with this.
Speaker 1: I didn't, this isn't even something I bought, but chip kid.
Speaker 1: chip kid is like a, the world famous designer of book covers.
Speaker 1: That's, you know, he does other things, but he's a super world famous mega rich designer guy in New York.
Speaker 1: And he, if you read the vertical mangas, he designs the covers on most of those.
Speaker 1: And he's awesome all around.
Speaker 1: He did a signing at the New York comic con missed it.
Speaker 1: He did a panel at mocha.
Speaker 1: It was Sunday.
Speaker 1: We weren't there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But he's doing a thing called bat manga, the secret history of Batman in Japan.
Speaker 0: I'm so excited about this.
Speaker 1: I was sorta iffy on it.
Speaker 1: I was like, do I really care?
Speaker 1: But no, I have the free pamphlet from Pantheon books, right?
Speaker 1: About bat manga.
Speaker 1: It's like this it's, it's, it's this pamphlet thing.
Speaker 1: They were handing out at their booth for free.
Speaker 1: And that sort of gives you a sample of what this bat manga is going to be all about.
Speaker 1: And I, as soon as they handed me this pamphlet, I was like, Oh, I am in desperate need of the bat mongers.
Speaker 1: Give me, give me more, please.
Speaker 1: Yes, I want.
Speaker 1: And, uh, I don't even know what to say.
Speaker 1: I mean, you've got Batman kicking a giant robot in the chest.
Speaker 1: Um, you've got Batman, a toy of Batman sitting in a metal tank with two turrets on it.
Speaker 1: What else can I say?
Speaker 1: This is the awesomeness, the super awesomeness.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I have to talk about this because one, I read the comic already.
Speaker 0: We'll probably review it at some point, but two, this person did such a good job of getting someone like me to read his comic.
Speaker 0: Like this is a marketing success story as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There it's, it's weird because like I normally buy comics based on solicitations and the cover and the title, because you can't really pick out new comics any other way besides that, you know, unless you go to the store and look through them.
Speaker 1: But when you go to like mocha, the people who make the comics can sell them to you.
Speaker 1: And if someone who happens to be a comic artist is an amazing salesperson, they will often sell a disproportionate number of their comic, usually to me, because I am very gullible when it comes to comic sell salespeople.
Speaker 1: But anyway, Mike Dawson, I mean, I, I was walking around and I like Dawson from, no, no, I see this big statue of Freddie Mercury, the kind of statue that you see in a comic book store.
Speaker 1: that would cost like $300.
Speaker 0: But usually those things are of Batman.
Speaker 0: This one was a Freddie Mercury.
Speaker 0: They sell those at comic book stores, but I, well, I've never seen a statue of Freddie Mercury before.
Speaker 1: I had seen that statue in the past.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't really go to comic book stores, but I've never seen a statue that big, a Freddie Mercury other than it's like a 12.
Speaker 1: It's a 12 inch, I think, or 16.
Speaker 1: It was 16 inch.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So of course I walk over because I am a huge fan of Queen.
Speaker 0: And of course I am presented with ready and me a coming of age Bohemian Rhapsody.
Speaker 1: See this thing actually sort of surprised me because I sort of like a month or two ago, I said, you know, someone should make like a story or a comic or a movie about like someone who can channel the spirits of like old rockers that are dead.
Speaker 1: Like, like, you know, basically be possessed by John Lennon and play music and sing like John Lennon, or that's not what this is about.
Speaker 1: I know that's not what that is about, but it's like, wow.
Speaker 1: You know, it's sort of weird.
Speaker 1: I had the, a symbol, an idea about, you know, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: So you're saying, wow.
Speaker 0: It's so weird that had an idea and then a completely different idea was made into a comic.
Speaker 1: No, it's, it's, it's a somewhat relate, not in that these channeling spirits of dead rockers, but in that it happens to involve Freddie Mercury rock and roll comic going on.
Speaker 0: That's a bit of a stretch.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of rock and roll.
Speaker 0: I feel like I'm getting a C. you were writing, I don't know, a comic or maybe a screenplay or a movie or a, or a, or a video game.
Speaker 0: Maybe you were writing a video game.
Speaker 0: I can cold read.
Speaker 0: You see anyway.
Speaker 0: Mike Dawson.
Speaker 1: This is my book, Freddy and me.
Speaker 1: It's about my obsession with the band.
Speaker 1: queen starts in 1984 with the song.
Speaker 1: I want to break free.
Speaker 1: Uh, and it goes on up through to 2003 with the, uh, with the questionable taste, uh, musical they had in London, which I went to go and see, and that's where the book ends.
Speaker 1: But it also like the whole, the whole idea is that like, you know, a story about me moving from England to America.
Speaker 1: Um, it's really a lot to do with memory and identity, but it's sort of, it's a way to kind of hang the story on the structure of the queen songs.
Speaker 0: So Freddie and me is not about Freddie mercury.
Speaker 0: It is about Mike Dawson.
Speaker 0: It's an autobiographical comic about this guy and his life.
Speaker 0: And he talks a lot about memory and remembering things when you're a kid versus when you're an adult and perspective and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's good stuff.
Speaker 0: It's just a good standup straight up laid back comic autobiography.
Speaker 0: And he happens to use Freddie mercury and queen's music as kind of this running thread through it because he was a fan of queen almost his entire life.
Speaker 0: And he was a fan of Freddie mercury's entire life.
Speaker 0: So the like songs from queen were very much linked with memories that he had.
Speaker 0: And that's kind of how he can remember all the events in his life is from these songs and this fandom.
Speaker 0: And of course it's not on the cover and you wouldn't get it until you actually read it, but it's also quite a bit about wham.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: That actually makes a lot of sense.
Speaker 1: I don't know much about wham, so I might miss a lot of really.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, you, you should read the history of wham and, and how about?
Speaker 0: no, actually you should, because you should see who came out of wham.
Speaker 0: You'd be surprised.
Speaker 0: I don't think you realize the whole story there.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll read the Wikipedia that it's worth it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I read the whole thing and this is, this is, this is what comics need more of.
Speaker 0: It is not a stereotypical comic as in superhero, whatever.
Speaker 0: It is just an autobiography that happens to be in comic form.
Speaker 0: And I suits the medium very well.
Speaker 1: I got a lot of comic autobiographies.
Speaker 1: I got fun home.
Speaker 0: If you read fun home, I haven't read it yet.
Speaker 1: I got, I got a couple others.
Speaker 1: I think I can't just, they're not coming to me right now.
Speaker 0: I just, I really, really enjoyed this.
Speaker 0: I'll review it at some point in more depth.
Speaker 1: I'll be reading that.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: There's a book called skyscrapers of the Midwest by Joshua Cotter.
Speaker 1: I haven't read it yet.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So I can't say much about it.
Speaker 1: All I know is that I knew the book was awesome and I knew I was going to buy it at some point, but it was only in a hard cover.
Speaker 1: so I didn't preorder it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I was waiting for some sort of soft cover action, but I'd never seen the book and mocha.
Speaker 1: Josh Cotter was there and I saw the book.
Speaker 1: As soon as I saw the book, I said, Oh, Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: Just give me one of those.
Speaker 0: Do you realize how often that would happen to me at the mocha in general?
Speaker 0: I walk into a table.
Speaker 0: It's like, what's that?
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: And then I hand over a bunch of money.
Speaker 1: So here, let me, I'm flip open, uh, this skyscrapers of the Midwest and I'm going to pick something out of it.
Speaker 1: Uh, let's see.
Speaker 1: I haven't read this yet, so I don't know.
Speaker 1: Let's see the merit badge.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: There's a page here all about merit badges and there's pictures of them and there's descriptions next to each one.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So let's see, I'm going to read two of these merit badges randomly.
Speaker 1: Uh, I did not prepare this in advance by the way.
Speaker 1: So one of the merit badges is a picture of a bunny on it and it says next to it, bunnies hunt the little bastards down.
Speaker 1: You are superior man.
Speaker 1: Tear off their heads, stuff them with sawdust and Mount him on varnished wood with deer antlers.
Speaker 1: It'll be hilarious.
Speaker 1: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Uh, shit taken at the bear badges, a picture of a roll of toilet paper.
Speaker 1: Lots of salty junk food.
Speaker 1: Walk around in the woods in the middle of July with his stomach full of fatty, greasy crap and soda.
Speaker 1: Get sick and relieve yourself behind a tree.
Speaker 1: Have others watch.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right then.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: That was, this book really looks like it's a lot of random stuff.
Speaker 1: Like parts of it's comics, part of it's stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Part of it is like a giant robot picking up a house.
Speaker 1: Part of it is like pages from school yearbooks.
Speaker 1: It's really, it's really pretty interesting.
Speaker 0: That's one thing that's actually really cool about the mochas that you'll run into a lot of really experimental stuff or just stuff like.
Speaker 0: you've never seen a comic like this before and you don't know what this even is.
Speaker 1: It's like, I haven't read this, so I can't say more, but just holding it and flipping through it and feeling it.
Speaker 1: I know this is quality.
Speaker 1: and at the table next to Joshua Cotter, there was another guy who started sharing a table with him and he didn't look that interesting.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to be honest, but I don't want to insult him because actually I was very much lucky to notice him while I was there waiting for Josh Cotter to draw a little doodle in the front of the, he drew a little skull doodle in front of this skyscrapers of the Midwest.
Speaker 1: But what's this guy's name?
Speaker 1: Did he write his name in his book?
Speaker 1: Did he not?
Speaker 1: Oh, here I go.
Speaker 1: Joey Weiser.
Speaker 1: There we go.
Speaker 1: Tragic-planet.com.
Speaker 1: On his table was a little book called Cavemen in Space.
Speaker 1: How can you not buy that?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: That's the problem.
Speaker 0: Half the things I see is how can you not buy that?
Speaker 0: Like remember Teen Boat?
Speaker 0: I bought Teen Boat because of that exact same feeling last year.
Speaker 0: How can you not buy Teen Boat?
Speaker 0: I should have bought the Teen Boat shirt.
Speaker 0: I forgot to and then we left.
Speaker 1: Teen Boat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this Cavemen in Space is a little tiny mini comic and you could probably buy one from Joey Weiser.
Speaker 1: I don't know how else you're going to get it because it's not like something that's going to be in comic book stores, but it's a little full color, well-printed mini comic actually.
Speaker 1: And I got some chuckles from this.
Speaker 1: I mean, you basically have cavemen in space and a robot gets loose and they fight the robot and just sort of like, you know, that the plot itself, not so great.
Speaker 1: You know, it's pretty, you know, straightforward, but the characters, even though there's maybe 10 pages in this thing and the little tiny jokes, you know, involving the characters were quite humorous.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I bought the Cavemen in Space.
Speaker 1: It gives me sort of a space wolf kind of vibe.
Speaker 0: I was about to say when you, when you introduce the concept, all I could think of was, uh, what's the guy's name?
Speaker 0: Ansabel.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Whatever his name was, he did space wolf.
Speaker 0: He was the thing of the day, the last duet on earth, all that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: You got anything else over there?
Speaker 0: Well, speaking of short comics or things like that, where you just have to buy it for the concept alone.
Speaker 0: Remember last year when I bought prison comics and they were utterly hilarious.
Speaker 1: That was two years ago, but yeah, they it was in the past previous mocha.
Speaker 0: I could not find prison comics this year, but Scott found something so similar, you know, short comic book about a very specific thing.
Speaker 0: And it was what?
Speaker 0: A dollar.
Speaker 1: It was a dollar.
Speaker 1: You are correct.
Speaker 0: What exactly was it called?
Speaker 1: Are you referring to the diarrhea diaries?
Speaker 0: I might be.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: See the, the thing that this has in common with the prison stories is that it's a comic consisting of multiple short, true stories, just sort of expressed in comic form for humor's sake.
Speaker 0: This is a genre, I guess that you see a lot of at things like the mocha.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of people who have like little seven page stapled together, 25 cent comics.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It is a dollar and it's basically, let me, let me read the front, right?
Speaker 1: The front page is a picture and it's of this guy.
Speaker 1: It's the guy who made the comic.
Speaker 1: He's sitting on a toilet with his pants on around his ankles.
Speaker 1: And he says, hi, my name is Phil.
Speaker 1: Throughout my life, I had problems with my bowel movements happening at inopportune times and I've crap myself a lot.
Speaker 1: I'm sure most of you have stories as well.
Speaker 1: Do you have enough to fill a book?
Speaker 1: So sit back and relax.
Speaker 1: And I hope you have as much fun reading my tales of gastric woe as I've had making them.
Speaker 0: that line, that line at the end is what we had to buy.
Speaker 1: And basically in this book are in comic form, three or four tales of gastric woe.
Speaker 1: And my favorite one is, is the second one that doesn't actually involve diarrhea.
Speaker 1: The second one does not involve diarrhea.
Speaker 1: The second
Speaker 0: one is definitely the best one, but it is because many of you, it seems like this is more a, I guess, stereotypically guy thing, but many of you have been in this situation before I'm sure, or know someone who has been in the situation before or been in the situation of the second guy introduced in that comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: It is quite, I'm glad this is a dollar, a dollar.
Speaker 1: It was totally worth diarrhea diaries.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 1: Uh, let's see, Phil, let's see.
Speaker 1: Oh no.
Speaker 1: Uh, fill me.
Speaker 1: Army is the story.
Speaker 1: Uh, Aaron de la Rosa and Mark Griffin did the artwork.
Speaker 1: This is issue.
Speaker 1: One is going to be an issue to go, man.
Speaker 1: I'm in for that for a dollar.
Speaker 1: I'll buy that for a dollar.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So sun yen fi lock motherfuckers.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: I haven't even read this yet, so I can't endorse it, but the concept alone and also talking to God, to the guy was enough for me to buy it.
Speaker 0: Now, the thing is Scott actually pointed it out because he thought it was something else.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was sitting, I'm just looking around and I see from far away, some letters on a comic that's standing up and I thought it said, uh, killing the quarter master, killing the quarter master, which I kind of looks like from a distance.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, Ooh, killing the quarter master.
Speaker 0: I'm in walk this way, but no, it is killing tree quarterly by Keith McCleary.
Speaker 0: And it is a multicultural comic in the wild west with a Chinese assassin, a native American, a black dude, and a woman who's a former prostitute who go around killing people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's coming back in the wild west.
Speaker 1: Pretty much anyone, but white man was persecuted.
Speaker 1: So you got white woman, uh, native American, Chinese dude, and black guy.
Speaker 1: And you just make them bad-ass heroes going around, killing everyone.
Speaker 1: And I read this and it was pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: I didn't read it yet, but talking to the guy, sold it, sold me on it.
Speaker 1: The guy was a really good salesman.
Speaker 1: He was a really energetic, happy dude.
Speaker 1: He was, he's really good at pushing his comic.
Speaker 1: So we totally bought it.
Speaker 1: Hey, my name is Keith McCleary and I'm here at mocha.
Speaker 1: I'm doing it with a book called killing tree quarterly, which is a 50 page book about multicultural assassins working their way along the California coast in the late 1800s.
Speaker 1: And so it's a native American, a Chinese American, a retired hooker, and the son of a European and a black slave that are all working together.
Speaker 0: So is this your first big published work?
Speaker 0: Have you done anything before?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've been working on this for about a year and a half and it's the original.
Speaker 1: Originally it was just a writer and I did graphic design work and I didn't know what to do about doing art for a comic.
Speaker 1: And then a couple of years ago, I found out about a software called poser, which is 3d 3d software.
Speaker 1: And so I do the book, all the characters are built in 3d and then the book put together in Photoshop.
Speaker 0: So pen never touches the page.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So where did the inspiration for this kind of idea come from?
Speaker 0: Well, I was originally a film student and was trying to figure out how to do a first feature.
Speaker 1: And when you're trying to figure out how to do a first feature, it's got to be you and your friends and what you did yesterday.
Speaker 1: And I really wanted to do something multicultural and something that was not in the present.
Speaker 1: And when I thought about doing something multicultural, I didn't want it to be kind of like a fake rainbow kind of thing like Barney and friends.
Speaker 0: So what could I do?
Speaker 0: that was historical?
Speaker 1: And I thought of the old west.
Speaker 1: And so I did a lot of research.
Speaker 1: I have some friends in San Francisco, so I went around to the museums there because I knew that's where the story would start.
Speaker 1: And yeah, it kind of went from there.
Speaker 1: So originally, it was going to be self-published.
Speaker 0: And then I hooked up with Terminal Press, who are out of Long Island.
Speaker 1: And I was doing some work for them.
Speaker 1: And all of a sudden, they said, do you really want to self-publish?
Speaker 1: And I said, no.
Speaker 1: So I'm doing some more work for them this year that's going to be coming out of San Diego Con.
Speaker 0: So how's the reception so far?
Speaker 0: Do you think this is being-- I think it's cool.
Speaker 1: I feel that the books that I like are always-- nobody has told me about them.
Speaker 1: I go and I find them.
Speaker 1: And everybody that wanders over the table, it's like they didn't see anything else.
Speaker 1: They saw that book.
Speaker 1: And then they walk away really fast.
Speaker 0: So I think I'm honing into the kind of book that I would want to read, which is what you want to do when you're making stuff.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So what else did we find?
Speaker 1: So First Second is a company that publishes comics.
Speaker 1: They publish things like American Born Chinese.
Speaker 1: They publish Klezmer.
Speaker 1: They publish Laika.
Speaker 1: They publish a lot of good books.
Speaker 1: They sort of have this unique publishing format that they put out all their books in.
Speaker 1: And I really like it.
Speaker 1: So they publish Robot Dreams, which I own.
Speaker 1: So of course I went to their table.
Speaker 1: And what do they have there?
Speaker 1: But they had Prince of Persia.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, Prince of Persia?
Speaker 1: And I'm wondering, is this related to the video game?
Speaker 1: Because it doesn't look like the video game.
Speaker 1: Are they just making something called Prince of Persia?
Speaker 1: What's the deal?
Speaker 1: But it is indeed licensed from the video game.
Speaker 1: But it's not actually looking like the video game or directly related to the video game.
Speaker 1: It's basically like, hey, we'll license Prince of Persia and then make something that is not, you know, like just a direct port to comic form.
Speaker 1: We'll actually just take the concept of Prince of Persia and make a comic.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty good idea.
Speaker 1: And I've got this little preview book here.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That sort of samples the Prince of Persia.
Speaker 1: And I am buying the Prince of Persia.
Speaker 1: No questions asked.
Speaker 1: I can tell you that much.
Speaker 1: Everyone should buy the Prince of Persia comic when it is available.
Speaker 1: It would be well worth your money if you are liking princes or Persia.
Speaker 0: I'm a big fan of Persians.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But here, check it out.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Prince of Persia, a publishing event, one hundred thousand dollar marketing campaign, one hundred and twenty five thousand copy first printing national consumer media advertising.
Speaker 1: There's going to be a movie on June 16th.
Speaker 1: Oh, nine.
Speaker 1: Jerry Bruckheimer, directed by Mark Newell and distributed by Disney tie in marketing with the new video game in October 08, dedicated website and book trailer.
Speaker 1: They're pushing this thing pretty big.
Speaker 1: You will not be able to miss the Prince of Persia comic when it comes.
Speaker 1: And you don't want to either.
Speaker 1: So Prince of Persia for a second also is an excellent publisher.
Speaker 1: You could buy anything they print.
Speaker 1: Odds are it's going to be good.
Speaker 1: If nothing else, get American born Chinese and like and Klezmer.
Speaker 1: Those three.
Speaker 0: I'll warn you, I've only read one of these so far.
Speaker 0: I have to read the rest.
Speaker 0: But like I mean, I often say that something is a tear jerker, that it made me cry like it was that times like 50.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Klezmer, I think, is the best of those.
Speaker 1: But the other ones are no slouches.
Speaker 1: And you can't go wrong with first second publishing.
Speaker 1: And it's funny because it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: it's very good pun.
Speaker 1: The name of the publisher, it's like first second, right?
Speaker 1: F.I.R.
Speaker 1: S.T.
Speaker 1: space as S.E.C.O.N.D.
Speaker 1: And their logo is a colon followed by a zero and a one.
Speaker 1: So it's like the first second, but also first, second, third.
Speaker 1: It's like I like it.
Speaker 0: I see what you did there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I got to mention this at least briefly.
Speaker 0: But Hairville looks pretty damn good based on what I saw.
Speaker 0: I don't have it.
Speaker 0: I haven't read it, but I think it'll be good.
Speaker 1: My name's Barry Deutsch.
Speaker 1: I'm a cartoonist from Portland, Oregon.
Speaker 1: This is my comic, Hairville.
Speaker 1: I consider it one of the top three or four comics about 11 year old Orthodox Jewish girls you'll find at this entire show.
Speaker 1: The comic's about Mirka.
Speaker 1: She's a girl being raised in a very traditional Jewish community.
Speaker 1: But what she wants to do is fight dragons.
Speaker 1: And it's about the magical adventure she has.
Speaker 1: Hairville has been nominated for a Russ Manning Award this year for best comic book by a newcomer.
Speaker 1: And it's about 57 pages long.
Speaker 1: And you can view it at www.hairville.com.
Speaker 0: So is this your first major published work?
Speaker 0: Have you done anything before independent projects?
Speaker 1: Well, I've been a political cartoonist for many years, but this is my first comic book or my first one that's been gotten this far.
Speaker 1: And this is actually self-published for now.
Speaker 1: And it's available in two editions, the Basic Edition and the Way Over Price Edition.
Speaker 0: To read from something said about this by the Webcomics Examiner, the story is leisurely and steeped in cultural tradition.
Speaker 0: Even troll killing must wait until after Shabbat rituals.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I like the style of it.
Speaker 1: Wait, Shabbat?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm not Jewish.
Speaker 1: Shabbat.
Speaker 0: Well, when I think Shabbat, I think of the robot.
Speaker 1: The robot's name is a OK.
Speaker 1: It's supposed to be OK.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That that sounds pretty cool to me.
Speaker 1: Another thing is check this out.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Oni Press, which also publishes all awesome comics, including Scott Pilgrim, among others.
Speaker 1: OK, so the Oni Press, they published this book a while ago called Side Scrollers.
Speaker 1: And the problem was the timing of the release of this book.
Speaker 1: You see, it was at a point in time where I had recently purchased such comics as Aliens versus Cowboys and Pirates versus Ninjas and been disappointed in buying comics and also one called Random Encounter.
Speaker 1: And I was disappointed in the results of buying comics based on the title.
Speaker 1: So they came out with one called Side Scrollers.
Speaker 1: And I said, I am not following for this again.
Speaker 1: I was a fool because they came out with this other comic called Saltwater Taffy, The Seaside Adventures of Jack and Benny.
Speaker 1: And I preordered it and I had it in my hands.
Speaker 1: And when I went to Mocha, I was walking around and I saw it on a table.
Speaker 1: And behind that table was a man wearing a centipede T-shirt whose name was Matthew Lux.
Speaker 1: And he was the creator of the Saltwater Taffy and also the creator of the Side Scrollers comic.
Speaker 1: And I had not at the time I had not read the comic.
Speaker 1: So but we talked to him and he was really cool.
Speaker 1: And I got home and I read the Saltwater Taffy comic Seaside Adventures of Jack and Benny.
Speaker 1: And I must say, the lobster action is perfection.
Speaker 1: It is the awesomeness and the fun.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much two kids go on vacation to the beach and awesome happens with giant lobsters.
Speaker 1: I don't know how that isn't like a perfect sale of a comic.
Speaker 1: And plus for a man wearing a centipede T-shirt, how can you say no?
Speaker 2: Hey, this is Matthew Lux.
Speaker 2: I'm doing comics with Oni Press.
Speaker 2: I just had the book that just came out this month, Saltwater Taffy.
Speaker 2: It's an all ages book starring two kids, Jack and Benny, who are on vacation with their family in a small mysterious port town in Maine.
Speaker 2: And it's about all the different adventures that they get into involving sea monsters, ghosts, different ghost stories, and giant animals.
Speaker 2: And it's a lot of fun and it's going to be a series.
Speaker 2: The next one's coming out in September.
Speaker 0: All right, so how did you get into comics?
Speaker 0: Did you always want to be a comic artist?
Speaker 0: Did you just fall into it?
Speaker 2: I did until I went to school.
Speaker 0: Then I wanted to be an illustrator.
Speaker 2: And then when I graduated, I realized I think I want to do comics again.
Speaker 2: So I kind of had to reinvent my entire portfolio.
Speaker 2: And eventually I was able to land.
Speaker 2: I did a couple minis and I hooked up with Oni Press and I did my first book, F-Stop, which was written by Anthony Johnston of Wasteland fame.
Speaker 2: And after that, I was able to pitch my own stories with Oni.
Speaker 2: And they totally went for it.
Speaker 2: And we've done two books.
Speaker 2: My first book was Side Scrollers, which did pretty well.
Speaker 2: And it made the top 10 list of greatest graphic novels for teens for the YALSA American Library Association.
Speaker 0: So I can't help but notice the shirt.
Speaker 0: Now, our show, we're geek nights.
Speaker 0: We talk about very geeky things.
Speaker 2: Now, are you a geek?
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I definitely would admit that.
Speaker 0: So video games, anime, like what geekeries are yours?
Speaker 0: What are your non-drawing hobbies?
Speaker 2: I like to get into a little bit.
Speaker 2: I used to be a big video game fan, hence my centipede t-shirt.
Speaker 2: I haven't really been able to get into games quite as much because I'm a little too busy doing comics right now.
Speaker 2: But I do like to play the occasional game.
Speaker 2: I'm down a few systems, though.
Speaker 2: My only system I have right now is a PS2, so I'm a little behind.
Speaker 0: Speaking of a perfect sale, we ran into, we're walking around, and suddenly we see these boxes, little boxes, not big enough to be like what you would expect them to be, but they have the cover of Splatterhouse 3 on them.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, "All
Speaker 0: right.".
Speaker 0: So we walk up, and we're like, "What's in those boxes?
Speaker 0: Are they for
Speaker 0: sale?".
Speaker 0: And they say, "Yes, they're for
Speaker 0: sale.".
Speaker 0: And they open one up, and inside it, of all things, are cassette tapes.
Speaker 0: So we're like, "All right, you've shown us more information, yet you have elucidated
Speaker 0: nothing.".
Speaker 0: So they explained.
Speaker 0: So we couldn't help but notice the cassette tapes in the Splatterhouse 3 box.
Speaker 2: So I'm Connor Stechsjoldi.
Speaker 2: This is our band Witch Head.
Speaker 2: It's our new tape.
Speaker 2: It's called Melancholy and the Witchity Hatness.
Speaker 2: We're pretty interested in obsolete media, I guess.
Speaker 2: I think we're going to be putting out a VHS tape pretty soon.
Speaker 1: All right, so top shelf, right?
Speaker 1: They always have the bar in the giant room every year, right, to set up their little display.
Speaker 1: They actually have so much stuff now.
Speaker 1: They had to put Andy Runt and the Owly guy down at a separate table, because they couldn't fit him up there with everything else, because he's got the hats, and he's got the plushies and everything going on.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 1: But top shelf was handing out their seasonal sampler, which is pretty high quality.
Speaker 1: It's like this giant thing with a sample of pretty much all the top shelf goodies.
Speaker 1: And the cover of said seasonal sampler is drawn by someone you may be familiar with from Geek Night's episode pasts.
Speaker 1: You see, it is drawn by Mr.
Speaker 1: Jeff Lemire of the Essex County fame.
Speaker 0: See, I was going to bring him up, because we actually talked to him too.
Speaker 0: So it's a trilogy of books, and they're all set in the small town where I grew up in Canada.
Speaker 0: And it's sort
Speaker 2: of, while the setting, the town itself
Speaker 1: is a real place,
Speaker 3: and the characters and the stories are fictionalized.
Speaker 1: And I guess over the course of the three books, we sort of get to know one family in this town, and I think we go through four different generations of one family and kind of see reoccurring themes and relationships that affect later generations and so on.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a generation spanning family epic.
Speaker 0: So I guess, you personally are a hockey fan?
Speaker 1: I am indeed, yes.
Speaker 1: I'm a big hockey fan.
Speaker 1: I'm a fan of the Toronto Maple Leafs, which is where I live, who unfortunately are pretty terrible, but you know, I'll stick by them.
Speaker 1: And I grew up in near Windsor, which is across from Detroit.
Speaker 0: So there's always a battle between the Red Wings and the Maple Leafs for fans there.
Speaker 0: I'm actually from Detroit.
Speaker 0: Turns out, he's a hockey fan, if you couldn't have guessed.
Speaker 1: Oh, guess, no.
Speaker 1: So we talked to, we were basically sitting there looking, we're like, ah, the Essex County, there it is.
Speaker 1: And then Jeff Lemire, he's just like, yup, there it is.
Speaker 1: And we're like, oh, you're the guy that happens at MOCA.
Speaker 1: a lot is you'll.
Speaker 1: just because you realize at most comic conventions, right, you're buying comics from like a comic book store who set up.
Speaker 1: So when you're buying a comic, you're not buying it from the person who made it.
Speaker 1: You're buying from a guy who sells comics at the MOCA.
Speaker 0: Not only will you oftentimes hand your money to the author or the artist, but they will sign everything like as a matter of course.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's like, I'll just take something and give them money.
Speaker 1: And they'll be like, do you want me to sign that or something?
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh, if you want to, I guess, you know, sure.
Speaker 0: Go ahead.
Speaker 0: I really like being at this thing.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's like you just be looking at something and then, oh, you're Jeff Lemire.
Speaker 1: How do you do?
Speaker 1: How's Canada these days?
Speaker 1: No, but Jeff Lemire has all sorts of awesomeness going on.
Speaker 1: First of all, he had the third volume of Essex County.
Speaker 1: There was a preview of it sitting there.
Speaker 0: I'm really excited about it.
Speaker 1: Excited about that.
Speaker 1: He also had these two little mini comics that were like these tiny stories from Essex County.
Speaker 1: They're really good.
Speaker 1: Did you read them?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: The boxing one I liked the most.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Also greatly enjoyed the boxing one.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: Reading that little comic kind of made me want to box.
Speaker 1: And we could, boxing's all right.
Speaker 0: You know, you want to get into boxing?
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 1: Oh, come on.
Speaker 1: I like teeth.
Speaker 0: Let's box.
Speaker 0: You were the moth guard.
Speaker 0: That doesn't help.
Speaker 0: Yes, it does.
Speaker 0: You won't lose your teeth.
Speaker 1: People lose their teeth anyway.
Speaker 0: We wouldn't lose our teeth in the kind of boxing we would be doing.
Speaker 1: Why do hockey players have missing teeth?
Speaker 0: They were like, you know, there's a difference between a fist that's padded and a puck.
Speaker 1: Now you lose teeth anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah, Jeff Lemire, the awesome.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I'm running.
Speaker 1: I got a few, a little bits here, right?
Speaker 1: So a while back image comics put out this comic called parade with fireworks.
Speaker 1: And it was like this really, like it was this really realistic sort of story of mafia in, you know, Italy, you know, it was really kind of hardcore and awesome, but I only got the first issue and it was only a two issue thing.
Speaker 1: So I wasn't waiting for a trade.
Speaker 1: I was waiting for the second issue.
Speaker 1: And the second issue never showed up.
Speaker 1: I never saw it listed for pre-order.
Speaker 1: I might've missed it.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: But I never got it.
Speaker 1: I knew there were only two issues because the first one said one of two.
Speaker 1: And I was desperate for that too.
Speaker 1: Walking around the mocha.
Speaker 1: I saw that too, sitting on a table.
Speaker 1: And I said, give me that.
Speaker 1: I want that.
Speaker 1: And the guy who made it though, he wasn't there.
Speaker 1: He was there, but he wasn't there when I was there.
Speaker 1: So the guy who shared the table with him took the money for, and you know, I took the comic and it was everything I lived up to.
Speaker 1: So if you can find parade with fireworks, uh, oh, the guy's name is not in the front.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to open it now to find out, but parade with fireworks from the image shadow line is totally awesome and everyone should read it, but it's the only way you can get it is to get the two issues.
Speaker 1: So do whatever you can.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have to find a comic store to help you out or something.
Speaker 0: So one thing I ended up picking up and reading pretty quickly at all.
Speaker 0: This was something called Emiko superstar.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's from jinx, which is actually DC.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And, uh, I won.
Speaker 0: This is another thing where I kind of want to actually review it because I'll read it.
Speaker 0: It w it's by, uh, Mariko Tamaki with, uh, Steve Rolston.
Speaker 0: And all I want to say is that I read it and it's super, super good.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about pre-ordering it, right?
Speaker 1: Cause it's, uh, it was on the most recent, you know, pre-order.
Speaker 1: I think you still have time to pre-order it.
Speaker 1: actually, if you haven't pre-ordered yet, but I was sort of like, ah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Cause I was going based on the name, but at the con they were giving it away for free.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I don't know if what we got for free is the same thing that I would have bought.
Speaker 1: I think it is.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: They were, they, we went up and someone in our party was like, Hey, yeah, it's free.
Speaker 0: We walk over.
Speaker 0: They're like, no, it's not free, but it turned out it's not free because they ran out.
Speaker 0: And then she was so nice to just give it to us to read.
Speaker 1: All right, that's cool.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was super, super, super good.
Speaker 0: And I rather enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: I think it has a lot to say.
Speaker 1: It's the only two other things I got here.
Speaker 1: Right at first, this thing rim look, I'm so about that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: This is a book.
Speaker 1: we saw just the graphical style of the cover of this book totally sold us.
Speaker 1: It's called fragment and I'm it's by John Lang.
Speaker 1: And on the cover is like a dude with a hat cover in his face, like a little sort of fedora hat and like a giant coat.
Speaker 1: And he's obviously some sort of spy dude.
Speaker 0: We actually did interview the guy.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to play it because it was pretty much, Hey, so what do you make a comic about spies?
Speaker 0: And he's like, yeah, I like that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He didn't really say much, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel like we almost pressured him into doing it.
Speaker 0: Cause we're like, Hey, you want to interview?
Speaker 0: He's like, ah, okay.
Speaker 1: Actually the universe that this world takes place in is actually super interesting.
Speaker 1: It's like, you've, there's like technology, but the people can't get their hands on it.
Speaker 1: So there's like people who are forging for technology and it's pretty cool stuff.
Speaker 1: I would definitely like some sort of role playing game in the fragment world.
Speaker 1: The only other book I got here is the claws come out by Pat Lewis.
Speaker 1: It is astounding tales of broads and monsters.
Speaker 0: Hey, this is Pat Lewis.
Speaker 1: Uh, my book is the claws come out from IDW.
Speaker 1: It is astounding tales of broads and monsters, women and monsters, my two favorite things to draw and to write about.
Speaker 0: So you can get the book in bookstores, Amazon, uh, from my website, lunch break, comics.com.
Speaker 1: It's astounding tales of broads and monsters.
Speaker 1: I opened it up and I, I, and I was flipping through it and I decided to buy it when I saw a picture of a chained up velociraptor indoors with a girl next to it with her hand on its shoulder, I guess.
Speaker 1: And she says, let's go for a ride junior.
Speaker 1: If you like broads and monsters, you like broads.
Speaker 1: And it's a very sort of like slick sort of cartoony style.
Speaker 1: It's sort of, it's not quite penny arcade ish, but it's, it's similar in a way.
Speaker 1: Uh, I'm definitely all about this comic.
Speaker 1: Haven't read it yet, but I will read it very, very soon.
Speaker 1: Uh, and I can tell it's going to be awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh, let me read the inside of the cover.
Speaker 1: Uh, a teenage girl runs into some unexpected visitors walking home after a date.
Speaker 1: An apathetic scientist works late defrosting the abominable snowman.
Speaker 1: A naive blood donor dates a rageaholic vampire, a downer like fortune teller inadvertently sparks a zombie epidemic.
Speaker 1: And it's all played for laughs.
Speaker 0: Also of all the business cards, because you know, these sorts of things, because we go around kind of half as press half as fans.
Speaker 0: I ended up with a lot of business cards and I usually look at them like a month later, forget who was wanting throw them all away.
Speaker 0: I think of all the business cards I have sprawled out across my desk right now.
Speaker 0: Pat Lewis has the best one.
Speaker 0: It's a picture of a, of a businessman lighting his cigar with money.
Speaker 0: And it's just, the style is so perfect.
Speaker 1: I don't know the John Lang, the, his business card is pretty freaking cool.
Speaker 1: Like this girl, this tennis playing girl, he's got on it pretty hot, pretty hot.
Speaker 0: Actually, I've got both of them in front of me.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And he's got like a James bond on the other side, but I guess the last little bit, uh, I swung by the wonder Mark people who were wonderful.
Speaker 1: I bought the wonder Mark guy.
Speaker 1: What's his name?
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: I keep forgetting.
Speaker 0: I read wonder Mark.
Speaker 0: However, I found out about wonder Mark at a previous mocha.
Speaker 1: Oh, Dave Malkey.
Speaker 0: That's it for the longest time.
Speaker 0: I, before I actually went to the comic, I just assumed the comic was called poop jokes in top hats.
Speaker 0: No, it's like the comic is, it is poop jokes in top hats, but it is called wonder Mark.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I first mocha, we were, we passed by him and we took his little poop jokes and top hats flyer, but I didn't actually start reading it till very, quite a time later.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: But, uh, he had stop signs.
Speaker 0: They're just normal stop signs made of metal, but they say poop instead of stop.
Speaker 0: So of course I bought one.
Speaker 0: And of course it is at face level in front of the toilet in the downstairs bathroom.
Speaker 1: You've got to be able to get that off the wall.
Speaker 0: If we move out, we can get it off the walls.
Speaker 0: It's two way tape.
Speaker 1: It's all you.
Speaker 0: It's not the no big deal.
Speaker 0: All I got to say is you got to stop it.
Speaker 0: You got to poop when that sign is there.
Speaker 0: And I, and I tried the sign out right when I got home and it worked.
Speaker 1: Did you stop pooping?
Speaker 0: I stopped.
Speaker 0: And then I pooped.
Speaker 0: You see if head, if the sign worked, if there's different ways it could work, if it caused you to stop pooping, then anyone who sees it, it's kind of like an eternal curse.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, if it causes you to stop and then poop, uh, putting it in the bathroom is really the only safe place to put it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you might be in the next diarrhea.
Speaker 1: comics is obviously designed to be put in bathrooms.
Speaker 0: I mean, come on.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel like I would like to have that sign just on my front door.
Speaker 0: No, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Of course you could turn it upside down.
Speaker 0: Now it says dude.
Speaker 0: No, it does.
Speaker 1: It smells dude incorrectly.
Speaker 0: It spells it in leets.
Speaker 0: It the last mocha.
Speaker 0: I bought what, what is what now?
Speaker 0: One of my favorite t-shirts, which is a wizard has turned you into a whale.
Speaker 0: Is this awesome?
Speaker 1: Oh, I bought a t-shirt too.
Speaker 0: I bought pretty much the exact same t-shirt, but instead it shows a picture of a boat and in classic text adventure style, it just says, take boat.
Speaker 0: It's a giant boat, but I got to tell you, I don't know what it is about these shirts, but they fit my style so well.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I bought a shirt.
Speaker 1: There's a green shirt and a, it was associated with a web comic.
Speaker 1: I think it was a dumb umbrella web comic, but I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: Um, and the reason I bought the shirt is not because of any relation to the web comic, but because the shirt on its own merits and had a picture of a trilobite, a cartoony, cute trilobite, which, you know, I love them.
Speaker 1: Trilobites wearing a graduation cap and it said old school is my new favorite shirt.
Speaker 0: I can't believe you didn't buy the teen boat shirt.
Speaker 0: I didn't buy the team boat shirt.
Speaker 1: I could have bought the team, but I'm waiting for a team boat trade.
Speaker 1: Come on comics, bakery, team boat trade.
Speaker 0: But, uh, one last thing.
Speaker 0: Uh, I remember last time we talked about how Indy Stinner had their awesome party.
Speaker 1: We went to it last year.
Speaker 0: They had it this year and I'm holding the kind of ticket slash invitation in front of me, but it's cool because one, they were there and those guys are awesome, but the party was later than it was last year.
Speaker 0: And we know we had enough and you go to a bunch of other people with us.
Speaker 0: So we didn't really want to stay in the city super late.
Speaker 0: And this year the Indy spinner rack party started at 9 PM.
Speaker 1: Oh, too late.
Speaker 0: So, but the cool thing is the guy walks up to me, he's like, yeah, I don't see Scott around.
Speaker 0: Uh, you guys probably aren't going to come because it's so late and I know you have to take your train, but, uh, just in case you go.
Speaker 0: And I was like, yeah, we're probably not going to make it, but, uh, we really want to be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Which guy was it?
Speaker 1: Do you remember?
Speaker 0: I don't re I don't remember any of their names.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to sit here and be like, well, it was the guy with the face like this, wearing the shirt like this, who talks like this, as opposed to the guy with the face like this and the hair like this.
Speaker 0: I just wish it because I was looking for some of those guys around the time like all the Indy spinner at guys who were there when you weren't around.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And they all like scattered when you appeared.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, I didn't, uh, I missed him.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: What else is going down?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We, I feel like we should end.
Speaker 0: This was kind of a rambling review of Mocha.
Speaker 1: That's how Mocha is.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a rambling place.
Speaker 1: You got all these different things.
Speaker 0: I got one more thing.
Speaker 0: I got to review the cookies you can buy and the snack area of Mocha are really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're all right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The thing with Mocha is it really is, you know, going to Mocha feels sort of like this episode feels.
Speaker 1: There's all these different little things vying for your attention.
Speaker 1: You're not there for very long, but there's all this awesome concentrated.
Speaker 0: It's just like awesome, a different, awesome, a different, awesome, a different, very different to decide to walk table by table through anywhere just because the way the crowd is, you'll pretty much wander around and things will catch your eye.
Speaker 0: And kind of like in Mike Dawson's Freddy and me, you'll, your memory of Mocha will be this haze with these bright spots kind of interspersed throughout.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And Mocha is totally awesome.
Speaker 1: It's fun to go every year.
Speaker 1: It was just as fun this year.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think it was the best one yet.
Speaker 1: I'll be going back next year for sure.
Speaker 0: Almost definitely.
Speaker 1: A hundred percent buying more awesome comics.
Speaker 1: And, uh, maybe we helped you find out about some not so mainstream comics that actually might be hard for you to get.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 0: And I guess we'll end it on the interviews that I grabbed that were worth listening to that I didn't bother thinking of a better place to put.
Speaker 0: So here they all are.
Speaker 0: So we're here with Hillary Tisman from Pantheon graphic novels.
Speaker 0: And we're really excited about My Brain is Hanging Upside Down by David Heatley, which is this kind of graphic memoir all about everything you wanted to know about him and even some stuff you might not have, but it's still totally quirky and really interesting.
Speaker 0: And Bat manga, which is the secret history of Batman in Japan, complete with toys.
Speaker 0: So both out in October, check them out.
Speaker 0: So you're at the Mocha Festival here.
Speaker 0: How are things going?
Speaker 0: What's the vibe of the crowd?
Speaker 0: How is it?
Speaker 0: You know, they all seem really excited.
Speaker 1: They keep telling us they already own our books, which I guess is a good thing, but, you know, we want them to buy a little more.
Speaker 1: So, so far, so good.
Speaker 1: No complaints.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm doing a book for DC Vertigo that I think is going to be released in spring of '09.
Speaker 1: Bob Shrek's my editor and it's called The Nobody.
Speaker 0: And it's sort of a loose play on the invisible man character from the H.G.
Speaker 1: Wells novel, but I kind of have him sort of hiding out in one of my little rural communities and interacting with townsfolk.
Speaker 3: So that's kind of what it's about.
Speaker 3: All right.
Speaker 3: My name's Tom Motley.
Speaker 3: I do cartoon and illustration.
Speaker 3: My book here today is called Twilight of the Bums.
Speaker 3: It's written by Raymond Fetterman and George Chambers, who are a couple of avant-garde novelists who emerged in the sixties.
Speaker 3: And they did this jam story of microfictions about two old bums, which stand for the two of them.
Speaker 3: They share a shadow in common.
Speaker 3: I drew some illustrations in the margins and the shadow represents me, the silent voice and the thing.
Speaker 3: So there's cartoons in the margins of every page, and it's a very nice book from Start Your Own Books.
Speaker 3: I hope you'll all check it out, www.startyourown.com.
Speaker 3: My other book is the new issue of my series, True Fiction.
Speaker 3: I've got True Fiction number seven, subtitled Ink Mathematics, and it has a lot of my experimental work over the years.
Speaker 3: I work with the group UBAPO America and other related experiments.
Speaker 3: It's all structural, formula stuff, but don't be put off by it.
Speaker 3: It's funny.
Speaker 3: It's all whimsical and silly, and I hope someone will check it out.
Speaker 3: My website is teamotley.com, and you can probably track it down that way.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Raymond Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution non-commercial share-alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.