Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Thursday, April 3rd.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and now for something completely different Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I've discovered the secret of the train the secret of space the secret of the train.
Speaker 0: you see Looking at you know.
Speaker 0: There's a problem taking commuter trains into New York City and that there are other people on these trains.
Speaker 0: and There is an interesting social problem where different people have different degrees of comfort With other people and as a result a lot of times people.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like in a urinal in a men's bathroom.
Speaker 0: people do Everything they can to not have to sit next to another human being.
Speaker 0: They'll like sit apart from each other.
Speaker 0: Like if you if you don't a stop-motion or just like you watch as time went on train cars fill up Pretty much every single seat will have one person in it before a single person sets next to sits next to anyone else
Speaker 1: unless they're People were together to begin with.
Speaker 1: like, you know Like someone gets on the train with their wife they'll sit next to each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but on the morning commute, that's pretty rare.
Speaker 0: I mean, I did that back when we rode our bikes to the train station every morning together.
Speaker 0: But now that I take the 530 train, I don't think that's happening anymore.
Speaker 1: No, not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: But Today this morning.
Speaker 0: I was thinking cuz next week at my job I'm actually giving a two-hour lecture on game theory and one of the like.
Speaker 0: the moral of my lecture is that Game theory can be applied to real life intuitively And you don't need to know the math so much as need to be able to intuit the you know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I was thinking about alright Here's the situation.
Speaker 0: I'm getting on the train getting a good seat because I the one fear that has Come to pass many times in my life since I started working in the city is that dude sits next to me?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's always bad.
Speaker 1: or get on the train like at the last second.
Speaker 1: All the seats are filled with people.
Speaker 0: or Someone sits next to me is really smelly or someone sits next to me with a wide leg spread.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I mean otherwise, I'll generally just sit right next to people.
Speaker 0: So I thought alright, let's look at this logically.
Speaker 0: How can I like what's my utility?
Speaker 0: My utility is the most space for me without anyone else mucking it up.
Speaker 1: That's what everyone else is thinking.
Speaker 1: Also, that's why they don't sit with anyone.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: But then I thought how can I maximize that and I tried something that I've never really seen anyone else do at least Not often, so there's two-seaters and three-seaters a lot of people.
Speaker 0: their strategy is they'll sit in the aisle of a two-seater Hoping that no one will have the courage to ask them to stand up so they can sit in the seat by the window.
Speaker 1: No No See a two-seater or a three-seater is probably gonna end up with two people.
Speaker 1: no matter what.
Speaker 1: the three-seater is a safer bet Because you know someone will.
Speaker 1: you'll sit on the way the window seat.
Speaker 1: someone will take the aisle in the middle.
Speaker 1: 99 out of 10 times will never get filled.
Speaker 0: Yep Now there's nice social engineering where what they did on a lot of the trains it didn't work.
Speaker 0: So well is the two seats next to each other in the three-seater have a headrest But the seat on the end doesn't hoping that people would kind of slide over.
Speaker 0: people don't slide over But I did the other day.
Speaker 0: They would rather go without a headrest than I did the other day and someone got so uncomfortable They got up and walked away and left me with a three-seater by myself.
Speaker 0: this was kind of the inspiration because I was looking and I wanted a headrest cuz I had my pillow I was gonna take a nap and I see that there's a whole bunch of three-seaters with one person in.
Speaker 0: I'm sitting by the window.
Speaker 0: So I just sat right next to one of those people.
Speaker 0: So I also got a headrest and the guy Sat there for a minute and then he's like, excuse me, and he got up and he went to another seat.
Speaker 0: All right, so I realized something and this morning I got in the middle of a three-seater.
Speaker 0: I sat in the middle of a three-seater and No, one guy was like, excuse me.
Speaker 0: Can I sit there?
Speaker 0: And I was like, yeah sure, but I didn't slide over.
Speaker 0: And then he kept standing there.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh do you want the window instead?
Speaker 0: And then he like he didn't know what to do and he walked away and sat next to some lady and the lady gave me An evil look because I don't think she wanted anyone sitting next to her.
Speaker 0: But then on the way home, I tried the same thing and it worked again.
Speaker 0: the same thing happened Really?
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone will sit next to you if you sit in the middle of a three-seater unless the train is crazy crowded.
Speaker 1: See that's not a bad strategy, especially if it works.
Speaker 1: however, I have found one better strategy.
Speaker 1: That is the the ultimate strategy.
Speaker 0: Well, the ultimate strategy is to be really smelly No, no, no.
Speaker 0: or to sit in the end of a four-seater facing the right way exactly.
Speaker 1: You sit in a four-seater where the two seats are facing each other.
Speaker 1: It's a two two-seaters facing each other and you just sit in one of them and you get all this leg room and as long As no one sits directly in front of you You're just fine.
Speaker 0: a lot of times someone will sit directly in front of it can happen and then you're screwed.
Speaker 0: cuz then It's the worst.
Speaker 0: your knees You're basically between all the guys legs and that other guy has a knee between your legs.
Speaker 1: going for the four-seater is the ultimate Gamble because you could either end up in the best possible comfort infinite legroom or in the worst possible comfort.
Speaker 0: So I think of course some trains have the three-seaters that face each other.
Speaker 1: That's like in a couple cars, I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 0: It's like randomly in the middle of the nice cars We don't get because the third rail doesn't go all the way up here.
Speaker 0: all have that.
Speaker 0: I know those cut.
Speaker 0: those are like luxury cars.
Speaker 0: I almost I almost miss working in Yonkers just because I could take that luxury train.
Speaker 1: I know it's not fair.
Speaker 1: Well, you couldn't take it the whole way, but you can think of some of the way I could take it a little under half.
Speaker 1: We can just move to Croton Harvin and take the luxury train.
Speaker 1: I don't know less money.
Speaker 0: So I have to go look at the rest of Croton Harvin because I've spent There have been many times where I was stuck in Croton Harvin with a lot of time to kill just because I've seen a pro.
Speaker 1: In Harman is a road a big parking lot a big train Train repair facility.
Speaker 1: there is nothing and some houses.
Speaker 0: There is not a single Place of business that is not shady and scuzzy.
Speaker 0: looking within walking distance of that train station I've looked.
Speaker 0: I walked many many moons.
Speaker 1: many Imagine if we did live within driving distance of that train station that we would Be a significant further distance from the train station than we are from our trains.
Speaker 0: Yes, I would rather have a slightly longer commute where I spend the entirety of it asleep or watching Avatar.
Speaker 0: Mmm, it's like I could drive to Croton Harman and then get on a train and it is faster.
Speaker 0: I've looked like it would be faster.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wonder how is it to drive to Croton Harman?
Speaker 0: It's I used to drive past Croton Harman every day when I drove to Yonkers.
Speaker 0: Wow, okay You know what driving there is really fast.
Speaker 0: In fact, you could be in Yonkers in an hour Not even an hour a lot less than an hour if you sped, you know the shortcuts there.
Speaker 0: There's no like traffic accident or anything.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I've learned the secret of the train and all it took was actually thinking.
Speaker 0: All right What's the best way with my limited options?
Speaker 0: There's only like 10 different places I can sit maybe 11 if I count sitting in the vestibule or a bathroom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the bathroom.
Speaker 0: That's the.
Speaker 0: if you don't have a sense of smell.
Speaker 0: That's your luxury box right there.
Speaker 1: Okay You have a news.
Speaker 0: I don't know you can go first.
Speaker 1: All right, I didn't?
Speaker 1: I couldn't find any decent news on the internet, right?
Speaker 1: So I found this sort of.
Speaker 1: It's a news but it's a local news for someone far away from us or at least I think they're far away from us.
Speaker 0: All news is local news for someone right?
Speaker 1: Well, you know, it could be world news or international.
Speaker 0: No one else lives in the world.
Speaker 1: Local means like small-time news.
Speaker 1: It's not a big story.
Speaker 0: Oh, so there's no local news in New York City.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's plenty I mean, but it doesn't happen to be the news that I found if I was sitting next to JFK.
Speaker 0: it affects me directly.
Speaker 0: It's local news for this.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the website I found this on is Chris online.
Speaker 1: It's it's a website that is just Brian Chris's blog.
Speaker 1: I hope I'm pronouncing his last name, right?
Speaker 1: Doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: The subtitle on the on his blog is when there's nothing else on the internet.
Speaker 1: There was nothing else on the internet.
Speaker 1: so I went to Chris online and here we go.
Speaker 1: He put made a blog post called how to catch a Netflix thief Basically crackhead.
Speaker 1: he has Netflix like we do and He kept getting them lost in the mail and he kept telling Netflix that they were lost in the mail.
Speaker 1: and Netflix is cool With that right, but he's like hi.
Speaker 1: I wonder if these are lost in the mail.
Speaker 1: I will set up a camera on my macbook to look at my mailbox.
Speaker 0: That's brilliant.
Speaker 1: It's not brilliant.
Speaker 0: It's obvious Yes, but it's brilliant cuz he actually did it.
Speaker 0: he did it.
Speaker 0: No, no matter how cool your idea is if you don't do it.
Speaker 0: It's not brilliant cuz he didn't do it exactly.
Speaker 1: So he set it up digital camcorder macbook squirrels.
Speaker 0: No, is it squirrels stealing his DVDs?
Speaker 0: No crackheads.
Speaker 1: No, it was the fat kid who lives in the nearby apartment.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what'd he do?
Speaker 1: He just came and sold his Netflixes.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, what did the guy do with his knowledge?
Speaker 1: Well first he called Netflix and he was like listen this fat kid and you get this pictures of the fat kid right here.
Speaker 1: God, is he a fat kid?
Speaker 1: That's disgusting This picture.
Speaker 1: and he's just like.
Speaker 1: yes, some kid was stealing my Netflixes.
Speaker 1: They're like, oh, okay Just you know, we just you know, call the police and we won't charge you or anything.
Speaker 1: You know that Netflix is cool.
Speaker 1: They didn't bother him about it.
Speaker 0: All right, that's step one.
Speaker 0: I'm curious if he is going through with the fullness that I would go through with that's.
Speaker 1: they call the police Right and the police came and I guess he talked to like a detective and they investigated or whatever.
Speaker 1: But you know, this is the reason I'm making this news is because I've always been curious.
Speaker 1: Tampering with the mail is a federal offense is well known well known and I wondered like it's.
Speaker 1: it is a federal offense But what?
Speaker 1: how bad is it?
Speaker 1: If you if you're caught, you know what it's.
Speaker 0: what about tampering with the mail?
Speaker 0: No, but what goes down, you know, I've always been kind of curious Always threatened me with that when we'd be at RIT be like I'll tamper with your mail.
Speaker 1: No, I used to say if you tamper with my mail, it's a federal pen one of the other.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, his site just broke from a database error.
Speaker 0: Oh, all right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, what happened?
Speaker 1: in the middle of reading my news?
Speaker 1: the website wrote?
Speaker 0: Well, do you know what happened?
Speaker 1: Yes I know what happened.
Speaker 1: Okay, basically uh The the local police are like, uh-huh.
Speaker 1: They did their investigation whatever and then they said, you know We're gonna had to pass this up because it is a federal offense.
Speaker 1: and indeed they did pass it up to a higher authority.
Speaker 1: and Then the guy received notice that the case went to trial and the trial was over.
Speaker 1: and they find the kid $750 I guess or his mom that's it whoever and They put him in some sort of like first offenders program, which is a like rehab for first offending kids.
Speaker 0: That's good That's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like huh?
Speaker 1: So but if it really is a federal offense and that the feds really will come and get you.
Speaker 1: well Yes as well they should they should but it's he was kind of interesting to actually see someone get in I guess arrested and then convicted of male Offending for stealing some dudes.
Speaker 1: Netflix's.
Speaker 0: damn you fat kid.
Speaker 1: It was a really schlubby looking fat kid.
Speaker 1: You see the pictures if the website ever comes back.
Speaker 0: I was trying to look but I don't know if I want to see it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just a schlubby fat kid.
Speaker 1: He's wearing just like shorts and nothing else and he's got this like little like crap fro and it's not a pleasant sight.
Speaker 1: it's a lot like You know Lord Gloom, but stealing a Netflix.
Speaker 0: Netflix is practically free.
Speaker 0: I know I know Even though I was listening to a certain unnamed podcast recently And I just want to point out that a lot of people don't seem to realize that Netflix on demand lets you watch as much As you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you could leave it streaming 24/7 seven days a week.
Speaker 0: They don't care at all.
Speaker 1: Yep, see I figured out Netflix's plan with the Netflix on demand.
Speaker 0: I figured it out too.
Speaker 1: What do you think their plan is?
Speaker 0: Well, I've noticed one thing because they have a lot of stuff in the Netflix on demand, but they don't have Enough because if you search for a movie it will not be in there like no matter what.
Speaker 0: if you search for a movie It's not gonna be in the on demand.
Speaker 0: but if you browse through the on demand you'll see a whole bunch of movies that you wouldn't mind watching right now and There's just enough there to keep me from going to Blockbuster ever again.
Speaker 1: Well, that's could be part of their plan, but my thinking is right The more you watch in the on demand the less the less.
Speaker 1: the less frequently You're gonna be sending your DVDs back and you're gonna be a less likely to pick those movies as DVDs.
Speaker 1: So they can buy less of those movies.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're expensive movies.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're movies.
Speaker 1: They're trying to.
Speaker 0: I think it's a confluence of all these factors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a it.
Speaker 1: people wonder like how is Netflix making money on this?
Speaker 1: Well, if you drop your Netflix subscription, you're gonna lose that.
Speaker 1: so if it hooks you in you're still gonna keep your subscription.
Speaker 1: You know, even if you don't you might reduce your discs, but you'll never leave because you let your hooked on the on demand.
Speaker 0: yeah, the old the only problem I've ever had with Netflix is that Two avatar DVDs in a row were too scratched to play you damn kids stop scratching your DVDs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, stop stealing them out my mailbox.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 0: There's no fat kid here.
Speaker 0: No, no, there's no fat kid anywhere near our house.
Speaker 0: All right, go go.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah news.
Speaker 1: Eh, yeah news That it the websites back.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, it's not.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe it is.
Speaker 0: All right, there's a whole bunch of news And there's a lot I want to talk about but at the same time all the political stuff.
Speaker 0: I know Scott doesn't care about it.
Speaker 0: So bringing it up really wouldn't really be interesting unless you wanted to hear me groan Guess what?
Speaker 1: I'll let you hear me groan.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I Mean I could talk about how as I said last week I'm Reasonably certain I give it a 95% chance that Barack Obama is going to be the nominee and that there's no way Hillary can come back.
Speaker 0: But Scott doesn't want me to talk about that.
Speaker 1: I can also say you said it already.
Speaker 0: I could also talk about saying the same thing for we interesting leaked White House men Memo, I almost said menu.
Speaker 0: That would be a little bit frightening.
Speaker 1: The menu is probably really great.
Speaker 1: there here They have like, you know babies on it and it's guaranteed not poison Wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's kind of like if you're the Emperor you've got that guy who tastes your food.
Speaker 1: You mean you?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: That doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 0: I'm not I am NOT an emperor nor am I an Emperor's food taster.
Speaker 1: The Emperor is his own food taste.
Speaker 1: I mean someone else might taste it first, but if he doesn't taste his food What?
Speaker 1: what's?
Speaker 1: the point is like someone remove his tongue?
Speaker 1: I?
Speaker 0: Farted as soon as he stopped talking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was fun.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: if he couldn't tell I like to talk.
Speaker 1: Let's try to keep this not like last Thursday, which is it's.
Speaker 0: I'd like to talk a little bit about not so much this news I'm not even gonna talk about the article or any of that.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about the topic a tiny bit because it it illustrates why I am NOT afraid of terrorism and why I think pretty much everyone in America who is afraid of terrorism in America is I don't want to say something so crude as being a goddamn liberal pussy.
Speaker 0: That's doofus.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to say goddamn liberal pussy.
Speaker 0: I don't like to use the word pussy I think doofus and I don't like to use the word liberal in that sense.
Speaker 1: And if you don't use a doofus we can use the word wuss.
Speaker 0: wuss works.
Speaker 0: doofus doesn't really fit but I'll put it this way Doofus.
Speaker 0: the title of the slash dot link here is engineers make good terrorists
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: I've seen a number of articles that broach this subject in the past talking about how if you want to analyze like the Thinking it would take to be an effective terrorist There's no one better to commit acts of terror than an engineer.
Speaker 0: And in fact a lot of terrorists that have been discovered or studied in history have had engineering backgrounds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I mean this is purely anecdotal here But you know, I'm among engineers and engineer type thinking people.
Speaker 0: I've seen a lot of people blow a lot of stuff up because they were bored.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and whenever there are You know real terrorists and ever a real terrorist attack happens, right?
Speaker 1: It's always the engineer type thinking people saying, you know, why did they do that?
Speaker 1: they would have succeeded if they only did this.
Speaker 1: and in fact I find that people who have an engineer type way of thinking are often less afraid of Because we look at the world and we say wow if you did this It would be so easy to cause a ludicrous amount of damage, you know, and no one's done it there.
Speaker 0: That is the point.
Speaker 0: I was going to make.
Speaker 1: the other thing is I think that while Engineer type thinking people like can come up with ways to you know Do really effective terrorist attacks and such I don't think they're any more likely to want to do terrorist attacks than anyone else.
Speaker 0: Well that that was the kind of the point I was gonna make is that you know, they talk they talk about this and I've noticed cuz I. a good example of this was when we were in high school because the Columbine Incident happened while Scott and I were in high school and I remember for the next week or so Pretty much there were two good tours.
Speaker 0: well there were three kinds of people in the schools.
Speaker 0: one kind were the people who were afraid after this and really freaked out and Like they were nervous and weird about it for the rest of high school.
Speaker 0: And then there were the group of people and I was among them who would kind of seriously debate How absolutely ineffective the attack was and couldn't imagine why if they were going to do something like that They did it.
Speaker 0: So quote unquote shoddily and it's not like we were planning on column binding.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it wasn't like, you know, they should have killed more people or killing people was good It was.
Speaker 1: if their goal was to kill people they did a really bad job and it's like you analyze the job They did even though you completely disagree with their goals and intents and and such, you know You can't.
Speaker 1: it's like if you see.
Speaker 1: it's sort of like, you know.
Speaker 0: And I got Bugs Bunny cartoon when like I was gonna use the example of a fat man trying to eat something.
Speaker 1: But go the Bugs Bunny cartoon where the gremlin is hitting the front of the bomb with the hammer Right and Bugs Bunny is like, you know, oh you're doing that all wrong.
Speaker 1: No, here's the right way to do it.
Speaker 1: and he hits it real hard, you know And it blows up.
Speaker 1: and it's like Bugs Bunny doesn't want the bomb to blow up.
Speaker 1: He's not looking out to kill people but he sees someone doing a bad job of something and he's like you're doing a bad job.
Speaker 1: This is how to do it better.
Speaker 0: as a brief aside.
Speaker 0: I would like to point out that Bugs Bunny was an Absolute asshole.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah that opera singer didn't deserve that at all.
Speaker 0: But anyway so I People who are afraid of terrorism and Scott brought this up very briefly, but I point out that how there have been very few Terrorist attacks in young US soil very few ever.
Speaker 0: you're more likely to die every day going to work Then you are to be killed for the driving is like a 10,000 times more dangerous than terrorists now Being.
Speaker 0: I mean we don't want to get the police on us.
Speaker 0: But consider this smart people can look around the world and it would be trivial To conduct some sort of act of terrorism some horrible act.
Speaker 0: There's so many opportunities in ways that Anyone smart or with a quote-unquote engineering background could trivially pull these things off.
Speaker 0: But despite it being so easy It doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: and that leads me to believe that either one.
Speaker 0: all the people who want to be terrorists are Independent of that stupid which is a lot of them are like look at that like look it's a lot of examples.
Speaker 1: There's a guy.
Speaker 1: actually recently he was caught.
Speaker 1: I don't know what he's trying to do But they just caught him cuz he's a moron.
Speaker 0: Oh, he had a. basically he had a bag full of pipe bomb making material.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, right and he said that's the guy he recently just had a bag full of pipe bomb making material got in a plane.
Speaker 1: So the security we have you know and Bruce Schneier the security expert of the universe will confirm is the security We have largely only catches idiots and mostly confuses normal people who mean no harm.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing because there's two parts of this here.
Speaker 0: one This is the thing that bothers me the most because people out there are afraid the shoe bomber was effective.
Speaker 0: He was an incredibly effective terrorist.
Speaker 0: The shoe bomber was one of the most effective terrorists in American history.
Speaker 0: all he had to do was try to light his shoes on fire and now I a Normal human being have to take my goddamn shoes off every time I get out of plane.
Speaker 0: Yep What kind of crap is that?
Speaker 0: He won?
Speaker 1: But you know his plan failed.
Speaker 1: if he was had it He was smarter and had an engineer way of thinking and still maintained his evil desires to blow shit up.
Speaker 1: Well, then then he probably would have had a you know a better plan and would have succeeded in.
Speaker 0: actually There's a correlation between being smart and not wanting to kill people.
Speaker 1: I think there there definitely is.
Speaker 0: but I think there's another possibility Because there are a lot of people who are very intelligent who are also on the wrong side of the whole terrorism thing I mean the 9/11 attacks for what it's worth were pulled off by very smart people who put together a very well staged Horrible thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Unabomber wasn't that dumb and he was dumb, but he wasn't you know But he was smart away with it for a long time.
Speaker 0: He was dumb for what he was doing, but he was smart in how he was going about it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but Maybe all this despite what a lot of people in the government and a lot of people in general would like you to believe Maybe there isn't this vast gigantic terrorist conspiracy to take down the United States.
Speaker 0: maybe Al-qaeda and all these things were just Semi unrelated strings of I don't want to get into you know second-order simulacra blah blah blah blah blah social blah.
Speaker 0: but Maybe it's all just kind of a sham and bad things happen.
Speaker 0: But it's not like there's this organized worldwide terrorist conspiracy to fuck us All.
Speaker 1: if there was a worldwide terrorist conspiracy to fuck us it would have already fucked us.
Speaker 1: We would have been you know, it did fuck us But it fucked us 20 times worse and the fact that it hasn't happened.
Speaker 0: I Really can't be cool with someone who is still afraid of terrorists in this day and age because that makes them win and I hate To use the phrase the terrorists have won.
Speaker 0: but as long as people out there are afraid then yes, they kind of have Yep, they're terrorists.
Speaker 1: their goal to make you afraid.
Speaker 1: Are you afraid?
Speaker 1: Yes, that's not good.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: my thing today is so hot.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Rogers plus breakdancing That's all I really have to say about that other than that.
Speaker 1: Is it as good as mr.
Speaker 1: Rogers plus the Donkey Kong machine?
Speaker 0: It's yeah, it's better.
Speaker 0: I think Cuz he tries some moves he tries to move he's okay.
Speaker 0: He's okay.
Speaker 0: He's not great.
Speaker 1: But uh, it's been you.
Speaker 0: You've never seen me breakdance.
Speaker 0: hence I'll say move you have zero moves.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Rogers win.
Speaker 0: I'll say this I'll try to get my mom to send me some of the tapes because you realize For much of my youth I was very into breakdancing.
Speaker 1: That's not good.
Speaker 0: And in fact when I used to go to Farm City week in Macomb When I was a kid because my grandparents were carpenters and they'd set up a little shop and they'd sell awesome stuff And it was this big fair and I would just kind of hang out there.
Speaker 0: I Would always bring this big sheet of cardboard and I'd set it up behind him and I'd pull out my little cassette player.
Speaker 0: It was a fisher-price cassette player.
Speaker 1: Is he yellow?
Speaker 0: It was white and red.
Speaker 0: mine was yellow And I also had the Big Bird record player, but that's my Big Bird record player.
Speaker 1: It was off the hook, especially I'd be like Green Led Zeppelin in the Beatles on my you know, Big Bird record play.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think off the hook of flies and I would play.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember what music I played and I would breakdance but I was like five and There were videos of this and I would gather a crowd Most.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was because I was good or more likely because you're a little kid because there's a little kid Spinning around on his butt on a piece of cardboard in the street.
Speaker 1: Yep All right, my thing of the day owns your thing that you think these piece of shit, uh-huh No, no, not really, but my thing it is so great.
Speaker 1: I think it dwarfs most things of the day.
Speaker 0: We'll see about that.
Speaker 1: All right, so if you're a kid and you you want to get high Imagine if you're a Japanese kid, right?
Speaker 0: I'm the happiest boy in the world.
Speaker 0: I play video games that out that me in the real world will never see.
Speaker 1: you're in elementary school Whatever.
Speaker 1: All right, and every day eat lunch.
Speaker 1: What kind of lunch do you eat?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well, what do you have for lunch?
Speaker 1: What me if you're you know, if you're a little elementary school Japanese kid, I Don't know a bento.
Speaker 1: Yes a bento.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: All right, and where would this bento come from?
Speaker 0: My girlfriend because I was rocking with the ladies in elementary school actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, actually, yeah Okay, I got a story about that.
Speaker 0: I got a couple stories.
Speaker 1: What so what is your elementary school bento look like?
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Is it high quality?
Speaker 0: Of course, is it?
Speaker 1: is it just you know, look like food?
Speaker 1: or is there something special about it?
Speaker 0: It's eight layers and every layer is set to a different famicom game.
Speaker 1: Ah, now we're talking.
Speaker 1: Here's a website that is devoted entirely to the making of the cute bentos.
Speaker 0: Oh, man Oh, man, I gotta totally make some cute bento.
Speaker 1: We're talking like pokeball rice balls.
Speaker 1: We're talking Hello Kitty thingies with like, you know a little flower like like.
Speaker 1: It's like god, it's so cute.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I Think maybe this weekend.
Speaker 0: We should try to make some bentos.
Speaker 1: I don't think you can make bentos like this because on this website They also have.
Speaker 1: I can only look at the pictures.
Speaker 1: I can't read the moon language.
Speaker 1: They also have all sorts of like links to different cute bento making tools and accessories Like different boxes.
Speaker 1: my favorite thing is this there's like a little pan so that you can make up like a pancake that has like a happy face.
Speaker 1: There's like little like Hello Kitty like cookie cutters.
Speaker 1: so you can you know Make a big flat thing of rice and then make Hello Kitty rice thingies.
Speaker 1: Oh God, it's just out of control off the hook.
Speaker 1: It is doubly off the hook if you like the cute bentos and if you don't like the cute bentos, you're a heathen.
Speaker 1: This is the website of win of a thousand times win.
Speaker 0: Anyhow, um tonight.
Speaker 1: Oh my guys the hungry hungry caterpillar bento.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and it's got a little dirt under it.
Speaker 0: Uh so it's Monty pythons flying.
Speaker 0: I Couldn't come up with a better way to introduce that.
Speaker 0: we're gonna talk about it last week.
Speaker 0: We got to talk about it tonight.
Speaker 0: One if you don't know what Monty Python is already.
Speaker 1: for the longest time in my life like up until middle school I knew there was a thing called Monty Python.
Speaker 1: I knew nothing else about it whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yes I used to come home from middle school every day and then it would be on TV and then right after that would be Benny Hill.
Speaker 1: before before we say what Monty Python is for the morons Flying Let's let's talk about the first discovery of Monty Python.
Speaker 0: All right Well, I think I mean I've seen I've been watching Monty Python But that like the real discovery the moment where I fully got it was for much of my life.
Speaker 0: my dad in particular but also my mom would get me into various things, you know movie type things and My dad would always every now and then we'd be in a video store or something.
Speaker 0: I'd be trying to buy anime and he'd be like, you know Monty Python in the Holy Grail and I'd be like, yeah, what's this?
Speaker 0: and I just hadn't seen it.
Speaker 0: and one day it happened to be on TV and I turned it was on.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, this is that thing and I laughed I watched it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I'm watching this I'm watching this and something happened.
Speaker 0: it was like we were like ten minutes in the movie and I laughed so hard and what I saw that I missed like the Next ten jokes and as soon as I recovered and my side stopped hurting and I looked up again I immediately started laughing again and it was like the funniest thing I'd ever seen in my life.
Speaker 1: alright, so me I was at a friend's house sometime middle school for a party, right and Everyone was like, oh we're gonna watch something something and it was Holy Grail, of course, and I was like, yeah, whatever Whatever.
Speaker 1: and at the time he had a much better computer than I had and many more computer games than I had.
Speaker 1: So I started playing Warcraft 2 Not having played Warcraft 2 and I just played it and I kept playing it and I was just sort of involved in this game And I wasn't really paying attention.
Speaker 1: and I turned around at one point, you know getting out of you know The zone that I was in and people were watching this movie and I saw like nights and stuff and I was like, oh man What the hell.
Speaker 1: but they were already sort of into the movie like halfway ish Like it was already at the the invincible connected, you know getting all his limbs chopped off and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So I was just like whatever.
Speaker 1: I just kept playing my Warcraft 2 and I heard people laughing crazily, but I mostly ignored it.
Speaker 1: It's sad story, isn't it?
Speaker 1: And then you know, eventually the movie was over but then you know it didn't stop.
Speaker 1: you see if we're over the next many days all my little middle school friends were saying such things as And I was just like what the fuck what the fuck is wrong with you guys.
Speaker 1: So I went to the blockbuster.
Speaker 1: Hey, I got the Holy Grail and I watched it with my family and I was like, oh man It was quite similar with the I remember sides.
Speaker 0: I'd finally see it and I I go to my dad the next day and I'm like.
Speaker 0: So I saw that Monty Python in the Holy Grail and he's very judicious like he raises an eyebrow He's like and what did you think of it?
Speaker 1: What did you learn?
Speaker 0: and at that point I just started laughing because I started remembering the movie and I'm sure this is the experience with pretty much every geek out there in the world.
Speaker 1: But you've seen Monty Python in the Holy Grail so many times that it's almost not funny anymore because you've memorized it Entirely, it's sort of funny in a way like, you know The Simpsons and like old Family Guy episodes and Spaceballs the first time.
Speaker 0: I watched it like literally that I'm not exaggerating at all.
Speaker 0: I was laughing so hard like I couldn't breathe in and my stomach hurt.
Speaker 1: That's pretty.
Speaker 0: it was really painful and it sucked but I couldn't stop laughing, you know I haven't laughed that hard in a long time.
Speaker 1: So actually before I was able to watch any more Monty Python, right?
Speaker 1: I got the this Monty Python computer game for Windows 3.1.
Speaker 0: Was that the Holy Grail one?
Speaker 1: No it was the the Flying Circus one with the giant foot on the front the one that had a million like 120 by 120 pixel like OLE videos.
Speaker 0: Yes, that one I also had.
Speaker 0: that.
Speaker 1: that is why the skits that were in those little hundred twenty one hundred twenty videos are much better Remembered by myself than some of the others.
Speaker 0: but Monty Python such as the large God we got to avoid turning this into the dirty vicar sketch.
Speaker 0: I like tits.
Speaker 0: Summarize Proust.
Speaker 0: Yes We're not gonna just sit here and say all the skits we like because eventually we'll name all of them.
Speaker 0: Yep My favorite one ever is salad days.
Speaker 1: Salad days you suck.
Speaker 1: Anyone fancy a game of tennis if I had to pick one?
Speaker 0: Well, no No, if I had to pick one it is of course the crimson permanent assurance.
Speaker 1: I like the crimson permanent assurance.
Speaker 1: It's a high quality, but that's really.
Speaker 1: it's not a skit.
Speaker 1: It's from the beginning of the you know, the meaning of life.
Speaker 0: Well, it was originally written as something else.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: they just stuck it at the beginning of the meaning of life movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, um, I Say, you know as cliched it is the silly walks is so great that it's you know Because the way that man moves those legs.
Speaker 0: John Cleese is a god among men.
Speaker 1: and then you take you know He believes in a lot of randy bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what also from from all I've read he was an asshole.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think he still is an asshole.
Speaker 1: He's a funny asshole.
Speaker 1: And the other one that if I had to go with one is the word The where.
Speaker 1: that the funny the joke, that's so funny that you're like read two words You have to go to the hospital.
Speaker 1: I don't know I use it to fight Germany and it's just like Something.
Speaker 0: there was the the argument skit which just because it's very relevant to my life is one.
Speaker 1: Oh, I forgot to mention I also had the vinyl album of Monty Python something something and it was had two sides.
Speaker 1: I know it had three sides I had and then there was a third hidden side or if you could put the needle in the groove you could actually hear a Third special thing on there.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: That was my dad's album.
Speaker 0: that he My dad's album - my dad was also at live at the Hollywood Bowl.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe my parents They must have seen him at some point.
Speaker 1: So what Monty Python is for you who are uninitiated?
Speaker 0: Monty Python is British people.
Speaker 1: It's six funny British dudes.
Speaker 0: It's a document from the 60s of life 70s 60s 70s.
Speaker 0: Well, technically it began at the end of 1969.
Speaker 1: All right, they have made basically their sketch comedy and they make they made some movies Monty Python the Holy Grail Monty Python life of Brian Monty Python meaning a life.
Speaker 1: Those are pretty much the three movies and there are some other things that they've each done.
Speaker 0: Oh, I mean, we're not gonna do the history of money.
Speaker 1: and they did Monty Python's flying circus Which is a TV show.
Speaker 1: that was just sort of sketch comedy and you can get the whole DVD box.
Speaker 1: Let's see how much it is on Amazon.
Speaker 0: I remember my mom and got me the DVD box set as a gift.
Speaker 0: and let me tell you I've seen Every one of those DVDs in its entirety more than once.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of them.
Speaker 1: It is well worth purchasing the DVD box.
Speaker 1: That is worth a Monty Python's flying circus.
Speaker 1: Teen-ton megaset is on Amazon for $64.99.
Speaker 0: a steal a winks is as good as a nod to a blind pet.
Speaker 1: Hey, hey nudge.
Speaker 0: No drink winks animal God, we have to stop this.
Speaker 1: It's really cheap.
Speaker 1: That is that is like an insta buy right there $65 for 16 discs of You know Hilarious comedies.
Speaker 0: now It's also there's a serious side because it also they have one character who is actually based on what every Welshman is Like as far as I've been told the Gumby the Gumby.
Speaker 1: Oh Take a bunch of flowers.
Speaker 0: Get No offense to any Welshman out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually I actually like Wales Flag with an awesome dragon lion thing on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Wales pretty much wins the flag contest.
Speaker 0: pretty much hands down.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, oh, yeah Monty Python the style of humor.
Speaker 1: I'm going to Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Look at the Welsh flag.
Speaker 1: Oh, look at that flag that big red dragon.
Speaker 0: That's pretty dangerous I mean for people aren't fully aware of all this Monty Python their style of humor.
Speaker 0: They were not the first people to do humor like this by any stretch.
Speaker 0: nor were they were the last people.
Speaker 0: but for a lot of Americans particularly this was kind of the icon of British comedy and this sort of humor appealed to geeky people in a way that very few things had ever appealed to geeky people before.
Speaker 0: and Monty Python.
Speaker 0: if you pretty much go to any anime con any video game con especially a gaming con and you can pretty much assume that anyone over the age of 16 or 17 has seen All of the Monty Python movies or at least the Holy Grail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's got.
Speaker 1: it's very strange that it's geek tie-ins.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's only because of the Holy Grail or what but it's it's somehow.
Speaker 1: in the modern day Like back in the day Monty Python was like comedy for everyone and it still is, you know.
Speaker 1: But for some reason now it has a geek, you know, at least a geek tie-in of some sort.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're selling.
Speaker 1: you know Must wow is actually a few years ago.
Speaker 1: They're selling like, you know, the bitey rabbit plush toys and stuff and it's like, you know Two geeks like you would go to a gaming con.
Speaker 1: You see the bitey rabbit for sale and you like what?
Speaker 0: No You don't go you go duh.
Speaker 0: Well, I know but it's like oh like like, you know We talk about all video games and anime fandom are kind of intertwined to a big degree.
Speaker 0: But then like sci-fi and fantasy are really intertwined because there's reasons for that.
Speaker 0: But sci-fi and gaming like tabletop gaming are really intertwined and there's kind of this whole Venn diagram web of geekery.
Speaker 0: But Monty Python and the enjoyment of that style of humor seems to be almost universal among geeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I've never met a person who is geeky that didn't enjoy the Monty Python's who also had seen it.
Speaker 0: I've very rarely in my life known people who were not already Intense fans of Monty Python long before I had ever met them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean It's like everybody knows.
Speaker 0: I mean how many is anyone out this anyone out there?
Speaker 0: I really want to know and our listeners who has never seen or at least heard of the parrot sketch?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you it's got to be on YouTube, right Lee I I'm of the mind that the car repair sketch from how to irritate people Which is basically the same sketch is superior.
Speaker 1: Uh No, I really like the parents.
Speaker 1: Yes, of course.
Speaker 1: I like the dirty pharmacist sketch Semprene, oh, it's it's the dirty chemist sketch right because they don't call it a pharmacist.
Speaker 0: and yes, you damn pretense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I learned one thing.
Speaker 0: I learned the quickest way to spot someone who was faking a British accent, but isn't actually British and sound like Monty Python.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's one way.
Speaker 0: But the other thing is I learned that someone could have a perfect British accent But then they'll say patronize and apparently everyone in Britain says patronize Uh-huh, but then again that might just be a trick to confuse me.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: It could be but anyway, hey Let's talk more about what?
Speaker 1: My money by then why I?
Speaker 0: the reason I like Monty Python.
Speaker 0: I can't speak for other geeks, but it's got this perfect combination of non-sequitur.
Speaker 0: just It's kind of like.
Speaker 0: this was non-sequitur humor before we had Family Guy and before we had you know This aqua teen whatever's like.
Speaker 0: this was the non-sequitur humor the weird humor the humor that you either thought it was the best thing in the world or you totally didn't get it.
Speaker 0: and In addition to that it was often very Intelligence and a lot of people will say oh that's pretentious and that's a cop-out.
Speaker 0: But no a lot of these sketches were brilliantly written and brilliantly performed brilliantly done Yeah, I mean at the time that I saw this stuff.
Speaker 1: I not seen anything else that was like it and a lot of it.
Speaker 1: there is still nothing like it.
Speaker 1: really I Mean you have a night and he's getting chopped up and he's like, oh no It's just a flesh wound and he's bleeding all over the place.
Speaker 1: It doesn't get funnier than that.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 1: there are funnier things than that No, but I mean just think about that bleeding all over the place and he's just like oh whatever But there's stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of non-sequitur kind of crazy humor like that nowadays, but it's sort of like You know, where would that?
Speaker 1: that wouldn't be there if Monty Python wasn't there?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you may be right I mean, it's hard to say but I think Monty Python is very heavily influenced a lot of comedy in the United States And in Britain.
Speaker 1: ever since you know Monty Python and all the surviving members of Monty Python have gone on to do other comedy things.
Speaker 0: One of them's dead.
Speaker 1: I know Yeah, they've all gone on to do separate things, you know all about influencing the arts in many ways.
Speaker 0: Yes I mean, of course, I don't know how many of you I mean I guess I might be described as a super fan because I know a lot about Monty Python and a lot of people can't seem to tell the difference between all the people in Monty Python.
Speaker 1: I can tell there's most of the people in Monty Python.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I mean there's people that no one ever saw so so much and there's feel like John Cleese.
Speaker 0: Everyone knows cuz he did like all these movies afterward.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Eric Idle acted a bunch of movies also.
Speaker 1: Yes, a Terry Gilliam is I think actually Eric Idle's best part in a non Monty Python role was I think there was a movie that was like You know my like.
Speaker 1: it was like something about like parents and aliens or something like my parents or I forget exactly what it was But like he played a part of like a guy in a dungeon chained up and he just kind of was hanging on the wall Being all silly.
Speaker 1: I really like that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't know I was always a big fan of John Cleese partly because he could do silly walks.
Speaker 0: I think he's the only human being in the world qualified to do a silly walk And I think he's the only person in the world who I could see doing a silly walk and actually laugh.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it's just and I mean he's done a lot of great things afterward Like I said before but he put together and it's mostly just Monty Python skits But he kind of did the links between all of them called how to irritate people.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend it because it is basically half a bunch of Monty Python or Monty Python esque skits and half a very well done concise Explanation of how to irritate other human beings.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's just it's great I know.
Speaker 0: so in a fish called Wanda and Fierce creatures, which is kind of an homage to a fish called Wanda, which I think was actually a lot better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's also Terry Gilliam was very important because he did like all the like.
Speaker 1: if you watch Flying Circus There's all these animations and things and even in like Holy Grail and such There'll be animations like in the movie and they're very the same sort of style as you'll see in yellow submarine.
Speaker 1: I think he had a hand in that too.
Speaker 1: Actually, I forget You know and he's sort of like.
Speaker 1: that's his animation.
Speaker 1: That's like he sort of.
Speaker 1: I don't know if he invented it but like that's you know, people see that in the gods Terry Gilliam animation that's that is.
Speaker 1: and then he went on to make you know other movies and such like like Brazil, right?
Speaker 1: He made you made Brazil, right?
Speaker 0: Yes, Brazil and He had a part in Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas 12 monkeys trying to think of what else.
Speaker 1: He went on to be like a filmmaker after Monty Python was done.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty important guy right there.
Speaker 0: Yes, of course I quick aside if anyone's seen the movie Brazil make sure you don't see the awful like kind of American.
Speaker 0: oh it ended happily crap.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: He did.
Speaker 0: In fact direct Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: I wasn't 100% sure but I had to check.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's not everyone is a fan of his later works But I am.
Speaker 1: yeah, I like him enough.
Speaker 0: I really like Brazil.
Speaker 0: a lot of people don't like Brazil.
Speaker 1: It's okay It wasn't great.
Speaker 0: Well, I wasn't great about it.
Speaker 0: Hey, it was a little long.
Speaker 0: I'll give you that it didn't thrill me I don't know, but I think John Cleese is my favorite.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: Graham Chapman is the guy who played none other than King Arthur.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's uh, it was alcoholic.
Speaker 0: Yes and dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well now he's dead Yes, but you'll you'll read many a tale of how he was drunk the whole time He was doing the King Arthur thing and yes like that He was also apparently very difficult to get along with.
Speaker 0: but all of that all the reports of that I read mostly coming from John Cleese.
Speaker 0: It was also reported as being very hard to get along with yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, actually the sudden it, you know The TV series, you know Flying Circus was how many seasons like five or six seasons?
Speaker 0: I think it was five seasons, right and you know John Cleese wanted to leave after like a few seasons after like the half first half of the second season.
Speaker 0: He was like fuck you guys.
Speaker 1: I'm gone Yeah, and you know cuz he thought that they were just repeating the same ideas over and over again or something like that.
Speaker 1: You know, he was.
Speaker 1: he's basically like, alright, we're done with this but he sort of stuck around for another season or so because they sort of made him kinda and then he left and he's not in like the Like final season or so of the show.
Speaker 0: the final season by the way is not nearly as good as the rest of it.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: The thing I find interesting is if you watch those seasons where he didn't want to be there, but he was there.
Speaker 1: Anyway, he was still just as funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah The skits that he actually wrote or actually played a part in were amazing not to discredit any other Monty Python people because they were All great.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh Monty Python.
Speaker 0: Actually, I don't know what else I could say other than descending back into.
Speaker 0: oh, I like tits.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's let's go through like some of the best skits and parts of movies and things that are awesome.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I really really like the Dennis Moore sketch.
Speaker 1: I don't know the Dennis Moore thing.
Speaker 1: to be perfectly honest It's not really that funny, but it's just sort of so quotable with the Dennis Moore.
Speaker 1: Dennis Moore And the bleeding lupins The cats Bradley choked to death on him.
Speaker 1: Yeah That part is just the fact that it's so I don't know.
Speaker 1: You just talk about Dennis Moore all day.
Speaker 0: Oh, could you yeah continue?
Speaker 1: All right, Dennis Moore.
Speaker 1: He's dumb dumb dumb.
Speaker 0: What else do you got about Dennis Moore?
Speaker 1: Dumb dumb dumb dumb dumb.
Speaker 1: all day All day He steals from the rage he gives to the poor Dennis Moore.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's funny because there's all the kind of classic like everyone knows the lumberjack skit or the the philosophers drinking song.
Speaker 1: No, what's the positive thing?
Speaker 0: song in it's the philosopher.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I don't remember that one.
Speaker 0: It's the philosophers drinking.
Speaker 0: Immanuel Kant was a real pissant who was very rarely stable.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I didn't know what it was called.
Speaker 0: I Think you could have figured it out.
Speaker 0: the philosophers drinking song.
Speaker 0: Immanuel Kant was a real pissant who was very rarely stay.
Speaker 0: I think you could have put two and two together.
Speaker 1: No, no, I wasn't, you know, okay, there's so much of it You can't keep it all in the mind all at once.
Speaker 0: Yes, you can.
Speaker 0: No, I think it's.
Speaker 0: I've got two legs from my hips To the ground and when I move them they walk around and when I lift and they climb the stairs and When I shave them, they ain't got hairs.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I Think the show is done.
Speaker 0: What are we gonna say?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's just like it feels like.
Speaker 1: what can we say other than sort of?
Speaker 1: researching and telling you more details of the history and amazingness of Monty Python or just Quoting it incessantly for a long time?
Speaker 1: What you know, what else can we do?
Speaker 0: I mean other than as a public service announcement if you're a geek?
Speaker 0: No not.
Speaker 1: if you're a geek anyone listening to this show who has not seen all Three of the major Monty Python movies and as much of the TV show as you can get your hands on.
Speaker 1: you have a problem.
Speaker 1: You just you got to see it all.
Speaker 0: I mean seriously.
Speaker 1: There's no way that you're not gonna like it.
Speaker 0: Monty Python and the Holy Grail.
Speaker 1: If you ever met anyone ever who has said I don't I at.
Speaker 1: they had they have seen Monty Python and they actively Did not like it.
Speaker 1: they were like, I hate Monty Python at least the Holy Grail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean no one.
Speaker 1: I've never met such a person pretty much as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 1: There are people who?
Speaker 1: Find Monty Python hilarious and people have never seen it.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: I mean my the Holy Grail.
Speaker 0: I've seen it so many times but the movie is like the greatest comedy film ever made.
Speaker 1: your mother was a hamster And your father smelt of elderberries.
Speaker 1: Who writes something like that doesn't matter but it's really funny.
Speaker 1: when you're in middle school There's a bunch of fart jokes, but you know what?
Speaker 0: It's still funny now I don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: And actually the funny thing is you talk to a lot of geeks and they can quote the movie Practically verbatim like the whole movie and you think oh, they can't quote.
Speaker 0: No the whole movie I mean some day loud.
Speaker 0: all this would be yours, but the cut All that you can see but mother father.
Speaker 0: I don't want tracks of Land, I don't want to sing.
Speaker 0: Oh stop that You stay here and make sure you don't be sure that doesn't leave.
Speaker 0: Are you going?
Speaker 0: we're coming with you, sir.
Speaker 0: No, no God, but I realized a lot of geeks have not seen the movie in recent memory.
Speaker 0: That's just criminal But I haven't seen it recently.
Speaker 0: the last I haven't seen Monty Python and the Holy Grail in like a decade.
Speaker 1: I've seen it in more recently than a decade But it's been a few years and I feel like I kind of want to extol.
Speaker 1: is it on Netflix Honda man?
Speaker 0: I feel like what needs to be done is all of you out there who have not seen this movie recently Should get all your geeky friends together and watch all of us.
Speaker 0: We'll do it to Monty Python and the Holy Grail Because you forget how funny that movie was and also how fucked up that movie was.
Speaker 1: Yeah I should mention this.
Speaker 1: the Broadway shows spam a lot which man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you seen Holy Grail It's like you go and it's like oh, it's sort of the same jokes as Holy Grail But with some singing and dance, they had to walk a really fine line because if they just did Holy Grail Everyone knows it verbatim.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if they stray too far people going will go.
Speaker 0: what the hell was that?
Speaker 0: That wasn't the Holy Grail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's just sort of like.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's exactly what you'd expect.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a Broadway production using many of the same jokes as Holy Grail with some new added jokes and singing and dancing.
Speaker 1: and You know, it's not bad You know, it's just.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna be lying and rolling around in the floor if you've seen Holy Grail before But if you haven't seen Holy Grail a lot of it will make no sense to you.
Speaker 1: So it is what it is.
Speaker 0: I think the target audience of that was someone who had seen the Holy Grail Like once when they were a child and had otherwise forgotten about it.
Speaker 1: I think that is the person who can enjoy that Broadway show the most.
Speaker 0: I can say one thing that nobody expects the Spanish Inquisition.
Speaker 0: Remember our Surprise yeah, and remember our promo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one of the promos he made was the Spanish Inquisition promo.
Speaker 0: It was it was bad bad.
Speaker 0: Well podcast promos in general are bad.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Podcast should not be playing promos.
Speaker 0: It's over.
Speaker 0: Stop it.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 0: God.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm done with the promos pretty much.
Speaker 0: We haven't played promos in a long time because I think there's a dumb idea.
Speaker 1: I think they're pretty dumb.
Speaker 1: I mean the pride.
Speaker 1: Getting someone who listens to another podcast to listen to yours isn't really gonna help you out.
Speaker 1: You need to get people who don't listen to podcasts to listen to podcasts.
Speaker 1: That is the key You know, I just remembered just like getting it's not you're not gonna.
Speaker 1: You know You don't need to convince someone who watches one Monty Python movie to watch another one.
Speaker 1: You need to get someone who doesn't watch any Monty Pythons and watch some.
Speaker 0: I'll admit though I didn't like.
Speaker 0: meaning a life that much see uh meaning a life.
Speaker 1: It has some Really amazing parts like why and that has them also.
Speaker 0: the only thing that ask anyone who's seen that movie and all they remember is the opening movie and then But it's way far thin.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's the best part is the way for thin part But what else?
Speaker 1: the second best part is where they?
Speaker 1: He's teaching them in the class about you know, like how to do foreplay and such.
Speaker 0: That was okay.
Speaker 1: Is the part where they're in?
Speaker 1: there is it was nowhere near the jungle and there's the tiger.
Speaker 0: oh whatever It was nowhere near the quality of the cycling tour Forget what it's called.
Speaker 0: but that one skit where a guy like goes to a house and he's waiting for like someone's like like the butler takes him like wait in this room and so and so will be down in a minute and he's standing there and then just like a Vase falls off the shelf completely by itself and breaks and the butler comes in.
Speaker 0: I was just standing here and it fell.
Speaker 0: the butler's looks at him with his look of sure sure you were just standing there But I'm a butler's I'm just gonna clean it up.
Speaker 0: He's like no But I really didn't cry whatever.
Speaker 0: and then the butler leaves and then like a shelf falls over And the butler comes back and is looking at the guy like he's crazy you guys seriously didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: and it escalates and eventually he accidentally stabs like the Man, that sketch is so crunchy frog.
Speaker 0: Ah crunchy frog.
Speaker 0: not the best sketch but pretty good overall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a it's a. it's got some lasting memorableness.
Speaker 0: I mean you can forget spams spams spams spams spams.
Speaker 0: I don't like spams spams spams spams spams spams back akins and bam akins.
Speaker 0: and yeah, I killed that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I also.
Speaker 1: I like there's a whole episode with the Dinsdale Table.
Speaker 1: oh, no, it's a wonderful man.
Speaker 1: Wonderful.
Speaker 0: We're doing it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is the reason we were so afraid of doing this show because it's movies You should see as this problem.
Speaker 0: all the time or whenever they do a funny movie You can't help but just turn it into a quote fest cuz what are you gonna say other than yeah, it was really funny It was.
Speaker 1: it's all really really really funny.
Speaker 0: It's so funny.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else I can say.
Speaker 1: I think we should watch some while we eat some dinner.
Speaker 0: I think maybe we should.
Speaker 0: you know what if Holy Grail is in the Netflix on demand that's trouble.
Speaker 1: Let's watch it right now.
Speaker 0: then This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: it's Thursday April 3rd, I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is you suck You.