Speaker 0: It's Monday January 21st.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is a cop-out episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: We talk about keyboards.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a MLK day Yeah, and I guess last year my company did not have this day off, but I wasn't working there at the time.
Speaker 1: But this year they do have it off.
Speaker 1: So Alright is the first time in many years.
Speaker 1: I've had this day off.
Speaker 0: I find it wonderful and hilarious that Every single one of us in the front row crew had today Martin Luther King day off Except Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh well so everyone else came over for burning wheel and all our business and then Everyone just kind of stuck around and we hung out Sunday night, but not Scott.
Speaker 0: He had to go all the way back to Pennsylvania.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it sucks.
Speaker 1: I hate these days cuz it's like I'm home from work I don't have to go and I could do what I want But then the mail doesn't come and some things are closed.
Speaker 1: that would normally be open and it's like ah I need a day I need a day off when no one else does.
Speaker 0: the worst thing is that when I get a holiday some holiday Especially if it's on like a Monday Sometimes it's obvious that the garbage won't get picked up.
Speaker 0: But sometimes I don't know what if the garbage or the city or whatever respects the holiday.
Speaker 1: It's not the city It's it's.
Speaker 1: we have a private trash pickup.
Speaker 0: I think it's contracted by the city.
Speaker 1: I'm not quite sure but it doesn't say city a beacon on the truck.
Speaker 1: That's all I know.
Speaker 0: But yeah The city's often contracted out.
Speaker 1: Yeah often but indeed in like New York City It says, you know New York City Department of Sanitation on the truck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because New York City has a full Department of Sanitation.
Speaker 1: Yes But anyway I usually look at if the neighbors have their trash out then we should put ours out that's.
Speaker 1: and if the neighbors have their Recycling out then I should put my recycling out.
Speaker 1: Of course if every neighbor is thinking that way Then it's like at least as long as one neighbor's got it, right then we're okay, but if not then we're in trouble.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the worst part is that like our one neighbor down like in the basement always thinks that we're dumb because we never remember When the like when the recyclables go out or whatever and she can't understand that we just care so little that we always forget And we just don't pay attention to it.
Speaker 1: Well, we do pay attention to it.
Speaker 0: It's just sometimes every week We say hey did the recyclables go out?
Speaker 0: Oh We'll I'm out there.
Speaker 1: in case we need some sort of like.
Speaker 1: how did they know originally there must be a schedule somewhere Where you know what?
Speaker 0: I went to the beacon website and there was jackaw.
Speaker 1: I know that's the sort of thing that should be on a town website, but no town has a good website.
Speaker 1: There might be one town out there which has like a Linux nerd for me.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: The real problem is that a lot of towns and cities take care of things like recycling or whatever the schedules are for city things.
Speaker 0: They do it in kind of a old world intuitive way.
Speaker 0: Like it's every other week or something like that When really it should be some sort of algorithm that you can determine just by having knowledge.
Speaker 0: For example, it'll be on the first and third week of every month Mm-hmm, but by doing it every other week, it slowly kind of gets out of skew.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it happens three times in a month.
Speaker 0: It's just it's BS.
Speaker 1: It is quite BS.
Speaker 1: It's not the most well thought-out thing.
Speaker 1: plus they should also.
Speaker 1: You know that you can look at statistics of like, you know how much the trash trucks fill up.
Speaker 1: You know when different times they go out and you could actually instead time the trucks to send them out as few times as possible.
Speaker 1: But you know at certain times of the year when there's more trash like holidays You could send them out more and other times of the year like during summer vacation when there's less trash send them out less.
Speaker 1: You could figure that all that shit out and then as long as there was in communication with the people via Technology, which most people don't know how to use but at least the newspaper also, you know People would know when it was because it would it would say and it wouldn't matter if you didn't remember because it would remind you Like hey trash today.
Speaker 0: Well, the the worst thing is that Beacons website has that animated gif of the fire.
Speaker 1: Oh Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta check this out.
Speaker 0: that animated gif was on the website the last time I checked.
Speaker 1: good god Let me check the city of Beacon homepage.
Speaker 1: I Don't see a fire.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, it's there.
Speaker 0: it's there now.
Speaker 0: now if any of you don't know what up to what I'm referred It's there for a memorial thing.
Speaker 0: It's been there since we moved here Good guy that memorial thing If you don't know what I'm talking about that animated gif was this someone made an animated gif of a fire and in the mid 90s late 90s before there was really a web internet to speak of.
Speaker 0: People who made websites were mostly people who were between 11 and 11 point one years old and nothing was cooler Than an animated gif of a rotating skull and bones with fire and fire or Some skull and fire.
Speaker 0: people would always have like that.
Speaker 1: email me link at the bottom and the email by email with a skull on fire a Flaming skull envelope was the best animated gif ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you think websites are ugly now take a trip back to 1994 and you'll see the day once that was like.
Speaker 1: this is what a dig would look like in 1997. and or I think there was also maybe one like.
Speaker 1: here's an example of websites, right?
Speaker 1: And it was that's.
Speaker 1: that's what it's like.
Speaker 0: So anyway in the news I don't think we have a lot to talk about because uh Aside from the stock market collapsing and Sprint being completely fucked and all that sort of fun stuff Something much more important happened last week that we didn't talk about.
Speaker 1: Well, isn't that?
Speaker 1: It's not that important really but but yeah last week, you know It was Monday with sci-tech day and we knew that on Tuesday Steve Jobs was gonna open his big fat mouth again.
Speaker 0: and this was important to me because I am going to buy a laptop and All the rumors were that Apple was gonna announce something with a laptop.
Speaker 0: and you know Just being even if I probably wasn't gonna get an apple.
Speaker 0: but there was a decent chance a non-zero chance that Apple was going to announce a Laptop product.
Speaker 0: that would have been exactly what I wanted.
Speaker 1: and yeah, it was a non-zero chance.
Speaker 1: It was actually a pretty but now we've determined that it is a zero chance.
Speaker 0: Yeah So what all was announced at Macworld?
Speaker 0: Well one the.
Speaker 0: the new laptop is not a 12-inch MacBook Pro.
Speaker 0: Thank you fanboys making stuff up.
Speaker 0: It is in fact a very very thin and largely useless laptop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean he's basically the thinness is good.
Speaker 1: The battery life is not as good as the battery life I have which is nine hours, but theirs is five hours.
Speaker 1: But five hours is still pretty respectable compared to other laptops.
Speaker 1: You're like to one hour Right, so it's not bad.
Speaker 1: It's then it's light is wicked light.
Speaker 1: It's got the wireless.
Speaker 1: It's got a good enough keyboard.
Speaker 1: It's got the multi touch touchpad.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: The resolution is pretty decent but it's 13 inches where I have almost the same resolution, but my laptops only 10.6 inches.
Speaker 1: So, you know It's $1,800 I think about.
Speaker 0: so now it's it's $1,800 for the basic standard one that doesn't have all the good stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the tricky part.
Speaker 1: Mine is 1650 for the base, but then I customized mine up to like 2k.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm probably just going to get the next iteration of Scott's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have the p72 30, but I think they're coming out with like a p8 some.
Speaker 0: but no there are two In fact MacBook Air's.
Speaker 0: there is the.
Speaker 0: well, they don't actually have names.
Speaker 0: There's the one and the other one.
Speaker 0: now They both have Intel core 2 duos But the slightly better one has a 1.8 gigahertz instead of a 1.6 gigahertz.
Speaker 1: How much more does it cost to upgrade that particular to that?
Speaker 0: and also the Normal one has an 80 gigabyte, you know regular hard drive.
Speaker 0: the slightly better one has a 64 gigabyte solid-state drive.
Speaker 1: So and that's the only difference Yeah I have a 16 gigabyte solid-state drive that I bought aftermarket and put into my laptop because Ubuntu killed the normal hard drive.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that was like $200.
Speaker 1: so a 64 gigabyte one.
Speaker 1: That's got to be wicked moneys.
Speaker 0: Now the difference between these two is Two gigahertz point two gigahertz more and a solid-state drive.
Speaker 1: Well, the solid-state drive is a huge improvement, especially with 64 gig.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's you don't need a 64 gig solid-state.
Speaker 0: But uh, Chris the difference in price the normal one is $1,800.
Speaker 0: all told it's 1790.
Speaker 0: It's $1,800.
Speaker 0: The other one's three thousand three thousand one hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: That's more than the eight core Mac Pro More.
Speaker 0: it's more money to get that thing and the only core Mac Pro is a solid-state drive and point two more giga.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it's point two times two more gigahertz, but still that's not gonna be that much of a day.
Speaker 1: No, it's not that much.
Speaker 1: That's pretty stupid.
Speaker 1: If you buy that one, that's all I can say.
Speaker 0: Now the real deal is when when I saw it, I saw it's really thin.
Speaker 0: Hey brought it out in Manila.
Speaker 0: Hahaha, I get it.
Speaker 0: It is stupidly thin like it's.
Speaker 1: it's crazily amazingly thin Yeah, but the problem is is that in order to make it so thin they had to cut some things out which is understandable.
Speaker 1: There's no way you can make something thinner without cutting something out.
Speaker 1: The problem is they cut out too much.
Speaker 1: First of all, there's only one USB port.
Speaker 1: now that's not too bad except until you realize that you can't plug your iPod in and Apple.
Speaker 0: you're not supposed to be using the USB Mouse gonna have the Bluetooth.
Speaker 1: Okay, so get the use Bluetooth Mouse.
Speaker 1: It's alright Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, what if you want to connect it to a wired network and also use your iPod at the same time?
Speaker 0: Well, actually you have to get a special dongle, but the special dongle is USB.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: You need to use because the thing It's a but I've used be hub.
Speaker 1: So what's the point of having this really light?
Speaker 0: Thing if I need to have carry around all these extra things you shouldn't need a wire because it's an Apple thing It's just wireless.
Speaker 0: It's just use it by itself.
Speaker 0: In fact, supposedly you're supposed to be able to share.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is not.
Speaker 0: supposedly they have something called remote disk where it doesn't come with an optical drive even nothing.
Speaker 0: There's no drives in this thing except for the one hard drive.
Speaker 0: But you can share a DVD or CD drive from a nearby Mac or Windows PC.
Speaker 0: It's probably not gonna work at all with Linux.
Speaker 1: No but if basically you install some software on a Windows or Mac and then you install and then from the Mac air you say look For CD roms.
Speaker 1: and basically you say it shows you all the computers on your network that are running the software and you say connect.
Speaker 1: And then a pop-up shows on the computer that has the disk drive and on that pop-up you say yes.
Speaker 1: and now the MacBook Air acts like that CD ROM in that other computer.
Speaker 1: is its CD ROM or DVD ROM or whatever, but You know the part of having a laptop especially for us the commuters is watching DVDs on the train.
Speaker 0: Yep, that was the thing.
Speaker 0: if if the MacBook Air had had an optical drive in it somehow I probably would have bought it despite all the other problems because it's it's a great little laptop.
Speaker 0: But the thing is It's okay.
Speaker 0: I think it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: It would do everything I needed it to do.
Speaker 0: It'd be a fantastic laptop for me to use for geek nights and going around and no Night, so doesn't have a microphone in hole.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't need one.
Speaker 0: All I need is the USB to use my external sound card.
Speaker 0: I'm never.
Speaker 1: I'm never recording anything with analog again Yeah, but even so I think the fact that it only has one USB and the fact that it's missing all these things.
Speaker 0: I don't think the one USB is a problem at all.
Speaker 1: Well, it's that you need a lot of external things like an external sound card to get these sort of necessary features that were cut Out now because it plays just fine even to use the video out.
Speaker 1: It has one of those mini HDMI holes So you need to get an adapter for that.
Speaker 0: That's because regular HDMI is too thick.
Speaker 1: I know that.
Speaker 1: but the point is is that because they cut enough out that you even though it's thinner and lighter The purpose is defeated because now you have to carry this extra shit around.
Speaker 1: I mean mine is defeated because mine is thicker, but I don't have to carry an extra shit.
Speaker 0: I don't think the purpose is defeated because the people who would buy this sort of thing wouldn't need to carry any that stuff around.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think Not that many people especially because you know, you're an Apple person you can buy all this Apple stuff.
Speaker 0: You're gonna be renting movies or buying movies with iTunes.
Speaker 1: You know, if you're a moron, you're a moron.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah Also, I think you're way too down on this.
Speaker 1: Well, also if you want to get online with like, you know your cell phone thing or whatever.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have a PCMCI slot So you can't even do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're an Apple person.
Speaker 0: You don't do that.
Speaker 0: Okay, sure Whatever plus it has a 802.11n.
Speaker 1: Uh But it'll probably and isn't finalized.
Speaker 1: but a lot of Apple products now have the end.
Speaker 1: So I'm sure it'll work with the other end Apple products, but You know, it's not end is not changed and is not going to change.
Speaker 0: You sure it's finalized as far as matters for technology.
Speaker 1: Then why don't we go get it?
Speaker 0: Why indeed?
Speaker 0: But you're the only person in this house uses wireless.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: I guess it would make it hard for other people in the house to connect if you're using n and they were using BG.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, well pretty much everything down.
Speaker 1: I know it down great gracefully, but then it would suck for us because you know Our ends would be.
Speaker 0: so you can know much about in.
Speaker 1: it's just better than V and G.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Do I have to do a show about it so I can explain exactly what any.
Speaker 1: is it different than B and G anyway?
Speaker 0: So, uh, what else did Apple announce?
Speaker 1: They got their movie rental business and the movie rental things kind of weird for me because at first I was like, oh That's not so bad because I thought about you know, the real-world situation.
Speaker 1: We're sitting there.
Speaker 1: You want to watch a movie?
Speaker 1: And we don't have net.
Speaker 1: we don't have it on Netflix right now.
Speaker 1: So we'd have to wait for Netflix to send the DVD, but friends are over and you want to watch the movie right now But you don't have the DVD.
Speaker 1: We could go to iTunes click on it wait a few minutes and then watch and it would cost the same amount as Blockbuster But only without the driving.
Speaker 1: and I said that's not really so bad.
Speaker 1: But then you think and I'm like, but wait this mad DRM is going on there Let me blah.
Speaker 1: and I and it's it's sorta you think about it more and more and you're like, huh?
Speaker 1: But then you look at the Engadget.
Speaker 1: put up this great post that has a list of things you can and can't do with the rented videos and it's like oh Well, plus the thing is then Netflix.
Speaker 0: You can pretty much do a million times more with Netflix.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's at Netflix sort of undercut Apple because a few days before Apple made this announcement Netflix announced they were going to remove met most of the restrictions on there, you know on demand go to their website watch video service Which is great, even though that's DRM.
Speaker 1: Do you know?
Speaker 1: you're going there and you're watching the movie somewhat streaming ish.
Speaker 1: So it's not you know, it's not like.
Speaker 1: you know, you're not.
Speaker 1: you don't think you're buying it or renting it.
Speaker 1: You know you're going and you're watching it and you can go of course and you're paying sided.
Speaker 0: All right We don't even use Linux downstairs.
Speaker 0: We have a real legitimate operating system as far as you know.
Speaker 0: old-world poorly run businesses consider It's.
Speaker 0: it's a Mac.
Speaker 0: It's a standard Mac.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and it's hooked up to the TV.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just go to Netflix and watch stuff like that?
Speaker 0: I'll use the Netflix thing.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work on Macs at all.
Speaker 0: It even says will not work on a Mac.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The Netflix thing is Windows only.
Speaker 1: I guess that's part of their DRM bullshit.
Speaker 1: So It's.
Speaker 1: it's really not a good situation for people who want to Download movies right now and watch them on some of a cheaper rental basis.
Speaker 0: I'd be willing to pay even a lot more to just be able to watch movies on my computer downloaded.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd be willing to pay quite a bit for that But every possible way to do that is just poorly done and not worth them.
Speaker 0: It's not worth the money and I am willing to pay a lot.
Speaker 0: So that says something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm willing to pay Up to the price of DVD.
Speaker 1: pretty much, you know Cuz I mean like.
Speaker 1: I got Netflix and Netflix is cheap.
Speaker 0: Wait, you're willing to pay up to the price of DVD to watch a movie.
Speaker 0: Hmm to rent a movie Oh, it's a rent it.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, but I meant to see it.
Speaker 0: I don't want to keep it.
Speaker 1: Oh just to see it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I try not to buy DVDs anymore because I don't want to keep them in the house We have all the DVDs we have just pile up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well just to see it I would pay, you know, Netflix divided by discs divided by time, you know, that's sadly we don't even watch our Netflix's.
Speaker 1: But well, you didn't mail them back.
Speaker 1: I bet you if you mail back the Shinjuku Triad Society piece of crap.
Speaker 0: The only reason we watch that movie is because we had a free day I know.
Speaker 1: but if you sent that back, we might get something we'd be excited about watching.
Speaker 0: I think the real problem is just that we don't have a lot of time to watch movies anymore.
Speaker 1: Maybe we just need a new determination of movie watching.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've had a new determination of anime watching recently and it's kind of working out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know Maybe if we stop playing video games.
Speaker 1: I'm not playing so many video games, even though I should.
Speaker 0: I got a punch out.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I gotta beat that.
Speaker 1: Mario Galaxy is what I have to do.
Speaker 0: I haven't even played Mario Galaxies yet I haven't even touched it.
Speaker 0: I have not other than playing as the second part of Scott's multiplayer business.
Speaker 0: I have not touched that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could play it someday.
Speaker 1: It's not going anywhere.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna be any different a year from now than it is now But then advanced wars is gonna come out and actually anything but that next week.
Speaker 0: It'll be out Okay, so what else there's?
Speaker 0: time capsule?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's see.
Speaker 1: the time capsule thing I think is the perfect example of what is wrong with Apple, right?
Speaker 1: It's basically all it is.
Speaker 1: hardware wise is a hard drive with a wireless adapter and some other bits, right a Hard drive with a wireless adapter.
Speaker 1: There's a lot you could do with that.
Speaker 1: They could have made a wireless NAS device, which is incredibly powerful and useful and it's.
Speaker 1: it's not too bad considering the price, you know.
Speaker 1: But what they do is the software they put on it.
Speaker 1: You pretty much can only use it for a time capsule.
Speaker 1: You can't use that hard drive as a NAS or a network file server or anything At least maybe you could hack it to do that.
Speaker 1: but that's not what it does out of the box.
Speaker 1: and it's like they make hardware that's capable of ABC D and E and They put software on it that's only capable of a B and some of C and D and E are right out and they charge more than they would for that.
Speaker 1: competitors charge for ABC D and E and the only difference is that the AB and half of C that they do do are very polished and shiny and And so if I didn't know about technology as a normal person That's kind of great because I'd rather have a shiny A and B that I need and D and E I don't even know or care about just cuz I don't know better.
Speaker 1: So it's a good time.
Speaker 1: But once you know better, there's no logical way you can bring yourself to make such a decision to purchase a product like that.
Speaker 1: it's just not gonna happen and Most of Apple's products are like that.
Speaker 1: The iPhone is capable of everything under the Sun hardware wise and the software lets it do like ten things.
Speaker 0: I just really don't get why they wouldn't have made it be more versatile because they could have made it really really slick and integrated With file share.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean imagine if Apple announced Apple Network NAS works perfectly with all computers.
Speaker 1: Yeah is amazing.
Speaker 0: It's plug it in.
Speaker 0: It's wireless.
Speaker 0: put it in your house And not only is all your stuff backed up to it all the time, but you can save all your files there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they could have done that.
Speaker 0: put your iTunes library there and then sync with it with your laptop with the same hardware.
Speaker 1: But they didn't.
Speaker 0: and it's kind of sad because again, it's a product that if it did one more Yes, that would be a huge.
Speaker 1: if you could have your iTunes library on this NAS and all the Macs in your house could you?
Speaker 1: Know store all their iTunes libraries in one place and share them all and that way even the DRM.
Speaker 1: They know you weren't copying anything that it was just Macs in your house that we're accessing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could do some sort of DRM to make that work and then that wouldn't be that bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I mean that would be kind of good then we people wouldn't have to deal so much They'd be less problems with the you know, migrating to the new Mac with your old library and all that bullshit.
Speaker 1: But no, they didn't do that.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 1: Well, see ya not buying any of these bro.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: and the Apple TV got a software upgrade and so did the iPod touch and iPhone.
Speaker 0: but but the Apple TV Cost way too much money for what you get.
Speaker 1: The only thing is I do think that next year when my phone's contract runs out in January The iPhone is getting quite some consideration and even though here's the thing Like the other Apple products where it's capable of everything under the Sun yet It only does a handful of things really well and doesn't do those other things at all.
Speaker 1: That's that's you know, sort of annoying.
Speaker 1: but in reality when I think about it, right?
Speaker 1: What would I really do with a phone that's better than the phone?
Speaker 1: I had right because so far every phone I've had has had more and more features and even my latest phone Right.
Speaker 1: I turned it on and when it was brand new I played with all the features and after a couple weeks All I did was make calls and occasionally text messages and even rarer than that took pictures.
Speaker 1: and that was it.
Speaker 1: I stopped using all those features that were so fancy and cool.
Speaker 0: See ya.
Speaker 0: I could have told you that Yeah, I use my phone to make calls and to occasionally make text message.
Speaker 1: Well didn't cost me anything.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't matter to me, you know, but if I had the iPhone, right?
Speaker 1: It would replace my iPod.
Speaker 1: So that would be at least one less thing I have to carry - it works with all the Google shit.
Speaker 0: So I would check my email on it and all that other such and also that the new the Google Maps Integration is pretty damn slick.
Speaker 0: I must say it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: And I would also, you know, I'd use it for phone and text message and whatnot.
Speaker 1: I'd probably use it for my alarm clock also.
Speaker 1: I think you can do that even though I heard the speaker is very quiet on it Which I guess would have to be fixed and the web browser on it is actually useful.
Speaker 1: So when we're sitting in the diner and someone says blah I could be like Wikipedia blah blah blah instead of going I'll remember to see that when I get home and then when I get home, of course, no one remembers.
Speaker 1: and The thing is if you look the Nokia like n-series like the n95 is capable of so much more than the iPhone.
Speaker 1: It can do all those things and more but people who have it don't really Statistically at least aren't using it for those things.
Speaker 1: if you look at like website traffic logs People, you know mobile phones that have web browsers most of them nowadays, right?
Speaker 1: Most mobile phones have web browsers.
Speaker 1: But if you look at the mobile, you know Percentage of different mobile web browsers that are visiting websites.
Speaker 1: about half of all mobile visitors are using iPhones Which means that all those other people with web browsers on their phones just aren't using the web browsers Even though they have them.
Speaker 0: because my phone has a web browser.
Speaker 0: I sure as hell don't use it.
Speaker 1: Well, you could install the opera browser on that on a blackberry.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about my blackberry.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay Yeah, I don't use that one.
Speaker 0: My razor has a web browser.
Speaker 0: I don't suck the web.
Speaker 1: Don't fucking use that piece of shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah The only reason I'm not gonna buy one is there's a good chance my company's just gonna get me and I guess I have a Pretty old blackberry right now, and I'm pretty sure they're just gonna get me a nice blackberry.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean a blackberry as sad as it is is sort of my second choice because It can do all the Google stuff just as well.
Speaker 1: And the only thing that iPhone has over the blackberry is That I would have to be able to get rid of my iPod and carry one less thing Which is sadly worth a lot to me.
Speaker 1: But the blackberry does everything else just fine better than anything else I've seen yet and the Android phone is the only thing that has a chance of unseating that the thing is.
Speaker 0: the only time I ever ever need to use any sort of smartphone feature is If I want to look at a map or look up a restaurant while I'm on the go.
Speaker 0: That's really the only time I would ever use it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't feel like it's worth the money or the time or the effort yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would actually see.
Speaker 1: thing is I made a lot.
Speaker 1: if I really think about it It's like having a piece of hardware that could do more than it does is annoying because I'm a nerd but in reality I would only use a B C D and E and even though the iPhone is hardware capable of XYZ It does all the ABC D and E's that I want to do and it does them.
Speaker 1: Well, yep So it even though I'd be pissed.
Speaker 1: I think it might work out for me And we'll see next year though because everything could change next year.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll get an iPhone Gen 2 Maybe I'll get an Android phone.
Speaker 0: Who knows I'm just gonna keep holding out.
Speaker 0: I could see my I'd be.
Speaker 0: it's more likely that I would instead of getting a smartphone or something just pay for Internet access via my laptop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not a bad deal either.
Speaker 1: The prices are going down and I think it's 60 a month now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially if I swing some sort of telecommuting periodically if I could just work from anywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is I've used those before cuz I had one, you know my job I quit and In my laptop, it would like even with the Verizon which is the best coverage here on the train It would cut in and out along the way.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's gonna do that for sure.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking more in terms of all right, say I'm telecommuting or something.
Speaker 0: I can go to the beach and just have my laptop.
Speaker 1: Yep, that that's a good.
Speaker 1: that's definitely a much better use of it than on the train on the way to work.
Speaker 0: No train on the way to work is not my primary.
Speaker 1: See what I'm really hoping for for train on the way to work is the Google gears.
Speaker 1: Yes They're working on more offline stuff.
Speaker 1: So right now the Google Reader sort of works offline, but not everything in my reader is like a full article.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of links.
Speaker 1: I want to click on.
Speaker 1: so but the Google gears?
Speaker 1: I think in the long run I'll be able to have my.
Speaker 1: you know I'll be able to sync my laptop sort of before I leave for work then go and All my stuff is on there and I could work on my laptop offline With all my Google apps and then get to work and sync it up to Google again.
Speaker 1: That'd be good times.
Speaker 0: Firefox Mozilla is also working on more offline stuff Yeah, and I've been playing around with Twiggy a lot and there's even an offline Twiggy.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I definitely think offline is gonna.
Speaker 1: offline work is gonna.
Speaker 1: you're gonna see major developments with that in the next 12 to 18 months.
Speaker 0: Well, at least I mean it really is just a stopgap until there is ubiquitous all the time always on internet everywhere Which is going to happen someday, but not in the neck.
Speaker 1: I definitely think that it's that the offline stuff is definitely a feature for the u.s Where there's not going to be ubiquitous internet for a very long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people in other countries are more cell phone action.
Speaker 1: don't care about that.
Speaker 0: I mean look we live in New York City and yet Ten minutes outside of once they get out of the tunnel on the train I lose my service like four times just because I go past buildings or around mountains or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep so things of the day.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: the one thing about Apple Mac worlds is that there's always the keynote that people make this crazy deal about.
Speaker 0: like a man Jobs is gonna say his thing and it's gonna be crazy and awesome and he's gonna say a million things.
Speaker 1: I think people don't.
Speaker 1: actually I mean some people Apple fanboys are excited about the keynote itself But really it's just the revealing of new things.
Speaker 1: You know if they could just if Apple just put up a web page.
Speaker 1: It's like these are the new things and these are the specs that would be just as you know because
Speaker 0: there are people and I direct evidence of this who actually thought of Mac world if they couldn't look at it at work or they as a spoiler and They avoided finding out what was announced until they got home so they could sit and watch the keynote.
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of it is also the slow reveal.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like they like things to be revealed like But I think sort of like opening a gift, you know If you went and it just opened your eyes and all the gifts are there unwrapped.
Speaker 1: It's not as good.
Speaker 0: plus Scott people do talk a lot about a. Steve Jobs gives these amazing keynotes.
Speaker 0: He's such an amazing speaker.
Speaker 0: A lot of people talk about that after Mac world.
Speaker 0: The thing is as someone has so wonderfully shown us on YouTube.
Speaker 0: He basically only talked for 60 seconds and everything else.
Speaker 0: He said was fluff.
Speaker 1: Yeah This is a pretty good thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, check out this video.
Speaker 0: it's just the entire everything that mattered from the keynote from Mac world this year in 60 seconds and actually a Significant part of that video was fooling around.
Speaker 0: stuff that didn't even need to be there could have been done in like 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: better better better All right.
Speaker 1: This is from 1993 or 2003.
Speaker 1: I think that's yeah, not 93 2003.
Speaker 1: So it's pretty.
Speaker 1: why would you say?
Speaker 1: 1993?
Speaker 1: I was being stupid.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So this is actually pretty old but it's new to me.
Speaker 1: So who gives a shit?
Speaker 1: What this is is a robot arm and it's like a top-of-the-line robot arm.
Speaker 1: It can pretty much move in any way that a robot arm can move and you know in all axes And it's got a little hand that can grip and move and do all this stuff, right?
Speaker 1: So people write software to make the robot arm do things that is cool or useful and then those people go on to Write the software for robot arms and factories.
Speaker 1: They do useful things like make cars or chips and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But in college you make the robot arm do funny things and that is this is why is my thing of the day?
Speaker 1: first the first video on this page is Describing how they got the road or not describing but it's an attempt to make the robot arm make a clock.
Speaker 0: Well more like 30 attempts or so, yeah, there's a whole bunch of different ways.
Speaker 1: Like what if we do it this way?
Speaker 1: What if we do it that way?
Speaker 1: the one way I really like is what they make a digital clock with numbers and the the arm moves the red sticks around to draw the numbers and then it counts to 60 and then it moves the hands around to Change the minute again.
Speaker 0: granted I was a fan most of all of the cop-out of just have it hold a stick that goes in a circle like the arm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it holds a stick and it rotates the stick like the arm of a clock And then occasionally picks up the other stick and rotates it.
Speaker 1: that's the top video on this page.
Speaker 1: Then there's a whole bunch of other like descriptions of the math and how robot arms work and cool stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he keeps scrolling down scrolling down scrolling down.
Speaker 1: There's another little video here.
Speaker 1: yes, which is a competition they had of basically these Denzel six dof robot arms, right and The competition is you have two robot arms and there's a piece of wood going from one to the other and there's a goal at either end of each piece of wood and there's three pegs right and you can program the robot arms to do whatever you want and The goal is to get your three pegs into the other guy's goal While also not letting his three pegs get into your goal, but both robot arms are activated at the same time.
Speaker 1: So it's like if you just try to score right away.
Speaker 1: You might leave yourself open unless you find some tricky way to score while also defending.
Speaker 1: Or if you defend right away, then they might knock your pegs over which you're done.
Speaker 1: if that happens.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know and it's it's a pretty clever problem thing.
Speaker 1: It's it's.
Speaker 1: it's a competition of both the humans programming the robot to solve this problem and also you know how well you can program the robot to move quickly and efficiently and precisely.
Speaker 1: and Some of the things people come up with his strategies are pretty.
Speaker 0: the guys who roll the pegs down instead of throwing them They get mad prom.
Speaker 1: the guys who roll the pegs are indeed my favorite guys.
Speaker 1: They are the most intelligent.
Speaker 1: but this I also like the guys who defend by moving back and forth very quickly Except it seemed like the slow-moving defense actually worked better.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: it's hard to tell one guy defended by holding the peg, you know, I've been moving the peg back and forth.
Speaker 1: I thought that was pretty clever too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't know how well that worked.
Speaker 0: I don't know how well it worked either but whatever And you get to see who wins in the end.
Speaker 1: so to Asian kids, of course Not to be racist but you know, there's this truth to that, uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean I was in this computer science competition thingy when I was in high school and it was you know It's pretty much.
Speaker 1: you go when you take a written test and then they it was bubbly in.
Speaker 1: and then they go and they you Know I could probably get a hundred on that test now But in that day not really.
Speaker 1: and then they go when they you know Run the test of these bubble scanners and then they say who wins and it was Asian kids Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: so today We're gonna talk about mice and keyboards.
Speaker 1: We realized we did a special on mice But we actually have quite a bit to say about keyboards.
Speaker 0: mostly I can boil it up pretty simply keyboards should be pretty standard.
Speaker 0: people who change the layout around sock and Particularly Dvorak is a dumb idea.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: That's not all I have to say.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there's more to.
Speaker 1: we can get to specifics here.
Speaker 1: back in the day It was the IBM XT keyboard.
Speaker 1: as far as I'm concerned is the keyboard.
Speaker 0: Everything else is just a hack compared to that except for the fact that it's loud as hell.
Speaker 1: It is live.
Speaker 1: I do like keyboards to be quiet.
Speaker 1: Actually, it's weird.
Speaker 1: I don't mind if my keyboard is loud as hell But if other people's keyboards are loud, it really really bothers me like complains all the time about my typing.
Speaker 1: I need other people to have quiet keyboards like no noise.
Speaker 0: Well, if I'm gonna have a quiet keyboard then you certainly don't get to have a loud keyboard.
Speaker 1: No, no, that's you know, that's I don't.
Speaker 1: so I don't have a loud one.
Speaker 1: It's only fair.
Speaker 1: but I don't like the IBM XT keyboard because it's loud, you know, even though I think that's the only reason you like.
Speaker 1: You know I like it because of the the tactility of the keys which happens to be to go along with loudness by a byproduct of the Spring.
Speaker 1: loaded keys that go click click click is the noise they make.
Speaker 1: if there's a way to make that silent.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't mind.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I really like keys that go click click click.
Speaker 1: with Springs.
Speaker 1: They're really hard to push and when you do push them down they go click and then they bounce back really hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually I prefer the membranes because they give a a lot of resistance up front.
Speaker 0: But once that is overcome then the resistance drops off and it's much more pleasant to type on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I pretty much use all membrane keyboards, but I would I would like a spring-loaded keyboard Time you used one.
Speaker 0: They're very not comfortable to type on and there's a lot more key travel per you tire yourself out faster.
Speaker 0: It's a bad idea.
Speaker 1: No, actually the spring-loaded happy hacking keyboard.
Speaker 1: I would get it but it's too much money.
Speaker 1: But what they did is they actually they have the tension on all the springs set differently for each key depending on you know Intelligentness and such and it's much quieter and you don't have to push them as far and it's good stuff anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that was that that was the keyboard, but it was too big.
Speaker 1: It was too loud.
Speaker 1: It went out of style.
Speaker 1: So since then people have gotten rid of a lot of the useless keys that were on that thing and we pretty much boiled it Down to escape the F keys those three the print screen and those other keys, you know
Speaker 0: Yeah the ones that no one knows what they do
Speaker 1: yeah the numpad the four arrows the six buttons above the arrows and then The keyboard with control and all right.
Speaker 0: What's always bothered me is that more and more?
Speaker 0: I always find it difficult to get a standard keyboard that has all the keys that have always been on keyboards in the proper places without anything weird or strange or different or special or I?
Speaker 0: Just a lot of those things are just so useless and just get in the way that I don't want them and it's getting harder And harder to get keyboards.
Speaker 0: They're just a keyboard.
Speaker 1: I mean the first thing that bothered me is you know They put the windows key in and I guess I can deal with the windows key now.
Speaker 0: but when the windows key was new it was like ah, I had no problem with the windows key because it was Pretty for what it did.
Speaker 0: It was a useful bit of functionality Yeah, but I guess well also the only complaint I ever saw from the windows key was from either fanboys who's am?
Speaker 0: Bill Gates blah?
Speaker 0: and People who were playing games like quake and they bumped the windows key.
Speaker 0: And my answer to that was don't bump the windows key.
Speaker 0: if you're accidentally hitting keys while you're playing an FPS That's probably why you're bad at them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hit it a couple times, but there's also the the Context menu key.
Speaker 1: Do you ever use that key?
Speaker 1: I bind it to do things Yeah, but I never use it for what it's supposed to be used for.
Speaker 0: I don't know why that key is there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really I. when they had they added that along with the windows key and I just don't understand it.
Speaker 0: I guess I just kind of.
Speaker 0: I look down I read forgot about that key and then I look down while Scott said that sure enough.
Speaker 0: There it is.
Speaker 1: There it is, and it's right in between the right control in the right alt.
Speaker 0: I just hit it and a context menu came up for Firefox.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hit the arrows.
Speaker 0: No, I'm in the context menu.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it's actually kind of useful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's in a bad place though.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, but I'd replace.
Speaker 0: I put it where caps lock is.
Speaker 1: I think well, I wouldn't put it where caps lock.
Speaker 0: Why don't use caps lock?
Speaker 1: I don't use caps like either.
Speaker 1: but you know what I put where caps like is control control because you know what?
Speaker 1: People don't use enough keyboard shortcuts.
Speaker 1: keyboard shortcuts are the way to go.
Speaker 1: I mean if you want to use your computer, you know, people always want faster computers, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, it takes too long to do things, you know It takes a long time Moving them using the mouse for absolutely everything them.
Speaker 1: how long it takes to move the mouse click move the mouse.
Speaker 0: granted that problem Can be solved and we've talked about this before.
Speaker 0: you should probably be using a really really high Sensitivity on your mouse.
Speaker 0: that too.
Speaker 1: but think even if you have that high sensitivity mouse, right?
Speaker 1: Even especially copy paste copy paste is the greatest example.
Speaker 1: What's faster?
Speaker 1: control C control V You know why you can mouse keyboard?
Speaker 0: Faster is highlight and then middle click.
Speaker 1: That's true, but My point is is that you know Firefox open a new tab control T. That's the way to do it.
Speaker 1: It's the fastest way.
Speaker 1: There's no faster way.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're opening a new a link in a tab, you can middle click on it.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: But the point is is that there are shortcuts to doing things faster And that is where you're gonna do.
Speaker 1: the only way to really do things faster to save the most time is To decrease the amount of time you spend interacting with the user interface and keyboard shortcuts are a part of that.
Speaker 1: There's also mouse shortcuts, but there are.
Speaker 1: keyboard shortcuts are very important and I mean mouse shortcuts.
Speaker 0: They have gestures and hot corners and things you can do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but with keyboard shortcuts control is a button you're gonna be hitting a lot and Over caps lock is a completely useless button that has no purpose in the modern world.
Speaker 0: caps lock has Some minor purposes.
Speaker 1: if you're writing in basic or something caps lock is really useful.
Speaker 0: if you're interacting with old software Yeah, or if you're doing like medical data entry or any sort of lights true factory kind of data entry stuff Yep, but see if I I guess if it's old software that requires all caps then caps like has a use.
Speaker 1: but modern software That wants all caps can just check to see if you input it a lowercase and all automatically uppercase it.
Speaker 1: So, but anyway caps like is not that useful.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna hit it that often unless you're dumbass.
Speaker 1: So Why should caps lock be in such a place that is easy to hit with your pinky finger all the time?
Speaker 0: this is why I like the idea of the optimist keyboard because I'm of the mind that in general the Layout of physically where all the keys are should never change Because muscle memory and that sort of thing is very important.
Speaker 0: and if you start to feel like I've used keyboard like they're all the worst Thing is at work, right?
Speaker 0: We have this Bloomberg terminal, which is like Oh, that's the thing that lets you trade just by pushing buttons.
Speaker 0: It's a special computer where I can look at about those things like stock prices and stuff Like.
Speaker 0: I can log and log into this thing and I can look up like security and from it All.
Speaker 1: those are real expensive those.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: You have to pay a fee monthly I think but I can all.
Speaker 0: it's funny.
Speaker 0: I can scan my fingerprint on it and it logs me in and I can hit a button and then I will be in a video chat with someone at Bloomberg.
Speaker 0: Yep immediately to get help Yep, but the keyboard physically is a little bit off.
Speaker 0: So the caps lock key is slightly bigger than it should be and By default no matter what unless I'm really careful.
Speaker 0: I'll hit caps lock every time.
Speaker 0: I mean to hit a Every single time.
Speaker 1: it's so bad It's awful.
Speaker 1: it's awful Yeah, and pretty much every computer I use I turn caps lock into control because control is very important for many sheet keyboard shortcuts especially in Firefox, which is the program I use most and Caps lock is much easier to hit than control controls all the way in the corner.
Speaker 1: I had to move my pinky real far to hit it and it makes it hard to you know.
Speaker 1: Also hit other letters, but if I use caps lock as control suddenly keyboard shortcuts are actually shortcuts and it's comfortable and it's good times
Speaker 0: Now in terms of muscle memory, I mean in the optimus, I think that in general people Changing the meta keys in different configurations is probably you could do that to be a more efficient typist or whatever.
Speaker 0: But I'm of the mind that changing the locations of primary use keys, you know letters and numbers is a bad idea.
Speaker 0: That is why Dvorak is a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Dvorak is a bad idea.
Speaker 1: I mean Dvorak if you don't know is basically the idea of Dvorak is this look at the way you're at.
Speaker 1: The letters on the keyboard are laid out right Q W E R T Y is what you see in the top left And that's why it's called QWERTY.
Speaker 1: QWERTY you yup, right now On a Dvorak, as difficult, right on a Dvorak keyboard?
Speaker 1: Yes on a Dvorak keyboard.
Speaker 1: The idea is that the letters you hit the most should be under your fingers.
Speaker 1: So like the left hand is like your four fingers are on like A O E U the vowels and like your right hand I think is like R S T L N something like that I'm not sure exactly but it's all the very frequently hit letters are right under your fingers.
Speaker 1: So the logically you if you're typing normal text you're moving your fingers less and you're Alternating more because like the vowels are on the left and the consonants on the right and you generally kind of alternate them a little Bit.
Speaker 1: so it's pretty well thought out from that logical standpoint.
Speaker 1: The problem is the reality does not match the logic.
Speaker 0: well, the thing is a lot of people who use Dvorak layouts have a very fundamental misunderstanding of what Dvorak is and what problem it is Theoretically going to solve.
Speaker 0: because the argument I always hear is that yeah QWERTY was designed back in the days of typewriters and typewriters jammed if you type too quickly.
Speaker 0: So QWERTY was designed to slow you down so that you couldn't cause a problem.
Speaker 1: That's not true.
Speaker 0: In fact QWERTY is one of the if you look at statistically like the a bit not in terms of human use But in terms of positioning of letters.
Speaker 0: Statistically as opposed to a random layout QWERTY is in the very very top percentile of Very efficient layouts already.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's designed, you know, they didn't want the keyboards to jam.
Speaker 0: So the best way to make them not jam is to make sure that on average you will not hit two keys that are next To each other very close to each other time wise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why people always talk about like, you know Secretaries is like or stewardesses is.
Speaker 1: stewardesses is one of the few one of the longest words You can type on one hand on a QWERTY keyboard because there aren't too many words You can type on one hand on a QWERTY keyboard.
Speaker 1: It's designed to make you alternate not to make you go slow.
Speaker 1: But for you to alternate that way the typewriter which has the hammers coming from both sides Won't hit two on the same side at the same time.
Speaker 1: It'll screw up.
Speaker 0: so Alternating like that between left hand and right hand is pretty much the most efficient way human being can type as far as we've seen.
Speaker 1: I mean you can make a layout.
Speaker 1: that is that you know.
Speaker 1: if someone learned it would be faster than QWERTY.
Speaker 1: but QWERTY is fast enough and the fact that it's already standard on so many keyboards around the world just you know Makes it so much better.
Speaker 1: It's like why should we change from something?
Speaker 1: That's 90% good to something 92% good which would have no significant advantage, you know Considering that everyone's gonna have to relearn it?
Speaker 0: now I have a lot of.
Speaker 0: I don't want to make this the QWERTY Dvorak show But yeah, I I just it is my opinion that the vast majority of people use Dvorak do it for pretentious.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm better than you.
Speaker 1: I'm different than your reasons and don't actually understand and they always come up with claims like oh I'm so much more comfortable doing it this way Oh, I'm so much faster doing it this way.
Speaker 0: There has never been a study that showed any Usefulness of Dvorak over QWERTY.
Speaker 1: Yes, and while you know individual anecdotes may say so every study of you know typing speed and comfort and you know, I guess What's it called the wrist problem?
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah carpal tunnel and all that RSI.
Speaker 1: no, no, there's been no link between any of that and QWERTY versus Dvorak.
Speaker 1: Dvorak is not scientifically shown to be better in any way and many studies show it being just as it's not significantly better.
Speaker 1: It's not worth learning.
Speaker 0: It's it's kind of a dumb idea for nerds, but you know, I always found it interesting I think back to when I was a kid and like I Didn't know how to type.
Speaker 0: but then again typing was not Commonly done by kids like computers were.
Speaker 1: so I didn't learn that I was using computers a lot like since I was you know kindergarten and I didn't learn to type until like 10th 11th grade.
Speaker 0: the funny thing is I remember I was I was an awful typist and They always at school tried to make us use these programs to teach you how to type and they those didn't work.
Speaker 1: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: So I remember I learned when I learned how to type was when I got ICQ and I made friends around the world You know back when there weren't that many people online.
Speaker 0: So if you just talk to a random person odds were they were pretty cool and I I still to this day Have a few friends around the world that I met through ICQ back in the day and Typing to friends online.
Speaker 0: I Learned how to type really really well really really quickly.
Speaker 0: The only way to learn how to type is just to type.
Speaker 0: Mmm, don't take classes just.
Speaker 1: actually funnily enough I learned how to type from a class in my school with this old lady on these IBM XT keyboards.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean part.
Speaker 1: it was really.
Speaker 1: it's like part of it was a. you know There was a program but the program was mostly just something like test.
Speaker 1: what I learned It was just.
Speaker 1: it was weird cuz like taking the class at first like I was just doing it and I felt like.
Speaker 1: you know I had felt before just like in all those other classes, you know We're using a program and I wasn't learning how to type.
Speaker 1: we were using like, you know, the original Microsoft Word or whatever, you know and Like.
Speaker 1: I didn't feel like I was learning how to type but amazingly enough somehow I came out of it typing and I was like Holy shit, it was amazing.
Speaker 0: but I feel like it's not really a newest thing to say but definitely Being able to type is pretty much a fundamental skill of the world.
Speaker 0: now Yeah You'll be like if I see someone under the age of 40 you cannot type very quickly and they don't have an injury or a reason Physically that they cannot type they're gonna have problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean typing is like if I see someone like not typing properly or quick speedily or in a good way That's like you can't read Really say properly because there are a lot of people type in a lot of really weird ways like you.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: The thing is the only weird thing is I don't use the home row.
Speaker 0: I type, you know, QWERTY standard nothing special But I type kind of.
Speaker 0: I float my hands around the keyboard back and forth and there's no place.
Speaker 0: There's no like default place for my hands are but I can dive really really freaking quick.
Speaker 0: So I think it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I type, you know, I use the home row action.
Speaker 1: But you know, it's sort of like DDR in a way where I don't always move the finger back to the home row.
Speaker 1: You know, sometimes I'll leave them hanging out there.
Speaker 1: But you know my hand position generally stays in such a way where if I do reset I'm on the home row.
Speaker 0: You know Scott always yells at me that I type loud.
Speaker 1: you do type loud I don't know.
Speaker 0: I hit.
Speaker 0: maybe I play the piano or something, but I always hit the keyboard really hard.
Speaker 0: I think I need a more beefy keyboard to stand up to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I try to hit the keys.
Speaker 1: Oh just like just hard enough like I tap like tap tap tap.
Speaker 1: I try to just you know Make them register just once because I have it set where if you hold it down a little bit too much if you hit it Too hard, you'll type like two or three letters.
Speaker 0: the weird thing though is I got this Logitech keyboard And I got it because way back when I needed a new keyboard suddenly at RIT This was the only keyboard in the entire store that had the proper layout of keys didn't have anything weird on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you look at keyboards today and I mean laptop is an exception because a laptop you have to rearrange the keys And use an FN key in order to fit all those things on to a small space.
Speaker 1: That's acceptable, right?
Speaker 1: The problem is a lot of normal keyboards have no reason at all to be.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: Change the layout like they move all the keys around nowadays like they'll make.
Speaker 0: They'll make the enter key double big and they'll put backspace over by tab or something.
Speaker 1: Why why do you do that?
Speaker 1: or like they'll make that you know?
Speaker 1: I guess older keyboards use the l-shaped enter key and the top.
Speaker 1: that shouldn't be.
Speaker 1: you need the backspace in the pipe there.
Speaker 1: That's what belongs there the backspace in the pipe not the l-shaped enter key.
Speaker 1: screw that now.
Speaker 0: the worst thing is a lot of people get rid of the numb pet now that I could see get ridding getting rid of the numpad.
Speaker 0: if You're you like a special purpose-built keyboard like on a laptop or whatever.
Speaker 0: But the numpad is the most efficient way to enter numbers.
Speaker 0: The numpad is the most efficient way if you're entering numbers because I learned 10 key my first job I ever had working for the census.
Speaker 0: part of what I did was 10 key data entry for like HR and in payroll and If you learn 10 key you can put data into a computer really freaking quick and you can type numbers like you wouldn't believe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I actually the keyboard I use is the happy hacking keyboard, right and I use it for many reasons.
Speaker 1: First of all, it's USB, right and it's got a USB hub in it so you can have.
Speaker 1: it has two USB holes on it, which is really cool and It doesn't have a numpad.
Speaker 1: and it's nice and small.
Speaker 1: and the advantages of it are it's small the keys are high quality Caps lock is control.
Speaker 1: So even if the operating system doesn't let you turn caps lock into control caps lock is control So it doesn't fucking matter.
Speaker 1: All right, all the keys, you know, it doesn't have a numpad but everything else is laid out really just perfectly and Escape is much closer to your fingers than it is on a normal keyboard Which is very important for me because I use VI a lot and in VI you have to hit escape very very often.
Speaker 0: Escape colon WQ bang.
Speaker 1: Alright, so because I hit the escape key So goddamn often I pretty much have to use the happy hacking keyboard if I'm coding or else I get very uncomfortable Hitting the escape key so far away from my finger.
Speaker 1: Oh my god It's great.
Speaker 0: The weird thing is I got this keyboard because it was the simplest one I could get at that store And I know there are good keyboards out there, but I was a poor college kid and you know was years ago.
Speaker 0: So I had to go to like a Best Buy and just buy whatever keyboard was there.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: along the top of this thing, there's all these like media control buttons.
Speaker 0: There's a. There's all these weird buttons that to this day.
Speaker 0: I've never seen anyone who actually use these buttons for anything useful.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've got an email button.
Speaker 0: great.
Speaker 0: I need an email button on my keyboard.
Speaker 0: for what?
Speaker 0: Yeah to open your email program and I've got a messenger slash SMS button to open up your a webcam button and I touch button a search button a shopping button.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah shopping.
Speaker 1: That's a useful button.
Speaker 1: What's a push?
Speaker 1: It goes to Amazon?
Speaker 0: Push it just.
Speaker 0: it just charges something random to my credit card.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean like a lot of the modern keyboards that you will buy at the store have all these crazy buttons on them and some Of them.
Speaker 0: I like the volume buttons the volume control on the keyboard I like and the other thing I like but I use it for a weird purpose is I have the like win and control suite on the top of here.
Speaker 0: It's you know, like track left right play pause.
Speaker 0: I like those two, but I never use those for that because I never need to do that on the keyboard.
Speaker 0: I never.
Speaker 0: it's never something I need to do, but I always bind those sorts of things to move windows between desktops Mmm, I'd use keyboard shortcuts for that.
Speaker 1: So yeah, but anyway, yeah though a lot of those keys They stick them on there and it's just.
Speaker 1: I don't like it It's not.
Speaker 1: most of them are not useful.
Speaker 1: and like I have an external numpad, you know so I can do ten key data entry when I need to.
Speaker 1: it's a USB numpad and It has some media buttons on it, you know, so when it's plugged in I might use them you know to volume control mute play pause whatever but It's I mostly use it for just.
Speaker 1: it's also a calculator by the way.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I do Yeah, it's good stuff.
Speaker 1: So I like that that combination but I The worst thing that bothers me about a lot of the keyboards besides adding the stupid extra keys that are useless is how they put The delete key, I guess people hate control delete so often that they got rid of the insert.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the delete key sort of eats it.
Speaker 0: I use the insert key.
Speaker 0: The injured key does stuff.
Speaker 1: It does do stuff and it I use it quite often like to do like, you know shift page insert to do like.
Speaker 1: You know pastes and vim and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: or also if I want to turn on overwrite if I'm editing some sort of configuration File.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess in vim you don't use insert to do that, but nobody like word.
Speaker 0: I do that and word.
Speaker 1: you do that sure and Fucking.
Speaker 1: they like they must.
Speaker 1: I think they put it somewhere else on the keyboard.
Speaker 1: But they make the delete key so much bigger and they make it eat up the insert key and they move the insert key.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 1: Don't do that.
Speaker 1: Why are you doing that?
Speaker 1: You're changing something.
Speaker 1: It's not broken.
Speaker 1: It's not broke.
Speaker 1: Don't fix it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, they'll say about keyboards.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: This was kind of a cop-out show.
Speaker 0: What do you want on a holiday where we're you know, don't worry tomorrow We're talking about one of the greatest games to ever be released for the Nintendo Entertainment System.
Speaker 0: Yes, we are and we're gonna talk a little bit about some the interesting technology related to that one.
Speaker 0: That's how I linked this in.
Speaker 0: Oh, you used to use a special chip.
Speaker 1: Maybe Maybe people might have figured it out.
Speaker 0: They better have.
Speaker 0: if you're a Nintendo fan You don't know what Nintendo game we're talking about.
Speaker 0: You're sad sad Nintendo fan.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.